<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46267" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>Preface</title>
	<subtitle/>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>PREFACE TO THIS VOLUME.</head>
		<para id="p1">The Sixth Volume of The Statutes of the Realm contains the Statutes from the
Commencement of the Reign of King James the Second, A. D. 1685, to the End of
the 6th and 7th Years of the Reign of King William and Queen Mary, A. D. 1694.</para>
		<para id="p2">This Volume has been printed, and the Chronological Table and Index have been framed,
in strict conformity with the Principles referred to in the Preface to the Fifth Volume; and
it is therefore unnecessary to repeat them here: it may however be proper to mention,
that although Queen Mary appears to have died between the passing of the Statutes
Chapter II. and Chapter III. of the 6th and 7th Years of the Reign of King William and
Queen Mary, yet the Heading is continued throughout those Years "6 &amp; 7 Gul. &amp; Mar.,"
as the Record affords no Authority for breaking the Year: Indeed it seems probable, had the
Attention of the Legislature at that time been called to the Subject, that the Statute which
now stands as Chapter III. 6 &amp; 7 William and Mary, would have followed a corresponding
Heading upon a new Parliament Roll as Chapter I. 1 William III.; as it is obvious that
no Year or Chapter from the last Act of the Reign of William and Mary could have been
correctly designated as a continuing Year or Chapter of the Reign of William the Third.</para>
		<para id="p3">Three Engravings, the First, of the Act for removing and preventing Questions and
Disputes concerning the assembling and sitting of the then present Parliament, 1 William
and Mary; the Second, of the Act for establishing the Coronation Oath, 1 William and
Mary; and the Third, of the Act for recognizing King William and Queen Mary, and for
avoiding all Questions touching the Acts made in the Parliament assembled at Westminster
the 13th Feb. 1688, 2 William and Mary, are inserted respectively at Pages 23, 56, and 156
of this Volume.</para>
		<para id="p4">London,<br/>
March 1819.</para>
		<para id="p5">JOHN RAITHBY,<br/>
Sub-Commissioner.</para>
	</section>
</report>


