<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46268" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>James the Second, 1685</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for setleing the Revenue on His Majestie for His Life which was setled on His late Majestie for His Life. [Rot. Parl. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Chapter I.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Grant to the late King of Subsidy of Tonnage, and Poundage by 12 Car. II. c. 4. confirmed by 13 C. II. st.I. c.7. Grant of Duties on Beer, &amp;c. by 12 Car. II. c. 23. confirmed by 13 Car. II. c. 7.; The said Subsidy of Tonnage and Poundage, and the faid Duties on Beer, &amp;c. granted to the present King for life; Recited Acts and an Order for Fees revived and continued.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS by an Act of Parlyament made in the Twelfth Yeare of His late Majestyes Raigne of Blessed
Memory and Confirmed in the Thirteenth Yeare of His said Majestyes Raigne Entituled A Subsidie
granted to the King of Tonnage and Poundage and other Summes of Money payable upon Merchandize Exported
and Imported, A certaine Subsidie of Tonnage and Poundage acording to the Rates therein mentioned and Rules
and Orders thereunto annexed was given and granted unto His late Majestye for His Life; And whereas by
an Act of Parlyament made in the Twelfth Yeare of His late Majestyes Raigne and Confirmed in the Thirteenth
Yeare of His said Majesties Raigne Entituled A Grant of certaine Impositions upon Beere Ale Cyder and other
Liquors for the Increase of His Majestyes Revenue dureing His Life severall Rates Impositions Dutyes and
Charges upon Beere Ale Cyder and other Liquors therein mentioned were given and granted to His late Majestie for
His Life; The Commons in Parlyament assembled doe Give and Grant to your most excellent Majestie the aforesaid.
Subsidie of Tonnage and Poundage and the several Rates Duties and Impositions upon Beere Ale Cyder and other
Liquors in the respective Acts aforesaid, And doe most humbly beseech your Majestie that it may be enacted, And bee
it enacted by the King's most excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and Commons in this your present Parlyament assembled and by Authoritie of the same, That the aforesaid
Subsidie of Tonnage and Poundage and the severall Rates Dutyes and Impositions upon Beere Ale Cyder and other
Liquors aforesaid be Levyed Collected and Paid unto Your Majestie dureing your Life; And that the aforesaid Acts and
and every Article Rule and Clause therein mentioned from the Sixth Day of February last past, And alsoe that an
Order of the Commons in Parlyament assembled made in pursuance of the Rules and Orders annexed to the
aforementioned Act of Tonnage and Poundage for setleing of Officers Fees Dated the Seventeenth of May One thousand
six hundred sixty two and signed by Sir Edward Turner then Speaker, shall be of full force and effect to all Intents
and Purposes dureing your Majestyes Life as if the same were particularly and at large recited in the Body of this Act.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. 12 Car. II. c. 19. 13 &amp; 14 Car. II. c. II. continued for the King's Life.</head>
			<para id="p3">And bee it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That one Act of Parlyament made in the Twelfth yeare of
his late Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act to prevent Fraudes and Concealments of Customs and Subsidies As alsoe
one Act made in the Fourteenth Yeare of his late Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for preventing Fraudes and
regulating Abuses in His Majestyes Customs be of full force and effect dureing His Majestyes Life which God long
preserve.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


