<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46270" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>James the Second, 1685</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for Granting His Majestie an Imposition upon all Wines and Vineger Imported betweene the Foure and and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred eighty five and the Foure and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety and three. [Rot. Parl. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>For Repairs of the Navy, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Imposition of &pound;8. per Ton on French Wine and Vinegar, and &pound;12. per Ton on Spanish Wine</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Most Gracious Soveraigne<br/>
Wee Your Majestyes most Dutifull and Loyall Subjects the Commons Assembled in Parlyament, towards a
Supply for Repaires of the Navy and providing Stores for the Navy and Ordnance and other your Majestyes
weighty and important Occasions, and with an humble and Thankfull Acknowledgement of Your Majestyes Favourable
and Tender Reguard of Us Your Commons, have Chearfully and Unanimously given and granted unto Your
Majestie an Aid and Assistance to be Raised and Levyed upon all Wines and Vineger to be imported into this Your
Majestyes. Kingdome according to such Rates and dureing such Time and in such manner and forme as herein after
followeth; And Wee doe humbly beseech Your Majestie that it may bee enacted, And bee it enacted by the Kings
most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in
this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same, That for all French Wines Spanish Wines or
other Wines whatsoever as alsoe for all Vineger which at any Time after the Fower and twentyeth Day of June in the
Yeare of Our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty five and before the Foure and twentyeth Day of June in the
Yeare of Our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety three shall bee Imported into England or Wales or the Towne
or Port of Berwicke upon Tweede there shall be duely Answered and Paid to His Majestie the further Rates and
Dutyes hereafter mentioned (that is to say) For every Tun of French Wine and of Vineger which shall bee Imported
within the Time aforesaid the Summe of Eight Pounds by the Tun and soe after that Rate for any greater or lesser
Quantity And alsoe for every Tun of Spanish Wines or of any other Wines which shall be Imported within the Time
aforesaid the Summe of Twelve Pounds by the Tun and soe after that Rate for any greater or lesser Quantity.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Importer to pay Duties before landing, or to be bound for Payment at Three equal Payments.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Sureties for Duties taken at Discretion of Commissioners</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the better and more sure Collecting and Receiving of all and singular the Dutyes hereby Imposed Bee it
further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any Person or Persons within the Time aforesaid shall Import or
cause to bee Imported by way of Merchandize or otherwise any of the Liquors such Importer shall upon the Entry
made of such Liquors and before the Landing thereof Pay downe the Dutyes hereby imposed in ready Money
deducting the Allowance hereafter mentioned or otherwise become Bound unto His Majestie with Two or more
sufficient Sureties or procure Three other Persons to become Bound to His Majestie to Answere and Pay unto His
Majestie the whole Rates and Duties hereby Imposed by Three severall and equall Payments The First Payment
thereof to be made within Three Months after the Date of the said Obligation The Second Payment to be made
within Six Months after the Date of the said Obligation And the Third and last Payment to be made within Nine
Months after the Date of the said Obligation The takeing which Bonds and the approbation of the Sureties therein to
be named is hereby left to the Discretion of such Farmers or other Commissioners for the Time being as shall be
intrusted with the Receipt and Management of His Majestyes Customes and Subsidies of Tonnage and Poundage or
their Deputy Collectors in the severall Ports or such other person or persons as His Majestie shall Authorize and
Appoint to Collect the Dutyes ariseing by this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Abatement out of Duties on Payment in ready Money.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Importers nevertheless liable to Duties.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">Provided alwayes And it is hereby Declared and Enacted That all and every person and persons Importing any
of the Liquors aforesaid within the time aforesaid by way of Merchandize or otherwise who shall pay the Dutyes which
by this Act are due and payable in ready Money shall be allowed and abated out of the said Dutyes after the Rate
of Ten Pounds per Cent, for a Yeare in consideration of such ready Money soe paid downe and advanced.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Liquors landed, without paying or securing Duties, forfeited.</head>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any of the said Liquors shall be Imported within
the Time aforesaid and Landed without present Payment made of the Rates and Duties by this Act imposed in Cases
where this Act requires present Payment to be made or without Security given for Payment thereof in Cases where
this Act admitts of Security to be taken That then and in every such Case all and every the Liquors soe Imported
and Landed or the value thereof shall bee forfeited One Moyety thereof to His Majestie and the other Moyety to
him or them that shall or will Sue for the same And shall and may be Recovered in any Court of Record by Action
of Debt Bill Plaint or Information wherein noe Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed nor any more
then One Imparlance And yet neverthelesse the person soe Importing and Landing any of the said Liquors shall
notwithstanding such Forfeitures soe as aforesaid incurred remaine and continue lyable unto and shall answere and
pay unto His Majestie the Rates and Duties for such Liquors which by this Act are due and payable.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Importer chargeable with Duty for what shall remain Neat after Allowances by Act of Tonnage and Poundage of &pound;8. per Cent.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Allowance to Importers not being Retailers on Liquors imported to sell again and lying on Hand; Oath by such Importers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And whereas by the Act for Tonnage and Poundage and the Instructions and Rules for Collecting His Majestyes
Dutyes ariseing thereby it is Directed that certaine Allowances be made upon Importation of Wines and other Liquors
Bee it further Enacted That noe Importer thereof shall bee chargeable by vertue of this Act to pay the Duty hereby
required for any greater proportion of Wines or other Liquors duely Entered at the Custome-House then what shall
remaine Neat after all such Allowances and Abatements; And whereas this present Act gives noe abatement to any
Person upon Exportation of any the Liquors aforesaid Bee it further Enacted and Declared That all Importers not
being Vintners or Retailers (who are hereby declared shall pay ready Money for the whole Duty) who shall Import
any of the aforesaid Liquors within the Time aforesaid and shall make Oath that the same are Imported by way of
Merchandize and with intent to Sell againe (which Oath the Farmers or Commissioners of His Majesties Customs for
the time being or in their absence the Collector of His Majesties Customes in each severall and respective Port or such
other person or persons as His Majestie shall Authorize and Appoint to Collect the Duties ariseing by this Act have
hereby power to Administer) That then and in every such Case for and in consideration of any defect or damage
that may happen by any of the aforesaid Liquors lyeing longer on the said Importers hands then heretofore or by
reason of any other Accident there shall be allowed and abated to every such Importer the further Allowance of
Eight Pounds per Cent. and noe more.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Merchants not liable to Duty for Prizage Wine.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided That noe Merchant shall be Charged with any Duty imposed by this Act for the Prizage Wine which
he Imports in any Shipp or Vessell Nor shall any Security bee by him given for the same but that it be recieved
and taken from the person who hath or enjoyeth the benefitt of the said Prizage Wine who is hereby appoynted to
pay the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. No Allowance, &amp;c. on Exportation of imported Liquors.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwayes And it is hereby Declared and Enacted That if any of the said Imported Liquors for which any
of the Rates and Duties by this Act Imposed shall be paid downe and advanced or otherwise secured as aforesaid
shall at any Time after such Importation be againe Exported into Parts beyond the Seas That then and in every such
case the Person or Persons soe Exporting the same shall bee wholly barred and excluded from haveing or recieving
backe the Duties of this Act soe paid downe [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] advanced or any Part thereof, nor shall the Securitie formerly given
by such person Exporting for the true payment of the Duties by this Act Imposed, be any wayes razed lessened or
discharged by reason of such Exportation but the same Securities shall remaine and continue in full force until the
Dutyes thereby secured be fully and wholly satisfyed and paid Any such Exportation to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Power of Officers to enter Ships and search, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Officers and others doing Acts tending to defraud Revenue liable to Penalties of former Acts; Proof of Payment of Duty to be on Claimant.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p13">And for the better Prevention of all such Frauds which at any time hereafter may be committed to the prejudice
of His Majestie in the due Collecting and Receiving of the Duties hereby Imposed upon such Liquors to be Imported as
aforesaid, Bee it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Officers of His Majestyes Customes or such other
Person or Persons as His Majestie shall Authorize and Appoint to collect the Duties ariseing by this Act shall have
like Power and Authoritie to enter on board Shipps and Vessells and make Searches and to doe all other Matters and
Things which may tend to secure the true Payment of the Duties by this Act imposed and the due and orderly
Collection thereof which any Customers Collectors or other Officers of any of His Majesties Ports can or may doe
touching the Secureing His Majesties Customs of Tonnage and Poundage and all the said Liquors to be Imported
within the Time aforesaid and Landed without doeing and performing what by this Act is required to be done and
performed before the Landing thereof: And all Officers of His Majestyes Customs and all Persons Importing any of
the said Liquors and all others imployed by His Majestie in the Collection of the Duties ariseing by this Act who shall
be found guilty of any Act or Neglect tending to defraude His Majestie of any the Duties hereby Imposed shall be
subject and lyeable to the same Seizures Penalties and Forfeitures which by vertue of any former Act can or may
be inflicted in such Cases where His Majestie is defrauded or endeavoured to be defrauded of any of His Customs
and Subsidies as fully and amply as if the same Clauses of Seizures Penalties and Forfeitures and the same Distribution
of such Forfeitures and the same Remedy for Recovery thereof had beene againe in this Act particularly Repeated
Applyed and Enacted. And if any Liquors Seised for any Offence committed against this Act shall be claimed
by any person as the Importer thereof the proofe whether the Duties thereof be duely Paid or Secured shall lye
upon such Claimer and shall not be incumbent on His Majestie or any Prosecutor or Informer on Behalfe of His
Majestie and himselfe.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


