<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46274" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>James the Second, 1685</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act for Reviveing and continuing Two former Acts for Encouragement of Coynage. [Rot. Parl. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>18 Car. II. c. 5; continued by; 25 Car. II. c.8.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas great Benefitt and Advantage hath accrued to this Kingdome by One Act of Parlyament passed in
the Eighteenth Yeare of the Raigne of His late Majestie King Charles the Second of Blessed Memory
Entituled An Act for Encouragement of Coynage and continued by another Act of Parlyament passed in the Five
and twentyeth yeare of the Raigne of the said late King both which said Acts are since determined and expired
soe that unlesse the said Acts be Revived and Continued the Encouragement given thereby will cease and this
Kingdome be deprived for the future of soe great a good as it hath thereby for these yeares last enjoyed.</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Revived and continued for Seven Years, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">Wee therefore Your Majestyes Dutifull and Loyall Subjects do Give and Grant unto Your Majestie the Rates
Duties and Impositions mentioned in the said Act of Parlyament made in the Eighteenth yeare of the Raigne of
His late Majestie King Charles the Second Intituled An Act for Encouragement of Coynage And doe humbly
pray that it may bee Enacted and bee it Enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice
and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament Assembled and by
the Authoritie of the same That the said Acts of Parlyament and every the Clauses Articles and Sentences therein
contained shall be and are by vertue of this Acts Revived and Continued and shall be in Force for the space of
Seven yeares to Commence from the First Day of August One thousand six hundred eighty five, and untill the
end of the first Session of Parlyament then next following and noe longer.</para>
	</section>
</report>


