<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46273" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>James the Second, 1685</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act for repealing certaine Clauses in an Act of Parlyament made in the Nine and twentyeth and Thirtyeth
yeares of the Raigne of His late Majestie for Prohibiting French Com[m]odities. [Rot. Parl. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>29 &amp; 30 Car. II; c. I.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas by a certaine Act made in the Twenty ninth and Thirtyeth yeare of the Raigne of his late
Majestie of ever Blessed memory Entituled An Act for the Raiseing Money by a Poll and otherwise to
Enable His Majestie to enter into an actuall Warr against the French King and for Prohibiting French Commodities
it is amongst other things Provided and Enacted That from and after the Twentyeth of March One thousand six
hundred seaventy seven noe French Wine Vineger Brandy Linnen Cloth Silks Salt Paper or any Manufactures made
of or mixed with Silke Thread Woole Haire Gold or Silver or Leather being of the Growth Product and
Manufacture of any of the Dominions or Territories of the French King should dureing the Terme of Three years
to be accounted from the Twentyeth Day of March or before the end of the first Session of Parliament after the
expiration of the said three yeares be brought in or imported into any Port or Place within His Majesties Kingdome
of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede or Isles of Jersey Guernsey Alderney Sarke
or Isle of Man from any Place or Port whatsoever mixt or unmixt with any Commodity of the Growth or Product
of any other Nation Place or County whatsoever under certaine Paines Penalties and Forfeitures to be adjudged,
recovered and executed as by the said Act appeareth.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Clause of Prohibition and Penalties thereon in the said Act repealed.</head>
			<para id="p2">Now for the Repealing the said Clause of Prohibition and all the Paines Penalties and Forfeitures thereupon
depending Bee it Enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament Assembled and by the Authoritie of the same
That from henceforward the said Clause of Prohibition and every Part thereof and every Matter and Thing therein
contained and all other Clauses in the said Act mentioned whereby any Paines Penalties or Forfeitures are imposed
for or by reason of the Importation or bringing in of any French Commodities contrary to the said Prohibition are
and every of them is hereby Repealed annulled and made void as if the same had never beene made.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


