<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46275" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>James the Second, 1685</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act against the Importation of Gun-powder Arms and other Ammunition and Utensils of Warr. [Rot. Parl. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">Whereas to the great Prejudice of this Kingdome and the Discouragement and Impoverishment of the
Gun-smiths and others Artificers great quantities of Arms and Ammunition have of late yeares beene
Imported to the endangering the Peace and Quiet of this Kingdome.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. None shall import Gunpowder, &amp;c. without Licence.</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">Upon Forfeiture of Goods imported, and Treble the Value thereof; Application of Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">For Remedy whereof Bee it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament Assembled and by the Authoritie
of the same That it shall not at any Time from and after the Tenth day of July One thousand six hundred
eighty and five be lawfull to or for any person or persons whatsoever without Licence from His Majestie His Heires
and Successors to Import or bring into this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede by way of Merchandize any Gunpowder Arms Ammunition or Utensills of Warr upon Paine and
Forfeiture of all and every such Goods soe Imported as aforesaid to His Majestie His Heires and Successors and
the person or persons who shall soe Import or bring in the same or in whose Custodie any such Gunpowder
Arms Ammunition or Utensills of Warr shall be found being thereof lawfully Convicted shall forfeite Treble the
Value of the Goods soe Imported One moyety thereof unto His Majestie His Heires and Successors and the other
moyety thereof to such person or persons who will Sue for the same by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information
in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law
shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Obtaining Grant or Licence for sole making or importing Gunpowder, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Premunire, Disability of Office, and Grant, &amp;c. void</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwayes That if any person or persons whatsoever Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate shall by colour of
this Act or otherwise obtaine from His Majestie His Heires or Successors any Letters Patents Licence or Grant
for the sole Makeing or Importing any Gunpowder Arms, Ammunition, or other Utensills of War and shall putt
the same in execution or by colour thereof molest or hinder any person or persons who lawfully make any the
things before mentioned in this Kingdome or shall obtaine any Letters Patents Licence or Grant for the Importing
of Gun-powder Arms Ammunition or other Utensills of Warr by way of Merchandize to make Profit thereof other
then for the immediate furnishing of the Publique Stores of his Majestie his Heires and Successors That then the
person and persons soe offending shall incurr and sustaine the Paines Penalties and Forfeitures contained and provided
in the Statute of Provision and Premunire made in the Sixteenth yeare of the Raigne of King Richard the
Second and be disabled to hold any Office or Imployment under his Majestie his Heires and Successors and all
and every such Letters Licence Patent and Grant and every of them for the sole makeing and Importing the
said Commodities shall be void to all Intents and Purposes as if the same had never beene had or made Any
Clause of Non obstante or other Provision or Covenant to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


