<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46277" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>James the Second, 1685</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for the Providing necessary Carriages for His Majestie in His Royall Progresse and Removalls. [Rot. Parl. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>12 Car. II. c. 24; &sect; 13.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas by an Act made in Parliament the Twelfth yeare of His [late <ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Majesties Raigne Entituled An Act for
takeing away the Court of Wards and Liveries and Tenures in Capite and by Knights-Service and Purveyance
and for Setleing a Revenue upon His Majestie in lieu thereof It was (amongst other things) Enacted for the Reasons
and Recompence therein expressed That from thenceforth noe Person or Persons by any Warrant Commission or
Authoritie under the Great Seale or otherwise by colour of Buying or makeing Provision or Purveyance for His Majestie
or any Queene of England for the time being or of any of the Children of any King or Queene of England that shall be
or for his their or any of their Houshold shall take any Cart Carriage or other thing whatsoever of any of the Subjects
of His Majestie His Heires or Successors without the free and full consent of the Owner or Owners thereof had and
obtained without menace or enforcement nor shall summon warne take use or require any the said Subjects to furnish
or finde any Horses Oxen or other Cattell Carts Ploughs Wains or other Carriages for the use of His Majestie His
Heires or Successors or of any Queene of England or of any Childe or Children of any of the Kings or Queens of
England for the time being for the carrying the Goods of His Majestie His Heires or Successors or the said Queens or
Children of any of them without such full and free consent as aforesaid Any Law Statute Custome or Usage to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Reciting that said Act may prove prejudicial to the King in His Royal Progress</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">Which Act may prove very prejudiciall and inconvenient to the Kings Majestie in His Royall Progresse upon
His necessary Occasions to severall Parts of this Realme in case any person or persons shall obstinately refuse
voluntarily to provide sufficient Carriages for Royall Service at ordinary and usuall Rates for such Carriages as are
paid by others of His Subjects in such places contrary to the true intent and meaning of the said Act.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Clerk of the King's Carriages to give Three Days Notice in Writing to Justice of Peace to provide Carts and Carriages.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Recompence; Persons refusing to provide same; Conviction by Oath; Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">Bee it therefore Enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authorite of the same
That the Clerke or Chiefe Officer of His Majestyes Carryages shall three dayes at least before His Majestyes
Arrivall by Warrant from the Greene Cloth give notice in writeing to two or more of His Majestyes Justices of
the Peace next adjoyning to provide such a number of Carts and Carriages from the places next adjacent as His
Majestie shall have present use of expressing the certainty of that number as alsoe the time and place when and
where the said Carts and Carriages are to attend which Carriages shall consist of foure able Horses or six Oxen
or foure Oxen and two Horses for each of which Cart [or<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Carriage the respective Owners shall receive Six pence
for each mile they shall goe laden And That in case any of His Majestyes Subjects of this Realme shall refuse to
provide and furnish His Majestie that now is or his Queene that is or shall be or his or her Household or her
Majestie Catherine Queene Dowager or her Household in their Progresse or Removalls with such sufficient and
necessary Carriages for their Wardrobe and other Necessaries for ready Moneys tendered to them or shall without
just and reasonable cause refuse to make their Appearance with such sufficient Carts and Carriages as are before
exprest That then upon due Proofe and Conviction of such neglect and refusall by the Oath of the Constable or
other Officer or two other Credible Witnesses before the said Justices of the Peace of the County or Maior or
other Chiefe Officer of the Citty or Corporation where he or they inhabite (which Oath they shall have power to
administer) the Partie soe refuseing shall for such his refusall and neglect forfeite the summe of Forty shillings to
the Kings Majestyes use to be forthwith levyed by Distressse and Sale of his Goods and Chattells (rendring to the
Partyes the overplus upon every such sale if there shall be any) by Warrant from the said Justices of the Peace Maior
or other Officer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Length of Journey; Ready Payment.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Justice of Peace,p &amp;c. acting unduly; Penalty &pound;10; Persons not empowered impressing Horses, &amp;c. Punishment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwayes That noe Horses Oxen Cart or Waine shall be enforced to travell above one dayes Journey from
the place where they receive their Ladeing and that ready payment shall be made in hand for the said Carriages at
the place of Ladeing without delay according to the aforesaid Rates And in case any Justice of the Peace Maior Cheife
Officer or Constable shall take any Gift or Reward to spare any person or persons from makeing such Carriage or
shall injuriously charge or grieve any person through envy hatred or evill-will who ought not to make such Carriage
or shall impresse more Carriages then he shall be directed from the Greene-Cloth to doe That then upon due proofe
and Conviction thereof the Partie soe offending shall forfeite the Summe of Ten pounds to the partie thereby grieved
or any other who shall sue for the same to be recovered by Action of Debt in any of His Majestyes Courts of Records
wherein noe Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law shall bee allowed And in case any person or persons shall presume
to take upon him or them to impresse any Horses Oxen Cart Waine or Carriages for his Majestyes Service other
then the person soe impowered then he or they soe offending shall upon due Conviction of the said Offence incurr
and suffer the Punishment contained in the first recited Act</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Rate of Lodging; for His Majesty's Servants; In what Case no Payment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And whereas of late in His Majestyes Progresses excessive Rates and Prices have beene exacted from His Majestyes
Servants for Lodging Horse-meate Stable-roome and other Accommodations Bee it therefore enacted by the Authoritie
aforesaid That none of his Majestyes said Servants shall be compelled to pay above Six pence by the night for every
Bed they themselves nor above Three pence by the night for every Bed that they shall use for their Servants And
that in all such Houses where any of his Majestyes said Servants shall pay for their Dyet or for Hay and Provinder
for their Horses convenient Lodgeing shall be provided for themselves and their Servants without paying any thing
for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Justices of Peace to; appoint Rates of; Hay and Oats, &amp;c; Proclaimed; Taking other Rates; Penalty 40s; Continuance of Act.</head>
			<para id="p10">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That any Two or more of the Justices of the Peace neare
adjoyning to the Roade through which his Majestie is to passe shall immediately after Notice in writeing from the said
Greene-Cloth and Avenor under their Hands and Seales Sett downe and appoint such reasonable Rates and Prices to
be paid dureing his Majestyes abode there both for Hay and Oates and other Accommodations for Horses as they in
their discretion shall thinke meete which Rates one day at the least before his Majestyes comeing to such place the
said Justices shall cause to be Proclaimed in the Market Towne next to such place and in such of the Neighbouring
Townes and Villages as to them shall seeme meete to the end that Notice may be taken of such Rates and Prices And
if any person shall take any other summe then what is or shall be soe limitted either for Lodgeing Horse-meate
Stable-roome or other such Accommodations and be thereof convicted by Confession of the partie or by the Oath
of one credible witnessse before any one Justice of the Peace (which Oath the said Justice of the Peace is hereby
Authorized to administer) that then in such Case every person soe offending shall forfeite and pay to the partie
grieved the summe of Forty shillings the same to be Levied by Distresse by Warrant from the said Justice of the Peace
and sale thereof returning the Overplus to the partie (the Charge of the Distraining being first deducted) This Act
to have continuance till the end of the first Session of the next Parliament and noe longer</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Carts with Four; Horses, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">summoned and not employed to be; paid 58; Officer not paying; Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">Provided alwayes That where any Cart or number of Carts shall be soe Summoned to Attend at the place
directed for takeing in their Loading or Carriage and shall not be imployed in every such case or cases the said
Cart-taker or Officer shall pay to the Owner or Servant of every such Cart with Foure Horses or more which shall
soe appeare and not be imployed the Summe of Five shillings for every Cart soe imployed And in case any Officer or
Cart-taker shall neglect or refuse to pay the same upon proofe thereof made to the Board of Greene-Cloth he shall
forfeite the summe of Forty shillings to the partie aggrieved for every such neglect.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. High Constables; &amp;c. to make a Return of Names, &amp;c. of Persons; warned to bring in Carts, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p13">And bee it further Enacted That the High Constables or Constables the Maior Bayliffe or other chiefe Officer who
shall be required by this Act to warne in the said Carts and Carriages as in the said Act directed doe make a return
in Writeing to the Clerke or other Officer of the Carriages of the names and places of Abode of every such person who
is soe warned to bring in his Cart or Carriage to the intent it may be knowne (in case of any failure) who is in default
and the said Constables and other chiefe Officer or Officers appointed by this Act to warne in the said Carriages as
abovesaid may be discharged and indempnified and the Defaulters punished as in this Act is Provided.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">or or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


