<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46279" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>James the Second, 1685</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII. An Act for Consolidating the Estates Tail and Reversion in Fee which His Majestie hath in the Post-Office and Twenty foure thousand pounds per Annum of the Hereditary Excise. [Rot. Parl. nu. 12.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>15 Car. II. c. 14. &sect;4.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas by one Act of Parlyament made in the Fifteenth yeare of the Raigne of his late Majestie King
Charles the Second of ever blessed Memory all the yearely Rents Summe or Summes of Money Revenues
Issues and Profitts whatsoever that should grow due accrue or be payable unto his late Majestie his Heires and
Successors for or by reason of the Generall Letter-Office or Post-Office or Office of Post-Master-Generall were Vested
and Setled in his Majestie that now is by the Name of James Duke of Yorke and the Heires Males of his Body
begotten or to be begotten with such Powers as in and by the said Act are provided for.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Reciting that in pursuance of an Agreement between King Charles II. and James Duke of York; and of 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 6.</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">Letters Patent; 18 Jan. 32 Car. II. were granted to the; Duke of York for; the yearly Sum of; &pound;24,000</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">And whereas alsoe in pursuance of an Agreement made by his Majestie then Duke of Yorke with his late Majestie
his Dearely beloved Brother for accepting of the Yearely Rent or Summe of Twenty foure thousand pounds to be
Issueing out of the Hereditary Excise of Beare Ale and other Liquors in Compensation and full Satisfaction of the
Revenue ariseing by Wine-Licences and of one Act of Parlyament Entituled An Act for Revesting the Power of
Granting Wine-Licences in his Majestie his Heires and Successors and for Setleing a Recompence on his Royall
Highnesse in lieu thereof made in the Two and twentyeth and Three and twentyeth yeares of the Raigne of his late
Majestie for Confirming and Ratifying of all such Letters Patents as should be Granted of and for the said Summe
of Twenty foure thousand Pounds his said late Majestie by his Letters Patents under the Great Seale of England
beareing Date the Eighteenth day of January in the two and thirtyeth yeare of his Raigne did give and Grant unto
his Majestie by the Name of James Duke of Yorke and the Heires Males of his Body begotten and to be begotten
the Yearely Rent or Summe of Twenty foure thousand pounds to be Issueing out of the Excise of Beare Ale and
other Liquors within the severall Counties and Shires of Bucks, Essex, Kent, Norfolke Suffolke Berks Bedfordshire and
Somersetshire with such Powers as in the said Letters Patents are Granted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Reciting that; by Demise of the; late King the; Inheritance of the; Post Office; Revenues, and the; said &pound;24,000.; per Ann. vested in; King James II.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Doubts removed as to due Execution of Power given to the King to settle a Jointure on the Queen; The King to stand seized of the said Revenues, and &pound;24,000. per Ann</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And whereas by the Demise of his late Majestie the Reversion Fee-simple and Inheritance as well of the said
Revenues Issues and Profitts of the Generall-Letter-Office or Post-Office as of the said Rent or Summe of Twenty
foure thousand pounds issueing out of the Excise of Beere Ale and other Liquors are come and vested to and in
the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors in right of the Crowne of England And his Majestie being Graciously
pleased to obviate all Doubts and Scruples which may at any time hereafter bee moved or stirred for or concerning the
due Execution of any Powers given to his Majestie by the name of James Duke of Yorke in and by the said Acts of
Parlyament and Letters Patents for setleing a Joynture upon his Royall Consort or in Relation to any further
Provision which his Majestie shall please to make out of the said Revenues for the better and more honourable
Support of the Royall State and Dignity of his Dearest Consort Maria now Queene of England Bee it Enacted by
the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
the Commons in this present Parlyament Assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the Kings Majestie
his Heires and Successors shall from henceforth be and stand Seized of and in all and singular the Revenues
Issues and Profitts of the said Generall Letter-Office or Post-Office and of and in the said Yearely Rent or Summe
of Twenty foure thousand pounds Issueing out of the Hereditary Excise of one Intire and Indefeasable Estate in
Fee-simple The said Acts of Parlyament and Letters Patents for Cr&eacute;ating of Estates Taile in His Majestie
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The said Jointure confirmed.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alwayes That this Act or any thing therein contained shall not avoid the Joynture heretofore Setled
by his Majestie upon his said Royall Consort the Queens Majestie but the same is hereby Confirmed and Ratified.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


