<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46272" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>James the Second, 1685</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act for Granting an Aid to his Majestie by an Imposition on all French Linnens and all East-India Linnen and
severall other Manufactures of India and on all French wrought Silks and Stuffs and on all other wrought Silks
and on all Brandyes Imported after the First Day of July One thousand six hundred Eighty five and before the First
Day of July One thousand six hundred and ninety. [Rot. Parl. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>For an extra-ordinary Supply; additional Duties granted on French Linens, Callicoes, and East India, Linens, India Silks, French and other wrought Silks, Foreign Brandy, and Home-made Spirits, viz.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">French Linen, Double Duties; East India Linen and Silk, and French wrought Silk, &pound;10. per cent. on former Duties; Other wrought Silk, &pound;7. per cent. Brandy, Single, 8d. per Gallon; Double, 2s; Home-made Spirits, 4d; Twelve Months allowed for Payment of Import Duties, with Discount of 10 per cent, and Drawback on Exportation</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Most Gracious Sovereigne.<br/>
Wee Your Majestyes most Dutifull and Loyall Subjects the Commons assembled in Parlyament for a Supply of
Your Majestyes Extraordinary Occasions for suppressing the Rebellion of the late Duke of Monmouth and
his Adherents, and with an Humble and Thankfull Acknowledgment of Your Majestyes Favourable and Tender Regard
of us Your Commons, have Chearfully and Unanimously Given and Granted unto Your Majestie An Aid and Assistance
to be Raised and Levyed upon all French Linnen and upon all Callicoes and all other Indian Linnen Imported from
the East Indies or from any other Parts from whence they may by Law be Imported And on all wrought Silks or
Manufactures of India made of or mixed with Herba or Silk and Thread or Cotton Imported from the East Indies
or from any other Parts from whence they may by Law be Imported And on all wrought Silks and other Stuffs
Manufactured in France or Avignion And on all other wrought Silks Imported from any other Place and on all Single
Brandy and on all Brandy above Proofe Imported into this Your Majestyes Kingdome, and on all Home-made Spirits
and Strong Waters according to such Rates and dureing such Time and in such manner and forme as herein after
followeth And wee doe humbly beseech Your Majestie That it may be Enacted And bee it Enacted by the Kings most
Excellent Majestie by (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Com[m]ons in this present
Parlyament Assembled And by the Authoritie of the same That for all French Linnen and for Callicoes and all other
Indian Linnen Imported from the East-Indies or from any other Parts from whence they may by Law be Imported
and for all wrought Silks or Manufactures of India made of or mixt with Herba or Silke and Thread or Cotton
Imported from the East Indies or from any other Parts from whence they may by Law be Imported and for all
wrought Silks and other Stuffs whatsoever Manufactured in France or Avignion and for all other wrought Silks
Imported from any other place whatsoever and for all single Brandy and for all Brandy above Proofe which at any
time after the First Day of July in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty and five and before the
First Day of July in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and ninety shall be Imported into England or
Wales or the Towne and Port of Berwicke upon-Tweede As alsoe for all Home-made Spirits and Strong Waters which
after the said First Day of July in the said Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty and five and before
the First Day of July in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and ninety shall be made or distilled for
Sale there shall be duely answered and paid to His Majestie the further Rates and Dutyes hereafter mentioned That
is to say; For all French Linnen Imported within the time aforesaid Double the Duties they stand charged with in the
Booke of Rates; And for all Callicoes and all other Indian Linnen Imported within the time aforesaid from the East
Indies or from any other Parts from whence they may by Law be Imported Ten pounds for every Hundred pounds
value thereof; And for all wrought Silks or other Manufactures of India mixed with Herba or Silke and Thread or
Cotton Imported within the time aforesaid from the East Indies or from any other Parts from whence they may by
Law be Imported Ten pounds for every Hundred pounds value thereof; And for all wrought Silks and other Stuffs
Manufactured in France or Avignion Imported within the time aforesaid Ten pounds for every Hundred pounds value
thereof; And for all other wrought Silks Imported within the time aforesaid from any other Place Seven pounds for
every Hundred pounds value thereof; And for every Gallon of Strong Water or Brandy com[m]only called single
Brandy or Strong Water Imported from beyond the Seas within the time aforesaid Eight pence over and above the
Dutyes of Excize and Custome already payable for the same, And for every Gallon of Strong Water or Brandy above
Proofe commonly called Double Brandy Imported within the time aforesaid Two shillings over and above the Duties
of Excise and Customs it already pays; and for every Gallon of Strong Waters Aqua Vite or Spiritts of the second
Extraction made here for Sale to be paid by the Maker Foure pence over and above the Duties of Excise already
payable for the same: for all which additionall Duties hereby Imposed upon the aforementioned Commodities Imported
as aforesaid the Importer giveing Security at the Custome House shall have time not exceeding Twelve Months for
the Payment of the same from the Importation to be paid by Foure equall and Quarterly Payments, or in case such
Importer shall pay ready Money he shall have after the Rate of Ten per Centum for a Yeare of the said Duty
abated to him and if the Commodities aforementioned Imported as aforesaid for which this Duty is paid or secured
at the Importation thereof bee againe Exported within Twelve Months after their Importation then the aforesaid
Duties shall be wholly repaid or the Security vacated as to what shall be soe exported except all Brandy for which
the aforesaid Duties shall not be repaid.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Duties levied as by; 12-Car. II.c.4; which Act is revived by Cap. I. ante.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the better Collecting of the Duties hereby Imposed upon all French Linnen Callicoes and other Linnen
Imported from the East Indies dureing the Time aforesaid as alsoe the severall Duties hereby Imposed on all Forreigne
wrought Silks Imported dureing the Time aforesaid from the East Indies or from France or any other Place
whatsoever Bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That the said severall Duties shall be raised levyed collected
and paid unto your Majestie dureing the Time aforementioned in the same Manner and Forme and by such Rules
meanes and wayes and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are mentioned and expressed in One Act of Parlyament
made in the Twelfth Yeare of His late Majestie King Charles the Second Entituled A Subsidie granted to the King
of Tonnage and Poundage and other Summes of Money payable upon Merchandize Exported and Imported and the
Rules and Orders thereunto annexed which said Act and every Article Rule and Clause therein stand now revived by
one Act of Parlyament made in this present Parlyament Entituled An Act for Setleing the Revenue on His Majestie
for His Life which was Setled on his late Majestie for His Life</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Duties on Spirits; levied as by; 12 Car. II. c. 24; 15 Car. II. c. 11.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the severall Rates and Duties of Excise upon Strongwaters Brandies and other Liquors above mentioned shall be raised levyed collected and paid unto your Majestie your
Heires and Successors dureing the Time before mentioned in the same Manner and Forme and by such Rules Meanes
and Wayes and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are mentioned expressed and directed in one Act of
Parliament made in the Twelfth Yeare of the Raigne of our late Gracious Soveraigne King Charles the Second of
Blessed Memory Entituled An Act for takeing away the Court of Wards and Liveries and Tenures in Capite and by
Knights-Service and Purveyance and for setleing a Revennue upon his Majestie in lieu thereof And alsoe in one
other Act of Parliament made in the Fifteenth Yeare of his said late Majesties Raigne Entituled An Additionall Act
for the better Ordering and Collecting the Duty of Excise and preventing the Abuses therein or in either of them</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Distiller concealing Low Wines, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 58. per Gallon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further enacted by the Authoritie of this present Parlyament That to the End His Majestie may not be
Defrauded of the Dutyes hereby granted and imposed on Strong-Waters Aqua Vit&aelig; or Spiritts That if any Distiller
or Maker of any Low Wines Spiritts or Strong-Waters shall at any Time hereafter hide conceale or convey any Low
Wines Spirits Aqua Vit&aelig; or Strong Waters from the sight or view of the Gager or Gagers appointed to take an
Account of the same whereby His Majestie or His Commissioners shall or may be Defrauded of any the Dutyes
hereby imposed That every such Distiller or Maker of such Low-Wines Spirits or Strong-Waters for every Gallon
of Low-wines Spirits Aqua Vite or Strong-waters soe hid concealed or conveyed as aforesaid shall forfeite the summe
of Five shillings to be sued for recovered and levyed in such Manner as any Penalties or Forfeitures are Recoverable
or Levyable by the last mentioned Acts or any of them the one moyety thereof to the use of His Majestie His
Heires or Successors and the other moyetie thereof to the Discoverer or to him or them that shall Informe or Sue
for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V.</head>
			<para id="p8">And for preventing the Frauds frequently used in Importing of Brandy in small Quantities whereby the same is
more easily conveyed away without Payment of the Duties thereof</para>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Contents of Casks in which Brandies to be imported; Importing in Casks of less Contents.; Brandy or Value forfeited</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">Bee it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the Twenty ninth Day of September next ensueing
noe Brandies single or double in this Act mentioned shall be imported from Parts beyond the Seas in any Vessell or
Caske which shall not containe sixty Gallons at the least upon Paine of forfeiting of the said Brandy or the value
thereof soe to be imported in small Vessells or Casks as aforesaid whereof one halfe shall be to the King's most
Excellent Majestie and the other halfe to such Person as shall and will Informe or sue for the same to be Recovered
of the Importer or Proprietor thereof by Plaint Bill Action of Debt or Information in any of His Majestyes Courts
of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Wager of Law or Protection shall be Allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Officer to keep distinct Accounts of Duties, and pay into Exchequer weekly.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And bee it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every the Officer and Officers
who shall be concerned in the Levying Collecting and Receiving the Duties ariseing by this Act doe keepe a separate
and distinct Account thereof and pay the same in Specie into the Receipt of His Majestyes Exchequer Weekely
and upon Neglect and Refusall of the same shall incurr the Penalties Forfeitures Damages and Costs as other the
Officers of the Exchequer herein after mentioned shall be liable to which Moneys soe Paid in shall be applyed to the
Uses hereafter mentioned in this Act and noe otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Persons lending any Money not exceeding &pound;400,000 on Credit of Act to have a Tally of Loan, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Orders for Repayment registered and paid in course</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And bee it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons who
shall Lend any Moneys not exceeding Foure hundred thousand Pounds in the Whole to Your Majestie upon the
Credit of this Act and Pay the same into the Receipt of the Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally of Loane
Strucke for the same and an Order for his Repayment beareing the same Date with his Tally in which Order shall be
alsoe contained a Warrant for Payment of Interest for Forbearance not exceeding the Rate of Eight Pounds per
Centu[m] per Annu[m] for his Consideration to bee paid every Three Months untill the repayment of his principall. And
that all Orders for Repayment of Money Lent shall be Registred in course according to the Date of the Tally
respectively And that all and every Person and Persons shall be paid in Course according as their Orders shall stand
Entred in the Register Booke bee it Orders for [Payment<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Directed by His Majestie or of Moneys Lent as aforesaid
soe as that the Person Native or Forreigner his Executors Administrators and Assignes who shall have his Warrant
or Order Warrants or Orders first entered in the said Booke of Register shall be taken and Accounted as the first
Person to be paid upon the Moneys to come in by vertue of this Act And he and he or they that shall have his or
their Warrants or Orders Warrant or Order next Entred shall be taken and Accounted to be the Second Person
to be paid And soe successively and in course.</para>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Monies liable in Order without Preference; No Fee for Search; Penalty; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty; By Deputy; Penalty; Auditor, &amp;c. not directing or making Payments according to the aforesaid Order; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And that the Moneys to come in by this Act shall be in the same Order lyable to the Satisfaction of the said
Respective Parties their Executors Administrators or Assignes successively without Preference of one before another
and not otherwise and not be divertible to any other use intent or Purpose whatsoever. And that noe Fee Reward
or Gratuity directly or indirectly be demanded or taken of any Your Majestyes Subjects for provideing or makeing of
any such Books Registers Entryes View or Search in or for Payment of Money Lent or the Interest thereof as aforesaid
by any of Your Majestyes Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputies on paine of Payment of treble Damages to the
partie grieved by the party offending with Costs of Suite or if the Officer himselfe take or demand any such Fee
or Reward then to lose his Place alsoe. And if any undue Preference of one before another shall be made either
in point of Registry contrary to the true meaning of this Act by any such Officer or Officers then the party
offending shall be lyable by Action of Debt or on the Case to pay the Value of the Debt Damages and Costs to
the Partie grieved and shall be fore-judged from his Place or Office. And if such Preference be unduely made
by any his Deputy or Clerke without Direction or Privitie of His Master then such Deputy or Clerke onely
shall be lyable to such Action Debt Damages and Costs and shall be for ever after uncapeable of his Place or
Office. And in case the Auditor shall not direct the Order or the Clerke of the Pells Record and the Teller make
Payment according to each Persons due place and order as afore directed Then he or they shall be judged to forfeite
and their respective Deputies and Clerks herein offending to be lyable to such Action Debt Damages and Costs in
such manner as aforesaid all which said Penalties Forfeitures Damages and Costs to be incurred by any of the
Officers of the Exchequer or any their Deputyes or Clerks shall and may be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint
or Information in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection Priviledge
Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise granted or allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Entering Tallies of same Date not undue Preference.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby Declared that if it happen that severall Tallyes of Loane or Orders for
Payments directed by Your Majestie as aforesaid beare Date or be brought the same Day to the Auditor of the
Receipt to be Registred then it shall be interpreted noe undue Preference which of those he enters first soe he enters
them all the same day</para>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Paying subsequent Orders brought in; course not undue Preference.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p19">Provided alsoe that it shall not be interpreted any undue Preference to incurr any Penalty in point of Payment
if the Auditor Direct and the Clerke of the Pells Record and the Teller doe pay Subsequent Orders of Persons that
come and demand their Money and bring their Order in their Course soe as there be soe much Money reserved as
will satisfie their Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest for Loane being to Cease
from the time the Money is soe Reserved and kept in Banke for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Person to whom Money due may assign his Interest in Warrant, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Entry thereof without Fee; Payment to Assignee good.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p21">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Person or Persons to whome any Money shall
be due by vertue of this Act after Warrant or Order Entred in the Booke of Register aforesaid for Payment thereof
his Executors Administrators or Assignes by Indorsement of his Order or Warrant may Assigne and Transferr his
Right Title Interest and Benefitt of such Warrant or Order or any part thereof to any other which being notified
in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt aforesaid and an Entry and Memoriall thereof alsoe made in the Booke
of Registry aforesaid for Warrants (which the Officers shall upon request without Fee or Charge accordingly
make) shall Entitle such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the Benefit thereof and Payment
thereon and such Assignee may in like manner Assigne againe and soe toties quoties and afterwards it shall not be
in the Power of such person or persons who have made such Assignments to make Void Release or Discharge the
same or any the Moneys thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Reciting cap. 4; ante.&sect;2; Security to be in Double Value of Duties</head>
			<para id="p22">And whereas by a Clause in an Act made in this present Parliament Intituled An Act for Granting to His
Majestie an Imposition upon all Tobacco and Sugar Imported betweene the Foure and Twentyeth Day of June
One thousand six hundred eighty and five and the Foure and twentyeth Day of June One thousand six hundred
ninety and three It was among other things Enacted That every Merchant or Importer that is not a Retailer
Consumptioner or Shop-keeper dealing in the said Commodities (after Entry of his or their Goods by Bill under his
or their Hands or the Hand of such Person for whome he or they shall engage to be answerable presently before he
or they be admitted or permitted to have any Warrant to receive his or their Goods out of the Shipp or from the
Water-side) shall become bound unto His Majestie with one or more sufficient Sureties or procure two other
Persons to become bound to His Majestie in such Summes of Money as shall amount to the value of the Duties by
the said Act Imposed upon his or their Goods with Condition for the Purposes in the said Act mentioned Bee it
Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That such Person and Persons aforementioned shall become bound unto His
Majestie for the Purposes aforesaid in such Summes of Money as shall amount to double the value of the said
Duties Imposed on the said Goods by the said Act Any thing therein contained to the contrary thereof
notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">and w<emph type="p">th</emph> the advice <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Payments <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


