<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46287" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for removeing and Preventing all Questions and Disputes concerning the Assembling and Sitting of this present Parlyament. [Rot. Parl. pt. 1. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">For preventing all Doubts and Scruples which may in any wise arise concerning the Meeting Sitting and
Proceeding of this present Parlyament Bee it Declared and Enacted by the King and Queenes most Excellent
Majestyes by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons now
Assembled and by Authoritie of the same.</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Convention of Jan. 22, 1688, declared to be the Two Houses of Parliament; This Act and other Acts before the next Prorogation taken to commence the 13th Feb. 1688</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">(<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) That the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons Convened at Westminster the Two and twentyeth day
of January in the Yeare of Our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty eight and there Sitting on the Thirteenth
day of February following are the Two Houses of Parlyament and soe shall be and are hereby Declared Enacted
and Adjudged to be to all Intents Constructions and Purposes whatsoever Notwithstanding any want of Writt or
Writts of Summons or any other defect of Forme or Default whatsoever as if they had beene Summoned according
to the usuall Forme, And that this present Act and all other Acts, to which the Royall Assent shall at any time
be given before the next Prorogation after the said Thirteenth of February shall be Understood Taken and
Adjudged in Law to Benginne and Commence upon the said Thirteenth of February on which Day Their said
Majestyes at the Request and by the Advice of the Lords and Commons Did Accept the Crowne and Royall
Dignity of King and Queene of England France and Ireland and the Dominions and Territories thereto belonging.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. 30 Car. II. st. 2. and other Acts as to the taking the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance by Members of either House of Parliament repealed.</head>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Act made in the Thirtyeth Yeare of King
Charles the Second Entituled An Act for the more effectuall preserveing the Kings Person and Government by
Disableing of Papists from Sitting in either House of Parliament [and all other Acts of Parlyament as to soe
much of the said Act or Acts onely as concerns the Takeing the Oathes of Supremacy and Allegiance or either
of them in the said Act or Acts respectively mentioned by any Member or Members of either House of Parlyament
with relation to their Sitting and Voteing in Parliament <ref idref="n2">2</ref>] shall be and are hereby Repealed to all Intents and Purposes
Any thing in the said recited Act or Acts to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Taking the Oaths after mentioned and subscribing Declaration of 30 Car. II. st. 2. to be good and effectual as if taken in the Manner and at the Time by the said Acts required.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">In all future Parliaments the Oaths herein after mentioned and the Declaration of 30 Car. II. stat. 2. to be taken within the Time and in Manner by said Act required.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further Enacted That the (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) Takeing the Oathes herein after mentioned and the Makeing Subscribeing
and Repeateing the Declaration in the said Act of the Thirtieth Yeare of King Charles the Second mentioned
by every Member of either House of this present Parlyament from and after the First day of March next ensueing
in such Manner as the Takeing the said Oathes of Allegiance and Supremacie and the Makeing Subscribeing
and Repeating the said Declaration in the said last mentioned Act are required shall be good and effectuall to
all Intents and Purposes as if the said Oathes of Allegiance and Supremacie had beene Taken and the said
Declaration had beene Made Subscribed and Repeated in such Manner and at such Time as by the said Act or
Acts or any of them they are required And that in all future Parlyaments the Oathes herein after mentioned
and the Declaration in the said Act made in the Thirtyeth Yeare of King Charles the Second mentioned shall be
Taken Made Subscribed and Repeated by every Member of either House of Parlyament within the Time, and in
the same Manner and Forme and under the Penalties and Disabilities as the said Oathes of Allegiance and
Supremacy and the said Declaration by the said Act of the Thirtyeth Yeare of King Charles the Second are
Limitted Ordained and appointed to be Taken Made Subscribed and Repeated and not at any other Time or in
any other Manner to enable them to Sitt and Vote in Parliament Any thing in the said Act or Acts or any of
them to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV.</head>
			<para id="p7">And it is hereby further Enacted and Declared by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Oathes above appointed by
this Act to be taken in the stead and place of the Oathes of Allegiance and Supremacy, shall be in the Words
following and noe other.</para>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Form of Oaths</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">I A B Doe sincerely Promise and Sweare that I will be Faithfull and beare true Allegiance to Their Majestyes
King William and Queene Mary Soe helpe me God.</para>
			<para id="p10">I A B Doe Sweare that I doe from my Heart Abhorr Detest and Abjure as Impious and Hereticall that damnable
Doctrine and Position That Princes Excommunicated or Deprived by the Pope or any Authoritie of the See of
Rome may be Deposed or Murthered by their Subjects or any other whatsoever And I doe Declare that noe
Forreigne Prince, Person, Prelate State or Potentate hath or ought to have any Power Jurisdiction Superiority
Preeminence or Authoritie Ecclesiasticall or Spirituall within this Realme Soe helpe me God.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. This Parliament may be dissolved in the usual Manner.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwayes and be it Declared That this present Parlyament may be Dissolved after the usuall manner
as if the same had been Summoned and called by Writt.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This Clause is annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Ibid.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">From thence to the End of the Act is annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule; and the Words "with relation to their
sitting and voting in Parliament," are interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


