<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46284" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>James the Second, 1685</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVII. An Act for Reviveing and Continuance of severall Acts of Parlyament therein mentioned. [Rot. Parl. nu. 17.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">Whereas many good and wholesome Lawes were made in the Raigne of Your Majestyes Royall Brother King
Charles the Second of Blessed Memory as Probationary Laws which by experience have beene found
very usefull and beneficiall both for the Service of the Crowne and good of the Subjects of this your Majestyes
Realme which said Acts being made Temporary are most of them expired and others neare expireing Your
Commons in this present Parlyament Assembled takeing the same into their Serious Consideration doe most humbly
beseech Your Majestie That it may Enacted</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. 13 &amp; 14 Car. II. c. 12. revived for 7 Years, except as to the Corporation therein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p2">And bee it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament Assembled and by Authoritie of the same
That One Act of Parlyament made in the Thirteenth and fourteenth yeares of his said late Majestyes Raigne
Entituled An Act for the better Reliefe of the Poore of this Kingdome (except what relates unto the Corporation
therein mentioned and Constituted thereby) shall be in force from the first day of this present Session of Parlyament
and soe to continue for the space of Seven yeares and from thence to the next Session of Parlyament</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Settlement of Poor intended by said Act accounted from Delivery of Notice in Writing to Churchwarden.</head>
			<para id="p3">And forasmuch as such poore persons at their first comeing to a Parish doe commonly conceale themselves
Bee it therefore hereby Provided and Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Forty dayes continuance of
such Person in a Parish intended by the said Act to make a Setlement shall be accompted from the time of his or
her Delivery of Notice in writeing (which they are hereby required to doe) of the House of his or her abode and
the number of his or her Family if he or she have any to one of the Church wardens or Overseers of the Poore of
the said Parish to which they shall soe remove.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. 13 &amp; 14 Car. II. chap. 21; made perpetual.</head>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That one other Act made in the said Thirteenth and
Fourteenth yeares of his said late Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for Preventing the unnecessary Charge of
Sheriffes and for Ease in passing their Accompts shall be in force and is hereby made perpetuall.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. 17 Car. II. c. 8. 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 10. explained by 29 Car. II. c.3. &sect;25. and which said Acts with the said Clause are continued by 30 Car. II. st. 1. c. 6.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">All the said Acts and Clauses made perpetual</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And bee it Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That one other Act made in the Seventeenth yeare of his said late
Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for avoiding unnecessary Suits and Delayes And alsoe one other Act made
in the Two and twentyeth and Three and twentyeth yeares of his late Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for the better
Setleing Intestates Estates (which said latter Act is explained by a Clause in one other Act made in the Nine and
twentyeth yeare of his said late Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for Prevention of Frauds and Perjuries) both
which said Acts with the said Clause are continued by one other Act made in the Thirtyeth yeare of his said late
Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for Reviveing both the said former Acts All which said Acts and Clauses shall
be in force and is hereby made perpetuall.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Administrators not compelled to account (except by an Inventory) but at the instance of Persons interested.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwayes and it is hereby further Enacted That noe Administrator shall from the from the Foure and
twentieth day of July next be cited to any the Courts in [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] last Act mentioned to render an Account of the
Personall Estate of his Intestate (otherwise then by an Inventory or Inventoryes thereof) unlesse it be at the
Instance and Prosecution of some person or persons in behalfe of a Minor or haveing a demand out of such
Personall Estate as a Creditor or next of Kin, Nor be Compellable to Accompt before any the Ordinaryes or Judges
by the said last Act impowered and appointed to take the same otherwise then as is aforesaid any thing in the
said last Acts contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Brother and Sister of Intestate to share equally with the Mother.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided alsoe and it is further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That if after the Death of a Father any of
his Children shall dye Intestate without Wife or Children in the Life-time of the Mother every Brother and Sister
and the Representatives of them shall have an equall Share with her Any thing in the last mentioned Acts to
the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso in the said Act for Customs of London and Province of Yorknot to extend to Intestate's Estate claimed by Administrator quatenus Administrator.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided and it is hereby for the determining some Doubts ariseing upon the Act aforementioned for the better
setleing Intestates Estates Enacted and Declared That the Clause therein by which it is Provided That that Act
or any thing therein contained should not any wayes prejudice or hinder the Customs observed within the City
of London and Province of Yorke was never intended nor shall be taken or construed to extend to such Part
of any Intestates Estate as any Administrator by vertue onely of being Administrator by pretence or reason of any
Custome may claime to have to exempt the same from Distribution but that such part in the hands of such
Administrator shall be subject to Distribution as in other Cases within the said Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. 19 Car. II. c. 12. in force for 7 Years, &amp;c. from 1st day of the Session.</head>
			<para id="p10">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That one other Act made in the Nineteenth Yeare of
King Charles the Second Entituled An Act for Assigning Orders in the Exchequer without Revocation shall be
in force from the first day of this present Session of Parlyament and soe to continue for the space of Seven yeares
and from thence to the end of the next &Sacute;ession of Parlyament</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 19. in force for 7 years, &amp;c. from June 24, 1685.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Salemen</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And bee it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That one other Act made in the Two and twentyeth and
Three and twentyeth yeares of [his<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] late Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act to prevent Frauds in the Buying and
Selling of Catle in Smithfield and elsewhere shall be in force from the Foure and Twentyeth Day of June One
thousand six hundred eighty five and soe to continue for Seven yeares and from thence to the end of the next
Session of Parlyament [Provided That the said Act or any thing therein contained shall not extend to Salemen or
Factors imployed by Farmers or Feeders.<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 22. in force for 7 years from 1st Day of the Session.</head>
			<para id="p13">And bee it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That one other Act made in the Two and twentieth and
Three and twentyeth [yeares<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of his said late Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for the better and more certaine
Recovery of Fines and Forfeitures due to His Majestie shall be in force from the First day of this present Session
of Parlyament and soe to continue for the space of seven yeares and from thence to the end of the next Session
of Parlyament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 23. in force for 7 years, from 1st Day of the Session.</head>
			<para id="p14">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That one other Act of the Two and Twentyeth and
Three and twentyeth of King Charles the Second Entituled An Act to Revive an Act Entituled An Act to prevent
the Disturbance of Seamen and others and to preserve the Stores belonging to his Majestyes Navy Royall with
some Alterations and Additions shall be in force from the first day of this present Session of Parlyament and soe
to continue for seven yeares and from thence to the end of the first Session of the next Parlyament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 26. in force for 7 Years, &amp;c. from the 1st Day of the Session.</head>
			<para id="p15">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That one other Act of the Two and twentyeth and
Three and twentyeth of King Charles the Second Entituled An Act to prevent the Planting of Tobacco in England
and for Regulateing the Plantation Trade shall be in force from the first day of this present Session of Parlyament
and soe to continue for seven yeares and from thence to the End of the next Session of Parlyament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. 30 Car. II. st. 1. c. 7. in force for 7 years, &amp;c. from 1st Day of the Session.</head>
			<para id="p16">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That one other Act made in the Thirtyeth Yeare of
King Charles the Second Entituled An Act to Enable Creditors to Recover their Debts of the Executors and
Administrators of the Executors in their owne wrong shall be in force from the first day of this present Session
of Parlyament and soe to continue for seven yeares and from thence to the end of the first Session of the next
Parlyament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. 13 &amp; 14 Car. II. c. 33. continued for 7 Years from June 24, 1685.</head>
			<para id="p17">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That one other Act made in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth
yeares of His said late Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for preventing the frequent Abuses in Printing Seditious
Treasonable and Unlicensed Bookes and Pamphletts, and for Regulating of Printing and Printing-Presses and every
Clause Article and thing therein contained be Revived and continue in force from the Foure and twentyeth Day
of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty five for the space of Seven yeares and from
thence to the end of the next Session of Parlyament.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">the said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">his said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">This Proviso is annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">yeare <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


