<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46288" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act for Impowering His Majestie to Apprehend and Detaine such Persons as He shall finde just Cause to Suspect
are Conspireing against the Government. [Rot. Parl. pt. 1. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">For the secureing the Peace of the Kingdome in this Time of Imminent Danger against the Attempts and Trayterous
Conspiracies of evill disposed Persons</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Persons committed by Warrant of Privy Council on Suspicion of Treason may be detained, and Judge, &amp;c. not to bail without Order</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">Bee it Enacted by the King and Queene's most Excellent Majesties by and with the Advice and Consent of the
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament Assembled and by the Authoritie of the
same That every Person or Persons that shall be committed by Warrant of Their said Majestyes most Honourable
Privy Councill Signed by Six of the said Privy Councill at least for Suspition of High Treason may be detayned in
safe Custodie till the Seventeenth Day of Aprill in the Yeare of Our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty and
nine, without Baile or Mainprize and that noe Judge or other Person shall Baile or Try any such Person or Persons soe
Committed without Order from Their said Majestyes Privy Councill Signed by Six of the said Privy Councill at least
till the said Seventeenth Day of Aprill any Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. But may have the Benefit of the 31 Car. II. c. 2. and of all other Statutes providing for the Liberty of the Subject.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes That from and after the said Seventeenth day of Aprill the said Persons soe Committed shall have
the Benefitt and Advantage of an Act made in the One and thirtyeth Yeare of King Charles the Second Entituled An
Act for the better Secureing the Liberty of the Subject and for Prevention of Imprisonment beyond the Seas and alsoe
of all other Laws and Statutes any way relateing to or provideing for the Liberty of the Subjects of this Realme</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Continuance of Act.</head>
			<para id="p5">And that this present Act shall continue untill the said Seventeenth day of Aprill and noe longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Privileges of Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That nothing in this Act shall be construed to extend to the Auncient Rights
and Priviledges of Parlyament or to the Imprisonment or Detayning of any Member of either House of Parlyament
untill the Matter of which he stands suspected be first communicated to the House of which he is a Member and
the Consent of the said House obtained for his Committment or Detayning.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


