<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46281" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>James the Second, 1685</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIV. An Act for Continuance of Three former Acts for Preventing of Theft and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders of England. [Rot. Parl. nu. 14.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>13 and 14 Car. II. c. 22.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">18 Car. II. c. 3; 29 and 30 Car. II. c. 2</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an Act was made in the Thirteenth and Foureteenth yeares of the Raigne of Our late Soveraigne
Lord King Charles the Second Intituled An Act for p[re]venting of Theft and Rapine upon the Northern
Borders of England And whereas alsoe another Act was made in the Eighteenth Yeare of the Raigne of the said
King Intituled An Act to continue a former Act to Prevent Theft and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders of
England Both which Acts were Continued by another Act made in the Twenty ninth and Thirtyeth yeares of the
Raigne of the said late King Intituled An Act for Continuance of Two former Acts for Preventing of Theft and Rapine
upon the Northerne Borders of England for and dureing the space and time of Seven yeares and alsoe from thence
until the end of the first Session of this present Parlyament which Laws have beene found very necessary for the
preservation of those places from that great number of lewd disorderly and lawlessse persons that usually infested and
frequented in those parts</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Further continued for 11 years, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">Bee it therefore Enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by Authoritie of the same That the
said Three former Acts and all and every of them and every Matter Clause and Clauses therein contained and all and
every the Powers and Authorities thereby given shall be continue and remaine in full Force from henceforth for and
dureing the space and Terme of Eleven yeares And alsoe from thence unto the end of the first Sessions of the next
Parlyament.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


