<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46299" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An Act for raising Money by a Poll and otherwise towards the Reduceing of Ireland.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>The Reasons for granting the King and Queen a Subsidy.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Grant to the King and Queene of 10s. in every &pound;100</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee Your Majestyes most Obedient and Loyall Subjects the Commons now in Parlyament Assembled being
highly sensible of the deplorable Condition of Your Majestyes Protestant Subjects within Your Kingdome
of Ireland occasioned by the Rebellion of the Earle of Tyrconnell and his Adherents with an humble and thankfull
Acknowledgement of Your Majestyes favourable and tender Regard of Us Your Commons doe most humbly
present unto Your Majesties a Free Gift of the severall Summes of Money hereafter specifyed towards the Reduceing
Ireland to its due Obedience to be Levyed in such manner as hereafter is expressed and doe beseech Your
Majestyes to accept thereof and that it may be Enacted And bee it enacted by the King and Queens most
Excellent Majestyes by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the
Com[m]ons in this present Parliament Assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That all and every Person and
Persons Bodies Pollitique and Corporate Guilds or Fraternities within this Kingdome of England Dominion of
Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede haveing any Personall Estate either in such Debts oweing to them
within this Realme or without which he she or they doe not account as desperate other then such Debts as now
are or shall be oweing from Their Majestyes (over and besides such just Debts as he she or they shall bona fide
owe) or in ready Moneys shall yield and pay unto Their Majestyes for every hundred pounds in such Debts and
ready Moneys the Summe of Ten shillings (to be paid by the Lender notwithstanding any Agreement to the
contrary) to be Assessed Imposed Levyed and Collected in manner herein after mentioned.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Public Officers to pay over and above Monthly Assessment of 1 W. &amp; M. c. 3. ante, 12d. in the Pound of the Profits of their Office.</head>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">said Payments how raised.; Officers not rated to Monthly Assessment to pay 3s. in the Pound of the Profits of their Office</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons Commissioner or
Commissioners haveing useing or exerciseing any Office Place or Publique Imployment whatsoever (such Persons who
are or shall be in Muster and Pay at Land or Sea for or in respect of such their Pay onely excepted) and all and
every their Deputies Agents Clerks Secondaries Substitutes and other their inferior Ministers and Servants whatsoever
shall pay unto their Majestyes over and above the severall Summs with which he or they are or shall be charged
in or to the Monthly Assesment by [any<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Act of this present Parliament Entituled An Act for the Granting a
present Aid to Their Majestyes the Summe of Twelve pence for every Twenty shillings which he or they doe
receive in one Yeare by vertue of any Fees Proffits Perquisites or other Advantage [to him or them accrueing<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]
or by reason or occasion of their severall Offices Agencies and Imployments and such who are not already
Taxed in and by the said Monthly Assesments for and in respect of their Commissions Offices Agencies and
Employments shall yield and pay unto Their Majesties the full Summe of Three shillings for every Twenty
shillings which he or they doe recieve in one Yeare by vertue of any Fees Proffits Perquisits or other Advantages
to him or them accruing or by reason or occasion of their severall and respective Commissions Offices and
Employments the said severall Summs of One shilling and Three shillings to be Assessed Imposed Levyed and
Collected in such manner as herein after is mentioned</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Pensions, &amp;c. from Government exceeding &pound;20. per ann. to pay 3s. in the pound.</head>
		<para id="p5">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons haveing or
Claiming to have any Pension or yearely Stipend or Annuity Issueing or Payable out of any part of Their Majesties
Revenue exceeding Twenty Pounds per Annum shall pay unto Their Majesties the Summe of Three shillings out
of every Twenty shillings by the Yeare soe given or granted as aforesaid to be Assessed Imposed Levyed and
Collected in such manner as is herein after mentioned.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Judges, Serjeants, at Law, Barristers, Advocates, Persons practising Physick, to pay 3s. in the Pound out of yearly Profits.</head>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">Servants at above &pound;3. Wages to pay 12d. in the Pound. &pound;3. and under, to pay 6d. in the Pound, except Board Wages.; Exceptions to the Poll</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p7">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Judges and other Persons haveing at the Time
of the Execution of this Act any Judiciall Office or other Office or Place of Profit And all Serjeants at Law.
Barresters Attourneys Sollicitors and Scriveners And all Advocats Proctors and Publique Notaries And all and
every Person and Persons Practising the Art of Phisick shall pay unto Their Majestyes the Summe of Three
shillings out of every Twenty Shillings which he or they doe receive by his or their respective Salaries Offices
Practices or Professions in one yeare And all and every Servant which at the time of the Execution of this
Act shall recieve above Three Pounds per Annu[m] Wages for his her or their Service shall pay unto Their
Majestyes the Summe of Twelve pence for every Twenty shillings by the yeare And that shall recieve Three
Pounds per Ann[um] Wages or under for his or her Service shall pay unto Their Majestyes the Summe of Six
pence for every Twenty shillings by the yeare which shall be due or payable to him her or them for his her
or their Wages Except for Board wages And all and every person and persons of what Age Sex or Condition
soever shall pay unto Their Majesties the Summe of One shilling Except such persons as shall recieve Almes
of the Parish where they dwell and their Children being under the Age of Sixteene yeares at the time of the
Execution of this Act And (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) Except all Children being under the Age of Sixteene yeares of all Day Labourers
and of all Servants in Husbandry and of all other Persons who by reason of their Poverty are Exempted from
Contributing to the Church and Poore And alsoe Except all Children being under the Age of Sixteene yeares of such
who hath Foure or more Children and is not worth in Lands Goods and Chattells the Summe of Fifty pounds.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. Rates of Payment by Peers, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">Dukes resident in the Kingdom, &pound;50; Marquesses, &pound;40.; Earls, &pound;30; Viscounts, &pound;25.; Barons, &pound;20.; Eldest Sons of Dukes of 16 Years, &pound;30.; Younger Sons, &pound;25.; Eldest Sons of Marquesses, &pound;25.; Younger Sons, &pound;20.; Younger Sons &pound;15.; Eldest Sons Viscounts, &pound;17. 10s.; Younger Sons, &pound;13. 6s. 8d.; Eldest Sons of Barons, &pound;12.; Baronets, &pound;15.; Knights of the Bath, &pound;15; Knights Bachelors, &pound;10.; King's Serjeant, &pound;20; Serjeants at Law, &pound;15.; Esquires, &pound;5; Gentlemen, 20s.; Widow to pay the Third Part of Rate on her late Husband's Degree</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p9">And bee it further Enacted and Ordained That all and every Person and Persons who at the Time of the
Execution of this Act shall be of the severall Ranks and Degrees hereafter mentioned shall to the purpose
aforesaid Contribute and Pay the severall Summes of Money hereafter in this Act sett downe and appointed That
is to say Every Person of the Degree of a Duke of England Scotland or Ireland Inhabiting and Resideing
within this Kingdome of England shall pay the Summe of Fifty pounds Every Person of the Degree of a
Marquesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kingdome shall pay the
Summe of Forty pounds Every Person of the Degree of an Earle of any of the said Three Kingdoms and
Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kingdome shall pay the Summe of Thirty pounds Every Person of the Degree of
a Viscount of any of the Three Kingdoms and Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kingdome shall pay the Summe
of Twenty five pounds Every Person of the Degree of a Baron of any of the said Three Kingdoms and Inhabiting
and Resideing within this Kingdome shall pay the Summe of Twenty pounds Every eldest Sonne of a Duke of
any of the said Three Kingdomes and Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kingdome being of the Age of Sixteene
yeares shall pay the Summe of Thirty pounds Every younger Sonne of a Duke of the said Three Kingdomes
and Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kingdome being of the Age of Sixteene yeares the Summe of Twenty
five pounds Every eldest Sonne of a Marquesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes and Inhabiting and Resideing
within this Kingdome being of the Age of Sixteene yeares the Summe of Twenty five pounds Every younger Sonne
of a Marquesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes and Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kingdome being of
the Age of Sixteene yeares the Summe of Twenty pounds Every eldest Sonne of an Earle of any of the said
Three Kingdomes and Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kindome being of the Age of Sixteene yeares the
Summe of Twenty pounds Every younger Sonne of an Earle of any of the said Three Kingdomes and Inhabiting
or Resideing within this Kingdome being of the Age of Sixteene yeares the Summe of Fifteene pounds Every eldest
Sonne of a Viscount [within<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] any of the said Three Kingdomes and Inhabiting or Resideing within this Kingdome
being of the Age of Sixteene yeares the Summe of Seaventeene pounds ten shillings Every younger Sonne of
a Viscount of any of the said three Kingdomes and Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kingdome being of the Age
of Sixteene yeares the Summe of Thirteene pounds six shillings eight pence Every eldest Sonne of a Baron of
any of the said Three Kingdomes Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kingdome (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) being of the Age of Sixteene
yeares the Summe of Fifteene pounds Every younger Sonne of a Baron of any of the said Three Kingdomes
and Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kingdome being of the Age of Sixteene yeares the Summe of Twelve
pounds Every Person of the Degree of a Baronet of any of the said Three Kingdomes or (<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) Nova Scotia and
Inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome the Summe of Fifteene pounds Every person that is a Knight of the
Order of the Bath Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kingdome the Summe of Fifteene Pounds Every Person
who is a Knight Batchelor Inhabiting and Resideing within this Kingdome the Summe of Ten pounds Every
Serjieant at Law being the Kings Serjieant the Summe of Twenty pounds And every other Serjieant at Law the
Summe of Fifteene pounds Every Person of the Degree of an Esquire or soe reputed or owning or writeing
himselfe such Inhabiting or Resideing within this Kingdome and being of the Age of Sixteene yeares the Summe
of Five pounds Every Gentleman or reputed Gentleman or owning or writeing himselfe such above the Age of
Sixteene yeares Inhabiting or Resideing in this Kingdome the Summe of Twenty shillings Every Widow respectively
according to her Husbands Degree shall pay the third part Rated by this Act on that Degree of which the Husband
of such Wife was in his Lifetime.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. Gentlemen having Estates of &pound;300 or more, to pay 2s. in the Pound, though an Infant; under that Estate, on Oath charged for his Title.</head>
		<para id="p10">And bee it further Enacted That every Gentleman haveing an Estate of the value of Three hundred pounds or
more shall be Charged with the Summe of Twenty shillings though he be a Minor under the Age of One and
twenty yeares And noe Gentleman not haveing such an Estate and thereof shall make Oath before any two or
more of the respective Commissioners shall be charged with the said Summe of Twenty shillings in respect of
his Title.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. Rates of Payment by Ecclesiastics. Archbishop, &pound;50. Bishop, &pound;20. Deans, &pound;10.</head>
		<para id="p11">
			<emph type="i">Archdeacons, &pound;2. 10s; Canons and Prebendaries not rated at above &pound;30. &pound;20. except Sole Prebends. Doctors in Divinity Law, and Physick, &pound;5; Two Livings amounting to &pound;120, &pound;5</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p12">And bee it further Enacted and Ordained That all and every the Person and Persons within the Kingdome of
England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede who at the time of Execution of this Act shall be
of the severall Orders Ranks or Degrees hereafter mentioned shall to the purpose aforesaid pay the severall Summes of
Money hereafter in this Act sett downe and appointed (That is to say) Every Person of the Order and Degree
of an Arch-Bishop shall pay the Summe of Fifty pounds Every Person of the Degree and Order of a Bishop
the Summe of Twenty Pounds Every Person of the Degree of a Deane of any Cathedrall or Collegiate Church
shall pay the Summe of Ten pounds Every Person of the Degree of an Archdeacon shall pay the Summe of
Fifty shillings Every Person of the Degree of a Canon or Prebendary of any Cathedrall or Collegiate Church
excepting such sole Prebendary who is a sole Corporation and his Prebend not rated in the Exchequer at above
Thirty pounds shall pay the Summe of Fifty-shillings Every Person of the Degree of a Doctor of Divinity Law or
Physicke shall pay the Summe of Five pounds Every Person holding two or more Benefices haveing Cure
of Soules which shall amount together to the cleare yearely value of One hundred and twenty pounds shall pay
the Summe of Five pounds</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. Proviso for D.D. not having Benefice, and for Widows of Ecclesiastical Persons.</head>
		<para id="p13">Provided alwayes That noe Doctor of Divinity not haveing any Benefice or Ecclesiasticall Preferment shall be
charged for his Title or Dignity of Doctor by vertue of this Act nor the Widow of any Ecclesiasticall Person
shall be charged for the Third part according to the Title or Dignitie of her late Husband</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>IX. Merchants of London not free, &pound;10. Merchants and Traders holding a House of &pound;30. per ann. in London, 10s.</head>
		<para id="p14">
			<emph type="i">Members of East India Company, 40s. in the &pound;100 for Shares.; Members of the Guinea Company, the like.; Members of the Hudson's Bay Company, the like.; Payments to Governors, &amp;c. deducted out of next Dividend</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p15">And bee it further Enacted and Ordained That the severall Persons hereafter mentioned resideing and inhabiting
within this Kingdome shall pay the severall Summes of Money hereafter in this Act respectively sett downe and
charged on them (That is to say) Every Merchant Tradeing in the Port of London and resideing within the
said City or Ten Miles thereof and not being free of the said City shall pay the Summe of Ten pounds And
every Merchant or other Person whatsoever useing any Trade or Manuall Occupation and holding [an<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] House of
Thirty pounds per Annum within the City of London [or<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] within Twenty miles of the same shall pay the Summe
of Ten shillings Every Member in the East India Company shall pay for his Share or Shares which he hath in
the Joynt Stock of the said Company Forty shillings for every Hundred pounds according to the first Capitall
of the said Stocke Every Member of the Guinea Company shall pay for his Share or Shares which he hath in
the Joynt Stock of that Company Forty shillings for every Hundred pounds according to the first Capitall of the
said Stock Every Member of the Company commonly called the Hudsons Bay Company shall pay for his Share
or Shares which he hath in the Joynt Stocke of that Company Forty shillings for every Hundred pounds according
to the first Capitall of the said Stock To be paid by the Governours and Treasurers of the said East India
Guinea and Hudsons Bay Companies and to be deducted at their next Dividend</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s10">
		<head>X. Alien Merchants and Jews, &pound;10. Proviso for French Protestants having received Charity.</head>
		<para id="p16">And bee it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authoritie aforesaid That every Merchant Stranger and Jew
resideing within this Kingdome shall pay the Summe of Ten pounds Provided that none of the French Protestants
that hath received any Share of the Publicke Charity collected by vertue of Letters Patents for their Reliefe shall
be charged with the said Summe of Ten pounds.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s11">
		<head>XI. Persons having Shares in the New River Company, 2s. in the Pound of yearly Value.</head>
		<para id="p17">And bee it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons
haveing any Share or Shares or Interest in the fresh Streame of runing Water brought to the North parts of
London commonly called the New River or any Rents or Profitts ariseing thereby shall pay for the same the
Summe of Two shillings for every Twenty shillings of the yearely value thereof</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s12">
		<head>XII. Certain Commissioners under 1. W. &amp; M. c. 3. ante, to be Commissioners under this Act.</head>
		<para id="p18">
			<emph type="i">General Meeting of Commissioners, 20th May 1689, to direct Precepts to Inhabitants, Constables, &amp;c. to attend; and thereupon the Commissioners to read, &amp;c. the Rates openly ,and prefix other Days for bringing in Certificates of Names, &amp;c. of Persons residing within certain Limits,; together with the Assessment.; Penalty &pound;5; and also the Names of Persons to be Collectors.; Payment to Receiver General; Certificates and Assessments returned to Commissioners on 26th June 1689; and thereupon Commissioners to issue Warrants, &#x0026;c. for collecting the Assessments; and Collectors to demand Payment accordingly within Six Days after Receipt of Warrant, and to levy and pay same on 26th July 1689; and if not paid then Distress upon Collector</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p19">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That for the better Assessing Ordering and Levying of
the severall Summes of Money soe as aforesaid limitted and appointed to be paid and for the more effectuall
putting of this present Act in Execution soe many of the Persons named and appointed to be Commissioners by
an Act of this present Session of Parlyament Entituled An Act for the Granting a present Ayde to Their Majestyes
as by their said Majestyes under the Great Seale of England shall be nominated and appointed for that
purpose shall be Commissioners for putting in Execution this present Act and the Powers therein contained within
all and every the severall and respective Countyes Rideings Cityes Burroughes Townes and Places for which by the
said former Act they are appointed Commissioners which said Commissioners in order to the speedy Execution of
this Act shall in their respective Counties Cityes Burroughs Townes and Places [meete together at the most usuall
or com[m]on Place of Meeting within such of the said Counties Cities Burroughs Towns and Places<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] respectively at
or before the Twentyeth day of May One thousand six hundred eighty nine next comeing And the said
Commissioners or soe many of them as shall be present at the first Generall Meeting or the major part of them
may by their Consents and Agrements divide as well themselves as other the Commissioners not then present for
the Execution of this Act in Hundreds Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Wards Townes and other Places within their
Limitts Priviledged or not Priviledged in such manner and forme as to them shall seeme expedient and shall direct
their severall or joynt Precept or Precepts to such Inhabitants High Constables Petty Constables Bayliffes and
other like Officers and Ministers and such number of them as they in their Discretions shall thinke most convenient
to be Presenters and Assessors requireing them to appeare before the said Commissioners at such Time and Place
as they shall appoint not exceeding Eight dayes And at such their Appearances the said Commissioners or soe
many of them as shall be thereunto appointed shall openly read or cause to be read unto them the Rates in this
Act mentioned and openly declare the Effect of their Charge unto them and how and in what manner they ought
and should make their Certificates according to the Rates aforesaid and shall then and there prefix another Day
to the said Persons to appeare before the said Commissioners and bring in their Certificates of the Names and
Sirnames Qualities Degrees and Titles of all and every the Persons dweling or resideing within the Limitts of
those Places with which they shall be charged and of the Substances and Values of every of them in Moneys
Debts Annuall Fees Salaries Perquisites Wages Proffits Emoluments and other things chargable by this Act together
with the Assesment of the respective Rates thereby Imposed on each perticular Person according to the Rules
and Directions thereof without Concealment Love Favour Dread or Malice upon paine of Forfeiture of any Summe
not exceeding Five pounds to be Levyed as by this Act is appointed and shall alsoe then returne the Names of
two or more able and sufficient Persons within the Bounds and Limitts of those Parishes or Places where they
shall be chargeable respectively as aforesaid to be Collectors of the Money due to their Majesties by this Act for
whose paying unto the Receiver Generall to be appointed by their Majesties their Deputy or Deputies in manner
following such Moneys as they shall be charged withall the Parish or Place by whome they are soe Employed
shall be answerable which Certificates and Assesments shall be ascertained and returned in to the Commissioners
at or before the Twentyeth Day of June One thousand six hundred eighty nine next comeing And upon the
Delivery and Returning in of such Certificates or Assessments unto the said Commissioners they or any Two or
more of them shall forthwith issue out and deliver their Warrants or Estreats to such Collectors as aforesaid for
the speedy Collecting and Levying of the said Assesments and all Moneys and Rates due thereupon according to
the intent and subsequent Directions of this present Act Of all which the said Collectors are hereby required to
make Demand of the Parties themselves or at the Places of their last abode within Six dayes after the receipt of
such Warrants or Estreates and to Levy and Pay in the same on or before the Twentyeth day of July One
thousand six hundred eighty nine at such Place as the Commissioners shall appoint unto the respective Receiver
Generall his Deputy or Deputyes who are hereby Impowered and Required to call upon and hasten the Collectors
to the said Payment And after the said Twentieth day of July to Levy by Warrant under the Hands and Seales
of any Two or more of the Commissioners upon the Collector by Distresse such Summe and Summes of
Money as he hath received and as ought by him to have beene paid and is not paid by reason of his failure in
doeing his Duty according to the Direction of this Act.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s13">
		<head>XIII. Duplicate of Sum charged within every Hundred, &amp;c. returned into the Exchequer under the Hands and Seals of Commissioners before 30th August 1689.</head>
		<para id="p20">
			<emph type="i">Appeals to be first determined, and like Duplicates delivered to Receivers General, and Money paid before 20th Sept. 1689; Commissioners may examine Presenters of Certificate, and if they have Cause to suspect that Property is of greater Value than represented, then to proceed against the Parties</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p21">And bee it Enacted That a true Duplicate of the whole Summe charged within every Hundred Lath Wapentake
Parish Ward or Place Rated and Assessed in pursuance of this Act without nameing the Persons shall under the
Hands and Seales of Two or more of the Commissioners thereunto appointed be returned into Their Majesties
Exchequer before the Twentyeth Day of August which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred eighty nine (all Appeales being first determined) And that like Duplicates be alsoe in convenient time
made out and delivered unto the Receivers Generall soe as every of them may be duely charged to answere their
respective Collections and Receipts and that the Money thereupon due be paid into Their Majestyes Exchequer
before the Twentyeth day of September which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
eighty nine and upon Returne of [any<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] such Certificate the said Commissioners or any Three or more of them
shall and may if they see cause Examine the Presenters thereof And if the said Com[m]issioners or any Three or
more of them within the severall Limitts shall at the time of the delivery of the Certificates or Six dayes after
have certaine knowledge or vehemently suspect that any person or persons who ought to be mentioned in the
said Certificates is or are ommitted or that any person or persons in the said Certificate mentioned is or are of a
greater Value or Estate then in the said Certificate is mentioned the said Commissioners or any Three or more
of them shall have power to warne such person or persons to appeare before them at a Day and Place prefixed
to be Examined [touching their Substance and Value or<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] touching other Matters which may any wayes concerne the
Premisses And if the person or persons warned to be soe Examined shall neglect to appeare not haveing a reasonable
Excuse for such his Default every person soe makeing Default shall pay unto Their Majestyes double the Summe
of the Rate he should or ought to have beene sett at</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s14">
		<head>XIV. Commissioners may enquire, but not on Oath, into the Value of Property assessed.</head>
		<para id="p22">
			<emph type="i">Receiver General 2d. in the Pound. The Collector 3d</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p23">And moreover the said Commissioners or any Three or more of them shall have Power by all Lawfull wayes
and meanes without Oath to Examine and inquire into the Value and Substance of such Persons as are soe
chargeable by this Act and to sett such Rate or Rates upon every such person or persons as shall be according
to the true intent and meaning of this Act And the said Receiver Generall shall have an Allowance of Two pence
in the pound for all Moneys which shall be by him Paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer And that every Collector
shall have Three pence in the pound for what Money he shall pay to the Receiver Generall his Deputie or Deputies</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s15">
		<head>XV. Commissioners Clerks 2d. per Pound.</head>
		<para id="p24">
			<emph type="i">Persons assessed refusing to pay on Demand, Officer may distrain; Proceedings thereon.; Persons assessed not paying in Twenty Days, and where no sufficient Distress, Party imprisoned in the Common Gaol without Bail.; Persons aggrieved by Rate, &amp;c. may complain to Commissioners. Commissioners</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p25">And for the carefull writeing and transcribing the said Warrants Estreats and Duplicates in due time Bee it
further Enacted that the Commissioners Clerks who shall respectively performe the same shall by Warrant
under Two or more of the Commissioners Hands have and receive from the respective Receivers Generall their
Deputie or Deputies Two pence in the pound of all such Moneys as he shall have Received by vertue of such
Warrants and Estreats who is hereby appointed and allowed to pay the same accordingly And if any Person or
Persons shall refuse to pay the severall Summe and Summes and Proportions appointed by this Act for such Person
to pay upon Demand made by the Officer or Collector of the Place according to the Precept or Estreats to him
delivered by the said Commissioners It shall and may be Lawfull to and for such Officer or Collector who are
hereby thereunto Authorized and Required for Non payment thereof to Distraine the Person or Persons soe
refuseing by his or their Goods or Chattells and the Distresse soe taken to keepe by the space of Foure dayes at
the Costs and Charges of the Owners thereof And if the said Owner doe not pay the Summe of Money due
by this Act within the said Foure dayes then the said Distresse to be appraised by Three or two of the Inhabitants
where the said Distresse is taken and there to be sold by the said Officer for payment of the said Money and
the Overplus comeing by the [said<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Sale (if any be) over and above the Charges of takeing and keeping the said
Distresse to be immediately restored to the Owner thereof And if any Person or Persons Assessed by this Act
shall refuse or neglect to pay the Summe or Summes soe Assessed by the space of Twenty Dayes after Demand
as aforesaid where noe [such<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] sufficient Distresse can or may be found whereby the same may be Levyed in every
such case Three or more of the Commissioners by this Act appointed for any such City County or Place are
hereby Authorized by Warrant under their Hands and Seales to Committ such Person or Persons to the Common
Gaole there to be kept without Baile or Maineprize untill payment shall be made And if any Person Certifyed
Assessed or Rated finde him or herselfe aggrieved with such Assessing or Rateing and doe within Ten dayes
after Demand thereof made Complaine to the said Commissioners The said Commissioners or any two or more of
them (whereof one of the Commissioners who Signed or Allowed his or her Rate to be one) shall and may
within Fourteene dayes next after such Complaint particularly Examine the Partie soe Complaining upon his or
her Oath of his or her Personall Estate aforesaid and upon due examination or knowledge thereof abate defalke
increase or inlarge the said Assesment and the same soe abated increased or inlarged shall be Estreated by them
into the Exchequer in manner aforesaid And to that end the said Commissioners are hereby required to meete
together for the Determining of such Complaints and Appeales accordingly</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s16">
		<head>XVI. Officers rated where their Office executed; other Persons not being Householders, &amp;c. and Servants where they live.</head>
		<para id="p26">And bee it further Enacted That every Person rated for his Office Place or publicke Imployment shall be
Rated and Pay for his said Office Place or publicke Imployment in the place where the said Office Place or
publicke Imployment is Executed and every Person to be otherwise Rated shall be Rated and the Summe and
Summes on him or her Sett and Levyed at such places where he or she and with his or her Family shall be
resident at the time of the Execution of this Act And that all Persons not being Householders nor haveing a
certaine place of abode and all Servants shall be Taxed at the place where they are resident at the time of the
Execution of this Act.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s17">
		<head>XVII. If Persons having several Mansions be doubly charged,</head>
		<para id="p27">
			<emph type="i">how such Persons discharged.; Persons out of the Realm rated at last Place of Abode. Persons escaping from Taxation charged at double Value</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p28">Provided alwayes That if any Person haveing severall Mansion Houses or places of Residence shall be doubly
Charged by Vertue of this Act That upon Certificate made by Two or more of the Commissioners for the
County City or Place (which Certificate the said Commissioners are required to give without Delay Fee or
Reward) of his or their last Personall Residence under their Hands and Seales of the Summe or Sums there
Charged upon him or them or in what capacity or respect he or they were soe Charged and upon Oath made
of such Certificate before the Commissioners to whome such Certificate shall be tendred which Oath the said
Commissioners are hereby Authorized to Administer when the Person and Persons soe doubly Charged shall (for
soe much as shall be certified) be Discharged in every other County City or Place And if any Person at the
time of the Assessing shall be out of the Realme such Person shall be Rated where such Person was last abideing
within the Realme And if any Person that ought to be Taxed by vertue of this Act by changing his place of
Residence or by Fraud or Covin shall escape from the Taxation and not be Taxed and the same proved before
the Commissioners or two of them or two Justices of the Peace of the County where such Person dweleth or
resideth at any time within Six Months next ensueing after such Tax made every Person that shall soe escape
from the said Taxation and Payment shall be charged upon proofe thereof at the double value of soe much as
he should or ought to have beene taxed by this Act the said double value upon Certificate thereof made into the
Exchequer by the Commissioners or Justices before whome such proofe shall be made to be Levyed of the Goods
Lands and Tenements of such Persons towards the Supply aforesaid</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s18">
		<head>XVIII. Commissioners may assess other Commissioners and Assessors.</head>
		<para id="p29">And bee it further Enacted That the Commissioners which shall be within any County or Place within their
respective Limitts or the major part of them shall Tax and Assesse every other Commissioner joyned with them
And the Commissioners within their Division shall Assesse every Assessor within their Division And as well all
Summs upon every of the said Commissioners and Assessors as the Assesments made and presented by the
Presenters as aforesaid shall be Written Estreated Levyed and Gathered as it should and ought to have beene as
if the said Commissioners had not beene named Commissioners</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s19">
		<head>XIX. Proviso for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey, and Guernsey.</head>
		<para id="p30">Provided That this Act shall not extend to the Inhabitants of Scotland Ireland Jersey or Guernsey for or
concerning any such Personall Estate as aforesaid which they or any other to their use have within the Places
aforesaid</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s20">
		<head>XX. Assessors or others appointed by Commissioners neglecting Duty; Penalty not exceeding &pound;20 for any one Offence certified into Exchequer.</head>
		<para id="p31">And bee it further enacted That if any Assessor Collector Receiver or other Person appointed by the Commissioners
shall wilfully neglect or refuse to performe his Duty in the due and speedy Execution of this present Act the said
respective Commissioners or any Three or more of them may and shall by vertue of this Act Impose on such
person or persons soe refuseing or neglecting their Duties any Fine not exceeding the Summe of Twenty pounds
for any one Offence the same to be Levyed and Certifyed as aforesaid into Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer
and charged upon the respective Receivers Generall amongst the rest of the Rates aforesaid</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s21">
		<head>XXI. Commissioners from Time to Time to require Accounts from Receiver General, and, in case of Failure, Money to be levied. If any Controversy between Commissioners concerning Rates, Proceedings.</head>
		<para id="p32">
			<emph type="i">Questions touching the Rates determined by Two or more Commissioners.
Receiver General to give Acquittances to Collectors gratis. Collectors to deliver to Receivers General a Schedule of Names, &amp;c. of the Persons rated making Default, to be returned into the Exchequer.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p33">And the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them may or shall from time to time call for and require
an Account from the respective Receivers Generall of all the Moneys received by them of the said Collectors and
of the Payment thereof into Their Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer according to the Direction of this Act And in
case of any failure in the Premisses the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them are hereby required to
cause the same to be forthewith Levyed and Paid according to the true intent and meaning of this Act And in
case of any Controversie ariseing betweene the said Commissioners concerning the said Rates or Assesments the
Commissioners that shall be concerned therein shall have noe [Vote<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] but shall withdraw dureing the Debate of such
Controversie untill it be determined by the rest of the Commissioners And all Questions and Differences that shall
arise touching any of the said Rates Taxes Assesments or Levyes shall be heard and finally determined by two
or more of the Commissioners upon Complaint thereof by them made by any Person or Persons thereby grieved
without further trouble or Suite in Law And the said Receiver Generall his Deputy or Deputies shall give Acquittances
gratis to the said Collectors for all Moneys of them received in pursuance of this Act which Acquittances shall be
a full Discharge to the said Collectors respectively And the said Collectors shall make and deliver to the said
Receivers Generall their Deputie or Deputies a perfect Schedule fairly written in Parchment under their Hands and
Seales Signed and Allowed by any two or more of the respective Commissioners containing the Names and Sirnames
and Places of abode of every person as well Peere or Commoner within their respective Collection that shall make
default of payment of any of the Sums that shall be Rated or assessed on such person by vertue of this Act and
the Summe and Summes charged on every such person the same to be by him returned into Their Majestyes
Exchequer whereupon every person soe makeing default of payment may be charged by Processe of the Court
according to the course thereof in that behalfe</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s22">
		<head>XXII. Proviso against Double Charge in respect of Titles.</head>
		<para id="p34">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That noe person shall by vertue of this Act be doubly Charged for or in
respect of severall Titles Honours or Degrees but that every such person shall be Charged and Assessed for such
Title Honour or Degree onely as is highest rated by this Act</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s23">
		<head>XXIII. Letters Patent, from the Crown, of Privileges, &amp;c. or Non obstantes, not to exempt from Payment of Assessment.</head>
		<para id="p35">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Letters Patents Granted by the King and
Queens Majesties or any of their Royall Progenitors or to be Granted by Their Majesties to any Person or Persons
Cities Burroughs or Townes Corporate within this Realme of any manner [of<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Liberties Priviledges or Exemptions
from Subsidies [Tolls Taxes Assessments or Ayds<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] shall be Construed or taken to Exempt any Person or Persons
City Burrough or Towne Corporate or any the Inhabitants of the same from the Burthen and Charge of any
Summe or Summes of Money Granted by this Act And all Non obstantes in such Letters Patents made or to
be made in Barr of any Act or Acts of Parliament for the Supply or Assistance of Their Majesties are hereby
Declared to be void and of none Effect Any such Letters Patents Grants or Charters or any Clause of Non
obstante or other matter or thing therein contained or any Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s24">
		<head>XXIV. Constables, &amp;c. to aid in executing Warrants, &amp;c. of Commissioners.</head>
		<para id="p36">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That all Constables Headburroughs Tythingmen and others Their Majestyes
Officers shall and are hereby required and enjoyned to be respectively Aiding and Assisting in the Execution of
this Act and to Obey and Execute such Precepts or Warrants as shall be to them directed in that behalfe by the
respective Commissioners hereby appointed or any two or more of them</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s25">
		<head>XXV. Persons lending Money on Credit of Act, not exceeding &pound;300,000, to have Tallies of Loan.</head>
		<para id="p37">
			<emph type="i">Persons furnishing Navy or Ordnance with Goods, on Certificate thereof, to have Warrants for Payment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p38">And bee it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons
who shall Lend any Moneys not exceeding Three hundred thousand Pounds in the whole to Their Majestyes
upon the Credit of this Act and pay the same into the Receipt of the Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally
of Loane strucke for the same and an Order for his Repayment bearing the same date with his Tally In which
Order shall be alsoe contained a Warrant for payment of Interest for Forbearance after the Rate of Seven pounds
per Centu[m] per Ann[um] for his Consideration to be paid every Three months untill Repayment of his Principall And
that all Person and Persons who shall furnish Their Majestyes Their Officers of the Navy or Ordnance with any
Wares Goods Shipps Victualls or any other Necessaries for the Service aforesaid shall upon Certificate of the
Commissioners and Officers of the Navy or of the Master or Commissioners and Officers of the Ordnance or some
of them without delay forthwith have made out to them Warrants or Orders for the Payment of the Moneys due
or payable unto them which Certificate the said Officers of their Navy Commissioners and Officers of the Ordnance
shall make without Fee Charge or Delay.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s26">
		<head>XXVI. Orders for Re-payment of Money lent, and Orders signed by Treasury, to be registered in course.</head>
		<para id="p39">And that all Orders for Repayment of Money Lent shall be Registred in Course according to the Date
of the Tally respectively And that all Orders Signed by the Lord Treasurer or Lords Comissioners of the
Treasury and Under-Treasurer of the Exchequer for payment of Moneys for Goods Wares Victualls and other
Necessaries furnished to Their Majestyes Their Officers Master or Commissioners as aforesaid shall be Registred
in Course according to the time of bringing to the Office of the Auditor of Receipt the Certificates above
mentioned</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s27">
		<head>XXVII. Orders signed by Treasury entered in course.</head>
		<para id="p40">And that all Orders soe Signed for Payments directed by Their Majestyes shall be Entred in Course according
to their respective Dates And none of the sorts of Orders above mentioned either for Loanes of Money Supplies
of Wares Goods Victualls or other Necessaries or by Speciall Direction shall have preference one before another
but shall all be Entred in their Course according to the Dates of the Tallies the Times of bringing their Certificates
and the Dates of the Orders for Payments Directed by Their Majestyes as they are in point of time respectively
before each other</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s28">
		<head>XXVIII. Persons to be paid in course as their Orders stand entered.</head>
		<para id="p41">And that all and every person and persons shall be paid in Course according as their Orders shall stand Entred
in the said Register Booke be it Orders for Payments Directed by Their Majesties or of Moneys Lent or for Wares
Com[m]odities Ships Victualls or other Necessaries furnished as aforesaid soe as that the Person Native or Forreigner
his Executors Administrators and Assignes who shall have his Warrant or Order Warrants or Orders first Entred
in the said Booke of Register shall be taken and accounted as the first Person to be paid upon the Moneys to
come in by vertue of this Act And he or they that shall have his or their Warrants or Orders Warrant or
Order next Entred shall be taken and accounted to be the second person to be paid and soe successively and in
Course</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s29">
		<head>XXIX. Monies raised by Assessments to be liable in the like Order</head>
		<para id="p42">And that the Moneys to come in by this Act shall be in the same Order lyable to the Satisfaction of the said
respective Parties their Executors Administrators or Assignes successively without preference of one before another
and not otherwise and not be divertible to any other use intent or purpose whatsoever</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s30">
		<head>XXX. No Fees to be taken for providing or making Registers, Entries, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p43">
			<emph type="i">Penalty, Treble Damages and Costs of Suit, and Officer demanding, &amp;c.; Fee to lose his Place; Undue Preference by Officer; Action by Party grieved and Loss of Place</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p44">And that noe Fee Reward or Gratuity directly or indirectly be demanded or taken of any Their Majestyes
Subjects for providing or makeing of any such Bookes Registers Entries View Search or Certificate in or for payment
of Money Lent or the Interest thereof or for payment of any Money upon any Order upon any Contract for Wares
and Goods furnished to the Use of Their Majestyes Navy and Ordnance as aforesaid by any of Their Majesties
Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputies on paine of payment of Treble Damages to the partie grived by the
partie offending with Costs of Suite or if the Officer himselfe take or demand any such Fee or Reward then to
lose his place alsoe And if any undue preference of one before another shall be made either in point of Registry
contrary to the true meaning of this Act by any such Officer or Officers then the party offending shall be lyable
by Action of Debt or on the Case to pay the value of the Debt Damages and Costs to the partie grieved and shall
be forejudged from his Place or Office</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s31">
		<head>XXXI. The like as to Deputy.</head>
		<para id="p45">And if such preference be unduely made by any his Deputy or Clerke without direction or privity of his Master
Then such Deputy or Clerke onely shall be lyable to such Action Debt Damages and Costs and shall be for ever
after uncapeable of his Place or Office</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s32">
		<head>XXXII. Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller offending, or their Deputies, liable to Forfeiture and Action.</head>
		<para id="p46">And in case the Auditor shall not Direct the Order or the Clerke of the Pells Record or the Teller make
payment according to each persons due place and Order as aforedirected then he or they shall be judged to
Forfeit and their respective Deputies and Clerks herein offending to be lyable to such Action Debt Damages and
Costs in such manner as aforesaid</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s33">
		<head>XXXIII. Penalties, &amp;c. how recovered.</head>
		<para id="p47">All which said Penalties Forfeitures Damages and Costs to be incurred by any of the Officers of the
Exchequer Navy or Ordnance or any their Deputies or Clerks shall and may be recovered by Action of Debt
Bill Plaint or Information in any of Their Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne
Protection Priviledge Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise granted or allowed</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s34">
		<head>XXXIV. What not interpreted undue Preference where Tallies brought the same Day.</head>
		<para id="p48">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby Declared That if it happen that severall Tallies of Loane or Certificates
for Wares delivered or Orders for payments directed by Their Majestyes as aforesaid beare Date or be brought the
same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be Registred Then it shall be Interpreted noe undue preference which
of those he Enters first soe he Enters them all the same day.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s35">
		<head>XXXV. The like Enactment when Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, and Teller pay subsequent Orders when first demanded.</head>
		<para id="p49">Provided alsoe That it shall not be Interpreted any undue preference to incurr any penaltie in point of
payment if the Auditor direct and the Clerke of the Pells Record and the Teller doe pay subsequent Orders
of Persons that come and demand their Money and bring their Orders before other persons that did not come
to demand their Money and bring their Order in their course soe as there be soe much Money reserved as
will satisfie precedent Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon Loane
being to cease from the time the Money is soe reserved and kept in Banke for them</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s36">
		<head>XXXVI. Proviso for Right of Persons having Money due to them to assign their Interest in Warrants, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p50">
			<emph type="i">Memorial of such Assignment to be made without Fee. Assignments not to be released by Assignor</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p51">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That every Person or Persons to whome any Money
shall be due by vertue of this Act after Warrant or Order Entred in the Booke of Register aforesaid for payment
thereof his Executors Administrators or Assignes by Indorsment of his Order or Warrant may Assigne and Transferr
his Right Title Interest and Benefit of such Warrant or Order or any part thereof to any other which being Notified
in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt aforesaid and an Entry or Memoriall thereof alsoe made in the Booke
of Registry aforesaid for Warrants (which the Officers shall upon request without Fee or Charge accordingly make)
shall intitle such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the Benefit thereof and Payment thereon
And such Assignee may in like manner Assigne againe and soe toties quoties And afterwards it shall not be in the
power of such person or persons who have made such Assignements to make void release or discharge the same or
any the Moneys thereby due or any part thereof</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s37">
		<head>XXXVII. Where Actions, &amp;c. commenced against Persons executing Act, they may plead the General Issue, and recover Treble Costs on Nonsuit, &amp;c. of Plaintiff.</head>
		<para id="p52">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any Action Plaint Suite or Information shall be
Commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in execution
of this Act such person or persons soe Sued in any Court whatsoever shall or may plead the Generall Issue Not
guilty and upon any Issue joyned may give this Act and the speciall Matter in Evidence and if the Plaintiffe or
Prosecutor shall become Nonsuite or forbeare further Prosecution or suffer Discontinuance or if a Verdict passe against
him the Defendant and Defendants shall recover their treble Costs for which they shall have the like Remedy as
in any Case where Costs by the Law are given to Defendants</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s38">
		<head>XXXVIII. Parents, &amp;c. of Infants making Default, to pay.</head>
		<para id="p53">And bee it further Enacted and Ordained That the respective Parents Guardians and Tutors of every Person under
the Age of One and twenty yeares shall upon default of payment by such Person and upon Demand pay what is
due and payable by this Act for every such Person resideing in their Family or under their Tuition and not Exempted
as before herein is mentioned</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s39">
		<head>XXXIX. Lodgers and Servants taxed at Place of Residence at Execution of Act.</head>
		<para id="p54">And bee it Enacted That all Persons not being Housholders not haveing a certaine Place of Abode and all
Servants shall be Taxed at the Place where they shall be resident at the time of the Execution of this Act and not
otherwise</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s40">
		<head>XL. The Times and Manner in which Collectors to pay Monies collected under this Act.</head>
		<para id="p55">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Moneys due and payable by this Act shall be
paid by the particular Collectors of the respective Countyes Cities Burroughes Townes Parishes and Places who shall
Collect the same unto such Receiver Generall as shall by Their Majestyes be appointed to Receive the same or to
the Deputy or Deputies of such Receiver Generall to be appointed under his Hand and Seale whereof Notice shall
be given by the Receiver Generall unto the Commissioners or any two of them within their respective Divisions
within Ten dayes after their first generall Meeting and soe from time to time within Ten dayes after every Death
or Removeall of any Deputy if any such shall happen And the Receipt of such Receiver Generall his Deputy or
Deputies or any one of them shall be a sufficient Discharge unto every such Collector</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s41">
		<head>XLI. Collectors not obliged to travel above 10 Miles to make their Payments.</head>
		<para id="p56">And bee it further Enacted That the particular Collectors for payment of any Summes by them received
unto such Receiver Generall or his Deputy shall not be obliged to Travell above Ten Miles from the Place of
their Habitations</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s42">
		<head>XLII. Receivers General within One Month to give Commissioners a Receipt of Monies received by him.</head>
		<para id="p57">
			<emph type="i">Such Receipt to be a Discharge of the Hundred, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p58">And bee it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Receiver Generall from time to time within
the space of one Month next after he shall have received the full Summe that shall be charged upon any Hundred
or Division for each particular Payment that is to be made to such Receiver Generall by vertue of this Act shall
give to the Commissioners that shall act in such Hundred or Division a Receipt under his Hand and Seale
acknowledging his Receipt of the full Summe charged upon such Hundred or Division for such particular Payments
which Receipt shall be a full Discharge of such Hundred or Division for such particular Payments both against
Their Majesties Their Heires and Successors</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s43">
		<head>XLIII. Receiver General certifying Arrears where none are due, or unduly setting insuper.</head>
		<para id="p59">
			<emph type="i">Penalty, Treble Damages, to be recovered by Action, and Forfeiture of double the Sum unduly certified</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p60">And for the better preventing of such unjust Vexations as might be occasioned by such Persons as shall be
appointed Receivers Generall of any of the Summs of Money granted by this Act And to the intent the said
Receivers Generall may returne a true Account into Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer of such Sums of Money
as shall be received by them and every of them their and every of their Deputy and Deputies Bee it further
Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any such Receiver Generall shall returne or Certifie into the said Court any
Summe or Sums of Money to be in Arreare or Unpaid after the same have beene received either by such Receiver
Generall or by his Deputy or Deputies or any of them or shall cause any person or persons to be sett insuper in
the said Court for any Summe or Summes of Money that hath beene soe Received That then every such Receiver
Generall shall forfeit to every person and persons that shall be Molested Vexed or Damaged by reason of such
unjust Certificate Returne or Setting insuper treble the Damages that shall be thereby occasioned The said Damages
to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in which noe Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law
shall be allowed nor any more then one Imparlance And shall alsoe Forfeite to Their Majestyes Their Heires and
Successors double the Summe that shall be soe unjustly Certifyed or Returned or caused to be sett insuper</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s44">
		<head>XLIV. Commissioners not liable to Penalties of 25 Car. II. c.2.</head>
		<para id="p61">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Com[m]issioner or Commissioners who shall be
Imployed in the Execution of this Act shall be lyable for or by reason of such Execution to any of the Penalties
mentioned in an Act made the Five and Twentyeth Yeare of King Charles the Second For the preventing of Dangers
which may happen from Popish Recusants</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s45">
		<head>XLV. Penalties, for the levying of which no Provision is made, to be levied by Distress under Warrant of Commissioners.</head>
		<para id="p62">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That all Penalties and Forfeitures to be incurred for any Offences against
this Act for which there is noe way of Levying therein before prescribed or appointed shall be Levyed by Warrant
of any two or more of the respective Commissioners of the Division or Place where any such Offence was or shall
be com[m]itted by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of the Offender rendring the Overplus to the Owner thereof after
a Deduction of reasonable Charges for Distraining the same</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s46">
		<head>XLVI. Commissioners at General Meetings, after Appeals determined, to cause Duplicates of Sums levied to be written and delivered to Sheriff, and to be by him transmitted into the Exchequer 1st Nov. 1689.</head>
		<para id="p63">And bee it further Enacted That the Commissioners in every County at a Generall Meeting to be by them
appointed after all Appeales shall be first determined shall cause Duplicates of the whole Summe charged within
every Hundred Lath Wapentake Parish Ward or Place Rated and Assesed in such County in pursuance of this Act
without nameing the Persons to be fairly written in Parchment and ascertained under two or more of their Hands
respectively to each Duplicate and the same soe by them subscribed and ascertained shall be joyntly and together
delivered to the Sheriffe of such County and be by him transmitted to the Exchequer at or before the First day of
November One thousand six hundred eighty and nine</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s47">
		<head>XLVII. Interest at &pound;7. per Cent. on Monies lent on Credit of 1 W. &amp; M. c. 3. ante.</head>
		<para id="p64">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That for all and every Summe and Summes of Money
that is are or shall be Lent or Advanced by way of Loane upon the Security of an Act of this present Parlyament
Entituled An Act for the Granting a present Ayde to Their Majestyes the respective Lenders thereof shall have
Interest for forbearance thereof after the Rate of Seven pounds per Centum per Annum for his Consideration to
be paid every Three months untill Repayment of his Principall The said recited Act or any other Act or Law to the
contrary notwithstanding</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s48">
		<head>XLVIII. Menial Servants refusing, &amp;c. to pay Assessments, Master or Mistress to pay, and may deduct out of Wages.</head>
		<para id="p65">And bee it further Enacted That in case any Meniall Servant receiveing Wages shall upon the demand of such
Assessment or Moneys as are due from him or her by vertue of this Act refuse or neglect to pay the same to the
respective Collectors in such case his or her Master or Mistresse shall pay such Servants Assessments And it shall
then be lawfull for such Master or Mistresse to deduct and stopp the same out of such Wages as shall or ought
to be next paid unto such Servant Any Law or Custome to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s49">
		<head>XLIX. Proviso for Persons dispossessed of their Estates in Ireland by reason of the Rebellion.</head>
		<para id="p66">
			<emph type="i">Except certain Persons having Estates in England</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p67">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe person or persons who by reason
of the present Rebellion in Ireland are dispossest of their Estates in that Kingdome shall be charged with or
made lyable to pay any of the Summe or Summes intended to be paid by the severall Degrees of Persons in
this Act mentioned Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding unlesse such person or persons
being of or above the Degree of a Baron shall have in the Kingdome of England an Estate of the cleare yearely
value of One thousand pounds or being of the Degree of a Baronet Knight Esquire or Gentleman and haveing
an Estate of the cleare yearely value of Five hundred pounds in the Kingdome of England aforesaid.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">an <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n7" number="7">a <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n8" number="8">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n12" number="12">Voice <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>


