<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46292" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act for Establishing the Coronation Oath. [Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Oath heretofore framed in doubtful Words.</head>
			<para id="p1">Whereas by the Law and Ancient Usage of this Realme the Kings and Queens thereof have taken a
Solemne Oath upon the Evangelists at Their respective Coronations to maintaine the Statutes Laws and
Customs of the said Realme and all the People and Inhabitants thereof in their Spirituall and Civill Rights and
Properties BUT forasmuch as the Oath itselfe on such Occasion Administred hath heretofore beene framed in
doubtfull Words and Expressions with relation to ancient Laws and Constitutions at this time unknowne To the
end therefore that One Uniforme Oath may be in all Times to come taken by the Kings and Queens of this
Realme and to Them respectively Administred at the times of Their and every of Their Coronation.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Oath hereafter mentioned to be administered,</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">by the Archbishop of Canterbury, &#x0026;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">May it please Your Majesties That it may be Enacted And bee it Enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent
Majestyes by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this p[re]sent
Parlyament Assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the Oath herein Mentioned and hereafter Expressed
shall and may be Administred to their most Excellent Majestyes King William and Queene Mary (whome God
long preserve) at the time of Their Coronation in the presence of all Persons that shall be then and there present
at the Solemnizeing thereof by the Archbishop of Canterbury or the Archbishop of Yorke or either of them or any
other Bishop of this Realme whome the King's Majesty shall thereunto appoint and who shall be hereby thereunto
respectively Authorized which Oath followeth and shall be Administred in this Manner That is to say,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Form of Oath and Administration thereof.</head>
			<para id="p4">The Arch-Bishop or Bishop shall say,</para>
			<para id="p5">Will You solemnely Promise and Sweare to Governe the People of this Kingdome of England and the
Dominions thereto belonging according to the Statutes in Parlyament Agreed on and the Laws and Customs of
the same?<br/>
The King and Queene shall say,<br/>
I solemnly Promise soe to doe.<br/>
Arch Bishop or Bishop,<br/>
Will You to Your power cause Law and Justice in Mercy to be Executed in all Your Judgements.<br/>
King and Queene,<br/>
I will.<br/>
Arch Bishop or Bishop.</para>
			<para id="p6">Will You to the utmost of Your power Maintaine the Laws of God the true Profession of the Gospell and the
Protestant Reformed Religion Established by Law? And will You Preserve unto the Bishops and Clergy of this
Realme and to the Churches committed to their Charge all such Rights and Priviledges as by Law doe or shall
appertaine unto them or any of them.<br/>
King and Queene.<br/>
All this I Promise to doe.<br/>
After this the King and Queene laying His and Her Hand upon the Holy Gospells, shall say,<br/>
King and Queene<br/>
The things which I have here before promised I will performe and Keepe Soe help me God.<br/>
Then the King and Queene shall kisse the Booke.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Oath to be administered to all future Kings and Queens.</head>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further Enacted That the said Oath shall be in like manner Administred to every King or Queene
who shall Succeede to the Imperiall Crowne of this Realme at their respective Coronations by one of the Archbishops
or Bishops of this Realme of England for the time being to be thereunto appointed by such King or Queene
respectively and in the Presence of all Persons that shall be Attending Assisting or otherwise present at such their
respective Coronations Any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


