<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46295" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IX. An Act for the Amoving Papists and reputed Papists from the Cityes of London and Westminster and Ten Miles distance from the same. [Rot. Parl. p. 5. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">Whereas the great numbers of Papists resorting to the Cityes of London and Westminster are and for a
long time have beene found dangerous to the Peace and Safety of this Kingdome For the better
Preservation of the Common Safety and avoiding their mischievous Practices and Designes</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">Lord Mayor and Justices of London may tender Declaration of 30 Car. II. st. 2. c. 1. to reputed Papists</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">Bee it Enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent Majesties by and with the Advice and Consent of the
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament Assembled and by the Authoritie of the
same That for the better discovering and amoveing all Papists and reputed Papists out of the said Cities and Ten
miles of the same it shall and may be lawfull and it is hereby Required that the Lord Mayor of London for
the time being and every Justice of the Peace [of the City of London and for the City and Liberties of Westminster
and Burrough of Southwarke and of the Countyes of Midlesex Surrey Kent and Sussex<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] within their respective
Countyes Cityes Boroughes and Limitts doe from time to time cause to be Arrested and brought before him every
person or persons not being a Merchant Forreigner within the said Cities or within Ten miles of the same as
are or are reputed to be Papists and tender unto him the Declaration mentioned in the Statute made in the
Thirtyeth Yeare of King Charles the Second Entituled An Act for the more effectuall preserveing the Kings
Person and Government by disableing Papists from Sitting in either House of Parlyament And in case such person
upon such tender refuse audibly and solemnely to repeate make and subscribe the said Declaration and shall
after such refusall remaine continue or be within the said City or Cityes or Ten miles distance from the same
That in every such Case he or she shall forfeite and suffer as a Popish Recusant Convict by the Lawes already
established shall or may forfeit or suffer</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Justices of Peace to certify Subscribers and Refusers to the Court of King's Bench.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Person certified to have refused, not appearing and taking Declaration in the next Term or Sessions, adjudged a Popish Recusant Convict</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And it is hereby further Enacted. That every Justice of Peace shall and doe certifie all and every Subscription
[or<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] before him by vertue of this Act taken and likewise the Names of all and every Person refuseing to repeate
take make or subscribe as aforesaid upon tender under the Hand and Seale of the said Justice into the Court of
Kings Bench the next Terme or else at the next Quarter Sessions that shall be of or for the County or Place where
such takeing subscribing or refusall shall happen And if the said Person soe refuseing and certifyed shall not
within the next Terme or Sessions after such refusall appeare in the Court of Kings Bench or Sessions where such
Certificate shall be Returned and in open Court audibly and solemnely repeate take make and subscribe the
Declaration aforesaid and Indorse or Enter his soe doeing upon the Certificate soe Returned shall be from the
time of such his neglect or refusall taken esteemed and adjudged a Popish Recusant Convict and as such to forfeite
and be proceeded against.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Tradesmen, or such as within Six Months before the 13th February 1688 lived in London or Westminster, or within Ten Miles, who shall certify their Names, &amp;c. before 1st August 1689.</head>
			<para id="p6">[Provided alwayes That this Act shall not extend to such person or persons as now use any Trade Mistery or
Manuall Occupation within the said Liberties of London and Westminster or within ten miles of the same Nor to
such as within Six months before the Thirteenth day of February One thousand six hundred eighty eight had
their Dwellings or Places of abode within the said Cities or ten miles compasse of the same not haveing any
Dwelling or Place of abode elsewhere soe as he or they before the First day of August One thousand six hundred
eighty nine doe certifie his or their Names Additions and Places of abode at the Sessions of the Peace to be held
for the said respective Cities Counties or Places And the Clerke of the Peace shall not take or receive above Two
pence for the Entry of the Name Addition and place of abode of any one Person<ref idref="n3">3</ref>.]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Aliens Servants to Ambassadors, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided that nothing in this Act shall relate to or have any effect upon any Forreigner that is or shall be a
Meniall Servant to any Ambassador or Publicke Agent.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Proviso for Portuguese Subjects sworn Servants to the Queen Dowager, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided That nothing in this Act shall relate to or have any effect upon any person being a naturall borne
Subject of the King of Portugall who now is or hereafter shall be a sworne Servant to the Queene Dowager nor
to any other Servants being naturall borne Subjects of Their Majestyes as her Majestie the Queene Dowager shall
under her Hand and Seale from time to time for that purpose be pleased to nominate the said Servants soe
nominated not exceeding the number of Thirty at any one time soe as none of the said Servants being naturall
borne Subjects of Their Majestyes be a Jesuite Priest Monke or Fryer Any Law or Statute to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


