<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46293" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act for Impowering His Majestie to Apprehend and Detaine such Persons as He shall finde Just Cause to Suspect are Conspireing against the Government. [Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Persons in Prison on the 25th April 1689, or after, by Warrant of the Privy Council; may be detained without Bail, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p1">For the Secureing the Peace of the Kingdome in this time of Imminent Danger against the Attempts and
Traiterous Conspiracies of Evill disposed Persons Bee it enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent
Majestyes by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present
Parlyament Assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That every Person or Persons that shall be in Prison
at or upon the Five and twentyeth Day of Aprill in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty and
nine or after by Warrant of Their said Majesties most Honourable Privy Councill Signed by Six of the said
Privy Councill for Suspicion of High Treason or Treasonable Practices or by Warrant Signed by either of His
Majesties Secretaries of State for such Causes aforesaid may be detained in safe Custodie without Baile or Mainprize
until the Five and twentieth Day of May next</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>III. No Judge, &#x0026;c. to hold such Persons to Bail without Order of Privy Council.</head>
			<para id="p2">And that noe Judge or Justice or Court of Justice shall Baile or Try any such Person or Persons soe Committed
without Order from Their said Majesties Privy Councill Signed by Six of the said Privy Councill till the said Five
and twentieth day of May any Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>IV. Proviso for 31 Car. II. c. 2. and all other Laws providing for the Liberty of the Subject.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Continuance of Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes That from and after the said Five and twentyeth Day of May the said Persons soe Committed
shall have the Benefit and Advantage of an Act made in the One and thirtyeth yeare of King Charles the Second
Entituled An Act for the better Secureing the Liberty of the Subject and for Prevention of Imprisonment beyond
the Seas, and alsoe of all other Laws and Statutes any way relateing to or provideing for the Liberty of the Subjects
of this Realme And that this present Act shall continue untill the said Five and twentyeth day of May and
noe longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>V. Proviso for Privileges of Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That nothing in this Act shall be Construed to Extend to the Ancient
Rights and Priviledges of Parlyament or to the Imprisoning or Detaining of any Member of either House of
Parlyament untill the matter of which he stands suspected be first Communicated to the House of which he is a
Member and the Consent of the said House obtained for his Commitment or Detaining.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


