<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46297" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XI. An Act for the Explaining and makeing Effectuall a Statute made in the First Yeare of King James the Second concerning the Haven and Pieres of Great Yarmouth. [Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1000"><emph type="i">1 Jac. II. c. 16.</emph></para>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Powers by the said Act given to the Mayor vested in the Bailiffs, Aldermen, &#x0026;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">For the preventing all Doubts and Scruples which may in any wise arise concerning the Power and Authoritie
of the Bayliffes Aldermen Burgesses and Commonalty of the Burrough and Towne of Great Yarmouth in the
County of Norfolke to putt in execution and take the Benefitt of an Act made in the First Yeare of the Raigne
of the late King James the Second Entituled An Act for Clearing Preserving Maintaining and Repairing the Haven
and Pieres of Great Yarmouth and for the Amendment of the said Act and makeing the same effectuall according
to the true intent and meaning thereof Bee it declared and Enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent
Majestyes by and with the Advice of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons now Assembled in Parlyament
and by the Authoritie of the same That all and every the Powers Authorities and Benefitts by the said Act given
or intended to be given to the Mayor Aldermen Burgesses and Co[m]monaltie in the said Act mentioned or to any
of them shall be and hereby are for and dureing the rest and residue of the time in the said Act limitted
Vested in the Bayliffes Aldermen Burgesses and Commonalty of the said Burrough that now are and their Successors
and shall be taken deemed and adjudged to be by vertue hereof soe Vested as aforesaid And that the Powers
Authorities and Benefitts by the said Act given or intended to be given to the said Mayor shall and hereby are
Vested in the Bayliffe or Bayliffes for the time being and their Successors to be by them joyntly or severally executed
in such manner as the said Mayor by the said Act might or was intended to have done</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>II. Collectors, &#x0026;c. by this and the former Acts may execute the same.</head>
			<para id="p3">And that all and every Officer and Officer Collector or Collectors Receiver or Receivers Commissioner or
Commissioners to be nominated chosen or appointed by the forementioned or this present Act shall and may execute
and pursue the severall and respective Powers therein given and directed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>III. Money by the former Act directed to be paid unto the Chamberlain, paid as Bailiffs, &#x0026;c. shall order.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes That all and every Summe or Summes of Money directed or appointed to be paid by the
said Act into the Hands of the Chamberlaine of the said Burrough for the time being shall hereafter be paid
into the Hands of such Person or Persons as the Bayliffes Aldermen Burgesses and Commonalty in Common Councill
assembled shall direct and appoint Any thing in the said Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Alterations by new Charters.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided likewise That if it shall happen that there shall be within the said rest and residue of the said
time by the said recited Act limitted any Alteration by any new Charter in the said Corporation from Bayliffes
to [Mayors<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] That then the Mayor Aldermen Burgesses and Commonalty and every of them shall have and execute
the Powers Authorities and Benefitts in the recited Act mentioned in such manner as in the said Act is expressed.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">Mayor <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		
	</section>
</report>


