<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46298" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII. An Act for the Encouraging the Exportation of Corne. [Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>Prices at which Corn may be exported.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Merchants to bring Certificate of Quantity and Quality of Corn to be exported.; Oath. Bond by Merchant. Bounty. No Fee for Bounty.; Upon Certificate returned under the Common Seal of Place Abroad, or under the Seals of Two English Merchants, that Corn was taken or lost,; Bond delivered up to Importer.; Monies paid by Commissioners allowed in Account</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Forasmuch as it hath beene found by experience That the Exportation of Corne and Graine into Forreigne Parts
when the Price thereof is at a low Rate in this Kingdome hath beene a great Advantage not onely to the Owners of
Land but to the Trade of this Kingdome in Generall Bee it therefore Enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent
Majestyes By and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Commons now Assembled
in Parlyament and by the Authoritie of the same That when Malt or Barley Winchester Measure is or shall be at Foure
and twenty shillings per Quarter or under Rye at Two and thirty shillings per Quarter or under and Wheate at
Eight and forty shillings a Quarter or under in any Port or Ports of this Kingdome or Dominion of Wales
Every Merchant or other Person who shall putt on Shipp-board in English Shipping the Master and Two thirds
of his Marriners at least being Their Majestyes Subjects any Sorts of the Corne aforesaid from any such Ports
where the Rates shall not then be higher then as aforesaid with Intent to Export the said Corne to Parts
beyond the Seas Every such Merchant or other Person shall bring a Certificate in Writeing under his or their
Hands containing the Quantity and Quality of Corne soe shipped to the Farmers Commissioners Collectors or
other Persons appointed or to be appointed for the time being to Collect the Duties and Rates ariseing by Customs
within any such Port and upon proofe made of any such Certificate by one or more credible Person or Persons
upon their Oaths which Oathes the said Commissioners or other Persons are hereby Authorized and Required
to Administer and upon Bond given by every such Merchant or other Person in the Summe of Two hundred
pounds at the least for every hundred Tuns of Corne soe Shipped and soe proportionably that the said Corne
(Danger of the Seas excepted) shall be exported into Parts beyond the Seas and not be againe Landed in the
Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales the Islands of Guernsey and Jersey or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede
Every such Merchant soe Shipping off any of the aforesaid Corne and giveing Certificate and Bond as aforesaid shall
have and receive from such Farmers Commissioners Collectors or other Persons in any Port respectively where the
same Corne shall be soe Shipped for every Quarter of Barley or Malt ground or unground Two shillings and
six pence For every Quarter of Rye ground or unground Three shillings and six pence For every Quarter of
Wheate ground or unground Five shillings Which Summe or Summes every such Commissioner Farmer or other
Person are hereby Authorized and Required upon Demand by such Exporter to make present Payment of
accordingly without takeing or requireing any, thing for Custome or any Fee or Reward for Corne soe Laden to
be Exported or for soe much Grain as shall be Exported in any Shipp wherein any other Goods shall be Shipped Any
Law Statute or Usage in any wise to the contrary notwithstanding And upon Certificate returned under the Common
Seale of the Chiefe Magistrate in any Place or Places beyond the Seas or under the Hands and Seales of Two knowne
English Merchants upon the Place that such Corne was there Landed or upon Proofe by credible Persons that such
Corne was taken by Enemies or perished in the Seas the Examination and Proofe thereof being left to the Judgement
of such Commissioners Farmers Collectors or other Persons which Proofe being made or Certificate delivered to such
Person or Persons respectively as tooke Bond as aforesaid the said Bond shall be delivered up to such Importer or
his Order to be Cancelled without any Fee for the same And the Moneys by any such Commissioners Farmers
Collectors or other Person soe paid in obedience to this Act shall be accepted of in his or their Accompts as soe
much paid to Their Majestyes and he and they is and shall be discharged therefore accordingly.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


