<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46302" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVI. An Act that the Simoniacall Promotion of one Person may not prejudice another.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Simoniacal Contract where it shall not prejudice.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas it hath often happened that persons Simoniack or Simoniacally promoted to Benefices or
Ecclesiasticall Liveings have enjoyed the benefitt of such Liveings many yeares and some times all their
Life-time by reason of the secret carriage of such Simoniacall dealing and after the death of such Simoniack person
another person innocent of such Crime and worthy of such Preferment being presented or promoted by another
Patron innocent alsoe of that Simoniacall Contract have beene troubled and removed upon pretence of Lapse (or
otherwise) to the prejudice of the innocent Patron in Reversion and of his Clerke whereby the Guilty goe away
with profitt of his Crime and the innocent succeeding Patron and his Clerke are punished contrary to all reason
and good Conscience For prevention whereof Bee it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and
with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and
by the authoritie of the same That after the death of the person soe Simoniacally promoted the Offence or Contract
of Simony shall neither by way of Title in Pleading or in Evidence to a Jury or otherwise hereafter be alledged
or pleaded to the prejudice of any other Patron innocent of Simony or of his Clerke by him presented or
promoted upon pretence of Lapse to the Crowne Metropolitan or otherwise unlesse the person Simoniack or
Simoniacally presented or his Patron was convicted of such Offence at the Common Law or some Ecclesiasticall
Court in the Life time of the person Simoniack or Simoniacally promoted or presented any Law or Statute to the
contrary notwithstanding</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Lease made bona fide by Simonist, good.</head>
		<para id="p2">[And bee it alsoe provided enacted and declared by the authoritie aforesaid That noe Lease or Leases really and
bona fide made or hereafter to be made by any such person as aforesaid Simoniack or Simoniacally promoted to any
Deanry Prebend or Parsonage or other Ecclesiasticall Benefice or Dignity for good and valuable consideration to any
Tennant or person not being privy unto or haveing notice of such Simony shall be impeached or avoided for or by
reason of such Simony but shall be good and effectuall in Law the said Simony notwithstanding.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
	</section>
</report>


