<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46304" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVIII. An Act for Exempting their Majestyes Protestant Subjects dissenting from the Church of England from the Penalties of certaine Lawes.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">23 El. c.1.; 29 El. c. 6.; IEl. c. 2. &sect; 14.; 3 Jac. I. c.3, 4.; 3 Jac. I. c. 5.; nor any other Law against Papists or Popish Recusants, except; 25 Car. II. c. 2.; 30 Car. II. st. 2.; to extend to Dissenters taking the Oaths of cap. 1. ante,; and making and subscribing the Declaration of 30 Car. II. st. 2.; Justices to tender Oaths and; Declaration, and keep a Register thereof.; Fee for Register and Certificate</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Forasmuch as some ease to scrupulous Consciences in the Exercise of Religion may be an effectuall
meanes to unite their Majesties Protestant Subjects in Interest and Affection Bee it enacted by the King
and Queens most excellent Majestyes by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall
and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That neither the
Statute made in the [three and twentieth yeare of the Raigne of the late Queene Elizabeth Entituled An Act
to Retaine the Queens Majestyes Subjects in their due Obedience, Nor the Statute made in the twenty ninth
yeare of the said Queene Intituled An Act for the more speedy and due Execution of certaine Branches of
the Statute made in the three and twentyeth yeare of the Queens Majestyes Raigne viz? The aforesaid Act,
nor that Branch or Clause of a Statute made in the first yeare of the Raigne of the said Queene Intituled An
Act for [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Uniformity of Common Prayer and Service in the Church and Administration of the Sacraments
whereby all persons haveing noe lawfull or reasonable excuse to be absent are required to resort to their Parish
Church or Chappell or some usuall place where the Common Prayer shall be used upon paine of Punishment by
the Censures of the Church and alsoe upon paine that every person soe offending shall forfeite for every such
Offence twelve pence Nor the Statute made in the third yeare of the Raigne of the late King James (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Intituled An
Act for the better discovering and repressing Popish Recusants Nor that other Statute made in the same yeare
Intituled An Act to Prevent and Avoid Dangers which may grow by Popish Recusants Nor any other Law or
Statute of this Realme made against Papists or Popish Recusants Except the Statute made in the five and twentyeth
yeare of King Charles the Second Intituled An Act for preventing Dangers which may happen from Popish
Recusants And except alsoe the Statute made in the thirtyeth yeare of the said King Charles the Second Intituled
An Act for the more effectuall preserveing the Kings Person and Government by disableing Papists from sitting
in either House of Parlyament Shall be construed to extend to any person or persons dissenting from the Church
of England that shall take the Oaths mentioned in a Statute made this present Parliament Intituled An Act for
removeing and preventing all Questions and Disputes concerning the assembling and sitting of this present Parliament
And shall make and subscribe the Declaration mentioned in a Statute made in the thirtyeth yeare of the Raigne of King
Charles the Second Intituled An Act to prevent Papists from sitting in either House of Parlyament Which Oaths and
Declaration the Justices of Peace at the generall Sessions of the Peace to be held for the County or Place where such
person shall live are hereby required to tender and administer to such persons as shall offer themselves to take make
and subscribe the same and thereof to keepe a Register And likewise none of the persons aforesaid shall give or pay
as any Fee or Reward to any Officer or Officers belonging to the Court aforesaid above the summe of six pence nor
that more then once for his or their Entry of his takeing the said Oaths and makeing and subscribeing the said
Declaration Nor above the further summe of six pence for any Certificate of the same to be made out and signed by
the Officer or Officers of the said Court.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Persons convicted, &amp;c. taking the Oaths, &amp;c. to be discharged.</head>
		<para id="p3">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That all and every person and persons already convicted or
prosecuted in order to Conviction of Recusancy by Indictment Information Action of Debt or otherwise grounded upon
the aforesaid Statutes or any of them that shall take the said Oaths mentioned in the said Statute made this present
Parliament and make and subscribe the Declaration aforesaid in the Court of Exchequer or Assizes or Generall
or Quarter Sessions to be held for the County where such person lives and to be thence respectively certified
into the Exchequer shall be thenceforth exempted and discharged from all the Penalties Seizures Forfeitures
Judgements and Executions incurred by force of any the aforesaid Statutes without any Composition Fee or further
Charge whatsoever</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Persons taking the Oaths, &amp;c. not liable to Penalties of 35 El. c. 1. and 22 Car. II. c. 1. nor to be prosecuted in any Ecclesiastical Court.</head>
		<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That all and every person and persons that shall as
aforesaid take the said Oathes and make and subscribe the Declaration aforesaid shall not be lyable to any Paines
Penalties or Forfeitures mentioned in an Act made in the five and thirtyeth yeare of the Raigne of the late Queene
Elizabeth Intituled An Act to retaine the Queenes Majestyes Subjects in their due Obedience Nor in An Act made in
the two and twentyeth yeare of the Raigne of the late King Charles the Second Intituled An Act to prevent and
suppresse seditious Conventicles Nor shall any of the said persons be prosecuted in any Ecclesiasticall Court for or by
reason of their Nonconforming to the Church of England.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Dissenters meeting with Doors locked, &amp;c. excluded from Benefit of this Act.</head>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for Tythes</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That if any Assembly of persons dissenting from
the Church of England shall be had in any place for Religious Worship with the doores locked barred or bolted
dureing any time of such Meeting together all and every person or persons that shall come to and be at such Meeting
shall not receive any benefitt from this Law but be lyable to all the Paines and Penalties of all the aforesaid Laws
recited in this Act for such their Meeting notwithstanding his takeing the Oaths and his makeing and subscribing the
Declaration aforesaid Provided alwayes That nothing herein contained shall be construed to exempt any of the persons
aforesaid from paying of Tythes or other Parochiall Duties or any other Duties to the Church or Minister nor from
any Prosecution in any Ecclesiasticall Court or elsewhere for the same</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V.</head>
		<para id="p7">
			<emph type="i">Dissenters appointed Officers, and scrupling Oaths, &amp;c. may act by Deputy.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p8">And bee it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any Person dissenting from the Church of
England as aforesaid shall hereafter be chosen or otherwise appointed to beare the Office of High Constable or
Petty Constable Churchwarden Overseer of the Poore or any other Parochiall or Ward Office and such person
shall scruple to take upon him any of the said Offices in reguard of the Oathes or any other Matter or Thing
required by the Law to be taken or done in respect of such Office every such Person shall and may execute
such Office or Employment by a sufficient Deputie by him to be provided that shall comply with the Laws on this
behalfe Provided alwayes the said Deputy be allowed and approved by such person [and<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] persons in such manner as
such Officer or Officers respectively should by Law have beene allowed and approved</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. Dissenters in Orders by what Means exempted from the Penalties of 13 &amp; 14 Car. II. c. 4. &sect; 10.</head>
		<para id="p9">
			<emph type="i">17Car. II. c. 2. and; 22 Car. II. c. 1.; Taking the Oaths, &amp;c. to be registered.; Meeting-Door to be unlocked.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p10">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That noe person dissenting from the Church of England
in Holy Orders or pretended Holy Orders or pretending to Holy Orders nor any Preacher or Teacher of any
Congregation of dissenting Protestants that shall make and subscribe the Declaration aforesaid and take the said Oaths
at the Generall or Quarter Sessions of the Peace to be held for the County Towne Parts or Division where such
person lives which Court is hereby impowred to administer the same and shall alsoe declare his approbation of and
subscribe the Articles of Religion mentioned in the Statute made in the thirteenth yeare of the Raigne of the late
Queene Elizabeth Except the thirty fourth thirty fifth and thirty sixth and these words of the twentyeth Article
[viz<emph type="p">t</emph><ref idref="n4">4</ref>] (the Church hath power to decree Rights or Ceremonies and Authority in Controversies of Faith and yet)
shall be lyable to any of the paines or penalties mentioned in An Act made in the seventeenth yeare of the Raigne of
King Charles the Second Intituled An Act for restraining Non Conformists from inhabiting in Corporations Nor the
penalties mentioned in the aforesaid Act made in the two and twentyeth yeare of his said late Majesties Raigne
for or by reason of such persons preaching at any Meeting for the Exercise of Religion Nor to the penalty of
one hundred pounds mentioned in An Act made in the thirteenth and fourteenth of King Charles the Second
Intituled An Act for the Uniformity of Publique Prayers and Administration of Sacraments and other Rites and
Ceremonies And for establishing the Forme of makeing ordaineing and consecrateing of Bishops Priests and Deacons
in the Church of England for officiating in any Congregation for the Exercise of Religion permitted and allowed by
this Act [Provided alwayes That the makeing and subscribing the said Declaration and the takeing the said
Oaths and makeing the Declaration of Approbation and Subscription to the said Articles in manner as aforesaid by
every respective person or persons herein before mentioned at such Generall or Quarter Sessions of the Peace as
aforesaid shall be then and there entred of Record in the said Court for which six pence shall be paid to the Clerke
of the Peace and noe more<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Provided that such person shall not at any time preach in any place but with the doores
not locked barred or bolted as aforesaid</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. Provison for Anabaptists.</head>
		<para id="p11">And whereas some dissenting Protestants scruple the baptizeing of Infants Bee it enacted by the authoritie
aforesaid That every person in pretended Holy Orders or pretending to Holy Orders or Preacher or Teacher that
shall subscribe the aforesaid Articles of Religion Except before excepted and alsoe except part of the seven and
twentyeth Article touching Infant Baptisme and shall take the said Oathes and make and subscribe the Declaration
aforesaid in manner aforesaid every such person shall enjoy all the Privileges Benefitts and Advantages which any
other dissenting Minister as aforesaid might have or enjoy by vertue of this Act</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. Teacher exempt from Office.</head>
		<para id="p12">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That every Teacher or Preacher in Holy Orders or pretended
Holy Orders that is a Minister Preacher or Teacher of a Congregation that shall take the Oathes herein required
and make and subscribe the Declaration aforesaid And alsoe subscribe such of the aforesaid Articles of the Church
of England as are required by this Act in manner aforesaid shall be thenceforth exempted from serveing upon
any Jury or from being chosen or appointed to beare the Office of Churchwarden Overseer of the Poore or
any other Parochiall or Ward Office or other Office in any Hundred of any Shire City Towne Parish Division
or Wapentake</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>IX. Justice of Peace may tender the Oaths, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p13">
			<emph type="i">First Refusal; Imprisonment, &amp;c; Second Refusal; Taken to be a Popish Recusant Convict</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p14">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That every Justice of the Peace may at any time hereafter
require any person that goes to any Meeting for Exercise of Religion to make and subscribe the Declaration aforesaid
and alsoe to take the said Oaths or Declaration of Fidelity herein after mentioned in case such person scruples
the takeing of an Oath and upon refusall thereof such Justice of the Peace is hereby required to committ such
person to Prison without Baile or Maineprize and to certifie the Name of such person to the next Generall or
Quarter Sessions of the Peace to be held for that County City Towne Part or Division where such person then
resides and if such person soe committed shall upon a second tender at the Generall or Quarter Sessions refuse to
make and subscribe the Declaration aforesaid such persons refuseing shall be then and there recorded and he shall be
taken thenceforth to all intents and purposes for a Popish Recusant Convict and suffer accordingly and incurr all the
penalties and forfeitures of all the aforesaid Laws</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s10">
		<head>X. Quakers making</head>
		<para id="p15">And whereas there are certaine other persons Dissenters from the Church of England who scruple the takeing of
any Oath Bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That every such person shall make and subscribe the aforesaid
Declaration and alsoe this Declaration of Fidelity following viz</para>
		<para id="p16">
			<emph type="i">Declaration of Fidelity, and subscribing Profession of Christian Belief, exempted from Penalties of the aforesaid Statutes, and also from the Penalties of</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p17">I A B doe sincerely promise and solemnely declare before God and the World that I will be true and faithfull
to King William and Queene Mary And I doe solemnly professe and Declare That I doe from my Heart Abhor
Detest and Renounce as Impious and Hereticall that damnable Doctrine and Position That Princes Excommunicated
or Deprived by the Pope or any Authority of the See of Rome may be Deposed or Murthered by their Subjects
or any other whatsoever And I doe declare that no Forreigne [Prince Person<emph type="p">2</emph>] Prelate State or Potentate hath
or ought to have any Power Jurisdiction Superiority Preeminence or Authoritie Ecclesiasticall or Spirituall within
this Realme.</para>
		<para id="p18">[And shall subscribe a Profession of their Christian Beliefe in these Words</para>
		<para id="p19">I A B professe Faith in God the Father and in Jesus Christ his Eternall Sonne the true God and in the Holy
Spirit one God blessed for evermore And doe acknowledge the Holy Scriptures of the Old and New Testament
to be given by Divine Inspiration,</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s11">
		<head>5 Eliz. c. 1. and 13 &amp; 14 Car. II. c. 1.</head>
		<para id="p20">Which Declarations and Subscription shall be made and entred of Record at the generall Quarter Sessions of the
Peace of the County City or place where every such person shall then reside<emph type="p">1</emph>] And every such person that shall
make and subscribe the two Declarations and Profession aforesaid being thereunto required shall be exempted
from all the pains and penalties of all and every the aforementioned Statutes made against Popish Recusants or
Protestant Nonconformists and alsoe from the penalties of an Act made in the fifth yeare of the Raigne of
the late Queene Elizabeth Intituled An Act for the Assurance of the Queenes Royall Power over all Estates and
Subjects within her Dominions For or by reason of such persons not takeing or refuseing to take the Oath
mentioned in the said Act And alsoe from the penalties of An Act made in the thirteenth and fourteenth yeares
of the Raigne of King Charles the Second Intituled An Act for preventing Michiefes that may arise by certaine
persons called Quakers refuseing to take lawfull Oaths And enjoy all other the Benefitts Priviledges and Advantages
under the like Limitations Provisoes and Conditions which any other Dissenters shall or ought to enjoy by vertue
of this Act</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s12">
		<head>XI. How purged after Refusal of the Oaths.</head>
		<para id="p21">
			<emph type="i">Certificate of belonging to a Congregation, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p22">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That in case any person shall refuse to take the
said Oaths when tendred to them which every Justice of the Peace is hereby impowred to doe such person shall not
be admitted to make and subscribe the two Declarations aforesaid though required thereunto either before any Justice
of the Peace or at the Generall or Quarter Sessions before or after any Conviction of Popish Recusancy as aforesaid
unlesse such person can within thirty one dayes after such tender of the Declarations to him produce two sufficient
Protestant Witnesses to testifie upon Oath that they believe him to be a Protestant Dissenter or a Certificate under
the Hands of foure Protestants who are conformable to the Church of England or have taken the Oaths and
subscribed the Declaration abovementioned and shall alsoe produce a Certificate under the Hands and Seals of six
or more sufficient Men of the Congregation to which he belongs owning him for one of them</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s13">
		<head>XII. Until Certificate produced, Justices to take Recognizance to produce same.</head>
		<para id="p23">Provided alsoe and bee it enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That untill such Certificate under the Hands of six
of his Congregation as aforesaid be produced and two Protestant Witnesses come to attest his being a Protestant
Dissenter or a Certificate under the Hands of foure Protestants as aforesaid be produced the Justice of the Peace
shall and hereby is required to take a Recognizance with two Sureties in the penall Summe of fifty pounds
[to be levyed of his Goods and Chattells Lands and Tenements to the use of the King and Queens Majestyes their
Heires and Successors<emph type="p">1</emph>] for his produceing the same and if he cannot give such Security to committ him to prison
there to remaine untill he has produced such Certificates or two Witnesses as aforesaid</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s14">
		<head>XIII. Laws for Divine Service in force.</head>
		<para id="p24">Provided alwayes and it is the true intent and meaning of this Act That all the Laws made and provided for the
frequenting of Divine Service on the Lords Day commonly called Sunday shall be still in force and executed against
all persons that offend against the said Laws except such persons come to some Congregation or Assembly of
Religious Worship allowed or permitted by this Act</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s15">
		<head>XIV. Papists, &amp;c. excepted from Benefit of Act.</head>
		<para id="p25">Provided alwayes and bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That neither this Act nor any Clause
Article or Thing herein contained shall extend or be construed to extend to give any ease benefitt or advantage to
any Papist or Popish Recusant whatsoever or any person that shall deny in his Preaching or Writeing the Doctrine
of the Blessed Trinity as it is declared in the aforesaid Articles of Religion</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s16">
		<head>XV. Disturbers of Religious Worship, Recognizance; or in Default, imprisoned; and on Conviction, Penalty &pound;20.</head>
		<para id="p26">Provided alwayes, and bee it enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any person or persons at any time or
times after the tenth day of June doe and shall willingly and of purpose maliciously or contemptuously come into any
Cathedrall or Parish Church Chapell or other Congregation permitted by this Act and disquiet or disturbe the
same or misuse any Preacher or Teacher such person or persons upon proofe thereof before any Justice of Peace by
two or more sufficient Witnesses shall finde two Sureties to be bound by Recognizance in the penall Summe of fifty
pounds and in default of such Sureties shall be committed to prison there to remaine till the next Generall or
Quarter Sessions and upon conviction of the said offence at the said Generall or Quarter Sessions shall suffer the paine
and penalty of twenty pounds [to the use of the King and Queens Majesties their Heirs and Successors<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s17">
		<head>XVI. Place for Worship to be certified.</head>
		<para id="p27">Provided alwayes That noe Congregation or Assembly for Religious Worship shall be permitted or allowed by
this Act untill the place of such Meeting shall be certified to the Bishop of the Diocesse or to the Arch-Deacon of
that Archdeaconry [or to the Justices of the Peace at the Generall or Quarter Sessions of the Peace for the County
City or Place<emph type="p">1</emph>] in which such Meeting shall be held and registred in the said Bishops or Archdeacons Court
respectively or recorded at the said Generall or Quarter Sessions The Register or Clerke of the Peace whereof
respectively is hereby required to register the same and to give Certificate thereof to such person as shall demand the
same for which there shall be none greater Fee nor Reward taken then the Summe of six pence.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">the first <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
	</section>
</report>


