<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46308" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXII. An Act for the Exportation of Beere, Ale, Syder and Mum.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Ale, &amp;c. may be exported.; Paying Duty of Custom.; Gauger, &amp;c. to certify Quantity.; Excise to be repaid</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the Advancement of Trade and Encouragement of Tillage and Manufacture of this Realme Bee it enacted
by the King and Queens most excellent Majestyes, by and with the advice and consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That from
and after the twenty fourth of June in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred eighty nine It shall
and may be lawfull for any person in any Seaport or upon any Navigable River to export and shipp off as
Merchandize within any of the usuall and allowed Ports by Law and at the common Keyes for Exportation and
ladeing on Board of Merchandize or Keyes to be appointed for that purpose and within the usuall houres of
Excize for accompt of himselfe or any other (to be exported into Forreigne parts) in the presence of a sworne
Gauger or other sworne Officer to be appointed by the Farmers Commissioners or Sub Com[m]issioners of their
Majestyes Excise upon Notice thereof to them given at the Office of Excise within the Limitts whereof the said
Ale Beere Sider and Mum was brewed or made of the respective Port or Place whence the same shall be shipped
any sort of strong Ale strong Beere Sider or Mum to be spent beyond the Seas paying Custome for the same after
the Rate of one shilling for every Tunn which shall be exported in any English or Forreigne Vessell and noe
more or other Duty whatsoever Which said Gauger or Officer aforesaid shall certifie the quantity of the said
Beere Ale Syde or Mum shipped off to the Commissioners and Officers of Excise where the Entry thereof shall
be made who are hereby required to make allowance or repay the Excise of the Beere Ale Syder or Mum soe
exported unto the Brewer or Maker thereof within one month after such Exportation deducting three pence per
Tunn for the Charges of their Officers and noe more</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Merchant unlading, &amp;c. such Ale, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Penalty, Ale, &amp;c. forfeited, and &pound;50 per Cask.; Proviso for Ale, &amp;c. spent on Shipboard.; Excise thereof how recovered</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That if any Merchant or Master of any Shipp or Vessell
or other person shall cause or suffer any of the said Liquors soe shipped in any Vessell as Merchandize to be
unshipped unladen and laid on Land or putt into any other Shipp or Vessell within the Kingdome of England
Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede he or they shall forfeite the same and fifty pounds of
lawfull Money of England more for every Caske he or they shall soe unduely land or putt aboard any Vessell to
be [recorded<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] in any of his Majestyes Courts of Record by Information Bill or Plaint The one moyety of which
Forfeiture shall be to the use of the King and Queens most excellent Majestyes the other moyety to the Informer
[or<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Prosecutor And to the intent their Majesties Duty of Excise may not be prejudiced for such Beere Ale Sider
or Mum as shall be spent on Shipboard their Majestyes Commissioners and Officers of the Customes are hereby
required and enjoyned to charge every Master of any Shipp or Vessell in his Victualling Bill with soe much Beere.
Ale Sider or Mum and noe more as such number of Men use to spend in such Voiages The Excise whereof to be
recovered according to the Laws and Rules already established</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Duty of Customs how levied.</head>
		<para id="p5">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the aforesaid rate of one shilling the Tunn for Beere
Ale Syder and Mum to be exported as aforesaid shall be levyed and paid under such Rules and Penalties and for
such time and in such manner as by the Laws of Tonnage and Poundage are ordained</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Duty for Foreign Mum on Importation not repaid on Exportation.</head>
		<para id="p6">Provided alwayes and bee it (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That noe Mum imported from Forreigne parts
dureing the continuance of this Act shall have any part of the Duty of Custome or Excise which was paid at
the Importation thereof repaid upon Exportation any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">recovered <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">further <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


