<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46307" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXI. An Act for enabling Lords. Commissioners for the Great Seale to execute the Office of Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Jurisdiction of Commissioners of Great Seal doubted.; Commissioners of the Great Seal may execute the Power and entitled to the Emoluments of Chancellor.; Their Place</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas their most Excellent Majestyes King William and Queene Mary have thought fitt that the Office
of the Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper of the Great Seale of England should be executed by Commissioners
appointed for the same under the Great Seale of England And whereas severall Authorities Jurisdictions and Powers
are by severall Acts of Parliament and otherwise vested setled and placed in the Lord Chancellor of England or
Lord Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the time being Now for the preventing of all Doubts and Questions
that may arise whether all or any of those Authorities Jurisdictions and Powers may be exercised by such
Commissioners Bee it enacted and declared and it is hereby enacted and declared by the King and Queens
most excellent Majestyes and by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by authoritie of the same That such Commissioners for the
time being may use and exercise at all times according to their Commissions as of right belonging to the Lords
Commissioners of the Great Seale of England for the time being all and every the same and like Offices Authority
Jurisdiction and Execution of Laws and all other Customes Priviledges Emoluments and Advantages which the
Lord Chancellor of England or Lord Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the time being of right ought to
[have use<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] or execute as belonging to their or either of their said Offices or otherwise howsoever to all intents and
purposes as if the said Lords Commissioners for the time being were Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper of the
Great Seale of England and shall have and take place next after the Peeres of this Realme [and Speaker of
the House of Commons unlesse any of them, shall happen to be a Peere and then to take place according to
his Peerage<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. One Commissioner may hear Motions, &amp;c. but not make Decree, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p3">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That any one Commissioner (in the absence
of the others) may heare Motions and give Orders and Directions touching the interlocutory Proceedings in any
Cause soe as such one Commissioner in the absence of the others shall not make any Decrees or putt the Great
Seale to any thing whatsoever whereunto the whole Broad Seale ought to be affixt unlesse there be two Commissioners
present</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Custos Rotulorum how to be chosen.</head>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">37 H. VIII. c. 1</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p5">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the nominating and appointing of the Custos Rotulorum
throughout all the Shires and Countyes of this Realme is and shall be as is directed by a Statute made in the thirty
seventh yeare of Henry the Eighth Entituled A Bill for Custos Rotulorum and [the Clerkship of<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] the Peace any Law
Usage or Statute to the contrary in anywise notwithstanding</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Clerk of the Peace how to be appointed.</head>
		<para id="p6">[And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the Custos Rotulorum or other person to whome
of right it doth or shall belong to nominate or appoint the Clerke of the Peace for any County Rideing Division
or other Place shall from time to time where the Office of the Clerke of the Peace now is or hereafter shall be
void nominate and appoint one able and sufficient person resideing in the said County Rideing Division or other
place for which he is soe appointed or to be appointed Clerke of the Peace to execute the same by himselfe or
his sufficient Deputy and to take and recieve the Fees Profits and Perquisits thereof for soe long time onely as such
Clerke of the Peace shall well demeane himselfe in his said Office</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. Justices of Peace in Sessions may discharge Clerk of the Peace.</head>
		<para id="p7">
			<emph type="i">What Person may nominate Clerk of the Peace upon such Vacancy</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p8">And bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That if any Clerke of the Peace already nominated or to be
nominated as aforesaid shall misdemeane himselfe in the Execution of the said Office and thereupon a Complaint
and Charge in Writeing of such Misdemeanor shall be exhibited against him to the Justices of the Peace in their
Generall Quarter Sessions it shall be lawfull for the said Justices or the major part of them from time to time upon
Examination and due proofe thereof openly in their said Generall Quarter Sessions to suspend or discharge him
from the said Office and that in such Case the Custos Rotulorum or other person to whome it shall of right
belong to nominate and appoint the Clerke of the Peace for such County Rideing Division or place shall nominate
and appoint one other able and sufficient person resideing in the said County Rideing Division or place as aforesaid
to be Clerke of the Peace in the place of such Person soe amoved as aforesaid and in case of refusall or neglect
to make such Nomination and Appointment before the next Generall Quarter Sessions to be holden after the said
refusall that it shall and may be lawfull for the said Justices of the Peace at their Generall Quarter-Sessions for the
said County Rideing Division or place or the major part of them to nominate and appoint one able and sufficient
person resideing in the said County Rideing Division or place to be Clerke of the Peace in the place of such
person soe amoved as aforesaid to have hold and enjoy the said Office of Clerke of the Peace and to execute the
same by himselfe or his sufficient Deputy and to receive the Fees Profits and Perquisits thereof</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. New Clerk of the Peace liable to Penalties, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p9">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That he shall be lyable and subject to all the
Penalties Forfeitures Conditions Limitations and Provisions herein and hereby mentioned and expressed and may be
amoved or discharged by the said Justices or the major part of them in such manner and way as is above
specified.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. Custos Rotulorum, &amp;c. shall take no Fee for appointing Clerk of the Peace.</head>
		<para id="p10">Buying and selling of Place of Clerk of the Peace. Penalty.</para>
		<para id="p11">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That it shall not be lawfull for any Custos Rotulorum
or other person to whome of right it doth or shall belong to nominate elect or appoint any Clerke of the Peace
to sell the said Place of Clerke of the Peace or to take any Bond or other assurance to recieve or have any
Reward Money Fee or Profitt directly or indirectly to him or any other person for such nominating electing or
appointing but that every such Custos Rotulorum or other person that shall soe sell the Clerkshipp of the Peace
and every Clerke of the Peace who shall soe buy his place are hereby disabled to hold their places of Custos
Rotulorum or Clerkship of the Peace and shall alsoe each of them respectively forfeite double the Summe or Value
of other thing that shall be soe given or taken to be recovered by him or them to their owne use that shall
sue for the same to be prosecuted by any Action of Debt Suite Bill Plaint or Information in any of their Majestyes
Courts at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law shall lye</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. Clerk of the Peace to take the Oath following.</head>
		<para id="p12">[And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That every Clerke of the Peace before he enter upon
the execution of his said Office shall in open Sessions take the Oath following viz<emph type="p">t</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p13">I A B doe Sweare That I have not nor will pay any Summe or Summs of Money or other Reward whatsoever
nor given any Bond or other Assurance to pay any Money Fee or Profitt directly or indirectly to any
person or persons whomsoever for such Nomination or Appointment Soe helpe me God.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>IX. Act not to extend to Duchy or County Palatine of Lancaster.</head>
		<para id="p14">Provided alwayes That nothing in this Act contained shall any ways affect or relate to the Clerke of the
Peace for the Dutchy and County Palatine of Lancaster onely which said Clerke of the Peace holds his said Office
for Lives by Grants from his late Majestie King Charles the Second as his Predecessors in the said place have
done from former Kings and Queens of this Realme in right of their Dutchy and County Palatine aforesaid
This Act to commence from the first day of May one thousand six hundred eighty nine.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">use have <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original Act in separate Schedules.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original Act in separate Schedules.</note>
	</section>
</report>


