<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46300" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIV. An Act for preventing Doubts and- Questions concerning the Collecting the Publique Revenue.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>All the Revenue payable to the Two late Kings shall be paid to their present Majesties till December next.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">All Acts concerning the Revenue in force.; Orders about Fees continued.; Stat. 12 Car. II. c. 4</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the preventing all Disputes and Questions concerning the collecting levying and answering of the Publique
Revenue due and payable in the Raignes of the late Kings Charles the Second and James the Second
whilst the better setling of the same is under the Consideration of this present Parylament Bee it enacted
by the King and Queenes most excellent Majestyes by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons in Parliament assembled and by authoritie of the same That the Subsidie
of Tonnage and Poundage and other Summes of Money payable upon Merchandize Exported and Imported
and the severall Impositions Duties and Charges upon Liquors Manufactures and other things and all and singular
the Revenue and Revenues whatsoever except the Duties ariseing by Fire-hearths and Stoves other then such as
are or shall be incurred at or before the five and twentyeth day of March one thousand six hundred eighty nine
given granted and payable to or lawfully enjoyed by the said late Kings or either of them which remained and
had continuance on the fifth day of November last and all Arreares of the same shall be raised levyed collected
answered and paid to their Majestyes untill the twenty fifth day of December which shall be in the yeare of our
Lord one thousand six hundred eighty and nine in the same manner and forme according to such Rates and
Orders and by such Rules Meanes and Wayes and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are mentioned
expressed and appointed in the Statutes made in the Raigns of the said late Kings or either of them concerning
the same respectively and as by Law the same might or ought to have beene dureing the said Raigns
And that all and singular Acts of Parliament made dureing the Reigns of either of the said late Kings for
the granting setling raising levying collecting answering and paying the same or for preventing Frauds or
Concealments or regulateing Abuses therein or for the better ordering or recovering the same and all Powers
Provisions Penalties Articles Clauses and Things contained in the said Acts or any of them be and are hereby
continued and confirmed and shall stand and be in force and be applyed practiced executed and putt in use
for the raising levying collecting paying and answering the said Subsidie Summes of Money Impositions Duties
and Revenues to their Majestyes according to the tenour and intent of this present Act And alsoe that an Order
of the Commons in Parliament assembled made in pursuance of the Rules and Orders annexed to the Act of
Parliament made in the twelfth yeare of the Raigne of the [said<emph type="p">1</emph>] late King Charles the Second Entituled A Subsidie
granted to the King of Tonnage and Poundage and other Summes of Money payable upon Merchandize Exported
and Imported for setling of Officers Fees dated the seventeenth day of May one thousand six hundred sixty two
and signed by Sir Edward Turner then Speaker shall be of full force and effect untill the said five and twentyeth
day of December one thousand six hundred eighty nine as if the same were particularly and at large recited
in this Act</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Persons who have received Subsidy indemnified, but answerable to their Majesties.</head>
		<para id="p3">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That all and every person and persons that have
received or collected the said Subsidy Summs of Money Impositions Duties or, any other publique Revenue or
any part or parcel thereof since the said fifth day of November shall and are hereby indempnifyed against all
persons from whome he or they levyed received or collected the same to be answerable neverthelesse to their
Majestyes for what he or they have soe received or collected</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Seizures and Forfeitures betwixt December and February valid.</head>
		<para id="p4">And bee it farther enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That all Seisures and Distresses made or to be made by
any Officer or Officers of the Customs or Excise or any person or persons thereunto lawfully authorized and all
Forfeitures and Penalties for any Offence against any Law concerning the Customs or Excise or relateing to the
Transportation of Woole or Importation or Exportation of Prohibited Goods incurred since the eleventh day of
December and before the thirteenth day of February one thousand six hundred eighty eight shall be prosecuted and
sued and all Recoveries Judgments and Proceedings thereupon shall and may be had and prosecuted as well by any
Informer sueing and prosecuteing for the Kings and Queens Majestyes and himselfe as by their Majestyes Attourney
Generall for their Majestyes in the same manner and forme as if such Seizures Distresses and Offences had beene
made and committed after the said thirteenth day of February.</para>
	</section>
</report>


