<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46305" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIX. An Act for Exempting their Majestyes Protestant Subjects dissenting from the Church of England from the Penalties of certaine Lawes.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Persons in Prison on 25th May 1689, or after, by Warrant of Privy Council, on Suspicion of Treason, may be detained without Bail as herein mentioned.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for Benefit of 31 Car. II. c.2. and all other Laws for the Liberty of the Subject</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the Secureing the Peace of the Kingdome in this time of Imminent Danger against the Attempts and
Trayterous Conspiracies of evill disposed Persons Bee it enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent
Majestyes by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present
Parlyament Assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That every person or persons that shall be in Prison at
or upon the Five and twentyeth day of May in the yeare of Our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty
and nine or after by Warrant of Their said Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Signed by Six of the said
Privy Councill at least for Suspition of High Treason or Treasonable Practices may be detained in safe Custodie
without Baile or Mainprize untill the Three and twentyeth day of October in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred eighty and nine And that noe Judge or Justice or Court of Justice or other person shall Baile or Try
any such person or persons soe Committed or in Prison as aforesaid without Order from Their said Majesties Privy
Councill Signed by Six of the said Privy Councill at least till the said Three and twentyeth day of October Any
Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding Provided alwayes That from and after the said Three and twentieth
day of October the said persons soe Committed or in Prison as aforesaid shall have the Benefitt and Advantage of an
Act made in the One and thirtyeth Yeare of King Charles the Second Intituled An Act for the better Secureing the
Liberty of the Subject and for Prevention of Imprisonment beyond the Seas And alsoe of all other Laws and
Statutes any way relateing to or provideing for the Liberty of the Subjects of this Realme And that this present
Act shall continue untill the said Three and twentyeth day of October and noe longer.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Privileges of Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That nothing in this Act shall be construed to extend to the prejudice
of the ancient Rights and Priviledges of Parliament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. True Copy of Warrant for Commitment entered and kept by Clerk of the Council and signed by such of the Council as granted the Warrant.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That a true Copy of every Warrant or Order
for such Committment as aforesaid shall be fairly Entred and kept by the Clerks of the Privy Councill respectively
in a Booke for that purpose onely and shall be Signed by such of the said Councill as shall grant such Warrant
or Order of Commitment And that noe Warrant or Order of which such Copy is not soe Entred and Signed and
kept shall be deemed or taken or adjudged to be a Warrant or Order by vertue of or in pursuance of this Act
or to be allowed of or justified thereby.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


