<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46314" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXVIII. An Act for Appropriating certaine Duties for paying the States Generall of the United Provinces their Charges
for His Majesties Expedition into this Kingdome and for other Uses. [Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">&pound;60,000, Part of the Monies granted by 1 Jac. II. c. 4. applied to pay the Wages of certain Servants of the late King Charles II.; The Residue of the Monies arising by 1 Jac. II.c. 3. &#x0026; c. 24. ante.; Applied in the first Place in Payment of &pound;600,000 to the United States for assisting His Majesty on coming into this Nation; and the Residue towards subduing the Rebellion in Ireland, &#x0026;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For satisfying and defraying the Debts and Charges and to the Purposes herein after mentioned Bee it Enacted
by the King and Queens most Excellent Majestyes by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in Parlyament Assembled and by Authoritie of the same That part of the
Money accruing and payable to Their Majesties by one Act of Parlyament made in the First Yeare of the Raigne
of the late King James the Second Entituled An Act for granting to His Majestie an Imposition upon all [Tobaccho<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
and Sugar imported betweene the four and twentyeth day of June One Thousand six hundred eighty five and the
Foure and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety three not exceeding in the whole the Summe
of Sixty Thousand pounds shall be appropriated and applyed to the Payment of the Wages due to the Servants
of the late King Charles the Second which were his Servants at the time of his Decease to be paid to them
his Executors Administrators and Assignes in Three Yeares from the Twenty fourth day of December One thousand
six hundred eighty nine by Three equall Payments and in such manner and proportion and to such of them as
His Majestie shall direct And that the residue of the Money ariseing and payable by the said Act and the
Revenue and Summes of Money ariseing and payable by Two other Acts of Parliament made in the said First Yeare
of the said late King James the one Entituled An Act for granting His Majestie an Imposition upon all Wines and
Vinegar imported betweene the Foure and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred eighty five and the
Foure and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety and three And the other An Act for granting
an Aide to His Majestie by an Imposition on all French Linens and all East-India Linen and severall other Manufactures
of India and on all French wrought Silks and Stuffs and on all other wrought Silks And on all Brandies imported
after the First day of July One thousand six hundred eighty five and before the First day of July One thousand
six hundred and ninety And by one other Act of this present Parliament Entituled An Act for an Additional
Duty of Excise upon Beere Ale and other Liquors shall be appropriated and applyed from and after the Nine
and twentyeth day of September One thousand six hundred eighty and nine dureing the respective continuance of
the said Acts In the first place for and towards the payment of Six hundred thousand pounds to the States of
the United Provinces for their Assistance to His Majestie at his comeing into this Nation for our Deliverance from
Popery and Arbitrary Power in such manner as His Majestie shall direct Which said Summe of six hundred
thousand pounds is meant and intended in full satisfaction of their said Assistance and the Charges thereof And
after the said Six hundred thousand pounds shall be soe paid the Residue shall be for and towards the Subduing
of the Rebellion of Ireland and other Charges of the Warr against France and for noe other Use or Purpose
whatsoever Any thing in this or any other Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Monies to be kept apart from other Monies payable to Their Majesties.</head>
			<para id="p3">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That all the Moneys that from and after the Nine
and twentyeth day of September One thousand six hundred eighty nine shall arise by the Additionall Duty of
Excise and the severall Impositions herein before mentioned shall be kept apart and distinct from all other Moneys
payable to Their Majestyes in one or more Books to be provided for that purpose by the Auditor of the
Receipt of Their Majesties Exchequer whereby it may be seene by such as shall be appointed thereunto by the
States Generall of the United Provinces or other Persons concerned how much of the said Additionall Duty
and Impositions are and shall be from time to time Paid and Answered into the Receipt of Their Majestyes
Exchequer</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. No Money to be paid to the Servants of the late King, unless they take the Oaths and make the Declaration of c. 8. ante, and produce a Certificate thereof attested by Clerk of the Peace.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes That noe part of the Money to be hereby issued and paid to any of the Servants of the
said late King Charles shall be distributed to any other of them their Executors or Administrators then to such
as shall at or before the First day of February next ensueing have taken the Oaths and Made and Subscribed
the Declaration mentioned in one Act of this present Parliament Entituled An Act for the Abrogating of the
Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance and Appointing other Oaths at the Generall Quarter Sessions of the Peace
of the County or Place where they shall respectively Reside and shall produce a Certificate thereof attested by
the Clerke of the Peace attending the same.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Tobacco <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


