<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46310" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for an Additionall Duty of [Excise] upon Beere Ale and other Liquors. [Chapter XXIV. Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for granting the Duties.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Additional Excise upon Ale, &amp;c. given for Three Years.; Beer or Ale above 6s. the Barrel, 9d. a Barrel.; Beer or Ale 6s. the Barrel or under, 3d. a Barrel.; Vinegar of English Materials, 1s. 6d. a Barrel.; Vinegar of Foreign Materials, 4s. a Barrel.; Foreign Beer, &amp;c. imported, 3s. a Barrel.; Cyder or Perry imported, &pound;4. a Tun.; Single Brandy imported, 2s. the Gallon.; Double Brandy imported, 4s. a Gallon.; Cyder and Perry retailed, 1s. 3d. the Hogshead. Metheglin or Mead, 3d. the Gallon</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee your Majestyes most dutyfull and loyall Subjects the Commons assembled in Parlyament takeing into
serious consideration the great and urgent Occasions which doe presse your Majestyes to an extraordinary
Expence of Treasure for the defence of your Kingdomes and Dominions against Invasion and for preserving to
your said Subjects the intercourse of Trade for which purpose your Majestyes have found yourselves obliged to
equipp and sett out to Sea a Royall Navy and to make and maintaine a Warr against the French King and in
most thankfull acknowledgment of your Majesties tender Care of the Welfaire of your People have chearfully and
unanimously given and granted and doe hereby give and grant to your Majesties the severall additionall Rates
and Duties of Excise herein after mentioned and doe most humbly beseech your Majesties that it may be enacted
And bee it enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by authoritie of the same
That from and after the four and twentyeth day of July which shall be in the yeare of our Lord one thousand
six hundred eighty and nine there shall be throughout your Majestyes Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales
and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede raised levyed collected and paid unto your Majesties and your Successors
dureing the space and terme of three yeares from the four and twentyeth day of July aforesaid and noe longer
for Beere Ale Sider and other Liquors herein after expressed by way of Excise over and above all other Duties
Charges and Impositions by any former Act or Acts sett and imposed and in manner and forme following that is
to say For every Barrell of Beere or Ale above six shillings the Barrell exclusive of the Duty of Excise brewed
by the common Brewer or any other person or persons who doth or shall sell or tapp out Beer or Ale publickly
or privately to be paid by the common Brewer or by such other person or persons respectively and soe
proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity over and above the Duties already payable for the same nine
pence For every Barrell of Beere or Ale of six shillings the Barrell or under brewed by the common Brewer
or any other person or persons who doth or shall sell or tap out Beere or Ale publickly or privately to be paid
by the said common Brewer or by such other person or persons respectively as aforesaid and soe proportionably
for a greater or lesser quantity over and above the Duty already payable for the same three pence For every
Barrell of Vinegar or Vinegar Beere brewed or made of any English Materialls by any common Brewer or any
other person for Sale to be paid by the maker thereof and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity over
and above the Duties of Excise already payable for the same one shilling six pence For every Barrell of Vinegar
or Liquor prepared for Vinegar made here for Sale of any Forreigne Materialls or any mixture with Forreigne
Materialls to be paid by the maker thereof and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity foure shillings
For every Barrell of Beere Ale or Mum imported from beyond the Seas and soe proportionably for a greater or
lesser quantity to be paid by the Importers before landing over and above the Duties already payable for the
same three shillings For every Tun of Syder or Perry imported from beyond the Seas and soe proportionably for
a greater or lesser quantity to be paid by the Importer before landing over and above the Duties already payable
for the same foure pounds For every Gallon of single Brandy Spirits or Aqua vite imported from beyond the
Seas to be paid by the Importer before landing over and above the Duties already payable for the same two
shillings For every Gallon of Brandy Spirits or Aqua vite above proofe commonly called double Brandy imported
from beyond the Seas to be paid by the Importer before landing over and above the Duties already payable for
the same foure shillings For all Sider and Perry made and sold by Retaile upon every Hogshead to be paid
by the Retailer thereof over and above the Duties already payable for the same and soe proportionably for a greater
or [lesser<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Measure one shilling three pence For all Metheglin or Mead made for Sale whether by Retaile or
otherwise to be paid by the maker for every Gallon three pence</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Distiller, after Account taken of Low Wines,</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">selling without distilling a Second Time, Penalty, 5s.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That if any Distiller or Maker of [any<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Low Wines shall
at any time after the twentieth day of July one thousand six hundred eighty nine after an account hath beene
taken by the Gauger of the quantity of his Low Wines sell dispose of or remove the same or any part thereof
without distilling or drawing it off a second time every such Distiller or maker of Low Wines for every Gallon
soe sold disposed of or removed shall forfeit the summe of five shillings to be levyed in manner as any penalties
or forfeitures are levyable by any Act relateing to the Revenue of Excise</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Excise how collected.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">12 Car. II. c. 24.; 15 Car. II. c. 11</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the severall Rates and Duties of Excise hereby
imposed on the Liquors aforesaid shall be raised levyed collected recovered and paid unto their Majesties and
their Successors dureing the time before mentioned and in the same manner and forme and by such rules wayes
and meanes and under such penalties and forfeitures as are mentioned expressed and directed in and by one Act
of Parlyament made in the twelfth yeare of the Raigne of the late King Charles the Second Entituled An Act for
takeing away the Court of Wards and Liveries and Tenures in Capite and by Knights Service and Purveyance and
for setling a Revenue upon his Majestie in lieu thereof And alsoe in and by one other Act of Parlyament made in
the fifteenth yeare of his said Majesties Raigne Entituled An Additionall Act for the better ordering and collecting
the Duties of Excise and preventing the Abuses therein or in either of them, Or by any other Law now in force
relateing to the Revenue of Excise not otherwise herein and hereby altered and provided against</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">What shall be accounted a Barrel.; Allowances for Leakage</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And for the avoiding all uncertainty and all differences and disputes which of late have beene betweene the
Gaugers and the Brewers Victuallers Retailers and other persons chargeable with the duties of Excise touching
Beere and Ale and touching the Returns or Charges made or to be made of Beere or Ale by the Gaugers or
Officers appointed to take account and ascertaine the same Bee it enacted [and declared<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] by the authority aforesaid
That every foure and thirty Gallons of Beere or Ale whether strong or small brewed or made in any part of
England Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede by any the person or persons aforesaid other then within the
Cityes of London and Westminster and within the Weekly Bills of Mortality taken by the Gauger according to
the Standard of the Ale Quart foure whereof shall make the Gallon remaineing in the Custody of the Chamberlaine
of their Majesties Exchequer shall be reckoned accounted and returned by the Gauger or Gaugers or other
Officers aforesaid for a Barrell of Beere or Ale And that the allowances appointed to be made and allowed to the
Common Brewers other then within the Cities of London and Westminster and the Weekly Bills of Mortality
aforesaid for Waste by filling and leakage of their Beere and Ale out of the said Returns or Charges made by
the said Gaugers or other Officers aforesaid shall be two Barrells and an halfe upon every three and twenty
Barrells of Beere or Ale whether strong or small and noe more any thing in the above mentioned Acts or any
other Act of Excise or any Law or Usage to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding and that every Barrell of
Beere and Ale made and brewed within the said Cities of London and Westminster and within the Weekly Bills
of Mortality aforesaid by any the persons aforesaid shall be reckoned accounted and returned as the same are
respectively to be reckoned accounted and returned by the former Acts of Excise and that the Common Brewers
within the Cities of London and Westminster and within the Weekly Bills of Mortality shall have the like allowances
for waste by filling and leakage out of the said Gaugers Returns as by the said former Acts are directed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Brewer chargeable with the Quantity of Worts missing</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And whereas by the Laws relateing to their Majesties Revenue of Excise It is enacted That Gaugers have
power to gauge all Coppers Fatts and Vessells in any Brewhouse and all other places whatsoever belonging to or
used by any Brewer Innkeeper Victualler or other Retailer of Beere or Ale and to take an accompt of Beere
Ale and Worts from time to time brewed or made and thereof to make Returne and Report in Writeing to the
Commissioners and Subcommissioners of Excise and such Returns to be a Charge upon such Brewers Now for the
preventing of Frauds and Disputes which may happen or arise by the Gaugers makeing their Returns [as<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] aforesaid
Bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That where it shall appeare to the Gauger or Gaugers that any Worts
are missing or not lett fairely downe into the Tun and such Gauger cannot finde the same in such Case it shall
be lawfull [for such Gauger<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] to charge such Brewer Victualler or other Retailer with soe much Beere or Ale as
such Worts soe missing would reasonably make</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Gaugers may make Returns upon warm Worts, and make Allowance to Brewer, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p11">And for the avoiding as much as may be all Disputes Bee it enacted That it shall and may be lawfull for all
Gaugers to take their gauges and make their Returns and Charges upon warme Worts in the Backs Coolers or
other Vessells and in such Case shall make allowance to the Brewer Innkeeper Victualler or other Retailer of one
tenth part thereof for Wash and Waste for all Worts soe Returned and Charged which Worts nor any part of the
same are to be in any sort afterwards charged with the payment of any Duty of Excise when brewed or made
into Beere or Ale.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Ale-seller not suable for selling at a higher Rate than formerly.</head>
			<para id="p12">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That noe Innkeeper Victualler or other Retailer
of Beere or Ale shall at any time hereafter dureing the continuance of this Act or of the additionall Duties hereby
imposed be sued impleaded or molested by Indictment Information or Popular Action or otherwise for selling or
uttering any Beere or Ale at any other or higher Prices then the Prices heretofore limitted and appointed any
thing in this Act or any other Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Frauds in Payment of Duties recited.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Distiller refusing to permit Gauger to come into his Storehouse, &amp;c.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And forasmuch as it is found by Experience that the payment of their Majesties Duties on Strong Waters Aqua
vite and Spirits is much avoided and defrauded by the Distillers or makers of the Commodities aforesaid by reason
that the Gaugers and Officers appointed to gauge and charge those Liquors are not duely admitted and permitted
to enter and come into the Houses Distilling-houses or Store-houses and other places belonging to or used by such
Distillers or Makers of such Strong Waters Aqua vite and Spirits and the penalties imposed by the former Acts are
often avoided for such denyall or refusall because proofe cannot be made by the Informers or Officers of any Sale
made of any their Commodities before the Duty thereof is paid Bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That from
henceforth in case any Distiller or Maker of the Commodities aforesaid shall upon due request or demand made by
the Gauger or Officer in the day time or in the night-time in the presence of a Constable refuse to permitt such
Gaugers to enter and come into his or their House Distillinghouse Store-house or other places belonging to or used
by such Distillers or Makers of Strong Waters Aqua vite or Spirits the partie and parties soe offending shall forfeit
and incurr the Forfeitures and Penalties by the said former Acts imposed and inflicted to be recovered in manner as
therein and thereby is directed and the Informer or Prosecutor shall not be obliged to prove that such Offenders
sold carryed or delivered out part of his Commodities aforesaid before he had paid or cleared the Duties due for the
same any thing in the said former Act or any other Act or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. 15 Car. II. c. 11. &sect;6, 7.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Brewer not discharged from Misentry, except he shewed to Gauger an Account of the Beer, &amp;c. at the Time of the Return.; Fraud of Duty.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And whereas in and by the said Act made in the fifteenth yeare of the Raigne of the late King Charles the
Second It is amongst other things therein provided or enacted in the words or to the effect following (viz<emph type="p">t</emph>) That
noe Common Brewer or Brewers shall be sued or prosecuted for any Penalty or Forfeiture by (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) or them incurred for
or by reason of any Misentry or short Entry if he or they shall within one Weeke after the delivery of the
Copy of the Gaugers Returne made on him certifie his or their Entry made for the Weeke for which such Copy
of the Returne is delivered according to such Returne for each respective Charge or Brewing or otherwise discharging
himselfe Bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That noe Brewer or Brewers shall from henceforth have or claime
any benefitt by the said Provisoe on any Information to be brought against him or them for Non Entry wilfull
false Entry or Non-payment If it shall appeare by the Evidence given that such Brewer soe sued for Non Entry
or short or false Entry or Non-payment did not (bona fide) shew to the Gauger or Gaugers appointed to take
account of the Beere or Ale by them brewed all the Beere Ale and Worts of each respective Guile for such
time for which such Copy of the Returne was made or given, Or if any apparent Fraud was acted or made
to defraud their Majestyes of their Duty for any part of the Drinke brewed in the time for which such Copy
of the Returne is made or given by the Gauger in such case such Brewer shall incurr all the Penalties and
Forfeitures by the former Acts provided or inflicted The said Provisoe or any thing in any Acts or Statute relateing
to the Excise in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Brewer, &amp;c. having concealed Storehouse, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Penalty, &pound;50.; Mixing, concealing, &amp;c. Worts, Penalty 20s. a Barrel.; Commissioners of Excise, &amp;c. may give Judgment of Penalties</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And for avoiding some Doubts that have arisen It is hereby declared and enacted by the authority aforesaid
That every Common Brewer Inn-keeper Victualler or Retailer of Beere or Ale who contrary to the said Act made
in the said fifteenth yeare of the Raigne of the late King Charles the Second shall make use of any private or
concealed Storehouse Celler or place for the laying of any Beere or Ale or Worts in Caske shall forfeit the Summe
of fifty pounds for every such Offence And every such Brewer Inn-keeper Victualler or Retailer who contrary to the
said Act made as aforesaid shall mix conceale or convey away any Worts shall forfeit twenty shillings for every
Barrell of Worts by him or them soe mingled concealed or conveyed away contrary to the said Act And the
Commissioners of Excise and Justices of the Peace and all others authorized to heare and determine Forfeitures
and Offences against the Laws relateing to the Excise respectively on Complaints or Informations brought for these
Offences or either of them and duely proved before them are hereby authorized to give Judgement or Sentence for
the respective Forfeitures accordingly any Ommission or not repeating of the said Offences or either of them in and
by the said Act notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Gaugers to leave Notes of their Gauges with Brewers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Penalty, 40s.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p20">And to the end Common Brewers and other persons paying the Duty of Excise may not be overcharged It is
hereby declared and enacted That true Notes in Writeing of the last Gauges made or taken by the said Gaugers
shall be left by them with all Brewers Makers or Retailers of Beere Ale or other exciseable Liquors respectively or
some of their Servants at the times of their takeing their said Gauges containing the quantity and quality of the
Liquors soe gauged upon penalty of forty shillings for every Offence or Neglect of the said Gauger or Gaugers</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. By whom and how Complaints of Overcharge returned may be determined.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Witnesses examined on Oath</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And it is hereby enacted That the Commissioners of Excise or Appeales or Justices of Peace within whose
Jurisdiction respectively any such Brewer Maker or Retailer shall inhabite or dwell upon Complaint to them made
by or on the behalfe of such Brewers Makers or Retailers of any Overcharge returned upon them by any of the
said Gaugers shall and are required to heare and determine all such Complaints and examine the Witnesses upon
Oath which shall be produced as well on the behalfe of the partie makeing such Complaint as on the behalfe of all
and every other party and parties (which Oath they have hereby power to administer) and thereupon or by other
due proofe to discharge or acquitt such Brewer Maker or Retailer of soe much of his and their respective Charges
as shall be soe made out before them any thing in this or in any former Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Offices for Duties, &amp;c. for Anglesey.</head>
			<para id="p23">And whereas there is but one Market Towne in the County of Anglesey by reason of which the Inhabitants of
some parts of the said County are putt to extraordinary trouble and expence to make their Entryes and Payments being
foure and twenty miles distant from the said Market Towne Bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That for
the ease of the said Inhabitants liveing remote from the said Market Towne there shall be Offices kept for the
makeing Entries and Payments in the severall Townes of Holyhead Newborough and Llanerchthmeth as well as in
the Towne of Beaumaris where onely the said Office has beene accustomed to be kept</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Commissioner or Officer of Excise taking Money of any Person but the King.</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And whereas severall Collectors Surveyors Gaugers and other persons imployed about collecting surveying or
gauging the Duty of Excise have beene forced to pay severall summs of money to the Commissioners of Excise
or their Registers or Clerks [upon<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] pretence that the same is for writeing signing and sealeing Instructions or Orders
for every such Officer to execute his place which must cause such Officer to reimburse himselfe upon the People
by one meanes or other For prevention whereof Bee it enacted That noe Commissioner or [other<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] person imployed
about the Duty of Excise shall demand take or receive any summe of money or other reward whatsoever from
any person other then their Majestyes upon paine of forfeiting his or their Office upon proofe thereof by two or
more credible Witnesses before any two of their Majesties Justices of the Peace soe as every such person soe
offending is hereby made uncapable of executeing any Office in their Majesties Revenue of the Excise for the future</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Information against Brewer, &amp;c. to be within Three Months after Offence, and Notice within a Week after laying Information.</head>
			<para id="p26">Provided alsoe That noe Information shall be brought laid or prosecuted against any Common Brewer or
Brewers or Alehousekeeper for any false or misentry or Offence made or committed from and after the foure
and twentyeth day of July one thousand six hundred eighty and nine unlesse the same Information or Informations
be laid and entred before such persons appointed to determine the same within three months next after every such
Offence committed and that notice thereof be given to such person or persons (against whome such Information
shall be laid) in writeing or left at their Dwelling Houses within one Weeke after the laying and entring such
Information to the end a timely provision may be had and made in defending the same any thing in this Act or
other Law to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Using Molossus or other Compositions in brewing.</head>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">Penalty, Forfeiture of Liquors and &pound;100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p28">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That from and after the first of September one thousand
six hundred eighty nine noe Common Brewer or Retailer of Beere or Ale shall use in the brewing or working of
any Beere or Ale any Molossus Course Sugar Honey or Composition or Extract of Sugar upon the penaltie of the
Forfeiture for every such Offence of all such Liquors wherein any Molossus or Course Sugar Hony or such
Composition or Extract shall be putt and alsoe of the Summe of one hundred pounds one moyety of all the said
Forfeiture to be to their Majesties the other moyety to the Informer to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint
or Information in any of their Majesties Courts of Record wherein no Essoigne Wager of Law or any more then
one Imparlance shall shall be allowed soe as such Suite be commenced within six months after such Forfeiture
incurred</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Exporter of Corn from Berwick to have the Advantage of c. 12. ante.</head>
			<para id="p29">And bee it further enacted That when Mault or Barley of English Growth Winchester Measure shall be at
foure and twenty shillings by the Quarter or under Rye of English Growth at two and thirty shillings by the
Quarter or under and Wheate of English Growth at eight and forty shillings by the Quarter or under in the
Towne or Port of Berwicke upon Tweede every Merchant or other person who shall putt on Shipboard in English
Shipping the Master and two thirds of his Marriners at least being their Majestyes Subjects any sorts of the Corne
aforesaid from the said Port or Towne of Berwicke with intent to export the said Corne into parts beyond the
Seas and shall pursue all and every the Methods and Things prescribed and appointed in that behalfe in and by
an Act made in this present Session of Parliament Entituled An Act for Encourageing the Exportation of Corne
shall have the benefitt and advantage of the said Act and of every thing therein contained as fully to all intents
and purposes as if the said Corne had beene put on Shipboard from any Port or Ports of this Kingdome or
Dominion of Wales</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Shipping Scotch Corn at Berwick.</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Penalty, Forfeiture of the Corn</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted That if any Merchant or other person whatsoever shall putt on Shipboard
any Corne of the growth of Scotland out of the said Port of Berwicke upon Tweede That all such Corne shall be
forfeited (that is to say) one third part to their Majesties one other third part to the Informer and the other
third part to the Poore of the said Towne of Berwicke.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Excise <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">lesse <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">him <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">under <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

