<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46315" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIX. An Act for Reliefe of the Protestant Irish Clergy. [Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Promotion of an Irish Clergyman in England shall not prejudice him in Ireland.; The Continuance of the Act</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">The King and Queene by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
Commons in Parlyament assembled doe hereby enact And bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That noe
Ecclesiasticall person of what dignity or degree soever promoted or beneficed in the Kingdome of Ireland and who
hath beene enforced to forsake the said Kingdome or hath soe done for feare of the Irish Rebells and being of
the Protestant Religion who are or shall be presented promoted collated instituted or inducted to any Church or
Benefice with Cure or without Cure or to any Ecclesiasticall Promotion whatsoever in the Kingdome of England
shall thereby or by acceptance thereof lose any Ecclesiasticall Benefice or Promotion in the said Kingdome of
Ireland but that he and every of them be continued and enabled still to hold and enjoy his Benefice and Promotion
in the said Kingdome of Ireland of what Dignity or Degree soever the same was any Law Statute or Canon
notwithstanding This Statute to be in force till that such person preferred in England may and shall be restored
to such his Promotion or Benefice in Ireland soe as he may take and enjoy the same as before the time of the
Troubles he might have done</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. How and within what Time he must make his Claim in Ireland, and resign his Promotions in England.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">If not made Presentation void, and Patron may present again</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes and bee (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) further it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That if any such Ecclesiasticall person
or persons soe presented promoted or collated or to be presented promoted or collated to any Benefice or other
Ecclesiasticall Preferment or Dignitie within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede shall not within three Calendar Months after the Courts of Justice in Ireland shall be open and
furnished with Protestant Judges soe as he may enjoy his or their Benefices Ecclesiasticall Promotions or Dignities
there resigne all such Benefices or other Ecclesiasticall Preferrments to which he shall be presented collated or
promoted within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweede as aforesaid
into the Hands of the Ordinary who is hereby required to accept of the same and thereof to give notice to the
respective Patrons for the time being to the intent such Patron for the time being may present or collate de
Novo That then the same shall be void to all intents and purposes whatsoever and in such case the Patron for
the time being shall and may if he thinke fitt present or collate againe</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Exemption from First-fruits.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it alsoe enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That such Ecclesiasticall person or persons soe presented
collated or promoted to any Benefice or other Ecclesiasticall Dignitie or Promotion within the Kingdome of
England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede as aforesaid shall be exempted from all manner
of First fruits and Tenths which may become due any Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">it <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


