<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46311" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>An Act to Regulate the Administrac[i]on of the Oathes required to be taken by Commission or Warrant Officers imployed in their Majestyes Service by Land by Vertue of an Act made this present Session of Parliament Entituled An Act for the Abrogating of the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance and appointing other Oaths. [Chapter XXV. Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Cap. 8. &sect; 10. ante, recited..; Commission Officers more than Twenty Miles from London, how to take the Oaths.; Refusing to take the Oath,; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act made in this present Session of Parliament Entituled An Act for the Abrogating of
the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance and appointing other Oaths all persons that shall hereafter be putt
into any Military Employment shall be obliged to take the Oaths and make and subscribe the Declaration therein
mentioned before such person as shall issue the Commission or Warrant for such Employment And whereas their
Majestyes Service does require the Regiments and Troops of Soldiers to march and be at great distances from
London and upon any Vacancy of any such Military Employment by death or otherwise tis necessary to fill up
such Vacancies by granting new Commissions for persons that may be at a great distance from London soe as
their Majestyes Service will not permitt them to repaire to London to take the said Oaths and make the said
Declaration as aforesaid Bee it enacted by the King and Queen's most excellent Majesties by and with the advice
and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and
by the authoritie of the same That if any Commission for such Military Employment shall hereafter be granted
to any person at any distance from London exceeding twenty miles that such person shall and may take the said
Oaths and make and subscribe the said Declaration at the next Muster after the receipt of the said Commission
before the Commissary of the Musters or his Deputy who is hereby authorized to tender administer and take the
same and are hereby required to send up a Certificate thereof under his Hand and Seale to the person who issued
such Commission any thing in the aforesaid Act to the contrary notwithstanding. And in case such person who shall
recieve such Commission shall refuse to take the said Oaths and subscribe the said Declaration as aforesaid such
person shall not be allowed upon the Musters but his Commission shall be void to all intents and purposes
whatsoever</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Militia and Trained Bands.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted That nothing in this Act contained shall extend to the Militia or Trained
Bands of England.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

