<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46313" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXVII. An Act for takeing away the Court holden before the President and Councill of the Marches of Wales. Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 7.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">34 &amp; 35 H. VIII. c. 26. &sect; 4.; Proceedings of the Court of Marches, a Grievance.; 34 &amp; 35 H. VIII. c. 26. &sect; 4. repealed, and the Court of Marches taken away</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by the Statute made in the thirty fourth and thirty fifth yeare of King Henry the Eighth
Intituled An Act for certaine Ordinances in the Kings Majestyes Dominion and Principality of Wales It
is enacted That there shall be and remaine a President and Councill in the said Dominion and Principality of
Wales and the Marches of the same with all Officers Clerks and Incidents to the same in manner and forme as
hath beene heretofore used and accustomed which President and Councill shall have power and authoritie to heare
and determine by their wisdomes and discretions such Causes and Matters as be or hereafter shall be assigned
to them by the Kings Majestie as heretofore hath beene accustomed and used And forasmuch as the Proceedings
and Decrees of that Court have by Experience beene found to be an intolerable burthen to the Subject within
the said Principality contrary to the great Charter the knowne Lawes of the Land and the Birthright of the
Subject and the meanes to introduce an Arbitrary Power and Government And forasmuch as all Matters
examinable or determinable or pretended to be examinable or determinable before the said Court of President and
Councill may have their proper Redresse in the ordinary course of Justice provided and setled in the severall
Shires within the said Principality and Dominion For Remedy whereof Bee it enacted by the King and Queens
most excellent Majestyes and by the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament
assembled and by the authoritie of the same That the before recited Clause in the said Statute made in the
thirty fourth and thirty fifth yeare of King Henry the Eighth shall be and is hereby repealed And that the said
Court commonly called the Court before the President and Councill in the Marches of Wales and all Jurisdiction
Power and Authority belonging unto or exercised in the same Court or by any the Judges Officers or Ministers
thereof be clearly and absolutely dissolved taken away and determined</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Sheriffs in Wales how chosen.</head>
			<para id="p3">And bee it hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Justices of the great Sessions in Wales
respectively for the time being shall yearely nominate three substantiall persons for each Shire in their respective
Circuits to be Shiriffes of the same and shall certifie their Names to the Lords of the most honourable Privy
Councill Crastino Animarum to the intent the King and Queen's Majestie and the Survivor of them and their
Successors being thereof advertised may appoint one of the persons soe certified in every of the said Shires to be
Sheriffe for that yeare</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Errors in Pleas personal in Wales how redressed, 34 &amp; 35 H. VIII. c. 26. &sect; 113.</head>
			<para id="p4">And bee it farther enacted That all Errors in Pleas personall within the said Principality or Dominion of Wales
shall be redressed by Writt of Error in the same manner as Errors in Pleas reall and mixed are appointed to
be redressed by the said Statute made in the thirty fourth and thirty fifth yeare of King Henry the Eighth</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Commencement of this Act.</head>
			<para id="p5">[Provided alwayes That noe Judgements nor Decrees passed in the said Court before the first day of June one
thousand six hundred eighty nine shall be by this Act repealed or annulled but all and every of them shall
remaine in the same force and all Executions upon them in the same State in which they were before the makeing
of this Act any thing in this Act [contained<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to the contrary notwithstanding.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


