<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46316" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>An Act to Repeale the Statute made in the fifth yeare of King Henry the Fourth against [the] Multiplying GoldSilver. [Chapter XXX Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">5 H. IV. c.4.; Repealed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by a Statute made and enacted in the Parliament held in the fifth yeare of the Raigne of
King Henry the Fourth late King of England It was amongst other things enacted in these Words or to
this Effect namely That none from thenceforth should use to multiply Gold or Silver or use the Craft of
Multiplication and if any the same doe they should incurr the Paine of Felony And whereas since the makeing
of the said Statute diverse persons have by their Study Industry and Learning arrived to great Skill and Perfection
in the Art of Melting and Refineing of Metalls and otherwise improveing them and their Ores (which very much
abound within this Realme) and extracting Gold and Silver out of the same but dare not exercise their said
Skill within this Realme for feare of falling under the Penalty of the said Statute but exercise the said Art
in Forreigne parts to the great Losse and Detriment of this Realme Bee it therefore enacted by the King and
Queens most excellent Majestyes by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
Commons in this present Parliament assembled That from henceforth the aforesaid Branch Article or Sentence
contained in the said Act and every Word Matter and Thing contained in the said Branch or Sentence shall
be repealed annulled revoked and for ever made void any thing in the said Act to the contrary in any wise
whatsoever notwithstanding</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Conditions of Repeal.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That all the Gold and Silver that shall be
extracted by the aforesaid Art of Melting and Refineing of Metalls and otherwise improveing of them and their
Ores as before sett forth be from henceforth employed for noe other Use or Uses whatsoever but for the Increase
of Moneys and that the place hereby appointed for the Disposall thereof shall be their Majestyes Mint within
the Tower of London at which place they are to recieve the full and true value for their Gold and Silver soe
extracted from time to time according to the Assay and Finenes thereof and soe for any greater or lesser weight
And that none of that Metall of Gold and Silver soe refined and extracted be permitted to be used or disposed in
any other place or places within their Majestyes Kingdomes and Dominions</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. What Mine not adjudged a Royal Mine.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alsoe and bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That noe Mine of Copper Tin Iron or
Lead shall hereafter be adjudged reputed or taken to be a Royall Mine although Gold or Silver may be extracted out
of the same.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

