<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46317" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXI. An Additionall Act for the Appointing Commissioners for the Executing an Act of this present Parliament Entituled
An Act for a Grant to their Majestyes of an Ayde of Twelve Pence in the Pound for One Yeare for the necessary
Defence of their Realmes. [Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 11.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Cap. 20. ante recited, as to Appointment of Commissioners to execute that Act.; In divers Counties not sufficient qualified Persons resident.; Their Majesties enabled to appoint such Persons in Counties, Cities, &amp;c. to be Commissioners, as they shall find necessary.; Proviso, that such Persons be resident, and have Estates to the Value of &pound;1,000; and in such Case they are enabled to execute the said Act, as though they had Real Estates of &pound;100 per Ann</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in and by one Act of this present Parlyament Entituled An Act for a Grant to Their Majestyes of
an Aide of Twelve pence in the Pound for One Yeare for the necessary Defence of their Realms It is
(amongst other things) Enacted That it should and might be lawfull for Their Majestyes to issue out or cause to
be issued out under the Greate Seale of England such and soe many Commissions as Their Majestyes should think
fitt and therein and thereby to Nominate Constitute and Appoint such and soe many Persons being Resident and
haveing Reall Estates to the value of One hundred pounds a yeare in the respective Counties or Shires for which
they should be soe Nominated to be Commissioners for putting the said Act in Execution and alsoe soe many of
them to be of the Quorum as Their Majesties should thinke convenient for the Execution of the said Act Which
said Commissioners soe as aforesaid to be Nominated and Appointed should in the respective Countyes Cities
Burroughs Divisions Townes and Places for which they should be Appointed Commissioners respectively meete
together and should execute and performe severall Powers Authorities and Directions in and by the said Act given
and Appointed. And whereas it falleth out That in diverse of the Counties Cities Burroughs Divisions Townes
and Places for which Com[m]issioners are to be Nominated and Appointed there are not a sufficient Number of Persons
resident and haveing Reall Estates to the value of a hundred Pounds a Yeare and that are apt and able to putt
the said Act in Execution whereupon Doubt and Question hath arisen whether or how the said Act may be
executed in such places Therefore for certaine Declaration and Supply of the Law in this behalfe Bee it Enacted
by the King and Queens most Excellent Majesties by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons in Parlyament Assembled and by Authoritie of the same That it shall and may be
Lawfull for Their Majestyes in and by their Commissions to be issued out under the Great Seale of England to
Nominate Constitute and Appoint such and soe many other Persons to be Commissioners for putting the said Act
in Execution in the respective Counties Cityes Burroughs Divisions Townes and Places as Their Majesties shall finde
to be necessary Provided that they be Persons resident within the said respective Places and that they have Estates
of the value of One thousand pounds And that the said Persons soe Nominated Constituted and Appointed shall
be Commissioners in like manner and shall have and execute the same Powers and Authorities Rules and Directions
for the Assessing Ordering Levying and Collecting of the severall Sums of Money Limitted and Appointed to be
paid by the said recited Act And for the effectuall putting the same in Execution as if they had Reall Estates
to the value of One hundred Pounds a Yeare according to the said Act.</para>
	</section>
</report>


