<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46321" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for a Grant to Their Majestyes of an Ayd of Two shillings in the Pound for One Yeare. [Rot. Parl. pt. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>The Reasons for granting the King and Queen a Subsidy.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Grant to the King and Queen of 2s. in the Pound on Personal Estate for One Year, on the Yearly Value</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee Your Majestyes most Dutyfull and Loyall Subjects the Commons in Parlyament assembled haveing entred
into a Serious Consideration of the Extraordinary Occasions which Engage Your Majestyes into a great
and present Expence for the necessary Defence of Your Realmes for the Reduceing of Ireland and for the Vigorous
Prosecution of the Warr against France both by Sea and Land and being desireous to Raise proportionable Aids and
Supplyes Doe humbly Present Your Majestyes with the Free Gift of the Rates and Assessments herein after mentioned
And beseech Your Majestyes That it may be Enacted And bee it Enacted by the King and Queenes most
Excellent Majestyes by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons
in this present Parliament Assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That Their Majestyes shall have and
receive the Rates and Assessments hereafter mentioned of and from every Person Spirituall and Temporall of what
Estate or Degree soever he or they be Which said Rates or Assessments shall be Taxed Assessed Levyed and
Paid into Their Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer according to the Tenor of this Act and in Manner and Forme
following (That is to say) That all and every Person and Persons Bodies Politique and Corporate Guilds and
Fraternities within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede haveing
any Estate in ready Moneys or in any Debts whatsoever oweing to them within this Realme or without or haveing
any Estate in Goods Wares Merchandizes or other Chattells or Personall Estate whatsoever within this Realme
or without belonging to or in trust for them (except and out of the Premisses deducted such Summes of Money
as he or they doe bona fide owe and such Debts as shall be adjudged desperate by the Commissioners appointed
by this Act And alsoe the Stocke upon Lands and such Goods as are used for Housholdstuffe) shall Yield and
Pay unto Their Majestyes Two Shillings in the Pound according to the true Yearely Value thereof for One Yeare
(That is to say) For every Hundred pound of such ready Money and Debts and for every Hundred pounds
worth of such Goods Wares Merchandizes or other Chattells or Personall Estate the Summe of Twelve Shillings
And soe after that rate for every greater or lesser Summe or Quantity to be Assessed Levyed and Collected in
manner hereafter mentioned.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Public Officers (Military and Navy Officers in Muster or Pay excepted,) and their Clerks, &amp;c. to pay 28. in the Pound on Fees or Profits.</head>
			<para id="p3">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons Commissioner
or Commissioners Haveing Useing or Exerciseing any Publicke Office or Imployment of Profitt (such Military
Officers who are or shall be in Muster or Pay in Their Majestyes Army or Navy onely Excepted) And all and
every their Agents Clerks Secondaries Substitutes and other Inferior Ministers whatsoever shall Yield and Pay unto
Their Majestyes the Summe of Two Shillings for every Twenty Shillings which he or they doe Receive in One
Yeare by vertue of any Fees or Profits to him or them accrueing for or by reason or occasion of their severall
Offices or Imployments to be Assessed Imposed Levyed and Collected in such manner as hereafter is
mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Manors, &amp;c. to pay 2s. in the Pound for One Year.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Persons, Bodies Politic and Corporate, Guilds, &amp;c. Corporate or not Corporate, holding Lands, &amp;c. to pay 2s. in the Pound at their full present yearly Value at a Rack Rent; without Respect to former Rates, or Allowance for Repairs, &amp;c.; Assessment paid Quarterly into the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And to the end a further Aide and Supplie for Their Majestyes Occasions may be Raised by a Charge upon
all Lands Tenements and Hereditaments with as much Equality and Indifferencie as is possible by a Pound-Rate of
Two Shillings for every Twenty Shillings of the true Yearely Value for One Yeare onely and noe longer Bee it
further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every Mannours Messuages Lands and Tenements as alsoe
all Quarries Mines of Coale Tin or Lead Iron Works Salt-Springs and Salt Works all Allom Mines or Works All
Parks Chases Warrens Woods Underwoods Coppices and all Fishings Tythes Tolls Annuities and all other yearely
Profitts and all Hereditaments of what Nature or Kinde soever they be Scituate Lying Being Happening or Ariseing
within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede or within any the
Counties Cities Burroughs Townes Divisions Rideings Hundreds Lathes Wapentakes Parishes and Places thereof as
well within Auntient Demesne and other Liberties and Priviledged Places as without shall be and are hereby
Charged for One Yeare onely and noe longer with the Summe of Two shillings for every Twenty shillings of the
full yearely Value and soe in proportion for any greater or lesser Value And all and every Person and Persons
Bodies Politick and Corporate Guilds Misteries Fraternities and Brotherhoods whether Corporate or not Corporate
Haveing or Holding any Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments or other the Premisses shall yield and
pay unto Their Majesties the Summe of Two shillings for every Twenty shillings by the yeare which the said
Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and other the Premisses are now worth to be Leased if the
same were truely and bona fide Leased or Demised at a Racke Rent and according to the full true Yearely
Value thereof without any respect had to the present Rents reserved for the same if such Rents have beene
reserved upon such Leases or Estates made for which any Fine or Income hath beane paid or secured or have
beene lessened or abated upon Consideration of Money laid out or to be laid out in Improvements And without
any respect had to any former Rates or Taxes thereupon Imposed or makeing any Abatement in respect of
Reparations Taxes Parish Dutyes or any other Charges whatsoever Which said Summe of Two shillings for every
Twenty shillings by the Yeare of the said true yearely value of the Premisses shall be Assessed Levyed and
Collected in manner hereafter mentioned and shall be paid into the Receipt of Their Majestyes Exchequer by
Foure Quarterly Payments The first Payment thereof to be made upon the Five and Twentyeth day of March
which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and ninety.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Landlords may retain the Assessment for Fee Farm and other Annual Rents charged on Lands, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Persons intitled to such Rents, are to allow such Deductions</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And whereas many of the Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Tithes Hereditaments or Premisses intended
by this Act to be Charged with the Pound-Rate as aforesaid stand incumbred with or are subject and lyable
to the Payment of severall Rent Charges or Annuities issueing out of the same or to the Payment of diverse
Fee-Farme-Rents Rent-Service or other Rents thereupon Reserved or Charged by reason whereof the true Owners
and Proprietors of such Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses doe not in truth
Receive to their owne use the true yearely value of the same for which neverthelesse they are by this Act Charged to
pay the full Pound Rate of Two shillings for every Twenty shillings of the true yearely value It is therefore Declared
and Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Landlords Owners and
Proprietors of such Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses as are Charged with
the Pound Rate as aforesaid to abate and deduct and to retaine and keepe in his or their Hands Two shillings in
the Pound for every Fee-farme Rent and other Annuall Rent or Payment Charged upon or Issueing out of the
p[re]misses or any part thereof or thereupon Reserved And all and every Person and Persons who are or shall be
any way Intitled to such Rents and Annuall Payments are hereby required to allow such Deductions and Payments
upon the Receipt of the residue of such Moneys as shall be due and payable to them for such Rents or Annuall
Payments Reserved or Charged as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Commissioners appointed.</head>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That for the better Assessing Ordering Levying and
Collecting of the severall Summes of Money soe as aforesaid limitted and appointed to be Paid and for the more
effectuall putting of this present Act in Execution all and every the Persons hereafter named shall be Commissioners
of and for the severall and respective Counties Cities Burroughes Townes and Places hereafter mentioned.</para>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>Names of the Commissioners.</head>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>For the County of Bedford</head>
			<para id="p9">The Honourable Edward Russell the Honourable Robert Russell the Honourable Robert Bruce the Honourable
Charles Leigh Esquires Sir William Gostwicke Sir John Napier Sir John Cotton Sir John Burgoyne Sir Rowland
Alston Sir Villiers Charnocke Sir John Osborne Baronets Sir William Becher Sir Francis Wingate Sir William
Francklin Sir John Mordant Sir John Francklin Sir James Astree Masters in Chancery Knights William Duncomb
Oliver Luke William Boteler Lewis Moneux Thomas Browne Benjamin Conquest Samuell Cater Thomas Hillersden
John Osborne William Farrer senior William Foster Thomas Cheyne William Palmer Richard Stone Edward Stone
John Vaux George Abbott John Cockayne Nicholas Spencer Richard Edwards Brooke Bridges John Delafontaine
George Edwards Thomas Bromsall Ralph Bromsall Walter Carey Robert Mountague Gaines Squier Henry Astley
junior Humphry Fish Charles Gery William Farrer junior Samuell Bedford Robert Audley William Daniell St John
Thompson Richard Orlebar of Harrold John Harvey of Thurley Thomas Cristie Mathew Denis Thomas Halfpeny
Samuell Rhodes William Livesay John Wagstaffe William Simcotts Nicholas Granger William Whitebread Richard
Orlebar of Hinwick John Davis William Boteler of Wootton Esquires William Crow George Nodes Gentlemen
Thomas Palmer Doctor of Physicke George Cobb, Gentleman Brandrife Samuell Ironside Esquires.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>For the Towne of Bedford</head>
			<para id="p10">William Becket Mayor Thomas Hillersden Esquire William Foster Doctor of Lawes Thomas Christie Esquire
John Beaumont Thomas Margetts John Hawes William Manley William Faldoe senior John Crawley and William
Bamforth Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>For the County of Berks</head>
			<para id="p11">The Right Honourable Henry Powle Esquire one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill and Speaker
of the House of Commons Henry Earle of Sterling in the Kingdome of Scotland Mountague Lord Norris Sir
Humphry Foster Sir John Stonehouse Sir Thomas Draper Sir William Rich Sir Henry Winchcombe Sir Thomas
Clarges Sir Edmond Fettiplace Sir John Hobby Sir Anthony Craven Sir Henry Henn Sir Willoughby Aston Sir
William Kendrick Sir Edward Read Baronets Sir Henry Fane Knight of the Bath Sir Robert Pye Sir Algernoon
May Sir Edward Norris Sir Christopher Wrenn Sir William Whitlocke Sir Jonathan Raymond Sir Thomas Dolman
Sir Jemmett Raymond Knights John Blandy Henry Barker Henry Nevile John Archer Richard Nevile Richard Aldworth
William Cherry Edmond Fettiplace Tanfield Vachell Edmond Pye Henry Kingsmill James Stonehouse Charles Garrard
John Blagrave Loftes Brightwell Paul Calton Henry Fairefax James Paul Charles Fettiplace Thomas Pettit Paul Calton
junior John Hippesly Samuell Whitlocke Richard Pye Thomas Fettiplace James Perrot Edmond Wiseman Henry
Heyling Roger Draper Thomas Medlicot John Hobby Simon Harcourt John Whitfield John Hayes Edward Sherwood
Richard Southby John Southby Thomas Southby Thomas Lee Francis Wight John Wightwick Thomas Dolman Thomas
Seymour Thomas Tipping Roger Knight John Topham Richard Jennens William Jennens Robert Mayott John
Verney John Wildman Senior John Wildman Junior Richard Brickenden Alexander Blagrave Arthur Anslow
Thomas Garrard Thomas Harwood Henry Battin Thomas Hoard Nathan Knight Bartholomew Tipping John Fincher
Phillip Weston John Edmonds Robert Leigh George Blagrave John Deane Bolton James John Peacock John Jennens
of Stanford John Dew John Dalby Richard Knapp John Loder Thomas Loder John Pottinger of Sadbury Sebastian
Lyford Edward Read Edward Lovedon Thomas Read Thomas Brompsteed Richard Palmer Francis Parry Richard
Stephens Esquires Moses Bruch Doctor in Physicke Ralph Howland Esquire John Bigg Moses Slade Charles
Calverley Thomas Stephens Edward Brackstone George Lamport Robert Selwood Thomas Barker Richard
Fishborne Henry Peacocke Thomas Harrison Thomas Edmonds Richard Cooper Thomas Cowslade Silas Sebroe Giles
Pocock Charles Peacocke John Tomkins John Pocock of Streatley and Richard Mathews Gentlemen the Mayor
of Reading the Mayor of Newberry the Mayor of Windsor the Mayor of Abingdon the Mayor of Wallingford
the Alderman of Ockingham.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>For the Burrough of New Windsor</head>
			<para id="p12">The Right Honourable Henry Powle Esquire one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill and Speaker
of the House of Commons the Mayor for the time being Sir Algernoon May Knight John Topham Esquire
Moses Brooch Doctor of Physicke Fishburne Gen[um] Silas Seaborough Alderman Thomas Staples
Steward.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>For the County of Bucks</head>
			<para id="p13">Anthony Lord Faulkland Richard Lord Wenman Thomas Wharton Esquire Richard Hambden Esquire Henry
Bertie Esquire Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir Thomas Tyrrell Sir Walter Clarges
Sir Anthony Chester Sir Richard Adkins Sir Thomas Proby Sir William Bowyer Sir Ralph Verney Sir William
Drake Sir Henry Andrews Sir Thomas Lee Sir William Dormer Sir Joseph Alston Sir Dennis Hampson Sir
Peter Tyrrell Baronets Sir Robert Gayer Knight of the Bath Sir Robert Clayton Sir Thomas Clarges Sir Roger
[Hill<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Sir Peter Apsley Sir John Tompson Sir Marmaduke Dayrell Sir James Etheredge Sir Purbecke Temple
Knights John Thurbarne Sergeant at Law William Jephson Thomas Lee John Hampden Edmond Waller Richard
Beke William Penn Thomas Hacket Alexander Denton Arthur Warren Thomas Piggott John Eddowes Joseph
Haynes Ralph Lawton Francis Duncomb of Broughton Owen Norton John Parkhurst Thomas Lewes senior
Thomas Lewes junior Robert Lovett Thomas Barringer John Backwell Edmond Umphreville Knightley Purefoy
Roger Price John Whiterong Richard Greenville Bud Wayes Basill Brent Edmond Verney Richard Atkins Charles
Stafford Richard Ingolsby Christopher Egleton Thomas Egleton Robert Dormer Edmond Waller of Gregories
Edward Nicholas Nicholas Salter William Fleetwood Robert Stiles Edmond Dorrell Henry Neale William Farrer
Thomas Farrer senior Thomas Farrer junior Simon Mayne Robert Dormer of Lee John Tyrringham William Busby
John Duncomb of Great Brickhill Henry Herbert James Herbert John Shalcrosse George Evelin Joseph Haynes Henry
Sumner senior Henry Sumner junior John Archdale John Topham Thomas Carter of Weston Charles Tyrrell
James Tyrrell Edward Bates Thomas Ligoe Thomas Beard Edward Baldwin Richard Meade Robert Hart William
Crooke John Chase James Chase Henry Cave senior Henry Cave junior Richard Dorrell Stephen Chase senior
Bartholomew Beale Henry Berry Benjamine Lane Richard Nicholls Esquires William Hill senior William Hill junior
John Grubb Richard Smith Thomas Smith of Beaconsfield Henry Harris Robert Gaynsford Hugh Horton Richard
Whitechurch Henry Gold Francis Duncomb Roger Chapman Thomas Chapman Christy Paul Dorrell
Mathew Butterfield John Gibbons Robert Weedon Richard Baldwin William Cleaver Thomas Gibson Timothy Doyley
John Sparkes Richard Barnaby senior George Alnot William Johnson of Oulney Thomas Corter John Theed John
Seare Thomas Hudson Henry Cooley Gentlemen John Tanner Doctor of Physicke.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>For the Towne of Buckingham</head>
			<para id="p14">The Bayliffe for the time being Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir Ralph Verney Knight
and Baronet Alexander Denton Edward Andrews Edmond Dorrell Esquires Hugh Ethersay George Dancer William
Hartley John Rogers Pelham Sandwell Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>For the Towne of Chipping Wycombe.</head>
			<para id="p15">The Mayor Recorder Aldermen Bayliffes and Towne Clerke for the time being William Jephson Esquire and Thomas
Lewes Esq[uire].</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>For the County of Cambridge</head>
			<para id="p16">The Right Honourable Richard Lord Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland Edward Russell Esquire one of his
Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Sir Thomas Chicheley Knight Sir Christopher Hatton Sir John Cotton
Sir Thomas Willis Sir Levinns Bennet Sir Rushout Cullen Sir John Cutler Baronets Sir Robert Cotton Sir
Marmaduke Dayrell Knights John Willis John Bennet John Cutts Devereux Martin Phillip Cotton William Russell
Granado Pigott Edward Nightingale Samuell Clerke John Millescent Samuell Fortery Thomas Ducket John Hagar
William Layer senior Thomas Story Edward Leeds Thomas Archer Gilbert Wigmore Anthony Thompson William
Layer junior Charles Baron [Thomas Daye<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Thomas Bucke Tyrell Dalton Esquires Robert Flacke Robert Baron
Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>For the University and Towne of Cambridge</head>
			<para id="p17">The Vicechancellor the Mayor for the time being Sir Thomas Chichely Knight Sir John Cotton Baronet Sir
Robert Sawyer Knight the Honourable John Mountague Doctor of Divinity Joseph Beaumont George Chamberlaine
John Covell Thomas Smolt Thomas Bainbridge Doctors of Divinity George Oxenden William Cooke
Roderick Doctors of the Civill Law Isaac Newton Andrew Pern Esquires Samuell Newton Thomas Story Isaac
Watlington John Ewen Thomas Fowles Fox Aldermen Robert Drake Gent[um].</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>For the Isle of Ely</head>
			<para id="p18">The Right Honourable Richard Lord Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland Doctor Spencer Deane of Ely Sir
Sewster Payton Baronet Sir Lyonell Walden Sir William Wren Knights William Cooke William Balaam Henry
Hitch Doctors of Civill Law William Colvile Thomas Edwards Roger Jennings Sigismond Trafford Thomas Wiseman
Everade Buckworth Lawrence Hewer alias Oxborough William March John Pamplin Henry Goodrick Esquires
Samuell Forteray Malborne Caryll John Twelves Ralph Peirson Thomas Towers Esquires Robert Drake Michaell
Beale Gentlemen Robert Swaine Richard Reade Harrison Roger Jennings junior Esquires Richard
Russell Thomas Benyon Richard Peachy Gen[um].</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>For the County of Chester</head>
			<para id="p19">Richard Lord Viscount Colchester Sonne and Heire Apparent to Thomas Earle Rivers Charles Lord Brandon
Sonne and Heire Apparent of Charles Earle of Maclesfield Mountague Lord Norris Sonne and Heire Apparent of
James Earl of Abingdon Thomas Needham Esquire Sir Thomas Wilbraham Sir Thomas Delves Sir Willoughby
Aston Sir Thomas Powell Sir Peter Warburton Sir William Drake Sir John Mainwaring Baronets Sir Robert
Cotton Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Bellott Sir Richard Brookes Sir Roger Puleston Sir Robert Duckenfield
Sir John Worden Baronets Sir John Crew Sir John Trevor Sir Joshua Allen Knights Thomas Delves Thomas
Leigh of Adlington Nathaniell Booth Peter Leigh of Lyme William Lawton of Lawton Roger Whitley John
Warren Peter Leigh of Booths George Booth George Vernon Richard Lister Thomas Lee of Dernhall Roger
Wilbraham Thomas Daniell Richard Leigh Augustine Leigh Thomas Whitley John Lawton Thomas Aldersey
Thomas Masterson Samuell Davenport John Brewen Will[ia]m Glegg of Gayton Charles Hurleston Roger Manwaring
Thomas Swettenham Peter Brookes Robert Lee John Pickering Joseph Hockenhall William Whitmore William
Davenport of Bromhall John Davenport Samuell Hardaware Thomas Warburton Robert Warburton (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) Henry Bradshaw
of Marple William Minshull John Baskervile John Leech William Glegg of Grange Richard Wright of Namptwich
Lawrence Wright of Mobberley John Goldsmith John Dod of Highfields John Wright of Brewers Hall Richard
Minshull Thomas Cooper John Hardawere John Traverse Esquires.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>For the City and County of the City of Chester.</head>
			<para id="p20">The Mayor for the time being Sir William Williams Knight and Baronet Sir John Mainwareing Baronet George
Booth Roger Whitley (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) Esquires William Streete Richard Wright Henry Lloyd John Anderson George Mainwareing
Peter Edwards Aldermen Edward Wynne John Wright Thomas Cooper Richard Minshull Esquires The Sheriffes
for the time being Richard Bridge Thomas Hand Thomas Wright Robert Denteth Robert Murrey Michaell
Johnson and Timothy Deane Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>For the County of Cornwall</head>
			<para id="p21">Hugh Boscawen Esquire one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Bernard Greenvile Esq[uire] Francis
Robarts Esquire Sir Bourcher Wray Sir John Carew Sir Violl Vivian Sir John Coriton Sir William Godolphin
Sir Peter Killigrew Sir Nicholas Slanning Sir John St Aubin Sir William Morrice Sir John Moleswoorth Baronets
Sir Joseph Tredenham Sir Walter Moile Sir John Cotton Sir John Tremayne Knights Colonell Charles Trevanion
Collonell Charles Trelawney Collonell Henry Trelawney Samuell Rolle Collonell John Specket Daniell Elliott
Jonathan Rashleigh John Buller senior John Tanner John Prideaux Walter Kendall Joseph Sawle Thomas Darrell
Nicholas Glynn John Vivian senior John Vivian junior Francis Vivian Edward Herle John Connock Humphrey
Nicholl Arthur Fortescue Hugh Fortescue Humphrey Courteney Edward Ellyott William Mohun John Kendall
John Gregor James Kendall John Trerry James Erisey Francis Calmady Ambrose Manaton John Buller junior
James Prade William Painter John Bleith Charles Grills Richard Hoblin of Nanswiddon Richard Hoblin of
Antaron George Robinson William Bond William Keigwin Francis Painter John Polewheele Nicholas Kelliow
Emanuell Piper John Pendarves Alexander Pendarves John Waddon William Arscott William Harris Thomas
Achim Samuel Ennis John Vowell Anthony Chenowath Nathaniell Moyle Christopher Billett Alexander Carew
Samuell Langford Edward Lower Phillip Mayow John Barret of Kelligreene Thomas Penhallow Richard Williams
of Trewithen John Murth James Bond Francis Wills Joseph Moy Jonathan Trelawney George Spry Abell French
Hugh Jones Edward Kneebone Hugh Tonkin Henry Vincent Henry Manaton Francis Mannaton Shadrack Vincent
Walter Vincent Thomas Kelly John Courteney John Hicks of Trevithick Hugh Trevanion William Simmons
William Bleith Anthony Rous William Coriton James Kestle of Kestle Narcissus Lutterell John Ennis Edmond
Phillips Charles Trevanion John Hoblin John Nicolls of Trewane Peter Treviza Thomas Hawkey Henry Gregor
Richard Pendarves of Pendarves Richard Bonithon Charles Bonithon William Arundell of Manadarva Christopher
Barnes Sampson Hill John Barret of Penquite William Williams of Treworgy John Williams of Trethowa John
Williams [of Carvian<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] William Hooper Thomas Dotson John Clarke Edmond Spowra Richard Moile Esquires
Charles Kendall Rennall Bawdon Jacob Robbins Stephen Robbins Thomas Waddon John Foote of Truro William
Martin of Kilminarth William Braddon Rennall Hawky Gentlemen John Kestle of Kestle Esq[uire] Nicholas Kimp of
Treasteaga William Hancock of Hendra Nicholas Archer Thomas Herle John Cole William Keckwitch John
Pennocke Thomas Johnson John Keckwin Charles Huddy Joseph Marke Tho: Glynn William Cock of Helston
and William Tregey Gentlemen Charles Trevanion of Tregarthen Richard Harris Esquire William Yeo William Amye.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>For the County of Cumberland</head>
			<para id="p22">Charles Lord Morpeth Sonne and Heire Apparent to Edward Earle of Carlisle Sir Henry Capell one of His
Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Sir John Lowther Baronet one of His Majestyes most Honourable
Privy Councill Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir John Dalston Sir George Fletcher Sir John Lowther of Whitehaven
Sir Wilfrid Lawson Sir Richard Musgrave Baronets Sir John Ballentine Sir Daniell Fleming Knights Henry
Fletcher Wilfrid Lawson Joseph Hudleston Robert Carleton Thomas Lamplough Richard Lamplough Thomas
Denton Anthony Hutton Richard Patrickson Christopher Richmond Edward Hasell Miles Pennington Edward
Stanley William Gilpin Ewen Christian Darcy Curwen Leonard Dykes John Senhouse Andrew Hudleston Henry
Browham Jeremiah Bubb Henry Fletcher of Tallenfire John Punsonby Andrew Whelpdale Esquires John Briscow
John Foster James Maxwell Gentlemen The Mayor of Carlisle for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>For the County of Derby.</head>
			<para id="p23">The Honourable Anchitell Grey Esquire Sir Thomas Greassey Sir Edward Coke Sir Henry Every Sir Nathaniell
Curzon Sir Philip Gell Sir William Boothby Sir Paul Jenkinson Baronets Sir Simon Degg Sir Gilbert Clerke
Sir Edward Abney Knights Willoughby Gray John Stanhope Henry Henihgam Rowland Okeover Henry Gilbert
John Low of Denbigh Mathew Smith Walter Burdet Henry Keys John Osborne Esquires William Horne Edmond
Winter William Flamsted Gentlemen The Mayor of Derby for the time being John Brookehouse Solomon Robarts
Thomas Goodwin Aldermen Biron Stanhope Samuell Dolton John Adderley Esquires George Beardsley William
Turner John Gisborne Joseph Parker Samuell Goodwin Edmond Parker Gentlemen John Coke William Sacheverell
Henry Every Robert Wilmott Robert Harding Henry Kendall Gilbert Thacker Gilbert Munday John Wilkins
Samuell Holden Walter Horton William Allestrey George Grisly George Vernon Henry Cavendish Robert Coke
Godfrey Menell Samuell Pole Thomas Browne Thomas Bates Nicholas Wilmott John Burowes Esquires Robert
Doxy Gentleman John Berisford Thomas Milward John Lowe of Alderwasle Esquires John Stuffin Doctor Botham
William James Robert Haywood Robert Dale Benjamin Haywood William Wingfield Gentlemen John Shallcrosse
William Eyre Thomas Right Henry Gilbert junior John Bullock Henry Bolgay Paul Jodrell Esquires Benjamin
Ashton John Stafford John Berisford Richard Batemen John Right Gentlemen Edward Finney John Revell George
Sitwell Cornelius Clerke Robert Revell Robert Mowre John Morewood John Wigfoll Robert Ashton Thomas
Woolhouse Samuell Halloe Thomas Cotchett John Spateman Esquires Andrew Clayton John Frogatt George
Milward Josia Trott John Bagnall Christopher Ley Thomas Bagshaw John Smithson of Bolseover John Steventon
Thomas Burley Gentlemen The Mayor of Chesterfield for the time being Richard Youle Peter Dowker Richard
Cope Francis Hatsworth Aldermen Paul Webster Roger Coates Gentlemen Gervase Brough.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>For the County of Devon</head>
			<para id="p24">The Honourable Edward Russell the Honourable Robert Russell the Honourable John Greenvile Esquires Sir
John Mainard one of the Commissioners of the Great Seale Sir Edward Seymour Sir Peter Prideaux Sir Francis
Drake Sir Ames Pollard Sir Bourchier Wrey Sir Courtney Pole Sir Coplestone Bampfield Sir Francis Northcott
Sir William Courtenay Sir John Davie Sir Hugh Ackland Sir William Drake Sir John [Howell<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Sir William
Morice Sir Henry Carew Sir Walter Younge Sir Nicholas Slanning Sir Arthur Chichester Sir Peter Colleton
Baronets Sir John Rolle Knight of the Bath Sir William Bastard Sir George Treby Attourney Generall Sir
Thomas Berry Knights Sir Henry Fane Knight of the Bath George Chudleigh Francis Courtnay Samuell Rolle
Richard Duke Thomas Reynell Hugh Bampfield John Clobery Richard Coffin Richard Newte William Spurway
of Oakeford Humphrey Prideaux of Solden Esquires John Bidgood Doctor of Physicke [Sir<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Richard Reynell
Knight and Baronet Sir John Trevor Knight Henry Fortescue of Buckland Felley Dennis [Rolls<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] of Beame Nicholas
Dennis John Colwich Esquires Henry Stephens Gentleman Henry Manaton Gideon Haydon Hugh Vaughan Joseph
Herne Esquires Sir Simon Leech Knight of the Bath Richard Carew of Barley John Northcot of Westwood
Bampfield Rodd James Rodd Esquires William Langford of Braddon John Harris of Wortham John Symmonds
John Rowe Richard Courtney John Copleston John Bluet Rich: Beavis John Burrington John Fry of Yartie
Henry Woolecombe Thomas Wood Roger Woolcombe Christopher Savery Rowland Whiddon Courtney Crocker
Arscott Brickford Henry Chichester of Coxleigh John Garland Henry Chichester of Hall Martin Rider Charles
Hore John Elwill Richard Lee of Winslade William Coleman Samuell Foote Sebastian Isaacke Henry Walrond John
Chichester of Widworthy Jonathan Prideaux Arthur Ackland William Hayne John Battishill John Sandford
Jonathan Elford William Fowell William Bragg Sampson Hele Edmond Parker Thomas Drew William Cary of
Clovelly Arthur Champernoone Francis Bassett John Ashford John Gifford John Arscott of Tetcott Henry
Nortleigh Edward Yard of Churchton Edmond Walrond Arthur Tremaine Rawlin Mallocke Arthur Fortescue
William Harris of Hayne Richard Shapleigh Francis Bulford Edward Fortescue of Pridleston William Stawell
John Quicke Hugh Stafford Henry Trelawney John Pole Edmond Prideaux of Ford John Pollexfenne George
Prestwood John Kelland John Kelland junior George Parker Ambrose Manaton Peter Fortescue Thomas Beare
Josias Calmady Richard Nutcombe Esquires John Pratt Councellor at Law James Hewish of Sand Edmond
Walrond junior Thomas Sampson the Mayor of Plymouth for the time being the Mayor of Barnestaple for the
time being the Mayor of Biddiford for the time being the Mayor of Totnes for the time being the Mayor of
Tiverton for the time being the Mayor of Torrington for the time being the Mayor of Dartmouth for the time
being the Mayor of Plympton for the time being Edmond Tremayne Nicholas Rowe James Fortescue James
Courtney William Drake of Netherton Elizeus Crimes John Fownes John Martin of Chadlewood Edmond
Pollexfen Peter Beavis John Rose Ellis Bartlett senior Thomas Southcott of Hedge-end George Southcott Henry
Fry Edward Lovett William Drake of Yarbery John Fortescue George Yeo Thomas Docton of Docton
Gentlemen John Cooke Christopher Mayne John Speccott John Tanner William Stawell Ambrose Roope
Christopher Bale Esquires Thomas Williams Walter Bogan Peter Atkins Anthony Salter John Cruwys John
Hanbery Edward Ford Doctor of Physicke Francis Sheppard Nicholas Lutterell of Hartland John Davye of Oarley
Matthias Jenkins Richard Carew of Plymouth William Savery of Slade Moses Gould Richard Duke junior Gilbert
Yard Sir John Tremaine Knight William Davie Barrister at Law Samuell Tanner Thomas Ford Edmond Starr John
Mercer William Chaplen John Contee Robert Rous Gentlemen Benjamin Oliver Esquire Richard Parminster Merchant
Dennis Rolle Esquire Nicholas Roope Esquire Southcott Lutterell Richard [Burhogg<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Doctor of Physick.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>For the City of Exeter.</head>
			<para id="p25">The Mayor for the time being Sir Edward Seymour Baronet Sir George Treby Knight Sir John Tremayne
Knight John Bidgood Edmond Davie Waterhouse and John Osmond Doctors of Physicke James
Walker Esquire John Snell William Sandford Christopher Brodridge Henry Smith Christopher Bale Robert
Dabinott and George Saffin Aldermen Thomas Bampfield Thomas Gibbon and Charles Vaughan Barresters at Law
John Gaudy Esquire Sheriffe Robert Walker Esquire Edward Crosse Malachy Pyne Humphrey Leigh Edward
Seaward Christopher Coke John Elwell John Banks Christopher [Mayne<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Nich: Brooking and John Curson Merchants
The Receiver for the time being Sir Peter Colyton Baronet Edmond Starre Abraham Troute Richard White William
Sealy Thomas Turner Jerom King Francis Pengelly Daniell Ivye Thomas Gould William Spry Thomas Brooking.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>For the County of Dorsett</head>
			<para id="p26">Sir William Portman Sir John Morton Sir Nathaniell Napper Sir Robert Napper Sir William Pinsent Baronets
Sir John Nicholas Knight of the Bath Sir George Strode Sir Henry Butler Sir Math Andrews Knights Thomas
Freke Thomas Strangwayes Francis Lutterell Edward Miller Samuell Rolle Richard. Fownes John Bancks Robert
Freeke senior William Okeden junior Robert Coker senior Robert Coker junior William Frampton William Whitacre
Edward Nicholas John Pole Sebastian Isaac Robert Culliford Thomas Chafin Henry Seymour Edward Seymour
Thomas Erle William Strode Robert Williams John Williams Michaell Harvey Francis Mohun Robert Seymer
Henry Seymer Thomas Chafe Hugh Hodges Sergeant at Law Henry Constantine Anthony Ettericke Robert Browne
Thomas Trenchard Richard Brodrep Henry Heming Edward St Lo, Henry Trenchard Nathaniell Bond His
Majestyes Serjeant at Law George Strangewayes John Hurding William Etterick John Still William Floyer
William Bennet of Shaston John Lawrence of Grange William Bowles senior John Ironside John Bowles John
Hardey Thomas Turberville Bullen Reymes Robert Oxenbridge Thomas Greene Seymour Bowman William
Churchill Richard Swayne Robert Erle Robert Thornhill George Dawbeny John Michell Thomas Skinner Charles
Brune William Sydenham Richard Bingham William Weston Robert Hussey of Stour Pani William Filliol James
Gould Nicholas Gould John Eashmont John Burridge Anthony Floyer Nicholas Hardey William Bennet Richard
Rose Andrew [Tucher<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] John Hoskins William Wake Nicholas Browne William Lawrence William Hull John
Lawrence of Whitechurch George Barber Thomas Bower Arthur Fowkes John Abingdon Roger Mompesson
William Bull senior Robert Burridge John Strode of Chauntrey Robert Tilly John Fitts Thomas Chetle Sir
Robert Henley Knight John Moore Sydenham Baker Thomas Gundry Robert Swayne of Corfe Robert Butler
Esquires Thomas Williams Peter Hoskins Thomas Hawles Gentlemen Richard Newman Esquire George Gould the
Mayors of Dorchester Shaftsbury Weymouth Melcomb Corfe Wareham Lyme Regis the Bayliffs of Bridport for
the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Poole</head>
			<para id="p27">The Mayor for the time being Moses Darrell senior John Carter Shadrache Beale Moses Darrell junior William
Bowles William Phillips Thomas Smith Thomas Hyde John Pyke Joseph Hopkins William Streete William Minty
John Gigger John Jabber Thomas Smith.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>For the County (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) of Durham</head>
			<para id="p28">The Honourable Charles Mountague Esquire Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir Ralph Cole Sir James Clavering Sir
Robert Eden Sir Marke Milbancks Sir William Blackett Sir William Chater Baronets Sir Ralph Carr Sir William
Bows Knights Christopher [Vane<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] John Tempest Thomas Craddock William Lambton Byerley George Morland Henry
Lyddell William Forrester Cuthbert Carr Lyonell Vane Francis Bows William Tempest John Davison Frevill
Lambton Ralph Bates John Clavering James Clavering John Sidewicke Robert Jenneson Robert Elleson William
Blackett Mark Shaftoe Rowland Place Thomas Lyddell John Midleton Esquires Francis Carr Bramley
[Esquires<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Lyonell Maddeson Robert Carr John Rogers Richard Midleton Thomas Wright William Carr Joseph
Carr John Carr Marmaduke Allenson John Hall Edward Shepperdson William Greveson John Elstob John Widdefield
Thomas Bowser James Cooke George Crosier William Fawcett Walter Etterick Ralph Holmes Anthony Salom
Simon Peacock Cuthbert Sanderson William Garth Thomas Watson Abraham Hilton Ralph Hedworth William
Wilson of Durham James Mickelton John Dale William Johnson William Killinghall Robert Dixon Thomas
Saunderson William Wilkenson Nathaniell Midleton John Spearman Gentlemen The Mayor of Durham for the
time being Captaine Thomas Brasse Arthur Priscott Ralph Gowland Thomas (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) [Fother<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] of Grinden Ridge William
Selby of Beale John Wilkie Thomas Grey of Morton Thomas Orde of Felkington Gilbert Orde of Holy Island
Bryan Grey of Kiley Ralph Watson Patricke Crow Esquires William Urwen Sir James Tillie William Hutchinsen
Peter Marley.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>For the West Rideing of the County of Yorke</head>
			<para id="p29">Charles Marquesse of Winton Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Duke of Bolton William Lord Eland Eldest
Sonne to the Marquesse of Hallifax Peregrine Earle of Danby Eldest Sonne to the Marquesse of Carmarthen
William Lord Pawlett Second Sonne to the Duke of Bolton Arthur Lord Viscount Irwin of the Kingdome of
Scotland George Lord Viscount Castleton of the Kingdome of Ireland John Lord Viscount Downe of the Kingdome
of Ireland Thomas Lord Fairfax of the Kingdome of Scotland Sydney Wortley Mountague Esquire Henry Dawney
Esquire Henry Fairfax Esquire Sir Henry Goodricke Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Armatage Sir John Kaye Sir
William Reresby Sir John Ingleby Sir John Bland Sir Henry Marwood Sir William Franckland Sir George Cooke
Sir Godfrey Copley Sir Edmond Wynne Sir Edward Blacket Sir John Tempest Sir John Cutler Sir Henry
Slingsby Sir Lyon Pilkinton Baronets Sir Thomas Yarborough Sir Edmond Jennings Sir Ralph Knight Sir John
Hewly Sir Jonathan Jennings Sir Michaell Wentworth Sir Patience Ward Sir Stephen Thompson Sir Thomas
Hodgshon Sir William Lowther Sir John Coghill Knights Henry Lyddell John Ramsden of Biram Thomas
Frankland William Palmes Robert Byerley Christopher Tankred Francis Nevile Richard Beaumont of Whitley John
Goodricke Walter Calverley Welbury Norton Cerill Arthington Thomas Fawkes William Stockdale John Savile of
Methley Charles Osborne Christopher Lister John Knight Denzill Onslow Arthur Ingram William Woombwell
Francis Foulgeham John Ranisden of Hatfield Thomas Yorke John Bradshaw Thomas Yarborough Thomas Vincent
John Beilby William Ellis William Vavasour Henry Thompson Henry Stapylton Inglebert Leeds Thomas Fairfax of
Menston Anthony Fletcher John Lister of Bawtry Ralph Lowther Henry Hitch Bryan Sunderland Ambrose Pudsey
Thomas Lister of Westby Thomas Horton John Eastoft Godfred Boswell John Ashton Francis Jessop John Lambert
Henry Edmond Richard Redman Thomas Fountaine Jasper Blythman Christopher Wilkinson John Farrer William
Rhodes Thomas Parker Francis White William Dodson John Gill John Harris Miles Staveley John Stanhope of
Horseforth Jonathan Jen[n]ings William Roundell Robert Mitford Christopher Adams John Garland Mathew
Boynton Roger Portington [Roger<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Baynes John Hatfield of Laughton Cuthbert Wade Lyonell Copley Richard
Staynes Thomas [Hessetine<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] John Rooks Rowland Norton Bennet Sherrard William Johnston Thomas Kirke Robert
Farrand Tobias Harvey Thomas Lee John Atkinson John Warner Andrew Wilkinson Richard Shutleworth William
Ingram Esquires Simon Sterne Thomas Rookeby Gentlemen John Batty Esquire Edmond Barker John Auby
William Norton John Copley Gentlemen Armstrong Gregory Esquire James Greenewood Thomas Edmonds Godfrey
Copley Bartin Allet John Savile of Cridlin Benjamin Watts Richard Nettleton Lawrence Warton Michaell Warton
of Bawtry Andrew Howden John Preston Stephen Wilks Thomas Graven Francis Eldwick Thomas Warder of
Northcoate Cuthbert Chambers Gregory Fish Josias Midgley Robert Inman Gentlemen The Mayor of Pontefract
for the time being The Mayor of Doncaster for the time being The Mayor of Rippon for the time being The
Mayor of Leeds for the time being Samuell Mellish Esq[uire] Recorder of Doncaster Edward Thompson Esq[uire].</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>For the North Rideing of the County of Yorke.</head>
			<para id="p30">Charles Lord Marquesse of Winchester eldest Sonne to the Duke of Bolton John Lord Viscount Downe of the
Kingdome of Ireland Thomas Lord Fairfax of the Kingdome of Scotland Phillip (<ref idref="n18">18</ref>) Darcie Esq[uire] Sir Marmaduke Wivell
Sir William Leveson Gower Sir William Strickland Sir David Fowlis Sir John Hotham Sir John Kaye Sir Watkinson
Payler Sir Bryan Stapilton Sir William Frankland Sir John Lowther Sir Henry Marwood Sir William Caley Sir
Christopher Wandesford Sir Thomas Pennyman Sir Edward Blacket Sir John Brooke Sir William Chater Sir Marke
Milbanke Baronets Sir William Hustler Sir John Hewly Sir Henry Bellasis Sir Barrington Bouchier Sir William
Ascough Sir William Bowes Knights Thomas Franckland George Marwood William Palmes Thomas Yorke William
Thompson Henry Metcalfe William Robinson of Newby George Smithson Francis Wivell Robert Walters Roger
Croft John Wastell John Hutton Roger Talbott Cornelius Caley Abstrupus Danby John How Thomas Croft Edward
Hutchinson William [Tankred<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Francis Thompson Bernard Greenvile John Trotter Leonard Smelt Thomas Harrison
Anthony Lowther Timothy Maleverer Thomas Worsley William Metcalfe John Gibson Henry Crosland Thomas
Lassells Richard Staynes Daniell Lassells Thomas Wakefield William Chalaner Francis Hall Edward Thompson Richard
Peirse John Peirse John Hill junior Thomas Gowre John Hopton James Mountaine Luke Robinson Thomas Pullen
John Beverley Durand Hotham Rowland Norton Thomas Cradock Thomas Wivell Humphrey Wharton Constable
Bradshaw William Dawson Mathew Anleby Richard Darley Christopher Percy Hay of Malton Roger Covell Thomas
Hesletine Esquires Doctor Smith of Easby Thomas Langley Towers Driffield Butler Buggin Esquires Leonard
Hartley Benjamin Purchas Edward Place William Davill Phillip Prince Robert Lumley James Conyers William
Kitchinman Robert Bell George Norton Stephen Driffield Robert Bushell Mathew Tomlinson Timothy Forde
William Sanders Ralph Porter William Robinson John Robinson senior Guy Butler William Fayreside junior
Paul Baylie John Cockerill senior Robert Burton William Stoope Roger Lee Thomas Pearson Timothy Portington
Stephen Thompson Thomas Holmes Mathew Smailes John Robinson of Easby Thomas Gile Robert Crosfeild
William Thornton of Ascrige Gentlemen The Mayor of Richmond for the time being, the Bayliffes of Scarborough
for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>For the East Rideing of the County of Yorke.</head>
			<para id="p31">Thomas Lord Fairfax of the Kingdome of Scotland Arthur Viscount Irwin of the Kingdome of Scotland
George Dawny Esquire Sir Francis Boynton Sir William Strickland Sir John Hotham Sir John Kaye Sir Henry
Saint Quintin Sir Watkinson Payler Sir John Legard Sir Thomas Rudston Baronets Sir William Cob Sir Ralph
Warton Sir Michaell Warton Sir Jonathan Atkins Sir Mathew Pearson Sir John Hewley Sir James Bradshaw
Sir Richard Osbaldeston Knights Tobias Jenkins senior Tobias Jenkins junior Robert Buck John Lister William
Osbaldeston William Gee William Thompson John Lister of Beverley Francis Thompson Edward Thompson Charles
Hilliard Durant Hotham John Ramsden Henry Thompson Griffith Boynton Henry Guy William Bethell Richard
Thompson senior Richard Thompson junior John Stapylton William St Quintin James Moyser John Moyser
Thomas Hesketh James Heblethwaite Richard Remmington Ralph Warton Charles Warton Colonell Mathew
Alured Thomas Alured Mathew Apleyard Edward Bernard John Eastoft Robert Hollis John Tayler Ingleby
Daniell William Hedlam Bernard Lister Robert Pricket Robert Mountaine Hugh Bethell Richard Darley
Benjamin Overton Robert Legard Robert Southby Walter Strickland Hen: Portington Thomas Langley Ralph
Lutton Esquires Edward Bower John Pearson Robert Mason Phillip Wilkinson Henry Masters Robert Carlisle
Gentlemen The Mayor and Recorder of Hull for the time being the Mayor of Beverley for the time being
the Mayor of Heddon for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>For the City of Yorke and County of the same City.</head>
			<para id="p32">The Lord Mayor Aldermen Recorder and Sheriffes for the time being Charles Lord Marquesse of Winchester
Eldest Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Duke of Bolton Arthur Viscount Irwin of the Kingdome of Scotland
Peregrine Earle of Danby Eldest Sonne to the Marquesse of Carmarthen Thomas Lord Fairfax of the Kingdome of
Scotland Sir Henry Goodrick Knight and Baronet Sir John [Brooke<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Baronet Sir John Hewley Sir Stephen Thompson
Knights Bennoit Sherwood Henry Stapleton William Robinson William Roundell Thomas Hutton Esquires Henry
Watkinson Doctor of Laws Henry Squire John Baines Thomas Hesletine Esquires Thomas Benson Andrew Perrott
Richard Reynolds Timothy Moyseley Robert Shakleton Francis Ducket William Thompson Thomas Nisbet Tobias
Wickham Robert Squire Thomas Holmes Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Kingston upon Hull.</head>
			<para id="p33">The Mayor Aldermen and Recorder for the time being Robert Legard John East William Gee and John
Ramsden Esquires.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>For the County of Essex.</head>
			<para id="p34">The Honourable Banister Mainard Ralph Grey William Mainard Esquires Sir William Appleton Baronet Sir
William Hicks Knight and Baronet Sir Francis Masham Sir Andrew Jenner Sir Thomas Nightingale Baronets Sir
Richard Everard Knight and Baronet Sir William Luckin Sir Thomas Litleton Sir Martin Lumley Sir Anthony Abdye
Sir John Abdye Sir Thomas Draper Sir Thomas Darcie Sir Jervase Elves Sir Edward Smith Sir Thomas Garrard
Sir Thomas Barnardiston Sir Charles Tyrrell Sir William Barker Sir Robert Smith Sir Josiah Childe Sir Peter
Soame Sir Cave James Sir John Sudbury Baronets Sir John Brampston Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Clarke Sir
John Sparrow Sir Richard Piggott Sir Thomas Fanshaw Sir Eliab Harvey Sir [Robert<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] Barrington Sir Edward Turner
Sir Thomas Midleton Sir Jacob Butler Sir Thomas Devall Sir John Marshall Sir Marke Gyon Sir Benjamin
Thorowgood Sir Samuell Husbands Knights John Osborne John Conyers Esquires The Kings Councill Henry
Mildmey John Wroth Francis Harvey alias Mildmey Carew Harvey alias Mildmay Thomas Luther William Coward
Abraham Wessell Thomas Dawtry Robert Bateman William Palmer William Peck William Pert William Atwood
John Greene Thomas Argall Samuell Reynalds Charles Mountague William Glascocke Thomas Burgh Brabazon
Aylmer William Beaumont Isaac Rebow Robert Cole John Wale John Simonds William Clopton William Lingwood
John Tindell Timothy Felton Thomas Barrington John Lemot Honeywood John Eldred William Eldred John Cox
Robert Mildmay Owen Wynn Guardian de le Mint Samuell Hare Francis Maidstone Samuell Westrow John Cooke
de Chesell Edward Bullocke senior Edward Bullocke junior John Locky Thomas Gray John Goodier William
Walker Thomas Weeley Thomas Harlackenden Bowes Thomas Waldgrave Giles Dent William Kendall Andrew
Searle Esquires Samuell Horsemanden Charles Tyrrell Clerks Alexander Prescot Anthony Brampston Esquires Marke
Mott Gentleman William Harvey William Scott Thomas Turner John Sparrow John Raymond junior John Cressener
John Penington William Nutt Henry Glascocke Waldgrave Pelham Samuell Wiseman Erasmus Smith John Meade
Thomas Abdy Henry Ayloffe Esquires Phillip Saltington Grey of Walsted John Hethersell Richard
Hyde Esquire Edmond Goodwin John Edwards Esquire William Mott Esquire Collonell John Cutts George
Brampston Doctor of Physick William Glascock John Fanshaw John Luther Cuthbert Martin Francis Bradbury
Haynes Barley senior Haynes Barley junior Nicholas Cursellis Ralph Creffield Nathaniell Lawrance Nathan Wright
Samuel Giggs Edward Rudge George Gent Henry Paschall Edward Thorowgood Esquires William Herris John
Haines Thomas Greene John Joseline Robert Barwell junior Jeremiah Richardson Gentlemen John Larkin John
Allin Robert Bragg Christopher Grange John Hopwood Esquires Joseph Sparrow Harrison
Nicholls Richard Cowper Gent[leman] Sigismond Trafford Robert Smith.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>For the Towne of Maldon</head>
			<para id="p35">The Bayliffes of Maldon for the time being Sir William Sprignell Baronet Thomas [Goe<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] John Stevens William
Carr Peter Robjent Gentlemen Sir Thomas [Darey<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Baronet Charles Mountague Esq[uire] Ezekiell Finch John Pond
Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>For the Towne of Colchester</head>
			<para id="p36">The Mayor of Colchester for the time being Sir John Shaw Knight Serjeant at Law Mathew Ives John Tatem
Nathaniell Lawrance John Stilliman John Potter Ralph Crayfield Esq[uire] Henry Lambe Thomas Loveny Joseph
Thurston Benjamin Cocke John Rayner Stephen Naggs Alderman William Mott senior Francis Wheeler Esquires
John Rebow Abraham Hedgthorne John Savile Jacop Tayspell Gent[leman] William Moore Esquire Thomas Ruse William
Boise William Milbanke Gentlemen John Eldred Samuell Reynalds Isaac Rebow.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>For the Towne of Harwich</head>
			<para id="p37">Sir Thomas Midleton John Eldred Esquire the Mayor of Harwich for the time being Thomas Langley John
Ralph Robert Seaman John Browne William Garrard Daniell Smith Charles Smith Aldermen John Phillips Thomas
Bradshaw John Westbrowne Robert Lane Henry Munt William Rudland Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>For the County of Gloucester.</head>
			<para id="p38">William Lord Viscount Tracy of the Kingdome of Ireland Henry Powle Esquire one of Their Majestyes most
Honourable Privy Councill and Speaker of the House of Commons [The Right Honourable Sir Robert Atkins
Lord Chiefe Baron of Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer and Speaker of the House of Peeres<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] Sir Henry Capell
Sir James Rushout Sir Richard Cox Sir William Kite James Thynne Esquire Benjamin [Baden<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] Richard Dowdeswell
George Pitt Richard Freeman John Marriot junior Charles Dowdeswell William Lane John Parsons junior John
Delabeere William Bagget John Carter Henry Coxwell William Dewy Thomas Janes Sir Francis Russell Charles
Wine Sir Robert Southwell Sir John Newton Sir William Forrester Samuell Hawlins Thomas Hales David Warren
Anthony Lawrance Danvers Hodges Henry Criswicke Charles Marquesse of [Worster<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] Charles Lord Dursley
Nathaniell Stephens Sir Gabriell Low Sir Thomas Stephens Thomas Rawlins Serjeant at Law Thomas Hodges
Walter Estcourt John Browning Samuell Trotman William Kingscot William Dennis Sir Ralph Dutton John Howe
John Coxewell William Hall Robert Veisey Sir Richard Onslow Baronet Andrew Barker Robert Pleydall
George Hanger Robert Oteridge Thomas Maisters Brierton Bourchier Richard How Thomas Smith Thomas Horton
Phillip Shepard Thomas Ridler Ridler of Edgworth Thomas Stephens [John<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] Castleman Lyonell Rich
Peachy Edward Stephens Paul Dodwell Sir Fleetword Dormer Conway Whithorne Joshua Aileworth
of Aileworth Sir Duncombe Colchester George Bond John Hickford Mainard Colchester Thomas Perke William
Maddocks Paul [Poley<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] Rice Yates Reginald Pindar William Rogers Wainam Winniatt William Bayly George
Lloyd James Michell Richard Yate William Try Sir John Aishfield Thomas Chester Sir John Fust Thomas Wise
Edward Smith Sir Richard Hart Sir Thomas Cann Richard Jones John Meredeth Thomas Burnell John Douse
Edward Mountague William [Painefoole<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] Thomas Browne of Coslawne John Parkhurst William Winter Samuell
Dobbins Michaell Beale Sir John Guise William Cooke Edward Cooke John Guise William Guise William Selwin
Rowland Wood William Lawrence John Powell Serjeant at Law Henry Brett John Cocks William Schudamore
William Hodges Sir Robert Atkins senior Stephen Baldwin Robert Codrington Christopher Mountacu Edward
Chamberlaine Samuell Barker John Griffin William Clutterbooke Richard Holford Richard Haynes John Stafford
Samuell Codrington John Nelin John Barkley Sir Hele Hooke William Bovey Thomas Trig Nathaniell Pert
Richard Hayward William Winter Pansfoot.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>For the City and County of the City of Gloucester.</head>
			<para id="p39">The Maior for the time being Alderman Rodgers John Powell Richard Wintle John Cox Thomas Lloyd Sir
Duncombe Colchester William Cooke George Lloyd Henry Futer Alderman Evans William Schudamore Thomas
Webb Mercer Thomas Webb Attourney Nicholas Webb senior Nicholas Webb junior Thomas Gosling.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>For the County of Hereford</head>
			<para id="p40">The Right Honourable Henry Powle Esquire one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill John
Lord Viscount Scudamore the Honourable Chambre Brabazon Esq[uire] Sir John Morgan Sir Herbert Croft Sir John
Hoskins Baronets Sir Edward Harley Knight of the Bath Sir Francis Winnington Sir William Gregory Sir
Thomas Duppa Sir John Williams Knights Thomas Coningsby William Fines Paul Foley Robert Harley Thomas
Price John Birch John Dutton Colt James Morgan John Schudamore Thomas Cornwall Thomas Harley Ambrose
Schudamore Richard Reed senior Richard Reed junior Herbert Westfailing Thomas Cockes Edward Hopton
Edward Cornwall William Dansey senior William Dansey junior John Arnold Charles Baldwin John Williams
Richard Williams of Cabalva Edward Litleton John Arnold James Penmoyre of the Moore Nicholas Arnold
Uvedall Tompkins Robert Chaplin Thomas Foley senior Thomas Foley junior James Gregory John Booth of
Letton John How Jeremiah Bubb Edward Jackson Younger Cooke Robert Dobbins Robert Minors William Wintour
William Lambe John Nourse Marshall Bridges Richard Barnaby Ferdinando Gorges Thomas Howorth Robert Payne
James Lloyd of the Moore Sandys Lechmoore John Parry of Dulas Thomas Delahays Esquires Bennet Hoskins
William Guillim William Bridges John Walsome Samuell Birch Gentlemen John Powell of the While Francis
Baskerville Thomas Wigmore John Kirle Esquires Thomas Owen of Litle Brompton Thomas Carpenter Richard
Skipp James Woodhouse of Woodhouse Essex Sherborne Francis Woodhouse Humphrey Mayo John Fletcher John
Carver of Upton Daniell Kerry James Walwin Henry Cornwall John Hereford of Sufton Henry Gorge Peter Smith
John Sallaway John Smith Gentlemen John Abrahall of Engiston.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>For the City of Hereford</head>
			<para id="p41">The Mayor for the time being John Lord Viscount [Schudamore<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] of Sligo in the Realme of Ireland Sir William
Gregory Knight one of Their Majestyes Justices of the Court of Kings Bench Paul Foley Henry Cornwall Herbert
Westfailing Thomas Price Esquires Robert Simons Thomas Panard Abraham Seward Thomas Mathews Richard
Wadeley Hugh Rodd Aldermen Richard Williams Thomas Clarke senior Thomas Clarke junior Henry Smith
Thomas Smith Edward Rodd John Williams senior John Williams junior James Price John Abrahall Richard Gower
Edmond Weaver Theophilus Alley Richard Poole Thomas Church and John Smith Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>For the Burrough of Lempster</head>
			<para id="p42">The Bayliffe for the time being Thomas Conningsby John Dutton Colt Edward Harley Esquires William Batch
Edward Bangham James Powle John Jennings John Powle Thomas Hardwicke Robert Ford Thomas Harris and
Richard Jones Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>For the County of Hertford</head>
			<para id="p43">The Right Honourable the Earle of Danby the Honourable Robert Cecill Esquire Sir Samuell Grimston Sir
Richard Francklin Sir John Garard Sir John Austen Sir William Leman Sir Robert Jocelin Sir John Witterong Sir
William Cowper Sir Thomas Pope Blount Sir Richard Anderson Sir Edmond Anderson Sir Jonathan Keate Sir
John Brograve Baronets Sir John Gore Sir Humphrey Gore Sir Thomas Bide Sir Charles Cesar Sir William Litton
Sir Ralph Ratcliffe Sir John Bucknell Sir Robert Marsham Knights Robert Austin John Plummer Thomas Halsey
Ralph Freeman Robert Elwayes Gilbert Hoo Keat William Gore James Witterong William Cowper Thomas
Shatterden Edward Briscoe junior Henry Childe Henry Guy Thomas Priestly George Hadley John Gape senior
John Ellis Thomas Arris George Nodes Thomas Arram William Briscoe Richard Helder Thomas Lomax Thomas
Austen Richard How John Eddowes John Cooke James Stedman Israell Mayo John Gore Bernard Turner Strange
Joycelin Joseph Jordan Marmaduke [Rayden<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] Henry Allington William Martin and Thomas Winford Esquires.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>For the County of Huntingdon</head>
			<para id="p44">The Honourable Robert Mountague Esquire The Honourable Sydney Wortley Mountague Esquire Sir Robert
Bernard Baronet John Proby John Conyers John Drydon Charles Cesar Robert Appreece Richard Naylor Anthony
Hammond John Bigg James Torkington William Naylour John Ferrer Robert Pulloyne John Pockington John
Trice Richard Drury Robert Throgmorton Esquires Richard Wynde Robert Clarke William Bellamy William
Fuller James Wright William Nicholls Richard Hatley Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>For the Towne of Huntingdon</head>
			<para id="p45">George Merritt Mayor Richard Astrey James Fairside William Dowse Thomas Sayer Edward Audley Joseph
Darlow Thomas Harris Angell Gentlemen John Pockington Esquire.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>For the County of Kent</head>
			<para id="p46">The Lord Viscount Faukland the Honourable Sir Vere Fane Knight of the Bath the Honourable Peregrine
Bertie Esquire the Honourable Sackvile Tufton Esquire The Honourable Heneage Finch Esquire Sir William
Twisden Sir Charles Sidley of Southfleete Sir Charles Sydley of Sir Thomas Robarts Sir Henry
Palmer Sir Philip Boteler Sir Thomas Culpeper of Aylesford Sir Thomas Stiles Sir George Rivers Sir Bazill
Dixwell Sir John Knatchbull Sir John Rayney Sir Robert Hales Sir Stephen Leonard Sir Humphrey Miller Sir
John Marsham Sir William Honeywood Sir Thomas Peirce Sir John Bankes Sir Nathaniell Powell Sir John Austen
Sir Thomas Selyard Sir Anthony Archer Sir John Fagg Sir James Oxenden Sir William Swan Sir Robert Filmer
Sir John Shaw Sir John Cutler Sir Roger Twisden Sir George Chute Sir Thomas Taylor Sir John Mordant Sir
John Lethelier Baronets Sir John Darrell Sir George Curteys Sir Charles Bickerstaffe Sir Henry Boswell Sir
Nicholas Crispe Sir Robert Faunce Sir Nicholas (<ref idref="n32">32</ref>) Sir Thomas Culpeper Sir Robert Marsham Sir James Hayes Sir
John Leigh Sir Joseph Williamson Sir William Langhorne Sir William Hooker Sir Edward Maisters Knights
Collonell Beaumont Governour of Dover Castle Christopher Vane Robert Smith Thomas Fane Edward Hales Esquires
Thomas Knatchbull William Watton Charles Amhurst Jeffery Amhurst Thomas Ryder William Campion Caleb
Bankes John Leech Robert Lewkener Gideon de Laune John Kitchell Esquires George Harlackenden Gentleman
William Boyse of William Henden Robert Austen senior Robert Crayford James Masters of Langden
Walter Breames Herbert Randolph Esquires John Boyse John Thurbon Serjeant at Law William Hammond Gent.
George Scott Esquire James Chadwick Gent. William Kingsley junior Christopher Mills Henry Thornhill Esquires Dancan
Abacromy Gent. Samuell Short Esq[uire] William Brockman of Bitchborough William Brockman of Cherriton John
Crump Thomas Moyle Gentlemen Thomas Papillon Thomas Munus Francis Bathurst Esquires James Bunce George
Petty William Selby George Polhill John Hyde Major Gibbins Robert Gibbon John Cooke Thomas Osborne James
Herbert Ralph Bufkin John Brewer John Parker Thomas Dallison Edward Gullison Reynald Peckham William Cage
Nicholas Miller John Wilkinson Richard Godden John Knatchbull Thomas Brewer Esquires Thomas Manley Esquire
Thomas Scott William Honeywood Gentlemen George Sayers Vice Chamberlaine to the Queene Dowager Gerrard
Gore John Le Mott Honeywood Nicholas Cooke Gentlemen William Hugesen Leonard Diggs Thomas Gomeldon
Julius Deeds John Sherman Christopher Dering Esquires Vincent Denn Serjeant at Law George Elcock Esquire
William Jacob Doctor of Physick Henry Oxenden Henry Hawley Richard Oxenden John Mitchell Esquires Captaine
Pettit of Thannet Moses Napleton Gentlemen Herbert Palmer Wortley Whorwood Henry Lee Esquires John Whitfield
Henry Godden Charles Bargrave William Courthope Gentlemen Robert Heath John Evelin Edward Austin William
Lambert William Ash Esquires William Wilkinson Gent. John Mascall Gent. Phillip Bartholomew Gent. William
Coriton George Gifford Francis Farnaby Ralph Petly William Swan John Buggins Robert Austin junior James
Codd Alexander Culpeper Samuell Plummer Esquires William White Gent. John [Crippe<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] of Maidstone Roger Payne
Thomas Napleton Thomas Godfrey Esquires Thomas Godfrey of Hoddiford Gent. George Rook Edward Nutt
Henry Marsh Thomas Brewer of Northfleet Thomas Washer Robert Mitchell Thomas Blisse Jeoffery Boyse Edward
[Boise<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] Samuell Shaw John Cason Thomas Hales senior Thomas Hales junior George Curteis Esquires George Maplesden
Charles Courtop Thomas Turner of [Ilins<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] Gent. Thomas Adrian John Fotherby Francis Barrell Thomas Selyard
Christopher Allison Henry Sandis Percivall Hart Edward Manning Edward Brent James Fortrey Edward Grace Henry
Hawley Esquire Creswell Draper Edward King Thomas Gifford Edward Battison Edmond Toke Esquires the Mayor
of Rochester for the time being the Mayor of Maidstone for the time being John Blome Charles Fagg Gent William
Randolp John Culpeper Esquire Thomas Meredith Gent. Humphry Stiles Esq[uire] Richard Hulse of Bethersden Gent.
George Withwick Gent. Thomas Withwick Esq[uire] Thomas Brett William Brett Gent. Edward Manley of Wooldham
the Jurates of Maidstone being Justices of the Peace John Eaves Gent. the [Bailiffes<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] and Expenditors of Romney
Marsh for the time being Benjamin Godfrey John Bond [Mayor Nellet<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] of Maidstone Thomas Morris Gent. William
James Esquire Captaine Tomlin Mr Coppin of Deale Christopher Mason Christopher Sherman Christopher May Edward
Bathurst Ricaut Thomas Marsh Gent. Charles Kenrick John Linch Esquires Thomas Chiffinch John Baron Gent.
William Spencer Esq[uire] Captaine Courthop Elhanon Tucker Gentlemen John Bryan Moyse of Rochester John
Cony John Hogg senior of Rochester Garret Colaut Thomas Blisse Richard Elay Robert Salmon of Maidstone
Wood of Maidstone Jurat Robert Saunders William Reader of Maidstone.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>For the City and County of Canterbury.</head>
			<para id="p47">Francis Jeoffrey Esq[uire] Mayor Vincent Denn Esq[uire] Serjeant at Law Recorder Sir William Honeywood Baronet Sir
Anthony Archer Knight and Baronet Henry Lee Thomas Godfrey Edward Nutt John Cason Jeofrey Boyes
Herbert Randolph Esquires William Jacob Doctor of Physick John Taylor Doctor of Law John Whitfield William
Wotson Gentlemen Thomas Fidge Thomas [Knowles<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] Nicholas Nicholson Thomas Dunkin John [Garting<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] Squier
Bruerton Henry Gibbs Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>For the Towne and Port of Sandwich</head>
			<para id="p48">The Mayor for the time being Sir James Oxenden Baronet John Thurborne Esquire Serjeant at Law John
Moore Peter Noell James Howe Edward Fellowes Isaac Rickesey William Maundy Jeremy Wells Jeofrey Sucket
Samuell Ferrer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>For the Towne and Port of Dover</head>
			<para id="p49">The Mayor for the time being Collonell Beaumont Governour of Dover Castle Sir Bazill Dixwell Baronet Sir
Abraham Jacob Thomas Papillon Captaine William Stoakes George [West<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] William Richards Nicholas Cullen
senior Thomas Scott Edward Wivell Edward Francklin Jurats Nathaniell de New Frederick de Vinck John
Matson Thomas Raworth John Ford William Eaton Nicholas Cullen junior Phillip Yorke Charles Johnson
Abraham Stock.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>For Feversham</head>
			<para id="p50">The Mayor for the time being Charles Kenrick Esq[uire] Thomas Napleton Thomas Knowler John Marsh Francis
Waterman Joseph Edwards Gent..</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>For the Towne and Port of New Romney</head>
			<para id="p51">The Mayor for the time being John Brewer James Chadwicke Esquires Peter Lancaster John Mascall Richard
Baker John Chalker Peter Martin John Hunt Jurats William Finch Thomas Baker.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s50">
			<head>For the Towne of Tenterden.</head>
			<para id="p52">The Mayor for the time being Sir George Chute Robert Austin Esquire Robert Wightwick Gentleman James
Skeats Elhanan Tucker Lemuell Tucker William Cartis John Mantle.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s51">
			<head>For the Towne and Port of Hythe.</head>
			<para id="p53">The Maior for the time being Edward Hales Julius Deeds Esquires Robinson Beau Henry Deeds William
Browne Elias Basset John Clemet Thomas Tournay Jurats.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s52">
			<head>For the Towne of Fordwich.</head>
			<para id="p54">The Mayor for the time being Samuel Short Francis Joll John Pilcher John Bix Jurats.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s53">
			<head>For the Towne of Folkestone</head>
			<para id="p55">The Mayor for the time being Sir Basill Dixwell Baronet Miles Jacob Thomas Fagg Gibbon Lad.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s54">
			<head>For the Towne of Lid</head>
			<para id="p56">Julius Deeds Henry Wynn Esquires John Bateman Humphry Lee William Batcheller Nicholas Dye.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s55">
			<head>For the Towne and Port of Hastings.</head>
			<para id="p57">The Mayor for the time being Collonell John Beaumont Captaine Thomas Muns Captaine Millard Phillip Lowell
Jurats Richard Holman.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s56">
			<head>For the auntient Towne of Rye.</head>
			<para id="p58">The Mayor for the time being Sir John Austin Sir John Darrell Michaell Cadman Thomas Tourney Nicholas
Mannouch John Spine Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s57">
			<head>For the Towne of Winchelsea</head>
			<para id="p59">The Mayor for the time being Robert Austen Esq[uire] Samuell Westorne Edward Martin.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s58">
			<head>For Seaford and Pevensey</head>
			<para id="p60">The Bayliffes for the time being Sir Nicholas Pelham William Campion Esquire Sir William Thomas William
Kenslay Thomas Row.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s59">
			<head>For the County Palatine of Lancaster</head>
			<para id="p61">The Right Honourable Robert Lord Willoughby of Eresby Chancellor of Their Majesties Dutchy and County
Palatine of Lancaster and Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Right Honourable the Earle of Lindsey Lord Great
Chamberlaine of England Richard Lord Colchester [eldest<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] Sonne and Heire Apparent of Thomas Earle Rivers
Charles Lord Brandon eldest Sonne and Heire Apparent of Charles Earl of Maclesfeld and Lord Lieftenant of
the said County Palatine The Honourable James Stanley The Honourable Fitton Gerrard Sir Charles Houghton
Sir Edmond Ashton Sir Thomas Stanley Sir Ralph Ashton Sir Richard Standish Sir Henry Ashurst Sir Robert
Duckenfield Baronets Sir Edward Chisenhall Sir Daniell Fleming Sir Edward Mosely Knights Thomas Cotton
Peter Bold Thomas Norris Peter Leigh Roger Noell Roger Kirby Thomas Preston Edward Fleetwood William
Hulton Richard Fleetwood Henry Farrington John Byrom James Holt Benjamin Houghton Lawrence Rausterne
William Bancks Robert Parker Richard Brooke Thomas Ashurst James Duckenfeild Thomas Braddyll Thomas
Greenhalgh William Kirby John Birch Joshuah Horton John Hartley Alexander Rigby of Layton James Lightbonne
James Chetham of Turton Thomas Mort Christopher Parker Thomas Rigby Ralph Lindsay George Pigott Thomas
Patten William Knipe Roger Moore John Braddyll Edward Rigby Ralph Longworth Christopher Wilkinson
Thomas Leaver Anthony Parker Edward Ogle Joseph Yeates Thomas Dodd Stephen Alcock Silvester Richmond
Thomas Cole Thomas Bretherton Alexander Maudesley James Cheetham of Smedley John Ashton Richard Ashton
John Starkey Peter Edgerton Nicholas [Towney<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] Miles Sands Bartholomew Heskith Alexander Heskith Thomas
Dickinson Robert Roper George Charnes Shaw Robert Atkinson Esquires Thomas Sclater Charles
Davenport Francis Sherrington Thomas Wilson Jonathan Blackborne Thomas Patten of Warrington William
Patten of the same Robert [Berkley<ref idref="n43">43</ref>] Martin Willis William Fleming John Sawry Samuell Sands William
Molineux Nathaniell Molineux Thomas Nailor Richard Dickenson Thomas Bradshaw John Hopwood junior
Doctor Grundy Thomas Percivall Nicolas Cuncliffe James Folds William Sagar Ambrose Barcroft John Blacow
Magull of Magull John Earle John Wilme Richard Parcivall James Prescott John Case John Wright
Henry Latham of Whiston Henry Latham of Kirkdow Richard Houghton Cuthbert Holland George Sharples
Jeffrey Roby Joseph Hudleston Joseph Fletcher John Launder junior Alexander Ratcliffe Esquire Legh
of Westhoughton Robert Markland Gentlemen The Mayor and Bayliffes of Lancaster for the time being John
Greenwood Joshua Partington Thomas Shearson Henry Jones Gentlemen Henry West Esquire Robert Sturzaker
Thomas Cole junior Gentleman the Mayor of Preston for the time being Roger Sudell senior Roger Sudell
junior Daniell Chaddock William Patten Richard Langton William Shaw William Cotton John Atherton Joseph
King Gentlemen The Mayor Recorder Aldermen and Bayliffes of Wigan for the time being Edward Earle
Esquire Catterall of Crooke Gentleman the Bayliffes of Clitherowe for the time being the Mayor of
Liverpoole for the time being [<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] Tyrer Alderman Windle Peter Atherton John Molyneux Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s60">
			<head>For the County of Leicester</head>
			<para id="p62">The High Sheriffe for the County of Leicester for the time being [Thomas Lord Beaumont of the Kingdome of
Ireland<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] [Thomas Lord<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] Bennet Lord Sherrard in the Kingdome of Ireland The Right Honourable Sir William
Rawlinson one of the Lords Commissioners for the Great Seale of England Sir William Villers Sir Thomas Halford
Sir Thomas Mackwith Sir Beaumont Dixie Sir Henry Hudson Sir Thomas Heisilrig Sir Thomas Beaumont Sir John
Noell Sir Roger Cave Sir Richard Nudigate Sir William Ellis Baronets Sir Ambrose Phillips Sir Edward Wigley
Knights John Cooke Jeofrey Palmer Richard Lister senior John De la Fountaine John Verney Thomas Boothby
William Boothby William Hartopp Thomas Babington St John Bennet Thomas Caldecote William Cole Samuell
Cotton Thomas Pochin William Streete William Whaley Stanhope Whalley Roger Roe Roger Smith George
Pochin Christopher Packe Henry Hastings Mathew Johnson Jeremy Dove William Francke George Hewet senior
George Hewet junior Richard Brudnall Edward Needham Francis Needham Richard Bradgate William Bainbrig
Lawrence Carter Edward Coniers Edward Hudson Edward Smith Rowland Browne William Palmer Richard
Lister junior George Moreton William Herricke John Wilson John Steale John Wilson William Faunt George
Ashby William Bird John Wilkins Henry Kendall Esquires Edward Bigland Serjeant at Law William Woollaston
Wolston Dixie William Herper John Herper Nathan Wright John Oneby John Major William Skeffington James
Armston Thomas Charnells Francis Mundy John Bainbridge Robert Heislrigge William Belgrave William Atkins
Henry Henningham John Chamberlaine William Rawlins William Jervis John Benskin Esquires William Whatton
John Goodman Thomas Palmer William Major John Hood Tyringham Stephens Michaell Wrightson Thomas May
George Vincent William Billers Mathew Symons Henry Dyson Thomas Andrews Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s61">
			<head>For the Burrough of Leicester</head>
			<para id="p63">The Mayor of the Burrough of Leicester for the time being Lawrence Carter Nathan Wright William Franke
John Major Thomas Babington Esquires Francis Noble William Southwell Andrew Freeman William Deane
George Beckett Phillip Abney John Robarts John Goodall George Bent Thomas Ludlam Walter Hood Francis
Ward Joseph Craddocke Mathew Simons William [Villers<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] William Major Thomas Palmer junior Thomas Wells
John Watts John Kilpin William Bentley John Dann John Wilkins John Brooksby Thomas Palmer senior
Edmond Johnson Gabriell Hill John Pare Edmond Cradock Henry Pate Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s62">
			<head>For the County of Lincolne and City of Lincolne and for the County of the said City.</head>
			<para id="p64">The Right Honourable George Lord Castleton of the Kingdome of Ireland The Right Honourable Robert
Lord Willoughby of Eresby Chauncellor of Their Majestyes Dutchy and County Palatine of Lancaster and Sonne
and Heire Apparent to the Right Honourable the Earle of Lindsey Lord Great Chamberlaine of England Bennet
Lord Sherrard The Honourable Nicholas Sanderson The Honourable Peregrine Bertie the Elder The Honourable
Charles Bertie the Younger The Honourable Peregrine Bertie junior The Honourable Phillip Bertie The Honourable
Charles Sanderson The Honourable William Mountague Craven Howard Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath
Sir Henry Monson Sir Thomas Hussey Sir John Newton Sir John Brownlow Sir John Tirwitt Sir Robert
Markham Sir John Thorold Sir Willoughby Hickman Sir William Ellis Sir Richard Cust Sir Edward Hussey
Sir William Buck Sir Richard [Bothwell<ref idref="n47">47</ref>] Sir John Oldfield Sir Thomas Trollop Sir John Bolles Sir Walter
Clarges Baronets [Sir Tho Meers Sir Edw: Ayscough Knt Sir Thomas Barnardiston Sir William Massenberd,
Sir John Sherrard Baronets<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] Sir William Yorke Sir Christopher Nevill Sir Edmond Turner Knights Sir Henry
[Henry<ref idref="n49">49</ref>] Heron Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Skipwith Baronet Sir Christopher Nevill Charles Dimock Champion
Charles Pelham William Marwood Thomas Broughton William Godfrey Thomas Lister Henry Stones Robert
Ryley Noell Neale Edward Paine Edward Mountague John Saunders William Welby William Hyde senior
William Hyde junior Anthony Palmer Christopher Clapham Pury Cust Esquires The Maior Aldermen and
Recorder of Lincolne The Maior Aldermen and Recorder of Grimsby The Mayor Aldermen and Recorder of
Boston The Mayor Aldermen and Recorder of Stamford The Aldermen of Grantham Edward Seaker Doctor
Leigh John Key Edward Coddington Simon Grant Robert Cole Thomas Cole Nicholas Becke William Clarke
Nathaniell Garthwaite Gentlemen Anthony Wingfield Charles Halford Peregrine Bertie of Gedney Esquires The
Warden of Louth Charles Fitz Williams John Newton Mountague Cholmley William Brownlow Richard Winch
Stephen Rothwell William Trollop Peregrine Buck Esquires John Goodrick Esq[uire] Richard Pell Samuell Ludington
Esquires John Browne Gentleman William Mountague Sir Edward Farmer Knight John Bolt John Wood Benjamine
King Andrew Burton Gentlemen Gilbert Bery Esq[uire] Peter Bird Gentleman Thomas Berry Ciprian Thornton
Edward Journey Christopher Berisford Charles Wooley Thomas Hall Vincent Grantham [Francis Grantham<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] George
Witchcott George Neville Bryan Neville Christopher Aiscough William Oldfield Esquires Deane and Chapter of
Lincolne Robert Cawdron George Hill Thomas Cowley Esquires Lake Gentleman John Harvey Esquire
George Fairfax Thomas Young William Tomson of Roxholine Gentlemen John Hussey John Chaplin Mathew
Lister Mathew Trollop Robert Rider senior Dimocke Walpoole John Bishop Esquires Richard Torsey John
Pindar George Knight Christopher Palmer Gentlemen Sigismond Trafford Francis [Putley<ref idref="n50">50</ref>] Peter Short Esquires
Benjamine Smith Gentleman Robert Archer Esquire Richard Cuthbert Charles Newcomen Gentlemen Charles
Fox Rawston Hart Edward Browne of Horbling Esq[uire] Charles Bates Esquire John How Gentleman John Toller
Esq[uire] John Greene junior Gent. George Langton senior George Langton junior Charles Hutton Robert Fisher
Francis Anderson Edmond Anderson Edwin Anderson John Rossiter Esquires James Ashton John Towne George
Smith William Bonner Gentlemen Joseph Edmonds Esquire Henry Jenkinson Henry Burrell Captaine Pownell
Esquires William Wallett William Ambler Francis Corey Gentlemen Ruben Sparks John Jay Walter Johnson
Esquires Martin Johnson Gentleman Robert Tirwhit Esq[uire] Peter Mapletoft John Emerson Gentlemen Daniell
Rhodes Esquire John Butler William Cauthrop Gentlemen Daniell de Line Robert Saunders Esquires Adam Bland
Gentlemen Richard Nelthrop Ciriack Westlid John Thorold Isaac Newton Esq[uire] John Burslem Thomas [Collivon<ref idref="n51">51</ref>]
Gentlemen Robert Tigh Thomas Harneys Lucas junior John Burton William Cotton Gentlemen John
Apleyard Francis Aiscough Esquires Thomas Webberley John Key Gentlemen John Evans William Tayler of
Heckington Edward Curtis.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s63">
			<head>For the City of London</head>
			<para id="p65">Sir Thomas Pilkington Knight Lord Mayor and the Lord Mayor for the time being Sir Thomas Aleine Sir
John Lawrence Sir Robert Clayton Sir Patience Ward Sir Robert Jeffrey Aldermen Sir William Pritchard The
Recorder for the time being Sir Jonathan Raymond Sir Thomas Stampe Sir Samuell Dashwood Sir Benjamine
Thorowgood Sir Thomas Kensie Sir William Ashurst Sir John Fleete Sir Peter Rich Sir William Goslin Sir
Thomas Lane Sir Humphry Edwin Edward Clarke Sir Francis Childe Aldermen Sir Christopher Lethieulier and
Sir John Houblin Aldermen and Sheriffes and the Sheriffes for the time being Sir Henry Ashurst Sir William
Turner Sir John Cope Sir William Williams Sir Thomas Litleton Sir Thomas Clargis Sir Mathew Andrews Sir
Benjamine Newland Sir John Mathews Sir William Cooper Sir Peter Vandeput Sir Thomas Fowle Sir Jeremy
Sambrooke Sir Gabriell Roberts Sir William Hodges Sir John Lethieulier Sir Ralph B Sir Richard
Raines Sir Thomas Halton Sir Thomas Vernon William Kiffin Joseph Herne Thomas Turgis Thomas Papillion
Collonell John Birch Thomas Westerne Charles Thorold Thomas Fredricke Samuell Sumerford Thomas Owen
Charles Duncombe Jeffery Nightingale Francis Thacker Paul Jodrell George Sitwell Martin Rider Esquires Lucy
Knightley Peter Houblan James Houblan John Gardiner William Moyler Charles Chamberlaine John Jolliffe John
Hainond Samuell Mayne Thomas Langham William Faukner Andrew Keurick Gilbert Heathcot Major Henry
Hatley Richard Chiswell Augustin Ballow Phillip Scarfe Thomas Eyre Michaell Godfrey Timothy Lanoy John
Deagle Arthur Shallet John Carey Samuell Moyer Daniell Allen James Denew Stephen Evans Francis [Gorfright<ref idref="n52">52</ref>]
William Gun William Ivat Lieutenant Collonell Robert Hatton William Strudwick George Oxinden Doctor of
Laws Samuell Wiggins John Cullum John Rayley Christopher Forster Thomas Firmin John Flavell [William<ref idref="n53">53</ref>] Cresner
John Morrice William Lethieulier Major Cuthbirt Jacob Foster Daniell Dorvill Francis Chamberlaine John Ward
Francis Griffith John Johnson Robert Dormer Esquire Robert Doddington William Gore Thomas Sandford Francis
Dashwood Esquires Captaine John Somers William Walker William Lethelieur Dorvell.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s64">
			<head>For Serjeants Inne in Fleetstreete.</head>
			<para id="p66">Lord Chiefe Justice Pollexfen Lord Chiefe Baron Atkins Mr Justice Dolben Mr Justice Rookby Mr Justice
[Ventricks<ref idref="n54">54</ref>] Mr Baron Lechmere Mr Baron Turton.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s65">
			<head>For Serjeants Inne in Chauncery Lane</head>
			<para id="p67">Lord Chiefe Justice Holt Mr Baron Nevill Mr Justice Powell Mr Justice Gregory Mr Justice Eyres Mr Serjeant
Hutchins Mr Serjeant George Strode Mr Serjeant Bigland Mr Serjeant Thurbarne.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s66">
			<head>For the Inner Temple and the Innes of Chauncery belonging thereto viz. Cliffords Inne Clements Inne and
Lyons Inne.</head>
			<para id="p68">Thomas Trevor William Farrer John Osborne Esquires Sir John Trevor Knight Thomas Farrer Esq[uire] Sir Robert
Sawyer Knight the Honourable Heneage Finch Esq[uire] John Mosier Esq[uire] Sir William Poultney Knight Charles
Holloway Esquire Paull Foley Esquire Edward Ward William Petyt Esq[uire] Sir Nathaniell Powell Knight.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s67">
			<head>For the Midle Temple and [Inns<ref idref="n55">55</ref>] of Chauncery thereto belonging viz New Inne.</head>
			<para id="p69">Sir George Treby Knight Their Majestyes Attourney Generall Sir John Sommers Knight Their Majestyes Sollicitor
Generall Sir Charles Porter Sir William Whitlock Knights The Honourable Oliver Mountague Richard Wallop
Esquires.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s68">
			<head>For the County of Middlesex</head>
			<para id="p70">Charles Lord Herbert Marquesse of Worcester Sonne and Heire Apparent [to<ref idref="n56">56</ref>] his Grace the Duke of Beaufort
The Right Honourable Edward Russell Esquire Sonne of the Earle of Bedford Charles Lord Cheney Henry
Powle Esq[uire] one of their Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill and Speaker of the Honourable House of
Commons The Right Honourable Sir John Mainard Knight and Baronet Sir Anthony Keck and Sir William
Rawlinson Lords Commissioners for the Custody of the Great Seale of England Sir John Holt Knight Lord
Chiefe Justice of Their Majestyes Court of Kings Bench Sir Henry Pollexfen Knight Lord Chiefe Justice of Their
Majestyes Court of Common Pleas Sir Robert Atkins senior Knight of the Bath Lord Chiefe Baron of Their
Majestyes Court of Exchequer The Right Honourable Henry Lord Coleraine of the Kingdome of Ireland Lord
Faulkland The Right Honourable Robert Lord Willoughby of Eresby Chauncellor of Their Majestyes Dutchy and
County Palatine of Lancaster Sonne and Heire Apparent to Robert Earle of Lindsey Lord Great Chamberlaine
of England Charles Lord Brandon Sonne and Heire Apparent to Charles Earl of Maclesfeld The Honourable
Henry Paget Esq[uire] The Honourable Sir Robert Howard The Honourable Craven Howard Esq[uire] The Honourable
Edward Mountague Esq[uire] Sir Charles Gerrard Sir William Cooper Sir William Robarts Baronets Sir Anthony
Craven Knight and Baronet Sir William Smith Sir Cave James Sir Richard Fisher Sir Paul Whichcott Sir
William Barkham Sir Thomas Pope Blunt Sir Hele Hooke Sir Thomas Litleton Baronets Sir Thomas Clarges
Sir William Poultney Sir Robert Henley Sir Thomas Byde Sir William Cooper Sir John Elwes Sir James Butler
Sir James Rushout Sir Thomas Rowe Sir Richard Dounton Sir William Hill Sir Francis Pemberton Sir Henry
Johnson Sir Theodore de Vaux Sir John Berry Sir Thomas Kensey Sir Bazill Firebrasse Sir William Hedges Sir
Mathew Andrews Sir Charles Cotterell Sir Edward Waldoe Sir Thomas Grantham Sir John Roberts Sir Purbecke
Temple Sir William Perkins Sir Goddard Nelthopp Sir Edward Abney Sir Adam Otteley Sir James Astrey Sir
Francis Childe Knights Sir Thomas Hodgshon Sir Cornwall Bradshaw Sir Michaell Heneage Sir William Ashurst
Sir Robert Henley Sir Walter Clarges Sir William Pritchell Knights Sir William Wogan Serjeant at Law Charles
Mountague Esquire Sir Richard Newdigate Baronet Sir William Williams Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Marwood
Baronet Sir John Bancks Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Ashurst Baronet Sir Charles Umphrevill Robert Dormer
Esq[uire] Ralph Bucknall Richard Onslow of Hatton-Garden (<ref idref="n57">57</ref>) Thomas Done Brooke Bridges Esquires Auditors of Their
Majestyes Imprest John Philips Esquire Auditor of Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer Nicholas Rainton John
Wolstenholme Josua Galliard James Munday William Avery John Smith Adam Andrews Edward Harris John
Huxley John Bathurst Thomas Austen William Austen William Tate William Blucke Peniston Whaley Cheeke
Gerrard Thomas Francklin Richard Page John Nicholl Lancelot Lake Edmond Prideaux John Carpender Thomas
Napier Ralph Hawtrey George Sitwell Edward Maplisden Richard Shorditch John Stanion Francis Ashby Lancelot
Johnson Roger Jennings Francis Merrick Thomas Harrison John Walker of Hillingdon William Gulston John
Walker of Hadley James Chadwick William Mellith James Southaby Henry Hawley Christopher Clitherowe
Nicholas Grice Thomas Owen John Davenport Robert Beale Robert Newdigate Henry Collins Thomas Pearshouse
Henry Reynell Thomas Wood Leonard Hamond Charles Duncombe John Jones Thomas Manning Daniell Proctor
John Slater Humphrey Etherington Henry Barker Esq[uire] Clerke of the Crowne Robert Sheffield Thomas Henshaw
Thomas Methold John Creed Gregory King Thomas Webb Thomas Henslo Thomas Aston Francis Brand Richard
Tayler Anthony Nourse Thomas Gregg Edward Allen John Raymond Richard Cradock Isaac Honeywood Paul
Jodrell Clerke to the Honourable House of Commons Richard Aston Thomas Harriot Thomas Hall James Dewey
Thomas Smith William Culliford Jeffery Nightingall William Withers John Perry Edward Northey Francis Tison
Thomas Cooke Thomas Casse Thomas Johnson Lucy Knightley Paull Duckmanque Peter Bundue Boone
William Willis Will: Johnson Nathaniell Owen Captaine Will. [Windy<ref idref="n58">58</ref>] Captaine John North Captaine Will. Wifeild
[Captaine John North Captaine Will: Ifeild<ref idref="n59">59</ref>] George Ford [Henry<ref idref="n60">60</ref>] Wakelin Henry Russell Richard Savile Henry
Risby (<ref idref="n61">61</ref>) Joseph Blisset Craven Peyton Ralph Bucknall John Le Neve Henry Hassard Samuell Bucke Richard Milner
Narcissus Lutterell Francis Twisden William Bridges Thomas Hobbs Robert Heyton William Freeman of St Giles Thomas
Simpson Albion Chaire William Thursby Esq[uire] John Cooke Thomas Windford William Tempest Esquires Prothonotaries
of the Court of Common Pleas at Westminster Francis Browne Samuell Somerford Edmond Griffen Roger Stoughton
Anthony Rowe Samuell Buck William Etricke Edward Bide Ralph Bide Hugh Simpson John Crosse Thomas Milward
Robert Clerkson Foote Onslow Charles [Bouxton<ref idref="n62">62</ref>] Francis Thacker Edward Noell Esquires Thomas Rudd John Hall
Gentlemen The Honourable Thomas Newport Esq[uire] James Chadwicke Esq[uire] Charles Hawtrey John Jennings of Hesse
Dixon of Hesse Adam Wareing William Fenn John Page senior Richard Lugg William Walker Nathaniell Lacy
Henry Burdet of Tottenham Samuell Pointer William Bampfield Richard Cheslin William Webb Abraham Nelson
Robert Skinner John Hookes Ambrose Isted Thomas Harris Anthony [Guidott<ref idref="n63">63</ref>] George Edwards Carew Guydot
Samuell Trotman John Cannon John Meridale John Baley Francis Barry James Alter Smart Goodenough William
Warr John Bourne Robert Cowden Captaine Richard Chinay George Board Nathaniell Mountage John Goldsborow
Thomas Grumble Captaine John Field Buckler Buggins Robert Clarkson Ralph Coule Mr Palmer Mr Midleton
Mr Bayley Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s69">
			<head>For the City and Liberty of Westminster</head>
			<para id="p71">Edward Lord Cornbury Lord Faulkland of the Kingdome of Ireland the Honourable Sir Robert Howard Sir
Thomas Clarges Sir William Poultney Richard Lord Gorges in the Kingdome of Ireland The Honourable Thomas
Newport Sir Peter Colliton Sir Walter Clerges Sir Thomas Rowe Sir Samuell Grimston Sir John Cutler Phillip
Howard Esq[uire] Craven Howard Esq[uire] Sir Phillip Meadowes Sir Thomas Mompesson Sir Charles Cotrell Sir John
Elwes Sir Christopher Wrenn Sir Roger Langley Sir Charles Umfrevill Collonell Sackvill William Bridgeman Richard
Morley Esquires Thomas Done Brooke Bridges Hugh Squire John Poultney Esquires John Phillips James Vernon Charles
Toll Charles Bertie Robert Nott Charles Bonithon Paul Jodrell Tho: Watkins Andrew Lawrence Edmond Waller
David Crawford Henry Thynn William Ball Albaine Cheere Thomas Sackvile Anthony [Now<ref idref="n64">64</ref>] John Smalbone John
Currance John Creed Simon Smith Esq[uire]rs Simon Smith Merchant Walter Bridall Joshua Drayner Francis Negus
John Martin Charles Twitty Morris Hunt Bartholomew Fillingham William Lownes Esq[uire]s Phillip Ryley Robert
Squib Esquires Crispe Grange Edmund Godwin Edmund Fuller Thomas Templeman John Worley John Stone
Michaell Miles Robert Briceden William Maskell [Dionesius<ref idref="n65">65</ref>] Andrewes Ralph Hutchinson Ralph Marshall Esq[uire]
Edmund Woodruffe Esq[uire] Robert Gisburne Charles Rampanie William Shaw Esquire John Tully Marke Lawne
Richard Fitzgerald John Ressington Matthias Cooper John Pottinger Esq[uire] Charles Chetwind Gentleman Sir Robert
Henley Knight William Thursby Esq[uire] John Cooke Thomas Winford William Tempest John Frost Esquires Richard
Campion William Greene Erasmus Dryden John England Richard Stephens Joseph Biscow Samuell Birch John
Comes Alexander Mann James Hulker James Chace George Nicholas Anthony Crahreede John Tisser Esquire
Doctor William Stockholme Doctor [Fieldencie<ref idref="n66">66</ref>] James Coningham John Ward Esq[uire] Mordet Creherode
Nehemiah Arnold John Taylder Thomas Martis Mr Withins Robert Brock William Salisbury Mr Thomas
Browne John Dolben William Hooker Edward Noell John Squibb Esquires William Barnaby Charles Brandon
Butler Buggins Thomas Hall Esquire Garrard Cotter Thomas Watson Esq[uire] Richard Rider George Bishop Robert
Harrison John Wilson Charles Mainewareing Esq[uire] Thomas Broughton Esq[uire] Richard Adams Goldsmith and Sir
Cornwall Bradshaw All the Officers of the Board of GreeneCloath for the time being Augustin Beare Thomas
Owen Esq[uire] Michaell Babbington Charles Twidder Collonell Edward Mayne Bartholomew Fillingham John Anger
Richard Fisher Joseph Cragg Esquires Simon Smith Esq[uire] Robert Stretur Robert Wood William Richards Esq[uire]
The Honourable Thomas Newport Esquire John Smith Esq[uire] Sir Francis Childe Knight Sir Thomas Litleton John
Walker [John<ref idref="n67">67</ref>] Gulston Humphry Ethrington William Mellish Esquires William Wogan Sergeant at Law James
Sotherby Thomas Mansell John Briscoe William Gulston Esquires Doctor Harvey Charles Peters Benjamin Schodee.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s70">
			<head>For the Society of Grays-Inne and the Innes of Chancery thereto belonging Viz Staple Inne and Barnards Inne.</head>
			<para id="p72">Sir William Williams Knight and Baronet Sir John Otway Knight John Amhurst George Gifford Samuell Buck
Thomas Temple Warner South Ralph Cooke Thomas Godrin Reginald Bretland John Brewer Richard Vaughan
Roger Fenwick Esquires.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s71">
			<head>For Lincolns Inne and Inns of Chauncery thereto belonging viz</head>
			<para id="p73">Sir William Yorke Knight Sir James Boteler Knight John Eldred James Stedman Luke Astrey John Hely
Robert Eyres Edward Stroude Thomas Windham Roger Mompesson Robert Dormer Esquires Thomas Washer
Gentleman John Hawles.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s72">
			<head>For the County of Monmouth</head>
			<para id="p74">Charles Lord Marquesse of Worcester Sonne and Heire Apparent of the Duke of Beaufort Sir Charles Kemeys
Sir Trevor Williams Sir John Morgan Baronets Sir Rowland Gwyn Sir James Herbert Knights Thomas Morgan
of Tredegar Richard Lewis John Williams Henry Probert Thomas Lewis John Arnold Charles Van Richard Lister
John Howe Thomas Morgan of Lawrumney Charles Price Hopton Williams Henry Morgan of Bedwelly Edmond
Morgan Edward Jones Roger Oates George Kemeys Edward Perkins John Morgan of Tredegar Lewis Morgan
Capell Hanbury Thomas Jones John Walter John Floyer Charles Hughes Robert Gunter James Morgan of Lantilio
Pertholey Charles Morgan of Tredegar John Prichard of Campson Nicholas Parker Christopher Price Nicholas
Arnold George Harris Walter Williams Thomas Williams Rodericke Gwynn Morgan Chambers David Morgan
Mathew Powell Henry Tomkins Richard Roberts John Scudamore Martin Scudamore James Morgan Esquires
William Blethin Edward Kemeys John Lewis of Ifton Hill John Morgan of Ballendege John Ketchmay Rowland
Williams Matthias Bird Walter Aldey Robert Jones Charles Williams Nehemiah Williams John Morgan of Grace
Due John Craggs Walter Fortune William Morgan Theophilus Reynolds Richard Jones Walter Cecill John Jones
Roger Williams John Harris of Bergavenny William Powell of Poole Hall Richard Vaughan Francis Williams
Morgan Thomas John Watkins Trevor Merricke William Evans William Price John Gwilliam Francis Pritchard
Nathan Rogers Shelden Powell the Mayor of Monmouth the Mayor of Newport the Portreve of Uske the Bayliffe
of Abergavenny Israell Waters Hugh Harris William Seyes Charles Jones of Magor Henry Ocold William Pritchard
of Langattock William George of the same George Lewis of Saint Peere John Morgan of Lanthewy James
Springet Michaell Bohume Clarke of Grace Due Gentleman.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s73">
			<head>For the County of Norfolk.</head>
			<para id="p75">Sir Robert Bacon Sir Henry Hobart Sir Robert Drury Sir John Holland Sir Augustine Palgrave Sir John
[Petrust<ref idref="n68">68</ref>] Sir Robert Kemp Sir Jacob Asteley Sir Roger Potts Sir Thomas Ward Sir William Cooke Sir Edmond
Doyley Sir Thomas Adams Sir Peter Glean Sir Thomas Gerrard Baronets Sir Nevill Catelin Sir Francis Guybon
Sir William Rant Sir John Turner Sir Edward Chisonhall Sir Cerill Wich Rich: Perry of Kirby Thomas Knivet
Robert Walpole John Harbord Edmond Woodhouse John Warkhouse John Knivett Thomas Baespoole James
Hoste Robert Wardell Joathim Mathews Percy Freake John Herne William Stone John Jay Robert Coney Gabriell
Armiger Richard Wyth Francis Gardner Robert Sucklin John Woodhouse Francis Windham Charles Le Grosse
Edward Soame John Norris Daniell Bedingfield Christopher Crow Robert Wilson Edward Wilson Erasmus Earle
Thomas Browne Francis Repps John Repps Charles Wright Riches Browne Henry Negus John Herne Robert
Davy Arthur Branthwait Nathaniell Simons Edmond Brittiffe George England Edmond Lamb Hatton Bemers
Robert Day John Ayd Thomas Wright Hugh Hovell Edward Le Strange Henry Marsham William Oldfield
Clement Hearne Robert Gouch Thomas Townshend John Thurston John Cropley Isaac Preston Thomas Bulwer
Brigg Fountaine William Branthwaite Robert [Brainsby<ref idref="n69">69</ref>] Benjamin England Phillip Bedingfield Francis Negus Richard
Carter John Brewster Valentine Pell James Host junior Thomas Rant Robert Doughty Augustine Briggs Samuell
Fuller Robert London of Loddon Oliver Neve John Anguish Mundiford Spelman Leonard Mayes Francis Thursby
George Townshend Gascoin Weld Anthony Freston Thomas Talbott John Richmond Edward Osborne Gardiner
Hewit John Pannell John Mingay Robert Buxton William Sydley Israell Long Thomas Blofield [Esquires<ref idref="n70">70</ref>] Robert
Herne Robert Stileman Francis Dusgate Doctor Pepper John Page Richard Ferier Lucy Blackman John Castle
Edward Bulwer Robert [Jenny<ref idref="n71">71</ref>] John Houghton Brampton Gourdon Jonathan Simonds William Rudin Thomas
Saunders Ralph Hare James Ward Esq[uire] Thomas Crick Charles Turner junior Brograve of Thorpland
Birken Benjamin Dethwick John Burrowes of De Thomas Newman Roger Jennings junior Esq[uire] Sir Phillip
Skippon Denzell Onslow Esq[uire] Sir Robert Clayton.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s74">
			<head>For the City and County of the City of Norwich.</head>
			<para id="p76">The Mayor for the time being Robert Davie Esq[uire] Recorder Robert Ward Esq[uire] Steward Sir Nevill Catlin
Thomas Blofield Esq[uire] The two Sheriffes for the time being Thomas Wisse (<ref idref="n72">72</ref>) Robert Bendish Hugh Bokenham
Robert Freeman John Low Nicholas Helwis Francis Gardiner William Salter Phillip Stebbing John Wrench Thomas
Cooke [Esq[uire]s<ref idref="n73">73</ref>] Robert Cooke Leonard Osbourne Jeremy Wynne Augustine Briggs Nicholas Bickerdicke John Ward
John Leverington William Guybon Michaell Beverley Samuell Warkehouse Thomas Postle Lawrence Goodwin
Aldermen Doctor Fairefax Deane of Norwich Doctor Pepper Thomas Townshend Esq[uire] John Mingay Francis Bacon
Thomas Bacon Arthur Branthwaite [Esquires<ref idref="n74">74</ref>] John Barnham John Dersley John Macherell Gent..</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s75">
			<head>For the Burrough of Great Yarmouth.</head>
			<para id="p77">The Bayliffes for the time being George England Esq[uire] Steward Samuell Fuller Robert Bramsby Esquires Edmond
Thaxter Richard Huntington Peter Caulier Mitchell Mew George Ward Thomas England Thomas Bradford Benjamine
England John Robbins John Ferrier Nathaniell Simons Thomas Godfrey Gabriell Ward Richard Ferrier Alderman.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s76">
			<head>For the Burrough of Kings Lynn.</head>
			<para id="p78">The Mayor for the time being Daniell Bedingfield Recorder Sir John Turner Sigismond Trafford Benjamin Holly
Giles Bridgeman John Kidd Edmond Hooke Benjamine Keene Charles Peast Henry Bell Charles Turner Ciprian
Anderson.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s77">
			<head>For Thetford</head>
			<para id="p79">Sir John Holland Sir Francis Guybon Wormly Hetherset William Croply John Thurstone Charles Wright
Thomas Wright Edmond de Gray Morris Kendall John Draper Edmond Winwood Thomas Smith Robert Caudell.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s78">
			<head>For the County [of<ref idref="n75">75</ref>] Northampton</head>
			<para id="p80">Jeremy Dove of Nottingham Arthur Brookes of Great Oakely Thomas Maidwell of Geddington Esquires Robert
Barton of Brigstocke Gentleman Sir William Farmer of Easton Weston Baronet Francis Arundell of Stocke Parke
Francis Crane of the same Thomas Jennings of Hartwell Esq[uire] Samuell Rolt of Alverton Gentleman John Parkhurst
of Catesby Henry Benson of Dadford Richard Butler senior of Preston Capes John Combes of Daventree William
Adams of Charwelton John Winston of Everdon Esquires Sir William Craven of Winwick Knight Sir Roger Cave
Baronet William Bateman of Gilsburrow Esq[uire] Sir Saint Andrew Saint John of Woodford Baronet John Bridges of
Barton Segrave John Weaver of Cranford William Fleetwood of Alwinckle Thomas Malsho of Twywell Henry
Sawyer of Kettering Thomas Catesby of Ecton William Wilmore of Sywell Goddard Pemberton of Higham Ferrers
Esquires The Mayor of Higham Ferrers for the time being Thomas Ekins of Rushden William Alston of Strixton
John Wiseman of Boseatt Francis Harby of Adston Thomas Trist of Maidford Jacob Dancer of Siresham Esquires
Sir Thomas Samuell of Baronet Thomas Andrewes of Harleston Henry Rushton of Floore Richard
Rainsford of Dallington John Thornton of Brockhall Robert Breton of Teeton Esquires Sir John Pickering of
Tytchmarsh Sir Mathew Dudley Baronets Jeffery Palmer of Stocke Doyle Sydney Wortley ais Mountague Charles
Fitzwilliams Gilbert Dolben Henry Neale of Stamford Baron John Royley of the same William Clarke of
Dorsthorpe Thomas Hacke of Peterburrough Esquires John Carrier of the same Gentleman John Dickinson of the
same Esquire John Wildbore of the same Gentleman Sir Justiniam Isham Baronet Sir William Langham Knight
Edward Saunders of Brixworth Harrald Kinsman of Broughton Bernard Walcot of Oundle Thomas Colthurst of
[Warrington<ref idref="n76">76</ref>] Esquires Mathew Orleber of Polebrooke Gentleman Francis Lane of Clendon Andrew Lant of Thorpe
Underwood Robert Mansell of Thorpe Mansor John Allicock of [Hoddington<ref idref="n77">77</ref>] Thomas Langham of Arthingworth
Esquires Lord Wainman Sir Pope Danvers Baronet William Lisle of Evenly Samuell Trist of Culworth John
Bagshaw of the same John Creswell of Purston John [Wodell<ref idref="n78">78</ref>] of Fenford Esquires John Blencow Sergeant at Law
the Mayor of Brackley for the time being Robert Frueing of Brackley Gentleman Francis Morgan of Kingsthorpe
Edward Stratford of Overston William Thursby of Abbington Harvey Ekins of Weston Flamell William Benson
of Towcester Richard Lockwood of Gayton Edward Mountague of Horton Henry Farmer Henry Edmonds of
Preston William Tate of Delapree Toby Chauncey of Edgecott Esquires Thomas Wagstaffe of Boddington Gentleman
Francis [Woodhill<ref idref="n79">79</ref>] of Warden Gentleman Edward Bagshaw of Aston on the Walls Samuell Tryone of Collyweston
Thomas Jackson of Duddington Esquires.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s79">
			<head>For the Towne of Northampton</head>
			<para id="p81">Mayor of Northampton for the time being Robert Heslerig Esquire Gerrard Gore Esq[uire] Salathiell Lovell
Sergeant at Law Robert Breton Esq[uire] John Knight Gent Richard Willoughby Esq[uire] John Selby John Brafield
John Clarke Edward [Knight<ref idref="n80">80</ref>] Robert Ives.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s80">
			<head>For the County of Northumberland</head>
			<para id="p82">Sir Ralph Delavall Sir John Heron Sir William Midleton Sir Thomas Lorraine Sir William Blacket (<ref idref="n81">81</ref>) Baronets
Sir Ralph Jennison Sir Robert Fenwicke Sir Francis Blake Knights Ralph Delavall William Forster Phillip
Bickerstaffe Roger Fenwicke Phillip Babington Thomas Forster John Shaftoe John Salkeld Robert [Whitford<ref idref="n82">82</ref>] of
Sighell Thomas Forster of Cornwall Thomas Collingwood John Blackiston John Hindmarsh Robert Bewick John
Sarnaby William Strother of Fobeny William Ogle William Carr Michaell Welden Henry Holmes Francis Addison
Charles Howard Joseph Carr Patricius Crowe William Revelly George Delavall Thomas Blenkinship Robert Hebron
John Bacon John Blacket Robert Lawson Thomas Allgood Robert Shaftoe Esquires Robert Lisle John Proctor
Richard Forster John Colson Samuell Salkeld William Ramsey of Brinckburne William Strother of Grindon Rigg
Francis Forster John Gray of Howick William Fenwicke Arthur Fenwicke Bayliffes of Morpeth Robert Fenwicke
Ralph Gery of Backworth George Lawson John Fenwicke Ralph Brandling Gilbert Parke George Wilson Ralph
Anderson William Peirson Thomas Gray Gent. George Collingwood Esq[uire].</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s81">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Newcastle upon Tyne.</head>
			<para id="p83">William Carr Esq[uire] Mayor Sir Robert [Shafts<ref idref="n83">83</ref>] Knight Recorder Sir William Blacket Baronet Sir Ralph Carr Knight
Timothy Davison Esq[uire] George Moreton Esq[uire] Timothy Robson Esq[uire] Nicholas Fenwicke Esq[uire] William Aubeny Esq[uire]
Nicholas Ridley Esq[uire] William Ramsey Esq[uire] William Proctor Esq[uire] Aldermen William Fetherston Sheriffe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s82">
			<head>For the Towne of Berwicke</head>
			<para id="p84">Ephraim Nealson Esq[uire] Mayor Sir Francis Blake Knight Phillip Babbington Esq[uire] Anthony Compton John Lucke
Stephen Jackson Edward Nealson senior John Sleath Robert Watson Mark Scott Cuthbert Brady William Scott.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s83">
			<head>For the County of Nottingham</head>
			<para id="p85">Patricius Viscount Chaworth of the Kingdome of Ireland The Honourable Anchitell Grey Esq[uire] The Honourable
William Byron Esq[uire] Sir Thomas Willoughby Baronet Sir Thomas [Perkins<ref idref="n84">84</ref>] Baronet Sir Scroope How Francis
Pierpoint William Sacheverell Richard Mansfeild Thomas Lewis William Williams Charles Hutchinson Phillip Sherrard
Esquires John Kerchervile of Orson Gentleman William Woolehouse Gentleman Richard Fanes of [Esperton<ref idref="n85">85</ref>] Gent.
Thomas Barret Gent. Sir William Stanhope Henry Bambrig Gent. Thomas Sharpe of Barnby Gent. Henry
Sherbrooke [Gent.<ref idref="n86">86</ref>] Arthur Warren Richard Slater Gilbert Millington Robert Sherbrooke William Burnell Esquires
Francis Mollineux Charles Stanhope William [Pickney<ref idref="n87">87</ref>] Darcy Mollineux John Digby John Strey Thomas Bristow
Gentleman John Thornhaugh John White John Knight Richard Tayler. William Mellish of Blyth Francis Jessopp
Francis Sandys Francis Stringer Gervas Eyre John Clerkson John Storey Esquires William Simpson (<ref idref="n88">88</ref>) [Jeremy Halsey<ref idref="n86">86</ref>]
Gentleman The Mayor of Newarke for the time being The six senior Aldermen for the time being Doctor
Yarborough Samuell Ellis Gentleman Timothy Ellis Gentleman Snell Gentleman William Clay of
Newarke William Welby Gentleman The Bayliffes of Retford for the time being William Lane Esq[uire] William Duriston
Simon Woolby James Mason William Hydes Thomas Sharpe Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s84">
			<head>For the Towne of Nottingham</head>
			<para id="p86">Charles Harvey Esq[uire] Maior John Dane Esq[uire] Francis Jessop Esq[uire] Richard Mansfield Esquire Samuell Staples Esq[uire]
George Langford Alderman John Hawkins Alderman William Greaves senior Gentleman William Drury senior
Gent Thomas Trigg Gent..</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s85">
			<head>For the County of Oxford</head>
			<para id="p87">Anthony Lord Viscount Faulkland of the Kingdome of Scotland Richard Lord Wainman Viscount Tuan of the
Kingdome of Ireland Robert Lord Tiveott of the Kingdome of Scotland Mountague Lord Norreys Sonne and
Heire Apparent to James Earle of Abington The Honourable Richard Hambden one of His Majestyes most
Honourable Privy Councill [The Ho&ntilde;ble Henry Bertue Esq[uire]<ref idref="n86">86</ref>] Sir John Cope Sir Robert Jenkinson Sir Fairmedon
Penniston Sir William Walter Sir Edward Reade Sir William Clynne Sir Edmond Fettyplace Sir Litleton Osbaldiston
Sir Robert Dashwood Sir John Holman Sir Thomas Litleton Sir John Doyley Sir Thomas Cobb Sir James
Chamberlaine Sir William Rich Baronets Sir Edward Hungerford Knight of the Bath Sir Edward Norreis Sir
Timothy Tyrrell Sir Thomas Tipping Sir James Hayes Sir Thomas Clayton Sir Thomas Rowe Sir Rowland Lacy
Sir Sebastian Smith Sir William Whitlocke Sir Edmond Warcopp Knights Anthony Hungerford Thomas Tipping
Richard Libb Esquires Edward Barry John Stone [Carelstone Stone<ref idref="n89">89</ref>] John Hambden George Alnutt Henry Alnutt
Francis Clarke William Lenthall John Dormer George Chamberlaine Rich [Chamberlaine<ref idref="n86">86</ref>] William Cannocke Thomas
Herd William Bayley John Croke Harry Cole Henry Heylin Robert Barber Robert Perrott James Perrott Richard
Powell William Pudsey Robert Sheppard Thomas Coghill Henry Hall John Wallis Esquires Adam Springall Robert
Jennings Thomas [Brightam<ref idref="n90">90</ref>] Symon Harcourt Thomas Wheate Robert Mayott Alexander Denton Edmond Goodier
Joseph Rawlinson Henry Ayleworth Henry Beeson and Edward Masters Doctors in Law Charles Holloway John
West William Oakly Ralph Holt Humphry Wickham John Gunne Lenthall Trotman John Bray William Walker
John Danvers Sunnybancke Veisay Roger Price Thomas Woodhall William Sacheverill Thomas Osbaldestone Henry
Peacocke Samuell Trotman Thomas Crispe of Darnford George Tipping of Draycott James Herbert Esq[uire] William
Tippinge of Ewelme Esq[uire] Richard Breddocke Lacy Osbaldestone William Blake Bartholomew Harris John Parsons
George Woodward John Wickham Mr Gregory of Horley George Cave Simon Worwood A Deane John Carey
Thomas Rowney Richard Tayler of Wilscott Francis Knapp Robert Parsons Henry Streete Richard Stephens Thomas
Carter Gilbert Jackson John Striblehill John Hickford Francis Greenway Richard [Evans<ref idref="n91">91</ref>] Anthony Evans Thomas
Greenwood Thomas Napper Richard Thompson Nicholas Busby Hawkins of Milton Sutton Coghill
John Coghill Martin May John Wheeler John Crispe Lawrence Lord John Croker John Dodwell John Wise of
Drayton John Smith Giles Diston Thomas Rolles Richard Croke Richard Blackhall George Gooding of Latchford
John Moreton Robert Standard Bezaliell Knight Gentlemen The Mayor Aldermen and Towne Clerke of the Towne
of Woodstocke for the time being The Mayor Recorder Aldermen and Towne Clerke of Banbury for the time
being The Warden of Henly for the time being The Bayliffes of Chipping Norton Burford and Whitney for the time
being Arthur Warren Esquire John Coker Gentleman John [Winslow<ref idref="n92">92</ref>] Edward Whistler of Gathampton Gentleman</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s86">
			<head>For the University of Oxford</head>
			<para id="p88">Doctor Jonathan Edwards Vice Chancellor the Honourable Heneage Finch Esq[uire] the Honourable William Leopald
Finch Warden of All Soules Sir Thomas Clayton Knight Warden of Merton Colledge Sir Thomas Clergis Knight
Doctor Henry Aldrich Deane of Christ Church Doctor John Hough Doctor Henry Beeston Doctor William
Levinz Doctor Robert Sey Doctor Timothy Halton Doctor William Jane Cannon of Christ Church Doctor John
Hamond of the same Doctor John Hall Doctor Ralph Bathurst Doctor Arthur Berry Doctor Thomas Turner Doctor
Thomas Bouchier Doctor Richard Lydell the Proctors for the time being Mr Benjamin Cooper Mr John Haslewood
Mr John Crosse Mr John Fulks Mr George Thompson Mr Thomas Moore Mr Edward Bartlet.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s87">
			<head>For the City of Oxford</head>
			<para id="p89">The Mayor for the time being the Honourable Henry Bertie Esq[uire] Sir Edward Norris Knight Sir John Cope Sir
Robert Jenkinson Sir John Doyley Sir Robert Dashwood Baronets Sir William Walker Knight John Townshend
Thomas Fifeild and Thomas Eustices Aldermen William Wright Recorder Collonell Henry Cope Tobias Browne
John Bowell John Crony Thomas Hunsden Edward Combs Charles Holloway and John Bateman Esquires Charles
Harris Gentleman and Edward Prince Towne Clerke Sir Robert Harrison Thomas Bee and Richard Keats Bailiffes
of the said City.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s88">
			<head>For the County of Rutland</head>
			<para id="p90">The Right Honourable Bennet Lord Sherrard of the Kingdome of Ireland the Honourable Phillip Sherrard Esq[uire]
Sir Thomas Mackworth Baronet Sir Thomas Barker Baronet William [Palmer<ref idref="n93">93</ref>] Esq[uire] Bennet Sherrard Esq[uire] John
Verney Esq[uire] Samuell Browne Esq[uire] Charles Halford Christopher Browne Edward Faulkener Robert [Mackleworth<ref idref="n94">94</ref>]
Cornelius Burton Edward Horseman Edward Browne John Weaver Charles Tyrrell Edward Faulkener junior John
Flavell Wellesborne Sill Richard Snow Thomas Hayes Anthony Palmer Esquires Richard Mathew [Andrew<ref idref="n95">95</ref>] Burton
Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s89">
			<head>For the County of Salop.</head>
			<para id="p91">The Honourable Richard Newport &amp; [Andrew Newport<ref idref="n95">95</ref>] Esquires Sir Henry Litleton Sir William Levison
Gore Sir William Whitmore Sir Humphry Briggs Sir John Corbet Sir Francis Lawley Sir Uvevat Corbett Sir
Edward Ackton Sir Francis Edwards Sir Thomas Litleton Sir William [Williams<ref idref="n95">95</ref>] Baronets Sir Job Charlton Sir
Lacon William Childe Knight Sir Thomas Woolrich Baronet Sir John Trevor Sir Thomas Jones Sir Adam
Oatley Sir Robert Owen Sir John Edwards Sir William Forrester Knights Jervas Pierpoint William Fowler
Francis Charleton of Appley John Charleton John Walcott Charles Manwairing Francis Forrester Edward Leighton
Richard Lister Edward Kineston of Oately Edward Kineston of Hordley Thomas Baudiwin John Kineston Phillip
Prince Henry [Harbert<ref idref="n96">96</ref>] Francis Herbert [Edward<ref idref="n95">95</ref>] Owen of Condover George Welt Humphry Briggs William
Oatley Robert Corbett Thomas Rocke John Coates Richard [Moore<ref idref="n95">95</ref>] Walter Wairein Charles [Badwin<ref idref="n97">97</ref>] Charles Coates
Robert Cresset Robert Owen Roger Pope senior Roger Pope junior Thomas Lloyd Richard Creswell John
Lacon Thomas [Oatley<ref idref="n98">98</ref>] Litleton Powis Henry Newton Francis Charlton of Whitton Thomas Cornwall Andrew
Hill Bartholomew Lutley Thomas Hill of Souton Thomas Kinnersley Thomas [Hanmore<ref idref="n99">99</ref>] Henry Davenport Eldred
Lancelott Leigh of Alveley Thomas Langley Robert Harley Richard Mason Thomas Childe Thomas Spratt
William Williams John Uxley John Chetwind Downes of Purslow Edward Kerry Orlando Nicholls Richard
Mitton Edward Cludd Rowland Hunt Henry Powell Jonathan Langley Tho Lister Tho Edwards Rich: Corbert
Robert Clowes John Tayleur Thomas Burton Thomas Smalman Soudley Eaton Robert Pigott Thomas Wingfield
Thomas Mackworth John Edwards of Rorington John Powell Thomas Powell Thomas Acton John Warter Francis
Berkley Arthur Weaver James Grove Thomas Jobber Robert Lloyd. John Whitehall Henry Mitton William
Heyward Esquires the Mayor of Salop for the time being the Bayliffes of Ludlow for the time being the
Bayliffes of Bridgenorth for the time being the Bayliffes of Bishops Castle for the time being the Bayliffes of
Wenlock for the time being the Bayliffes of Oswestrey for the time being Richard Carew Edward Owen of
Pulley William Jones Charles Herbert Ralph Browne Thomas Sandford Esquires Job Walker Edward Mitton William
Leeke Richard Hosier Richard Saller Edward Gosnell Roger Griffith Samuell Wollaston Richard Betton John
Langley of the Tuckis Adam Wareing Richard Deaves William Grosvenour Richard Jenkins Samuell Bowdler
Simon Hanmer Jonathan Scott Collins Wolrich Richard Muccleston Robert Wood John Bright Edward Pulley
Thomas Hawkes William Bridgen Thomas Crompton John Morris Thomas Sabry Thomas Hill of Alkaston John
Atkinson Doctor of Physicke Timothy Hassell Samuell Sandford George Chambre Jonathan Wingfield [Jonathan<ref idref="n100">100</ref>]
Latham George Walker John Langley of the Amys William Kinaston Lancelott Stephens Phillip Cole John Colbach
Francis Boycott Thomas Rogers Richard Walker Thomas Hincks Robert Smith John Fowler Thomas Mason
Richard [Ridby<ref idref="n101">101</ref>] Edward Brooks of Stretton Richard Bradley Alexander Midleton Edward Mathews Humphrey
Owen Samuell Hunt Francis Butler John Parker Arthur Tong and John Clarke Gent..</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s90">
			<head>For the County of Somerset</head>
			<para id="p92">The Right Honourable Maurice Lord Viscount Fitzharding The Honourable Sir Edward Seymour Baronet Sir
William Portman Baronet Sir John Smith Baronet Sir Edward Windham Baronet Sir John Trevillion Baronet
Sir Francis Warr Baronet Sir Haswell Tynts Baronet Sir Thomas Bridgesse Knight Sir William Basset Knight
Sir Edward Phillips Knight Sir John St Barb George Horner Edward Gorges Francis Lutterell Nathaniell Palmer
Edward Barker Thomas Windham John Hunt Henry Bull John Sandford William Hellier junior Thomas Saunders
Esquires Henry Rolls Esq[uire] Thomas Beare of Huntsome in [the<ref idref="n102">102</ref>] County of Devon Will: Helyar senior Warwicke
Bampfield John Pigott Edward [Barber<ref idref="n103">103</ref>] William Gore William Lacy senior George Long Thomas Chaffin John
Spekee Thomas Carew Edmond Windham Baldwin Mallet John Bluet John Ashford Joseph Langhton Henry
Mompesson William Strode Henry Gould William Coward William Phillips William Ettericke Richard Morgan
Edward Hobbs Esquires William Coward Richard Crosse Edward Clarke John Champneys Alexander Lutterell
James Prowse James Webb William Hiliard of Sea Henry Lite George Clerke Thomas Strode of Maperton
Robert Syderfin Ferrers Grisley Thomas Langhton Harry Roynon William Harbin Andrew Crosse Francis Vaughan
John How Richard [Lanfdowne<ref idref="n104">104</ref>] George Doddington William Cutford James Cade John Worth William Player
George Musgrave Samuell Gorges William Westley William Hughs James Twiford Richard Cox John Hody
junior John Sandys Roger Leversage William Whitchurch senior William Whitchurch junior Phillip Bennet Edward
Thurston Cornelius Lyde John Acourt Thomas Ledgenham William Champneys Summer of Wello John
Burland Samuell Raymond William Dyke William Blackford William Bacon George Bacon Robert Blake Matthias
Hanvile Henry Prater William Boulton Mr Blackdon of Milton Samuell Bindon Richard Snow Francis Hobart
Thomas Towills John Lucas Merchants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s91">
			<head>For the City and County of the City of Bristoll</head>
			<para id="p93">Arthur Hart Esq[uire] Mayor Sir Richard Hart Knight Sir Richard Crumpe Knt [Sir Thomas<ref idref="n105">105</ref>] Earle Knight Sir
John Knight Sir William Clutterbooke Knight Sir William Haman Knight Sir William Merricke Knight Sir
William Cann John Hicks William Crabb Joseph Cresswicke Abraham Saunders William Swimmer Richard Lane
Thomas Day William Jackson Edward Fielding [Esquire<ref idref="n105">105</ref>] William Pawlet Serjeant at Law and Recorder Esq[uire]
William Downing Esquire John Bubb John Blackersell Sheriffes George Hart Nathaniell Driver Edmond Arundell
Giles Merricke James Twiford Robert Yate George Morgan Edward Tocnell John Sandford Samuell Wallis John
Hyne Thomas Cole George White John Dutton Colt Esquires Michaell Pope Merchant Robert Henley Thomas
Edwards Gentlemen Richard Codrington John Yeomans senior Merchant.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s92">
			<head>For the City of Bath</head>
			<para id="p94">The Right Honourable Maurice Lord Viscount [Fitcharding<ref idref="n106">106</ref>] Sir William Bassett Knight The Mayor for the time
being Walter Gibbs Benjamin Baber Edward Bushell Alderman.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s93">
			<head>For the City of Wells.</head>
			<para id="p95">Edward Berkley Esq[uire] Thomas Windham Esq[uire] The Mayor for the time being William Coward Recorder George
Doddington Esq[uire] William Hughs Gent Richard Thomas.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s94">
			<head>For the Burrough of Bridgewater</head>
			<para id="p96">Sir Francis Warr Baronet Henry Bull Esq[uire] The Mayor for the time being Alderman Popham Alderman Gilbert.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s95">
			<head>For the County of Stafford</head>
			<para id="p97">The Right Honourable John Lord Viscount Mazarine of the Kingdome of Ireland The Honourable John Gray
The Honourable Henry Pagitt The Honourable William Ward Esquires Sir Thomas Pershall Sir Will: Levison
Gower Sir Walter Wrotesley Sir Henry Litleton Sir Edward Litleton Sir John Boyer Sir Thomas Bellet Sir
Francis Lawley Sir Michaell Biddulph Sir Thomas Wilbraham Sir Charles Wousley Baronets Sir Bryan Broughton
Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Hungerford Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Gough Sir Charles Skrimshire Sir
John Floyer Knights Walter Chetwind William Chetwind John Chetwind Henry Boyle Thomas Broughton Edward
Litleton Thomas Lane Humphrey Wyrley Robert Burdett John Every John Lawton George Rodney Bridges
Robert Leveson Phillip Foley Esquires Rowland Oakeover Henry Vernon Thomas Kinnersley senior Thomas
Kinnersley junior Thomas Lawley William Crompton Thomas Rudiard John [How<ref idref="n107">107</ref>] William Parker George Parker
John Swinfin Edward Birch Serjeant at Law Thomas Birch William Juge Phillip Hollins Mathew Floyer Phillip
Pargitur Jonas Grosvenor junior Charles Coates Francis Whitwick senior Francis Whitwicke junior John Whitwicke
Jonathan Cope William Cotton Walter Aston Edward Arablaster Thomas Whitby Michaell Noble William Turton
Peter Warburton William Sneyd of Kyell Esquires John Huntbache John Bagnall Copwood Hollins Francis Elde
Edward Foden William Trafford senior William Trafford junior Thomas Scott Thomas Jevon senior Edward Barber
Daniell Watson Christopher Lea Phillip Chetwood Samuell Pipe John Badeley Richard Pyott Richard Dyott Thomas
Foden of Fulford John Shilton John Fenton Henry Leigh of Rushall James Rudyard of the Abbey
Roade of Ruston Henry Brace Girdle James Rudiard William Abnet John Wilson Esquires Edward Short William
Jarvis Thomas Pigott Walter Fowler John Amphlett John Pearshouse Clotworthey Skevington Thomas Foley
William Whitbey Walter Moseley Will. Nabbs Tomins Dickins Francis Wolverston Richard Whitworth Tho
Jolliffe Will Jolliffe Thomas Milward William Milward Robert Wolseley Roger Fouke John Goreing Charles
Blunt Samuell Hunt Jonas Astley Michaell Branderith Bernard Whaley Browne of Thornes Esquires the
Mayor of Stafford for the time being and the Mayor of Newcastle under Lyne for the time being the Bayliffes
of Tamworth for the time being William Feake Edward Foden [Esquires<ref idref="n108">108</ref>] Humphrey Perry Edward Bird Nehemiah
Farmer Sampson Birch Gentlemen Thomas Parker John Greene William Nabbs Nicholas Parker Ralph Wood
George Alsop and John Wilson Esquires William Baddeley Baughey William Burslam Samuell Rocke
William Lawton Nathaniell Beard Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s96">
			<head>For the City and County of Litchfield</head>
			<para id="p98">The two Bayliffes for the time being the Sheriffe for the time being Sir Michaell Biddulph Baronet Sir John
Floyer Knight Phillip Pargiter Robert Burdet Richard Pyett Richard Dyott John Babbington John Goreing
Esquires Thomas Hamond [Will<ref idref="n109">109</ref>] Whitbey Richard Wakefeild John Rawlins Gentlemen Richard [Barnes<ref idref="n110">110</ref>] William
Jesson William Walmesley Edward Wilson William Potts John Barker.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s97">
			<head>For the County of Southampton</head>
			<para id="p99">The Right Honourable Charles Lord Marquesse of Winchester Lord Chamberlaine to Her Majestie Sonne
and Heire Apparent of Charles Duke of Bolton the Right Honourable Henry Earle of Sterling in the Kingdome
of Scotland the Right Honourable William Lord Pawlet second Sonne to the Duke of Bolton Richard Earle of
Ranelaugh of the Kingdome of Ireland the Honourable Francis Pawlet Esquire Sir. John Mill Sir Hugh Stewkley
Sir Nicholas Steward Sir John Dillington Sir Hele Hooke Sir John Hoby Baronets Sir Charles Windham Sir
William Kingsmill Sir Thomas Higgens Sir Robert Sawyer Sir William Stephens Sir Robert Holmes Sir James
Worsley Sir Benjamin Newland Sir Thomas Draper Sir Robert Henley Sir John St Barb Knights Henry Russell
Richard Norton Thomas Jervois senior George Pitt senior Thomas Hoby Leonard Bilson Esquires John Kent
Esq[uire] Sheriffe Henry Rolle Gabriell Whistler Ralph Hastings Henry Wallup Henry Dawley Francis Morley
Fredericke Tilney Richard Holt Richard Whitehead Rich Cobb Charles Cole George Evans White Tichborne John
Smith of Tidworth Esquires John Pollen Richard Bishop Richard Chandler John Wallop Thomas Bilson William
Bishop Charles Morley Henry Slingsby Samuell Gawden George Bridges Charles Wither George Abbot John
Fawkener Charles Forrester Thomas Brottas Oliver Cromwell Thomas Jervois junior John Deane Edward Chute
Henry Brumfeild John Burrard Robert Smith Henry Compton John Venables Henry Hooke Edward Fleming Robert
Knollis William Buckley George Stanley Edward Hooper Esquires Henry Perrin Doctor of Physicke Thomas Miller
Richard Stanley Richard Carter Thomas Tutt William Coleman Henry Tulse Richard Love junior George Pitt
junior Benjamine Rudiard Thomas Wither William Norton Robert Mitchell Richard Cooper Thomas Buckley
William Batten Roger Barton Robert Barton George Duke Thomas Smith Thomas Edmonds Thomas Douse of
Wallop Thomas Douse of Brooke John Rives of Drayton John Rives of Bransberry Edward Pile Christopher
Stokes Peter Blake Richard Pile junior Thomas Fitzjames John Lisle Mathew Bennet William Guydott Esquires
Richard Bele Giles Lyford Robert Love Allen Goddard Anthony Guydott Thomas Goddard Edward Rooke Henry
Christmas George Wakeford Gentlemen The Mayor of Winton for the time being Richard Harris Esquire Recorder
Ellis Mews Esq[uire] Anthony Yalden James Earle John Purdue Paul Burrard Richard Good John Conger Mathew
Ember The Mayor of Portsmouth for the time being Lewis Barton Thomas Wavell Gentlemen The Bayliffe of
Andover for the time being Walter Robinson James Grove Henry Curle Richard Hill Gentlemen John Stephens
Gentleman Mayor of Christ Church Mayor of Newport for the time being Edward Dillington Richard Knight John
Worsley Nicholas Lisle John Chapman David Urrey of Easton Thomas Urrey of Freshwater Thomas Urrey of
Gatcombe Esquires Eustace Mann Robert Leigh John Bowler Gentlemen John Stephens of West Cowes Gentleman
William Fielder Thomas Dore William Knapton</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s98">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Southampton</head>
			<para id="p100">The Mayor for the time being Sir [Giles<ref idref="n111">111</ref>] Eyre Knight one of the Justices of the Kings Bench William Buckley
Esq[uire] John Speede Doctor of Physicke Thomas Cornelius Richard White James Crosse Adam De Cardinall Christopher.
Smith Cornelius Mackham Robert Culliford Thomas Bracebridge Richard Hunt Sir Richard Beech.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s99">
			<head>For the County of Suffolke</head>
			<para id="p101">Lord Huntingtower Sir Henry Felton Sir John Barker Sir John Platers Sir Robert Kempe Sir Simons Dewes
Sir John Castleton Sir Dudley Cullam Sir Jervaise Elwes Sir John Cordell Sir Henry North Sir John Rouse Sir
Thomas Allin Sir Thomas Barnadiston Sir John Duke Sir Robert Brooke Sir Phillip Parker Sir Edmond Bacon
Sir Samuell Bernadiston Sir Robert Davers Sir Charles Bloys Sir William Cooke Baronets Sir Charles Gaudy
Knight and Baronet Sir Robert Rich Knight and Baronet Sir Peyton Ventris Sir John Poley Sir Thomas Harvey
Sir George Wenyeve Sir Nevill Catelin Sir Henry Johnson Sir Charles Crofts Reede Sir Phillip Skippon Sir Joseph
Brand Sir Richard Gipps Knights [Ptolmey<ref idref="n112">112</ref>] Tolmach Nicholas Bacon Thomas Holland Adam Felton Thomas
Walgrave Thomas Glemham Thomas Knivett Thomas Tolmash Henry Haveningham William Johnson Phillip
Gurdon Thomas Tyrrell Robert Theobald Thomas Coell Henry Parker Edmond Warner John Robinson Henry
Shalton John Thurston Richard Norton Henry Warner Edward Hobert John Brame Phillip Bedingfield William
Barker Francis Barker William Dade Robert King Ham[m]ond Le Strainge John Scrivner Edward North William Rivett
Thomas Edgar James Calthorpe John Cornwallis Will: Crofts Henry Poley Robert Barker Robert [Maulton<ref idref="n113">113</ref>] John
Corrance Robert [Maltiwond<ref idref="n114">114</ref>] Thomas Wright Henry Edgar Lawrence Rouse junior Thomas Golding William
Glover Thomas [Glemham<ref idref="n115">115</ref>] George Fleetwood John Bence Robert Warren Awbrey Porter Christopher Calthrop
Henry Goldwell John Jermy of Springhton John Lamb John Spencer Edmond Bence John Jermy of Stutton
Anthony Wroth Allen Cotton Edward Alpe Edmond Sheppard John Smith of Parfeild John Hall Thomas Smith
Lyonell Hold William Cullum William Guavas Thomas Love Robert Davye Thomas Rivett John Beamont Thomas
Smith Nicholas Brage William Covell Charles Whitaker John Hooke Doctor Thomas Carver William Betts
Thomas Coyell Master John Browne Roger Herrington Thomas Neale Thomas Deye Thomas Else Nicholas Freman
Thomas Hastings Edward Alston of Bonford John Hodges Peter Alderman John Spinke Renaldo Pitfield John
Gerling Gregory Clarke William Randall Richard Vesey Thomas Dade Thomas Wright senior Doctor John
Bourchier Sir Cesar Cranmer Knight Sir Charles Umphrevile Knight Thomas Felton John Felton Thomas Barnadiston
Richard Wareing Thomas Brand (<ref idref="n116">116</ref>) John Barker of Wickham Market Robert Jenny William Hammond Samuell
Clarke William Cooke Andrew Warner Francis Brewster John Hill Martin Folkes Simon Folkes Samuell Blackerby
Doctor Nathaniell Fairfax Richard Porter Phillip French William Hammond Henry Dawson Joseph Hastings Sir
Francis Bloudell Samuell Baker Isaac Rebow [Esquires<ref idref="n117">117</ref>] Tho Ewen Tho Aldrige Charles Blosse Will Lucas Thomas
Roper Esquires Samuell Pacy Esq[uire] Thomas Bendish Esquire Bartholomew Soames Esq[uire] William Bright of Brissor
Esq[uire] Robert Russell Esq[uire] Edward Gayell James Goodwin Thomas Fokes Gentlemen John Nicholls senior Francis
Haylocke Henry Ward Gentlemen Henry North Esq[uire] Lawrence Stisteade Richard Phillips John Blomfeild Robert
Clarke William Tye of Ipswich William Blomfield of Barking Gentlemen Richard Margatt Esq[uire] William Fowles
Esq[uire] Joseph Weld Esq[uire] Crompton Felton (<ref idref="n118">118</ref>) Nathaniell Simonds Richard Ferrier William Neave of Ipswich William
Glascock [Esquires.<ref idref="n119">119</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s100">
			<head>For the Towne of Ipswich</head>
			<para id="p102">The Bayliffes for the time being Sir John Barker Sir Charles Blois Baronets Sir [Peiton<ref idref="n120">120</ref>] Ventris Thomas Edgar
Esq[uire] Recorder Charles Wright Lawrence Stisted Richard Phillips Edward Reynolds John Burroughs William
Neave William Browne John Blomfeild John Wade Miles Wallis Henry Sparrow Gentlemen Robert Clarke Towne
Clerke.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s101">
			<head>For the Burrough of Eye</head>
			<para id="p103">The Bayliffes for the time being Thomas Knivett Henry Poley Esquires Thomas Deye Henry Edgar Thomas
Browne Nathaniell Deye Thomas Deye junior Gentlemen Francis Deye Thomas Brampton Tho: Flowerdy
Smith Chenery.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s102">
			<head>For the Burrough of Sudbury.</head>
			<para id="p104">The Mayor for the time being Sir John Poley Knight Phillip Gourdon Esq[uire], John Parish William Cocke William
Hasell Samuell Hazell William Fothergill Gent. Robert Chaplaine Martin Harnis Clement Ray Bernard Carter
Benjamin Carter Henry Crossman William Hall Robert Girling Miles Birket.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s103">
			<head>For the Burrough of Dunwich.</head>
			<para id="p105">The Bailiffes for the time being Sir Robert Rich Knight and Baronet Sir Phillip Skippen Knight John Benefice
John Postle Jeremiah Burlingham Gentlemen William Weathersby Thomas Neale Esquires William Betts William
Hammond Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s104">
			<head>For the Burrough of Bury Saint Edmonds.</head>
			<para id="p106">The Aldermen for the time being Sir Robert Davers Baronet Sir Thomas Harvey Knight Sir Charles Crofts
Read Knight Robert Sharpe Richard [Prince<ref idref="n121">121</ref>] Martin Spenceley Gentlemen Thomas Holland Esq[uire] Thomas Macro
senior Gentleman the Recorder for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s105">
			<head>For the Towne of Orford.</head>
			<para id="p107">Sir John Duke Baronet Thomas Glemham Esquire Thomas Hastings Joseph Hastings Thomas Palmer William
Morgan.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s106">
			<head>For the Burrough of Alborough.</head>
			<para id="p108">Sir Henry Johnson Knight William Johnson Esquire Mr Coxshall Mr John Bence Bayliffes Thomas Neale Esq[uire] John
Browne Thomas Wall Edward Wall Alexander Osborne Jechingam Wright Samuell Grome John Burwood
Covell Richard Gardner Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s107">
			<head>For the County of Surrey.</head>
			<para id="p109">The Honourable Sir Robert Howard The Honourable Sir Henry Capell Knight of the Bath The Honourable
Heneage Finch Esq[uire] The Honourable Francis Coventry Esq[uire] Sir Walter St Johns Sir Francis Vincent Sir
Adam Browne Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir Richard Onslow Sir John Thompson Sir Lawrence Stoughton Sir
Edward Bromfeild Sir Edward Evelin Sir William Temple Sir Robert Napper Sir Richard Atkins Baronets Sir
John Nicholas Knight of the Bath Sir William Morley Knight of the Bath Sir William Hoskins Sir Mathew
Andrews Sir St John Broderick Sir Robert Clayton Sir Purbecke Temple Sir Peter Rich Sir Christopher Buckle
Sir Cornwall Bradshaw Sir James Butler Sir William Elliott Sir Robert Knightley Sir George Vernon Sir Samuell
Dashwood Sir Edward Fruin Sir Thomas Vernon Knights Mr Serjeant Fuller Thomas Howard George Meggott
High Sheriffe George Evelin Henry Saint Johns Thomas Vincent Roger James Thomas Turgis Denzill Onslow
White Titchbourne Foote Onslow John Weston Edward Nicholas John Arnold John Evelin Anthony Bowyer Phillip
Hildyard Edward Harvey James Zouch George Woodroffe Nicholas Carew John Milner George Evelin of Nutfield
Morgan Randall Ambrose Browne Haestreet James Sigismond Stidolph Roger Duncombe George Duncombe
Edward Bray John Sands William Hooker Richard Nicholls Shem Bridges Richard Morley Ambrose Muschampe
Peter Hussey Phillip Rawleigh William Harvey Christopher Buckle Thomas Lant John Gore Richard Garth Francis
Brend William Hatton Charleton Whitelocke Stephen Harvey Robert Gavill John Burgoyne John Thynne William
Perry William Vanbrough George Coldham William Nuttall John Love Thomas Newton Nicholas Hookes George
Smith William Haward John Mitchell Thomas Eures Anthony Bowyer Henry Whistler John Wight Peter [Delamoy<ref idref="n122">122</ref>]
Hatton Thomas Trapps John Rainsden Henry Ludlow Jeffrey Amhurst Henry Lloyd John Heather
John Turner Samuell Luen Walter Howland Esquires The Mayor and Magistrates of Guilford for the time being
Bayliffes of Kingston for the time being Maximilian Emeley John Austin William Boothby Timothy Wilson Captaine
Lampard Captaine Salmond Joseph Lee Robert Moore John Lug Dewy Thomas Burrows Charles
Shorter Urban Hall Crispe Lawrence March John Spencer Ralph Drake Richard Jewell Thomas Harris
Samuell Wall Benjamine Le Cane Captaine Bartholomew Thomas Jordan of Gatwick William Jordan
Doctor Rosewell Thomas Jordan Richard Gwinne Henry Johnson Edward Woodward William Jenue William
Summers Peter Norborow Thomas Cusden Jerrat Andrews Simon Smith Richard White Christopher Geere Henry
Wyat Gentlemen James Reading Samuell Atkinson William Hester Phillip Forster Esquires Sir Peter Daniell Knight
William Gibbs Francis Wilkinson Jonadab Balam William Sherlocke Captaine Edward Laine Jonas Shish Daniell
Wight Thomas Jordan Daniell Duthees John Greene Gentlemen William Eyre Ralph Snow Samuell Somerford
Esquires Joseph Wood Thomas Cox Captaine Henry Wilcason Kent Charles Shorter Gent. William
Midleton.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s108">
			<head>For the County of Sussex</head>
			<para id="p110">Sir John Pelham Sir William Thomas Sir Denny Ashburnham Sir John Fagg Sir William Wilson Sir Thomas
Dyke Sir Richard Shirley. Baronets Sir James Moreton Knight Sir William Morley Knight of the Bath Sir Richard
Onslow Baronet Sir Nicholas Pelham Sir John Briscoe Sir Christopher Conyers Sir Edward Selwin Sir Edward
Hungerford Sir Phillip Gell Thomas Pelham Esq[uire] Thomas Sackvile John Lewkner William Morley Esquires
Thomas Brigs Doctor at Law Henry Pelham Esquire Thomas Newdigate Henry Shelley Nisell Rivers Richard
Bridger William Board Timothy Burrell Esquires John Burrell Gentleman George Goreing George Nevill James
Butler Thomas Beard Esquires Thomas Bromfeild junior Gentleman John Spence James Graves John Fuller
John. Hay John Baker Alexander Stapleys Humphry Foulke Simon Smith Phillip Parker Esquires John Nevenham
Gentleman Walter Doubti junior William Mackworth John Board Thomas Burrell Gentlemen Thomas May
Thomas Miller Thomas Bickley Esquires John Peachey Barrester at Law George Guntur John Freman Richard
Farrington Esquires Nathaniell Palmer William Parker Esquires Thomas Palmer William Williams Esq[uire] John
Peachy of Saint Peters the lesse John Marlote Gentleman Randolph Tutty Gentleman Francis Page Gentleman
Thomas Woodier Gentleman [Thomas<ref idref="n123">123</ref>] Gott Henry Apsley Thomas Fruin Edward Dyne George Courthope
John Weekes John Busbridge Samuell Highland Esquires Walter Roberts senior William [Peacham<ref idref="n124">124</ref>] Thomas
Betswort William Young Thomas Gray Thomas Carr Abraham Chapman Esquires Edward Morley William
Cosden Gentlemen John Apsley Wesbrooke William Garroway Thomas [Garrow<ref idref="n125">125</ref>] John Cock Esquires
John Cocke of Goreing Gentleman Thomas Gratwick of Ham Gentleman John Tayler Esq[uire] Francis Mosse
Gentleman John Lee of Plaistow Esq[uire] Walter Bartlet Gentleman Richard Cooper Esq[uire] Henry Bernard Thomas
Nash Edward Staker John Styent Oliver Whitby William Alwen Gentlemen Humphry Jewkes Esq[uire] Thomas
Peckham John Pellet Thomas Colbrooke Richard Banckes. Thomas Dewet William Peachey Gentlemen the [Mayor<ref idref="n126">126</ref>]
of Chichester and Arundell for the time being Charles Goreing John Chaulx Esquires Nathaniell Turner John
Gratwick of Eaton Gentlemen John Gratwick of Jarvis Gentleman Thomas Poole Gentleman John Munck John
Alford Robert Fagg John Machell Anthony. Eversfeild Esquires Stephen Humphrey William Alderton Gentlemen
Henry Yates Esq[uire] Thomas Ellis Charles Fagg. Thomas White junior John Wicker Gentlemen Robert Orme
Samuell White Gentlemen John Miller Gentleman Henry Cooper Esq[uire] Sir William Culpeper Baronet Richard
Onslow Esq[uire] Henry Peckham Francis Goater Robert Thornden Aldermen of Chichester George Osbourne
Gentleman Paul Burrard Esquire George Elfred Gent Anthony Crutenden Esq[uire].</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s109">
			<head>For the County of Warwicke.</head>
			<para id="p111">The Right Honourable (<ref idref="n127">127</ref>) Viscount Tiveott the Right Honourable William Lord Digby of the Kingdome of
Ireland the Right Honourable Thomas Coventry Sir John Mordant Sir Clement Fisher Sir John Burgoine Sir
William Boughton Sir Basill Price Sir Charles Shugburgh Sir Reginald Forster Sir John Bridgman Sir Richard
Nudigate Sir Charles Holt Sir Thomas Samwell Sir Henry Puckering Baronets Sir William Craven Sir John
Clopton Sir William Bishop Sir William Underbill Sir Richard Verney Knights Thomas Rawlins Serjeant at Law
Robert Burdet Walter Chetwind Henry Parker William Palmer [Scabright<ref idref="n128">128</ref>] Repington Arden Adderley Francis
Fisher junior William Peito Andrew Archer Charles Newsham Hastings Ingram Robert Somervile Edward Bentley
William Colmer Humphrey Jennings Hercules [Bufoy<ref idref="n129">129</ref>] Thomas Marriot William Bolton John Astley John Stratford
Thomas Kite Thomas Wagstaffe Nathaniell Stoughton Humphrey Holden William Dugdale James Prescott Mathew
Holbech Thomas Peirce, Thomas Newsham John Smith Richard Hopkins Thomas, Hopkins Esquires Ambrose
Holbech Dixwell of Coton Hall Henry Mathews of Mercott Hall. Wilcox of Brandon
William Loggans John Stanton Gentlemen Mayor of Warwicke Mayor of Stratford, Bayliffes of Tamworth for the
time being Arden Baggot Esq[uire] Richard, Beake Esq[uire] James Harvey Edward Ludford William Bromley [Esquires<ref idref="n130">130</ref>].</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s110">
			<head>For the City and County of Coventry.</head>
			<para id="p112">The Mayor for the time being Sir Thomas Norton Sir John Dugdale Knights James. Hales Richard Hopkins
Thomas Hopkins Richard Beake Henry Greene Basil Feilding Edward Tayler Bawater Esq[uire] Alderman
Nayler Nathaniell Herryman Francis Herriman Edward Owen Thomas Lawrence Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s111">
			<head>For the County of Westmorland</head>
			<para id="p113">Sir John Lowther Baronet one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir
George Fletcher Sir John Lowther of Whitehaven Baronets Sir John Otway Sir Daniell Fleming Sir Christopher.
Phillipson Knights Richard Lowther John Dalston Thomas Hilton Edward Wilson William Sandford William
Fleming Thomas Wilson Richard [Blaithwaite<ref idref="n131">131</ref>] Christopher Dalston Thomas Fletcher Roger Moore Edward Musgrave
Hugh Matchell John Philipson Richard Pindar James Bird Esquires Thomas Godsalve Richard Crakenthorpe
John Nevison Ephraim Sandford Ciprian Hilton Arthur Scaife James Simpson Anthony Saul Thomas Shepherd
Daniell Fleming John Hall Thomas Heblethwaite Reginald Dobson John Browham Lancelott Ford the Mayors
of Apleby and Kendall for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s112">
			<head>For the County of Wilts</head>
			<para id="p114">Charles Marquesse of Winchester Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Duke of Bolton Edward. Viscount Cornbury
Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Earle of Clarendon Anthony Lord Ashley Sonne and Heire Apparent to Anthony
Earle of Shaftsbury Mountague Lord Norris Sonne and Heire Apparent to Earle of Abingdon Henry
Lord Colraine of the Kingdome of Ireland Boyle Viscount Shanion of the Kingdome of Ireland The
Honourable Peregrine Bertie Esq[uire] Sir Edward Seamour Sir Walter St John Sir John Button Sir Richard Grubham
Howe Sir Walter Long Sir James Long Sir William Pinsent Sir Edward Windham Baronets Sir Edward Hungerford
Sir John Nicholas Knights of the Bath Sir Giles; Eyre Knight one of the Justices of His Majestyes Court of Kings
Bench Sir. Henry Coker Sir John Erule Sir John. Talbott Sir Thomas Mompesson Sir George Hungerford Sir
Stephen Fox Sir Thomas Estcourt Knights Sir Mathew Andrews Sir Eliab Harvey Sir Charles Raleigh Sir Edmond
Warnford Sir John Collins Sir Richard Harte Sir George Willoughby Sir James Howe Sir Thomas Fowles
Knights The Honourable Evelin Pierpoint Esq[uire], Boyle Francis Pawlett George Pitt Richard Lewis Robert
Hyde Francis Wroughton senior John Hall Richard Howe Thomas Hobby John Windham Henry Baynton Thomas
Lambert Samuell Eyre Henry Brunker Thomas Freake of Shrowton. Thomas Bennet Edward Nichols of Maningford
Maurice Buckland Thomas Pitt William Ash Alexander Thistlethwaite Francis Morley Henry St John Charles Fox
Edward Nicholas of Winterbourne Walter Earule John Smith of Tidworth John Deane Edward Nicholas of Camins
Francis Goddard Francis Stonehouse William Trenchard Lawrence Swanton Thomas Jarvaise Thomas Chamberlaine
John Bowles John Hawlis William Harvey. Thomas Penrudducke William Windham Thomas Windham John
Grubb John Davenant Henry Chivers Nicholas Baynton John Wildman senior Richard Chandler Richard Jones
of Ramsbury John Ash of Haywood Michaell Erule Samuell Ash Thomas Goddard of Swinden Thomas Mitchell
William Sacheverille John Young Francis Morley Richard Whitehead, Charles Godfrey. John Wildman junior
Edmond Lambert John Marvin William Chaffin William Willoughby William Norborne Francis Hill.
Seamour Richard Nevill William George Charles Raymond Charles. Tucker Benjamin Gifford John Fitzherbert
Edmond Hungerford John Bennett William Hearst Gabriell Ashley John Wallis Richard Aldworth Herbert Saladine
Richard Kent William Brewer John Milner Nevill, Mascaline. William, Player David Thomas Doctor of Physicke
Charles Yorke Walter Greene John Hippesley John Ash of Teffont Edmond Webb John Flower senior John
Bond Thomas Harris Richard Poore John Jacob Edward Duke George Duke of Lake Anthony Hungerford Thomas
Polden Charles Danvers Walter Parker Henry Coker Francis. Wroughton junior Robert Fewell Thomas Marke
John Gantlett John Bigge Francis Swanton William Grinfield Charles Mitchell; Thomas Rolt William Hitchcocke
Henry Pinnell John Curll Charles Pleydall Charles Bowles Robert Grove senior John. Grove Robert Grove John
Long Francis Thistlethwaite William Beach of Fidletom Andrew Duke Charles Stewart Walter Long of Raxall
Robert Wadman Edward Hart Samuell Trotman. Stringer of Ivy Church George Hill William [Cole<ref idref="n132">132</ref>]
Thomas Bennet of Salthorpe Thomas Phipps Henry Fairfax Robert Guilmore William Hussey Richard Nevill
Brereton Bouchier Henry Blake Thomas Grove George Hill Esquires John Mompesson William Hues Thomas
Powell Nathaniell Trotman William Gantlet Nicholas Elliot Christopher Gardiner Richard Minifie John Brooke
Nicholas Daniell William Clare Christopher Lippiat John Foster Mathew Smith Jonathan Hill John Twogood
John Flower Henry Wattman John Jesse Edmond Medlicott Thomas Hunt of Enford Henry. Eyre of WoodHampton Edmond Hemings Albinas Davies Mathew Smith Francis Goddard of Perton Henry Southby Charles
Chiswell John Fisher Francis Coles senior Thomas Francklin Robert Bisse Robert Mandrell Thomas Long of
Rowdre Thomas Stump Elias Ferris Bennet Swaine William Westfield Gentt. The Mayor of Salisbury for the time
being The Mayor of Wilton for the time being The Mayor of the Devizes for the time being The Mayor of
Marlbrough for the time being The Bayliffes of Chippernham for the time being John Foster Christopher Lipiett
George Willoughby Thomas Mitchell James Croom Nicholas Hayes Richard Smith of Kenney George Duke of
Sarson Humphry Wall.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s113">
			<head>For the City of New Sarum and the Close of the same.</head>
			<para id="p115">The Mayor for the time being Sir Giles Eyre Knight Recorder one of the Justices of Their Majestyes Court
of Kings Bench Sir Thomas Mompesson Knight Thomas Hobby John Wyndham Thomas Pitt William Hearst
Francis Hill Esquires Christopher Gardiner William Smith Thomas Kenton John Priaulx Andrew Baden Roger
Basket James Harris Faulkoner William Viner Hasket Gentlemen David. Thomas Doctor of
Physick Richard Minifie Lawrence Swanten Gabriell Ashley Thomas Lambert Herbert Salladine Esquires.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s114">
			<head>For the County of Worcester.</head>
			<para id="p116">The Right Honourable Richard Earl of Bellamont in the Kingdome of Ireland Thomas Coventry Robert Tracey
Henry Foliott Esquires Sir Robert Atkins Knight of the Bath and Lord Chiefe Baron of Their. Majestyes Court
of Exchequer Sir [Nicholas Letchmere one of the Barons of Their Majesties Court of Exchequer<ref idref="n133">133</ref>] Sir Henry
Litleton Sir John Packington Sir Francis Russell Sir Thomas Rouse Sir Edward Seabright Sir William Kyte Sir
Christopher Musgrave Sir James Rushout Baronets Sir Rowland Berkley Sir Henry Coningsby Sir Francis
Wiu[m]ington Sir Thomas Streete Sir Thomas Haslewood. Sir Edward Dinely Sir John Mathews Knights Sir John
Somers Their Majestyes Sollicitor Generall Samuell Sandys Henry Herbert William Bromley Thomas Foley Richard
Dowdeswell Thomas Savage senior Henry Jeffryes George Walsh William Walsh Edwin Sandys Thomas Savage
junior Edmond Leshmore Robert Berkley Thomas Jolliffe Bridges Nanfan Charles Baldwin John Charleton Walter
Savage senior Walter Savage junior Thomas Vernon of Astwood Thomas Cornwall Robert Dormer Robert Foley
Francis Sheldon John Marriott William Hancocke Higgons James George Dowdeswell John Soley John Bearcroft
John Clutton Robert Wilde Edward Bull Chambers Slaughters Gerrard Dannet Richard Nash junior Allen Cliffe
senior Allen Cliffe junior Francis Bromley Humphrey Litleton John Sheldon Richard Freeman Charles Cox George
Harris Edward Stainer Godard Carter Benjamine Jolliffe Esquires Heigham Cooke Thomas Bushell Phillip Bearcroft
Henry Toy Thomas Hunt of Ribenhall Edward Walker Will: Bird John Emmes Giles Parsons Martin Ballard
Thomas Harris Richard Young Gent. The Mayor of Evesham for the time being The Bayliffes of Droitwich for
the time being The Bayliffe of Bewdley for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s115">
			<head>For the City and County of the City of Worcester</head>
			<para id="p117">The Mayor Aldermen and Sheriffe for the time being Sir John Somers Knight Their Majestyes Sollicitor
Generall William Bromley Esq[uire] Sir Rowland Berkley Sir Thomas Streete Henry Herbert Walter Savage junior
Robert Wilde Esquires. Phillip Bearcroft of the Parish of St Swithins John Blurton Edward Cooksey senior James
Higgons Samuell Swift John Handy Thomas Smith senior Nicholas Baker.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s116">
			<head>For the County of Anglesey.</head>
			<para id="p118">Richard Lord Bulkley Viscount Cashells in the Kingdome of Ireland Lewis Lord Viscount Dunganon in the
Kingdome of Ireland Thomas Bulkley Robert Bulkley Sir Hugh Owen Baronet Sir Roger Mostin Knight and
Baronet Sir William Williams of Vanoll Baronet Sir [William<ref idref="n134">134</ref>] Williams Knight and Baronet Thomas Burton John
Hooke Nicholas Bagnoll Pierce Lloyd Francis Bulkley John Griffith of Careg Lloid John Owen of Penchose
[John<ref idref="n135">135</ref>] Bold William Meirick John Grosvenor Conisby Williams Owen Hughes John Jones Doctor of Divinity John
Ellis Doctor of Divinity Owen Wynne William Robinson William Griffith of Llanvayethley Robert Owen of
Hollyhead William Morgan John Wynne Thomas Lloyd Henry Jones William Bulkley David Lloyd Lloydiast
Hugh Wynne of Treyerworth Roger Hughes Rowland Wynne Henry Sparrow Thomas Williams Maurice Lewis
Francis Lloyd Hugh Williams David Williams Owen Davies of Llandefredog Henry Wynne of Penheskin Thomas
Mostin Edward Lewis William Jones John Owen of Bodiar Richard Edwards John Hill Richard Hughes William
Griffith Thomas Roberts of Costellor Richard Vaughan John Williams of Bodafan John Price Owen Roberts
Richard Bulkley Maurice Parry The Mayor of Beaumaris for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s117">
			<head>For the County of Brecon</head>
			<para id="p119">Charles Lord Marquesse of Worcester Sonne and Heire Apparent of Henry Duke of Beaufort Sir Walter
Williams Baronet Sir Edward Williams Sir Rowland Gwynne Knights [Bassey<ref idref="n136">136</ref>] Mansell Thomas Morgan John Lewis
of Coldmore Richard Williams Jeffery Jefferyes Charles Morgan John Jefferyes Edward Jones Thomas Walker
Daniell Williams Walter Vaughan Edward Games Thomas Flower John Williams John Morgan Marmaduke Gwynne
John Walters John Gunter Marmaduke Lloyd Edward Lewis Phillip Parry Lodowick Lewis Charles Lloyd Lewis
Jones James Parry Richard Jefferies John Stedman Francis Lloyd John Walbeof Walter William Robert Lucy
William Bowen John Gwynne John Lewis Jasper Miller Rice Price Morgan Watkins Richard Williams Henry
Jones Thomas Williams. William Jones. Esquires Bartholomew Games Gwynne Vaughan Charles Powell Edward
Games Hugh Penry Thomas Williams Henry Vaughan Doctor of Physicke Richard Williams [Richard<ref idref="n137">137</ref>] Watkins of
Penyrwrled Lewis Lloyd Thomas Gwynne William Phillips William Williams of Veliewith Wil: Williams of Battell
John Madox. Lewis Havard James Watkins Sam: Williams Tho: Jones Henry Williams Tho: Bowen William
Lloyd James Donne Morgan. Price Robert Rumsey John Herbert Francis Lewis John Rumsey Howell Morgan
Samuell Pritchard Edward Williams Howell Jones William Aubry Walter Vaughan John Phillips Richard Watkins
Edward Price Thomas Lloyd of Rosrerick.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s118">
			<head>For the Town of Brecon</head>
			<para id="p120">The Bayliffe Recorder and Aldermen for the time being Sir Rowland Gwynne. Thomas Morgan Jeffery Jeffryes
Richard Williams Thomas Walker Daniell Williams John Waters Robert Lucy Lodowicke Lewis Saunder Saunders
Esquires John Jeffres William Awbry Henry Thomas Edward Hughes William Williams Gentlemen Meredith
James Towne Clerk.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s119">
			<head>For the County of Cardigan</head>
			<para id="p121">Sir Carbery Price of Gogarthan Baronet Sir Bazill Price of Kilkennin Baronet Sir Thomas Powell Serjeant at
Law Sir William [Morgan<ref idref="n138">138</ref>] Knight Their Majestyes Serjeant at Law John Lewis John Vaughan Hector Phillips
John Herbert William Herbert William Powell Thomas Lloyd of Castle Howell Walter. Lloyd of Almach Charles
Lloyd of Massevelin Thomas Lloyd of Bronnith David Parry Daniell Evans David Lloyd of Crunfrin David Lloyd
of Werne Richard Stedman Cornelius Le Brwn Edward Jones Thomas Lewis of Crigmore John Lewis of Pant
David John Williams of Abernant Bythan Richard Lloyd of Mavus Hugh Lloyd of Phosheligg Thomas Knolles
Samuell Hughes Esquires John Lewis of Gernos John Knolles William Jenkins John Phillips of Cammaven John
Prise Francis Vaughan Edward Price John Morrice of Carrog Walter Price Henry Jones of Tigglin David Griffith
of Llannarth George Jones Jenkin Lloyd of Llanvithan Gentlemen The Mayor of Cardigan for the time being
John Morrice Hector Morgans David Howells Henry Davies William Parry Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s120">
			<head>For the County of Carmarthen</head>
			<para id="p122">Sir Edward Mansell Sir Sackyile Crow Sir Rice Rudd Sir William Russell Baronets Sir Rice Williams Knight
Sir John Powell Knight Richard Vaughan of Tarracoed Griffith Rice Thomas Cornwallis Rowland Gwynne
Christopher Midleton Thomas Lloyd of Berthlandowell Richard Vaughan of Derthlis Richard Jones John Williams
of Abercothe John Evans of Trevente Thomas Lloyd of Altacadnoe Richard Gwynne of Gwempa Griffith Loyd
Rawleigh Mansell Edward Mansell Richard Mansell Roger Manwaring Henry Owens Edward Vaughan William
Brigstocke Thomas Brigstocke Arthur Gwynne John Williams of Talley Thomas Gwynne the elder Edward Jones
of Lleathernoiad Henry Lloyd of Llunstephan William Beetans of Pencoad Esquires Thomas Lloyd of Dunneralt
George Gwynne Anthony Rudd David Gwynne Owen Bowen Thomas Phillips of Kilsant David Lewis of
Lisnewith Henry Vaughan of Place Gwynne William Jones of Colebrooke William Brigstocke of Abberguilly
Walter Morgan Hugh Jones James Philips Henry Lewis Anthony Williams Walter Thomas Benjamin Lewis
William Davies of Drufloine Charles Dalton.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s121">
			<head>For the Burrough of Carmarthen</head>
			<para id="p123">The Mayor Recorder Towne Clerke and Chamberlaine for the time being Sir Edward Mansell Sir Sackvile
Crow Sir Rice Rudd Baronets Sir John Powell Sir Rice Williams Knights Richard Vaughan Rowland Gwinne
Griffith Lloyd William Brigstocke Edward Vaughan of Penny-Banke Marmaduke Williams Esquires Dawkin Gove
John Williams William Jones William Brigstocke Martin Beynon Aldermen David Edwards Anthony Rudd Thomas
Rogers Thomas Lloyd George Lewis Griffith Lewis Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s122">
			<head>For the County of Carnarvan</head>
			<para id="p124">Richard Lord Bulkley Viscount Cashells in the Kingdome of Ireland the Right Honourable Robert Lord
Willoughby of Eresby Chauncellor of Their Majestyes Dutchy and County Palatine of Lancaster and Sonne and
Heire Apparent to the Right Honourable the Earle of Lindsey Lord Great Chamberlaine of England The
Honourable Edward Russell Thomas Bulkley Sir John Wynne Knight and Baronet Sir William Williams of
Vaynoll Baronet Sir Roger Mostin Knight and Baronet Sir Robert Owen Knight Thomas Burton John Hooke
Tho Mostin Nicholas Bagnall Col: Will: Price Roger Price Griffith Vaughan Robert Wynne William Wynne of
the Abbey William Williams George Twestleton John Jones Doctor of Divinity John Ellis Doctor of Divinity
Richard Jones Doctor of Law Owen Wynne of Glascoed Edward Williams William Madrin George Coitmore
James Brunkire Love Parry John Thomas Owen Hughes Co[m]ningsby Williams Robert Hookes Lewis Meyricke
Hugh Boderda William Wynne of Llanunda John Rowlands Richard Edwards William Glynne Randall Wynne
William Wynne of Werne William Wynne of Glan'r afon Griffith Wynne of Stinlin John Wynne Richard
Kiffin Griffith Carreg William Griffith of Madrinissa Owen Jones John Owen William Lloyd Hugh Lewis Robert
Pugh Owen Wynne [of<ref idref="n139">139</ref>] Pen y brin Owen Coitmore Humphrey Roberts Robert Griffith Thomas Fletcher William
Williams Griffith Parry John Vaughan Evan Lord Penmachno Henry Arthur Hugh Stodart Owen Roberts John
Maurice Thomas Ellis.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s123">
			<head>For the County of Denbigh</head>
			<para id="p125">Sir John Wynne Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Powell Baronet Sir Richard Midleton Baronet Sir Jeffery
Shakerley Sir William Williams Knight and Baronet Sir Griffith Jefferies Sir Roger Puleston Sir Robert Owen
Sir John Conway Baronet Sir Francis Compton Sir Roger Moston Knight and Baronet Sir John Trevor Sir.
Thomas Grosvenor William Williams of Plastward Esq[uire] William Winne of Mela Edward Vaughan of Lloidiarth
Robert Davies of Llannerch Edward Brereton Thomas Carter Joshuah Edisbury Eubule Thelwall senior Eubule
Thelwall junior Roger Mostin of Brimbo William Robinson Ellis Lloyd of Pen y lan Robert Price of Geeler
David Maurice of Pen y bont Edward Maurice of Llorraine Esquires Eubule Lloyd Gentleman John Midleton
of Gwaninog John Puleston Thomas Midleton Robert Griffiths of Brimbo Hedd Lloyd John Chambers Foulke
Lloyd of Foxall Esquires Booth Basnet Gentleman John Dolben Esq[uire] Ellis Meredith Esq[uire] Mr Richard Eaton of
Erbistock Richard Midleton of Llansillin Charles Midleton Kenrick Eyton Richard Midleton Esquires The Right
Honourable Robert Lord Willoughby of Eresby Chauncellor of Their Majestyes Dutchy and County Palatine
of Lancaster and Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Right Honourable the Earle of Lindsey Lord Great
Chamberlaine of England Sir Robert Cotton Knight and Baronet Sir Walter Baggot (<ref idref="n140">140</ref>) [Sir<ref idref="n141">141</ref>] Robert Wynne of
Berchddu (<ref idref="n142">142</ref>) Cadwallader Wynne [Esquires<ref idref="n143">143</ref>] Sir Evan Lloyd Baronet Sidney Godolphin Peter Ellis Esquires Sydney
Binner [Esq[uire]<ref idref="n144">144</ref>] Edward Lloyd of Plasmaddock David Lloyd of Llangollan Vecan Richard Wynne of Maesmochant
Esq[uire] Richard Wynne of Aberkinleth Simon Thelwell of Llanbeder Esq[uire] John Roberts of Havebuch Esq[uire] David
Lloyd of Bodnant Roger Midleton Robert Wynne of [Carthmegelio<ref idref="n145">145</ref>] Robert Ellis of Plasyollin Edward Wynne of
Llanyfied Edward Lloyd of Dwifaen Thomas Lloyd of Kefu Robert Lloyd of Hendrewilod Peter Foulkes of
Eriviate John Vaughan of Eriviate Evan Lloyd of Crosyoctin Thomas Price of Bwlch Gen&tilde; Richard Lloyd of
Moylevre David Williams Robert Lloyd Rich: Lloyd of Llaninis Owen Thelwell John Masemore Andrew Thelwall
John Lloyd of Bruiliarth The Aldermen and Bailiffes for the Towne of Denbigh for the time being Mr Foulke
Davies Mr Tho Harper Mr Robert Knollis Mr John Lloyd of Rossa John Chambres of Place Chambres Esq[uire]
John Midleton of Guaneonog Esq[uire] John Foulkes Roberts Roberts Owen Lloyd.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s124">
			<head>For the County of Flint.</head>
			<para id="p126">Sir John Hanmer Knight and Baronet Sir Evan Lloyd Baronet Sir John Conway Baronet Sir Roger Mostin
Knight and Baronet Sir William Glin Baronet Sir Robert Cotton Baronet Sir Richard Midleton Baronet Sir
William Williams Knight and Baronet Sir St John Gwilliams Baronet Sir Phillip Egerton Sir John Trevor Sir
Robert Owen Sir Roger Puleston Coll Roger Whitley Coll Will Price Coll Thomas Salisbury William Hanmer
Esquires Thomas Mostin Esquire Thomas Hanmer Esq[uire] Thomas Carter Esq[uire] Kenrick Eaton Esq[uire] of Eaton Kenricke
Eaton Esq[uire] of Pentremadock Thomas Whitley Esq[uire] of Alrhu Thomas Whitley Esq[uire] of Aston Robert Davies Esq(uire)
Langley Esquire Twistleton William Lloyd Edward Ravenscroft John Broughton Thomas</para>
			<para id="p127">Eaton Richard Mostin George Hope. John Wynne Hugh Griffith Owen Barton senior Owen Barton junior Peirce
Pennant Thomas Evans Edward Kinaston of Oatley Edward Morgan Richard Parry William Griffith William
Rutter Thomas Williams Esquires Thomas Jones Roger Mostin Gentlemen Luke Lloyd Esq[uire] Peter Wynne, Ellis
Young Roger Jones. John Pennant Thomas Foulkes Josiah Jones of Oaken Holt. Thomas Lloyd of Glascock
Gentlemen Roger Edwards Thomas Lloyd of Guernhailud.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s125">
			<head>For the County of Glamorgan</head>
			<para id="p128">Sir Edward Mansell Sir Edward Stradling Sir Charles Kemys Sir John Awbrey Baronets Sir Richard Bassett
Sir Rowland Gwynne Sir Humphrey Mackworth Sir Humphrey Edwin Knights John Windham Serjiant at Law
Thomas Mansell Thomas Morgan Richard Lewis Marmaduke Gibbs David Jenkins Richard Seys William Herbert
Francis Gwynne Bussey Mansell Thomas Lewis Edward Mathew Charles Mathew William Thomas William
Windham Martin Button Richard Lougher William Herbert junior Thomas Button Oliver St John William
Mathew William Awbrey Thomas Gibbon Reynald Deere Walter Evans Rowland Dawkins Edward Mansell
Esquires John Price Thomas Rees Thomas Mansell of Penrice Jeremy Dawkins Thomas Price Godwin Herbert
William Seys Thomas Popkins William Lewis Phillip Williams Thomas Williams of Cardiffe Gentlemen the
Bayliffes of Cardiffe for the time being the Bayliffes of Cowbridge for the time being Anthony Gwynne Edmond
Perkins Richard Perkins and Anthony Powell.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s126">
			<head>For the County of Merioneth</head>
			<para id="p129">The Right Honourable [the<ref idref="n146">146</ref>] Lord Willoughby of Eresby Chauncellor of Their Majestyes Dutchy and County
Palatine of Lancaster and Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Right Honourable the Earle of Lindsey Lord
Great Chamberlaine Sir Richard Midleton Baronet Sir Hugh Owens Baronet Sir William Williams Knight and
Baronet Sir Robert Owen Knight Griffith Vaughan of Corfigedoll Hugh Nanney of Nanney John Lloid of
Madsipandu William Lewis Anwill William Price of Rhiwlas Edward Vaughan of Lloydiarth William Pugh of
Mathavarn William Wynne of Mela Owen Anwill of Penrin Lewis Owen of Penniarth John Lloyd of Abberlaveny
Vincent Corbet John Nanney of Llanvendiged Roger Price of Rhiwlas John Vaughan of Glanylin Charles Hughes
of Gwerkles Owen Wynne (<ref idref="n147">147</ref>) Pengwren Edmond Meirick Simon Lloyd Robert Wynne of Mayesinduod Richard
Mostin Richard Mitton Lewis Lewis Jenkin Vaughan Owen Eyton Meredith Lloyd Anthony Thomas Richard Poole
of Caenest John Mayesmore Thomas Lloyd of Llandeckwin Mr William Eyton William Williams Robert Price of
Ysgroweddar John Jones of Mowthway Rowland Price Richard Owens Hugh Tydder of Egrynn Esquires Robert
Wynne of Garthmelli Gentleman Mr Robert Nanney of Kefudauddwr Mr Edward Lloyd of Dwifane Mr John
Morgan of Plasse Mr Ellis Davies Mr John Lewis Mr John Lloyd of Kefufais Mr Harry Mostin Mr William
Owens of Llangar Mr John Humphryes Mr Hugh Hughes Mr [Caleb<ref idref="n148">148</ref>] Lloyd Mr John Edwards of Tonfane
Mr Ellis Oliver of Penmayne Mr Evan Lloyd of Rhiwgoth Mr Oliver Thomas Mr John Lloyd of Uron
Mr Rees Pritchard of Llwyngwrill Mr Robert Oliver of Penmayne Mr Thomas Roberts of Llandervell Mr
Griffith Roberts of Rhiwgorth Mr Robert, Lloyd of Uron Mr Edward Hughes of Towin Mr Hugh Owens of
Kaerberllan Mr Robert Vaughan of Kerwnwch Mr William Humphreys Mr Thomas Lloyd of Hendivr Mr Richard
Humphrys Mr Griffith Vaughan of Dolymelyullwyn Mr. John Price of Llwyngavern Mr Morris Davies Mr
Humphrey Hughes of Penbrin Mr Andrew Jones of Rhidiven Sir John Wynne Knight and Baronet.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s127">
			<head>For the County of Mountgomery</head>
			<para id="p130">The Honourable Andrew Newport Sir John Price Baronet Sir William Williams Knight and Baronet Price
Devereux William Pugh of Mathaverne Edward Lloyd of Berth Lloyd Edward Vaughan John Mathews Mathew
Morgan Richard Mostin John Kiffin Walter Clopton Charles Herbert John Edwards of Roreington Edward [Leighton<ref idref="n149">149</ref>]
Edward Barret Arthur Vaughan Thomas [Rock<ref idref="n150">150</ref>] Arthur [Devereux<ref idref="n151">151</ref>] Charles Lloyd of Garth Gabriell Wynne
Richard Lee Phillip Eyton Daniell Wittingham Richard Herbert Richard Stedman Thomas Mason Nathaniell Maurice
Humphrey [Knaston<ref idref="n152">152</ref>] Thomas Lloyd Edward Price Robert Lloyd Arthur Weaver Mathew Price [Mederith<ref idref="n153">153</ref>] Morgan
Esquires William Williams Evan Glynn Vincent Peirce Rowland Owen of Kunloeth Richard Owens senior Richard
Owens junior John Thomas of Penegos Edward Evans Edmond Lloyd Richard Ingram Humphrey Jones Sydney
Buner Esquires [Rumley<ref idref="n154">154</ref>] Williams junior Richard Mason Edward Jones Tho Jucks Gilbert Jones John Griffiths
of Glanhaveren Richard Rocke Roger Trevor William Lloyd of Finnat Richard Price of Gunley Vaughan
Dervereux Thomas Griffiths Thomas Hodson Solomon Bowen Humphrey Lloyd of Goytree Samuell Lloyd John
Griffith of Bachayee John Vaughon of Mivod John Reed Hugh Derwas Robert Kinaston Hugh Davies of
Colfrin John Davies of the same William Evans of Llandrinio Evan Jones (<ref idref="n155">155</ref>) Llanlothian Richard Davies of
[Kenhinna<ref idref="n156">156</ref>] Rees Lloyd of Cowny John Herbert George Robinson Griffith Robinson Richard Price of Cettas
David Merdith of Llanwothelan Thomas Gwynne Richard Glynne Price Clunn Rees Lloyd of Clothean Edward
Bowen of Penyralt John Wilson Edward Price of Streetvalog Edmond Price Morgan David of Penegos Rondle
Owen Humphrey Owen Evan Jones Roger Jones George Higgins Gent..</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s128">
			<head>For the County of Pembrooke</head>
			<para id="p131">The Right Honourable Richard Lord Bulkley Viscount [Vassells<ref idref="n157">157</ref>] in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Erasmus
Phillips Baronet Sir Hugh Owen Baronet Sir John Barlow Baronet Sir William Wogan Knight Their Majestyes
Serjeant at Law Hector Phillips Essex Miricke Arthur Owen Rowland Langharne Edward Phillips Hugh Bowen
William Scourfield Walter Midleton John Owen John Williams David Williams Griffith Dawes John Langharne
Thomas Lloyd of Greenhill John Barlow of Lawrenny Lewis Wogan of Boulston Lewis Wogan of Wiston George
Lort William Mordant Arthur Owen junior Will: Lucy John Cannon Griffith Hawkwell George Bowen James
Lloyd Julius Deeds William Warren Thomas Corbett William Skirme George Meare Lewis John Charles Phillips
Henry Walter John Barlow junior George Lehunt David Maurice William Wogan junior John Phillips John
Lewis Arthur Langharne Hugh Langharne John Edwards Hugh Wogan Esquires Erasmus Corbett Robert
Williams Gwynne Vaughan William Ford senior Owen Ford William Jones William Ford junior John Childe
Thomas Jones George Harries John Owen of Priskelly George Lloyd John Owen of Berlam Rice Powell James
Langharne Rice Adams John Wogan John Morris Gentlemen The Mayor of Pembrooke for the time being
Francis Rogers Francis Dawes John Coursey Aldermen the Mayor of Tenby for the time being Henry Williams
James Lloyd Devereux Hammond John Morris.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s129">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Haverford-West.</head>
			<para id="p132">The Mayor for the time being Sir Erasmus Phillips Baronet Sir Hugh Owen Baronet Sir William Wogan
Knight Their Majestyes Serjieant at Law Arthur Owen Lewis Wogan of Bolston Richard [Howell<ref idref="n158">158</ref>] Hugh Wogan
William Skirme John Lewis of Manernawan Esquires William Flaerton Doctor in Physicke Roger David Robert
Prust senior John Bateman John Fowler Thomas Poyer William [Bowne<ref idref="n159">159</ref>] William Browne George Lewis Jacob
Wolford Vincent Powell Robert Prust junior William Bateman junior Aldermen Thomas Harries William Bowen
Thomas Lewlin Gentt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s130">
			<head>For the County of Radnor.</head>
			<para id="p133">Sir John Morgan Sir Standish Hartstongue Sir Edward Williams Baronets Sir Edward Harley Knight of the
Bath Sir Rowland Gwinne Sir Lacon Childe John Fowler Esq[uire] High Sheriffe William Fowler Richard Williams
Henry Walcott Thomas Lewis Thomas Lewis junior Edward Lewis Marmaduke Gwynne Samuell Powell Thomas
Harley Litleton Powell Henry Probert Thomas Vaughan Edward Houerth Robert Lucy Edward Price Nicholas
Taylor Jeremiah Powell William Morgan Peter Richards Herbert Veston Charles Creed James Lloyd William
Brewster John Walsam Charles Lloyd Esquires Lewis Lloyd Thomas Lewis of Nantguilt Nicholas Meredith
Thomas Davies John Davies of Coedgelasson John Davies of Bronlaes Thomas Howerth Evan Vaughan William
Lloyd Lemuell Lloyd Coroners William Tayler Hugh Lewis of Hendwall Jonas Stephens John Stephens Lloyd
Weston Henry Tall Henry Vaughan Walter Vaughan Thomas Powell David Powell Edward Philips Griffith Payne
Thomas Griffith John Whitney Nehemiah Ketlebye Gentlemen John Davies John Stephens Herbert Weston Lloyd
Weston Thomas Lewis senior [Esquires<ref idref="n160">160</ref>] Thomas Lewis junior Esquire The Bayliffe of New Radnor Sir Standish
Hartstongue.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s131">
			<head>Commissioners to meet on or before the Fifth Day of February.</head>
			<para id="p134">
				<emph type="i">At the First Meeting to divide themselves in Hundreds, &amp;c. To direct Precepts to certain Number of Inhabitants, Constables, &amp;c. to appear before Commissioners.; At their Appearances the Commissioners to read the Rates and instruct them how to proceed in Execution of Act.; Such Persons absenting or refusing to serve. Penalty 40s.; Commissioners to appoint Assessors; and to appoint a Day and Place for Assessors to bring in Certificates of Names, &amp;c. and Substance of Persons liable. Assessors to inform themselves of the Value of Lands, &amp;c and thereupon to assess the same; and to bring at the Time so prefixed a Certificate of such Assessment; and also to return Names fit to be Collectors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p135">Which said Commissioners soe as aforesaid Nominated and Appointed shall in the respective Counties Cities
Burroughs Divisions Townes and Places for which they are Appointed Commissioners respectively meete together
at the most usuall or common Place of meeting within each of the said Counties Cities Burroughes Divisions
Townes and Places respectively at or before the Fifth day of February which shall be in the Yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred eighty and nine And the said Commissioners or soe many of them as shall be
present at the First generall Meeting or the major part of them may by their Consents and Agreements divide
as well themselves as other the Commissioners not then present for the Execution of this Act in Hundreds Lathes
Wapentakes Rapes Wards Townes and other Places within their Limitts Priviledged or not Priviledged in such
Manner and Forme as to them shall seeme expedient (Neverthelesse not thereby to restraine the said Commissioners
from Acting as Commissioners in any other part of the County or Place for which they are Nominated) And
shall Direct their severall or joynt Precept or Precepts to such Inhabitants High-Constables Petty Constables
Bayliffes and other like Officers and Ministers and such number of them as they in their Discretion shall thinke
most convenient requireing them to appeare before the said Commissioners at such Place and Time not exceeding
Ten Dayes as they shall appoint, And at such their Appearances the said Commissioners shall openly Reade or
cause to be Read unto them the Rates and Assesments in this Act mentioned and alsoe openly declare the
Effect of their Charge to them and how and in what manner they ought and should make their Certificates
and how they ought to proceede in the Execution of this Act according to the Rates aforesaid And if any High
Constables Petty Constables Bayliffes Inhabitants or other Officers or Ministers to whome any Precept shall be
directed shall absent themselves without lawfull Excuse to be made out by the Oathes of Two credible Witnesses
which Oathes the [said<ref idref="n161">161</ref>] Commissioners or any Two of them are hereby impowered to administer Or if any Person
appeareing shall refuse to Serve Then every such Person soe makeing Default or refuseing to Serve shall for every
time of such Default or Refuseall forfeite and lose unto Their Majestyes such Summe as the Com[m]issioners or soe
many as shall be present or the major part of them being present shall thinke fitt not exceeding the Summe
of Forty shillings And at or after such generall Meeting had and Charge given as aforesaid the said Commissioners
shall take care that Warrants be issued forth and directed to Two at the least of the most able and sufficient
Inhabitants of each Parish Towneship or Place within the respective Divisions thereby appointing and requireing them
to be Assessors of all and every the Rates and Duties by this Act Imposed and shall therein alsoe appoint and
prefix a certaine Day and Place for the said Assessors to appeare before them and [to<ref idref="n161">161</ref>] bring in their Certificates in
Writeing of the Names and Sirnames of every Person dwelling and resideing within the Limitts of those Places
with which they shall be charged and of the Substance and Values of every of them in ready Moneys Debts
Goods Chattells or other Personall Estate whatsoever (except before excepted) or in Publique Offices or Imployments
of Profitt And the said Assessors are therein alsoe to be required and are hereby enjoyned to ascertaine and informe
themselves by all lawfull Wayes and Meanes they can of the true and full yearly Value of all Mannours Messuages
Lands and Tenements as alsoe of all Quarries Mines of Coale Tinn or Lead Iron Workes Salt Springs and Salt Workes
Allom Mines or Workes Parks Chases Warrens Woods Underwoods and Coppices and all Fishings Tythes Tolls Annuities
and other yearely Profitts and of all Hereditaments of what nature or kinde soever scituate lying and being happening
or ariseing within the Limitts of those Place swith which they shall be charged and being [thereof soe<ref idref="n162">162</ref>] ascertained
they are to Assesse all and every the said Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements and Premisses before appointed
to be Charged after the Rate of Two shillings for every Twenty shillings of the full yearely Value as the same
are Lett for or [are<ref idref="n163">163</ref>] worth to be Lett at the time of Assessing thereof as aforesaid and to bring with them at
the Time and Place soe as aforesaid prefixed for their Appearance a Certificate in Writeing of the said Assessment
and shall then alsoe returne the Names of Two or more able and sufficient Persons liveing within the Limitts and
Bounds of those Parishes Towneships Constablewicks or Places where they shall be chargeable respectively to be
Collectors of the Moneys to be paid to Their Majestyes by this Act for whose paying in to the Head Collector in
manner hereafter mentioned such Moneyes as they shall be charged withall the Parish or Place wherein they
are soe imployed shall be Answerable.</para>
		</section>
		</section>
		</section>
		<section id="s132">
			<head>VI. Assessors neglecting or refusing to serve, or making Default of Appearance, or not performing their Duty.</head>
			<para id="p136">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.; Oaths to be taken by the Assessors.; 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. I. c. 8.; Form of Oath</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p137">And if any Assessor soe as aforesaid appointed or to be appointed shall neglect or refuse to Serve or shall
make Default at the time appointed for his Appearance (not haveing a lawfull Excuse to be Witnessed by the
Oathes of Two credible Witnesses which the said Commissioners or any Two of them have power to Administer)
or shall not performe his Duty every such Assessor shall for every such Neglect Refusall or Default forfeit and
lose unto Their Majesties such Summe as the Commissioners or soe many of them as shall be present or the
major part of them shall thinke fitt not exceeding the Summe of Ten pounds nor under the Summe of Five
pounds to be Levyed by Distresse and Sale of the Offenders Goods and Chattells in like manner as by this Act
is appointed for Levying the severall Rates and Assesments herein mentioned in case of neglect or refusall of
Payment and to be charged upon the respective Receivers Generall together with the said Rates and Assesments
And every Assessor soe as aforesaid appointed or to be appointed shall before he take upon him the Execution
of the said Imployment take the Oathes mentioned and required to be taken by an Act of this present Parlyament
Entituled An Act for Abrogating the Oathes of Supremacy and Allegiance and Appointing other Oathes And
alsoe take an Oath to be Administred in these Words following</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s133">
			<head>Form of Oath.</head>
			<para id="p138">You shall Sweare well and truely to Execute the Duty of an Assessor and to cause the Rates and Duties
Imposed by an Act Entituled An Act for a Grant to Their Majestyes of an Ayd of Two shillings in the
Pound for One Yeare to be Duely and Impartially Assessed according to the best of your Skill and Knowledge
And therein you shall spare noe Person for Favour or Affection nor any Person Grieve for Hatred or Ill Will.</para>
			<para id="p139">Soe helpe you God.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s134">
			<head>Commissioners to administer same.</head>
			<para id="p140">Which Oathes any two Commissioners in the County where the said Assesment is to be made have hereby Power
and are required to Administer</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s135">
			<head>VII. Assessments on Personal Estate, Offices, &amp;c. to be made, and Certificates returned on or before the 19th of Feb. unless longer Time be given by the Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p141">
				<emph type="i">The like Provision as to Assessments on Real Estates.; On Return of Certificates, Commissioners may examine Presenters.; Commissioners having Cause to suspect that any Persons or Lands are omitted or undercharged, may summon the Persons concerned to be examined.; Persons summoned neglecting to appear; Penalty, Double Rate.; Commissioners may examine into the Values, and set such Rates as are according to the Intent of the Act.; Assessors to give one Copy of their Assessment to the Commissioners.; Commissioners to give Duplicates to the Sub-Collectors, Head Collectors, and Receivers General; And to cause a Copy or Extract under Hand and Seal to be certified into the Exchequer before the 17th of March; Which the King's Remembrancer shall transcribe within Three Months and transmit to the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt; Who is to enter the same</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p142">And bee it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Rates and Assesments upon all ready Moneys
Debts Goods Chattells Personall Estate and Publiq[uire] Offices and Employments of Proffit charged by this Act shall
be ascertained and the Certificates thereof returned to the Commissioners upon or before the Nineteenth day of
February One thousand six hundred eighty nine unlesse the Commissioners shall thinke fitt to give further time
And alsoe the Taxations and Assesments of the Pound-Rate of Two shillings in the Pound for every Twenty
shillings of the yearely Value of all Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses charged
by this Act shall be made and ascertained and the severall and respective Certificates thereof returned in to the
Com[m]issioners upon or before the Nineteenth day of February aforesaid unlesse the Commissioners shall thinke fitt to
give further time And upon returne of any such Certificate the Commissioners or any Three or more of them
shall and may (if they see cause) Examine the Presenters thereof And if the said Com[m]issioners or any Three or
more of them within their severall Limitts at the time of the returne of the Certificates as aforesaid or within
Twenty dayes after shall know or have good cause to suspect that any Person or Persons or any the Mannours
Messuages Lands or other the Premisses which ought to be mentioned and charged in the said Certificates
is or are ommitted or that any Person or Persons in the said Certificate mentioned is or are of a greater Estate
or that any the said Mannours or other Premisses are of a greater yearely Value then in the said Certificate is
mentioned the said Commissioners or any Three or more of them shall have Power to Summon such Person or
Persons and the Owners or Possessors of such Mannours or other Premisses to appeare before them at a Day and
Place prefixed to be Examined touching the Matters aforesaid And if the Person or Persons Summoned to be
soe Examined shall neglect to appeare (not haveing a reasonable Excuse for such his Default) every Person soe
making Default shall pay to Their Majestyes double the Summe he should or ought to have beene Sett at or
Rated And moreover the Commissioners or the major part of soe many of them as shall be present shall have
Power by all lawfull Wayes and Meanes to Examine into the Estate of such Person and the Value of such
Premisses chargeable by this Act and to Sett such Rate or Rates upon the same as shall be according to the
true intent of this Act And the said Assessors are hereby required to give one Copy of their Certificates or
Assesments fairely Written and Subscribed by them unto the said Commissioners by whome they were appointed
And the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them are hereby ordered and required to cause the said
severall and respective Assesments to them delivered (when by them Approved of or Altered according to the
true intent of this Act) to be fairely Written and to Signe and Seale severall Duplicates or Copies of the said
Assesment and one of them soe Signed and Sealed forthwith to deliver or cause to be delivered unto the Sub
Collectors and shall likewise deliver or cause to be delivered other Copies thereof soe Signed and Sealed unto the
Head Collectors and Receivers Generall according to their severall and respective Collections and Receipts And
moreover the Commissioners shall cause a true-Copy or Extract of the whole Summes Assessed and Charged
within every Hundred Lath Wapentake Parish Ward or Place Rated or Assessed in pursuance of this Act and
of the whole Summes Rated or Assessed upon Personall Estates Offices or Imployments to be Certifyed and
Transmitted into Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer under the Hands and Seales of any Two or more of the
Commissioners but without nameing the Persons in such their Certificates And this the said Commissioners shall
cause to be done upon or before the Seaventeenth Day of March then next ensueing or within Thirty dayes
after (all Appeales to them made being first determined) And the Kings Remembrancer in the Exchequer for
the time being shall and is hereby required within Three monthes after the Duplicates of the last Payment shall
be Transmitted to him to Transcribe all the Schedules and Duplicates of the Summes returned to him from and
for every respective County Rideing City and Towne and every Hundred Wapentake Parish Division Towne and
Place therein in a Booke of Parchment in Alphabeticall Order and a faire Legible Handwriteing and within Three
monthes after the same shall be soe by him received to Transmitt all and every the same Schedules and Duplicates
to the Office of the Writer of the Tallyes com[m]only called the Auditor of the Receipt of the Exchequer who is
hereby likewise authorised and required to Enter the same in the like Alphabeticall Order in another Booke of
Parchment fairely Written to be [provided<ref idref="n164">164</ref>] for that purpose</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s136">
			<head>VIII. Two or more Commissioners to issue Warrants to the Sub-Collectors.</head>
			<para id="p143">
				<emph type="i">Sub-Collectors to demand; Assessments; and to levy and pay the same to Head Collectors.;Head Collectors to hasten Sub-Collectors; and to levy and distrain upon Sub-Collectors being behind.; Head Collectors to make Payment to the Receiver General.; Receiver General to pay into the Exchequer on or before the 25th of March, or within 20 Days after.; Sub-Collectors to levy 1st Quarterly Payment, and to pay same to Head Collectors.; Head Collectors to hasten Sub-Collectors, and in case of Failure to proceed as aforesaid. Head Collector to make Payment to the Receiver General on the 15th of March, or within 20 Days after.; Receiver General to hasten Head Collectors, and to pay into the Exchequer on or before the 25th of March, or within 20 Days after.; Sub-Collectors to levy 2d Payment, and pay the same to Head Collectors. Head Collectors to make Payment thereof to Receiver General.; Receivers General to pay into the Receipt of the Exchequer on the 24th of June, or within 20 Days.; Sub-Collectors to levy the 3d Quarterly Payment.; Head Collectors to hasten the Sub-Collectors. Head Collector to make his Payment to the Receiver General. Receiver General to hasten Head Collectors, and to; make his Payment into the Exchequer on or before 29th Sept. or within 20 Days.; Sub-Collectors to levy the Fourth Quarterly Payment. Head Collectors to make Payment to Receiver General, who is to make Payment into the Exchequer, on or before the 25th Dec. or within 20 Days</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p144">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Commissioners or any Two or more of them
shall issue out their Warrants or Estreates to the Subcollectors under their Hands and Seales thereby Requireing
them to Levy and Collect all and every the Assesments and all the Moneys and Rates due thereupon according to
the Duplicates thereof by them received and according to the Intent and Directions of this present Act Which said
Sub Collectors are hereby required to demand all and every the Rates and Assesments herein mentioned which are
laid upon Persons in respect of their Personall Estates Offices or Employments and to make such Demands of the
Parties themselves if they can be found or otherwise at the Place of their last Abode and to Levy and Pay the
same upon or before the First day of March in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty and nine
or within Twenty dayes after at such Place as the Commissioners shall appoint unto their respective Head Collectors
who are hereby required to call upon and hasten their Subcollectors to the said Payments And at or upon the
Eighth day of March aforesaid or within Twenty dayes after to Levy by Warrant under the Hands and Seales of
any Two or more of the said Commissioners by Distresse upon the Subcollectors respectively such Summe and
Summes of Money as by him or them ought to have beene paid and is or are not paid by reason of his failure
in doeing his Duty according to the Directions of this Act soe as every Head Collector may make Payment unto
the Receiver Generall of the said County City or Place to be Appointed by Their Majestyes of the full Summes
by him to be paid on the Fifteenth day of March aforesaid or within Twenty dayes after And the Receiver Generall
is likewise required to call upon and hasten the said Head Collectors and to Pay what he shall soe receive from
the said Head Collectors into Their Majesties Receipt of [Excheque<ref idref="n165">165</ref>] upon or before the Five and twentyeth day
of March aforesaid or within Twenty dayes after to the end that all and every the Rates and Assesments which
by this Act are Imposed upon any Person or Persons in respect of his or their Personall Estate Offices or
Employments may be spedily brought into Their Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer and there paid in upon or
before the said Five and twentyeth day of March or within Twenty dayes after at One entire Payment And
the said Sub Collectors are alsoe required and enjoyned to Levy one Fourth part of the Pound Rate charged
upon all Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses as aforesaid and to pay the
same unto their respective Head Collectors on or before the Eighth day of March aforesaid or within Twenty
dayes after And the said Head Collectors are to hasten the said Sub Collectors And in case the same shall not
be Collected by reason of [defect<ref idref="n166">166</ref>] or failure of Duty of the said Sub Collectors the said Head Collectors are to
proceede against them by Distresse in like manner and by like Warrant as aforesaid And every Head Collector is
hereby required to make Payment of what shall be soe Levyed or Received unto the Receiver Generall of the
said County City or Place upon or before the Fifteenth day of March aforesaid or within Twenty dayes after And
the Receiver Generall is likewise required to call upon and hasten the said Head Collectors and to pay what he
shall Receive from the said Head Collectors unto Their Majesties Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the Five
and twentyeth day of March aforesaid or within Twenty dayes after to the end that the First Payment of the
said Pound-Rate of Two shillings may by that time be fully Answered and Paid in to Their Majestyes, And the
Subcollectors shall alsoe Levy the Second Quarterly Payment of the said Pound-Rate Charged as aforesaid upon
or before the Second day of June then next ensueing or within Twenty dayes after and shall alsoe Pay the same
unto the said Head Collectors upon or before the Ninth day of June aforesaid or within Twenty dayes after
And the said Head Collectors shall make Payment thereof to the Receiver Generall of the said County City or
Place upon or before the Sixteenth day of June aforesaid or within Twenty dayes after And the said Receiver
Generall is alsoe required to make Payment of all which he shall soe Receive into Their Majestyes Receipt of
Exchequer upon or before the said Foure and twentyeth day of June then next ensueing or within Twenty
dayes after to the end that the Second Payment of the said Pound Rate soe Charged as aforesaid may by that
time be fully Answered and Paid in to Their Majestyes And the said Sub Collectors are alsoe required and
enjoyned to Levy One other Quarterly Payment of the said Pound Rate Charged as aforesaid upon or before
the Fourth day of September then next ensueing and shall alsoe Pay the same unto the respective Head
Collectors on or before the Twelfth day of September aforesaid or within Twenty dayes after And the said
Head Collectors are to hasten the said Sub Collectors And in case the same shall not be Collected by reason
of neglect or failure of Duty in the said Sub Collectors the Head Collectors are to proceede against them by
Distresse in like manner and by like Warrant as aforesaid And every Head Collector is hereby required to make
Payment of what shall be soe Levyed or Received unto the Receiver Generall of the said County City or
Place upon or before the Nine and twentyeth day of September aforesaid or within Twenty dayes after And the
Receiver Generall is likewise required to call upon and hasten the said Head Collectors and to Pay what he
shall Receive from the said Head Collectors unto Their Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the Nine
and twentyeth day of September aforesaid or within Twenty dayes after to the end that the Third Payment of
the said Pound-Rate of Two shillings may by that time be fully Answered and Paid in to Their Majesties And
the Subcollectors shall alsoe Levy One other Quarterly Payment of the said Pound Rate Charged as aforesaid
upon or before the Second day of December then next ensueing or within Twenty dayes after and shall alsoe
Pay the same unto the said Head Collectors upon or before the ninth day of December aforesaid or within twenty
dayes after And the said Head Collectors shall make Payment thereof to the Receiver Generall of the said County
City or Place upon or before the Sixteenth day of December aforesaid or within Twenty dayes after And the said
Receiver Generall is alsoe required to make Payment of all which he shall soe Receive into Their Majestyes
Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the Five and twentyeth day of December aforesaid or within Twenty dayes
after to the end that the Fourth and last Quarterly Payment of the said Pound Rate soe Charged as aforesaid
may by that time be fully Answered and Paid in to Their Majesties And all Commissioners Collectors and
Receivers are hereby required and enjoyned to apply themselves with all Diligence to the most speedy and
effectuall Execution of their severall and respective Duties that soe Their Majestyes Service herein may not be
delayed or hindred through any of their wilfull neglect or default.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s137">
			<head>IX. Sub-Collectors to pay Monies received by them to Head Collectors, whose Receipt to be a Discharge. Reward to Sub-Collector, Head Collectors to pay to Receiver General, and to be nominated by him. Receivers General answerable.
Sub-Collectors not obliged to travel more than 10 Miles to make their Payments.; Receiver General's Acquittance a Discharge to Head Collector.; Reward to Head Collector.; Receiver General to pay Monies received by him into the Exchequer, as before mentioned. Allowance to Receiver General.</head>
			<para id="p145">And it is further Enacted and Declared by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Moneys Received by the Sub
Collectors within the respective Divisions or Hundreds shall from time to time be duely Paid to the Head
Collectors whose Receipt shall be a sufficient Discharge unto every such Sub Collector which Sub Collector for
Gathering the said particular Summes shall retaine in his Hands for every Twenty shillings by him soe Paid
Three pence as a Reward for his Paines and Service And the Head Collectors shall accordingly Pay over the
said Moneys unto the Receiver Generall of each County City or Place respectively in manner aforesaid (which
Head Collector or Collectors shall be Nominated and Appointed by the Receivers Generall of the respective
Counties which said Receivers Generall shall be Answerable for all such Summes of Money as shall be by him
or them Collected or Received) And that noe Sub Collector shall be enforced to Travell above the space of
Ten miles for the Payment of the said Moneys that shall be by him Collected or Received And the said Receiver
[Generall<ref idref="n167">167</ref>] Acquittance shall be a sufficient Discharge unto every such Head Collector who shall retaine in his
Hands for every Twenty shillings soe by him Paid One Peny as a Reward for his Paines and Service And the
Receiver Generall shall Pay the whole Summes by him Received into the Receipt of Their Majestyes Exchequer
in such manner and at or before such Dayes and Times as are herein before limited and shall have an Allowance
of Two pence in the Pound for all Moneys which shall be by him Paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer
upon or before the Times prefixed in this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s138">
			<head>X. Fee to Commissioners Clerks for transcribing Warrants. Persons neglecting, &amp;c. to pay Assessment in respect of Personal Estate, Offices, or Lands; Distress issued and Proceedings thereon.</head>
			<para id="p146">
				<emph type="i">Rate not paid in Four Days Distress appraised and sold for Payment, and Overplus to Owner.; Houses, &amp;c. may be broken open</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p147">And for the carefull Writeing and Transcribeing the said Warrants Estreats and Duplicates in due time It is
further Enacted That the Commissioners Clerkes who shall respectively performe the same shall by Warrant under
Two or more of the Commissioners Hands have and receive from the respective Head Collectors One Peny in
the Pound of all such Moneys as he or they shall have Received by vertue of such Warrants and Estreats
(who are hereby appointed and allowed to Pay the same accordingly) And if any Person shall neglect or refuse
to pay the severall Rates and Assesments wherewith he is Charged by this Act for or in respect of his Personall
Estate Offices or Employment and which he ought to Pay Or if the Pound Rate or any Payment thereof soe
as aforesaid Charged upon any Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses shall be
neglected or refused to be Paid Then upon Demand made by the Officer or Collector of the Place according to
the Precept or Estreate to him delivered by the said Commissioners it shall and may be lawfull to and for such
Officer or Collector and he and they is and are hereby required for Non-payment thereof to Distraine the
Person or Persons soe refuseing or neglecting to Pay by his or their Goods or Chattells or to Distraine [in and<ref idref="n168">168</ref>]
upon the Messuages Lands Tenements and Premisses soe Charged and the Goods and Chattells then and there
found and the Distresse soe taken to keepe by the space of foure Dayes at the Costs and Charges of the Owner
thereof and if the said Owner doe not pay the Summe of Money due by this Act within the said Foure dayes
Then the said Distresse to be Appraised by two or three of the Inhabitants where the said Distresse is taken and
to be sold by the said Officer or Collector for the payment of the said Money and the overplus comeing by the
said Sale (if any be over and above the Charges of takeing and keepeing the Distress) to be immediately restored
to the Owner thereof And moreover it shall be lawfull to breake open in the day-time any House and upon
Warrant under the Hands and Scales of any two or more of the said Commissioners any Chest Trunke or Box
or other things where such Goods are (calling to their Assistance the Constables Tythingmen or Headburroughs
within the Countyes Townes or Places where any Refusall Neglect or Resistance shall be made which said Officers
are hereby required to be Aiding and Assisting in the Premisses)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s139">
			<head>XI. Infants making Default, Parents, &amp;c. to pay, and on Default may be proceeded against.</head>
			<para id="p148">
				<emph type="i">Parents, &amp;c. allowed such Payments in their Accounts. Tenants to pay for Landlords and may deduct out of; their Rents, and Landlords to allow such Deductions.; Tenant hereby acquitted for such Payments</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p149">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That where any Person or Persons chargeable with
any Rates or Assessments by this Act Imposed shall be under the Age of One and twenty years in every such
Case the Parents Guardians or Tutors of such Infants respectively upon default of payment by such Infants shall
be and are hereby made lyable to and chargeable with the Payments which such Infants ought to have made And
if such Parents (<ref idref="n169">169</ref>) Guardians or Tutors shall neglect or refuse to pay as aforesaid if shall and may be lawfull to
proceede against them in like manner as against any other Person or Persons makeing default of payment as
herein before appointed And all Parents Guardians or Tutors makeing payment as aforesaid shall be allowed all
and every the Summes soe paid for such Infants upon his and their Accompts And the severall and respective
Tennants of all and every the Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses which by vertue
of this Act shall be chargeable with any Pound Rate as aforesaid are hereby [authorized and required<ref idref="n170">170</ref>] to pay
such Summe or Summes of Money as shall be Rated upon such Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments
and Premisses and to deduct out of their Rents soe much of the said Rates as in respect of the said Rents
payable for such Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments or Premisses the Landlord should and
ought to beare And all Landlords both mediate and immediate (according to their respective Interests) are hereby
required to allow such Deductions and Payments upon Receipt of the residue of the Rents And every Tennant
paying the said Assessments of the Pound Rate shall bee and is hereby Acquitted and Discharged for soe much
Money as the said Assesment shall amount unto as if the same had beene actually paid unto such Person or
Persons unto whome his Rent should have beene due &amp; payable.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s140">
			<head>XII. Persons in Office rated where such Office is executed.</head>
			<para id="p150">
				<emph type="i">Other Persons, in respect of Personal Estate, to be rated where resident. Persons not being Householders, &amp;c. to be rated where resident at Execution of Act. Absentees rated at last Place of Abode.; Proviso as to Persons having Goods, &amp;c. in any County other than County where resident.; Persons rated for Lands, &amp;c. to be rated where Lands situate</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p151">And bee it (<ref idref="n171">171</ref>) Enacted That every Person Rated or Assessed for his Office or Employment shall be Rated
and Pay for his (<ref idref="n172">172</ref>) Office and Employment in the County City or Place where such Office or Employment is
executed. And every Person who is or shall be Rated for or in respect of any Personall Estate to him any way
belonging shall be Rated at such Place where he or she shall be resident at the time of the Execution of this
Act And all Persons not being Householders nor haveing a certaine Place of Residence shall be Taxed at the
Place where they shall be resident at the time of the Execution of this Act And if any Person who ought to
be Taxed by vertue of this Act for or in respect of his Personall Estate shall at the time of his Assesment be
out of the Realme such Person shall be Rated therefore in-such County City or Place where he was last abideing
within the Realme Provided that where any Person shall have any Goods Wares or Merchandizes in any County
or Countyes other then the County where he shall be resident or had his last Residence it shall be lawfull to
Rate or Assesse such Person for such Goods Wares and Merchandizes in the County or Countyes where the
[same<ref idref="n173">173</ref>] shall be [And every Person who shall be<ref idref="n173">173</ref>] Rated or Assessed for or in respect of any Mannours Messuages
Lands Tenements or other the Premisses according to the Poundrate of Two shillings as aforesaid shall be Rated
and Assessed in the Place where such Messuages Mannours Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses respectively
doe lye and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s141">
			<head>XIII. If Persons having several Mansions be doubly charged in respect of Personal Estate,</head>
			<para id="p152">
				<emph type="i">on Certificate of Commissioners, to be granted without Fee, and on Oath before Justices of Peace, such Persons discharged; Persons escaping from Taxation charged at Double the Value</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p153">Provided alwayes That if any Person or Persons by reason of his or their haveing severall Mansion houses or
places of Residence or otherwise shall be doubly Charged by occasion of this Act for or in respect of his or
their Personall Estate then upon Certificate made by two or more of the Commissioners for the County City or
Place of his or their last Personall Residence under their Hands and Seales of the Summe or Summes charged
upon him or them and in what Capacity or Respect he or they were soe charged (which Certificate the said
Commissioners are required to give without Delay Fee or Reward) And upon Oath made of such Certificate
before any one Justice of the Peace of the County or Place where the said Certificate shall be made (which Oath
the said Justice of Peace is hereby Authorized and Required to Administer) Then the Person and Persons soe
doubly Charged shall for soe much as shall be soe certified be Discharged in every other County City or Place,
And if any Person that ought to be Taxed by vertue of this Act for or in respect of his Personall Estate shall
by changeing his Place of Residence or by any other Fraude or Covin escape from the Taxation and not be
Taxed and the same be proved before the Commissioners or any two of them or before any two Justices of the
Peace of the County where such person dweleth or resideth at any time within Six Moneths next ensueing after
such Taxe made every Person that shall soe escape from the Taxation and Payment shall be Charged (upon
proofe thereof) at the double Value of soe much as he should or ought to have beene Taxed at by this Act
the said double Value (upon Certificate thereof made into the Exchequer by the Commissioners or Justices before
whome such Proofe shall be made) to be Levyed of the Goods Lands and Tenements of such Persons</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s142">
			<head>XIV. The Power of Commissioners to assess other Commissioners and Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p154">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Commissioners that shall be within any
County City or Place within the respective Limitts or the major part of them shall Rate Tax and Assesse every
other Commissioner joyned with them for and in respect of the Ready Money Debts Goods Chattells and Personall
Estate of such Commissioners And alsoe for and in respect of the Offices and Employments of Profitt which at
the time of such Taxation shall be held and enjoyed by such Commissioner soe as the Residence and usuall
Dwelling-place of such Commissioner soe to be Taxed be within the Division of such Commissioner by whome
he is Taxed And soe as the Office or Employment held and enjoyed by such Commissioner soe to be Taxed be
likewise to be Exercised within the Division or Limitts of such Commissioner by whome he is to be Taxed And
the Commissioners within their Division shall alsoe Assesse every Assessor within their Division for all and singular
the Premisses for which by this Act he ought to be Rated and Assessed And as well all Summes Assessed upon
every the said Commissioners and Assessors as the Assesments made and sett by the Assessors aforesaid shall be
Written Estreated Levyed and Gathered as the same should and ought to have beene if such Commissioners had
not beene named Commissioners</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s143">
			<head>XV. Shares in New River, and in the Thames, Hyde Park and Marybone Waters.</head>
			<para id="p155">
				<emph type="i">Shares in the King's Printing House.; Companies of Merchants in London how and by whom assessed; And by whom and to whom the Rates in such Cases paid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p156">And bee it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons
haveing any Share or Shares or Interest in the Fresh Streame of Running Water brought to the North Parts of
London Com[m]only called the New River or in the Thames Water workes or in the Hyde-Parke or Marybone
Waters or any Rents or Profitts ariseing thereby And all Person and Persons haveing any Share or Interest in
the Stocke or Stocks for Printing of Bookes in or belonging to the House commonly called The Kings Printing
House shall pay for the same the Summe of Two shillings for every Twenty shillings of the full yearely Value
thereof And that all Companyes of Merchants in London charged by this Act shall be Assessed by the Commissioners
Nominated and Appointed for the said City or any Three of them for their respective Joynt Stocke and Stocks
And all and every Person and Persons haveing any Share or Shares or Interest in the [New<ref idref="n173">173</ref>] River Water brought
to the North part of London or in the Thames Water Workes or the Hyde Parke or Marybone Waters or [in<ref idref="n174">174</ref>]
any [Rent<ref idref="n175">175</ref>] or Profitts ariseing thereby charged by this Act And alsoe the said Stocke and Shares for Printing as
aforesaid shall be Assessed for the same in like manner by the said Commissioners or any Three of them after
the Rates herein Contained And the same shall be paid to such Person or Persons as the said Commissioners shall
Appoint by the Governours and Respective Treasurers of the said Respective Companies and by the Treasurer or
Receivers of the said River Waters and Water Works and Stocke for Printing and be deducted at and out of
their next Dividend.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s144">
			<head>XVI. Proviso for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey, and Guernsey; and for Persons born in Ireland, who have fled into this Kingdom.</head>
			<para id="p157">
				<emph type="i">Persons aggrieved by, Rate,; complaining within Ten Days to Commissioners,; the Commissioners may examine upon Oath,; and may abate or increase Assessment, and certify, &amp;c, same into Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p158">Provided also That this Act shall not extend to the Inhabitants of Scotland Ireland Jersey or Guernsey for and
concerning any such Personall Estate which they or any to their use have within the Places aforesaid Nor to any
Persons who haveing beene Inhabitants of Ireland have fled into this Kingdome since the First day of November
One thousand six hundred eighty and eight for or concerning any Personall Estate which they or any to their
use have in this Kingdome of England or in the said Kingdome of Ireland And if any Person or Persons Certified
Assessed or Rated for or in respect of any Reall or Personall Estate or for or in respect of any Matter or Thing
for which by this Act he or they is or may be Rated or Charged doe finde him or themselves agrieved with such
Assessing or Rateing and doe within Ten dayes after Demand thereof made Complaine to the Com[m]issioners the
said Commissioners or any Three or more of them (whereof one of the Commissioners who Signed or Allowed
his or their Rate to be one) shall and may within Ten dayes next after such Complaint perticularly Examine any
person or persons upon his or their Oath touching the Value of his or their Reall or Personall Estate and other
the Matters aforesaid and upon due Examina&amp;ctilde;on or Knowledge thereof. Abate Defaulke Increase or Enlarge the said
Assessment and the same soe Abated Increased or Enlarged shall be Levyed and shall be Certified or Estreated into
the Exchequer in manner aforesaid And to that end the said Commissioners are hereby required to meete together
for the Determineing of such Complaints and Appeales accordingly</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s145">
			<head>XVII. Assessors or others appointed by Commissioners neglecting Duty. Penalty certified into Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p159">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners from Time to Time to require Accounts from Receiver General, and in case of Failure, Money to be levied.; If any Controversy between Commissioners concerning the Rates, Proceedings.; Question touching the Rates determined by Two or more Commissioners.; Receiver General to give Acquittances to Head Collectors gratis, and Head Collectors to Subcollectors, Subcollectors to deliver to Head Collectors a Schedule under Hand and Seal of Names, &amp;c., of the Persons rated making Default when no Distress found.; Head Collector to deliver the same to the Receiver General to be by him returned into the Exchequer.; Proceedings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p160">And it is further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any Assessor Collector Receiver or other Person
appointed by the Com[m]issioners shall wilfully' neglect or refuse to performe his Duty in the due and speedy
Execution of this Act Or if any Assessor shall wittinly or knowingly Underrate or Assesse at an Under value
any Person or Thing chargeable by this Act The said respective Commissioners or any Three or more of them
may and shall by vertue of this Act Impose on such person and persons soe refuseing neglecting or not performeing.
their Duties any Fine not exceeding the Summe of Ten pounds nor under the Sum[m]e of Five pounds for every
Offence the same to be Levyed and Certified as aforesaid into Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer and Charged
upon the respective Receiver Generall amongst the rest of the Rates aforesaid And the said Commissioners or any
Two or more of them may and shall from time to time call for and require an Accompt from the respective
Receiver Generall of all the Moneys Received by him of the said Head Collectors and of the Payment thereof
into Their Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer according to the Direction of this Act And in case of any failure in
the Premisses the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them are hereby required to cause the same to
be forthwith Levyed and Paid according to the true intent and meaning of this Act And in case of any Controversie
ariseing betweene the said Commissioners concerning any Rates or Assessments to be laid by vertue of this Act the
Commissioners that shall be concerned therein shall have noe Voice but shall withdraw dureing the Debate of such
Controversie untill it be determined by the rest of the Commissioners And all Questions and Differences that shall
arise touching any of the said Rates Taxes Assesments or Levyes shall be Heard and finally Determined by Two
or more of the Commissioners upon Complaint thereof to them made by any person or persons thereby grieved
without further trouble or Suite in the Law And the said Receiver Generall shall give Acquittances gratis to the
said Head Collectors for all Moneys of them Received And the said Head Collectors shall also give Acquittances
gratis to the Subcollectors for all such Moneys as shall be paid them in persuance of this Act And the said
Subcollectors shall make and deliver to the said Head Collectors a perfect Schedule fairly Written in Parchment
under their Hands and Seales Signed and Allowed by any Two or more of the respective Commissioners containing
the Names Sirnames and Places of Abode of every Person within their respective Collection that shall make
default of payment of any of the Summes that shall be Rated or Assessed on such person by vertue of this Act
where noe sufficient Distresse is to be found and not otherwise and the Summe and Summes charged on every
such Person the same Schedule to be delivered by the Head Collector to the Receiver Generall of the County
City or Place respectively to be by him returned into Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer Whereupon every
Person soe makeing default of payment may be charged by Processe of the said Court according to the Course of
the Court of Exchequer in such Cases</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s146">
			<head>XVIII. Letters Patent from the Crown of Privilege or non obstantes not to exempt from Payment of Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p161">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Letters Patents Granted by Their Majesties or
any of Their Royall Progenitors to any Person or Persons Cities Burroughs or Townes Corporate within this
Realme of any manner of Liberties Priviledges or Exemptions from Subsidies Tolls Taxes Assessments or Aids shall
be construed or taken to Exempt any Person or Persons City Burrough or Towne Corporate or any of the
Inhabitants of the same from the Burthen and Charge of any Summe or Summes of Money Granted by this Act
But that all and every such Person and Persons City Burrough and Towne Corporate shall pay their Proportions
of all Rates and Assesments by this present Act Imposed (any such Letters Patents Grants or Charters or any
Clause of Non obstante Matter or Thing therein contained or any Law Statute Custome or Prescription to the
contrary notwithstanding)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s147">
			<head>XIX. Persons dwelling in Cities, &amp;c. not compelled to be Assessors, &amp;c. out of them.</head>
			<para id="p162">Provided alsoe That noe Person inhabiting in any City Burrough or Towne Corporate shall be compelled to be
any Assessor or Collector of or for any part of the Rates and Assessments hereby granted in any Place or Places
out of the Limitts of the said City Burrough or Towne Corporate.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s148">
			<head>XX. Proviso for Universities and Colleges of Windsor, Eton, Winchester, Westminster, Corporation for Relief of Clergymen's Widows, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p163">
				<emph type="i">College of Bromley, Free Schools, Hospitals, and Alms-Houses, Masters, &amp;c. in such Colleges, Christ's Hospital, St. Bartholomew, Bridewell, St. Thomas's and Bethlehem; but Tenants of said Hospitals, Colleges, &amp;c. to be rated according to Yearly Value above Rent reserved to said Hospitals, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p164">Provided alsoe That nothing in this Act contained shall be extended to Charge any Colledge or Hall in either
of the Universities or the Colleges of Windsor Eaton Winton or Westminster (or the Corporation of the Governours
of the Charity for Reliefe of poore Widows and Children of Clergymen) or the Colledge of Bromley or any
Hospitalls or Almeshouses or any Free Schoole for or in respect of the Scites of the said Colledges or Halls or
Hospitalls or Almeshouses or Free Schoole or any Master Fellow or Scholler of any such Colledge or Hall or in
any other Free Schooles or any Reader Officer or Minister of the said Universities Colledges or Schools or of any
Almesmen of any Hospitalls or Almshouses for or in respect of any Stipend Wages or Profitts whatsoever ariseing
or growing due to them in respect of the said severall Places and Employments in the said Universities Colledges
Halls Schools, Hospitalls or Almeshouses nor to Charge any of the Houses or Lands belonging to Christs Hospitall
or the Hospitalls of Saint Bartholomew Bridewell Saint Thomas and Bethlehem Hospitall within the City of London
and Burrough of Southwarke or any of them or to any Colledge or Hall in either of the Universities or to the
Colledges of Eaton Winchester or Westminster or to any Hospitall Almeshouse or Free Schoole whatsoever for or
in respect of any Rents or Revenues payable to the said Hospitalls being to be Received and Disbursed for the
immediate Use and Reliefe of the Poore in the said Hospitalls. Provided That noe Tenants of any Lands or Houses
by Lease or Grant from any of the said Hospitalls Colledges Halls Almeshouses or Free Schooles or the said
Corporation shall Claime or enjoy any Freedome or Exemption by this Act but that all the Houses and Lands
which they soe hold shall be Rated for soe much as they are yearely worth over and above the Rents reserved
and payable to the said Hospitalls Colledges Halls Almeshouses or Free-Schooles.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s149">
			<head>XXI. Persons dwelling in one Parish or Ward, and having Goods, &amp;c. in other Parishes or Wards, charged where they dwell.</head>
			<para id="p165">Provided alsoe That where any Person Inhabiting within the City of London or any other City or Towne
Corporate hath his Dwellinghouse in one of the Parishes and Wards therein and hath any Goods Wares or
Merchandices chargeable by this Act in one or more [of the other<ref idref="n176">176</ref>] Parishes or Wards in the same City That
then such Person shall be Charged Taxed and Assessed for such his Goods and Merchandices in the Parish or
Ward where he dwelleth and not elsewhere in the said City</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s150">
			<head>XXII. All Places to pay and be assessed in such County, &amp;c. as heretofore.</head>
			<para id="p166">Provided alwayes and bee it further Declared and Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That for [the<ref idref="n176">176</ref>] avoiding
all Obstructions and Delayes in Assessing and Collecting the Sums which by this Act are to be Rated and
Assessed all Places Constablewicks Divisions and Allotments which [have<ref idref="n176">176</ref>] used to be Rated and Assessed shall Pay
and be Assessed in such County Hundred Rape Wapentake Constablewicke Division Place and Allotment as the
same hath heretofore usually beene Assessed in and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s151">
			<head>XXIII. Lands and Houses lying unoccupied, and no Distress found, nor Owner found in the County;</head>
			<para id="p167">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to certify to Exchequer, &amp;c.; Such Certificate a sufficient Charge; Process thereupon out of Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p168">Provided alwayes and bee it further Enacted That in case any Lands or Houses in any Parish or Constablewicke
shall lye unoccupied and noe Distress can be found on the same nor the Person of the true Owner or
Proprietor can be found within the County wherein such House or Land lyeth by reason whereof the Rate and
Assessment upon such unoccupied [House<ref idref="n177">177</ref>] and Lands cannot be Levyed That then upon Complaint made thereof
to the Commissioners for the County where such Case shall happen to be the said Commissioners or any Two
or more of them shall Certifie into Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer the Name of the Person whose Lands
or House soe lyeth unoccupied together with the Summe thereupon Assessed and the Parish or Place where
such Land or House lyeth which Certificate is hereby declared to be a sufficient Charge upon the Person and
Land or House therein named and shall make the Person Debtor to Their Majesties for the Summe soe Assessed
and the Court of Exchequer shall issue out Processe thereupon against the Body Goods and all other the Lands
of such Debtor untill the Summe soe Assessed be fully and actually Levyed and Paid to Their Majestyes</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s152">
			<head>XXIV. At the Expiration of Time for Payment of Assessment, Commissioners to call before them the Collectors, &amp;c. to examine as to Payments.</head>
			<para id="p169">
				<emph type="i">In case of Failure, Commissioners to proceed forthwith</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p170">And it is hereby further Enacted and Declared That at the expiration of the respective Times in this Act
prescribed for the full payment of the severall and respective Rates and Assesments herein before granted the
severall and respective Commissioners or any Two or more of them within their Division and Hundred shall and
are hereby required to call before them the Chiefe Collectors and Sub Collectors within each respective Division
and Hundred to Examine and Assure themselves of the full and whole Payment of the particular Summe and
Summes of Money Charged within and upon the said Division and Hundred and every Parish and Place
therein and of the due Returne of the same into the Hands of the Receiver Generall of the said County City
Towne and Place respectively and by such Receiver Generall to the Receipt of Their Majesties Exchequer to
the end there may be noe failure in the Payment of any part of the Rates and Assessments which by this Act
ought to be Levyed and Paid And in case of any failure in the Premisses the Commissioners or any Two of
them are to cause the same forthwith to be Levyed and Paid according to the true intent and meaning of
this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s153">
			<head>XXV. Money may be lent to the Crown, on Security of Act, at &pound;7 per Cent. per Ann.</head>
			<para id="p171">Provided alwayes and it is hereby Enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any person and
persons to Advance and Lend unto Their Majestyes upon the Security of this Act any Summe or Summes of
Money and to have and receive for the Forbearance thereof after the Rate of Seven pounds by the Hundred
for One whole Yeare and noe more directly or indirectly And moreover that noe Money soe Lent upon the
Security of this Act or any other Act of this present Parliament shall be Rated or Assessed by vertue of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s154">
			<head>XXVI. Register to be kept in the Exchequer of Monies paid into Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p172">
				<emph type="i">Persons lending Money to have Tally of Loan, and Order containing Warrant for Payment of Interest at &pound;7 per Cent. per Ann. until Repayment of Principal.;
Such Orders to be registered to Date of Tally; and Persons paid in Course as Orders stand entered.;
Monies raised under Act liable in the same Order for such Repayment; and not to be divertible to any other Use.; No Fee for providing such Books, or making Entries, &amp;c. or for Payment of the Money so lent.; Penalty.; If undue Preference by Officer.; Penalty.; If by Deputy.; Penalty.; Auditor, &amp;c. or Deputy not directing Order and making Payment in Order as aforesaid.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p173">And to the end that all Moneys which shall be Lent unto Their Majesties upon the Credit of this Act may
be well and sufficiently Secured out of the Moneys ariseing and payable by this Act Bee it further Enacted by
the Authoritie aforesaid [Th<ref idref="n178">178</ref>] there shall be provided and kept in Their Majestyes Exchequer (that is to say) in
the Office of the Auditor of the Receipts one Booke or Register in which all Moneys that shall be paid into
the Exchequer by vertue of this Act shall be Entred and Registred apart and distinct from all other Moneys
paid or payable to Their Majestyes upon any other Branch of Their Majestyes Revenue or upon any other
Account whatsoever And that all and every Person and Persons who shall Lend any Money to Their Majestyes
upon the Credit of this Act and pay the same into the Receipt of the Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally.
of Loane strucke for the same and an Order for his Repayment beareing the same Date with his Tally in which
Order shall be alsoe contained a Warrant for Payment of Interest for Forbearance after the Rate of Seaven
pounds per Centum per Annu[m] for his Consideration to be paid every Three months untill Repayment of his
Principall And that all Orders for Repayment of Money shall be Registred in course according to the Date of
the Tally respectively without preference of one before another. And that all and every Person and Persons shall
be paid in course according as their Orders shall stand Entred in the said Register Booke soe as that the Person
Native or Forreigner his Executors Administrators and Assignes who shall have his Order or Orders first Entered
in the said Booke of Register shall be taken and accounted as the first Person to be paid upon the Moneys to
come in by vertue of this Act And he or they who shall have his or their Order or Orders next Entred
shall be taken and accounted to be the second Person to be paid and soe successively and in course And that
the Moneys to come in by this Act shall be in the same Order lyable to the Satisfaction of the said respective
Parties their Executors Administrators or Assignes successively without preference of one before another and not
otherwise and not to be divertible to any other Use Intent or Purpose whatsoever And that noe Fee Reward
or Gratuity directly or indirectly be demanded or taken of any Their Majestyes Subjects for provideing or makeing
of any such Bookes Registers Entryes View or Search in or for Payment of Money Lent or the Interest as aforesaid
by any of Their Majestyes Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputyes on paine of Payment of treble Damages
to the Partie grieved by the Partie offending with Costs of Suite Or if the Officer himselfe take or demand any
such Fee or Reward then to lose his Place alsoe And if any undue Preference of one before another shall be
made either in point of Registry or Payment contrary to the true meaneing of this Act by any such Officer or
Officers then the Partie offending shall be lyable by Action of Debt or on the Case to pay the Value of the
Debt Damages and Costs to the Partie grieved and shall be forejudged from his Place or Office and if such
Preference be unduely made by any his Deputie or Clerke without direction or privity of his Master Then such
Deputy or Clerke onely shall be lyable to such Action Debt Damages and Costs and shall be for ever after
uncapeable of his Place or Office And in case the Auditor shall not direct the Order or the Clerke of the Pells
Record or the Teller make Payment according to each persons due Place and Order as afore directed Then he
or they shall be judged to Forfeite and their respective Deputyes and Clerks herein Offending to be lyable to
such Action Debt Damages and Costs in such manner as aforesaid All which [said<ref idref="n179">179</ref>] Penalties Forfeitures Damages
and Costs to be Incurred by any of the Officers of the Exchequer or any their Deputies or Clerks shall and may
be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of Their Majestyes Courts (<ref idref="n180">180</ref>) at Westminster
wherein noe Essoigne Protection Priviledge Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise
granted or allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s155">
			<head>XXVII. What not interpreted undue Preference, where Tallies brought the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p174">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby declared That if it happen that severall Tallies of Loane or Orders for
Payment as aforesaid beare Date or be brought the same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be Registred
then it shall be Interpreted noe undue Preference which of those he Enters first soe he Enters them all the
same day.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s156">
			<head>XXVIII. The like Proviso upon Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, and Teller paying subsequent Orders when first demanded.</head>
			<para id="p175">Provided alsoe That it shall not be Interpreted any undue Preference to incurr any Penaltie in point of Payment
if the Auditor Direct and the Clerke of the Pells Record and the Teller doe Pay subsequent Orders of Persons that
come and demand their Money and bring their Order before other Persons that did not come to demand their
Money and bring their Order in their Course soe as there be soe much Money reserved as will satisfie precedent
Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them (Interest upon Loane being to cease from the
time the Money is soe reserved and kept in Bancke for them.)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s157">
			<head>XXIX. Proviso for Right of Persons having Money due to them to assign their Interest in order for Repayment.</head>
			<para id="p176">
				<emph type="i">Memorial of Assignment without Fee.; Assignee may assign.; Assignments not to be released, &amp;c. by Assignor</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p177">And bee it [further<ref idref="n179">179</ref>] Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That every person or persons to whome any Moneys
shall be due by vertue of this Act after Order Entered in the Booke of Register aforesaid for Payment thereof his
Executors Administrators or Assignes by Indorsement of his Order may Assigne and Transferr his Right Title
Interest and Benefitt of such Order or any part thereof to any other which being notifyed in the Office of the
Auditor of Receipt aforesaid and an Entry or Memoriall thereof alsoe made in the Booke of Register aforesaid
for Orders (which the Officers shall upon request without Fee or Charge accordingly make) shall Entitule such
Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the Benefit thereof and Payment thereon And such Assignee
may in like manner Assigne againe and soe toties quoties and afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person
or persons who have or hath made such Assignments to make Void Release or Discharge the same or any the
Moneys thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s158">
			<head>XXX. Where Action, &amp;c. commenced against Persons executing Act.</head>
			<para id="p178">
				<emph type="i">General Issue.; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p179">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any Action Suite Plaint or Information shall be
Commenced or Prosecuted against any person or persons for [whatsoever<ref idref="n181">181</ref>] he or they shall doe in Pursuance or in
Execution of this Act such person or persons soe Sued in any Court whatsoever shall and may pleade the
Generall Issue Not guilty and upon any Issue joyned may give this Act and the speciall Matter in Evidence and
if the Plaintiffe or Prosecutor shall become Nonsuite or forbeare further Prosecution or suffer Discontinuance or
if a Verdict passe against him the Defendants shall recover their treble Costs For which they shall have the
like Remedy as in Case where Costs by Law are given to the Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s159">
			<head>XXXI. Proviso for Houses of Ambassadors, Landlords, &amp;c. answerable.</head>
			<para id="p180">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That every Rate Tax or Assessment which shall be made or imposed by
vertue of this Act in respect of any House or Tenement which an Embassador Resident Agent or other publick
Minister of any Forreigne Prince or State now doth or shall hereafter Inhabite or Occupie shall be paid by the
Landlord or Owner of the said House or Tenements respectively</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s160">
			<head>XXXII. Proviso as to Extra-parochial and Privileged Places.</head>
			<para id="p181">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to appoint Assessors and Collectors.; Duty of such Collectors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p182">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That in all Priviledged and other Places being Extraparochiall
or not within any the Constablewicks or Precincts of the respective Assessors to be appointed by vertue of this
Act (although in any Monethly or other Tax they have not been Assessed or Rated heretofore) the said Commissioners
or any two or more of them shall and are hereby required to Nominate and Appoint two fitt Persons liveing in
or neere the said Priviledged or other Places as aforesaid to be Assessors for the said Places and to make and
returne their Assessments in like manner as by this Act is appointed in any Parish Tything or Place And alsoe
to appoint one or more Collectors who are hereby required to Collect and Pay the same according to the Rates
appointed by this Act for Collecting and Paying all Summes of Money payable by this Act</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s161">
			<head>XXXIII. Proviso for Contracts between Landlords and Tenants touching Payment of Taxes.</head>
			<para id="p183">Provided alwayes That nothing in this Act contained shall be Construed to alter change determine or make
void any Contracts Covenants or Agreements whatsoever betweene the Landlord and Tenant touching the payment
of Taxes or Assessments any thing herein before mentioned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s162">
			<head>XXXIV. Commissioners executing Act not liable to Penalties of 25 Car. II. c. 2.</head>
			<para id="p184">Provided alwayes and bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Commissioner or
Commissioners who shall be imployed in the Execution of this Act shall be lyable for or by reason of such
Execution to any of the Penaltyes mentioned in an Act made in the Five and twentyeth yeare of the Raignc of
King Charles the Second for the preventing of Dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s163">
			<head>XXXV. Commissioners to take the Oaths of c. 8. ante.</head>
			<para id="p185">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That noe person shall be capeable of Acting as a Commissioner in the
Execution of this Act before he shall have taken the Oathes appointed by an Act of this present Parlyament
Entituled An Act for Abrogateing of the Oathes of Supremacy and Allegiance and Appointing other Oathes (which
Oathes it shall be lawfull for any Two or more Commissioners to Administer and are hereby required to Administer
to any other Commissioners)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s164">
			<head>XXXVI. Papists of the Age of 17 and upwards, not having taken the Oath of c. 8. ante, to pay Double Rate.</head>
			<para id="p186">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Papists taking the said Oaths within Ten Days after First Meeting of Commissioners</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p187">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That every Papist or reputed Papist being of the Age
of Sixteene yeares or upwards who shall not have taken the Oathes mentioned and required to be taken by an
Act made in the last Session of this present Parlyament Entituled An Act for the Abrogating of the Oathes of
Supremacy and Allegiance and Appointing other Oathes shall Yeild and Pay unto Their Majestyes Double the
Summes and Rates which by force or vertue of any Clause in this Act before mentioned or contained he or
she [should or<ref idref="n182">182</ref>] ought to pay or be charged with (that is to say) for every hundred pounds of ready Money and
Debts and for every hundred pounds worth of Goods Wares Merchandices Chattells or personall Estate the
Summe of Fowre and twenty shillings and soe after that Rate for every greater or lesser quantity And for every
Twenty shillings of the full yearely value of any Mannours Messuages or other Hereditaments or Premisses charged
by this Act which he or she shall have or hold the Summe of Foure shillings to be Assessed Levyed and
Collected Answered Recovered and Paid in such manner by such wayes and meanes and according to such Rules
and Directions and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are before in this Act expressed or appointed for and
concerning the above mentioned Rates and Summes which are hereby intended to be doubled as aforesaid. Provided
neverthelesse That if any such Papist or reputed Papist within Ten dayes after the First Meeting of the said
Commissioners in the respective Counties or Places where he or she ought to be Taxed or Assessed according
to the intent of this present Act shall take the said Oathes before Two or more of the said Commissioners which
Oathes the said Commissioners are hereby impowered to Administer That in such Case he or she shall not be
lyable to be doubly Assessed as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s165">
			<head>XXXVII. Persons of and above the Age of 16, &amp;c. not having taken Oath of c. 8. ante, and being summoned by Commissioners, and not appearing;</head>
			<para id="p188">
				<emph type="i">Penalty, Double Rate</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p189">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That every Person being of the Age of Sixteene years
or upwards and being within this Realme at the time of the Execution of this Act who shall not before that
time have taken the said Oathes mentioned and required to be taken by the said Act Entituled An Act for the
Abrogating of the Oathes of Supremacy and Allegiance and Appointing other Oathes and upon Summons by
Warrant under the Hand and Seale of any One or more of the Commissioners appointed by this Act shall refuse
to take the said Oathes at the Time appointed in the said Warrant or shall neglect to appeare at such Time
before the Commissioners in order to take the said Oathes (which Oathes the said Commissioners or any Two
or more of them are hereby impowered and required to Administer) shall yield and pay unto Their Majestyes
double the Summes and Rates which by force or vertue of any Clause in this Act before mentioned or contained
he or she should or ought to pay or be charged with in manner as is before in this Act appointed touching
Papists or reputed Papists to be Assessed Levyed Collected Answered Recovered and Paid in such Manner by such
Wayes and Meanes and according to such Rules and Directions and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are
before in this Act expressed or appointed for and concerning the above mentioned Rates and Summes which are
hereby intended to be doubled as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s166">
			<head>XXXVIII. On Information on Suspicion, Commissioners to summon Persons to take the said Oaths.</head>
			<para id="p190">And bee it further Enacted That any one or more of the Commissioners appointed by this Act upon Information
given or upon any Cause of Suspition in that behalfe shall and are hereby required and enjoyned to cause every
Person suspected or against whome such Information shall be given to be summoned to appeare and take the said
Oathes as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s167">
			<head>XXXIX. Proviso for Quakers making, &amp;c. the Declaration of Fidelity of c. 18. ante.</head>
			<para id="p191">Provided neverthelesse That whereas certaine Persons Dissenters from the Church of England commonly called
Quakers and now knowne to be such doe scruple the takeing of any Oath It shall be sufficient for every such
Person to Make and Subscribe the Declaration of Fidelity contained in an Act made in the late Session of this present
Parlyament Intituled An Act for Exempting Their Majestyes Protestant Subjects dissenting from the Church of
England from the Penalties of certaine Lawes Which Declaration any two or more of the Commissioners appointed
for the Execution of this Act are hereby Impowered and Required to take And every such Person soe doeing
shall not be lyable to or chargeable with any of the Double Rates aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s168">
			<head>XL. Loans to the Crown between the 11th of Nov. and 21st of Dec. 1689, upon the Credit of c. 20. ante.</head>
			<para id="p192">
				<emph type="i">and all Orders for the same not exceeding &pound;300,000, and Interest, to be transferred, on Application of the Lenders, to the Register under this Act; and such Monies repaid, with Interest at &pound;7 per Cent. per Ann. out of Monies raised under this Act.; Auditor of Receipt to make Memorandums in the Margin of his Books accordingly.; Succeeding Orders to be paid in Course</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p193">And bee it further Enacted That all and every the Loanes which betweene the Eleaventh day of November
One thousand six hundred eighty and nine and the One and twentyeth day of December One thousand six
hundred eighty and nine have beene or shall have beene made by any Person or Persons Bodyes Pollitique or
Corporate into the Receipt of the Exchequer upon Credit of an Act made in the late Session of this present
Parlyament Entituled An Act for a Grant to Their Majestyes of an Ayd of Twelve pence in the Pound for One
Yeare for the necessary Defence of Their Realmes. And all and every or any of the Orders for the same Loanes
or any of them not exceeding Three hundred thousand pounds in the whole and the Interest thereof shall by
Vertue and Authoritie of this present Act at the instance or instances of the Lenders thereof his her or their
Executors Administrators or Assignes to be made to the Auditor of the Receipt of the said Exchequer be
transferred to the Register appointed to be kept by this present Act and be Registred therupon And the Moneys
soe lent and which are or shall be contained in such transferred Orders with the Interest after the rate of Seaven
pounds per Centum per Annum shall be payable and paid to the Lenders of the same his her or their Executors
Administrators or Assignes out of the Moneys ariseing by Vertue of this Act as fully and effectually as if such
Loanes had beene Originally made upon the Credit of this present Act and as if such transferred Orders were
Originally Registred upon the Register by these Presents appointed to be kept And that the Auditor of the said
Receipt upon the transferring of the said Loanes or the Orders for the same as aforesaid shall make Memorandums
in the Margin of his Bookes where the same doe or shall stand Entered or Registred upon the said Act for
the Grant of the said Twelve pence in the Pound importing the Tranferrence thereof and that they are to be paid
out of the Moneys ariseing by Vertue of this Act And any succeeding Orders which shall or may be or remaine
upon the said Register for the Twelve pence in the Pound (if any such shall be) shall be payable and paid in
course out of the Moneys ariseing by the said Act for the Grant of the said Twelve pence in the Pound in such
order and manner as if the transferred Loanes or Orders had never beene Registred thereupon Any thing in this
present Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s169">
			<head>XLJ. Fees to Officers of Exchequer for Monies issued to the Army out of Monies of this Act.</head>
			<para id="p194">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Officers of the Receipt of Their
Majestyes Exchequer shall and may receive and take for their Fees Three farthings in the Pound and noe more
for all or any the Sum[m]e or Summes of Money to be Issued or Paid to any Their Majestyes Garrisons or other
Land Forces out of the Money ariseing by this present Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s170">
			<head>XLII. Proviso for certain Goods on Shipboard, and detained for want of Convoy.</head>
			<para id="p195">Provided alwayes and bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Goods and Merchandize
which on or before the Three and twentyeth day of October One thousand six hundred eighty nine were on
Board any English Shipp or Vessell Outward bound in the River of Thames or any other Port in Their Majestyes
Dominions haveing paid their Customes and shall be detained for want of Convoyes untill the Tenth day of March
next ensueing shall be exempted out of this Tax.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s171">
			<head>XLIII. Proviso for Lands under the yearly Value of 20s.</head>
			<para id="p196">Provided That noe poore Person shall be charged with or lyable to the Pound Rate Imposed by this Act upon
Lands Tenements or Hereditaments whose Lands Tenements or Hereditaments are not of the yearely Value of
Twenty shillings in the whole.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s172">
			<head>XLIV. Officers of the Court of Chancery, executing their Offices within the Liberty of the Rolls, to be assessed there.</head>
			<para id="p197">Provided alwayes That the Right Honourable the Master of the Rolls the Masters of Chauncery Six Clerks
Clerkes of the Petty Bagg Examiners Registers Clerks of the Enrollment Clerkes of the Affidavitts and Subpena
Office and all others the Officers of the Court of Chauncery that Execute their Offices within the Liberty of the
Rolls shall be there Assessed for their respective Offices and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s173">
			<head>XLV.</head>
			<para id="p198">
				<emph type="i">After all the aforesaid Allowances and Repayments,; &pound;400,000, Part of the Monies to be raised by this Act, to be applied to the Service of the Navy</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p199">And to the intent that the Summe of Foure hundred thousand pounds part of the Moneys to be raised by
vertue of this Act may be certainly applyed to the speedy Payment of Seamen in Their Majestyes Navy Royall
and to the Paying for necessary Stores Provisions and Victualls supplyed and to be supplyed for Their Majestyes,
Navy Royall Bee it Enacted That out of the First Money which shall be Leavyed and Paid by vertue of this
Act into the Receipt of the Exchequer as well upon Loane as otherwise (Except the Allowances herein made to
the respective Collectors Clerks Receivers Generall and Officers of the Exchequer and what shall be Issued thence
for the Repayments of Loanes made betweene the Eleaventh day of November One thousand six hundred eighty
and nine and the Twenty first day of December One thousand six hundred eightie and nine upon the Credit of
an Act made in the late Session of this present Parlyament Entituled An Act for a Grant of Twelve pence in
the Pound for One Yeare for the necessary Defence of Their Realms and which shall be Transferred to the
Register appointed to be kept by this present Act in such manner as is herein before appointed) the Summe of
Foure hundred thousand pounds shall be applyed and appropriated [and is hereby appropriated<ref idref="n183">183</ref>] to and for the
speedy Payment of Seamen in Their Majestyes Navy Royall and to and for the Paying for necessary Stores
Provisions and Victualls supplyed and to be supplyed for Their Majestyes Navy Royall (That is to say) Two
hundred thousand pounds part thereof for the speedy Payment of Seamen One hundred thousand pounds part
thereof for the Paying for Victualls supplyed and to be supplyed for the said Navy And One hundred thousand
pounds the residue thereof for and towards the Paying for other necessary Provisions and Stores supplyed and to
be supplyed for the said Navy Royall and for the Wages of the Yards</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s174">
			<head>XLVI. Collectors of Parishes, &amp;c. keeping Monies collected in their Hands unduly, or unduly paying away the same;</head>
			<para id="p200">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5.; Head Collectors in like Manner offending; Penalty &pound;20. Receiver General or Deputy unduly paying Monies received under this Act; Penalty &pound;500</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p201">And for the more effectuall doeing thereof and that the said Summe of Foure hundred thousand pounds
hereby appropriated to the Uses aforesaid may not be diverted or applyed to any other Purpose and alsoe to the
Intent that all the Moneys given by this Act may be duly paid into Their Majestyes Exchequer. Bee it further
Enacted That if any Collector of any Parish or Place shall keepe in his hands any part of the Money by him
Collected for any longer time then is by this Act directed (other then the Allowance made unto him by this Act)
or shall pay any part thereof to any Person or persons other then the Head-Collector or Receiver Generall of
such County or Place or his respective Deputie That every such Collector shall forfeit for every such Offence
the Summe of Five pounds And in case any Head Collector shall keepe in his hands any part of the Money
paid to him by any Collector by vertue of this Act for any longer time then is by this Act directed (other then
the Allowance made to him by this Act) or shall pay any part thereof to any person or persons other then the
Receiver Generall of such County or Place or his Deputy every such Head Collector shall forfeite for every such
Offence the Summe of Twenty Pounds And in case any Receiver Generall or his Deputy shall pay any part of
the Moneys paid to him or them by any Collector or Head Collector by vertue of this Act to any person or
persons whatsoever (other then the Receipt of Their Majestyes Exchequer and that or within the respective times
Limitted by this Act) or in case such Receiver Generall or his Deputy shall pay any part of the said Moneys
by any Warrant of the Commissioners of the Treasury or the Lord Treasurer Under Treasurer or Commissioners
of the Treasury for the time being or upon any Tally of Pro or Tally of Anticipation or other Way or Device
whatsoever whereby to divert or hinder the Actuall Payment thereof into the Receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid
That then such Receiver Generall shall for every such Offence of himselfe or his Deputy forfeit the Summe of
Five hundred pounds to him or them that shall Sue for the same in any Court of Record by Bill Plaint or other
Information wherein noe Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law is to be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s175">
			<head>XLVII. Treasury not to direct any Warrant to Collectors or Receivers General for Payment of Monies hereby given, to any Person, other than into Receipt of Exchequer; nor direct any Warrant for striking of any Tally of Pro, or Tally of Anticipation. Teller not to throw down any Bill, &amp;c. till he shall have received Money.</head>
			<para id="p202">And it is hereby further Enacted That the Commissioners of the Treasury or the Lord Treasurer Under
Treasurer or Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being or any of them doe not direct any Warrant to
any of the said Collectors Head Collectors or Receivers Generall or their Deputies for the payment of any part
of the Moneys hereby given to any person or persons other then into the Receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid
nor shall they or any of them direct any Warrant to the Officers of the Exchequer for the Strikeing of any
Tally of Pro or Tally of Anticipation nor doe any other Matter or Thing whereby to divert the actuall payment
of the said Moneys into the Receipt of the Exchequer Nor shall the Officers of the Exchequer Strike or Direct
or Record the Strikeing of any Talley of Pro or Talley of Anticipation upon any of the said Moneys upon any
Account or Warrant whatsoever Nor shall any Teller throw downe any Bill whereby to charge himselfe with
any of the said Moneys until he shall have actually Received the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s176">
			<head>XLVIII. Regulations as to Officers of Exchequer keeping distinct the Accounts respecting the said Sum of &pound;400,000, and as to Treasury signing Warrants, &amp;c. for issuing any Part of the said Sum.</head>
			<para id="p203">
				<emph type="i">Auditor of Receipt not to draw Order for issuing any Part of the said Sum to any other than Treasury of the Navy or his Deputy; nor direct, nor Clerk of the Pells or Teller make, Payment of such Money otherwise than as mentioned in the Warrant</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p204">And it is hereby further Enacted That the Officers of the Receipt of Their Majestyes Exchequer shall keepe
the said Summe of Foure hundred thousand pounds hereby appropriated and the Account thereof distinct from
all other Moneys and Accounts whatsoever And that the Commissioners of the Treasury or the Lord Treasurer
Under Treasurer or Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being doe not Signe any Warrant or Order or doe
any other matter or thing for the Issueing of any part of the said Summe of Foure hundred thousand pounds
hereby appropriated as aforesaid to any Person or Persons other then the Treasurer of the Navy or his Deputy for
the time being and Expressing therein That the same is for the Payment of Seamen and for the Paying for the
Victualls Provisions and Stores Supplyed and to be Supplyed for the Navy respectively as aforesaid Nor shall the
Auditor of the Receipt draw any Order for the Issueing any part of the said Summe of Foure hundred thousand
pounds hereby appropriated to any Person or Persons other then the Treasurer of the Navy or his Deputy as
aforesaid Nor shall he direct or the Clerke of the Pells Record or any Teller make Payment of any of the said
Moneys by vertue of any Warrant or upon any Order or other Way or Device whatsoever other then to the
Persons and for the Uses aforesaid and to be soe mentioned and expressed in such Warrant or Order.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s177">
			<head>XLIX. Treasurer of Navy to keep such &pound;400,000 distinct from other Monies, and issue and pay the same by Warrant of Principal Officers, &amp;c. of the Navy.</head>
			<para id="p205">And it is hereby further Enacted That the Treasurer of the Navy for the time being shall keepe the said Summe
of Foure hundred thousand pounds appropriated as aforesaid by vertue of this Act as the same shall be paid in to
him distinct and apart from all other Moneys and shall Issue and Pay the same by Warrant of the Principall
Officers and Commissioners of the Navy or any Three or more of them and mentioning and expressing That the
same is for the Respective Uses for which the same is appropriated as aforesaid and for noe other Use Intent or
Purpose whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s178">
			<head>L. Commissioners, &amp;c. of the Navy not to issue Warrant or Navy Bill for any other Purpose than as Money is appropriated, and the Uses to be expressed in such Warrant or Navy Bill.</head>
			<para id="p206">And it is hereby further Enacted That the Principall Officers and Commissioners of the Navy or any of them
shall not Signe any Warrant or Navy-Bill or doe any other Act or Thing for the Issuing and Paying any part
of the said Summe of Foure hundred thousand pounds soe appropriated by this Act to any Use Intent or Purpose
whatsoever other then for the respective Uses for which the same is appropriated as aforesaid and to be soe mentioned
and expressed in such Warrant or Navy-Bill.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s179">
			<head>LI. Officers appointed to receive, misapplying the said &pound;400,000, or any Part;</head>
			<para id="p207">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p208">And it is further Enacted That if any of the Officers which are appointed by this Act to Receive the said Summe
of Foure hundred thousand pounds hereby appropriated or any part thereof shall after the Receipt of the said
Money divert or misapply the same or any part thereof by vertue of any Warrant from the Commissioners of the
Treasury or from the Lord Treasurer or other Superior Officers for the time being contrary to the true intent of
this. Act That then such Officer or Officers soe diverting or misapplying the said Money shall Forfeite the like Summe
soe diverted or misapplyed Which said Forfeiture shall be Recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information
in any of Their Majestyes Courts of Records at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law
shall be allowed the one Moyety of which Forfeiture soe to be Recovered shall be to the Informer or him who
shall Sue for the same the other Moyety thereof to be distributed to the Poore of the Parish where such Offence
shall be committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s180">
			<head>LII. The like Offence by any Officer of the Exchequer or Navy;</head>
			<para id="p209">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p210">And bee it further Enacted That if any [Officer<ref idref="n184">184</ref>] or Officers mentioned in this Act or in any wise belonging to
the Exchequer or Navy shall willingly and wilfully offend against this Law or any Clause thereof by diverting or
misapplying any part of the said Summe of Foure hundred thousand Pounds appropriated as aforesaid contrary to
the true intent of this Act that for any and every such Offence such Officer and Officers soe Offending shall forfeite
his Office and Place and is and are hereby disabled and made uncapeable to Hold or Execute the said Office or
any other Office whatsoever for the future.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s181">
			<head>LIII. No Stay of Prosecution admitted in any Suit for Recovery of Penalties.</head>
			<para id="p211">Provided alsoe and bee it Enacted That noe Stay of Prosecution upon any Command Warrant Motion or
Order or Direction by Non vult ulterius Prosequi shall be Had Made Admitted Received or Allowed by any Court
whatsoever in any Suite or Proceeding by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information or otherwise for the Recovery
of all or any the Paines Penalties or Forfeitures upon any person or persons by this Act inflicted or therein
mentioned or for or in Order to the Conviction or Disability of any person Offending against this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s182">
			<head>LIV. Commissioners appointed to execute Act, to examine upon Oath and receive the Assessments made in pursuance of Act Sess. I. c. 20. and if they find any Person assessed at a lower Rate than directed by the said Act, to cause such Deficiency to be raised.</head>
			<para id="p212">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That the Commissioners appointed to putt this Act in Execution shall and
are hereby impowered and required within their respective Counties Divisions Cityes and Places to Examine upon
Oath and [Receive<ref idref="n185">185</ref>] the severall Assessments of each Parish and Place made in pursuance of the late Act Entituled
An Act for a Grant to Their Majestyes of Twelve pence in the Pound for One Yeare for the necessary Defence
of Their Realms And where they shall finde any Person or Place Assessed at a lower Rate or lesser Summe then
was directed by the said Act to cause the Summe so ommitted to be raised and paid to Their Majestyes in such
manner and by such wayes and Meanes and under such Paines and Penalties as are herein before Provided and
Directed for the Assessing and Levying the Summes chargeable by this present Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s183">
			<head>LV. An Account to be rendered to the Commons of Monies raised under this Act.</head>
			<para id="p213">And it is hereby further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That an Accompt shall be given and made unto
the Commons in Parlyament Assembled of and for all and every Summe and Summes of Money whatsoever that
shall be Collected Levyed and Paid to the Use of Their Majestyes by Vertue of this present Act of Parlyament.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Hell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">of Grange <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Thomas Whitley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Fowell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Rolle <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Burthogg <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Tucker <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Palatine <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Forester of Cornehill Esquire William <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Strother <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">Robert <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">Hesletine <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">Arthur Viscount Irwin of the Kingdome of Scotland <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">Tanckred <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">Brookes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">Gobert <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">Coe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">Darcy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">Baron <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">Worcester <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">Jonathan <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">Foley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">Pansfoot <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">Scudamore <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">Rawden <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">Toke <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">Cripps <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">Boyse <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">Hing <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">Bayliff <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">Major Nellir <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">Knowler <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39">Garling <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n42" number="42">Townly <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n43" number="43">Birley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n44" number="44">Alderman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n45" number="45">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n46" number="46">Billers <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n47" number="47">Rothwell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n48" number="48">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n49" number="49">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits</note>
			<note id="n50" number="50">Purley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n51" number="51">Collison <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n52" number="52">Gosright <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n53" number="53">John <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n54" number="54">Ventris <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n55" number="55">Inn <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n56" number="56">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n57" number="57">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n58" number="58">Wildy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n59" number="59">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n60" number="60">William <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n61" number="61">Dethick <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n62" number="62">Bonyton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n63" number="63">Guydott <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n64" number="64">Row <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n65" number="65">Dionisius <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n66" number="66">Feilding <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n67" number="67">William <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n68" number="68">Pettus <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n69" number="69">Bransby <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n70" number="70">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n71" number="71">Jermy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n72" number="72">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n73" number="73">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n74" number="74">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n75" number="75">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n76" number="76">Warmington <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n77" number="77">Loddington <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n78" number="78">Woodhall <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n79" number="79">Woodhull <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n80" number="80">Knighton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n81" number="81">Sir Francis Lyddell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n82" number="82">Mitford <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n83" number="83">Shafto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n84" number="84">Parkyns <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n85" number="85">Eperaton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n86" number="86">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n87" number="87">Pinckney <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n88" number="88">Gentleman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n89" number="89">Careltonstone <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n90" number="90">Brigham <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n91" number="91">Eyans <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n92" number="92">Winlow <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n93" number="93">Palmes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n94" number="94">Mackworth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n95" number="95">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n96" number="96">Herbert <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n97" number="97">Baldwin <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n98" number="98">Otteley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n99" number="99">Hanmer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n100" number="100">John <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n101" number="101">Ridly <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n102" number="102">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n103" number="103">Baber <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n104" number="104">Launsdawne <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n105" number="105">Esq[uire]s <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n106" number="106">Fitzharding <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n107" number="107">Hoo <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n108" number="108">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n109" number="109">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n110" number="110">Burnes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n111" number="111">Gyle <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n112" number="112">Ptolemy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n113" number="113">Naunton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n114" number="114">Maltiward <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n115" number="115">Leman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n116" number="116">John Brand <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n117" number="117">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n118" number="118">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n119" number="119">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n120" number="120">Peyton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n121" number="121">Prime <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n122" number="122">Delanoy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n123" number="123">Peter <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n124" number="124">Peckham <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n125" number="125">Garroway <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n126" number="126">Mayors <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n127" number="127">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n128" number="128">Seabright Repington <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n129" number="129">Beaufoy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n130" number="130">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n131" number="131">Braithwaite <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n132" number="132">Coles <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n133" number="133">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n134" number="134">interlined on the Record.</note>
			<note id="n135" number="135">Owen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n136" number="136">Bussey <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n137" number="137">William <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n138" number="138">Wogan <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n139" number="139">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n140" number="140">Baronet <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n141" number="141">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n142" number="142">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n143" number="143">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n144" number="144">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n145" number="145">Garthmelio <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n146" number="146">Robert <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n147" number="147">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n148" number="148">Calep <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n149" number="149">Keighton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n150" number="150">Rocke <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n151" number="151">Dervereux <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n152" number="152">Kynaston <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n153" number="153">Meredith <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n154" number="154">Kumley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n155" number="155">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n156" number="156">Kenhinva <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n157" number="157">Cassells <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n158" number="158">Howells <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n159" number="159">Bowen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n160" number="160">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n161" number="161">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n162" number="162">soe thereof <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n163" number="163">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n164" number="164">produced <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n165" number="165">Exchequer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n166" number="166">neglect <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n167" number="167">Generalls <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n168" number="168">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n169" number="169">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n170" number="170">required and authorized <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n171" number="171">further <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n172" number="172">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n173" number="173">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n174" number="174">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n175" number="175">Rents <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n176" number="176">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n177" number="177">Houses <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n178" number="178">that <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n179" number="179">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n180" number="180">of Record <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n181" number="181">what <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n182" number="182">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n183" number="183">interlined on the Record.</note>
			<note id="n184" number="184">Office <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n185" number="185">reveiwe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


