<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46328" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for preventing vexatious Suits against such as acted in order to the bringing in their Majestyes or for their Service. [Chapter VIII. Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Prosecutions against any Persons for having done any thing in bringing in their Majesties, void;
Defendant may plead General Issue, and recover Double Costs</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS about the time of his Majestyes glorious Enterprize for delivering this Kingdome from Popery and
Arbitrary Power and in aid and pursuance of the same diverse Lords Gentlemen and other good People well
affected to their Country did act as Lieutenants Deputy Lieutenants Justices of the Peace or other Officers Civill or
Military though not sufficiently authorized thereunto and did apprehend and putt into Custodie severall criminous and
suspected persons and did seize and use diverse Horses Arms and other things and did enter into the Houses and
Possessions of severall persons and did quarter and cause to be quartered Soldiers and others there In which
Proceedings some Force and Violence and defect of Forme was unavoidable which in a time of Peace and Common
Safety would not have beene warrantable, And alsoe since their Majesties happy Accession to the Crowne by reason
of the Warrs and Troubles raised and occasioned by the [Enimies<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of their Majestyes and this Kingdome diverse
like Matters and Things have beene acted and done all which were necessary and allowable in reguard of the exigence
of publique Affaires and ought to be justifyed and the parties [concerned<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] therein indemnified Neverthelesse some
persons ill affected to their Majesties Government and the Safety and Welfare of this Kingdome have commenced and
prosecuted and threaten to commence and prosecute Actions and Suits against their Majesties good Subjects for and by
reason of their Actings and Doeings aforesaid Therefore for the preventing the Trouble and Charges which the said
good Subjects might be putt to by the means of such vexatious Suites Bee it enacted by the King and Queens most
excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this
present Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That all personall Actions Suites Molestations and
Prosecutions whatsoever and Judgements had thereupon if any be for or by reason of any of the Premisses or any
Matter or Thing advised commanded appointed happened or done in order to the bringing in their Majesties to this
Kingdome or for their Service or for the Safety of the Government be and are hereby discharged and made void
And if any Action or Suite hereby declared or intended to be discharged shall be commenced or prosecuted every person
soe sued may pleade the Generall Issue and give this Act and the Speciall Matter in Evidence And if the Plaintiffe shall
become Nonsuite or forbeare further Prosecution or suffer Discontinuance or if a Verdict passe against him the said
Defendant shall recover his double Costs for which he shall have the like Remedy as in Case where Costs by Law
are given to Defendants.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">Enemyes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>

