<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46323" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for preventing all Doubts and Questions concerning the Collecting the Publique Revenue [Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Arrears of Subsidy and Duties, (Exception) to be collected and paid until 25th Dec. 1690, as herein mentioned.</head>
		<para id="p1">For the preventing all Disputes and Questions concerning the Collecting Levying and Answering the Publique
Revenue due and payable in the Raignes of the late Kings Charles the Second and James the Second whilst
the better Setleing the same is under the Consideration of this present Parlyament Bee it enacted by the King and
Queens most Excellent Majestyes by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
Commons in this present Parliament Assembled and by Authoritie of the same That the Subsidie of Tonnage and
Poundage and other Summes of Money payable upon Merchandize Exported and Imported and the severall Impositions
Duties and Charges upon Liquors Manufactures and other things And all and singular the Revenue and Revenues
whatsoever (Except the Duties ariseing by Fire Hearths and Stoves other then such as were incurred at or before
the Five and twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred eighty nine) Given, Granted and Payable to or
Lawfully Enjoyed by the said late Kings or either of Them which Remained and had Continuance on the Fifth
Day of November One thousand six hundred eighty eight And all Arreares of the same shall be Raised Levyed
Collected Answered and Paid to Their Majestyes untill the Twenty fifth day of December which shall be in the
yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and ninety in the same manner and forme according to such Rates
and Orders and by such Rules Meanes and Wayes and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are mentioned
expressed and appointed in the Statutes made in the Raignes of the said late Kings or either of them concerning
the same respectively and as by Law the same might or ought to have beene dureing the said Raignes.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Former Acts for collecting, &amp;c. the Public Revenue, to be in force until the said 25th Dec. 1690;</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">and also an Order of the Commons made in pursuance of the Rules and Orders annexed to Stat. 12 Car. II. c. 4</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">And that all and singular Acts of Parlyament made dureing the Reigns of either [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the said late Kings for
the Granting Setleing Raising Levying Collecting Answering and Paying the same or for p[re]venting Fraudes or
Concealments or regulateing Abuses therein or for the better Ordering or Recovering the same And all Powers
Provisions Penalties Articles Clauses and things contained in the said Acts or any of them be and are hereby
Continued and Confirmed and shall stand and be in force and be Applyed Practiced Executed and putt in Ure
for the Raising Levying Collecting Paying and Answering and said Subsidie Summes of Money Impositions Duties
and Revenues to Their Majestyes according to the Tenor and Intent of this present Act And alsoe that an Order
of the Commons in Parlyament Assembled made in pursuance of the Rules and Orders annexed to the Act of
Parlyament made in the Twelfth yeare of the Raigne of the late King Charles the Second Entituled A Subsidie
Granted to the King of Tonnage and Poundage and other Summes of Money payable upon Merchandize Exported
and Imported for Setleing of Officers Fees Dated the Seventeenth day of May One thousand six hundred sixty
two and Signed by Sir Edward Turner then Speaker shall be of full Force and Effect untill the said Five and
twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred and ninety as if the same were particularly and at large
recited in this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Letters Patent of the 20th Feb. 2 Jac. II. to Trustees for the Prince and Princess Anne of Denmark.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That nothing in this Act contained shall extend or be construed in any
way to extend to the Confirming or Invalidating certaine Letters Patents bearing Date the Twentyeth day of
February in the Second Yeare of the Raigne of the late King James the Second and Granted by the [said<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] late
King Jame the Second to the Right Honourable Henry Earle of Clarendon Lawrence Earle of Rochester and others
in Trust for their Royall Hignesses the Prince and Princesse Anne of Denmarke containing a Grant of the
yearely Summe of Thirty thousand pounds issueing out of certaine Revenues therein mentioned But that the same
shall be continue and remaine in as full Force and in the same State and Condition as they were before the
makeing of this Act and noe other Any thing herein to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Continuance of this Act.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted by the Authoritye aforesaid That this Act shall continue in Force from
the Fower and twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred eighty nine for One whole Yeare and
noe longer.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


