<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46322" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act declareing the Rights and Liberties of the Subject and Setleing the Succession of the Crowne. [Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">WHEREAS the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Com[m]ons assembled at Westminster lawfully fully and
freely representing all the Estates of the People of this Realme did upon the thirteenth day of February
in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred eighty eight present unto their Majesties then called and
known by the Names and Stile of William and Mary Prince and Princesse of Orange being present in their
proper Persons a certaine Declaration in Writeing made by the said Lords and Com[m]ons in the Words following viz</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">The Heads of Declaration of Lords and Commons, recited.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p3">Whereas the late King James the Second by the Assistance of diverse evill Councellors Judges and Ministers
imployed by him did endeavour to subvert and extirpate the Protestant Religion and the Lawes and Liberties
of this Kingdome</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Dispensing and Suspending Power.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p5">By Assumeing and Exerciseing a Power of Dispensing with and Suspending of Lawes and the Execution of
Lawes without Consent of Parlyament.</para>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">Committing Prelates.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p7">By Committing and Prosecuting diverse Worthy Prelates for humbly Petitioning to be excused from Concurring
to the said Assumed Power.</para>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">Ecclesiastical Commission.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p9">By issueing and causeing to be executed a Commission under the Great Seale for Erecting a Court called The
Court of Commissioners for Ecclesiasticall Causes.</para>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">Levying Money.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p11">By Levying Money for and to the Use of the Crowne by p[re]tence of Prerogative for other time and in other
manner then the same was granted by Parlyament.</para>
		<para id="p12">
			<emph type="i">Standing Army.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p13">By raising and keeping a Standing Army within this Kingdome in time of Peace without Consent of Parlyament
and Quartering Soldiers contrary to Law.</para>
		<para id="p14">
			<emph type="i">Disarming Protestants, &amp;c.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p15">By causing severall good Subjects being Protestants to be disarmed at the same time when Papists were both
Armed and Imployed contrary to Law.</para>
		<para id="p16">
			<emph type="i">Violating Elections.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p17">By Violating the Freedome of Election of Members to serve in Parlyament.</para>
		<para id="p18">
			<emph type="i">Illegal Prosecutions.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p19">By Prosecutions in the Court of Kings Bench for Matters and Causes congizable onely in Parlyament and by
diverse other Arbitrary and Illegall Courses.</para>
		<para id="p20">
			<emph type="i">Juries.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p21">And whereas of late yeares Partiall Corrupt and Unqualifyed Persons have beene returned and served on Juryes
in Tryalls and particularly diverse Jurors in Tryalls for High Treason which were not Freeholders,</para>
		<para id="p22">
			<emph type="i">Excessive Bail.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p23">And excessive Baile hath beene required of Persons committed in Criminall Cases to elude the Benefitt of the
Lawes made for the Liberty of the Subjects.</para>
		<para id="p24">
			<emph type="i">Fines.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p25">And excessive Fines have beene imposed.</para>
		<para id="p26">
			<emph type="i">Punishments.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p27">And illegall and cruell Punishments inflicted.</para>
		<para id="p28">
			<emph type="i">Grants of Fines, &amp;c. before Conviction, &amp;c.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p29">And severall Grants and Promises made of Fines and Forfeitures before any Conviction or Judgement against
the Persons upon whome the same were to be levyed.</para>
		<para id="p30">All which are utterly and directly contrary to the knowne Lawes and Statutes and Freedome of this Realme.</para>
		<para id="p31">
			<emph type="i">Recital that the late King James II. had abdicated the Government, and that the Throne was vacant, and that the Prince of Orange had written Letters to the Lords and Commons for the choosing Representatives in Parliament.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p32">And whereas the said late King James the Second haveing Abdicated the Government and the Throne being thereby
Vacant His [Hignesse<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the Prince of Orange (whome it hath pleased Almighty God to make the glorious Instrument of
Delivering this Kingdome from Popery and Arbitrary Power) did (by the Advice of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall
and diverse principall Persons of the Commons) cause Letters to be written to the Lords Spirituall and Temporall
being Protestants and other Letters to the severall Countyes Cityes Universities Burroughs and Cinque Ports for
the Choosing of such Persons to represent them as were of right to be sent to Parlyament to meete and sitt at
Westminster upon the two and twentyeth day of January in this Yeare one thousand six hundred eighty and eight
in order to such an Establishment as that their Religion Lawes and Liberties might not againe be in danger of
being Subverted, Upon which Letters Elections haveing beene accordingly made.</para>
		<para id="p33">
			<emph type="i">The Subject's Rights.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p34">And thereupon the said Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons pursuant to their respective Letters and
Elections being now assembled in a full and free Representative of this Nation takeing into their most serious
Consideration the best meanes for attaining the Ends aforesaid Doe in the first place (as their Auncestors in like
Case have usually done) for the Vindicating and Asserting their auntient Rights and Liberties, Declare</para>
		<para id="p35">
			<emph type="i">Dispensing Power.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p36">That the pretended Power of Suspending of Laws or the Execution of Laws by Regall Authority without
Consent of Parlyament is illegall.</para>
		<para id="p37">
			<emph type="i">Late dispensing Power.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p38">That the pretended Power of Suspending of Laws or the Execution of Laws by Regall Authority as it hath
beene assumed and exercised of late is illegall.</para>
		<para id="p39">
			<emph type="i">Ecclesiastical Courts illegal.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p40">That the Commission for erecting the late Court of Commissioners for Ecclesiasticall Causes and all other Commissions
and Courts of like nature are Illegall and Pernicious.</para>
		<para id="p41">
			<emph type="i">Levying Money.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p42">That levying Money for or to the Use of the Crowne by p[re]tence of Prerogative without Grant of Parlyament
for longer time or in other manner then the same is or shall be granted is Illegall.</para>
		<para id="p43">
			<emph type="i">Right to petition.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p44">That it is the Right of the Subjects to petition the King and all Commitments and Prosecutions for such
Petitioning are Illegall.</para>
		<para id="p45">
			<emph type="i">Standing Army.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p46">That the raising or keeping a standing Army within the Kingdome in time of Peace unlesse it be with Consent
of Parlyament is against Law.</para>
		<para id="p47">
			<emph type="i">Subjects' Arms.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p48">That the Subjects which are Protestants may have Arms for their Defence suitable to their Conditions and as
allowed by Law.</para>
		<para id="p49">
			<emph type="i">Freedom of Election.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p50">That Election of Members of Parlyament ought to be free.</para>
		<para id="p51">
			<emph type="i">Freedom of Speech.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p52">That the Freedome of Speech and Debates or Proceedings in Parlyament ought not to be impeached or questioned
in any Court or Place out of Parlyament.</para>
		<para id="p53">
			<emph type="i">Excessive Bail.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p54">That excessive Baile ought not to be required nor excessive Fines imposed nor cruell and unusuall Punishments
inflicted.</para>
		<para id="p55">
			<emph type="i">Juries.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p56">That Jurors ought to be duely impannelled and returned and Jurors which passe upon Men in Trialls for High
Treason ought to be Freeholders.</para>
		<para id="p57">
			<emph type="i">Grants of Forfeitures.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p58">That all Grants and Promises of Fines and Forfeitures of particular persons before Conviction are illegall
and void.</para>
		<para id="p59">
			<emph type="i">Frequent Parliaments.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p60">And that for Redresse of all Grievances and for the amending strengthening and preserveing of the Lawes
Parlyaments ought to be held frequently.</para>
		<para id="p61">
			<emph type="i">The said Rights claimed; Tender of the Crown; Regal Power exercised; Limitation of the Crown; New Oaths of Allegiance, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p62">And they doe Claime Demand and Insist upon all and singular the Premises as their undoubted Rights and
Liberties and that noe Declarations Judgements Doeings or Proceedings to the Prejudice of the People in any of
the said Premisses ought in any wise to be drawne hereafter into Consequence or Example. To which Demand
of their Rights they are particularly encouraged by the Declaration of his Highnesse the Prince of Orange as
being the onely meanes for obtaining a full Redresse and Remedy therein. Haveing therefore an intire Confidence
That his said Highnesse the Prince of Orange will perfect the Deliverance soe farr advanced by him and will still
preserve them from the Violation of their Rights which they have here asserted and from all other Attempts upon
their Religion Rights and Liberties. The said Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons assembled at Westminster
doe Resolve That William and Mary Prince and Princesse of Orange be and be declared King and Queene of
England France and Ireland and the Dominions thereunto belonging to hold the Crowne and Royall Dignity
of the said Kingdomes and Dominions to them the said Prince and Princesse dureing their Lives and the Life of
the Survivour of them And that the sole and full Exercise of the Regall Power be onely in and executed by
the said Prince of Orange in the Names of the said Prince and Princesse dureing their joynt Lives And after
their Deceases the said Crowne and Royall Dignitie of the said Kingdoms and Dominions to be to the Heires of
the Body of the said Princesse And for default of such Issue to the Princesse Anne of Denmarke and the Heires
of her Body And for default of such Issue to the Heires of the Body of the said Prince of Orange. And the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons doe pray the said Prince and (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Princesse to accept the same accordingly.
And that the Oathes hereafter mentioned be taken by all Persons of whome the Oathes of Allegiance and
Supremacy might be required by Law instead of them And that the said Oathes of Allegiance and Supremacy
be abrogated.</para>
		<para id="p63">
			<emph type="i">Allegiance.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p64">I A B doe sincerely promise and sweare That I will be faithfull and beare true Allegiance to their Majestyes King
William and Queene Mary Soe helpe me God.</para>
		<para id="p65">
			<emph type="i">Supremacy.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p66">I A B doe sweare That I doe from my Heart Abhorr, Detest and Abjure as Impious and Hereticall this damnable
Doctrine and Position That Princes Excommunicated or Deprived by the Pope or any Authority of the See
of Rome may be deposed or murdered by their Subjects or any other whatsoever. And I doe declare That noe
Forreigne Prince Person Prelate, State or Potentate hath or ought to have any Jurisdiction Power Superiority
Preeminence or Authoritie Ecclesiasticall or Spirituall within this Realme Soe helpe me God.</para>
		<para id="p67">
			<emph type="i">Acceptance of the Crown; The Two Houses to sit; Subjects Liberties to be allowed, and Ministers hereafter to serve according to the same; William and Mary declared King and Queen. Limitation of the Crown; Papists debarred the Crown; Every King, &amp;c. shall make the Declaration of 30 Car. II; If under 12 Years old, to be done after Attainment thereof; King's and Queen's Assent</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p68">Upon which their said Majestyes did accept the Crowne and Royall Dignitie of the Kingdoms of England
France and Ireland and the Dominions thereunto belonging according to the Resolution and Desire of the said
Lords and Commons contained in the said Declaration. And thereupon their Majestyes were pleased That the
said Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons being the two Houses of Parlyament should continue to sitt and
with their Majesties Royall Concurrence make effectuall Provision for the Setlement of the Religion Lawes and
Liberties of this Kingdome soe that the same for the future might not be in danger againe of being subverted,
To which the said Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons did agree and proceede to act accordingly.
Now in pursuance of the Premisses the said Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in Parlyament assembled
for the ratifying confirming and establishing the said Declaration and the Articles Clauses Matters and Things
therein contained by the Force of a Law made in due Forme by Authority of Parlyament doe pray that it may
be declared and enacted That all and singular the Rights and Liberties asserted and claimed in the said Declaration
are the true auntient and indubitable Rights and Liberties of the People of this Kingdome and soe shall be esteemed
allowed adjudged deemed and taken to be and that all and every the particulars aforesaid shall be firmly and
strictly holden and observed as they are expressed in the said Declaration And all Officers and Ministers whatsoever
shall serve their Majestyes and their Successors according to the same in all times to come. And the said Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons seriously considering how it hath pleased Almighty God in his marvellous
Providence and mercifull Goodness to this Nation to provide and preserve their said Majestyes Royall Persons
most happily to Raigne over us upon the Throne of their Auncestors for which they render unto him from the
bottome of their Hearts their humblest Thanks and Praises doe truely firmely assuredly and in the Sincerity of
their Hearts thinke and doe hereby recognize acknowledge and declare That King James the Second haveing
abdicated the Government and their Majestyes haveing accepted the Crowne and Royall Dignity [as<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] aforesaid Their
said Majestyes did become were are and of right ought to be by the Lawes of this Realme our Soveraigne Liege
Lord and Lady King and Queene of England France and Ireland and the Dominions thereunto belonging in and
to whose Princely Persons the Royall State Crowne and Dignity of the said Realmes with all Honours Stiles
Titles Regalities Prerogatives Powers Jurisdictions and Authorities to the same belonging and appertaining are most
fully rightfully and intirely invested and incorporated united and annexed And for preventing all Questions and
Divisions in this Realme by reason of any pretended Titles to the Crowne and for preserveing a Certainty in the
Succession thereof in and upon which the Unity Peace Tranquillity and Safety of this Nation doth under God
wholly consist and depend The said Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons doe beseech their Majestyes
That it may be enacted established and declared That the Crowne and Regall Government of the said Kingdoms
and Dominions with all and singular the Premisses thereunto belonging and appertaining shall bee and continue to
their said Majestyes and the Survivour of them dureing their Lives and the Life of the Survivour of them And
that the entire perfect and full Exercise of the Regall Power and Government be onely in and executed by his
Majestie in the Names of both their Majestyes dureing their joynt Lives And after their deceases the said Crowne
and Premisses shall be and remaine to the Heires of the Body of her Majestie and for default of such Issue to
her Royall Highnesse the Princess Anne of Denmarke and the Heires of her Body and for default of such Issue to
the Heires of the Body of his said Majestie And thereunto the said Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons
doe in the Name of all the People aforesaid most humbly and faithfully submitt themselves their Heires and
Posterities for ever and doe faithfully promise That they will stand to maintaine and defend their said Majesties
and alsoe the Limitation and Succession of the Crowne herein specified and contained to the utmost of their
Powers with their Lives and Estates against all Persons whatsoever that shall attempt any thing to the contrary.
And whereas it hath beene found by Experience that it is inconsistent with the Safety and Welfaire of this
Protestant Kingdome to be governed by a Popish Prince or by any King or Queene marrying a Papist the said
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons doe further pray that it may be enacted That all and every person
and persons that is are or shall be reconciled to or shall hold Communion with the See or Church of Rome
or shall professe the Popish Religion or shall marry a Papist shall be excluded and be for ever uncapeable to
inherit possesse or enjoy the Crowne and Government of this Realme and Ireland and the Dominions thereunto
belonging or any part of the same or to have use or exercise any Regall Power Authoritie or Jurisdiction within
the same [And in all and every such Case or Cases the People of these Realmes shall be and are hereby absolved
of their Allegiance<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] And the said Crowne and Government shall from time to time descend to and be enjoyed by
such person or persons being Protestants as should have inherited and enjoyed the same in case the said person
or persons soe reconciled holding Communion or Professing or Marrying as aforesaid were naturally dead [And
that every King and Queene of this Realme who at any time hereafter shall come to and succeede in the Imperiall
Crowne of this Kingdome shall on the first day of the meeting of the first Parlyament next after his or her
comeing to the Crowne sitting in his or her Throne in the House of Peeres in the presence of the Lords and
Commons therein assembled or at his or her Coronation before such person or persons who shall administer the
Coronation Oath to him or her at the time of his or her takeing the said Oath (which shall first happen) make
subscribe and audibly repeate the Declaration mentioned in the Statute made in the thirtyeth yeare of the Raigne
of King Charles the Second Entituled An Act for the more effectuall Preserveing the Kings Person and Government
by disableing Papists from sitting in either House of Parlyament But if it shall happen that such King or Queene
upon his or her Succession to the Crowne of this Realme shall be under the Age of twelve yeares then every
such King or Queene shall make subscribe and audibly repeate the said Declaration at his or her Coronation or the
first day of the meeting of the first Parlyament as aforesaid which shall first happen after such King or Queene
shall have attained the said Age of twelve yeares.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] All which Their Majestyes are contented and pleased
shall be declared enacted and established by authoritie of this present Parliament and shall stand remaine and be
the Law of this Realme for ever And the same are by their said Majesties by and with the advice and consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same
declared enacted and established accordingly</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Non obstantes made void.</head>
			<para id="p69">
				<emph type="i">Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p70">And bee it further declared and enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That from and after this present Session
of Parlyament noe Dispensation by Non obstante of or to any Statute or any part thereof shall be allowed but that
the same shall be held void and of noe effect Except a Dispensation be allowed of in such Statute [and except
in such Cases as shall be specially provided for by one or more Bill or Bills to be passed dureing this present
Session of Parliament.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Charters, Pardons, &amp;c. granted before 23d October.</head>
			<para id="p71">Provided that noe Charter or Grant or Pardon granted before the three and twentyeth Day of October in
the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred eighty nine shall be any wayes impeached or invalidated by
this Act but that the same shall be and remaine of the same force and effect in Law and noe other then as if
this Act had never beene made.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Highnesse <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


