<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46325" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1688</title>
	<subtitle> Chapter V. An Act for a Grant to Their Majestyes of an Additionall Ayd of Twelve Pence in the Pound for One Yeare. [Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 4]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for this Grant.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Cap. 1. ante, recited; Grant of further Rate; Persons charged by cap. 1. ante, 12s. to pay a further Sum of 6s. and so proportionably</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS Wee Your Majestyes Dutifull and Loyall Subjects the Commons Assembled in Parlyament haveing
Entred into a serious Consideration of the Extraordinary Occasions which did Engage Your Majestyes into
a Great Expence for the necessary Defence of Your Realmes for the Reduceing of Ireland and for the vigorous
Prosecution of the Warr against France both by Sea and Land and being desireous to Raise proportionable Aids
and Supplyes did humbly Present Your Majestyes with the Free Gift of the Rates and Assesments mentioned in
an Act of this present Parlyament Entituled An Act for a Grant to Their Majestyes of an Ayd of Two shillings
in the Pound for One Yeare, By which it was Enacted That all and every Person and Persons Bodies Politick
and Corporate Guilds and Fraternities within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede haveing any Estate in ready Moneys or in any Debts whatsoever oweing to them within this
Realme or without or haveing any Estate in Goods Wares Merchandices or other Chattells or Personall Estate
whatsoever within this Realme or without belonging to or in Trust for them (Except and out of the said Premisses
Deducted such Summes of Money as he or they did bona fide owe and such Debts as should be adjudged
Desperate by the Commissioners appointed by the said Act And alsoe the Stocke upon Land and such Goods as
were used for Housholdstuffe) should Yield and Pay unto Your Majestyes Two shillings in the Pound according to
the true yearely value thereof for One Yeare (That is to say) For every Hundred Pound of such ready Money
and Debts and for every Hundred pounds worth of such Goods Wares Merchandices or other Chattells or Personall
Estate the Summe of Twelve Shillings and soe after that rate for every greater or lesser Summe or Quantity to be
Assessed Levyed and Collected in manner in the said Act mentioned And alsoe that all and every Person
and Persons Commissioner or Commissioners Haveing Useing or Exerciseing any Publique Office or Employment
of Profitt (such Military Officers who were or should be in Muster or Pay in Your Majestyes Army or Navy onely
Excepted) And all and every their Agents Clerks Secondaries Substitutes and other Inferior Ministers whatsoever
should Yield and Pay unto Your Majestyes the Summe of Two shillings for every Twenty shillings which he or
they Received in One Yeare by Vertue of Fees or Profitts to him or them accrueing for or by reason or occasion
of their severall Offices or Employments to be Assessed Imposed Levyed and Collected in such manner as in the
same Act is mentioned And alsoe that all and every Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Quarries Mines of Coale
Tinn or Lead Iron Works Salt Springs and Salt Works all Allom Mines or Works all Parks Chases Warrens Woods
Underwoods Coppices and all Fishings Tythes Tolls Annuities and all other Yearely Profitts and all Hereditaments of
what nature or kinde soever situate lying being happening or ariseing within the Kingdome of England Dominion of
Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede as well within auntient Demesne and other Liberties and Priviledged
Places as without should be and were thereby Charged for One Yeare onely with the Summe of Two shillings for
every Twenty shillings of the full Yearely Value and soe in proportion for any greater or lesser Value And all
and every Person and Persons Bodies Pollitick and Corporate Guilds Misteries Fraternities and (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Brotherhoods whether
Corporate or not Corporate haveing or holding any Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments or other
the Premisses should Yield and Pay unto Their Majestyes the Summe of Two shillings for every Twenty shillings
by the Yeare which the said Mannours Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and other the Premisses were
worth to be Leased if the same were truely and Bona fide Leased or Demised at a Rack Rent and according to
the full true Yearely Value thereof without any respect had to the Rents reserved for the same if such Rents
had beene reserved upon such Leases or Estates made for which any Fine or Income had beene paid or secured
or had beene Lessened or abated upon Consideration of Money laid out or to be laid out in Improvements and
without any respect had to any former Rates or Taxes thereupon Imposed or makeing any Abatement in respect
of Reparations Taxes Parish Dutyes or any other Charges whatsoever Which said Summe of Two shillings for
every Twenty shillings by the Yeare of the said true Yearely Value of the Premisses was by the said Act appointed
to be Assessed Levyed and Collected in certaine manner therein mentioned and to be Paid into the Receipt of
Your Majestyes Exchequer by Foure Quarterly Payments the first Payment thereof to be made upon the Five
and twentyeth day of March in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and ninety And whereas it
was thereby further Enacted That every Papist or reputed Papist being of the Age of Sixteene yeares or upwards
who had not taken the Oathes mentioned and required to be taken by an Act of this p[re]sent Parlyament Entituled
An Act for the Abrogating the Oathes of Supremacy and Allegiance and Appointing other Oathes should Yield
and Pay unto Your Majestyes double the Summes and Rates which by vertue of any Clause in the said first
mentioned Act he or she should or ought to pay or be Charged with (That is to say) For every Hundred
pounds of ready Money and Debts and for every Hundred pounds worth of Goods Wares Merchandizes Chattells
or Personall Estate the Summe of Foure and Twenty shillings and soe after that Rate for every greater or lesser
Quantity And for every Twenty shillings of the full yearely value of any Mannours Messuages or other Hereditaments
Charged by the said Act which he or she should have or hold the Summe of Foure shillings to be Assessed
Levyed and Collected Answered Recovered and Paid in such Manner by such Wayes and according to such
Rules and Directions and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as were in the said Act expressed or appointed
for or concerning the said Rates and Sums intended to be doubled as aforesaid unlesse such Papist or reputed
Papist should take the said Oathes at such Time and in such Manner as in the said Act is appointed And
it was alsoe thereby further Enacted That every Person being of the Age of Sixteene yeares or upwards and being
within this Realme at the time of the Execution of the same Act who should not before that time have taken
the said Oathes mentioned and required to be taken by the aforesaid Act Entituled An Act for the Abrogating of
the Oathes of Supremacy and Allegiance and Appointing other Oathes and upon Summons by Warrant under the
Hands and Seales of One or more of the Commissioners appointed by the said first mentioned Act should refuse
to take the said Oaths at the time appointed in the said Warrant or should neglect to appeare at such time before
the Commissioners in order to take the said Oaths should Yield and Pay to Your Majestyes double the Summes and
Rates which by vertue of any Clause in the said Act he or she should or ought to Pay or be Charged with
in Manner as was in the same Act appointed touching Papist or reputed Papist to be Assessed Levyed Collected
Answered Recovered and Paid in such Manner by such Wayes and according to such Rules and Directions and
under such Penalties and Forfeitures as were in the said first mentioned Act expressed for and concerning the
above mentioned Rates and Summes intended to be doubled as aforesaid, And in the said Act it was further
Provided That every Person commonly called a Quaker and knowne to be such who should Make and Subscribe
the Declaration of Fidelity contained in an Act of this present Parlyament Entituled An Act for Exempting Their
Majesties Protestant Subjects Dissenting from the Church of England from the Penalties of certaine Lawes should
not be lyable to or chargeable with any of the double Rates aforesaid And whereas wee Your Majestyes said
Subjects the Commons are sensible That a further Aid and Supply is Requisite and Necessary for the Ends and
Purposes aforesaid Wee doe humbly present Your Majestyes with the Free Gift of the further Rates and Assesments
herein after mentioned And doe beseech Your Majestyes that it may be Enacted And bee it Enacted by the
King and Queens most Excellent Majestyes by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament Assembled and by Authoritie of the same That Their Majesties
shall over and besides the Rates and Assesments mentioned in the said former Act have and receive the further
Rates and Assesments hereafter mentioned of and from every Person Spirituall and Temporall of what Estate or
Degree soever he or they be to be Taxed Assessed Levyed and Paid in Manner and Forme following (That is
to say) That all and every Person and Persons Bodies Pollitick and Corporate Guilds and Fraternities aforesaid
who in respect of any Estate in ready Money or Debts or Goods Wares Merchandices or other Chattells or
Personall Estate whatsoever were Charged by the said former Act and ought to Pay unto Their Majesties the
Summe of Twelve shillings shall be Charged with and shall Yield and Pay unto Their Majesties the further
Summe of Six shillings (That is to say) in the whole the Summe of Eighteene shillings and soe after that Rate
for every greater or lesser Summe or Quantity</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners and their Agents, &amp;c. by said Act charged at 2s. in the Pound, to pay the further Sum of 1s.</head>
			<para id="p3">And bee it further Enacted That all and every Person and Persons Commissioner or Commissioners and all
and every their Agents Clerks Secondaries Substitutes and other Inferior Ministers whatsoever who by the said
former Act were Charged and ought to Pay Two shillings for every Twenty shillings which he or they doe
receive in One Yeare by vertue of any Fees or Profitts to him or them Accrueing for or by reason or occasion
of their [severall<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Offices or Imployments shall be Charged with and shall Yield and Pay unto Their Majesties the
further Summe of One shilling (That is to say) in the whole the Summe of Three shillings for every Twenty
shillings which he or they doe soe Receive in One Yeare.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Lands, &amp;c. charged by said Act at 2s. in the Pound, to pay the further Sum of 1s.</head>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further Enacted That all and every Mannours Messuages Lands and Tenements Quarries Mines of
Coale Tinn or Lead Iron-Works Salt-Springs Salt-Works Allom-Mines or Works Parks Chases Warrens Woods
Underwoods Coppices Fishings Tythes Tolls Annuities and all other yearely Profitts and Hereditaments of what
nature or kinde soever Charged by the former Act for One yeare with the Summe of Two shillings for every
Twenty shillings of the full yearely Value and soe in Proportion for any greater or lesser Values shall be Charged
with and they who have or hold the same shall Yield and Pay unto Their Majestyes the further Summe of
One shilling for every Twenty shillings That is to say Three shillings in the whole for every Twenty shillings
of the full yearely Value and soe in proportion for any greater or lesser Value</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Papists and other Persons charged by said Act at a Double Rate, charged further double the Rate granted by this Act, and also 2s. on every 4s. granted by the said Act.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further Enacted That every Papist and Reputed Papist and every other Person which by the said
former Act was Charged with and made lyable to Pay unto Their Majestyes Double the Summes and Rates
aforesaid shall be Charged with and shall Pay unto Their Majesties over and besides the same Double the Summes
and Rates Given and Granted by this Act (That is to say) the Summe of Twelve shillings over and besides every
Summe of Twenty foure shillings And the Summe of Two shillings over and besides every Summe of Foure
shillings which such Papist reputed Papist or other Person was Charged with or lyable to Pay by vertue of the
said former Act</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Commissioners under former Act to execute this Act.</head>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further Enacted That all and every the Persons named and appointed to be Com[m]issioners for
putting the said former Act in Execution shall be Commissioners for putting this present Act in Execution and
shall respectively have and execute all Powers Authorities and Priviledges for and in relation to this present Act
as they had and ought to have by and in relation to the said former Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Rates granted by this Act to be assessed, levied, &amp;c. under the Provisions of the said former Act;</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">and all Persons employed under this Act entitled to the Benefits and liable to all the Penalties of the said Act.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">And that the Rates and Summes Given and Granted to Their Majesties by this present Act shall be Assessed
Taxed Collected Levyed Answered and Paid at such time and times and in such respective Proportions and in
such Manner by such Meanes and Wayes and according to such Rules and Directions and under such Penalties
and Forfeitures and with such Abatements Deductions and Allowances as in the said former Act are respectively
Appointed of for and concerning the severall Rates and Summes thereby Given and Granted to Their Majestyes
And all and every Person and Persons who shall be lyable to or any way Concerned or Imployed in the Assessing
Collecting Levying Receiving or Paying any of the Summes Rates or Moneys by this Act Appointed to be
Assessed Taxed Levyed Answered or Paid shall have like Benefitts Advantages and Discharges and shall be
subject to like Penalties and Forfeitures in case of Neglect or Refusall to Pay the Summes that shall hereupon
be Assessed or Charged or to performe their respective Duties as in like case any Person or Persons by Vertue
of the said former Act ought to have or be subject unto as Fully and Amply as if all and every the Clauses
in the said former Act contained for such purpose had beene againe in this Act respectively Repeated and Enacted
perticularly</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Persons may lend Money to the Crown under this Act on Interest at &pound;7 per Cent. per Ann. such Money not to be rated.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Tallies and Orders to Lenders; assignable; Orders paid in Course, and Interest every Three Months, under the Provisions of former Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby Enacted That it shall and may be lawfull for any Person or Persons to
Lend unto Their Majesties upon Security of the Moneyes given by this present Act any Summe or Summes of
Money and to have and receive Interest for the same after the Rate of Seven pounds in the Hundred for a
Yeare And that none of the Money soe to be Lent shall be Rated or Assessed by vertue of this Act And that
Tallies of Loane shall be Stricken and Orders of Repayment for the Moneys soe to be Lent and the Interest
thereof Signed and Registred in a distinct Register for this purpose to be provided And such Orders or any
part thereof shall be Assignable and the Principalls upon such Orders shall be paid in Course and the Interest
every Three months in the like Method Order and Forme and under such Penalties Forfeitures Damages and
Costs to be Incurred by any Officer or Officers Clerks or Deputies respectively for giveing any undue Preference
or for takeing of undue Rewards Fees or Gratuities as in and by the first mentioned Act are in the like Cases
Enacted Prescribed Provided or Declared.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Book kept for Account of One Third Part of Monies paid into the Exchequer under the former Act and this Act. Such Third Part of the said Monies applied in the Repayment of the Loans.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">The Two other Third Parts applied to the Purpose of the said former Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And to the end that all the Moneys which shall be Lent unto Their Majestyes upon Credit of this Act with
the Interest thereof may be well and sufficiently Secured and Paid according to the true meaning of the same
It is further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That there shall be provided and kept in Their Majesties
Exchequer (to witt) in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt One Booke in which One Third part of all the
Moneys which in any One Day shall be brought or paid into the Exchequer ariseing as well by the said former
Act as by vertue of this present Act shall be Entred apart and distinct from the other Two Third parts thereof
and from all other the Revenue and Treasure there Which Third part soe from time to time ariseing shall be
applyed and is hereby appropriated to the Satisfaction of the Loanes to be separately made on this Act and the
Interest of the same And the other Two Third Parts of all the said Moneys ariseing by both Acts as aforesaid
shall remaine appropriated and be applyed according to the true intent and meaning of the said former Act Any
thing in this or the said former Act to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Cap. 1. ante, or this Act, not to extend to Timber Trees standing or growing on the Stem.</head>
			<para id="p13">Provided alwayes and bee it Declared and Enacted That this Act nor any thing therein contained nor any
thing contained in a former Act of this present Session Entituled An Act for a Grant to Their Majestyes of an
Ayd of Two shillings in the Pound for One Yeare shall extend or be construed to extend to the Taxing or
Assessing any Person or Persons for or in respect of any Timber Trees standing or growing on the Stem Any
thing in this Act or in the forementioned Act of a Grant to Their Majesties of an Ayd of Two shillings in the
Pound for One Yeare to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">and <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


