<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46330" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1689</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for Recognizing King William and Queene Mary and for avoiding all Questions touching the Acts made in the Parliament assembled at Westminster the thirteenth day of February one thousand six hundred eighty eight. [Rot. Parl. pt. 1. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>King and Queen recognized.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Acts of the said Parliament were and are Laws and Statutes, and to be obeyed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee your Majestyes most humble and loyall Subjects the Lords Spirituall and (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Temporall and Commons in
this present Parlyament assembled doe beseech your most excellent Majestyes that it may be published and
declared in this High Court of Parlyament and enacted by authoritie of the same That we doe recognize and
acknowledge your Majestyes were are and of Right ought to be by the Laws of this Realme our Soveraigne Liege
Lord and Lady King and Queene of England France and Ireland and the Dominions thereunto belonging in and
to whose Princely Persons the Royall State Crowne and Dignity of the said Realms with all Honours Stiles
Titles Regalities Prerogatives Powers Jurisdictions and Authorities to the same belonging and appertaining are most
fully rightfully and intirely invested and incorporated united and annexed. And for the avoiding of all Disputes
and Questions concerning the Being and Authority of the late Parliament assembled at Westminster the thirteenth
day of February one thousand six hundred eighty [eight<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Wee doe most humbly beseech your Majestyes that it
may be enacted And bee it enacted by the King and Queenes most excellent Majestyes by and with the advice and
consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by authoritie of
the same That all and singular the Acts made and enacted in the said Parlyament were and are Laws and Statutes of this
Kingdome and as such ought to be reputed taken and obeyed by all the People of this Kingdome.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>


