<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46339" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1689</title>
<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for the King and Queens most Gracious Generall and Free Pardon. [Rot. Parl. pt. 1. nu. 12.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">All Persons pardoned of Treason, &amp;c.; before 16th May 1690</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">The King and Queens most excellent Majestyes takeing into their serious Consideration the long and great
Troubles and Discords that have beene within this Kingdome and that by occasion thereof and otherwise
many of their Subjects are fallen into danger of and lye open to great Penalties and Forfeitures and withall
graciously considering the faithfull Hearts and dutyfull Affections of their loyall Subjects Out of an earnest desire
to deliver their Subjects from the Penalties and Forfeitures aforesaid and to the intent that their Offences may
not hereafter be brought in Judgment Question or Remembrance to the least endamagement of them either in
their Lives Liberties Estates or Reputations but that they haveing an entire Confidence in their Majesties and
perfect Union among themselves may be encouraged in their Duty to their Majestyes Government and more fully
and securely enjoy the benefit of it Their Majesties are of their Princely and Mercyfull Disposition and meere
Motion most graciously inclined to extend unto them their Generall and Free Pardon and that in a more bountyfull
manner then hath beene accustomed Their Majestyes assuredly trusting that all their Subjects by this Clemency
and indulgent Grace will be the rather induced henceforth more carefully to observe the Laws and performe their
loyall and due Obedience to their Majesties And therefore their Majesties are well pleased and contented That it
be enacted by authority of this present Parliament and Bee it enacted by authoritie of the same in manner and
forme following that is to say That all and every the said Subjects as well Spirituall as Temporall of this their
Majestyes Realme of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede their Heires Successors
Executors and Administrators and every of them and all and singular Bodies in any manner of wise corporated
Cityes Burroughs Shires Rideings Hundreds Lathes Rapes Wapentakes Townes Villages Hamlets and Tythings
and every of them and the Successor and Successors of every of them shall be by authority of this present
Parlyament acquited pardoned released and discharged against their Majesties their Heires and Successors and every
of them of and from all manner of Treasons Felonies Misprisions of Treason Treasonable or Seditious Words or
Libells Misprisions of Felony Seditious and unlawfull Meetings and Conventicles and all Offences whereby any person
may be charged with the Penalty and danger of Premunire and alsoe of and from all Riotts Routs Offences
Contempts Trespasses Entryes Wrongs Deceits Misdemeanors Forfeitures Penalties and Summes of Money Paines
of Death Pains Corporall and Pains Pecuniary and generally of and from all other Things Causes Quarrells Suits
Judgements and Executions in this present Act not hereafter excepted or foreprized which may be or can be by
their Majestyes in any wise or by any means pardoned before the sixteenth day of May in the yeare of our Lord
one thousand six hundred and ninety to any of the Subjects or Bodyes Corporate aforesaid</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. The Pardon to be as good as if all things were particularly named.</head>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Proviso for Exceptions</emph>.</para>
<para id="p4">And alsoe the King and Queens most excellent Majestyes are contented that it be enacted by authoritie of this
present Parlyament and Bee it enacted by authoritie of the same That this their Free Pardon shall be as good and
effectuall in Law to every of their said Subjects Bodies Corporate and others before rehearsed in for and against
all things which be not hereafter in this present Act excepted and foreprized as the same Pardon should have
beene if all Offences Contempts Forfeitures Causes Matters Suits Quarrells Judgments Executions Penalties and
all other things not hereafter in this present Act excepted and foreprized had beene particularly singularly specially
and plainly named rehearsed and specifyed and alsoe pardoned by proper and expresse Words and Names in their
Kinds Natures and Qualities by Words and Terms thereunto requisite to have beene putt in and expressed in
this present Act of Free Pardon and that their said Subjects or any of them the Heires Executors or Administrators
of any of them or the said Bodies Corporate and others before named and rehearsed or any of them be not nor
shall be sued vexed or unquieted in their Bodies Goods Chattells Lands or Tenements for any manner of Matter
Cause Contempt Misdemeanour Forfeiture Trespasse Offence or any other thing suffered done or committed or
ommitted before the said sixteenth day of May against their Majesties their Crowne Dignity Prerogative or the
Laws or Statutes of this Realme but onely for such Matters Causes and Offences as be rehearsed mentioned or
in some wayes touched in the Exceptions of this present Act to be foreprized and excepted and for none other
any Statute or Statutes Laws Customs or Usages heretofore had made or used to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. Grant of all Forfeitures incurred before 16th May 1690 to the Subject.</head>
<para id="p5">And their Majestyes of their bounteous Liberality and by the authoritie of this present Parlyament doe grant
and freely give to every of their Subjects every of the said Bodyes Corporate and others before rehearsed and
every of them all Goods Chattells Debts Fines Issues Profitts Amerciaments Forfeitures and Summes of Money by
any of them forfeited which to their Majestyes doe or shall belong or appertaine by reason of any Offence
Contempt [Entry Trespasse<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Misdemeanour Matter Cause or Quarrell suffered done or committed by them or any
of them before the said sixteenth day of May which be not hereafter in this present Act foreprised and excepted</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>IV. Grants or Executions upon Forfeitures how far of Force.</head>
<para id="p6">And bee it enacted neverthelesse That all Grants thereof or of any part thereof made by any such as have
soe forfeited the same and are hereby restored as aforesaid and all Executions thereof or of any part thereof had
against any such after such Forfeiture thereof committed or made shall be of such force and effect as if noe such
Forfeiture had beene had or made and of noe other The same Forfeiture or any thing before in this Act to the
contrary notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>V. Any Person may plead this Pardon by themselves or their Attornies.</head>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">Fee to Clerk entering Plea, &amp;c.</emph></para>
<para id="p8">And Bee it further enacted That all and every their Majestyes Subjects and all and singular Bodies Corporate
and others before rehearsed may by him or themselves or by his or their Deputy or Deputies or by his or their
Attourney or Attourneys according to the Law of this Realme plead and minister this present Act of Free Pardon
for his or their Discharge of or for any thing that is by vertue of this present Act pardoned discharged given or
granted without any Fee or other thing paying to any person or persons for Writeing or Entry of the Judgments
or other cause concerning such Plea Writeing or Entry but onely sixteene pence to be paid to the Officer or Clerke
that shall enter such Plea Matter for Judgment or the Parties Discharge in that behalfe any Law Custome or Usage
to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>VI. Pardon to be expounded beneficially to the Subject, and allowed without Delay, &amp;c.</head>
<para id="p9">And furthermore their Majestyes are contented and pleased that it be enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That
this their Free Pardon by the generall Words Clauses and Sentences before rehearsed shall be reputed deemed
adjudged expounded allowed and taken in all manner of Courts of their Majesties and elsewhere most beneficiall
and available to all and singular the said Subjects Bodies Corporate and others before rehearsed and to every of
them in all things not in this present Act excepted and foreprized without any Ambiguity Question or other
Delay whatsoever to be made pleaded objected or alledged by the King and Queens Majesties their Heires or
Successors or their or any of their Generall Attourney or Attourneys or by any person or persons for their Majesties
or any of their Heires or Successors</para>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>VII. Officer offending in making out Process, or taking Money for Things pardoned.</head>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">Penalty &pound;10, and Treble Damages and Costs; Process void</emph>.</para>
<para id="p11">And Bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That if any Officer or Clerke of any of their Majestyes
Courts commonly called the Chancery Kings-Bench Common Pleas or Exchequer or any other Officer or Clerke of any
other their Majesties Courts within this Realme at any time after the last day of Easter Terme next make out or
write out any Writts Processe Summons or other Precept whereby any of the said Subjects or of the Bodies Corporate
or others before rehearsed or any of them shall be in anywise arrested attached distrained summoned or otherwise
vexed inquieted or grieved in his or their Bodies Lands Tenements Goods or Chattells or any of them for or
because of any manner of thing pardoned or discharged by vertue of this Act or if any Sheriffe (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Escheatour or any
their Deputy or Deputies or any Bayliffe or other Officer whatsoever by colour of his or their Office or otherwise
after the said last day of Easter Terme next doe levy recieve take or withhold of or from any person or persons
any thing pardoned or discharged by this Act That then every such person soe offending and thereof lawfully
convicted or condemned by any sufficient Testimony Witnesse or Proofe shall yield and pay for Recompence thereof
to the party soe grieved or offended thereby his or their treble Damages besides all Costs of the Suite and shall
alsoe forfeit and lose to the King and Queens Majesties for every such Offence ten pounds And neverthelesse all
and singular such Writts Processe and Precepts soe to be made for or upon any manner of thing pardoned or
discharged by this present Act of Free Pardon shall be utterly void and of none effect</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">Exceptions, High Treason</emph>.</para>
<para id="p13">Excepted and alwayes foreprized out of this Generall and Free Pardon all and all manner of High Treasons
and other Offences committed or done by any person or persons against the King and Queens Majestyes most Royall
Persons or either of them and all Conspiracies and Confederacies trayterously had committed or done by any person
or persons against their Majesties most Royall Persons or either of them</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">Treasons in Ireland</emph>.</para>
<para id="p15">And alsoe excepted all and every manner of Treasons committed or done by any person or persons in Ireland
or in any the parts beyond the Seas or in any other places out of this Realme since the thirteenth day of February
in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred eighty and eight and alsoe all Suites Punishments Outlawries
Judgements Executions Paines of Death Forfeitures and Penalties for or by reason or occasion of any the Treasons
and Offences before excepted</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">Forging Great Seal, &amp;c. Diminishing the Coin, Misprision of Treason, &amp;c.</emph></para>
<para id="p17">And alsoe excepted out of this Free Pardon all Offences in Forging and false Counterfeiting the Great or Privy
Seale Signe Manuall or Privy Signet or of any of the Moneys currant within this Realme and alsoe all Offences
of unlawfull diminishing any of the said moneys by any wayes or meanes whatsoever contrary to the Laws and
Statutes of this Realme and all Misprisions and Concealments of the Treasons before excepted and all abetting
aiding comforting and procureing of the same Offences or any of the said Treasons before excepted</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">Murders, Petit Treason, Poisoning</emph>.</para>
<para id="p19">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all manner of voluntary Murders Petit [Treasons<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] and wilfull Poysonings
done or committed by any person or persons and all and every the Accessaries of the same Offences or any
of them</para>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">Piracies, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p21">And alsoe excepted and foreprized out of this Generall Pardon all Piracies and Robberies done upon the Seas
and all and every procureing or abetting any such Offenders and the comforting and recieveing of them or any of
them or of any Goods taken by way of Piracy or Robbery upon the Seas as aforesaid</para>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">Burglaries, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p23">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all Burglaries and all breaking into and stealing out of any Dwelling house
or Houses in the day and all Accessaries to (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) the said Burglaries and Felonies</para>
<para id="p24"><emph type="i">Robberies in Churches and on the Highway</emph>.</para>
<para id="p25">And alsoe except all Robberies of Churches and stealing any Plate Utensils or Goods of or belonging to the same
and alsoe all Robberies committed upon any person or persons in or neare the Highway.</para>
<para id="p26"><emph type="i">Buggery</emph>.</para>
<para id="p27">And alsoe excepted the detestable or abominable Vice of Buggery committed with Mankind or Beast</para>
<para id="p28"><emph type="i">Rape</emph>.</para>
<para id="p29">And alsoe excepted all Rapes and Carnall Ravishments of Women</para>
<para id="p30"><emph type="i">Taking away or marrying Women</emph>.</para>
<para id="p31">And alsoe excepted all Ravishments and wilfull takeing away or marrying of any Maid Widow or Damsell against
her Will or without the assent or agreement of her Parents or of such as then had her in Custodie And all Offences
of aiding and comforting procureing or abetting any such Ravishments wilfull takeing or marrying had committed
or done</para>
<para id="p32"><emph type="i">Perjury, Subornation, forging Records, Examination of Witnesses, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p33">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all Offences of Perjury and the Subornation of Witnesses and endeavouring
to bribe and corrupt any Person to give a false Testimony and the Offences of Forgeing and Counterfeiting and
Sollicitation of Forging or Counterfeiting any Fines or other Records Deeds Wills Escripts or Writeings whatsoever
and all Offences of Forgeing or Counterfeiting any Examinations or Testimonies of any Witnesse or Witnesses
tending to bring any person or persons into danger of his Life and all procureing or councelling of any such
Forgings or Counterfeitings had made committed or done</para>
<para id="p34"><emph type="i">Forest Offences</emph>.</para>
<para id="p35">And also excepted all Offences committed in any Forest since the thirteenth day of February in the yeare of
our Lord one thousand six hundred eighty eight in takeing killing or destroying any Deere and in cutting downe
takeing away or destroying any Timber or Trees or any Fences or Inclosures of or in the said Forests</para>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">Certain Forfeitures due or that may grow due to the Crown</emph>.</para>
<para id="p37">And alsoe except all Forfeitures and other Penalties and Profits now due accrued and grown or which shall
or may be due accrue or grow to the King and Queens Majestyes by reason of any Offence Misdemeanour or
Contempt or other Act or Deed had suffered committed or done contrary to any Act Statute or Statutes (other
then useing or causeing to be used any Craft Mistery or Occupation by any person not brought up therein seven
yeares as an Apprentice) or contrary to the Common Law of this Realme And whereof or for the which any
Action Bill Plaint or Information at any time within six yeares next before the day of the assembling and holding
of this Parlyament (videlicet) the twentyeth day of March in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred
eighty nine hath beene commenced or sued in any of their Majestyes Courts at Westminster and is depending and
remaineing to be prosecuted or whereupon any Verdict Judgement or Decree is already given or entred or whereof
or whereupon their Majestyes by their Bill signed or otherwise have made any Gift or Assignement to any person
or persons before the said sixteenth day of May and all Awards of Court Orders Sentences Judgments Executions
and Proceedings upon or concerning or by reason or occasion of any such Offence Misdemeanour Contempt Act
or Deed</para>
<para id="p38"><emph type="i">Informations about Highways, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p39">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all Informations and other Proceedings depending concerning any Common
Highwayes or Bridges and all Issues returned upon any Processe concerning the same since the twentyeth day
of March in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred seaventy and nine</para>
<para id="p40"><emph type="i">Embezzling their Majesties Goods, &amp;c; Conveying Stores, &amp;c. to the French King</emph>.</para>
<para id="p41">And alsoe excepted all Offences in takeing away imbezzilling or purloyning any of the King and Queens
Majestyes Goods Moneys Chattells Jewells Armour Munition Stores Navall Provisions Shipping Ordnance and
other Habiliments of Warr and all Offences in conveying to the French King or any of his Subjects any
Navall Stores or Commodities or Contraband Goods or supplying him or them with the same</para>
<para id="p42"><emph type="i">Breach of Covenant with their Majesties</emph>.</para>
<para id="p43">And alsoe excepted all Conditions and Covenants and all Penalties Titles and Forfeitures of Conditions or Covenants
accrued or growne to their Majesties by reason of the Breach and not performing of any Covenant or Condition
whatsoever</para>
<para id="p44"><emph type="i">Incest, Simony, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p45">And alsoe excepted all Offences of Incest Simony or Dilapidations for which any Suite is or was depending upon
the said first day of this Parliament</para>
<para id="p46"><emph type="i">Adultery, and Crimes of Persons in Orders</emph>.</para>
<para id="p47">And alsoe excepted Adultery and all other enormous Crimes committed by any person in Holy Orders punishable
in any Ecclesiasticall Court and all Proceedings and Sentences thereupon</para>
<para id="p48"><emph type="i">First-fruits, &amp;c; Bishops or Receivers not discharged, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p49">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all First-fruits and Tenths Pensions Procurations Synodalls and other
Payments out of any Ecclesiasticall Promotion or Benefice other then Arrears of Tenths which at any time before
the said first day of this Session of Parlyament did become due for upon or out of any small Rectory Vicarage or
Benefice which at the true and greatest Valuation and Improvement is not of the yearely Value of thirty pounds
and which shall be soe certified by the respective Bishop or Guardians of the Spiritualities to their Majesties Court
of Exchequer before the last day of next Michaelmas Terme Provided That this shall not be construed to
pardon or discharge any Bishop or Receiver of or from answering or paying any of the said Arreares by him
received.</para>
<para id="p50"><emph type="i">Concealment of Duties</emph>.</para>
<para id="p51">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) all and every the Summes of Money and Duties following and the
Concealment or wrongfull Detainments thereof (that is to say) of any Custome or Subsidy Excise Arrears of the
Hearth-Money Imposition upon Wine or other Liquors or Commodities Duties ariseing by Wine-Licences or the
Post-Office or any other Tax Assessment Duty or Imposition due or belonging to the King and Queens Majestyes
or given or levyable by any Act of Parliament and all Arreares thereof and all Forfeitures ariseing thereby or for
the Non-payment thereof and all Corruptions and Misdemeanours of any Officer or Minister of in or concerning
the same and all Accounts and Suits whatsoever to be had made or prosecuted for the same and all Concealments
Frauds and Offences by which their Majestyes have beene decieved and not truely answered of or for
the same</para>
<para id="p52"><emph type="i">Taking away Goods or Rents, &amp;c. forfeited to King Charles II. or James II. or their present Majesties</emph>.</para>
<para id="p53">And alsoe excepted all and every manner of takeing from the King and Queens Majestyes or the late Kings
Charles the Second and James the Second or either of them any Goods or Chattells forfeited by reason of any
Treason Petit Treason Murder or Felony heretofore committed or done And alsoe all and every manner of takeing
from their Majesties or either of the said Kings the Issues Rents Revenues or Profitts of any Manours Lands
Tenements or Hereditaments which were of any Traytor Murderer Felon Clerke or Clerks attainted or any of
them And alsoe all and all manner of takeing from the King and Queens Majestyes or either of the said Kings
the Issues Rents Revenues and Profits of any Mannour Lands Tenements or Hereditaments parcell of the Possessions
of any Bishopricke the Temporalties whereof upon the said twentyeth day of March in the yeare of our Lord
one thousand six hundred seventy nine or at any time since were or of right ought to have beene in their or
either of their Hands</para>
<para id="p54"><emph type="i">Exception of Arrearages due from Farmers of the Revenue</emph>.</para>
<para id="p55">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all Arrearages of Rent due from any Farmer of any part of the
Revenue ariseing by Customs Excise or Hearthmoney or Impositions upon Proceedings at Law and all Arrearages
of Fee-Farme Rents or other Rents</para>
<para id="p56"><emph type="i">Of Accounts, &amp;c. from Collectors, &amp;c. to the King</emph>.</para>
<para id="p57">And alsoe excepted all and singular accounts of all and every Collector and Collectors Commissioners Treasurers
or Recievers who have collected [or recieved<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] any Subsidie Custome Subsidy of Tonnage and Poundage additionall
Duty prize-Goods or other things growne due or happening since the five and twentyeth day of March in the
yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred seventy three And all accounts of every other person whatsoever
that ought to be accomptant to the King and Queens Majesties for or in respect of any Receipt or other Charge
which hath grown since the said five and twentieth day of March and the Heires Executors Administrators and
Sureties of any person that ought to account for all things touching onely the same accounts and all and singular
arrearages of accounts and untrue accounts made or rendred since the said five and twentyeth day of March and
all Impetitions Charges Seisures Suites Demands and Executions which may or can be had of or for any such
account or accounts or any arrearages of the same</para>
<para id="p58"><emph type="i">Of Receivers' Recognizances</emph>.</para>
<para id="p59">And alsoe excepted all Recognizances Obligations and other Securities given or entred into by any Receiver
Reeve Bayliffe Collector or other Accomptant in the Court of Exchequer and their Sureties and their
Accounts respectively and all other Recognizances and Obligations whatsoever conditioned for the payment
of Money</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>VIII. Of forfeited Recognizances, &amp;c.</head>
<para id="p60"><emph type="i">Of Penalties, &amp;c. due to their Majesties since 25th March</emph>.</para>
<para id="p61">Provided alwayes and Bee it enacted That this Act shall not extend or be construed to pardon or discharge any
[Recognizance or Obligation not yet forfeited nor to pardon or discharge any<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] forfeited Recognizance or Obligation or
any other Forfeiture or Penaltie whereof the Farmers of the Excise or the Farmers of any other part of the publick
Revenue ought to recieve any benefitt or advantage Nor to pardon or discharge any Debt due by Recognizance
Obligation or other Specialty to any person or persons indebted to their Majestyes which hath beene duely seized
in aid of their Majestyes Debt Nor to pardon or discharge any Debt due by Recognizance Obligation Condemnation
or otherwise whereupon any Estalment or Seizure hath beene at any time heretofore made upon which Estalment
or Seizure any thing is or at any time since the said five and twentyeth day of March hath beene answered and
paid Nor to pardon or discharge any Penalties Forfeitures or Sums of Money due or accrued to their Majesties by
reason of any Act Statute or Statutes which Forfeitures Penalties and Sums of Mony since the said five and twentyeth
day of March be converted into the nature of any Debt by any Judgement Order Decree or by the Agreement of
the Offender or Offenders or have beene estalled or any Seizure made for the same and upon such Seizure or
Estalment any thing answered or paid since the said five and twentyeth day of March.</para>
<para id="p62"><emph type="i">Proviso for Recognizances for Appearance, except the Lord Almoner</emph>.</para>
<para id="p63">Neverthelesse it is hereby declared That all Obligations and Recognizances forfeited since the said five and
twentyeth day of March for Non appearance in any Court or other place whatsoever or not keeping the Peace or
not being of the Good Behaviour shall be clearly pardoned and discharged except Recognizances granted to or in
trust for the Lord Almoner</para>
<para id="p64"><emph type="i">Exception of Issues lost</emph>.</para>
<para id="p65">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all Issues Fines and Amerciaments lost imposed or assessed since the
said five and twentyeth day of March being totted levyed or recieved by any Sheriffe Under Sheriffe Bayliffe
Minister or other Officer before the last day of this present Session of Parlyament</para>
<para id="p66">And alsoe excepted all Issues Fines and Amerciaments lost imposed or assessed since the said five and twentyeth
day of March affeered taxed sett estreated or entred severally or particularly touching or concerning any one or
more persons joyntly or severally above the Summe of six pounds</para>
<para id="p67"><emph type="i">Of Issues, &amp;c. returned, &amp;c. within a Year before this Parliament</emph>.</para>
<para id="p68">And alsoe excepted all Issues Fines and Amerciaments returned affeered taxed sett or entred severally or
particularly in any Court of Record at Westminster at any time within the space of a yeare before the said first
day of this Parliament</para>
<para id="p69"><emph type="i">Proviso for other Fines and Issues</emph>.</para>
<para id="p70">And yet neverthelesse all other Fines as well Fines Pro Licentia Concordandi as other sett taxed estreated or
entred before that time And alsoe all Issues and Amerciaments as well reall as others within any Liberties or
without being sett taxed estreated or entred before the time aforesaid and which severally and particularly extend
to or under the Summe of six pounds and not above whether they be estreated or not estreated or whether
they be turned into Debt or not turned into Debt and not being totted levyed or recieved by any Sheriffe Under
Sheriffe Minister or other Officer before the said first day of this Parliament shall be freely clearely and plainly
pardoned and discharged against the King and Queens Majestyes their Heires and Successors by force of this
present Act</para>
<para id="p71"><emph type="i">Estreats of Fines, &amp;c. already estreated to be delivered into the Pipe Office</emph>.</para>
<para id="p72">And yet neverthelesse all Estreats of such Fines Issues and Amerciaments as be now pardoned by this Act
and which be already estreated forth of the Court of Exchequer and (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) remaineing in the Hands of the Sheriffe
Under-Sheriffe or Bayliffe for collecting of the same Fines Issues and Amerciaments shall upon the returne of the
same Estreats be duely and orderly charged and delivered by Scrows into the Office of the Pipe in the Court
of Exchequer as heretofore hath beene accustomed to the intent that thereupon Order may be taken that their
Majestyes may be truely answered all such Fines Issues and Amerciaments not by this Act pardoned and which
any Sheriffe Under-Sheriffe Bayliffe or other Officer or Minister hath received or ought to answere by force or
colour of any such Estreat Processe or Precept to him or them made for the levying thereof</para>
<para id="p73"><emph type="i">Sheriffs and other Accountants on Petition for Allowance of Fines, &amp;c. to have same granted without Fee</emph>.</para>
<para id="p74">And yet that notwithstanding all and every Sheriffe and Sheriffes and other Accomptant upon his or their
Petition or Petitions to be made for the allowance of any such Fines Issues and Amerciaments as by this Act
are pardoned shall have all and every such his and their Petition allowed in his and their account and accounts
without paying any Fee or Reward to any Officer Clerke or other Minister for the makeing entring or allowing
of any such Petition or Petitions any Usage or Custome to the contrary hereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s9">
<head>IX. Exception of King Charles the First's Murderers excepted by 12 Car. II. c. 11. and the Two Persons appearing upon the Scaffold with Vizors.</head>
<para id="p75">Provided alwayes that this Act shall not extend to pardon discharge or give any benefitt whatsoever unto any
person or persons who are by Name particularly excepted out of the Act of Free and Generall Pardon Indempnity
and Oblivion made in the twelfth yeare of the Raigne of his late Majestie King Charles the Second for their
execrable Treason and horrid Murder of their Majestyes Royall Grandfather of gracious Memory nor to those two
persons or either of them who being disguised by Frocks and [Vizors<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] appeared upon the Scaffold at the time
when the said Murder was committed</para>
<para id="p76"><emph type="i">Of Disabilities</emph>.</para>
<para id="p77">Nor shall this present Act give or restore any Ability or Capacity to take have hold or exercise any Office
Place Authority or Employment Ecclesiasticall Civill or Military to any person or persons who in and by the said
last mentioned Act or by vertue or reason of any other Act or Law were or are made or become incapable or
disabled to have take hold or execute the same or of serveing as a Member in Parlyament but all and every
such person or persons shall remaine and continue under all and every the Disabilities and Incapacities aforesaid
any thing in this present Act to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
<para id="p78"><emph type="i">Of Persons who have accepted any Office contrary to 12 Car. II. c. 11</emph>.</para>
<para id="p79">Nor shall this Act extend to pardon discharge or give any benefitt to any person who if he after the first day
of September one thousand six hundred and sixty hath accepted or exercised or hereafter shall accept or exercise
any Office Ecclesiasticall Civill or Military or any other publick Employment within England Wales or the Towne
of Berwicke upon Tweede is by the said Act made in the twelfth yeare of King Charles the Second to stand and
be as if he had beene totally by Name excepted out of the said last mentioned Act, but all and every such
persons shall if they have or shall accept any Office or Employment contrary to the tenor of the said last
mentioned Act be out of this Act wholly excepted and foreprised</para>
<para id="p80"><emph type="i">Of Persons attainted of Rebellion, Treason, Murder, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p81">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all such persons as be and remaine still attainted or condemned by Act
of Parlyament or otherwise of or for any Rebellion or levying of Warr or of [or for any Conspiracy of any Rebellion
or levying Warr<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] within this Realme or any other their Majesties Dominions and all such persons who are attainted
or outlawed of or for any other Treason Petit Treason Murder wilfull Poysoning or Burglary and all Executions
therefore</para>
<para id="p82"><emph type="i">Of Persons exiled, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p83">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all such persons who by vertue of any former Act of Parlyament are by
expresse Name exiled or made lyable to any other Pains Penalties or Disabilities whatsoever</para>
<para id="p84"><emph type="i">Transported</emph>.</para>
<para id="p85">And alsoe excepted all such Persons who after Conviction or Attainder of or for any manner of Felony have
desired to be transported into any of their Majesties Forreigne Plantations</para>
<para id="p86"><emph type="i">Of Persons fined by any Act since 12 Car. II. c. 11</emph>.</para>
<para id="p87">And alsoe except all such persons who being excepted out of the said Act of Generall Pardon have had any
pains or penalties imposed upon them by any subsequent Act of Parlyament</para>
<para id="p88"><emph type="i">Of all &pound;500 Penalties for holding Office, &amp;c. contrary to 25 Car. II. c. 2</emph>.</para>
<para id="p89">And alsoe excepted out of this Act all Penalties of five hundred pounds which shall by any Act passed in this
Session of Parlyament be inflicted or appointed to be levyed upon any person or persons for or in respect of
holding or exerciseing any Office or Place and offending contrary to an Act of Parlyament made in the five and
twentyeth yeare of the Raigne of King Charles the Second Entituled An Act for preventing Dangers which
may happen from Popish Recusants,</para>
<para id="p90"><emph type="i">Of particular Persons</emph>.</para>
<para id="p91">Except alsoe out of this present Act<br/>
William Marquesse of Powis<br/>
Theophilus Earle of Huntington<br/>
Robert Earle of Sunderland<br/>
John Earle of Melfort<br/>
Roger Earle of Castlemain<br/>
The Lord Thomas Howard<br/>
Nathaniell Lord Bishop of Durham<br/>
Thomas Lord Bishop of St. Davids<br/>
Henry Lord Dover<br/>
William Molineux<br/>
Sir Edward Hales<br/>
Sir Edward Herbert<br/>
Sir Francis Withens<br/>
Sir Richard Holloway<br/>
Sir Edward Lutwich<br/>
Sir Richard Heath<br/>
Sir Thomas Jenner<br/>
Sir Roger L'Estrange<br/>
Sir Nicholas Butler<br/>
Edward Petre<br/>
Thomas Tindesley alias Tildesley<br/>
&mdash;Townley lately called Collonel
Townley<br/>
Rowland Tempest<br/>
Edward Morgan<br/>
Obadiah Walker<br/>
Robert Brent<br/>
Richard Grajam<br/>
Phillip Burton<br/>
Robert Lundy<br/>
Mathew Crone<br/>
And alsoe excepted George Lord Jeffreys
deceased</para>
<para id="p92"><emph type="i">Of Crimes against 27 El. c. 2</emph>.</para>
<para id="p93">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all and every Offence and Offences committed or done by any Jesuite
Seminary or Romish Priests whatsoever contrary to the tenor or effect of the Statute made in the seven and
twentyeth yeare of the Raigne of the late Queene Elizabeth Entituled An Act against Jesuits Seminary Priests and
other Disobedient Persons or of any part thereof and all Outlawries Proceedings Judgments and Executions for
the same Offences or any of them</para>
<para id="p94"><emph type="i">Of Convictions of Recusants</emph>.</para>
<para id="p95">And except alsoe all Convictions of Popish Recusants for their Recusancy</para>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>X. Outlawry how reversed.</head>
<para id="p96">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That noe Processe of Outlawry or Proceedings
thereon at the Suite of any person Plaintiffe shall be by vertue of this Pardon stayed or avoided unlesse the
Defendant appeare and putt in Baile where by Law Baile is necessary and take forth a Writt of Scire facias
against the partie at whose Suite he was outlawed and that this Pardon be not allowed to discharge any Outlawry
after Judgment till Satisfaction or Agreement be made to or with the partie at whose Suite the Outlawry was obtained</para>
</section>
<section id="s11">
<head>XI. This Pardon may be given in Evidence.</head>
<para id="p97">And it is further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That every person or persons hereby pardoned may plead
the Generall Issue without Speciall Pleading of this Pardon and give this Act of Pardon in Evidence for his
discharge and that the same shall be thereupon allowed and the advantage thereof had as fully to all intents and
purposes as if the same had beene fully and well pleaded and in such manner as any Justice of Peace Constable
or any other Officer questioned for Matters acted by them as Officers may have the advantage of the Matter of
their Justification upon the Generall Issue by them pleaded by the Laws and Statutes of this Realme</para>
</section>
<section id="s12">
<head>XII. Good against the King's Grantee.</head>
<para id="p98">And Bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That this present Pardon shall be of as good force and
effect to pardon and discharge all and singular the Premisses above mentioned and intended to be pardoned and
discharged as well against such person or persons Bodyes Politick and Corporate as doe or shall claime the same
by or under any Letters Patents Lease or Grant by the King and Queens Majestyes or any their Predecessors as
against the King and Queens Majestyes themselves</para>
</section>
<section id="s13">
<head>XIII. Exception of Persons levying War against their Majesties, &amp;c. unless they take the Oath.</head>
<para id="p99">Provided That nothing in this Act contained shall extend to pardon or discharge any person of or for any
counselling contriveing abetting or procureing the Raising of Warr or Rebellion against their Majestyes or adhereing
to their Enimies since the thirteenth day of February in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred eighty
and eight unlesse such person shall and doe before the twentyeth day of July next or sooner if required take
the following Oath publickly and duly in such Court and before such persons as have or shall have power to
administer the same viz<emph type="p">t</emph>.<br/>
I A B doe sincerely promise and sweare That I will be faithfull and beare true Allegiance to their Majestyes
King William and Queene Mary<br/> Soe helpe me God.</para>
</section>
<section id="s14">
	<head>ITEM qued&amacr; Petitiones privatas personas concernentes (in se forma&amacr; Actus continentes) exhibite fuerunt predicto Domino
Regi in Parliamento predicto quor&umacr; Tituli subscribuntur.</head>
<para id="p100">An Act for separateing and makeing the Chappell of Wortenbury a distinct Church from the Parish Church of Bangor.</para>
<para id="p101">An Act to supply a defect in a former Act of the last Parliament for the sale or leasing of a house late Henry
Coventryes Esquire in Pickadilly.</para>
<para id="p102">An Act to enable John Wolstenholm Esquire to sell Lands for payment of debts.</para>
<para id="p103">An Act to illegitamate any Childe or Children which Jane the Wife of John Lewknor Esq[uire] hath had or shall
have dureing her elopement from him.</para>
<para id="p104">An Act to enable Algernoon Earle of Essex to make a wife a Joynture and for raising of moneys for payment of
Six thousand pounds borrowed to make up the Lady Morpeths portion and to make a Settlement of his estate on
his marriage.</para>
<para id="p105">An Act for the makeing some provision for the daughters and younger sonnes of Anthony Earle of Shaftsbury.</para>
<para id="p106">An Act for the sale of the capitall Messuage or Mansion House of Harleford and Mannour of Great Marlow and
other Lands in the County of Bucks.</para>
<para id="p107">An Act to enable Sir Robert Fenwicke to sell Lands for payment of his debts.</para>
<para id="p108">An Act for confirming a Setlement made by Sir Hugh Midleton Baronet for a separate maintenance for Dame
Dorothea his wife and for other Trusts and for the better enableing Trustees to sell part of his Estate for payment
of his debts.</para>
<para id="p109">An Act whereby the Freehold and Inheritance of the Mannour of Loleworth alias Lollworth and the Advowson
of the Church of Loleworth alias Lollworth in the County of Cambridge and diverse other Lands and Hereditaments
in Loleworth aforesaid and in Long Stanton in the said County are vested in Altham Smith of Grays Inne in the
County of Midlesex Esq[uire] and William Gore of London Merchant and their heires in Fee Simple in possession to the
use of them and their heires in trust for John Edwards of Debdon Hall in the County of Essex Esq[uire] and his heires
to the intent the same may be sold.</para>
<para id="p110">An Act to enable Sir Humphry Forester to settle and dispose Lands.</para>
<para id="p111">An Act to enable Thomas Berenger Esquire to sell Lands for payment of his debts.</para>
<para id="p112">An Act to vest the Estate of Cadwallader Wynne Esq[uire] in Trustees for the payment of his debts.</para>
<para id="p113">An Act for the naturalizing of David Le Grand and others.</para>
<para id="p114">An Act for confirming to the Governour and Company tradeing to Hudsons Bay their Priviledges and Trade.</para>
<para id="p115">An Act for the encouraging and better establishing the manufacture of White paper in this Kingdome.</para>
<para id="p116">An Act to enable Sir Edwin Sadlier to sell Lands for payment of debts.</para>
<para id="p117">An Act for the granting unto Elizabeth relict of John Hobby Esquire and now the wife of the Lord Alexander
sonne and heire apparent of Henry Earle of Starling in the Kingdome of Scotland one Annuity or yearely RentCharge of foure hundred and fifty pounds for her life in satisfaction of five hundred pounds a yeare in Lands which
she was to have for her Joynture.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">Trespasse Entry <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">Treason <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n4" number="4">any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n5" number="5">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n6" number="6">received or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n8" number="8">be <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n9" number="9">Vizards <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


