<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46337" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1689</title>
<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for Reversing the Judgment in a Quo Warranto against the City of London and for Restoreing the City of London to its antient Rights and Priviledges. [Rot. Parl. pt. 1. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>Judgment of the Court of King's Bench in a Quo Warranto against the Mayor, &amp;c. of London, in Trinity Term 35 Car. II. recited.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">The said Judgment, and all the Judgments against the Charter of London, void; Vacates to be entered on the Roll</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">Whereas a Judgement was given in the Court of Kings Bench in or about Trinity Terme in the five
and thirtyeth yeare of the Raigne of the late King Charles the Second upon an Information in the
nature of a Quo Warranto exhibited in the said Court against the Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the
City of London That the Liberty Priviledge and Franchise of the said Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens being
a Body Politicke and Corporate should be seized into the Kings Hands as forfeited. And forasmuch as the said
Judgement and the Proceedings thereupon is and were illegall and arbitrary And for that the Restoreing of the
said Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens to their antient Liberties of which they had beene deprived tends very
much to the Peace and good Setlement of this Kingdome Bee it declared and enacted by the King and Queens
most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons
in this present Parliament assembled and by authoritie of the same That the said Judgement given in the said
Court of Kings Bench in the said Trinity Terme in the five and thirtyeth yeare of the Raigne of the said King
Charles the Second or in any other Terme And all and every other Judgement given or recorded in the said
Court for the seizing into the [said<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] late Kings Hands the Liberty Priviledge or Franchise of the Mayor and
Commonaltie and Citizens of the City of London of being of themselyes a Body Corporate and Politick by the
Name of the Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of London and by that Name to plead and be
impleaded and to answere and to be answered or in what manner or words soever such Judgement was entred is
shall be and are hereby reversed annulled and made void to all intents and purposes whatsoever and that Vacats
be entred upon the Rolls of the said Judgement for the Vacating and Reversall of the same accordingly</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Mayor, &amp;c. of the City of London to remain a Corporation; and to enjoy the Rights, &amp;c. which they had at the time of the said Judgment.</head>
<para id="p3">And bee it further declared and enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the Mayor and Commonaltie and
Citizens of the City of London shall and may for ever hereafter remaine continue and be and prescribe to be a
Body Corporate and Politick in re facto et nomine by the Name of Mayor and Commonaltie and Citizens of
the City of London and by that Name and all and every other Name and Names of Incorporation by which
they at any time before the said Judgement were incorporated to sue plead and be impleaded and to answere and
to be answered without any Seizure or Forejudger of the said Franchise Liberty and Priviledge or being thereof
excluded or ousted for or upon any pretence of any Forfeiture or Misdemeanour at any time heretofore or hereafter
to be done committed or suffered And the said Mayor and Commonaltie and Citizens of the said City shall and
may as by Law they ought peaceably have and enjoy all and every their Rights Gifts Charters Grants Liberties
Priviledges Franchises Customs Usages Constitutions Prescriptions Immunities Markets Duties Tolls Lands Tenements
Estates and Hereditaments whatsoever which they lawfully had or had lawfull Right Title or Interest of in or to
at the time of the recording or giveing the said Judgment or at the time or times of the said pretended
Forfeitures</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. Grants, &amp;c. by Car. II. and Jac. II. since the said Judgment, void.</head>
<para id="p4">And bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaide That all Charters Letters Patents and Grants for incorporating
the Citizens and Commonaltie of the said City or any of them and all Charters Grants Letters Patents and
Commissions touching or concerning any of their Liberties or Franchises or the Liberties Priviledges Franchises
Immunities Lands Tenements and Hereditaments Rights Title or Estates of the Mayor and Commonaltie and
Citizens of the City of London made or granted to any person or persons whatsoever by the late King Charles
the Second since the said Judgement given or by the late King James the Second be and are hereby declared
and adjudged null and void to all intents and purposes whatsoever</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>IV. Recoveries, &amp;c. in the Mayor's Court, &amp;c. since the said Judgment, good.</head>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">Persons not having qualified to act upon the said Charters, &amp;c. liable to Penalties</emph>.</para>
<para id="p6">Provided neverthelesse That noe Recoveries Verdicts Judgments Statutes Recognizances Inquisitions Indictments
Presentments Informations Decrees Sentences Executions nor any Plaints Processe or Proceedings in Law or Equity
had made given taken or done or depending in the Mayor or either of the Sheriffes Courts or any other Court
within the said City or Liberties thereof since the said Judgement given shall be avoided for want or defect of any
legall Power in those that acted as Judges Justices Officers or Ministers of in or as belonging to any of the said
Courts But that all and every such Recoveries Verdicts Judgments and other things above mentioned and the
Actings Doeings and Proceedings thereupon shall be of such and noe other force effect and vertue then as if such
Judges Justices Officers and Ministers had acted by vertue of legall authority and that noe person or persons shall
be in any wise prosecuted sued impeached or molested for any cause or thing by him or them lawfully acted or
done in pursuance of any such Charters Letters Patents Grants or Commissions Provided that this Act shall not
extend to discharge any person or persons from any penalty or penaltyes or forfeitures by him or them incurred
for not duely qualifying him or themselves to act upon the said Charters Letters Patents Grants or Commissions</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>V. Officers, so being at the Time of the Judgment, confirmed.</head>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">Exception; Officers chosen, &amp;c. since the said Judgment confirmed</emph>.</para>
<para id="p8">And bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That all Officers and Ministers of the said City that rightfully
held any Office or Place in the said City or Liberties thereof or in the Burrough of Southwarke at the time
when the said Judgement was given are hereby confirmed and shall have and enjoy the same as fully as they
held them at the time of the said Judgement given except such as have voluntarily surrendred any such Office
or Place or have beene removed for any just Cause and that every person who since the said Judgement given
hath beene chosen admitted and placed into any Office or Imployment within the said City upon the Death
Surrender or Removeall as aforesaid of the former Officer shall be and is hereby confirmed in his said Office
or Employment and shall have and enjoy the same in as full and ample manner as if he had beene admitted or
placed therein according to the antient Customs of the said City</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>VI. Leases, Grants, &amp;c. made since the said Judgment, good; and the Mayor, &amp;c. to have the Benefit thereof.</head>
<para id="p9">Provided alsoe and bee it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That all Leases and Grants of any of the
Lands Tenements Hereditaments and other things before the time of the said Judgement given belonging to the said Mayor
and Commonalty and Citizens and usually leased or granted by them made since the time of the said Judgment
given by the said late King Charles the Second or King James the Second or by any person or persons takeing
upon them to be Trustees for the said City for the preservation or maintenance of the Government or publick
Offices of the said City by or upon pretence of any Grant or Commission by their said late Majesties King Charles
the Second and King James the Second or either of them such Grants and Leases being made for just good and
valuable considerations and whereupon the old accustomed yearely Rent or more hath beene reserved payable
into the Chamber or Bridgehouse or any of the Hospitalls of the said City shall be as good and valid for
the Terms and under the Rents Payments Provisoes Conditions Covenants and Agreements therein respectively
contained against the Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the said City and their Successors as if the same
had beene made by the Mayor and Com[m]onaltie and Citizens of the said City under their Common Seale and the
said Judgment had never beene given and not otherwise And the said Mayor and Commonaltie and Citizens and
their Successors shall have the benefit and advantage of all Rents Reservations Payments Conditions Covenants
Clauses and Agreements in every such Grant or Lease contained and the like Remedy for Non-payment Breach or
Nonobservance thereof as if the said Grants or Leases had beene made by the said Mayor and Commonalty and
Citizens and the said Rents Payments Conditions Covenants Clauses and Agreements had beene made payable
reserved covenanted or agreed to and with the said Mayor and Commonaltie and Citizens</para>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>VII. Judgments, &amp;c. obtained by Trustees for Lands, &amp;c. of the said Corporation to remain in force.</head>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">Freedoms obtained since the said Judgment, good</emph>.</para>
<para id="p11">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That all Judgements Decrees and Sentences had or obtained
by any person or persons takeing upon them to be Trustees as aforesaid for or concerning any Lands Tenements
Duties Tolls and Interests whatsoever of or belonging to the said Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the said
City shall stand and remaine in force and shall be prosecuted and executed by and to and for the use of
the said Mayor and Commonaltie and Citizens as if the same had beene obtained in the Name of the said Mayor
and Commonalty and Citizens And that all persons being naturall borne Subjects or Denizens that have beene
admitted into the Freedome of the said City since the said Judgment given shall be free thereof and have and
enjoy the said Freedome to all intents and purposes as if they had beene thereunto admitted before the said
Judgment given</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>VIII. The present Mayor, &amp;c. to continue till new Election.</head>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">New Election of Mayor, Sheriffs, and Chamberlain, to be made on the 26th May 1690; of Common Council 10th June</emph>.</para>
<para id="p13">Provided alwayes That the present Mayor Sheriffes Chamberlaine and Common Councill of the said City shall
continue untill a new Election shall be made of such Officers and the persons elected sworne into their respective
Offices and that such new Election be made at the times hereafter mentioned that is to say the Election of the
Mayor and Sheriffes and Chamberlaine shall be made on the six and twentieth day of May in the yeare one
thousand six hundred and ninety And the Election of the Common Councill shall be made on the tenth day of
June in the yeare one thousand six hundred and ninety And such persons soe elected shall continue till the usuall
times of Election of such Officers according to the antient Usage and Custome of the said City and from thence
shall continue for the yeare ensueing</para>
</section>
<section id="s9">
<head>IX. If Election not made in time, Mayor, &amp;c. at the time of the Judgment, to continue till new Election.</head>
<para id="p14">Provided neverthelesse and Bee it enacted That if the Mayor Sheriffes Chamberlaine and Common Councill
shall not be elected at the times hereby limitted the Mayor Sheriffes Chamberlaine and Common Councill which
were in being at the time of the said Judgement given shall be and continue in those respective Offices and
places till new Elections be made of the like Officers and Common Councill according to the antient Usage and
Custome of the said City</para>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>X. Persons restored, &amp;c. to take Oaths required by 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 8.</head>
<para id="p15">And Bee it further enacted That all persons soe to be restored and continued shall be and are hereby required
to take the Oathes appointed by a certaine Act made in the first yeare of their Majesties Raigne Entituled An Act
for the Abrogating of the Oaths of Supremacie and Allegiance and appointing other Oaths the next Terme after
such Restitution under the Penalties Forfeitures Disabilities and Incapacities in the said Act provided and appointed</para>
</section>
<section id="s11">
<head>XI. Mayor, &amp;c. to be sworn as usual.</head>
<para id="p16">And Bee it enacted That the Mayor Sheriffes and Chamberlaine soe to be elected shall be sworne in usuall
manner on or before the twentyeth day of June next ensueing</para>
</section>
<section id="s12">
<head>XII. Companies restored.</head>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">Surrenders and Charters for new Incorporation by Car. II. and Jac. II. since the said Judgment, void; Proviso against Prosecutions in consequence of acting thereon</emph>.</para>
<para id="p18">And Bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That all and every of the severall Companies and Corporations
of the said City shall from henceforth stand and be incorporated by such Name and Names and in such sort and
manner as they respectively were at the time of the said Judgment given and every of them are hereby restored
to all and every the Lands Tenements Hereditaments Rights Titles Estates Liberties Powers Priviledges Precedences
and Immunities which they lawfully had and enjoyed at the time of giveing the said Judgment And that as
well all Surrenders as Charters Letters Patents and Grants for new incorporating any of the said Companies or
touching or concerning any of their Liberties Priviledges or Franchises made or granted by the said late King
James or by the said King Charles the Second since the giveing of the said Judgment shall be void and are hereby
declared null and void to all intents and purposes whatsoever Provided neverthelesse That noe person or persons
shall be in any wise prosecuted sued impeached or molested for any Cause or Thing by him or them lawfully
acted or done in pursuance of any such Charters Letters Patents or Grants</para>
</section>
<section id="s13">
<head>XIII. Leases, &amp;c. by the said Companies, made since the Judgment, good.</head>
<para id="p19">Provided also neverthelesse and it is hereby further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That all Leases Terms
and Estates made or granted by any of the said Companies since the giveing of the said Judgment for just and
valuable Considerations and whereupon the old accustomed yearly Rents or more are reserved shall stand and be
of the same force and effect as if the same had beene made or granted by the said severall Companies as hereby
restored and the said respective Companies and their Successors shall have the benefit and advantage of all Rents
Reservations Payments Conditions Covenants Clauses and Agreements in all and every such Lease or Grant
contained and the like remedy therefore as if the same Grants and Leases had beene made by the said respective
Companies as now restored and the said Rents Payments Conditions Covenants Clauses and Agreements had beene
made payable reserved convenanted and agreed to or with them respectively</para>
</section>
<section id="s14">
<head>XV. Freedoms of the said Companies good.</head>
<para id="p20">Provided alsoe and bee it enacted That all and every person and persons who at any time since the said
Judgment have beene admitted into the Freedoms or into the Liveryes of the said Companies according to the
Usages and Customs of the said City and their respective Companies shall be and enjoy all the Rights and
Priviledges of a Free man and of a Livery man to all intents and purposes as if they had beene admitted before the
said Judgment</para>
</section>
<section id="s15">
<head>XVI. Public Act.</head>
<para id="p21">Provided alwayes and be it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That this present Act of Parlyament shall be
accepted taken and reputed to be a Generall and Publick Act of Parliament Of which all and every the Judge and
Judges of this Kingdome in all Courts shall take notice on all Occasions whatsoever as if it were a publick Act
of Parlyament relating to the whole Kingdome any thing herein contained to the contrary thereof in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


