<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46338" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1689</title>
<subtitle>Chapter IX. An Act for the discouraging the Importation of Throwne Silke. [Rot. Parl. pt. 1. nu. 11.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">12 Car. II. c. 18; Thrown Silk no Manufacture within 12 Car. II. c. 18; Thrown Silk how imported; Ships importing how navigated; Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">Whereas the Importation of some sorts of Throwne Silke into this Realme is greatly prejudiciall to the
Exportation of the Woollen Manufactures thereof and tends very much to the Impoverishing great Numbers
of Artificers whose Livelyhood and Subsistance depends upon the Throwing of Raw Silke and if longer permitted
may endanger the Overthrowing of that Art or Mistery in this Nation And whereas of late great quantities of
Throwne Silke have beene imported from severall Parts and Places in Europe which are not the places of its
Growth or Production and thereby the true intent and meaning of the Act made in the twelfth yeare of King
Charles the Second Entituled An Act for the Encouragement and Increasing of Shipping and Navigation is evaded
For the prevention of which mischiefs and for the better Encouraging the severall Manufactures of this Kingdome
and of that usefull and Nationall Trade into Turkey and the better supporting the Art of Throwing Silke in this
Realme and the Poore therein employed Bee it declared and enacted by the King and Queens most excellent
Majestyes by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this
present Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That the Throwing of Silke is not nor ought
to be construed a Manufacture within the intention of the said Act for the Encouraging and Increasing of Shipping
and Navigation and that noe Throwne Silke of the Growth or Production of Turkey Persia East India or China
or of any other Country or place (except onely such Throwne Silke as is or shall be of the Growth or Production
of Italy Sicily or of the Kingdome of Naples and which shall be imported in such Shipps or Vessells and navigated
in such manner as in the said Act of Navigation is directed or allowed and brought from some of the Ports of
those Countryes or places whereof the same is of the Growth or Production and which shall come directly by
Sea and not otherwise) shall at any time after the five and twentyeth day of May in the yeare of our Lord one
thousand six hundred and ninety be brought or imported into the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales the
Islands of Jersey or Guernsey or the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede under the Penaltie and Forfeiture of all
such Throwne Silke soe imported contrary to the purport true intent and meaning of this Act one moyety whereof
shall be to the use of the King and Queens Majestyes their Heires and Successors and the other moyety thereof
to such person or persons as shall seize informe or sue for the same to be recovered by Bill Plaint Information
or other Action in any of their Majesties Courts of Record wherein noe Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law
shall be allowed</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Proviso for Thrown Silk from Italy, &amp;c. imported on or before 1st Sept. 1690.</head>
<para id="p3">Provided neverthelesse That this Act shall not extend to any Throwne Silke of the Growth or Production of
Italy Sicily or Kingdome of Naples that shall be brought in or imported into England otherwise then by this Act
is directed at or before the first day of September one thousand six hundred and ninety and which shall be
proved by the Oath of the Partie his Servant or Agent to whome the same doth belong or appertaine to have
beene provided and bought by his and their Order from England in some part or place in Italy Sicily or the
Kingdome of Naples at or before the first day of June one thousand six hundred and ninety which said Oath the
Commissioners of the Customs or any two of them for the time being are hereby impowered to administer</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. Proviso for Thrown Silk from India, &amp;c. imported on or before 20th Sept. 1691.</head>
<para id="p4">Provided alwayes That noe Throwne Silke laden in India Persia or China to be imported into England on or
before the twentyeth day of September one thousand six hundred ninety one shall be lyable to any Forfeiture by
vertue of this Act any thing to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
</section>
</report>


