<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46335" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1689</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the Exercise of the Government by her Majestie dureing his Majestyes Absence. [Chapter VI. Rot. Parl. pt. 1. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1"><emph type="i">1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 2.; The Queen shall govern in the King's Absence, in the Names of their Majesties; The King's Acts in his Absence good; The passing this Act or the King's Absence not to dissolve the Parliament</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act of Parlyament made in the first yeare of their Majestyes Raigne Intituled An Act
Declareing the Rights and Liberties of the Subject and Setleing the Succession of the Crowne It is
amongst other things enacted established and declared That the Crowne and Regall Government of the Kingdoms
of England and Ireland and the Dominions thereunto belonging shall be and continue to their said Majestyes and
the Survivour of them dureing their Lives and the Life of the Survivor of them and that the entire perfect and
full Exercise of the Regall Power and Government be onely in and executed by his Majestie in the Names of
both their Majestyes dureing their joynt Lives And whereas the King's most excellent Majestie hath resolved to
make a Royall Voyage and goe in Person into Ireland for the speedy and effectuall reduceing of that Kingdome
to its due Obedience to their Majestyes and hath likewise declared his pleasure to leave the Administration of
the Government in the Hands of the Queens most Excellent Majestie dureing his Absence out of this Kingdome
Bee it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the
same That whensoever and as often as it shall happen that his said Majestie shall be absent out of this Realme
of England It shall and may be lawfull for the Queens Majestie to exercise and administer the Regall Power
and Government of the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede and the
Plantations and Territories thereunto belonging in the Names of both their Majestyes for such time onely dureing
their joynt Lives as his said Majestie shall be absent or continue out of this Realme of England any thing in
the said Act to the contrary notwithstanding [Provided alwayes That nothing in this Act shall be taken or
construed to exclude or debarr his Majestie dureing such his absence out of this Realme from the Exercise or
Administration of any Act or Acts of Regall Power or Government within this Realme the Kingdome of Ireland
or any other their Majestyes Dominions whatsoever But that all and every such Act and Acts shall be as good
and effectuall as if his Majestie was within this Realme and shall not be contradicted or controlled but by his
Majestie onely And that neither the passing of this Act nor his Majestys Royall Voyage or Absence out of this
Realme shall be any way taken or construed to dissolve this present Parliament or avoid or determine any
Commission or Commissions which have beene or shall be granted by his or their Majesties Nor to avoid any
other Act or Acts of Government executed or to be executed by his Majestie</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. King, when in England, to have the sole Administration of Regal Power.</head>
		<para id="p3">Provided alwayes That as often as his Majesty shall returne into this Kingdome of England the sole Administration
of the Regall Power and Government thereof and all the Dominions Territories and Plantations thereunto belonging
or annexed shall be in his Majestie onely as if this Act had never beene made.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in separate Schedules.</note>
	</section>
</report>

