<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46341" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1690</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act concerning the Comissioners of the Admiralty.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>The Powers of Lord High Admiral may be executed by Commissioners.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas the Office of Lord High Admirall of England hath at sundry times and for severall yeares beene
executed and all the Authorities to the same belonging exercised by diverse Commissioners for that
purpose appointed by their Majestyes and the late Kings but of late some doubt hath risen whether certaine
Authorities belonging to the said Office of Lord High Admirall did or doe of Right belong to and might may or
ought to have beene or be exercised by such Com[m]issioners for the time being Now for avoiding all such
Doubts and Questions Bee it declared and enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majestyes by and
with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the authoritie of the same That all and singular Authorities Jurisdictions and Powers which by
any Act of Parliament or otherwise have beene and are lawfully vested setled and placed in the Lord High
Admirall of England for the time being have alwayes appertained to and of right might have beene and may and
shall be had enjoyed used exercised and executed by the Commissioners for executeing the Office of High Admirall
of England for the time being according to their Commissions to all intents and purposes as if the said
Co[m]issioners were Lord High Admirall of England.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. This Act gives no new Power.</head>
		<para id="p2">[Provided That nothing in this Act contained shall extend or be taken or construed to extend to give or
allow to the Lord High Admirall or to the Commissioners for executeing the Office of High Admirall any other
Authority Jurisdiction or Power then the Lord High Admirall lawfully had or might have had used and exercised
if this Act had not beene made.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Officers present at Trials under Commissions from Admiralty to take an Oath.</head>
		<para id="p3">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted That upon all Tryalls of Offenders by Courts Martiall to be held by vertue
of any Commission to be granted by the Lord High Admirall or the Commissioners for executing the Office of
High Admirall every Officer present shall before any Proceeding to Tryall take an Oath before the Court (which
Oath the Judge Advocate or his Deputy for the time being are hereby respectively authorized to administer) in
these words following</para>
		<para id="p4">The Oath.</para>
		<para id="p5">You shall well and truely try and determine the Matter now before you betweene our Soveraigne Lord and
Lady the King and Queens Majestyes and the Prisoner to be tryed</para>
		<para id="p6">Soe helpe you God.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in separate Schedules.</note>
	</section>
</report>


