<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46349" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1690</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for Granting to their Majesties severall Additional) Duties of Excise upon Beere Ale and other Liquors for foure yeares from the time that an Act for doubling the Duty of Excise upon Beere Ale and other Liquors dureing the space of one yeare doth expire. [Chapter X. Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	
		<section id="s2">
			<head>Reasons for the present Grant.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Additional Excise.; Beer above 6s. 1s. 6d. per Barrel.; Beer of or under 6s. 6d. per Barrel.; Vinegar, English, 3s. per Barrel.; Vinegar, Foreign, 8s. per Barrel.; Beer, &amp;c. imported, 6s. per Barrel.; Cider imported &pound;8 per Tun.; Brandy, single, imported, 4s. per Gallon.; Brandy, double, 8s. per Gallon.; Cider, &amp;c. retailed 2s. 6d. per Hogshead.; Metheglin, 6d. per Gallon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Most Gracious [Soveraigne<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]<br />Wee your Majestyes most Dutyfull and Loyall Subjects the Commons assembled in Parliament takeing into
serious Consideration the great and urgent Occasions which doe presse your Majestyes to an extraordinary
Expence of Treasure for the Defence of your Kingdomes and Dominions against Invasion and for preserveing to
your said Subjects the Intercourse of Trade for which purpose your Majestyes have found yourselves obliged to
equip and sett out to Sea a Royall Navy and to maintaine a Warr against the French King And in most thankfull
Acknowledgment of your Majestyes tender Care of the Welfare of your People and for the augmenting the Navall
Strength of this your Kingdome by building some new Shipps of War have chearfully and unanimously given and
granted and doe hereby give and grant to your Majesties the severall additionall Rates and Dutyes of Excise
herein after mentioned and doe most humbly beseech your Majestyes that it may be enacted And bee it
enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majestyes by and with the advice and consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Com[m]ons in this present Parlyament assembled and by authoritie of the same
That from and after the seventeenth day of November in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred
ninety one there shall be throughout your Majestyes Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of
Berwicke upon Tweede raised levyed collected and paid unto your Majestyes and your Successors dureing the space
and terme of foure yeares and noe longer for Beere Ale Cider and other Liquors herein after expressed by way
of Excise over and above all other Duties Charges and Impositions by any former Act or Acts (then unexpired)
sett and imposed and in manner and forme following (that is to say) For every Barrell of Beere or Ale above six shillings
the Barrell exclusive of the Duty of Excise brewed by the common Brewer or any other person or persons who doth
or shall sell or tapp out Beere or Ale publickly or privately to be paid by the Com[m]on Brewer or by such other
person or persons respectively and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity over and above the
Duties payable for the same one shilling six pence For every Barrell of Beere or Ale of six shillings the Barrell
or under brewed by the com[m]on Brewer or any other person or persons who doth or shall sell or tapp out Beere
or Ale publickly or privately to be paid by the said Com[m]on Brewer or by such other person or persons respectively
as aforesaid and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity over and above the Duties payable for the
same six pence For every Barrell of Vinegar or Vinegar Beere brewed or made of any English Materialls by any
Common Brewer or any other person for Sale to be paid by the Maker thereof and soe proportionably for a
greater or lesser quantity over and above the Duties of Excise payable for the same three shillings For every
Barrell of Vinegar or Liquor p[re]pared for Vinegar made here for Sale that hath runn through Rape or made with or
passing through any Forreigne Materialls or any mixture with Forreigne Materialls to be paid by the Maker therof and soe
proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity eight shillings For every Barrell of Beere Ale or Mum imported from beyond
the Seas or from the Islands of Guernsey or Jersey and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity to be paid
by the Importers before Landing over and above the Duties payable for the same six shillings For every Tun of
Cider or Perry Imported from beyond the Seas and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity to be paid
by the Importer before Landing over and above the Duties payable for the same eight pounds. For every Gallon
of single Brandy Spirits or Aqua vite Imported from beyond the Seas to be paid by the Importer before Landing
over and above the Duties payable for the same foure shillings For every Gallon of Brandy Spirits or Aqua vite
above proofe com[m]only called double Brandy imported from beyond the Seas to be paid by the Importer before
Landing over and above the Duties payable for the same eight shillings For all Cider and Perry made and sold
by Retaile upon every Hogshead to be paid by the Retailer thereof over and above the Duties payable for the
same and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser Measure two shillings six pence For all Metheglin or Mead
made for Sale whether by Retaile or otherwise to be paid by the Maker for every Gallon six pence</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>II. Duties levied as by</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">I. W. &amp; M. Sess. I. c. 24. and other Laws in force</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the severall Rates and Duties of Excise hereby
imposed on the Liquors aforesaid shall be raised levyed collected [recovered<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and paid unto their Majesties and their
Successors dureing the time before mentioned and in the same manner and forme and by such Rules Wayes and
Means and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are mentioned expressed and directed in and by one Act of
Parluiament made in the first yeare of their present Majesties Raigne Entituled An Act for an Additionall Duty of
Excise upon Beere Ale and other Liquors or by any other Law now in force relateing to the Revenue of
Excise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>III. Continuance of Excise under 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 24.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided that nothing in this Act contained shall be construed to continue the Duties of Excise granted by
an Act made in the First yeare of their Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for an Additionall Duty of Excise
upon Beere Ale and other Liquors or any other Duties of Excise upon Beere Ale or other Liquors for any longer
time then the same are respectively granted by the said Act or any other Act or Acts for that purpose</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>IV. Victuallers, &amp;c. may brew, paying the Excise;</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">free from Penalty of &pound;100 of c. 3. ante</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for any Victuallers or
Retailers or Common Brewers who for or within the space of one yeare before the seventeenth of November last
have not brewed their owne Beere and Ale to brew and make the strong Beere Small Beere or Ale [drank<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
consumed spent or sold in their respective Houses Outhouses or other places paying the Duty of Excise for the
same in manner as Brewers and Retailers of Beere and Ale brewing and makeing the same are lyable by the
Laws of Excise now in force And on their entring the Beere and Ale by them respectively made at the Excise
Office within the Limitts wherein such Beere and Ale shall be made And on the payment of the Duty of Excise
for the same such person and persons shall not be lyable to the Penalty of one hundred pounds imposed in an
Act made in this present Parliament Entituled An Act for doubling the Duty of Excise upon Beere Ale and other
Liquors dureing the space of one yeare Any thing in the same Act to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>V. 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 28. recited.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 24.; Appropriation of this and the Residue of the Excise before given by 1 W. &amp; M. c. 24. to the building Twenty-seven Men of War</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And whereas by an Act made in the first yeare of their Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for appropriating
certaine Duties for paying the States Generall of the United Provinces their Charges for his Majestyes Expedition
into this Kingdome and for other Uses the Money accruing and payable to their Majesties by force of another
Act made in the said first yeare of their Majesties Raigne Entituled An Act for an Additionall Duty of Excise
upon Beere Ale and other Liquors (together with other Money ariseing and payable by certaine other Acts of
Parliament) was appropriated for and towards the Payment of six hundred thousand pounds to the States of the
United Provinces And after the said six hundred thousand pounds soe paid the residue of the Money which should
accrue and be payable to their Majesties by vertue of the said Act to be for and towards the subdueing of the
Rebellion of Ireland and other Charges of the Warr against France And whereas the Encrease of the Navall
Strength and Force of this Kingdome is one of the best and most effectuall means for carrying on the Warr
against France and for maintaining the Honour and Safety of the Realme Bee it further enacted by the authority
aforesaid That all Moneys which shall accure and become payable to their Majestyes by vertue of the said Act
Entituled An Act for an Additionall Duty of Excise upon Beere Ale and other Liquors from and after the said
six hundred thousand pounds shall be paid to the (<emph type="p">4</emph>) States Generall and alsoe all Moneys to be collected levyed and
paid by vertue of this Act shall be applyed to the uses following (that is to say) the Summe of five hundred and
seventy thousand pounds part thereof shall be applyed and appropriated and is hereby appropriated for the Building
and for the Guns Rigging and other Furnishing of seven and twenty Shipps of Warr whereof seventeene to be
of the third Rate and to containe and measure eleven hundred Tuns or thereabouts and to carry eighty Guns
apiece and ten to be of the fourth Rate and to containe and measure nine hundred Tuns or thereabout and to
carry sixty Guns apiece</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VI. The said Ships to be built within Four Years.</head>
			<para id="p10">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the said seven and twenty Shipps of Warr hereby
directed to be built as aforesaid shall be and are hereby directed to be built and furnished with all convenient
Expedition the whole number to be completed with Guns Rigging and Furniture within the space of foure yeares
to be accounted from the five and twentyeth day of March one thousand six hundred ninety one</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VII. The Duties of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 24. and this Act to be kept separate, and paid Weekly into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p11">And to the end that the said five hundred and seventy thousand pounds may be applyed to the building and
furnishing of the said Shipps of Warr And alsoe that their Majestyes may be enabled to borrow upon the Credit
of this Act any Summe or Summs of Money not exceeding ten hundred thousand pounds for the Uses of
the said Warr Bee it further enacted That from and after the said six hundred thousand pounds shall be paid to
the said States Generall untill the eighteenth day of November which shall be in theyeare one thousand sixh undred
ninety five the Commissioners and Governours for the management of the Receipt of Excise at the Head Office in
London shall separate and keepe apart as well the said Moneys ariseing by vertue of the said Act Intituled An Act
for an Additionall Duty of Excise upon Beere Ale and other Liquors as the Moneys ariseing by vertue of this Act
as the same shall from time to time arise or be paid into the said Office of Excise by the Recievers or Collectors
of the same or by any other person whatsoever And the Auditor and Comptroller of the Excise for the time
being or their respective Deputies shall keepe a perfect and distinct Account in Books fairly written of the said
Moneys as the same shall come in to which Books all persons concerned shall have free accesse at all seasonable times
without Fee or Charge And the said Commissioners and Governours of Excise for the time being are hereby
required and strictly enjoyned from time to time to pay weekly, to witt on Wednesday in every Weeke if it be
not an Holy-Day and if it be then the next day after that is not an Holy-day the said Moneys into the Receipt
of their Majestyes Exchequer distinct and apart from the other Moneys which the said Commissioners and
Governours of Excise shall recieve for their Majestyes use</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>VIII. A separate Account thereof kept in the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p12">And it is further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the Officers of the Receipt of their Majestyes Exchequer
shall keepe all Moneys which shall be paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer by vertue of this Act or of the
said former Act and the Account thereof distinct from all other Moneys and Accounts whatsoever and shall alsoe
keepe a particular account of the Charge of the Building Guns Rigging and other Furnishing of each of the said
seven and twenty Shipps of Warr hereby directed to be built as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>IX. One Third part to be paid to the Treasurer of the Navy, &amp;c. Warrant for Payment to Treasurer of Navy, &amp;c. only.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Officers of the Exchequer not to pay, &amp;c. the same for any other Purpose</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And Bee it further enacted That out of the Moneys soe from time to time paid into the Receipt of their
Majesties Exchequer one third part thereof the whole in three equall parts to be divided shall in each and every
of the said yeares be issued and paid out for and towards the Building and for and towards the Guns Rigging
and other Furnishing of the said seven and twenty Shipps of Warr And that the Commissioners of the Treasury
or Lord Treasurer or Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being doe not signe any Warrant or Order or
doe any other matter or thing for the issuing of any part of the said one third part to any person or persons
other then the Treasurer of the Navy or the Treasurer or Paymaster of the Ordnance for the time being and
expressing therein that the same is for the Building or for the Guns Rigging or other Furnishing of the seven
and twenty Shipps of Warr above mentioned nor shall the Auditor of the Receipt draw any Order for the
issueing any part of the said one third part to any person or persons other then the Treasurer of the Navy or
Treasurer or Paymaster of the Ordnance as aforesaid nor shall he direct or the Clerke of the Pells Record or
the Teller make Payment of any part of the said one third part by vertue of any Warrant or upon any Order
or other Way or Device whatsoever other then to the persons and for the Uses aforesaid and to be soe mentioned
and expressed in such Warrant or Order</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>X. Treasurer of the Navy, &amp;c. may assign over the Third Part.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee.; Assignee may assign</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Treasurer of the Navy and the Treasurer or
Paymaster of the Ordnance respectively may assigne and transferr any part of the said One third part due and
payable to them upon any Order by Indorsment upon such Order which being notified and an Entry and
Memoriall thereof alsoe made in the Office of the Auditor of Receipt (which on Request he shall accordingly
make without Fee or Charge) shall entitle such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the benefit
of such Order or Orders or any part thereof and payment thereof And such Assignee may in like manner
assigne and so toties quoties And afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person or persons who have
or hath made such Assignments to make void release or discharge the same or the Moneys thereby due or any
part thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XI. Treasurer of the Navy to keep an Account of such Monies.</head>
			<para id="p17">And it is hereby further enacted That the Treasurer of the Navy and Treasurer or Pay Master of the Ordnance
for the time being shall keepe all Moneys paid to them respectively by vertue of this Act distinct and apart from
all other Moneys and issue and pay the same by Warrant of the principall Officers and Commissioners of the Navy
or Ordnance respectively or any three or more of them and mentioning and expressing that it is for the Building
or for the Guns Rigging or other Furnishing of the Seven and twenty Shipps of Warr as aforesaid and to noe
other intent or purpose whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XII. Principal Officers of the Navy, &amp;c. to sign Bills only for building, &amp;c. the said Ships.</head>
			<para id="p18">And it is further enacted That the principall Officers and Commissioners of the Navy and the principall Officers
of the Ordnance respectively or any three or more of them shall not signe any Warrant or Navy Bill or doe any
other Act or Thing for the issueing and paying any of the said Moneys to any use intent or purpose whatsoever
other then for the Building or for the Guns Riging or other furnishing of the seven and twenty Shipps of Warr
as aforesaid and to be soe mentioned and expressed in such Warrant or Navy Bill</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIII. Clause of Credit for &pound; 1,000,000 upon the Two Thirds.</head>
			<para id="p19">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any person
and persons Natives or Foreigners Bodies Politicke or Corporate to advance and lend to their Majesties into the
Receipt of the Exchequer upon the Credit of two third parts the whole in three equall parts to be divided of
the Moneys to be brought in to the Receipt pursuant to the directions of this Act as aforesaid any Summe or
Summes of Money not exceeding the Su[m]me of ten hundred thousand pounds in the whole and to have and recieve
for the Forbearance thereof Interest not exceeding the rate of seven pounds by the hundred for one yeare</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XIV. Entry of Monies distinct.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Tally, Orders, &amp;c. granted to Lenders.; Orders for Repayment registered and paid in course.; No Fee, &amp;c. for providing, &amp;c. Books, nor for View or Search; Penalty.; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty.; By Deputy; Penalty.; Auditor, &amp;c. offending; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And to the end that all Moneys which shall be soe lent to their Majesties may be well and sufficiently secured
out of and by the Moneys ariseing by this or the said former Act and appointed by this present Act to be paid
into the Exchequer as aforesaid (other then and besides the said one third part appropriated as aforesaid) together
with the Interest for the Money soe lent not exceeding the rate aforesaid Bee it further enacted by the authority
aforesaid That there shall be provided and kept in their Majestyes Exchequer (that is to say) in the Office of
the Auditor of the Receipt one Booke in which all Moneys which shall be paid into the Exchequer as aforesaid
shall be entred apart and distinct from all other Moneys paid or payable to their Majestyes upon any accompt
whatsoever And that all and every Person and Persons Natives or Forreigners Bodies Politicke or Corporate who
shall lend any Money to their Majestyes upon the Credit of this Act and pay the same into the Receipt of the
Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally of Loane strucke for the same and an Order for his or their Repayment
beareing the same Date with the Tally in which Order shall be alsoe contained a Warrant for Payment of Interest
for Forbearance not exceeding the Rate aforesaid for his or their Consideration to be paid every three months
untill Repayment of the Principall and that all Orders for Repayment of Money shall be registred in course
according to the Date of the Tally respectively without preference of one before another and that all and every
person and persons shall be paid in course according as their Orders shall stand entred in the said Register Booke
soe as that the person Native or Forreigner his her or their Executors Administrators and Assignes who shall
have his her or their Order or Orders first entred in the said Booke shall be taken and accounted as the first
person to be paid upon the Moneys to come in by vertue of this Act (other then and besides the said one
third part appropriated as aforesaid) And he or they who shall have his or their Order or Orders next entred
shall be taken and accounted to be the second person to be paid and soe successively and. in course and that
the aforesaid two third parts (the whole in three equall parts being divided) of all the Moneys before mentioned
shall be in the same Order lyable to the satisfaction of the said respective Parties their Executors Administrators
or Assignes successively without preference of one before another and not otherwise and not to be divertible to
any other use intent or purpose whatsoever and that noe Fee Reward or Gratuity directly or indirectly be
demanded or taken of any of their Majestyes Subjects for providing or makeing of any such Books Registers
Entryes View or Search as aforesaid by any of their Majestyes Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputyes on paine
of Payment of treble Damages to the Partie grieved by the Partie offending with Costs of Suit Or if the Officer
or Officers themselves take or demand any such Fee or Reward then to lose their places alsoe and if any undue
preference of one before another shall be made either in point of Registry or Payment contrary to the true
meaning of this Act by any such Officer or Officers then the Partie offending shall be lyable by Action of Debt
or on the Case to pay the value of the Debt Damages and Costs to the Partie grieved and shall be forejudged
from their Places or Offices And if such preference be unduely made by any their Deputies or Clerks without
direction or privity of the Officer or Officers then such Deputy or Clerke onely shall be lyable to such Action Debt
Damages and Costs and shall be for ever after uncapeable of his Place or Office And in case the Auditor shall
not direct the Order or the Clerke of the Pells Record or the Teller make payment according to each Persons
due Place and Order as afore directed then he or they shall be judged to forfeite and their respective Deputies
and Clerks herein offending to be lyable to such Action Debt Damages and Costs in such manner as aforesaid All
which said Penalties Forfeitures Damages and Costs to be incurred by any of the Officers aforesaid or any their
Deputies or Clerks shall and may be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of Their
Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection Priviledge Wager of Law Injunction
or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise granted or allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XV. Payment of any Tally of same Date not undue Preference.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Paying subsequent Orders where first not demanded how far not undue Preference</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby declared That if it happen that severall Tallies of Loane or Orders for
payment as aforesaid beare Date or be brought the same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be Registred then
it shall be interpreted noe undue Preference which of those he Enters first soe he Enters them all the same day
Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpreted any undue p[re]ference to incurr any Penalty in point of payment
if the Auditor direct and the Clerke of the Pells record and the Teller doe pay subsequent Orders of persons
that come and demand their Money and bring their Order in their course soe as there be soe much Money
reserved as will satisfie precedent Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them (Interest upon
Loane being to cease from the time the Money is soe reserved and kept in Banke for them)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVI. Order for Repayment transferrable.</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">Memorial without Fee.; Assignee may assign.; Commissioners, &amp;c. neglecting to pay, or misapplying Monies; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every person and persons to whome any
Moneys shall be due by vertue of this Act after Order entred in the Booke of Register aforesaid for payment
thereof his Executors Administrators or Assignes by indorsment of his Order may assigne and transferr his Right
Title Interest and Benefitt of such Order or any part thereof to any other which being notified in the Office
of the Auditor of the Receipt aforesaid and an Entry or Memoriall thereof alsoe made in the said Booke of
Register for Orders (which the Officers shall upon request without Fee or Charge accordingly make) shall Entitle
such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the Benefitt thereof and payment thereon And such
Assignee may in like manner assigne againe and soe toties quoties And afterwards it shall not be in the power
of such person or persons who have or hath made such Assignments to make void release or discharge the same
or any the Moneys thereby due or any part thereof And if the said Com[m]issioners or Governours of the Excise for
the time being shall refuse or neglect to pay into the Exchequer the said Moneys in such manner as they are
before required or enjoyned to doe or shall divert or misapply any part of the same Or if any [other<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Officer
mentioned in this Act of or belonging to the Exchequer Navy or Ordnance shall offend against this Act or any
Clause thereof by diverting or misapplying any Moneys whatsoever contrary to the true intent and meaning of this
Act That then such Commissioner Governour or Officer soe refuseing or neglecting to pay or diverting or
misapplying as aforesaid shall forfeit and lose his Office or Place and is hereby disabled and made uncapable to
hold or execute any Office or Place of Trust for the future and shall be lyable to pay the full value of any
Summe or Summes soe diverted or misapplyed unto any person or persons who will sue for the same by
any Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of their Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster
wherein noe Essoigne Protection Priviledge Wager of Law or more then one Imparlance shall be granted or
allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVII. No Stay of Prosecution in Actions for Penalties.</head>
			<para id="p26">Provided alsoe and bee it Enacted That noe stay of Prosecution upon any Command Warrant Motion Order
or Direction by Non vult ulterius prosequi shall be had made admitted recieved or allowed by any Court
whatsoever in any Suite or Proceeding by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information or otherwise for the recovery
of all or any the pains forfeitures or penalties upon any person or persons by this Act inflicted or therein
mentioned or for or in order to the Conviction or Disability of any person offending against this Act</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XVIII. c. 4. ante, &sect; 57.</head>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">c. 5 ante.; An Office of Receipt for Customs given formerly upon East India Goods and Tobacco, &amp;c. to be in London.; Receiver General to keep apart the Duties of c. 4. and c. 5. ante; and so to remain after Payments thereout herein mentioned.; Comptroller General of the Customs to keep distinct Accounts.; Receiver General to pay into the Exchequer weekly.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p28">And whereas by an Act made in this present Session of Parliament Entituled An Act for granting to Their
Majesties certaine Impositions upon all East India Goods and Manufactures and upon all Wrought Silks and
severall other Goods and Merchandize to be Imported after the Five and twentyeth day of December One
thousand six hundred and ninety It is Enacted That it shall be lawfull for any person or persons to advance
and lend to Their Majestyes any Summe or Summes of money upon the Security of the said Act and whereas
by another Act made in this p[re]sent Session of Parlyament Entituled An Act for the Continuance of severall former
Acts therein mentioned for the laying severall Duties upon Wines Vinegar and Tobacco It is Enacted That it shall
be lawfull for any person or persons to advance and lend to Their Majestyes any Summe or Summes of money as
well upon the Security of the same Act as upon the Security of two former Acts therein mentioned made in the
Raigne of the late King James in such manner as in the said last mentioned Act made in this present Session
of Parlyament is expressed Now to the end that it may appeare what moneys shall arise or become payable to
Their Majesties by vertue of the said Acts whereby the moneys advanced to Their Majesties upon the Credit of
the same may be the better secured Bee it Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That from and after the Five and
twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred and ninety dureing the continuance of the said Acts
respectively there shall be continued and be within the City of London an Office for the Receipt of all the Duties
and Sum[m]s of Money granted or payable to Their Majesties by vertue of the (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) last mentioned Acts or either of them
In which Office all the Moneys ariseing by the same within the Port of London or in the Out-Ports or elsewhere
shall be well and truely answered and paid to the Reciever or Recievers Generall of Their Majestyes Customs to
be appointed by Their Majesties Which said Reciever or Recievers Generall is and are hereby directed and
required from time to time at the said Office to separate and keepe apart the whole Receipt of the said Moneys
due and payable by vertue of the said Act Intituled An Act for granting to Their Majesties certaine. Impositions
upon all East India Goods and Manufactures and upon all Wrought Silks and severall other Goods and Merchandize
to be Imported after the Five and twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred and ninety As alsoe to
separate and keepe apart the whole Reciept of all Moneys granted to Their Majestyes by the said Act intituled
An Act for the Continuance of severall former Acts therein mentioned for the laying severall Duties upon Wine
Vinegar and Tobacco or thereby made a Fond of Credit as aforesaid as the same shall respectively become due
and be paid into the said Office by the severall Recievers Collectors or any others who are or shall be imployed
to pay the same and shall remaine from time to time after the payments which shall be made thereout by
vertue of any Laws in force upon Debentures for Goods that shall be Reshipt or for Corne exported or for
Discounts upon Bonds where Discounts are allowable by Law and of such allowances of damaged Goods and of
Bills of Portage as have usually beene made And the Comptroller Generall of the Accounts of the Customs
for the time being is hereby alsoe required and commanded to keepe perfect and distinct Accounts in Books
fairly written of the said severall and respective Duties and Summs of Money as the same shall respectively
come in to which Books all persons concerned shall have free accesse at all seasonable times without Fee or
Charge And the said Receiver or Recievers Generall is and are hereby required and strictly enjoyned from time
to time to pay weekly to witt on Wednesday in every Weeke unlesse it be an Holy-day and then the next Day
after which shall not be an Holy-day the said severall and respective Sums as aforesaid into the Receipt of
Their Majestyes Exchequer distinct and apart from all the other Moneys which he or they shall receive for Their
Majestyes use And if the Reciever or Recievers Generall for the time being shall refuse or neglect to pay into
the Receipt of the Exchequer the said Sums of Money ariseing as aforesaid in such manner as he or they are
before required or enjoyned to doe or shall divert or misapply any part of the same then he or they for any
such Offence shall forfeit his or their Office of Reciever or Recievers Generall and be incapable of any Office
Employment or place of Trust whatsoever and shall be lyable to pay the full value of any Summe or Summes
soe diverted or misapplyed to any person or persons who shall sue for the same by any Action of Debt Bill
Plaint or Information in any of Their Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection
Wager of Law or Priviledge or more than one Imparlance shall be granted or allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XIX. Appropriation of the Residue of the Money of this Act to the Navy and building Three Ships of War;</head>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">and to the Ordnance of the Navy.; Appropriation of Monies granted by this or any other Act, except</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p30">And bee it Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That out of the Money which shall be levyed and paid by
vertue of this Act into the Receipt of the Exchequer as well upon Loane as otherwise the Summe of Seven
hundred thousand pounds shall be applyed and appropriated and is hereby appropriated to and for the payment
of Seamen that shall serve in Their Majestyes Navy Royall for the yeare One thousand six hundred ninety one
And to and for the building of Three Shipps to be of the Third Rate to containe and measure each of them One
thousand and fifty Tunns and for providing Guns Rigging and other Furniture for the said Shipps And to
and for the paying for Stores Provisions and Victualls to be supplyed for the said Navy And to and for the
Expences of Their Majestyes Office of Ordnance in respect to Navall Affaires and for other necessary Uses and
Services to be performed for the said Navy in the time aforesaid And that out of all other the Money which
shall be levyed and paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer as well upon Loane as otherwise by vertue of
this Act or any other Act of this Session of Parlyament for granting aids or supplyes to Their Majestyes for
Reduceing Ireland or prosecuting the Warr against France (other then what is as aforesaid appropriated by this</para>
		
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">c. 1. ante,; to the Navy,; to the Army; to the Prosecution of the War against France and reducing Ireland</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p32">Act and the Act For Granting an Aid to Their Majesties of the Summe of Sixteene hundred fifty one thousand
seven hundred and two pounds eighteene shillings for the payment of Seamen and other payments relating to
Their Majestyes Navy) the Summe of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds shall be applyed and appropriated and is
hereby appropriated to and for [the payment of<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Their Maj&egrave;sties Land-Forces and Armies that have served
and shall serve in England or Ireland or elsewhere and the paying for Arms Ammunition Carriages and all
incident Charges necessary to the same and not otherwise And that all other Sum[m]s of Money paid and payable
into the Exchequer by vertue of any of the said Acts over and above the Summs appropriated to and for the
uses therein expressed dureing their respective continuance shall be applyed and appropriated to and for the
prosecution of the said Warr against France and the Reduceing Ireland and the payment of the Debts that shall be
incurred by reason of the said Warr and to noe other use or purpose whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XX. The said three Ships of War to be built in a Year.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That the said Three Shipps of Warr herein last mentioned to be built
shall be and are hereby directed to be built and compleated with Guns Rigging and other Furniture within the
space of One yeare to be accounted from the Twentyeth day of March next ensueing</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXI. Their Majesties may dispose of &pound;500,000 not appropriated.</head>
			<para id="p34">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for Their Majestyes to
make use of any summe or summes of Money not exceeding Five hundred thousand pounds in the whole
granted in this present Sessions of Parliament and not particularly appropriated soe as the same be repaid and
applyed to the carrying on of the present Warr out of such Moneys as shall arise from Their Majesties Revenue
before the Foure and twentieth day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and one
Any thing to the contrary thereof notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Sovereignes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">drunk <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		
	</section>
</report>

