<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46347" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1690</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. All Act for Paveing and Cleansing the Streets in the Cityes of London and Westminster and Suburbs and Liberties thereof and Out-Parishes in the County of Midlesex and in the Burrough of Southwarke and other places within the Weekly Bills of Mortality in the County of Surrey and for Regulating the Markets therein mentioned.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that 13 &amp; 14 Car. II. c. 2. is expired.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this Act.; Inhabitants in Middlesex, Borough of Southwark, &amp;c. shall sweep the Streets twice a Week.;
Penalty 3s. 4d. Casting Ashes, &amp;c. into the Street; Penalty 5s.; But shall keep the Ashes, &amp;c. until the Scavenger arrives; Penalty 20s</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an Act was made at a Parlyament held at Westminster in the thirteenth and fourteenth years
of the Raigne of his late Majesty King Charles the Second for the repairing the Highwayes and Sewers
and for paveing and keeping cleane the Streets in and about the Cities of London and Westminster wherein
(amongst other things) many necessary and wholsome provisions were made for the cleansing and paveing the
said Streets and other Parishes and Places comprized within the Weekly Bills of Mortality which said Act being
since expired many persons in the Out-Parishes in Midlesex and other Parishes in the Limitts aforesaid which
have beene chosen to serve the Office of Scavenger refuse to take the Execution of the said Office upon them
and others who have beene rated and assessed towards the cleansing and carrying away the Dirt and Soile out
of the Streets have refused to pay the Rates assessed upon them there being noe Law in force to compell them thereunto
soe that noe person can be imployed to be Raker to carry the Dirt out of the said Streets for want of some
provision for payment for doeing that Service and the poorer sort of People dayly throw into the said Streets all
the Dirt Filth and Coale-Ashes made in their Houses By reason whereof the said Streets are become extreamly
dirty and filthy soe that their Majestyes Subjects cannot conveniently passe through the same about their lawfull
Occasions and many other Inconveniences dayly arise for want of the like provisions in other Cases relateing to the
Street Pavements and Common Wayes May it therefore please your most excellent Majestyes That it may be
enacted And bee it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majestyes by and with the advice and consent of
the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authority of the
same That from and after the fifteenth day of December one thousand six hundred and ninety all and every
person and persons inhabiting in the said Parishes in Midlesex and Westminster and the Liberties thereof and in
the Burrough of Southwarke or in any of the said Streets Lanes or Alleys comprised within the Weekly Bills of
Mortality and the Towne of Kensington [shall twice in every Weeke<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] (that is to say on every Wednesday and
Saturday at the least sweepe and cleanse or cause to be swept and cleansed all the Streets Lanes Alleys and
publique places before their respective Houses Buildings and Walls and the Buildings and Walls of Churches and
other publicke places to the end the Dirt and Soile in the said Streets may be ready for the Scavenger Baker
or other Officer appointed for that purpose to carry away upon paine to forfeit three shillings and foure pence for
every Offence or Neglect respectively And that noe person or persons whatsoever shall throw cast or lay or cause
permitt or suffer to be thrown cast or laid any Sea-Coal Ashes Dust Dirt Rubbish Dung or other Filth or
Annoyance in any open Streete Lane or Alley within the said City or places aforesaid before his her or their owne
Dwellinghouses Stables Buildings or Walls or the Buildings and Walls of Churches Church Yards and other
publique places on the Penalty of five shillings And noe person or persons shall lay any Ashes Dirt or Soile
before the Houses Buildings or Walls of any person or persons Inhabitants of the City Parishes or Pallaces aforesaid
or before or against any Church Church Yard Wall or any of their Majestyes Buildings Pallaces or Places
whatsoever Or shall cast lay or throw or cause to be cast laid or throwne into any Common or Publique
Sincke Vault Watercourse or Co[m]mon Sewer or Highway within any of the Parishes or Places aforesaid or any other
private Vault or Sinck of any of the Inhabitants aforesaid any Ashes Dirt Filth Ordure or any other noysome thing
whatsoever but shall keepe or cause the same to be kept in their respective Houses Yards or Backsides or the
Yards or Backsides of Churches and other Publicke Buildings untill such time as the Raker Scavenger or other
Officer thereto appointed of the said Ward Parish Streete or Place where they dwell or such Churches or Buildings
as doe come by or neere their Houses Doores or Places with his Cart Barrow or other thing or things used for
the cleansing the Streets and carrying away thereof and then shall carry or cause to be carried the said Ashes
Dirt Dung or other such Filth or Annoyance aforesaid out of their Houses Yards and Backsides and deliver
it unto the Raker Scavenger or other Officer or otherwise to putt the same into his Cart Barrow or other thing
as aforesaid upon paine to forfeit the Summe of twenty shillings for every such Offence</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Churchwardens, &amp;c. liable to the Penalties for such Offences before</head>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Churches and other Public Buildings</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the respective Churchwardens and the Housekeepers
and other Keepers of Whitehall Somersett House Saint James House and Saint James's Parke and the Guard-houses
and Stables neare it and other their Majestyes Houses and the Ushers Porters or Keepers of Courts of Justice and
and all other Publique or other Houses [or<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Places respectively shall be lyable to and suffer the like Penalties
Forfeitures and Punishments for every the before-mentioned Offences or Neglects done committed or suffered to be
done before any Church or Church Yard or before any of their Majestyes Houses Buildings or Walls or before any
Houses Buildings or Walls or before any Publicke Buildings Houses or Places whatsoever</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Hooping Barrels, &amp;c. placing rough Timber, &amp;c. to be sawn;</head>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">Penalty 20s</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That from and after the said fifteenth day of December
noe person or persons shall hoope wash or cleanse any Pipes Barrells or other Casks or Vessells in any [of<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] the Streets
Lanes or open Passages aforesaid nor shall sett out any Dung Soile Rubbish or empty Coaches to make or
mend or rough Timber or Stones to be sawne or wrought in the Streets on the Penalty of twenty shillings for
every Offence.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Scavengers to carry away all Dirt, &amp;c.;</head>
		<para id="p7">
			<emph type="i">to have a Bell, &amp;c.; Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p8">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the Rakers Scavengers or other Officers therunto
appointed every day in the Weeke except Sundayes and other Holy dayes shall bring or cause to brought Carts
Dung-Potts and other fitting Carriages into all their respective Parishes Limitts Precincts Streets Charges and
Divisions where such Carts and Carriages can passe and at or before their approach by a Bell Horne or Clapper
or otherwise shall make distinct and loud Noise and give notice to the Inhabitants thereof of their comeing and
make the like Noise and give the like Notice in every Court Alley or Place unto which the said Carts cannot
passe and abide and stay there a convenient time in such sort that all persons concerned may bring forth their
respective Dust Dirt Ashes Filth and Soyle to the respective Carts and Carriages soe staying as aforesaid all
which the said Rakers Scavengers or other Officers aforesaid shall dayly carry or cause to be carryed away upon
paine to forfeite forty shillings for every such Offence or Neglect respectively</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. Paved Streets, &amp;c. to be kept in Repair;</head>
		<para id="p9">
			<emph type="i">Mode in which same to be done</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p10">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That all open Streets Lanes and Alleys which now are
paved within any of the Parishes or places aforesaid shall be from time to time repaired amended and paved at
the Costs and Charges of the Householders Inhabitants in any such Streets and Lanes respectively and where any
Houses shall be empty and unoccupied in any such Streets and Lanes then to be paved and repaired at the
Charge of the Owners or Proprietors thereof in manner following (that is to say) Every of the said Housholders
Owners or Proprietors of Houses to repaire pave and keepe repaired amended and paved the Streets Lanes or
Alleys before his House Stables or Outhouses soe farr as his Houseing Walls or Buildings extend unto the
Denter Stone Channell or midle of the same Streete Lane or Alley upon paine to forfeit twenty shillings for
every Perch or Rodd and after that Rate for a greater or lesser quantity for every default and of twenty shillings
a Weeke for every Weeke after untill the same shall be sufficiently paved and amended</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. Justice of Peace may order new Streets, &amp;c. to be paved.</head>
		<para id="p11">
			<emph type="i">Certificate to Quarter Sessions.; Inhabitants, &amp;c. thereupon to pave in front, &amp;c.; Penalty 40s. per Perch per Week.; Ancient Streets paved as formerly</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p12">And whereas there are in the Parishes aforesaid many new Streets and Wayes made which are fitt and convenient
to be paved with Stones but for want of good Order therein are almost unpassable to Passengers Bee it enacted
by the authoritie aforesaid. That it shall and may be lawfull for any one or more Justice or Justices of the
Peace of the Place or Division where any new Streets or Wayes are or shall be made from time to time to
view and inspect the same and if upon such View they shall judge them fitt to be paved or otherwise amended
to certifie the same under their Hands to the Justices of the Peace at the next respective Generall Quarter Sessions
of the Peace for the Place where such Streets or Wayes are or shall be made who are hereby respectively
thereupon authorized and required to take such Order for the paveing or otherwise amending the same as they
shall thinke fitt And all and every person and persons Owners and Inhabitants of all and every the Houses new
built or hereafter to be built or adjoyning to any new Streets or Wayes adjudged to be paved or amended shall
and are hereby required according to their severall and respective Interests therein by Order of such Justices at
their Session and by a time in such Order limitted pave with Stone or Gravell or otherwise amend all the
Ground that doth or shall lye in Front before every Dwellinghouse or other Buildings in such Streets and Wayes
extended to the midle of the Way that doth or shall lye before the same And every person offending herein
or that shall not from time to time repaire and amend his or her proportion of the Pavements in such Streets
and Ways where they shall be paved shall forfeit forty shillings for every such Offence or Default for every
Perch and after that Rate for a greater or lesser quantity and the like Sum[m]e for every Weeke till the same be
paved or amended and repaired and when paved or amended the like Summe as those that shall not pave and
repaire open Streets Lanes and Allyes now paved by vertue of this Act Provided alwayes That such antient Streets
Lanes and Alleys within the said places or any of them as by Custome and Usage have beene repaired and
paved by any other Order or in any other Manner shall be hereafter repaired paved and maintained in such sort
and manner and by such person and persons as have heretofore used to repaire pave and maintaine the same
under the Penalties aforesaid any thing in this Act contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. Charges of cleansing, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p13">
			<emph type="i">Streets, how raised.; Election of Scavengers.; Persons elected, and confirmed by Justices of Peace, refusing to serve; Penalty &pound;10.; Other Persons chosen and refusing, the like Penalty.; Penalties paid to Surveyor of Highways.; How levied.; Distress.; Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p14">And for the better raising and levying of Monyes to defray the Charges and pay the Wages of the said
Scavengers Rakers and other Officers imployed in cleansing of the Streets and other Places aforesaid and carrying
away the said Ashes Dirt Filth and Soile Bee it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That within the
Parishes of Saint Anne and Saint James within the Liberty of Westminster the Scavengers Rakers and such like
Officers shall be chosen as by the said respective Acts is directed and appointed And the Rates Taxes and
Assessments for Scavengers Rakers and such like Officers Wages for cleansing the Streets shall be rated taxed and
assessed raised and paid by the Parishioners and Inhabitants of those respective Parishes according to the Custome
and Usage of the said City where it is not otherwise in the said Acts provided and enacted And the Receivers
of all such Moneys shall be accountable in such manner as they now are by the said Acts or otherwise by the
Law in case there is noe Provision for the same thereby appointed And all new Messuages Tenements and Houses
now or at any time hereafter built and erected within the Limitts and Parishes aforesaid shall be likewise rated
taxed and assessed and shall pay proportionable with others And in all other [Parishes and Places<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] aforesaid upon
every Munday or Tuesday in Easter Weeke the Constables Churchwardens and Overseers of the Poore and
Surveyours of the Highwayes of every of the said Parishes and Places respectively or the greater number of
them giveing Notice unto or calling together such other ancient Inhabitants of their respective Parishes as
according to the Custome of the said Parishes or Places are usually present at the Election of Parish Officers
they or the greater number of them present shall make choice of and shall nominate and appoint two or
more able persons that are Tradesmen of their Parish to be Scavengers for the Streets Lanes and Alleys and
other open Passages of each Ward and Division within their said Parish for the yeare then next ensueing
and untill others be chosen and setled in their Places which persons soe chosen and being approved and
confirmed under the Hand of any two Justices of the Peace within their respective Limitts and Jurisdictions
shall within seven dayes after their Election and Confirmation and Notice thereof take that Office and Duty upon
them upon paine to forfeit ten pounds for every Refuser respectively and in case of refusall by any
person or persons soe chosen and confirmed then other able persons shall be chosen and confirmed in manner
aforesaid within seven dayes after such Refusall in the place of him or them which shall soe refuse And the
person or persons soe chosen and confirmed and haveing Notice thereof shall undergoe the like paine of ten
pounds in case of Refusall or not takeing upon him or them the said Office or Duty within seven dayes after
he or they shall be chosen and confirmed and have Notice thereof as aforesaid The said Penalties to be paid to
the Surveyors of the Highwayes of the place and disposed of and imployed by them for and towards the mending
and repairing of the Highwayes and Streets of the same Parish Ward or Division and to be levyed by Distresse
and Sale of the Goods and Chattells of the Offenders by Warrant under the Hand and Scale of any one Justice
of Peace of any of the Places aforesaid to be directed to the Constables or other Officers of the same Parish
or any two or more of them rendering the Overplus to the Partie (reasonable Charges for the Distresse onely to
be deducted) And in default of Distresse or Nonpayment within six dayes after Demand thereof or Notice left in
Writeing at the House or Dwelling place of the Offender by the said Constables or Officers respectively the said
Offender to be committed to the Common Gaole of the said County City or Place respectively by the Warrant of
any such Justice under his Hand and Seale there to remaine without Baile or Mainprize untill Payment be thereof
made as aforesaid And soe in like manner for every person or persons neglecting or refuseing the same</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. Inhabitants may make a Pound Rate.</head>
		<para id="p15">
			<emph type="i">Nonpayment.; Distress.; Imprisonment.; Proviso for Peers</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p16">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That within twenty dayes after the Election and
Confirmation of the said Scavingers as aforesaid the Constables Churchwardens and Overseers of the Poore and
Surveyours of the Highwayes of the Parishes and Places aforesaid respectively or the greater number of them
giveing Notice unto or calling together such Inhabitants of their respective Parishes as aforesaid they or the greater
number of them then present shall make and settle a Taxe Rate or Assessment according to a Pound Rate to be
imposed or sett upon the Inhabitants of every respective Parish Ward or Division for the yeare following for the
purposes aforesaid which being allowed and confirmed by any two of the Justices of the Peace of the Places
aforesaid respectively which they are hereby authorized and required as farr as the same shall be equall and
reasonable to allow shall be quarterly paid by every respective Inhabitant upon Demand made thereof by the
Scavengers or Officers appointed to gather and collect the same And in case of a Refusall or Neglect shall by
Warrant under the Hands and Seals of any two Justices of the Peace of the Division Parish or Place be levyed
by Distresse and Sale of the Offenders Goods and for want of Distresse by Imprisonment of the Offender (he not
being a Peere of this Realme) untill Payment as aforesaid.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>IX. Scavengers must account for Monies paid,</head>
		<para id="p17">
			<emph type="i">and pay the Overplus to succeeding Scavengers. Refusing to account, Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p18">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted That such Sums of Money as shall be yearly assessed and collected in
the said Parishes for cleansing the Streets shall be yearly accounted for by the Scavenger for the time being
which collected the same to two or more of the next Justices of the Peace for the Place resideing in or neere
to the respective Places for which such Scavengers were appointed within eight and twenty dayes aftet the Election
of new Scavengers for the ensueing yeare And such Summe or Summes as shall be remaining in their Hands
shall be by them paid over to the next succeeding Scavengers elected for such Parish And any two such Justices
of the Peace as aforesaid shall and may by vertue hereof committ to Prison every one of the said Scavengers
which shall refuse to account there to remaine without Baile or Mainprize untill he [hath<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] made a true Account
and satisfied and paid soe much as upon the said Account shall be remaining in his Hands</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s10">
		<head>X. Where the Scavenger must lay his Dirt, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p19">
			<emph type="i">Appeal from Rate, &amp;c. to Quarter Sessions.; Order therein final</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p20">Provided alwayes That the respective Scavengers and Rakers for any of the Parishes aforesaid shall have
Liberty by the Approbation and Order of the Justices at their Petty Sessions or any two or more of them to
lodge their Dirt Dust Ashes or other Filth in such vacant and publique places in or neare the Streets or
Highwayes as shall be thought convenient by the said Justices for the Accommodation of the Country Carts returning
empty from the said Parishes they giveing Satisfaction to the Owners and Occupiers of such vacant places and in
case of unreasonable demands such Justices in their Petty Sessions shall heare moderate and determine the same
according to Equity and good Conscience And in case any person shall finde him her or themselves aggrieved
with any Rate Tax or Assessment made by vertue of this Act or any wayes prejudiced by any determination of
the said Justices in their Petty Sessions he or they soe grieved or prejudiced shall and may have recourse in all
such Cases to the Justices of the Peace assembled at the Generall Quarter Sessions of the Peace to be held for
the Place wherein the Matter of Grievance doth arise to sett forth his her or their Case by Petition or otherwise
And the said Justices in such their Quarter Sessions are hereby impowred to heare and determine all Matters to
them complained of concerning the same respectively and their Determination and Order therein shall be finall
without any Appeale to any other Court whatsoever</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s11">
		<head>XI. Assessment how made for the Highways.</head>
		<para id="p21">
			<emph type="i">To be levied by Distress.; Amount of Assessment in any one Year</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p22">And whereas there are many Common Highwayes within the said Parishes which cannot be sufficiently amended
repaired and supported by meanes of the Lawes now in force without the helpe of this present Act Bee it enacted
That for the better amending and repairing the same one or more Assessment or Assessments upon all and every
the Inhabitants Owners and Occupiers of Lands Houses Tenements and Hereditaments or any Personall Estate
usually ratable to the Poore within any of the said Parishes shall be from time to time made levyed collected
and allowed by such person and persons as the said Justices at such their Generall Quarter Sessions shall direct
and appoint in that behalfe and the Money thereby raised shall be employed and accounted for according to the
Order and Direction of the said Justices for and towards the amending repairing and supporting such Highwayes
from time to time as need shall require And the said Assessment shall be levyed by Distresse and Sale of the
Goods of every person soe assessed (not paying the same within fourteene dayes after demand) rendring the
Overplus of the Value of the Goods soe distrained to the Owner and Owners thereof the necessary Charges
of makeing and selling such Distresse being first deducted Provided alwayes That noe such Assessment or
Assessments to be made in any one yeare shall exceede the Rate of foure pence in the pound of the yearly
value of any Lands Houses Tenements and Hereditaments soe assessed nor the Rate of eight pence for every
twenty pounds in Personall Estate.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s12">
		<head>XII. New Sewers subject to the Commission of Sewers.</head>
		<para id="p23">
			<emph type="i">23 H. 8. c. 5</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p24">And whereas many new Sewers Sincks and Vaults have beene made in the Parishes within the City and Liberty
of Westminster and other the Parishes aforesaid by the Commissioners appointed by the said recited Act which
since the Expiration thereof are much neglected and noisome to the Inhabitants because of some doubt whether
such new Sewers are within the Jurisdiction of the Laws of Sewers Bee it therefore enacted by the authoritie
aforesaid That all new Sewers at any time since the twelfth yeare of the Raigne of the said late King Charles
the Second made in any of the said Parishes shall be henceforth subject to the Commission of Sewers and to
the Laws and Statuts made for Sewers as fully to all intents and purposes as if such Sewers Sincks and Vaults
had beene expressly mentioned in the said [Statute<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] of Sewers to be under the Survey of the said Commissioners
And the Commissioners of Sewers for the time being within the Limitts of their respective Commissions shall have
power and authority by vertue of this Act to alter amend cleanse and scowre any such new Sewers Sincks and
Vaults and to order and direct the makeing of any other new Vaults and Sewers and to cutt into any Draine or
Sewer already made and to alter or take away any Nusances in the same and to alter or take away any Crosse
Gutter or Channells in all or any of the Streets and Lanes in the Parishes aforesaid</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s13">
		<head>XIII. Householders to set up Lights</head>
		<para id="p25">
			<emph type="i">from Dark till Twelve at Night.; Penalty. Unless Lamps used</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p26">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every Householder within any of the Parishes Places
or Precincts in the Countyes of Midlesex and Surrey and City and Libertie of Westminster comprized within the
Weekly Bills of Mortality whose House adjoyns unto or is neare the Streete from Michaelmas unto our Ladyday
yearly shall every [night<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] sett or hang out Candles or Lights in Lanthorns on the outside of the House next
the Streete to enlighten the same for the convenienly of Passengers from time to time as it shall grow darke
untill twelve of the Clocke in the Night upon paine to forfeit the Summe of two shillings for every default [(excepting
such person or persons as shall agree to make use of Lamps of any sort to be placed at such distances in the
Street as shall be approved of by two or more Justices of the Peace)<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s14">
		<head>XIV. The Weight of a Truss of Hay.</head>
		<para id="p27">
			<emph type="i">Penalty, 1s. 6d. per Truss</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p28">And whereas great Abuses and Deceits are committed by Carters and others who bring and sett Hay within
the Cityes of London and Westminster and the Haymarkets and places comprised within the Weekly Bills of
Mortality the Loads and Trusses of such Hay being of lesse Weight then they ought and are pretended and
declared to be betweene the Buyer and Seller thereof For remedy herein Bee it further enacted by the authority
aforesaid That every Trusse of old Hay brought or offered to be sold hereafter in any place within the Cities of
London and Westminster and all other places comprised within the Weekly Bills of Mortality betweene the last
day of August and first day of June shall containe and be the full Weight of six and fifty pounds at least and
that every Trusse of Hay brought or offered to be sold within the Cityes or Places aforesaid betweene the first
day of June and the last day of August in any yeare being new Hay of that Summers Growth shall be and
containe the full Weight of sixty pounds and being old Hay of any former yeares Growth the Weight of six
and fifty pounds as aforesaid And if any Hay after the said fifteenth day of December shall be brought or
offered to be sold within the Cityes or places aforesaid whereof any Trusse shall be of lesse Weight then aforesaid
the person or persons aforesaid soe bringing or offering such Hay to be sold shall forfeit for every such Trusse of
Hay not being the full Weight aforesaid the Summe of eighteene pence</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s15">
		<head>XV. At what Hours, &amp;c. loaden Hay Carts to stand in the Haymarket, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p29">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That from and after the said fifteenth day of December
noe person or persons whatsoever shall permitt or suffer his or their Waggon Cart or Carr to stand or be in
the place now called the Hay Market neere Pickadilly in the Parish of Saint Martin in the Fields and Saint James
within the Liberty of Westminster or Burrough of Southwarke or any other place in the Parishes within the
Weekly Bills of Mortality loaden with Hay or Straw to sell the same from Michaelmas to Ladyday after two of
the Clocke in the Afternoone and from Lady-day to Michaelmas after three of the Clocke in the Afternoone on
paine to forfeit for every Offence and Neglect five shillings respectively</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s16">
		<head>XVI. Offenders how to be convicted.</head>
		<para id="p30">
			<emph type="i">One Witness.; Penalties how disposed; when Conviction on Prosecution; when on View of Justice.; Penalty how to be levied.; Default of Distress, Imprisonment.; Proviso for Peers</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p31">And for the more speedy Reformation and Punishment of all and every the Offences aforesaid Bee it further
enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That every Justice of the Peace within the Counties of Midlesex and
Surrey and City and Liberties of Westminster and places aforesaid within their severall Limitts respectively shall
have Power and Authority upon his owne Knowledge or View Confession of the Partie or Proofe of one credible
Witnesse upon Oath before him (which Oath the said Justice is hereby impowered to administer) to convict any
person or persons of any the Offences aforesaid whereby such person or persons soe convict shall incurr the
Pains Penalties and Forfeitures aforesaid one moyety whereof shall bee disposed and employed for and towards
the Reliefe of the Poore of the Parish or Place where the Offence shall be com[m]itted or done to be paid to
the Overseers of the Poore of the same for that use and the other Moyety thereof for him or them that shall
discover and prosecute the same in case the said Conviction be by Discovery and Prosecution And if the
Conviction shall be by [the<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] View or Knowledge of any one or more Justice or Justices of the Peace then one
halfe of the Penalty shall be disposed of to the Reliefe of the Poore as aforesaid and the other Moyety if for a
default of Payment to goe to and be imployed for and towards the repaireing paveing and cleanseing [of<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] the said
Streets or places to be paid to the Scavengers of the place and by them imployed for that use or otherwise to
the Reliefe of the Poore as aforesaid And all the said Penalties shall be levyed by Distresse and Sale of the
Goods and Chattells of the Offender by Warrant under the Hand and Seale of any Justice of the Peace of the
place to be directed to the Constables and Headburroughs of the same Parish where the Offence was done
rendering the Surplusage to the partie And in default of Distresse or not payment of the said Penalties within
six dayes after demand thereof where it is not hereby otherwise provided or Notice in Writeing left at the House
or Dwelling place of the Offender by the said Constable or Headburrough (the said Offender not being a Peere
of this Realme) shall be committed to the Common Goale of the said Countyes or City respectively by the
Warrant of any such Justice under his Hand and Seale there to remaine without Baile or Mainprize untill
Payment</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s17">
		<head>XVII. Wheels of Carts, Drays, &amp;c. how to be made.</head>
		<para id="p32">
			<emph type="i">Penalty 40s. Proviso for Country Carts</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p33">And whereas the Wheeles of many Carts Carrs and Brewers Drays now commonly used for the Carriage of
Goods Beere Ale and other things from place to place within the Cities of London and Westminster and Parishes
aforesaid where the Streets are paved are made thinner or narrower in the Felleys then formerly and many are
shod with Iron Tyres by means whereof the Pavements in the Streets of the said Cities and places are dayly
impaired and broaken up and made dirty and rough For prevention whereof for the time to come Bee it
therefore enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That from and after the [said<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] fifteenth day of December the Wheels
of every Cart Carr or Dray to be used for the Carriage of any thing whatsoever from any place within the said
Cities and places to any place scituate in the said Cities and places where the Streets are paved shall be made
to containe the full breadth of six Inches in the Felley and shall not be wrought about with any Iron Worke
whatsoever nor be drawne with above the number of two Horses after they are up the Hills from the Waterside
And the Owners and Proprietors of any Cart Carr or Dray to be used as aforesaid the Wheels whereof shall
not be made six Inches in the breadth or shall be shod with Iron or be drawne with above two Horses as
aforesaid shall forfeit the Summe of forty shillings for every time such Cart Carr or Dray shall be used as
aforesaid for the Uses and to be levyed as aforesaid Provided neverthelesse That this shall not extend to any
Country Cart or Waggon that shall bring any Goods to the Cities or places aforesaid or shall carry any Goods
halfe a mile beyond the paved Streets of the said Cities and places</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s18">
		<head>XVIII. Swine kept within London, &amp;c. forfeited.</head>
		<para id="p34">
			<emph type="i">Churchwardens, &amp;c. on Warrant from Lord Mayor, &amp;c. may search and seize and sell such Swine.; Produce to the Poor</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p35">And for the better keeping and preserving the Streets and Sewers in and about the said Cities of London and
Westminster and the Liberties thereof and the Burrough of Southwarke and other the Parishes aforesaid Bee it
further enacted That noe person or persons whatsoever from and after the said fifteenth day of December shall
breed feede or keepe any sort or manner of Swine within any part of the Houses or Backsides of the paved
Streets of the said Cityes Burrough or Parishes where the Houses are contiguous upon paine of forfeiting the
same to the Churchwardens and Overseers of the Poore of the Parish where such Swine shall be kept bred or
fedd to the use of the Poore thereof And that it shall and may be lawfull for all or any of the Churchwardens
Chappellwardens Overseers of the Poore Constables Beadles Headburroughs or Tythingmen of any of the Parishes
of the said Cityes and places respectively at all times hereafter in the day-time by Warrant under the Hand and
Scale of the said Maior of London or any other of their Majestyes Justices of the Peace of the place respectively
to search in all such places in their respective Parishes for the finding all such Swine and all that shall be soe
found to seize take drive and carry away and the same to sell for the best price that can be had and the Money
thereby produced forthwith to deliver the Churchwardens or Overseers of the Poore of the Parish where such
Swine shall be seized to be distributed to the Poore of the same in such manner and proportions as the said
Churchwardens and Overseers respectively shall thinke fitt</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s19">
		<head>XIX. Proviso for Custom of London for cleansing, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p36">And for the better cleansing and keeping cleane the Streets Lanes and Passages within th&edot; City of London
and Liberties thereof at all times hereafter Bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That the same shall be ordered
and managed and Rates and Impositions laid and levyed and all other Wayes and Means therefore used and
observed according to the antient Usage and Custome of the said City</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s20">
		<head>XX. Lord Mayor, &amp;c. may present upon View.</head>
		<para id="p37">
			<emph type="i">Fine upon the Presentment,; paid to Chamber-lain of London</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p38">And for the better effecting the same and preventing the throwing out or laying any Ashes Soile Dust or
Rubbish or other Nusance or Obstruction in any the Streets Lanes or Passages of the said City or Liberties
thereof It is further enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Lord Mayor of the said City for
the time being and to and for any Alderman of the said City for the time being upon his owne proper knowledge
or View in the open Generall Sessions to make Presentment for any such Offence committed done or suffered
within the said City or Liberties thereof which Presentment shall be good and effectuall And the Lord Mayor
and Justices of the same City shall immediately at the same Generall Sessions have Authority to assesse Fines
for such Offences not exceeding twenty shillings for any one Offence Which Fines soe to be assessed as aforesaid
shall be levyed and paid unto the Chamberlaine of the City of London for the time being for the use of
the same City to be employed in the publicke Payments of the same City any Law or Statute to the contrary
notwithstanding</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s21">
		<head>XXI.</head>
		<para id="p39">
			<emph type="i">22, 23 Car. II. c. 17.; Vexatious Prosecutions prevented.; General Issue.; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p40">And whereas there are many good Provisions made and ordained for the cleansing the Sewers and well
paveing the Streets in London by one Act made in the two and twentyeth and three and twentyeth years of
King Charles the Second Entituled An Act for the better Paveing and Cleansing the Streets and Sewers in and
about the City of London which have beene much obstructed by occasion of many frivolous and vexatious Actions
commenced and prosecuted by evill disposed persons against Officers and others imployed in the Execution of
the said Act Wherefore to prevent the like vexatious Prosecutions for the future Bee it further enacted That if
any Action Suite Plaint or Information shall at any time after the said fifteenth day of December be commenced
or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance of or in Execution of
the said last recited Act or this Act such person or persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall or may plead
the Generall Issue and upon any Issue joyned may give the said respective Acts or either of them as the Case
may require and the speciall matter in Evidence And if the Plaintiffe or Prosecutor shall become Nonsuite or
suffer Discontinuance or if a Verdict passe against him or her the Defendant and Defendants shall recover their
treble Costs for which they shall have the like Remedy as in any Case where Costs by the Law are given to
Defendants</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s22">
		<head>XXII. Proviso for paving Way to St. John's Street.</head>
		<para id="p41">[And it is hereby enacted and declared for avoiding any Doubt touching the Highway leading from the East
side of Clerkenwell Greene to St. Johns Street That the said Way shall be paved according to the Direction
of this Act.<ref idref="n10">10</ref>]</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">Places &amp; Parishes <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">have <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">Statutes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n8" number="8">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n10" number="10">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
	</section>
</report>


