<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46344" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1690</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act for the Continuance of severall former Acts therein mentioned for the laying severall Duties upon Wines Vinegar and Tobacco.</subtitle>
	
	<section id="s2">
		<head>Reasons for the present Grant.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Duties upon Wines and Vinegar given 1 Jac. II. c. 3. given to their present Majesties, &amp;c. till 24th June 1696</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Most Gracious [Soveraigne.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]<br />Wee your Majestyes most Dutyfull and Loyall Subjects the Commons in Parliament assembled taking into
our serious Consideration the great and necessary Expences in which your Majesties are engaged for our
Defence and Safety have chearfully and unanimously given and granted unto your Majestyes the Impositions and
Duties hereafter mentioned for and dureing the Terme hereafter expressed And wee doe most humbly beseech your
Majestyes that it may be enacted And bee it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majestyes by and
with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament
assembled and by the authoritie of the same That the severall Impositions [and Duties<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] upon Wines and Vinegar
granted by an Act made in the first yeare of the late King James intituled An Act for granting his Majestie an
Imposition upon all Wines and Vinegar imported betweene the foure and twentyeth day of June one thousand six hundred
eighty five and the foure and twentyeth day of June one thousand six hundred ninety and three shall be continued
from the three and twentyeth day of June in the said yeare one thousand six hundred ninety three and shall be
raised levyed collected answered and paid unto their Majestyes and their Successors untill the foure and twentyeth
day of June one thousand six hundred ninety six and noe longer And that the said Act and all Powers Provisions
Penalties Articles and Clauses therein contained shall continue and be of full Force and Effect untill the said foure
and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety six [and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] shall be applyed practised and executed for
the raising levying collecting answering and paying the said Duties hereby continued according to the tenor and intent
of this present Act.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>II. Duty upon Tobacco given by 4 Jac. II. c. 4. continued till 1696.</head>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">The said Act, as to Tobacco only, continued until 24th June 1696.; This Act not to repeal or alter 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 34</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the Rates and Dutyes for all sorts of Tobacco
granted by an Act made in the first yeare of the Raigne of the late King James Entituled An Act for granting to
his Majestye an Imposition upon all Tobacco and Sugar imported betweene the foure and twentyeth day of June
one thousand six hundred eighty five and the foure and twentyeth day of June one thousand six hundred ninety
three shall be continued from the three and twentyeth day of June in the said yeare one thousand six hundred
and ninety three and shall be raised levyed collected answered and paid unto their Majestyes and their Successors
untill the foure and twentieth day of June one thousand six hundred and ninety six and noe longer And that the
said last mentioned Act as for and concerning Tobacco onely and all Powers Provisions Penalties Articles and
Clauses therein contained concerning the said Rates and Dutyes upon all sorts of Tobacco shall continue and be
of full Force and Effect untill the said foure and twentyeth day of June one thousand six hundred and ninety six
and shall be applyed practised and executed for the raising levying collecting answering and paying the said Duties
upon Tobacco hereby continued according to the tenour and intent of this present Act Provided neverthelesse That
this Act nor any thing therein contained shall not extend or be construed or taken to repeale or alter an Act
made in the first yeare of their Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for prohibiting all Trade and Commerce with
France, or any part of the same</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>III. Credit of Loan at Eight per Cent. on this Act, and 1 Jac. II. c. 3, 4. 1 W. &amp; M. c. 28.</head>
		<para id="p5">Provided alwayes and it is hereby enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any person and persons
to advance and lend unto their Majestyes as well upon the Security of this Act as upon the Security of the said
two former Acts made in the Raigne of the late King James (from and after the Summe of six hundred thousand
pounds mentioned in an Act made in the first yeare of their Majestyes Raigne Entituled An Act for appropriating
certaine Duties for paying the States Generall of the United Provinces their Charges for his Majestyes Expedition into
this Kingdome and for other Uses shall be fully satisfied and paid to the said States Generall) any Summe or Summes
of Money and to have and receive for the Forbearance thereof any Summe not exceeding Eight pounds by the Hundred
for one whole yeare and noe more directly or indirectly</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>IV. Tally, Order, &amp;c. granted by Lenders.</head>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">Entry of Monies distinct.; Tally, Order, &amp;c. granted to Lenders.; Orders for Repayment to be registered, and paid in course.; No Fee, &amp;c. for providing, &amp;c. Books, nor for View or Search; Penalty.; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty.; By Deputy; Penalty.; Auditor, &amp;c. offending.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p7">And to the end that all Moneys which shall be lent unto their Majestyes upon the Credit of this Act may be
well and suffici ntly secured out of the Moneys ariseing and payable by this Act Bee it further enacted by the
authoritie aforesaid That there shall be provided and kept in their Majestyes Exchequer (that is to say) in
the Office of the Auditor of the Receipts one Booke or Register in which all Moneys that shall be paid into the
Exchequer by vertue of this Act shall be entred and registred apart and distinct from all other Moneys paid
or payable to their Majesties upon any other Branch of their Majesties Revenue or upon any other Account
whatsoever And that all and every person and persons who shall lend any Money to their Majestyes upon the
Credit of this Act and pay the same into the Receipt of the Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally of Loane
strucke for the same and an Order for his Repayment bearing the same date with his Tally in which Order shall
be alsoe contained a Warrant for Payment of Interest for Forbearance after the Rate soe to be allowed for the
same soe as such Interest doe, not exceede the rate of eight pounds per Centu[m] per Annu[m] for his Consideration to
be paid every three months untill Repayment of his Principall And that all Orders for Repayment of money shall
be registred in course according to the date of the Tally respectively without preference of one before another
and that all and every person and persons shall be paid in course according as their Orders shall stand entred in
the said Register Booke soe as that the person Native or Forreigner his Executors Administrators and Assignes who
shall have his Order or Orders first entered in the said Booke of Register shall be taken and accounted as the
first person to be paid upon the Moneys to come in by vertue of this Act and he or they who shall have his
or their Order or Orders next entred shall be taken and accounted to be the second person to be paid and soe
successively and in course and that the Moneys to come in by this Act shall be in the same Order lyable to the
satisfaction of the said respective parties their Executors Administrators or Assignes successively without preference of one (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>)
another and not otherwise and not to be divertible to any other use intent or purpose whatsoever and that noe Fee Reward
or Gratuity directly or indirectly be demanded or taken of any of their Majesties Subjects for provideing or makeing of any
such Books Registers Entryes View or Search in or for Payment of Money lent or the Interest as aforesaid by any of their
Majestyes Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputyes on paine of Payment of treble Damages to the partie
grieved by the partie offending with Costs of Suite or if the Officer himselfe take or demand any such Fee or
Reward then to lose his Place alsoe And if any undue Preference of one before another shall be made either
in point of Registry or Payment contrary to the true meaning of this Act by any such Officer or Officers then
the partie offending shall be lyable by Action of Debt or on the Case to pay the value of the Debt Damages
and Costs to the partie grieved and shall be forejudged from his Place or Office And if such preference be
unduely made by any his Deputy or Clerke without direction or privity of his Master then such Deputy or
Clerke only shall be lyable to such Action Debt Damages and Costs and shall be for ever after uncapable of his Place
or Office And in case the Auditor shall not direct the Order or the Clerke of the Pells Record or the Teller
make Payment according to each persons due Place and Order as aforesaid Then he or they shall be judged
to forfeit and their respective Deputies and Clerks herein offending to be lyable to such Action Debt Damages
and Costs in such manner as aforesaid All which said Penalties Forfeitures Damages and Costs to be incurred
by any of the Officers of the Exchequer or any their Deputies or Clerks shall and may be recovered by Action
of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of their Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe
Essoigne Protection Priviledge Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise granted or
allowed</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>V. Payment of any Tally of same Date not interpreted Preference.</head>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">Paying subsequent Orders, when first not demanded, how far not undue Preference</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p9">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby declared That if it happen that severall Tallys of Loane or Orders for
Payment as aforesaid beare date or be brought the same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be registred Then
it shall be enterpreted noe undue preference which of those he enters firste soe he enters them all the same day
Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpreted any undue preference to incurr any Penalty in point of Payment
if the Auditor direct and the Clerke of the Pells record and the Teller doe pay subsequent Orders of Persons
that come and demand their Money and bring their Order before other Persons that did not come to demand
their Money and bring their Order in their course soe as there be soe much money reserved as will satisfie precedent
Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon Loane being to cease from the time
the Money is soe reserved and kept in Banke for them.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VI. Order for Repayment assignable.</head>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">Memorial without Fee.; Assignee may assign</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p11">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That every person or persons to whome any [Moneys<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]
shall be due by vertue of this Act after Order entered in the Booke of Register aforesaid for Payment thereof
his Executors Administrators or Assignes by Indorsment of his Order may assigne and transfer his Right Title
Interest and Benefit of such Order or any part thereof to any other which being notified in the Office of the
Auditor of the Receipt aforesaid and an Entry or Memoriall thereof alsoe made in the Booke of Register aforesaid
for Orders (which the Officers shall upon Request without Fee or Charge accordingly make) shall entitle such
Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the benefit thereof and payment thereon And such Assignee
may in like manner assigne againe and soe toties quoties and afterwards it shall not be in the power of such
person or persons who have or hath made such Assignments to make void release or discharge the same or any
the Moneys thereby due or any part thereof</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VII. Proviso for Wages due to the Servants of King Charles II.</head>
		<para id="p12">Provided That nothing in this Act shall extend or be construed to defeat or obstruct the Provision made by
the said Act in the first yeare of their Majesties Raigne for payment of Wages due to the Servants of the late
King Charles the Second not exceeding in the whole the Summe of sixty thousand pounds in such manner as by
the said Act is directed.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">Soveraignes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">before <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">Money <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


