<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46340" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1690</title>
<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for Granting an Ayd to Their Majestyes of the Summe of Sixteene hundred fifty one thousand seaven hundred and two pounds eighteene shillings. [Rot. Parl. pt. 2.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>The Reasons for this Grant.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">&pound;1,651,702. 18s. to be rained in manner herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">[<ref idref="n1">1</ref>Most Gracious [Soveraigne<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]]<br/>
Wee Your Majestyes most Dutifull and Loyall Subjects the Commons in Parlyament Assembled being deeply
sensible of the abundant Care Wisedome and Resolution with which Your Majestyes have Defended and
Preserved these Kingdomes against the Opposition of Open and Secret Enimies and being Resolved Effectually
to Support Your Government and Assist Your Majestyes for the Entire Reduceing of Ireland and Secureing
the Peace of this Kingdome and Vigorously carrying on the Warr against France have towards the Ends and
Purposes aforesaid Chearfully and Unanimously Given and Granted unto Your Majestyes the Rates and Assessments
hereafter mentioned And wee doe humbly beseech Your Majestyes that it may be enacted And Bee it Enacted
by the King and Queens most Excellent Majestyes by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament Assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the
Summe of Sixteene hundred fifty one thousand seven hundred and two pounds eighteene shillings shall be
Raised Levyed and Paid unto their Majestyes in manner following That is to say The Summe of One hundred
thirty seven thousand six hundred forty one pounds eighteene shillings and two pence by the Month for Twelve
Months begining from the Five and twentyeth day of December in the Yeare of Our Lord One thousand six
hundred and ninety shall be Assessed Taxed Levyed and Paid by Foure Quarterly Payments in the severall
Countyes Cities Burroughs Townes and Places within England and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon
Tweede according to the Proportions following Vi[z] For each of the said Twelve Months</para>
<para id="p3">FOR the County of Bedford the Summe of One thousand seven hundred ninety three pounds fifteene shillings
six pence.</para>
<para id="p4">For the County of Berks the Summe of Two thousand two hundred sixty foure pounds thirteene shillings two
pence.</para>
<para id="p5">For the County of Bucks the Summe of Two thousand six hundred and thirty pounds twelve shillings ten
pence.</para>
<para id="p6">For the County of Cambridge the Summe of Two thousand and forty pounds.</para>
<para id="p7">The Isle of Ely the Summe of Six hundred ninety nine pounds fifteene shillings ten pence.</para>
<para id="p8">The County of Chester One thousand foure hundred ninety five pounds fourteene shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p9">The City and County of the City of Chester the Summe of One hundred and six pounds sixteene shillings
eight pence.</para>
<para id="p10">The County of Cornwall the Summe of Three thousand eighty one pounds sixteene shillings six pence.</para>
<para id="p11">The County of Cumberland the Summe of Three hundred thirty six pounds twelve shillings two pence.</para>
<para id="p12">The County of Derby the Summe of One thousand seven hundred twenty foure pounds sixteene shillings eight
pence.</para>
<para id="p13">The County of Devon the Summe of Six thousand foure hundred fifty nine pounds eighteene shillings foure
pence.</para>
<para id="p14">The City and County of the City of Exeter the Summe of two hundred thirty two pounds fourteene shillings
eight pence.</para>
<para id="p15">The County of Dorset the Summe of two thousand six hundred eighty nine pounds and ten pence.</para>
<para id="p16">The Towne and County of Poole the Summe of Twenty one pounds nineteene shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p17">The County of Durham the Summe of Six hundred forty seven pounds thirteene shillings six pence.</para>
<para id="p18">The County of Yorke with the City and County of the City of Yorke and Towne and County of Kingston upon
Hull the Summe of Six thousand nine hundred thirty eight pounds ten shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p19">The County of Essex the Summe of Six thousand one hundred ninety six pounds seventeene shillings and
eight pence.</para>
<para id="p20">The County of Gloucester the Summe of Three thousand six hundred seventeene pounds and six pence.</para>
<para id="p21">The City and County of the City of Gloucester the Summe of Seventy eight pounds sixteene shillings.</para>
<para id="p22">The County of Hereford the Summe of Two thousand two hundred sixty three pounds six shillings and
eight pence.</para>
<para id="p23">The County of Hertford the Summe of Two thousand six hundred ninety one pounds twelve shillings and
six pence.</para>
<para id="p24">The County of Huntingdon the Summe of One thousand two hundred sixty seven pounds eight shillings and
foure pence.</para>
<para id="p25">The County of Kent with the City and County of the City of Canterbury the Summe of Six thousand six
hundred fifty three pounds seventeene shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p26">The County of Lancaster the Summe of two thousand and thirteene pounds seven shillings.</para>
<para id="p27">The County of Leicester the Summe of Two thousand one hundred sixty nine pounds eight shillings six
pence.</para>
<para id="p28">The County of Lincolne with the City and County of the City of Lincolne the Summe of Five thousand one
hundred fifty pounds foure shillings.</para>
<para id="p29">The City of London, with the Liberties of Saint Martins le Grand the Summe of Eight thousand five hundred
eighty three pounds two shillings eight pence.</para>
<para id="p30">The County of Midlesex with the City and Liberty of Westminster the Summe of Six thousand eighty one
pounds.</para>
<para id="p31">The County of Monmouth the Summe of Seven hundred and eighty pounds.</para>
<para id="p32">The County of Northampton the Summe of Two thousand eight hundred twenty seven pounds sixteene shillings
foure pence.</para>
<para id="p33">The County of Nottingham with the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham the Summe of One thousand
seven hundred forty six pounds sixteene shillings.</para>
<para id="p34">The County of Norfolke the Summe of Six thousand seven hundred forty one pounds foure shillings.</para>
<para id="p35">The City and County of the City of Norwich the Summe of Three hundred sixty pounds.</para>
<para id="p36">The County of Northumberland with the Towne of Newcastle and Berwicke upon Tweede the Summe of Seven
hundred forty five pounds eleven shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p37">The County of Oxon the Summe of Two thousand two hundred seventy one pounds one shilling foure pence.</para>
<para id="p38">The County of Rutland the Summe of Foure hundred eighty pounds seventeene shillings and ten pence.</para>
<para id="p39">The County of Salop the Summe of Two thousand foure hundred and seven pounds eight shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p40">The County of Stafford the Summe of One thousand seven hundred and five pounds three shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p41">The City and County of the City of Litchfield the Summe of Twenty six pounds.</para>
<para id="p42">The County of Somerset the Summe of Five thousand five hundred forty three pounds one shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p43">The City and County of the City of Bristoll the Summe of Three hundred ninety eight pounds sixteene shillings
eight pence.</para>
<para id="p44">The County of Southampton with the Towne and County of Southampton and the Isle of Wight the Summe of
Foure thousand three hundred seventy eight pounds seventeene shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p45">The County of Suffolke the Summe of Six thousand five hundred ninety seven pounds one shilling foure pence.</para>
<para id="p46">The County of Surrey with the Burrough of Southwarke the Summe of Three thousand one hundred ninety foure
pounds and foure pence.</para>
<para id="p47">The County of Sussex the Summe of three thousand six hundred forty two pounds fifteene shillings six pence.</para>
<para id="p48">The County of Warwicke with the City and County of the City of Coventry the Summe of Two thousand three
hundred eighty foure pounds seventeene shillings six pence.</para>
<para id="p49">The County of Worcester the Summe of Two thousand one hundred seven pounds eighteene shillings.</para>
<para id="p50">The City and County of the City of Worcester One hundred and ten pounds nineteene shillings.</para>
<para id="p51">The County of Wilts the Summe of Three thousand nine hundred thirty three pounds fifteene shillings two
pence.</para>
<para id="p52">The County of Westmorland the Summe of two hundred thirty two pounds.</para>
<para id="p53">The County of Anglesey the Summe of Two hundred fifty one pounds seven shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p54">The County of Brecknocke the Summe of Five hundred sixty five pounds eleven pence.</para>
<para id="p55">The County of Cardigan the Summe of Two hundred eleven pounds eleven shillings seven pence.</para>
<para id="p56">The County of Carmarthen the Summe of Five hundred forty foure pounds thirteene shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p57">The County of Carnarvan the Summe of Two hundred ninety three pounds foure shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p58">The County of Denbigh the Summe of Foure hundred forty seven pounds one shilling two pence.</para>
<para id="p59">The County of Flint the Summe of Two hundred thirty seven pounds fourteene shillings eight pence.</para>
<para id="p60">The County of Glamorgan The Summe of Seven hundred fifty seven pounds fifteene shillings eight pence.</para>
<para id="p61">The County of Merioneth the Summe of Two hundred and one pounds twelve shillings two pence.</para>
<para id="p62">The County of Montgomery the Summe of five hundred fifty three pounds foure shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p63">The County of Pembrooke the Summe of Six hundred fifty three pounds.</para>
<para id="p64">The County of Radnor the Summe of Three hundred forty eight pounds thirteene shillings foure pence.</para>
<para id="p65">The Towne of Haverford West the Summe of Thirty pounds six shillings ten pence.</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Commissioners appointed.</head>
<para id="p66">And bee it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That for the effectuall putting of this present Act in
Execution all and every the Persons hereafter named shall be Commissioners of and for the severall and respective
Counties Cities Burroughs Towns and Places hereafter mentioned.</para>
<section id="s3">
<head>For the County, of Bedford</head>
<para id="p67">The Honourable Edward Russell The Honourable Robert Russell The Honourable Robert Bruce The Honourable
Charles Leigh Esquires Sir John Mordant Sir William Gostwick Sir John Napier Sir John Cotton Sir Anthony
Chester Sir John Burgoyne Sir Rowland Alstone Sir Villier Charnock Sir John Osborne Baronets Sir William
Becher Sir Francis Wingate Sir William Franklyn Knights Sir John Franklin Sir James Astrey Masters in Chancery
William Duncombe Oliver Luke William Boteler Lewis Monoux Thomas Browne Benjamin Conquest Samuell
Cater Thomas Hillersden John Osborne William Farrer the Queens Sollicitor William Foster Thomas Cheyne
William Palmer Richard Stone Edward Stone John Vaux George Abbot John Cockaine William Spencer Richard
Edwards Brooke Bridges George Edwards Thomas Bromsall Ralph Bromsall Walter Cary Robert Mountague
Gains Squire Henry Astley junior Humphry Fish Charles Gery William Farrer junior Samuell Bedford Robert
Audley William Daniell Esquires Sir John Thompson John Harvey of Thurley Thomas Christy Mathew Denis
William Livesay William Alstone Thomas Halfepeny Samuell Rhodes John Wagstaffe William Simcotts Nicholas
Granger William Whitebread George Bernardiston Richard Orlebar of Hinwick John Davies William Botelor of
Wotton William Brandrefe Samuell Ironside Esquires Thomas Arnold of Ampthill William Crow George Nodes
George Cobb Gent.</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>For the Town of Bedford</head>
<para id="p68">The Mayor for the time being Thomas Hillersdon Thomas Christie William Foster William Farrer Esquires
John Beaumont John Hawes William Manley William Faldo John Crawley William Becket Ralph Smith Gent.</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>For the County of Berks</head>
<para id="p69">The Right Honourable Sir John Trevor Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons and First Lord
Commissioner of the Great Seale The Right Honourable Henry Powle Esquire one of Their Majestyes most
Honourable Privy Councill Henry Earle of Sterling of the Kingdome of Scotland Mountague Lord Norris Henry
Lord Alexander the Honourable Bernard Greenville Esquire Sir Humphry Foster Sir John Stonehouse Sir Thomas
Draper Sir William Rich Sir Henry Winchcombe Sir Thomas Clarges Sir Edmund Fettiplace Sir John Hobby
Sir Anthony Craven Sir Henry Henn Sir Willoughby Aston Sir William Kendrick Sir Edward Read Baronets
Sir Henry Fane Knight of the Bath Sir Charles Porter Sir Robert Pye. Sir Robert Sawyer Sir Algernoon [May<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
Sir Edward Norris Sir Christopher Wrenn Sir William Whitlock Sir Jonathan Raymond Sir Thomas Dolman
Sir Jemmet Raymond Sir George Willoughby Sir Thomas Travaile Knights William Stonehouse John Blandy
Henry Barker Henry Nevill John Archer Richard Nevill Richard Aldworth William Cherry Edmond Fettyplace
Tanfield Vachell Edmond Pie Henry Kingsmill James Stonehouse Charles Garrard John Blagrave Loftes Brightwell
Paul Calton Henry Fairfax James Paul Charles Fettiplace Thomas Pettit Paul Calton junior John Hippesley
Benjamin Rudyerd John Standing Richard Pie Thomas Fettiplace James Perrot Edmond Wiseman Henry Heyling
Roger Draper Symon Harcourt William Jenings John Whitfield James Hayes Edward Sherwood Richard Southby
John Southby Thomas Southby Thomas Lee Francis White John Wightwicke Thomas Dolman Thomas Seymour
Thomas Tipping Roger Knight John Topham Richard Jennens Christopher Willoughby William Adderley John
Wallis John Holloway Robert Mayott Angell of Binfield William Thompson John Verney John Wildman
senior John Wildman junior Richard Brickendon Arthur Ounslow Thomas Garrard Thomas Harwood Henry Battin
Thomas Hoard Nathan Knight Bartholomew Tipping John Fincher Phillip Weston John Edmonds Robert Leigh
George Blagrave John Deane Bolton James John Peacock John Jennens of Stanford John Dew John Dalby Richard
Knapp John Loder Thomas Loder John Pottenger of Sudbury Sebastion Lyford Edward Read Edward Lovedon
Thomas Read Richard Palmer Francis Parry Richard Stephens John Pottinger of Inkpen John Collins David Bigg
Scory Barker Charlton Whitelock Esquires Moses Bruch Doctor in Physicke Joseph Cowslade Ralph Howland
Esquires Robert Jenings John Bigg Moses Slade Richard Skinner Richard Payne Charles Harrison John Smith
Anthony Leaver Nicholas Humphrys Charles Calverley Thomas Stephens Edward Brackston George Lamport
Robert Selwood Richard Pusey John Oliver Robert Blackaller James Corderoy Richard Paine Grove of
Grove Thomas Barker Richard Fishborne Henry Peacock Peter Sawyer Robert Mason Thomas Harrison Thomas
Edmonds Richard Cooper Thomas Cowslade Silas Sebroe Giles Pocock Charles Peacock John Pocock of Streatly
Richard Matthews Richard Lyford Edward Pocock John Wilder Silas Scarborough Fishburne John Head
of Langley John Head of Hodcott Gentlemen John Plummer Esquire The Mayor of Reading The Mayor of
Windsor The Mayor of Abingdon The Mayor of Wallingford The Mayor of Newberry The Alderman of
Ockingham.</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>For the Burrough of New Windsor</head>
<para id="p70">James Bridgeman James Perry John Smith John Chalk William Peasly Steward Nicholas Courtney John Topham
Francis Negus William Smith Simon Smith Esquires George Lush Gentleman.</para>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>For the County of Bucks</head>
<para id="p71">Anthony Lord Viscount Falkland of the Kingdome of Scotland The Right Honourable Thomas Wharton Esquire
Comptroller of Their Majestyes Household one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill The Right
Honourable Richard Hampden Esquire Chauncellor and Under Treasurer of Their Majestyes Exchequer and one of
Their Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Charles Lord Cheyne of the Kingdome of Scotland Henry Bertie
Esquire Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir Thomas Tyrrell Sir Walter Clarges Sir Anthony
Chester Sir Thomas Proby Sir William Bowyer Sir Ralph Verney Sir Henry Andrewes Sir Thomas Lee Sir
William Dormer Sir Dennis Hampson Sir Peter Tyrrell Sir Richard Atkins Baronets Sir Robert Gayre Knight
of the Bath Sir Robert Clayton Sir Thomas Clarges Sir William Whitelocke Sir Roger Hill Sir Peter Apsley
Knights Sir John Thompson Baronet Sir Marmaduke Dayrell Sir James Ethridge Knights William Jepson Thomas
Lee John Hampden Edmond Waller Richard Beake William Penn Sir Orlando Gee Sir William Pritchard William
Mountague Sergeant at Law William Cheyne Thomas Hacket John Duncombe of Great Brickhill Alexander Denton
Thomas Pigott John Parkhurst Thomas Lewis senior Thomas Lewis junior Robert Lovett Thomas Berringer John
Backwell Edward Humfrevile Thomas Ferrar senior Thomas Ferrar junior Knightley Purefoy Roger Price John
Whittewrong Richard Greenville Budd Wase Basill Brent Charles Stafford Richard Ingoldsby Thomas Egleton
Robert Dormer Edmond Waller of Gregories Esquires Sir Joseph Alston Benjamin Lane Nicholas Salter William
Fleetwood Robert Stiles William Busby Richard Nichols Edmond Dorrell Thomas Carter Henry Neale John
Grubb John Machell John Shalcrosse William Farrar Simon Mayne Robert Dormer of Lee Henry Herbert James
Herbert George Evelin John Haines Henry Somner senior Henry Somner junior Ralph Lawton Charles [Tyrrill<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]
Edward Bates Thomas Bard Thomas Ligo of Stoke Mandeville Richard Mead Robert Hart James Tyrrell William
Crooke James Chase Richard Dorrell Stephen Chase junior John Thurbarne Sergeant at Law Henry Cave senior
Henry Cave junior Esquires William Hill senior William Hill junior Richard Smith Thomas Smith of Beckonsfield
Whitchurch Henry Harris Robert Gainsford Hugh Horton William Clever Thomas Gibson Timothy
Doyley Henry Gold Thomas Ligo of Burkett John Sparks Richard Barnaby senior George Alnott John Theed
John Seare Gentlemen John Tanner Doctor of Physick Thomas Hudson Henry Cooley Gent.</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>For the Towne of Buckingham</head>
<para id="p72">The Bailiffe for the time being Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir Ralph Verney Baronet
Alexander Denton Henry Andrewes Edmond Dorrell Esquires Hugh Ethersey George Danser William Hartley
Pelham Sandwell Gentlemen William Busby Esq[uire] John Rogers Gent. Edward Bates Esq[uire].</para>
</section>
<section id="s9">
<head>For the Towne of Chipping Wicombe</head>
<para id="p73">The Mayor Recorder Aldermen Bayliffes and Towne Clerke for the time being William Jephson and Thomas
Lewis Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>For the County of Cambridge</head>
<para id="p74">The Right Honourable Richard Lord Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland the Right Honourable Edward Russell
Esquire one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Sir Thomas Chichley Knight Sir Christopher Hatton
Sir John Cotton Sir Thomas Willis Sir Levinus Bennett Sir Henry Pickering Sir Rushout Cullen Sir John Cutler
Baronets Sir Robert Cotton Sir Marmaduke Dayrell Knights John Willis John Bennett John Cutts Granado Pigott
Phillip Cotton Devereux Martyn William Russell Edward Nightingale Edward Pickering Samuell Clarke John
Milliscent William Fortrey Thomas Duckat Thomas Bucke John Hagar William Layer senior Thomas Story Edward
Leeds Thomas Archer Gilbert Wigmore Humphry Gardiner Anthony Thompson William Layer junior Charles
Baron Esquires William Cooke Doctor of Civill Law Thomas Day Tirrell Dalton Sclater Lownes
Esquires Robert Flack Gent.</para>
</section>
<section id="s11">
<head>For the University and Towne of Cambridge</head>
<para id="p75">The Vice Chancellor The Mayor for the time being the Honourable John Montague Doctor of Divinity Sir
Thomas Chichley Knight Sir John Cotton Baronet Sir Robert Sawyer Knight The Honourable Edward Finch
Granado Piggot Esquires George Chamberlaine Joseph Beaumont Humphrey Gower Thomas Smolt John Balderson
John Covet Thomas Bainbridge Doctors of Divinity Rodericke George Oxenden William Cooke [Doctors
of Civill Law Samuell Newton<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Thomas Story John Ewen Thomas Fowles Isaac Watlington John Pepis Thomas
Fox John Page Aldermen William Baron Robert Drake Gentlemen James Johnson Isaac Newton Samuell Perne
Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s12">
<head>For the Isle of Ely</head>
<para id="p76">Richard Lord Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland Doctor Spencer Deane of Ely Sir Sewster Payton Baronet
Sir Lyonell Walden Knight William Cooke William Balaam Henry Hitch Doctors of Civill Law William Colville
Thomas Edwards Roger Jennings senior Robert Swayne Thomas Wiseman Everade Buckworth Lawrence Hewer
alias Oxborough William March John Pamplin William Fortery Thomas Steward Malborne Carill John Twelves
Ralph Peirson Thomas Towers Henry Goodricke Sigismond Trafford Richard Read Harrison Esquires
Robert Drake Michaell Beale Gentlemen Roger Jennings junior Esquire Thomas Benion Richard Russell Richard
Peachy Gent. Samuell Barnardiston Esq[uire].</para>
</section>
<section id="s13">
<head>For the County of Chester</head>
<para id="p77">The Right Honourable Sir John Trevor Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons and First Lord
Commissioner of the Great Seale of England Richard Lord Viscount Colchester Sonne and Heire Apparent of
Thomas Earle Rivers Charles Lord Brandon Sonne and Heire Apparent of Charles Earle of Maclesfield Mountague
Lord Norris Sonne and Heire Apparent of James Earle of Abingdon George Lord Delamer Sonne and Heire
Apparent of Henry Earl of Warrington The Honourable George Cholmley Esquire Sir Thomas Wilbraham Sir
Thomas Delves Sir Thomas Grosvenour Sir Willoughby Aston Sir Thomas Stanley Sir Peter Warburton Sir
John Manwaring Sir Thomas Bellet Sir Richard Brooks Sir Robert Duckenfield Sir John Worden Baronets Sir
Robert Cotton Knight and Baronet Sir Jeffery Shakerley Sir John Arderne Sir Roger Puliston Sir John Crew
Sir William Clegg Sir Richard Reynolds Sir Josua Allen Knights Thomas Delves Thomas Cotton Nathaniell Booth
Thomas Leigh of Adlington Peter Leigh of Lyme Thomas Leigh of Dernhall William Lawton Roger Whitley
John Warren William Davenport Peter Leigh of Booths Thomas Daniell Richard Leigh Peter Brookes George
Booth Peter Shakerley John Bruen Edward Minshall Roger Manwaring Roger Wilbraham Samuell Davenport
George Vernon Richard Lister John Davenport Thomas Masterson Charles Hurleston John Lawton Thomas Whitley
Thomas Swettenham Edmond Jodderell Austin Leigh Thomas Aldersey Robert Lee William Minshull Reginald
Bretland Richard Wright John Goldsmith Gent Recorder of Congleton Samuell Hardaware Joseph
Hockenhall John Venables William Domvile John Pickering Lawrence Wright William Whitmore Thomas Glasier
John Baskervile George Lucy Henry Bradshaw William Jackson Doctor of Physicke Thomas Hollinshed George
Dod Charles Manwaring William Glegg of Grange John Hardaware and John Traverse Esquires John Egerton
of Broxton John Daniell of Darisbury John Davies of Manley John Massy of Coddington Spencer
of Huntington Edward Wright of Stretton Thomas Dodd of Edge Dodd of Broxton
Dodd of Hampton Robert Cholmondeley of Holford George Croxton Richard Leveing Lownds of
Overton William Oldfield of Bradwell John Booth of Twamlow Ralph Walley of Stanthorn Eampson
Esquires John Holford of Midlewitch John Parker of the same Sabbath Church John Tench Gentlemen Thomas
Wright Esq[uire] Mayor of Macclesfeild Leigh of Ridgley Esquire Recorder Henry Barber Samuell
Mottershed William Row Peter Wright Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s14">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Chester</head>
<para id="p78">Nathaniell Williamson Esq[uire] Mayor Sir William Williams Knight and Baronet Recorder Sir Thomas Grosvenour
Baronet Roger Whiteley Esquire Richard Levinge Esq[uire] Griffith Williams Esq[uire] Deputy Recorder William Streete
Thomas Wilcock Richard Wright Henry Lloyd William Ince John Anderson George Manwaring Peter Edwards
William Wilson Hugh Starkey Francis Skellerne Aldermen John Warrington Robert Deintieth Sheriffes William
Allen Henry Bennett William Bennett Peter Bennet Alderman Captaine John Sparke Lieutenant John Hulton
Benjamin Cratchley Thomas Hand Thomas Wright William Starkey Robert Hewett John Johnson Richard Oulton
Mathew Anderton Edward Starkey Jonathan Whitby John Colbourne Robert Morrey Edward Partington Randle
Bathoe Joseph Madocks Samuell Heath.</para>
</section>
<section id="s15">
<head>For the County of Cornwall</head>
<para id="p79">The Right Honourable Hugh Boscawen Esquire one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Bernard
Greenvile Esq[uire] Francis [Roberts<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Esq[uire] Sir Bourchier Wray Sir John Carew Sir Violl Vivian Sir William Godolphin Sir
William Corriton Sir Peter Killegrew Sir Nicholas Slannen Sir John St Aubin Sir John Molesworth Sir Peter Colleton
Baronets Sir Joseph Tredenham Sir Walter Moile Sir John Cotton Sir John Tremayne Knights Charles Trevanian
Charles Trelawney Henry Trelawney Samuell Roll John Speccot Daniell Ellyott Jonathan Rashleigh John Buller John
Tanner John Prideaux Walter Kendall Joseph Sawle Thomas Darrell Nicholas Glyn John Vivian junior Edward
Herle John Connack Samuell Traverse Humphrey Nicholl Arthur Fortescue Hugh Fortescue Humphrey Courtney
Edward Ellyott William Mohun John Kendall John Gregor James Kendall John Trefry John Tredenham James
Erisey Francis Calmady Ambrose Manaton John Buller junior James Prade William Painter John Bligh Charles
Grills Richard Hoblin of Anteron George Robinson William Bond John Clobery Francis Painter John Polewheell
Nicholas Morris Emanuell Piper Alexander Pendarves John Waddon William Arscott William Harris Thomas
Achim Samuel Enys John Vowell Anthony Chenowith Nathaniell Moyle Christopher Bellott Alexander Carew
Samuell Langford Edward Lower Phillip Mayow John Barrett of Killegreen Thomas Penhallow Richard Williams
John Murth James Bond Francis Wills Joseph Moyle Jonathan Trelawney George Spry Hugh Jones Henry Vincent
Hugh Tonkin Henry Manaton Francis Manaton Shadrick Vincent Walter Vincent Thomas Kelley John Courtney
John Hicks of Trevithick Hugh Trevanion William Simonds William Bligh Anthony Rouse James Kestle of Kestle
Narcissus Lutterell John Ennis Edmond Phillips Charles Trevanian John Hoblin John Nichold of Trewarn Peter
Trevissa Thomas Hawkey Henry Gregor Richard Pendarves Richard Bonithon Charles Bonithon William Arundell
of Menedarva Christopher Barnes Sampson Hill John Barret of Penquite William Williams of Treworge John
Williams of Trethowa John Williams of Carvean William Hooper Thomas Dodson John Clarke Edmond Spore
Richard Moyle Esquires Charles Kendall Reginald Bawden Jacob Robins Stephen Robins Thomas Waddon John
Foote William Martin William Braddon Reginald Hawkey John Hestell Nicholas Kemp William Hancock Nicholas
Archer Thomas Herle John Robins John Cole William Keckwich John Pennock Thomas Johnson John Kegwin
Charles Huddy Joseph Marke Thomas Glyn William Cock of Helston William Tregea Gentlemen Charles Trevanian
of Tregarthan Richard Harris William Yeo William Ameie Richard Erisey Esquires Christopher Tucker John Foote
John Borlase of Pendeen Esquire Thomas Hoblin of St Columbe Richard Smith of Moorewinstow Gent. William
[Stawen<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Esq[uire] Richard Remfry John Haweis Henry Remfry Phillip Hawkins Gentlemen Dennis Glyn Samuell Gilbert
William Penrose Edward Knebone.</para>
</section>
<section id="s16">
<head>For the County of Cumberland</head>
<para id="p80">Charles Lord Morpeth Sonne and Heire Apparent of Edward Earle of Carlisle The Right Honourable Sir John Lowther
Baronet one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir John Dalston Sir
George Fletcher Sir John Lowther of Whitehaven Sir William Pennington Sir Wilfred Lawson Sir Richard Musgrave
Baronets Sir John Ballentine Sir Daniell Fleming Knights Henry Fletcher Wilfrid Lawson Joseph Hudleston Robert
Carlton Thomas Lamplugh Richard Lamplugh Thomas Denton Anthony Hutton Richard Patrickson Christopher
Richmond Edward Hasell Miles Pennington Edward Stanley William Christian William Gilpin Ewen Christian
Darcy Curwen Leonard Dykes Charles Orpheur John Senhouse Andrew Hudleston Henry Browham Jeremiah Bubb
Christopher Musgrave Henry Fletcher of Tallentire John Punsonby Andrew Whelpdale Richard Lamplugh junior
Thomas Beach John Winder junior Esquires John Briscoe John Foster John Parke junior Richard Senhouse Thomas
Addison James Maxwell Thomas Tickell Charles Smalwood Gent. The Mayor of Carlisle for the time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s17">
<head>For the County of Derby</head>
<para id="p81">The Honourable Anchitel Grey Esquire Sir Thomas Greasley Sir Edward Cooke Sir Henry Every Sir Nathaniell
Curzon Sir Phillip Gell Sir Paul Jenkinson Baronets Sir Simon Degg Sir Gilbert Clarke Sir Edward Abney Knights
Willoughby Gray William Sacheverell Henry Gilbert Francis Munday John Low of Denbigh Mathew Smith Gilbert
Munday Henry Keys Paul Jodrell John Osborne Esquires William Horne William Right Edmond Winter William
Flamsted Henry Lowe Henry Cope William Hunter John Richardson Samuell Richardson Gent. The Mayor of
Derby for the time being John Brookhouse Thomas Goodwin Samuell Spateman Edward Walker Solomon Roberts
Aldermen Biron Stanhope Samuell Bolton John Adderley Esquires George Beardsley Joseph Parker John Bagnold
Samuell Goodwin John Gisborne John Oldershaw Gent. John Stanhope Henry Heveningham Walter Horton Walter
Burdett Robert Wilmott Robert Harding John Every George Greasley Henry Harpur Henry Kendall Gilbert
Thacker William Allestrey John Allen Samuell Holding John Wilkins Esquires John Harpur of Litle Over
Richard Sales Gent. George Vernon Henry Every Henry Cavendish Robert Coke Godfrey Menell Alexander
Stanhope Samuell Pole Thomas Browne Richard Bates Nicholas Wilmott John Burrowes Esquires Robert Doxy
Richard Stubbings Samuell Bradshaw Gentlemen Rowland Oakeover John Berisford Richard Leving Nicholas Hurt
Thomas Milward Robert Milward Esquires John Trott John Stuttin Robert Dale Henry Buxton William James
John Hayne Christopher Ley Sampson Baker William Wingfield John Slacke William Allsopp Francis Sleigh Joseph
Woodhouse Doctor Botham Gentlemen John Shalcrosse William Eyre Thomas Right Henry Bolgay Henry Gilbert
junior John Bullock Esquires John Right John Berisford Thomas Bagshaw Thomas Statham Benjamin Ashton John
Stafford John Calvert James Nailer Gentlemen Samuell Pierpoint Edward Finney John Revell George Sitwell
Cornelius Clarke John Wigfall Robert Revell Thomas Gladwin Thomas Eyre Robert Moore Robert Ashton Thomas
Woolhouse Samuell Halloe Thomas Cotchet John Spateman Esquires The Mayor of Chesterfield for the time
being Richard Youle Richard [Coke<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Peter Dowker Francis Halsworth Aldermen Andrew Clayton John Frogat
John Stevinson Thomas Burley John Smithson George Milward John Wingfield Richard Hall Arthur Dakein John
Dand Paul Webster Gervase Brough Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s18">
<head>For the County of Devon</head>
<para id="p82">The Honourable Edward Russell Esq[uire] the Honourable Robert Russell Esq[uire] the Honourable John Greenvile Esq[uire]
Sir George Hutchins one of the Lords Commissioners of the Great Seale Sir Edward Seymour Sir Peter Prideaux
Sir Francis Drake Sir Ames Pollard Sir Bourchier Wray Sir Courtney Poole Sir Copplestone Bampfield Sir Francis
Northcote Sir William Courtenay Sir John Davie Sir Hugh Ackland Sir William Drake Sir John Fowell Sir Henry
Carew Sir Richard Reynell Sir Walter Young Sir Nicholas Slanning Sir Arthur Chichester Sir Peter Colleton Sir
Thomas Leere Baronets Sir John Rolle Sir Simon Leach Sir Henry Fane Knights of the Bath Sir George Treby
Attourney Generall Sir Thomas Berry Sir Joseph Herne Sir John Tremaine Sergeant at Law Knights Francis
Courtenay Samuell Rolle Henry Portman George Chudleigh Nicholas Morice Richard Duke senior Thomas Reynell
Hugh Bampfield John Clobery Richard Coffin William Spurway of Okeford Humphrey Prideaux of Solden Arthur
Fortescue of Buckland Fillygh Dennis Rolle of Beame Nicholas Dennis John Cholwich Henry Manaton Gideon
Haydon Henry Luscomb Hugh Vaughan Hugh Fortescue Richard Hillersdon Richard Carew of Barly Richard
Carew of Anthony John Moore Richard Osborne Charles Kelland William Hockmore Edmond Reynell of Malston
&AElig;neas Newton John Northcote of Westwood Bamfield Rodd James Rodd John Rowe Richard Courtenay John
Coppleston John Blewet Richard Beavis John Burrington John Fry of Yarty Henry Walcombe Thomas Wood
Roger Wollacombe Christopher Savery Rowland Whiddon Courtenay Crocker Arscott Bickford Henry Chichester
of Coxleigh John Garland Henry Chichester of Hall Martin Rider Charles Hore Richard Langdon of Totnesse
John Elwell Richard Lee of Winslade William Coaleman Samuell Foote Sebastian Isaac Henry Walrond John
Chichester of Widworthy Jonathan Prideaux William Hayne John Battishill John Sandford Jonathan Elford William
Fowell William Bragg Sampson Hele Edmond Parker Thomas Drew William Cary of Clovelly Arthur Champernoon
Francis Bassett John Gifford John Arscott of Tedcott Henry Northleigh Edward Yard of Churston Edmond
Walrond Arthur Tremaine William Harris of Hayne Richard Shapleigh Francis Fulford Edward Fortescue of
Pridleston William Stawell John Quick Hugh Stafford Henry Trelawney John Pole Edmond Prideaux of Ford
John Pollexfen George Prestwood John Kellond George Parker Ambrose Manaton Peter Fortescue Nicholas Martin
Thomas Bere Josias Calmady Richard Nutcombe John Pratt Barister at Law James Hewish of Sand Edmond
Walrond junior Edmond Tremaine Nicholas Rowe James Fortescue James Courtenay William Drake of Netherton
Elise Crimes John Fownes John Martin Edmond Pollexfen Peter Beavis John Rose Elize Bartlett senior Thomas
Southcote of Hedge-End George Southcote Henry Fry Edward Lovett William Drake of Yarbery John Fortescue
George Yeo Robert Hache Christopher Mayne Lewis Incleton John Speccott John Tanner Arthur Champneys
Ambrose Roope Christopher Bale Walter Bogan Peter Atkins Anthony Salter John Cruwis Francis Sheppeard
Nicholas Lutterell of Hartland John Davie William Savery of [Sclade<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Moses Gould Richard Duke junior Gilbert
Yard William Davie Barrister at Law Samuell Tanner Edmond Starre Benjamin Oliver Southcott Lutterell Thomas
Ford Esquires John Bidgood Edmund Davie Edward Ford Richard Burthogge Isaacke Batchlor
of Physicke Doctors of Physicke Jasper Ratcliffe Thomas Southcote of Offwell John Mercer John Upcott John
Southele John Velly of Hartland Henry Stephens William Langford of Braddon John Harris of Wortham John
Simmonds John Northmore Thomas Sampson Thomas Docton of Docton John Cooke Matthias Jenkins John
Hanbury John Contee Robert Rouse Richard Parminster John Hache Gentlemen the Mayor of Plymouth for the
time being the Mayor of Barnstaple for the time being the Mayor of Bidiford for the time being the Mayor
of Totnes for the time being the Mayor of Tiverton for the time being the Mayor of Torrington for the time
being the Mayor of Dartmouth for the time being the Mayor of Plimpton for the time being the Mayor of
Okehampton for the time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s19">
<head>For the City of Exeter</head>
<para id="p83">The Mayor Aldermen Sheriffe and Common Councill for the time being Sir Edward Seymour Baronet Sir
Peter Colleton Baronet Sir George Treby Knight Sir John Tremaine Knight John Bidgood Edmond Davy Thomas
Waterhouse and John Osmond Doctors of Physicke James Walker (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) Thomas Gibbond Barrister at Law John Banks
John Elwill Christopher Mayne Jasper Ratcliffe Nicholas Brooking Thomas Brooking William Adams Thomas
Baron Thomas Potter William Sealy Edmond Starr Richard White Abraham Trout Thomas Gould Robert Rouse
John Pratt Councellor at Law William Wescombe Jerome King Daniell Ivy Edward Dally Henry Newcombe.</para>
</section>
<section id="s20">
<head>For the County of Dorsett</head>
<para id="p84">Sir John Morton Sir Nathaniell Nappier [Sir Robert Nappier<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Baronets Sir John Nicholas Knight of the Bath
Sir George Strode Sir Henry Butler Sir Mathew Andrewes Knights Thomas Freke Thomas Strangwaies Edward
Miller Samuell Rolle Richard Fownes John Banks Robert Freke senior William Okeden junior Thomas Erle
Robert Coker senior Robert Coker junior Edward Nicholas William Whitacre John Still Thomas Greene John
Poole Sebastian Isaack Thomas Chafin Robert Culliford Thomas Freeke junior Thomas Pile Henry Portman
Edward Semour William Strode Robert Williams Thomas Hardy John Williams Michaell Hervey Francis Mohun
Henry Seymour Thomas Chafe Hugh Hodges Sergeant at Law John Eastmont John Fisher Edward Saintloe
George Parry Henry Constantine Anthony Ettericke Robert Browne Thomas Trenchard Richard Brodrip Nathaniell
Bond His Majestyes Serjeant at Law Henry Henning Henry Trenchard George Strangways John Hurding William
Ettrick William Floyer William Bennet the younger of Hartgrove John Lawrence of Grange William Bowles
senior Simon Whetcombe John Ironside John Bowles John Hardy Thomas Turbervile Bullen Reymes Robert
Oxenbrig Seamour Bowman Robert Browne Nathaniell Napier William Churchill Richard Swaine Robert Erle
George Dawbeny John Mitchell Thomas Skinner Charles Bruine William Sidenham Richard Bingham William
Weston Robert Hussey of Stower Paine William Fillioll James Gould Nicholas Gould John Burridge Anthony
Floyer Nicholas Hardy William Bennett Richard Rose Richard Burge Robert Pope Andrew Tucker William
Wake Robert Stephens William Romaine Nicholas Browne Andrew Loder junior George Lester William Lawrence
William Hull Thomas Blandford John Lawrence of White Church George Barber Thomas Bower Arthur Fowkes
John Flint Thomas Cockram William Collin of Linch John Pike John Abington Lewis Cockram Roger Mompesson
Robert Burredge John Edwards Merchants John Strode of Chauntry Solomon Andrews John Fitts Thomas
Chatle John Moore Thomas Gundry Daniell Dugdale Robert Swayne of Corfe Richard Swaine Robert Butler
Thomas Hawles Richard Newman John Richards Henry Henly Thomas Williams the Mayors of Dorchester
Shaftsbury Weymouth and Melcombe Corfe Waream Lyme Regis the Bailiffes of Blandford and Bridport for the
time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s21">
<head>For the Town and County of Poole</head>
<para id="p85">The Mayor for the time being William White Esq[uire] Recorder Moses Darrell senior the Sheriffe for the time
being George Lewin Captaine Robert Bennet John Carter Shadrack Beale senior Moses Durrell junior William
Bowles William Phillips Thomas Smith Thomas Hyde John Pike William Streete William Minty John Gigger
John Jabber.</para>
</section>
<section id="s22">
<head>For the County Palatine of Durham</head>
<para id="p86">The Honourable Charles Mountague Esq[uire] Sir Christopher Musgrave Knight and Baronet Sir Ralph Cole Sir
James Clavering Sir Robert Eden Baronets Sir Ralph Carr Sir William Bowes Knights Christopher Vane John
Tempest William Lambton Robert Bierley Will: Tempest George Morland Henry Lyddell Nicholas Cole Lyonell
Vane Francis Bowes Cuthbert Carr William Foster Mark Shafto Robert Jennison John Davison Thomas Lyddell
James Clavering John Clavering Robert Elleson John Sedgwick William Blacket Charles Wren Edward Tong
Francis Bowes Phillip Bickerstaffe Rowland Place Esquires Thomas Foster of Cornhill Ralph Hedworth Ralph Bales
Frevill Lambton Francis Carr James [Micklton<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Richard Midleton Anthony Salvin John Midleton John Elstobb John
Hall John Hutchinson Esquires William Greevson William Garth William Johnson Edward Shepardson John Carr
John Spearman Captaine Thomas Brasse George Crosier William Wilson William Ettricke Ralph Holmes Abraham
Hilton Thomas Watson Thomas Blacket Robert Dixon Gent. The Mayor of Durham for the time being the Mayor
of Stockton for the time being Arthur Prescott James Cooke Peter Marley William Hutchinson Bernard Doutwaite
William Selly of Beale John Wilky Thomas Gray of Morton Thomas Ord of Felkinton Gilbert Ord of Holy
Island Bryan Gray of Kiley Ralph Watson Patrick Crow Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s23">
<head>For the West Rideing of the County of Yorke.</head>
<para id="p87">Charles Marquesse of Winchester Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Duke of Bolton William Lord Eland Sonne
to the Marquesse of Hallifax William Lord Pawlett second Sonne to the Duke of Bolton Arthur Lord Viscount
Irwin of the Kingdome of Scotland George Lord Viscount Castleton of the Kingdome of Ireland John Lord
Viscount Downe of the Kingdome of Ireland Thomas Lord Fairfax of the Kingdome of Scotland Sydney Wortley
Mountague Esq[uire] Henry Dawney Esq[uire] Henry Fairfax Esq[uire] the Right Honourable Sir Henry Goodricke one of His
Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Sir Thomas Armitage Sir John Kaye Sir William Reresby Sir John
Ingleby Sir John Bland Sir Henry Marwood Sir William Franckland Sir George Cooke Sir Godfrey Copley Sir
Edward Blacket Sir John Tempest Sir John Cutler Sir Henry Slingsby Sir Lyon Pilkington Baronets Sir Edmond
Jennings Sir Ralph Knight Sir John Hewley Sir Jonathan Jennings Sir Michaell Wentworth Sir Patience Ward
Sir Stephen Thompson Sir Thomas Hodgson Sir William Lowther Sir John Coghill Knights Henry Lyddell Thomas
Franckland Christopher Tanckred William Palmes Robert Bierley Francis Nevill Richard Beaumont of Whitley John
Goodrick Walter Calverley Cerill Arthington Welbury Norton Thomas Fawkes William Stockdale Charles Osborne
Christopher Lister John Knight Denzill Onslow Arthur Ingram William Wombwell Francis Foulgham John Ramsden
of Hatfield Thomas Yorke John Bradshaw Thomas Yarbrough Thomas Vincent William Ellis William Vavasour
Henry Thompson Henry Stapleton Inglebert Leeds Anthony Fletcher John Lister of Bawtry Ralph Lowther Henry
Hitch Bryon Sunderland Ambrose Pudsey Thomas Lister of Westby Thomas Horton John Eastoft Godfrey Bosvile
John Ashton Francis Jessop Metcalfe Robinson John Lambert Henry Edmunds Richard Redmund Thomas Fountagn
Jasper Blithman Christopher Wilkinson John Ferrar William Rhodes Thomas Parker Francis White Thomas Dodson
John Gill Henry Cooke Miles Staveley John Stanhope of Horseforth Jonathan Jennings William Roundhill Robert
Mitford Christopher Adams Roger Portington William Fairfax John Garland William Jennings Mathew Boynton
Robert Baines Gervase Nevill John Hatfield of Laughton Cuthbert Wade Richard Staines Christopher Driffield
Bennet Sherrard Thomas Hesletine John [Rockes<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Rowland Norton William Johnston Thomas Kirke Robert Ferrand
Tobias Harvey Thomas Lea John Warner Henry Bouch John Atkinson George Towlson Richard Shutleworth
William Ingram Andrew Wilkinson John Auby Henry Currer Robert Frank Thomas Wakefield William Bethell
Thomas Beech Esquires Richard Hutton Thomas Edmonds senior Thomas Edmonds junior John Batty Gent. Simon
Sterne Esq[uire] Thomas Rokeby Robert Parker William Norton Armstrong Gregory John Copley Richard Hewit
James Greenwood Godfrey Copley Bartin Allott John Savill of Cridlin Benjamin Watts Richard Nettleton Edward
Thompson Lawrence Warton Michaell Warton of Bawtry Gentlemen Francis Wheatley Phisician John Spencer of
Canan Hall Henry Wood Richard Cholmley of Breame Andrew Holden John Preston Stephen Wilks Thomas
Craven Coates of Kilwick Francis Elwicke Thomas Warder of Northcoate Thomas Carleton Cuthbert
Chambers Gregory Fish Josias Midgley Robert Inman Robert Squire Southern Thomas Thompson Benjamin
Mawds Gerase Hill Gentlemen The Mayor and Aldermen of Pontefract the Mayor and Aldermen of Doncaster
the Mayor and Aldermen of Rippon the Mayor and Aldermen of Leeds.</para>
</section>
<section id="s24">
<head>For the North Rideing of the County of Yorke</head>
<para id="p88">Charles Lord Marquesse of Winton Eldest Sonne to the Duke of Bolton John Lord Viscount Downe of the
Kingdome of Ireland Thomas Lord Fairfax of the Kingdome of Scotland Arthur Lord Viscount Irwin of the
Kingdome of Scotland Phillip Darcey Esq[uire] Sir Marmaduke Wivell Sir William Leveson Gower Sir William Strickland
Sir John Bowles Sir David [Fowles<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Sir John Kaye Sir John Hotham Sir Watkinson Payler Sir Bryan Stapilton Sir
William Frankland Sir John Lowther Sir Henry Marwood Sir William Caley Sir Christopher Wandesford Sir
Thomas Pennyman Sir Edward Blacket Sir John Brooke Sir William Chater Sir Marke Milbank Sir William
Robinson Sir Gilbert Gerrard Baronets Sir William Hustler Sir Babington Bourchier Sir John Hewley Sir Henry
Bellasis Sir William Ascough Sir William Bowes Sir Samuell Gerrard Knights Thomas Frankland George Marwood
William Palmes Thomas Yorke William Thompson Henry Metcalfe George Smithson Francis Wivell Robert Water
Roger Crofft John Wastall John Hutton Roger Talbutt Cornelius Caley Abstrupus Danby John Howe Thomas
Croft Edward Hutchinson William Tankred Francis Thompson Bernard Greenvill John Trotter Leonard Smelt
Charles Duncomb Christopher Darcy John Dodsworth Thomas Harrison Anthony Lowther Timothy Maleverer
Thomas Worsley William Metcalfe John Gibson Thomas Lassells Richard Staynes Daniell Lassells Thomas Wakefield
William Chaulenor Francis Hall Theodore Bathurst Edward Thompson Richard Peirs John Peirs William Osbaldeston
John Hill junior Thomas Gower John Hopton James Mountaigne Luke Robinson Thomas Pullen Thomas Metcalfe
John Beverley John Beilby George Norton Rowland Norton Thomas Cradock Thomas Wivill Humphrey Wharton
Constable Bradshaw Thomas Binloes of Hargrave William Dawson Mathew Anglaby Richard Darley Thomas
Hesletine Towers Driffield Thomas Langley Esquires Christopher Pearcy Hay of Whalton Gentleman Roger Covill
Esq[uire] Doctor Smith of Easby Doctor Henry Squire Leonard Hartley Benjamin Percusse Edward Place William Davill
Phillip Prince James Conyers William Kitchinman Robert Bell George Norton Stephen Driffield Robert Bushell
Timothy Ford Ralph Porter John Robinson Guy Butler William Farside junior Paul Batty John Cockerill senior
Robert Burton William Stoope Roger Lee Gentlemen Thomas Lassells of Soreby Esq[uire] Thomas Pierson Timothy
Portington Stephen Thompson Thomas Holmes Mathew Smales John Robinson of Easby Thomas Guise Robert
Crosfield The Mayor and Aldermen of Richmond the Bailiffes of Scarborough for the time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s25">
<head>For the East Rideing of the County of Yorke.</head>
<para id="p89">Arthur Lord Viscount Irwin of the Kingdome of Scotland Thomas Lord Fairfax of the Kingdome of Scotland
Charles Boyle Esq[uire] George Dawney Esq[uire] Sir Francis Boynton Sir John Hotham Sir William Strickland Sir Henry
St. Quinton Sir Watkinson Payler Sir Thomas Rudston Sir John Legard Sir John Kaye Baronets Sir Michaell
Warton Sir Ralph Warton Sir William Cobb Sir Mathew Peirson Sir [James Bradshaw Sir Jonathan Atkins Sir<ref idref="n14">14</ref>]
Richard Osbaldeston Sir John Hewley Sir John Napier Knights Griffith Boynton William Osbaldeston William
Grimston Ingleby Daniell Henry Thompson William Gee Henry Guy William Thompson Francis Thompson
Mathew Appleyard Charles Osborne John Ramsden James Heblethwaite Ralph Warton Charles Warton Edward
Bernard Hugh Bethell Walter Strickland Robert Mountayne Thomas Langley William Bethell John Stapylton
Thomas Hesket Robert Pricket John Lister John Eastoft William Dawson Richard Remington Richard Gee
Richard Thompson senior Robert Bucke Mathew Alured Thomas Alured Edward Hutchinson Tobias Jenkins
senior Tobias Jenkins junior Humphrey Robinson Walter Compton Robert Constable William St Quinton Christopher
Lister John Tayler Thomas Southaby Edward Thompson James Moyser John Moyser William Moore Robert Hollis
William Headlam Richard Darley Henry Portington Esq[uire] Ralph Lutton Benjamin Overton Bernard Lister Gentlemen
Charles Hilyard Esq[uire] John Bucke John Peirson John Gee Charles Hotham Charles Best William Dickenson Robert
Jeggon Edward Bower William Bower William Wilberfosse Philip Wilkinson Thomas Johnson Henry Maisters
Thomas Rickaby John Rickaby John Hill William Hudson senior Richard Thompson junior Henry Bernard
Christopher Piercy Hay Leonard Robinson of Newton Garth Francis Blunt of the same William Rowsby Gent.
The Mayor and Aldermen of Beverley the Mayor and Aldermen of Heddon.</para>
</section>
<section id="s26">
<head>For the City of Yorke and County of the same City</head>
<para id="p90">The Lord Mayor Aldermen and Sheriffes for the time being Charles Marquesse of Winchester eldest Sonne to
the Duke of Bolton Arthur Lord Viscount Irwin of the Kingdome of Scotland Thomas Lord Fairfax Baron
Cameron of the Kingdome of Scotland The Right Honourable Sir Henry Goodricke Knight and Baronet one of
Their Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Sir William Robinson Sir John Brooke Baronets Sir John Hewley
Sir Stephen Thompson Knights George Pricket Esq[uire] Recorder Toby Wickham Doctor of Divinity Deane of Yorke
Henry Watkinson Doctor of Law Henry Thompson Thomas Hutton Henry Stapilton Bennett Sherard William
Fairfax of Steeton William Roundell Edward Thompson of Marston Thomas Hesletine John Baines Henry Squire
Thomas Langley Thomas Moseley Roger Shackleton Esquires Andrew Perret Thomas Nesbit Thomas Benson
Richard [Rynolds<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] Phillip Prince Francis Duckworth [Christopher<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Hutton Christopher Breary William Thompson
William Hesletine Robert Squire Thomas Holmes Richard Hewitt Richard Sowray Thomas Thompson Nicholas
Sugar Thomas Harrison Samuell Walker William Mortimer Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s27">
<head>For the Towne and County of Kingston upon Hull</head>
<para id="p91">Anthony Ivison Esq[uire] Mayor Robert Hollis Esq[uire] Recorder Christopher Richardson Thomas Johnson Henry Maisters
Simon Sissons Robert Mason Francis Delachamp Phillip Wilkinson Robert Carlile Robert Trippet William Hydes
Richard Gray George Battus Aldermen William Hall Sheriffe Charles Osborne John Ramsden John Eastoft William
Dawson [John<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Legard Esquires Sir James Bradshaw Knight.</para>
</section>
<section id="s28">
<head>For the County of Essex</head>
<para id="p92">The Right Honourable Charles Lord Cheyne of the Kingdome of Scotland The Honourable Robert Bertie
Bainister Maynard Richard Barrett Ralph Grey William Maynard Esquires Sir John Barrington Sir William
Appleton Sir Samuell Grinston Sir William Hicks Sir Francis Masham Sir Andrew Jenour Sir Thomas Nightingale
Sir Richard Everard Sir William Luckin Sir Thomas Litleton Sir Martin Lumley Sir Anthony Abdy Sir John
Abdy Sir Thomas Draper Sir Thomas Darcy Sir Gervase Elwes Sir Edward Smith Sir James Rushout Sir
Thomas Bernardiston Sir Charles Tyrrell Sir William Barker Sir Robert Smith Sir Josiah Childe Sir Peter Soame
Sir John Dyer Sir Cave James Sir John Sudbury Baronets Sir John Brampston Knight of the Bath Sir Edward
Farmer Sir Anthony Browne Sir John Sparrow Sir Richard Piggott Sir Thomas Fanshaw Sir Eliab Harvey Sir
Gobart Barrington Sir Thomas Chambers Sir Thomas Midleton Sir Edward Turner Sir Thomas Devall Sir John
Marshall Sir Mark Guyon Sir Benjamin Thorowgood Sir John Rotheram Sir Samuell Husbands Knights John
Osborne John Conyers Esquires the Kings Councill Henry Mildmay John Le Mott Honeywood [Henry<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] Wroth
Collonell John Cutts Francis Ha vey alias Mildmay [Carew Harvey ats Mildmay<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Thomas Luther William Coward
Abraham Wessell Thomas Dawtry Robert Bateman Charles Mountague Edward Cary Samuell [Rinolds<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] William
Palmer William Peck William Pert William Atwood John Greene Josiah Childe Ralph Freeman Richard Hutchinson
Thomas Argoll William Glascock James Butler William Campion Joseph Offley Evan Lloyd William Wright
Benjamin Desbrow Richard Andrews Francis Barrington Thomas Gardner Christopher Fowler Anthony Brampston
Anthony Lowther Nathaniell Tench Richard Vaughan John Rotheram Robert Ashton John Barrington Isaac
Rebow Thomas Burgh Brabazon Aylmer William Beaumont Robert Cole John Wale John Simonds William
Clopton William Lingwood John Tyndall Timothy Felton Thomas Barrington John Eldred Samuell Westerne John
Cox Robert Mildmay John Cooke of Chissell Owen Wynne Samuell Hare Francis Maidstone Edward Bullocke
senior Edward Bullocke junior John Lockey Neale of Avery Hatch Thomas Gray John Goodyer
William Walker Thomas Weely Thomas Harlackenden Bowes Thomas Waldgrave John Plummer Giles Dent
William Kendall Andrew Searle Alexander Prescott Clutterbucke of Engelston Richard Staines Cuthbert
Martin William Harvey William Scott William Nutt John Pennington Francis St Johns Henry St Johns Thomas
Turner John Sparrow John Cressener Henry Glascock Waldgrave Pelham Samuell Wiseman Erasmus Smith
John Meade Thomas Abdy Henry Ayloffe Phillip Sattinston John Hothersell Richard Hyde William Mott
Edmond Goodwin John Edwards Nathaniell Right John Fanshaw John Luther Luther of Miles Francis
Bradbury Haines Barley senior Haines Barley junior Nicholas Corsellis Ralph Creffield Nathaniell Lawrence
Francis Wheeler Samuell Gibbs George Gent Henry Pascall Edward Thoroughgood John Haines John Hopwood
John Godbold John Allyn John Larkin Sigismund Trafford Robert Smith Robert Bragg Christopher Grange
Nicholas Martin Samuell Rawston Esquires John Elliston Isaac Lutman John Litle Gent. James Horsmanden Charles
Tyrrell Clerks Marke Mott Samuell Warner Robert Barwell junior Ralph Hawkins Robert Tayler John Bennet
William Herris Thomas Greene John Josceline Jeremiah Richardson John Savill William Boice John Potter Henry
Lambe Thomas Scarlet Nichols John Stilman John Rayner Hope Gifford Richard Willis Charles Wale
of Walden Joseph Sparrow Harrison of Braintree Richard Cowper John Elliott Nicholas Jekill George
Wale of Radwinter Thomas Coe senior John Wiggoner John Rebow Abraham Hodgthorne John Witham
Gentlemen Robert Williamson Thomas Chambers Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s29">
<head>For the Towne of Malden</head>
<para id="p93">The Bailiffes for the time being Sir John Brampston Knight of the Bath High Steward Sir Thomas Darcey
Sir William [Sprignoll<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] Baronets Charles Mountague Anthony Brampston Esquires John Mathews William Heckford
Phillip Ralling John Cockerill John Pond Samuell Pond Thomas Horsenaile Aldermen William Carr Towne Clerke
William Vernon Thomas Coe senior John Stevens John Brickwood Ezekiell Finch Thomas Stace Henry May
John Straite Thomas Stephens William Coe Thomas Coe junior.</para>
</section>
<section id="s30">
<head>For the Towne of Colchester</head>
<para id="p94">The Mayor and Aldermen for the time being John Eldred Recorder Isaac Rebow Esquire Samuell Reynolds
Edward Cary Nathaniell Lawrence Ralph Creffield John Shaw Francis Wheeler William Moore Esquires William
Boyce John Savile Robert Moore Gentlemen John Rebow Abraham Hedgethorne Charles Richardson Thomas Ruse
William Mott Esquire Samuell Greet Jacob Fromanteal Mathew Scrivener</para>
</section>
<section id="s31">
<head>For the Towne of Harwich</head>
<para id="p95">The Mayor for the time being the Right Honourable Charles Lord Cheyne of the Kingdome of Scotland Sir
Thomas Midleton Knight Sir Phillip Parker Baronet Sir Thomas Devall Knight John Eldred Esq[uire] Thomas Langley
John Rolfe Robert Seaman John Browne William Garrard Daniell Smith Charles Smith Aldermen John Phillips
Thomas Bradshaw John Westbrowne Robert Lane Henry Munt Henry Cole William Wood Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s32">
<head>For the County of Gloucester</head>
<para id="p96">Charles Marquesse of Worcester Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Duke of Beaufort William Lord Viscount
Tracy of the Kingdome of Ireland The Right Honourable Henry Powle Esq[uire] Master of the Rolls and one of his
Majesties most Honourable Privy Councill The Right Honourable Sir Robert Atkins Knight of the Bath and Lord
Chiefe Baron of Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer and Speaker of the House of Peeres The Right Honourable
Sir Henry Capell Sir James Rushout Sir Richard Cox Sir William Kyte Sir Francis Russell Sir Robert Southwell
Sir John Newton Sir William Forester Sir Gabriell Lowe Sir Thomas Stephens Sir Ralph Dutton Sir Richard
Onslow Sir Fleetwood Dormer Sir Duncombe Colchester Sir John Ash Sir John Fust Sir Richard Hart Sir
Thomas Cann Sir John Guise Sir Robert Atkins senior Sir Heale Hooke James Thynne Esq[uire] Benjamin [Barton<ref idref="n22">22</ref>]
Richard Dowdeswell Thomas Foley George Pitt Richard Freeman John Mariott junior Charles Dowdeswell
William Lane John Parsons junior John Delabeare William Baggot John Carter junior Henry Coxwell William
Dewy Thomas Janes Samuell Hawlins Thomas Hales David Warren Anthony Lawrence Danvers Hodges Henry
Criswick Nathaniell Stephens Thomas Rawlins Sergeant at Law Thomas Hodges Walter Estcourt John Browning
Samuell Trotman William Kingscote William Dennis John Howe John Coxwall William Hall Robert Vesey Andrew
Barker Robert Plydall George Hanger Robert Outridge Thomas Maisters Brierton Bouchier Richard Howe Thomas
Smith Thomas Horton Phillip Shepard Thomas Ridler of Edgeworth Henry Chivers Esquires Thomas Stephens
Jonathan Castleman Lionell Rich Peachy Edward Stephens Paul Dodwell Conway Withorne Josua
Aylworth George Bond John Hickford Maynard Colchester Thomas Parke William Madocks Paul Foley Rice
Yeates Reginald Pindar William Rogers Wenman Winniatt William Bayly George Lloyd James Mitchell Richard
Yeate William Try Thomas Chester Thomas Wise Edward Smith Richard Jones John [Meridiath<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Thomas Barwell
John Dowse Edward Mountague William Pansefoote Thomas Browne of Coslawne John Parkhurst William
Winter Samuell Dobbins Michaell Beale William Cooke Edward Cooke William Guise William Selwin Rowland
Wood William Lawrence John Powell Sergeant at Law Henry Brett John Cox William Scudamore William
Hodges Stephen Baldwin Robert Codrington Christopher Mountacu Edmond Chamberlaine Samuell Barker John
Griffin William Clutterbook Richard Holford Richard Haynes John Stafford Samuell Codrington John Nelin John
Berkley William Bovey Thomas Trigg Nathaniell Perke Richard Haward William Winter Pansfoote
Edward Smith George Smith William Blathwaite Christopher Cole David Warren Richard Diton Jasper Chapman
William George Richard Holford Edmund Madock.</para>
</section>
<section id="s33">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Gloucester</head>
<para id="p97">The Mayor for the time being Sir Duncombe Colchester Knight John Powell Sergeant at Law William Cooke
William Try John Cox Esquires John Rogers William Lamb Robert Payne John Ewins William Nicholls William
Hodges William Corsly William Tayler Aldermen John Githens Gent. Peter Haynes Thomas Webb Sheriffes
Thomas Browne Thomas Snell William Jourdon Nicholas Webb senior Nicholas Webb junior Samuell Eckly
Samuell Palmer Benjamin Hyott Thomas Webb Arnold Aram Thomas Longdon Edward Gibbs Henry Hutter
Gent. John Hyet Benjamin Rose Samuell Lye Samuell Burrougs John Bebb.</para>
</section>
<section id="s34">
<head>For the County of Hereford</head>
<para id="p98">The Right Honourable Henry Powle Esquire Master of the Rolls and one of Their Majestyes most Honourable
Privy Councill John Lord Viscount Scudamore of Sligo in the Realme of Ireland The Honourable Chambre
Brabazon Esq[uire] Sir William Gregory Knight one of the Justices of Their Majesties Court of Kings Bench Sir
John Morgan Sir Herbert Croft Sir John Hoskins Baronets Sir Edward Harley Knight of the Bath Sir Francis
Winnington Sir Thomas Duppa Sir John Williams Knights Thomas Coningsby of Hampton-Court Thomas Geeres
Serjeant at Law William Fines Paul Foley Robert Harley Thomas Price John Birch John Dutton Colt Robert
Price James Morgan John Scudamore of Kentchurch Thomas Cornwall of Stepleton Thomas Harley of Kinsham
Ambrose Scudamore Richard Reed senior Richard Reed junior Herbert Westfailing Thomas Cockes Edward
Hopton Robert Cornwall Edward Cornwall William Dansey senior William Dansey junior John Arnold Charles
Baldwin John Williams Richard Williams of Cabalva Edward Litleton Uvedale Tompkins Robert Chaplin Thomas
Foley senior Thomas Foley junior James Gregory John Booth of Letton John How Jeremiah Bubb Edward
Jackson Younger Cooke James Penoyer of the Moore [Robert Dobins Robert Minors William Wintour Will Lambe
John Nourse Marsyall Bridges Richard Barnby (<ref idref="n24">24</ref>) Fardinando Gorges<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] (<ref idref="n26">26</ref>) Sandys Lechmere John Parry of Dulas
Thomas Delahay [Thomas Hewer James Lloyd of the Moore<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] Richard Kidley Esquires John Hoskins of Ponithan
William Gwillim of Langstone William Bridges of Colwell John Phillips of the Worlds End John Walsham
Samuell Birch John Whittington Henry Jones Gentlemen Anthony Rowden John Powell of the While Francis
Baskerville of Eardesley Thomas Wigmore John Kirle John Goodyar James Wellington Gilbert Nicholas Henry
Bull Silas Vaughan John Price Esquires Thomas Owen of Litle Brompton Thomas Carpenter of Tillington Richard
Skipp James Woodhouse of Woodhouse Essex Sherborne Francis Woodhouse Humphrey Mayo John Woolrich
Edward Rodd John Fletcher Francis Geeres John Kidley junior of Fownehope John Hereford of Hom-Lacy
James Westfailing John Carver of Upton James Walwine John Hereford of Sufton Daniell Kerry Peter Smith
John Smith of Holmer Gentlemen John Abrahall of Ingeston Esq[uire] John Scudamore of Langarron Roger Scudamore
of Trecella Thomas Rawlins Esquire William Gwilliam of Langston junior.</para>
</section>
<section id="s35">
<head>For the City of Hereford</head>
<para id="p99">The Mayor for the time being John Lord Viscount Scudamore of Sligo in the [Kingdome<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] of Ireland Sir William
Gregory Knight one of the Justices of Their Majestyes Court of Kings Bench Paul Foley Henry Cornwall Herbert
Westfailing Thomas Price Esq[uire]s Robert Simonds Thomas Paynard Abraham Seward Thomas Matthews Richard
Wadeley Aldermen Gabriell Bleeke Esq[uire] Hugh Rodd Richard Williams Thomas Clarke senior Thomas Clarke
junior Henry Smith Thomas Smith Edward Rodd John Williams senior John Williams junior James Price John
Abrahall Richard Gower Edmund Weaver Theophilus Alye Richard Poole Thomas Church Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s36">
<head>For the Burrough of Lempster</head>
<para id="p100">The Bayliffe for the time being Thomas Coningsby John Dutton Colt Edward Harley Esquires William Bach
Edward Bangham James Powle John Jennings Thomas Hardwick Thomas Manings John Bangham Richard Powle
Henry Browne James Caswald Caleb Powle William Phillips.</para>
</section>
<section id="s37">
<head>For the County of Hertford</head>
<para id="p101">The Right Honourable Sir Henry Capell Knight of the Bath and one of Their Majestyes most Honourable
Privy Councill The Honourable Robert Cecill Esquire The Honourable Sir William Egerton Knight of the Bath
Sir Samuell Grimston Sir John Garrard Sir Richard Franklin Sir John Austin Sir Robert [Joscelin<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] Sir William
Cowper Sir William Leman Sir Thomas Pope Blount Sir John Brograve Sir Jonathan Keate Sir John Witterong
Sir Richard Anderson Sir Edmund Anderson Sir John Reed Baronets Sir Humphrey Gower Sir Charles Cesar
Sir Ralph Ratcliffe Sir Thomas Bide Sir William Litton Sir John Bucknall Sir Robert Marsham Sir Francis Leigh
Sir William Parkins Sir Nicholas Miller Sir Adam Ottley Sir Benjamin Tichburne Knights George Churchill
Silus Titus Henry Guy Robert Austen Thomas Austen William Gore John Gore Ralph Freeman senior Ralph
Freeman junior Robert Elwayes Thomas Halsey John Plummer Edward Chester William Cowper George Munson
Francis Flyer Jeremiah Hale Thomas Priestly Thomas Atkins Israell Mayo Edward Briscoe senior Edward Briscoe
junior William Briscoe Thomas Aram Gilbert Hoo Keat George Hadley James Witterong James Stedman
John Charleton William Emmerton Thomas Emmerton James Forrester James Gulston Mathew Blucke James
Berners William Newce Samuell Robinson James Wilmott Thomas Stone John Gardener Roger Coningsby
Marmaduke Rawden Thomas Arris Robert Robotham John Gape senior Henry Childe Richard Helder Goodwin
Barrington John Methwen Joseph Marsh Thomas Ellis George Nodes Ralph Wingate Thomas Bird of Mattacks
Bernard Turner Paris Slaughter John Duncombe George White Daniell Shelden Edward Saires John Weatherhead
Esquires John Leman Josua Lomax Thomas Lomax John Woolleston Thomas Nicholls of Bushey John Gape junior
Eynon Bynon Thomas How Thomas Windford Edward Seymour Francis King John Poyner Nudigate Pointz
Gentlemen Thomas Bownest Esq[uire] John Woodhouse Batchlour in Physicke Edmond Smith William Greenhill John
Jenkins Gentlemen The Mayors of Saint Albans and Hertford for the time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s38">
<head>For the Borough of St Albans</head>
<para id="p102">The Mayor Recorder and Aldermen for the time being Sir Samuell Grimston Baronet George Churchill
Thomas Arris John Gape Robert Robotham Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s39">
<head>For the County of Huntington</head>
<para id="p103">The Honourable Robert Mountague Esq[uire] The Honourable Sidney Wortley Mountague Esq[uire], The Honourable
Richard Mountague Esq[uire] Sir John Cotton Sir Robert Bernard Baronets Charles Mountague John Proby John Dryden
John Conyers Robert Appriece Arthur Turnour Charles Cesar John Bigg Anthony Hamound Richard Nailour
William Nailour James Torkington John Ferrer John Pockington Robert Pulline Philip Storey Robert Throckmorton
John Trice Richard Drury Esquires Robert Clarke Richard Winde Richard Hatley William Fuller James Wright
Thomas Gilbert Edward Checkley William Love Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s40">
<head>For the Towne of Huntingdon</head>
<para id="p104">The Mayor for the time being The Honourable Sidley Wortley alias Mountague Esq[uire] The Honourable
Richard Mountague Esq[uire] John Pocklinton Esq[uire] George Meritt Richard Astrey James Fairside William Downe
Thomas Sayer Joseph Darlow Thomas Harris Angell Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s41">
<head>For the County of Kent.</head>
<para id="p105">Anthony Lord Viscount Faulkland of the Kingdome of Scotland Thomas Lord Fairfax Baron of Cameroon of
the Kingdome of Scotland The Honourable Sir Vere Fane Knight of the Bath The Honourable Peregrine
Berty Esq[uire] Sir William Twisden Sir Charles Sidley of Southfleet Sir Charles Sidley of Saint Cleare Sir Thomas
Roberts Sir Henry Palmer Sir Phillip Boteler Sir Thomas Culpeper of Aylesford Sir Thomas Stiles Sir George
Rivers Sir Bazill Dixwell Sir John Knatchbull Sir John Rainy Sir Robert Hales Sir Stephen Leonard Sir Humphrey
Millerd Sir John Marsham Sir William Honeywood Sir Thomas Pierce Sir John Banks Sir Nathaniell Powell Sir
John Austen Sir Thomas Selyard Sir Anthony Aucher Sir John Fagg Sir James Oxenden Sir William Swan Sir
Robert Filmore Sir John Shaw Sir John Cutler Sir Roger Twisden Sir William Cooper Sir Francis Lawley Sir
George Chute Sir Thomas Tailor Sir John Mordant Sir John Lethelier Baronets Sir William Pritchard Sir John
Darrell Sir George Curteis Sir Charles Bickerstaffe Sir Henry Boswell Sir Nicholas Crispe Sir Robert Faunce
Sir Nicholas Toke Sir Thomas Culpeper Sir Robert Marsham Sir James Hayes Sir Joseph Williamson Sir William
Langhorne Sir William Hooker Sir Edward [Masters<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] Sir Purbecke Temple Knights Collonell Beaumont Lieutenant
of Dover Castle Christopher Vane Robert Smith Thomas Fane Edward Roper Edward Hales Thomas Knatchbull
William Watton [Jeffery Amhurst Charles Amhurst<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] Thomas Rider William Campion Caleb Banks John Leech
Robert Lewkener Gideon de Laune John Kitchell Esquires George Harlackenden Gentleman William Boyes of
Hawkhurst William Henden Robert Austen senior Robert Craford James Masters of Langden Walter Breames
Herbert Randolph Esquires John Boyes Gentleman John Thurbone Serjeant at Law William Hammond Gent.
George Scott Esquire James Chadwicke William Kingsley junior Christopher Mills Samuell Short Esquires
William Brockman of Bitchburrow William Brockman of Cheriton John Crump Thomas Moile Gentleman
Thomas Papillon Thomas Munn Francis Bathurst Esquires John Plummer of Northdowne William De Laune Thomas
Sackvill James Bunce George Petty William Selby George Polhill John Hide Major Gibbons Robert Gibbon
John Cooke Thomas Osborne James Herbert Ralph Bufkin John Brewer John Packer Thomas Dallison Edward
Gulston Reynold Peckham William Cage Nicholas [Miller<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] John Wilkinson Richard Godden John Knatchbull Andrew
Brewer Thomas Manley Esquires Thomas Scott William Honeywood Gentlemen George Sayers Vice-Chamberlaine
to the Queene Dowager John Le Mott Honeywood William Hugesen Leonard Diggs Thomas Gomelden Julius
Deeds John Sherman Christopher Deering Esquires Gerrard Goore Nicholas Cooke Gentlemen Vincent Denn
Serjeant at Law George Elcock Esquire William Jacob Doctor of Physick Henry Oxenden Henry Hawley Richard
Oxenden John Mitchell Esquires Doctor John Taylor Francis Clerke Esq[uire] Captaine Pettit of Thannet Moses
Napleton Gent. Herbert Palmer Wortley Whorwood Henry Lee Esquires John Whitfield Henry Godden Charles
Bargrave William Courthope Gentlemen Robert Heath John Evelin Edward Austin William Lambert William
Ash Esquires William Wilkinson John Mascall Phillip Bartholomew Gent. George Gifford Francis Farnaby Ralph
Petley William Swan John Buggins Robert Austin junior James Codd Alexander Culpeper Samuell Plumer
Esquires William (<ref idref="n33">33</ref>) White Gent. John Cripps of Maidstone Roger Paine Thomas Napleton Esquires Thomas Godfrey
of Hoddiford Gent. George Rooks Edward Nutt Henry Marsh Thomas Brewer of Northfleete Thomas Washer
Robert Mitchell Thomas Blisse Jeffery Boise Edward Boise Samuell Shaw John Cason Thomas Hales senior Phillip
Papillon Thomas Hales junior George Curteis Esquires George Maplesden Charles Courthope Thomas Turner
Gentlemen Thomas Adrian John Fotherby Francis Barrell Thomas Selyard Christopher Allison Henry Sandis
Percivall Hart Edward Manning Edward Brent James Fortrey Edward Grace Creswell Draper Edward King Thomas
[Gilford<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] Edward Bettison Edward Toke Esquires The Mayor of Rochester for the time being The Mayor of
Maidstone for the time being John Bloome Charles Fagg Gentlemen William Randolph John Culpeper Esquires
Thomas Meredith Gent. Humphrey Stiles Esq[uire] Richard Hulse of Bethersden Gent. George Withwicke Gent. Thomas
Withwicke Esq[uire] Thomas Brett William Brett Gent. Edward Manley of Wooldham the Jurats of Maidstone being
Justices of the Peace John Eve Gent. the Bayliffe and Expenditors of Rumney Marsh for the time being Benjamin
Godfrey John Bond Major Nettit of Maidstone William Turner Barnham Powell [Esquires<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] Thomas Morris Gent.
William James Esq[uire] Captaine Tomlin Mr Coppin of Deale Christopher Mason Christopher Sherman Christopher
May Edward Bathurst Thomas Marsh Gent. Charles Kenrick John Linch Esquires Thomas Chiffinch John Baron
Gentlemen William Spencer Esq[uire] Captaine Curthope The Mayor of Gravesend for the time being Christopher
Waters Gent. William Yardley Esquire William Culpeper of Hollingbourne George Etkins John Christmas Thomas
Cooke of Bobbing Place William Tyndall William Courthope Esquires Captaine Richard Simons Captaine Francis
Wheeler George Cartar Gent. Charles Cesar Esq[uire] Henry Parker Robert Minors Esquire Governour of Upnoare
Castle John Moyse William Watson Bartholomew Gent. Francis Brookes Gent. John Dyke Esq[uire]</para>
</section>
<section id="s42">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Canterbury</head>
<para id="p106">Henry Waddell Esq[uire] Mayor Vincent [Deane<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] [Esq[uire]<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] Sergeant at Law Recorder Sir William Honeywood Sir Anthony
Aucher Baronets Henry Lee John Cason Edward Nutt Esquires Herbert Randolph Jeffery Boyes William Turner
William Courthope Esquires William Jacob Doctor of Phisick John Taylor Doctor at Law John Whitfield William
Watson Gentlemen Thomas Fidge Thomas Knoller Nicholas Nicholson Thomas Dunkin William Guilbert John
Gnarling Squire Bennerton Henry Gibbs and Francis Jeffery Aldermen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s43">
<head>For the Towne and Port of Sandwich</head>
<para id="p107">The Mayor and Jurats for the time being John Thurborne Serjeant at Law Edward Brent Esq[uire] Richard Hawker
Towne Clerke.</para>
</section>
<section id="s44">
<head>For the Towne and Port of Dover.</head>
<para id="p108">The Mayor for the time being Thomas Papillon and James Chadwicke Esquires Captaine William Stokes George
West William Richards John Bullock Nicholas Cullen senior Thomas Scott Edward Wivell Edward Francklin
Jurats Sir Abraham Jacob Knight Nathaniell Denew John Matson Frederick De Vinck Robert Jacob Thomas
Raworth John Ford Charles Johnson William Eaton Phillip [Yorke<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] Abraham Stock and Nicholas Cullen junior Gent.</para>
</section>
<section id="s45">
<head>For the Towne and Port of Rumney</head>
<para id="p109">The Mayor for the time being Sir Charles Sidley Barronet John Brewer Esq[uire] John Chalker John Hunt Peter
Martin Richard Baker Jurats William Finch Anthony Evans and Peter Evans.</para>
</section>
<section id="s46">
<head>For the Towne and Port of Hyeth</head>
<para id="p110">The Mayor for the time being Sir Phillip Boteler Baronet William Brockman Esq[uire] Julius Deedes Esq[uire] Robinson
Beane Henry Deeds William Browne Claudius Clares Elias Bassett Jurats Thomas Tournay Gentleman.</para>
</section>
<section id="s47">
<head>For the Towne of Fordwich</head>
<para id="p111">The Mayor for the time being Samuel Short Esquire.</para>
</section>
<section id="s48">
<head>For Feversham</head>
<para id="p112">The Mayor for the time being Charles Kendricke Esq[uire] Thomas Napleton Thomas Knoller John Marsh Thomas
Waterman and Joseph Edwards Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s49">
<head>For the Towne of Folkeston</head>
<para id="p113">The Mayor for the time being Sir Bazill Dixwell Baronet William Brockman Esq[uire] Mr William Jenkins Miles
Jacob Thomas Fagg Robert Hammond Gibbon Ladd and Thomas Jenkins Gent.</para>
</section>
<section id="s50">
<head>For the Towne of Lidd</head>
<para id="p114">Julius Deeds Henry Wynne Esquires John Bateman Humphry Lee William Batchelour Nicholas Dye.</para>
</section>
<section id="s51">
<head>For the Towne of Tenterden</head>
<para id="p115">The Mayor for the time being Sir George Chute Robert Austen Esq[uire] Robert Wightwicke James Skeats William
Curties John Mantle Thomas Sharpe Thomas Marshall Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s52">
<head>For the Towne and Port of Winchelsea</head>
<para id="p116">The Mayor for the time being Edward Martin Thomas Hovenden John Richardson Richard Head Thomas
Simons.</para>
</section>
<section id="s53">
<head>For the Towne and Port of Hastings</head>
<para id="p117">The Mayor for the time being Thomas Lovell Captaine John Hyde Phillip Lovell Captaine John Millard Richard
Holman John Medhurst Jurates.</para>
</section>
<section id="s54">
<head>For the Ancient Towne of Rye</head>
<para id="p118">The Mayor for the time being John Spaine Michell Cadman Nicholas Manouch John Smith and Henry Goldsmith.</para>
</section>
<section id="s55">
<head>For the County of Lancaster</head>
<para id="p119">Richard Lord Colchester Sonne and Heire Apparent of the Earle Rivers Charles Lord Brandon Sonne and
Heire Apparent of the Earle of Macclesfield the Honourable James Stanley the Honourable Fitton Gerrard [Esquires<ref idref="n38">38</ref>]
the Honourable Hugh Willoughby the Honourable George Cholmondeley William Spencer Esquires Sir Charles
Hoghton Sir Edmond Asheton Sir Henry Ashurst Sir Thomas Stanley Sir Ralph Ashton Sir Robert Duckingfield
Sir Richard Standish Sir Henry Ashurst Baronets Sir Jefferey Shackerley Sir John Chichley Sir Edward Chisehale
Sir Daniell Fleming Knights Sir Edward Moseley Peter Hugh Peter Bold Thomas Norres James Holt Roger
Kirkby Thomas Preston Edward Fleetwood Henry Farrington Alexander Rigby of Layton Lawrence Rawstorne
William Hilton Thomas Greenhalgh Alexander Butterworth Thomas Braddill John Starkey Robert Parker Richard
Asheton of Caerdale [John<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] Lightboane John Entwistle Thomas Dodd Stephen Alcock Thomas Parker Christopher
Parker Thomas Ashurst Thomas Bancks James Duckenfield Richard Brooke James Chatham of Turton John
Hopwood junior Joshuah Horton John Hartley Joseph Yeates John Warren Alexander Rigby of Midleton Edward
Rigby Thomas Rigby of Wrea Christopher Wilkinson Ralph Longworth Peter Shackerley Christopher Greenfield
Anthony Parker Roger Kenion James Chetham of Smedley Silvester Richmond Peter Egerton William Hulme of
Daryhulme John Braddill Thomas Richardson William Kirkby Thomas Cole Roger Moore Edward Wilson Miles
Sands Thomas Shierson Benjamin Hoghton Thomas Mort Alexander Maudesley Ralph Livesay senior Edward
Rishton Nicholas Townley Roger Lacy William Apleton John Ashton Thomas Bretherton Nicholas Starkey Thomas
Lever Thomas Dickinson Richard Entwisle William Fleming Edward Herle Thomas Rigby of Aspull Edward
Ogle Oswald Moseley George Pigot John Veale Henry Rigley Joseph Grey William Maghall Thomas Pattent
Thomas Serjeant Esq[uire] of Warrington William Patten John Savery Ralph Egerton Richard Fleetwood Alexander
Ratcliffe William Emmott William Molineux Nathaniell Molineux Edward [Boothe<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] Richard Haworth Peter Ormerod
Thomas Rishton Nicholas Hammond George Sharples Jonathan Blackburne William Lowd Edmund Hornby
Richard Longworth Thomas Smith Thomas Fife William Sclater Richard Riveington John Case Thomas Cooke
Thomas Aynsworth James Asheton Cuthbert Holland Andrew Dandy Jeofrey Roby John Clayton Thomas Clayton
Richard Hoghton Thomas Wilson Ralph Livesay junior William Asheton Alexander Davies John Sorocold John
Lawnders Robert Bootle Robert Mollineux Richard Percivall John Wright Henry Latham James Asheton Thomas
Percivall Josua Nuttall Martin Willis Thomas Bradshaw Thomas Grantham John Copley Joseph Fletcher Robert
Atkinson George Allenson John Widdowes Miles [Whittaye<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] John Allen Peter Worthington William Leigh John
Johnson Robert Sturzaker Robert Shaw Nathan Abram [Jeremiah<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] Smethurst George Derbyshire Robert Halliwell
James Holland Edmond Tayler Richard Hoghton Ralph Fincham Thomas Wilson Richard Dickinson John Talson
of Grisdell Gentlemen The Mayor and Bailiffes of Lancaster for the time being Charles Rigby Esq[uire] John Foster William
Penny Henry Jones Josua Partington Thomas Greenwood Gentlemen Thomas Catterell John Hodgeson The
Mayor Aldermen and Bayliffes of the Burrough or Towne of Preston for the time being John Ferrers Edward
Rigby Alexander Johnson Esquires Doctor Charles Lee John Walker Daniell Chadwick John Adderton Joseph
King John Francks John Cockshutt James Asheton William Patten William Lemon the elder Christopher Nowell
Richard Langton William Hebson Thomas Greenfield John Law Henry Sollom Richard Hartley Ralph Rishton
Joseph King Gentlemen Roger Sudell senior Roger Sudell junior William Shaw William Cotton The Mayor Recorder
Aldermen and Bayliffes for the Burrough of Wygan for the time being Edward Earle The Steward of the Burrough of
Newton for the time being George Leigh Legh Bowden Gentlemen The Bayliffes of the Corporation of Cliderow
for the time being John Lister Arthur Ashton Edmund Robinson Robert Sclater John Webster Thomas Alston
William Oddy Gentlemen The Mayor and Bailiffes of Leverpoole for the time being William Clayton William
Williamson James Prescott Richard Wyndle Thomas Tyrer Aldermen Alexander Norres Peter Atherton John
Molineux Thomas Johnson junior Gent..</para></section>
<section id="s56">
<head>For the County of Leicester</head>
<para id="p120">The High Sheriffe for the time being Thomas Lord Beaumont of the Kingdome of Ireland Bennett Lord
Sherrard of the Kingdome of Ireland the Right Honourable Sir William Rawlinson one of the Lords Commissioners
for the Great Seale of England Sir William Villers Sir Thomas Hesilrig Sir Beaumont Dixie Sir Henry Hudson
Sir William Holford Sir Thomas Beaumont Sir John Noell Sir William Ellis Sir Edward Abney Baronets Sir
Ambrose Phillips Sir Edward Wigley Sir William Yorke John Cooke Jeffery Palmer Richard Lister senior John
De la Fountaine John Verney Chais Moris Thomas Boothby Robert Hesilrig William Boothby William Hartopp
Thomas Babbington St John Bennet Thomas Caldecote William Cole William Bird Charles Duncombe Samuell
Cotton Thomas Pochin senior Thomas Pochin junior William Streete William Whaley junior Roger Roe Roger
Smith George Pochin Christopher Packe Henry Hastings Mathew Johnson Thomas Wilson Edward Needham
Stanhope Whaley William Franke Thomas Noble William Jesson George Hewit Richard Brudnell Edward Needham
junior John Danvers Stanton of Langton Rowland Browne Edward Conniers Francis Needham Richard
Bradgate Lawrence Carter William Bainbrigge' Edward Hudson Edward Smith William Palmer Richard Lister
junior [George Morton<ref idref="n43">43</ref>] George Ashby William Faunt Henry Kendall John Wilkins William Herricke John
Wilson John Steele William Wooleston Woolleston Dixie Nathan Wright John Major John Oneby William
Harper John Harper Thomas Lewes James Armston Thomas Charnells Michaell Wrightson Francis Mundy John
[Bainbridge<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] William Belgrave Henry Heveningham John Chamberlaine William Rawlins William Jarvis William
Rawlins junior Henry Turner John Benskin John Streete Henry Gilbert Esquires William [Watson<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] Thomas Palmer
William Major John Hood Theophilus Greene John Goodman William Atkins Tirringham Stephens John Coles
Robert Freeman Robert Johnson Thomas Andrews George Vincent William Billers Mathew Dison Thomas Miles
of Shenton Charles Jennens Robert Heslerig junior Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s57">
<head>For the Burrough of Leicester</head>
<para id="p121">John Goodall Esq[uire] Mayor of the Burrough of Leicester and the Mayor for the time being Nathan Wright
William Franke John Major Esquires William Southwell William Deane George Becket Phillip Abney John
Roberts George Bent William Bentley Francis Ware Joseph Craddock Mathew Symonds William Billers William
Major Thomas Palmer junior Thomas Wells John Watts John Wilkins John Bent John Dan Edmond Johnson
Gabriell Hill Gentlemen Sir Edward Abney Knight Laurence Carter Esq[uire] John Kilpin John Brooksby Thomas
Palmer senior Edmond Cradock Thomas Lawrence John Norris Captaine Cox William Sheeres Gent.</para>
</section>
<section id="s58">
<head>For the County of Lincolne and City of Lincolne and for the County of the said City</head>
<para id="p122">The Right Honourable William Lord Pawlet second Sonne to the Duke of Bolton The Right Honourable George
Lord Castleton of the Kingdome of Ireland Bennet Lord Sherrard in the Kingdome of Ireland The Honourable
Nicholas Sanderson The Honourable Peregrine Bertie the Elder The Honourable Charles Bertie senior The
Honourable Peregrine Bertie the Younger The Honourable Phillip Bertie The Honourable Charles Sanderson The
Honourable William Mountague Craven Howard Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Monson Sir Thomas
Hussey Sir John Newton Sir John Brownlow Sir John Firwitt Sir Robert Markham Sir John Thorold Sir Willoughby
Hickman Sir William Ellis Sir Richard Cust Sir Edward Hussey Sir William Buck Sir Richard Rothwell Sir
John Oldfield Sir Thomas Trollop Sir John Bowles Sir Walter Clarges Sir Thomas Bernadiston Sir Robert Barkham
Baronets Sir Thomas Meeres Sir Edward Ascough Sir Thomas Rolte Sir Thomas Clarges Sir William Massingberd
Sir John Sherrard Sir Thomas Skipwith Baronets Sir William Yorke Sir Christopher Nevill Sir Edmond Turner
Knights Sir Henry Herne Knight of the Bath Charles Dimmocke Champian Charles Pelham William Marwood
Thomas Broughton Thomas Skipweth Thomas Lister Henry Stone Robert Riley Noah Neale Edward Paine Edward
Montague John Saunders William Welby William Hyde senior. William Hyde junior Anthony Palmer Christopher
Clapham Sir Pury Cust The Mayor Aldermen Recorder and Sheriffes of the City of Lincolne The Mayor Aldermen
and Recorder of Grimsby The Mayor Aldermen and Recorder of Boston The Mayor Aldermen and Recorder
of Stamford The Alderman of Grantham William Hascard Thomas Walton Edward Secker Doctor Lee John Key
Edward Coddington Simon Grant Robert Cole Thomas Ireland Thomas Cole Nicholas Becke William Clarke
Nathaniell Garthwaite Gentlemen Anthony Wingfield Charles Halford Peregrine Bertie of Gedney Esquires The
Warden of Louth John Newton Mountague Cholmley William Brownlow Richard Winch Stephen Rothwell William
Trollop Peregrine Bucke John Micklethwaite John Goodricke Richard Pell Samuell Luddington Esquires John
Browne William Montague Gentlemen Sir Edward Farmer Baronet John Bolt John Wood Benjamin King Andrew
Burton Gentlemen Gilbert Bury Esq[uire] Peter Bird Gent. Thomas Bury Ciprian Thornton Edward Tourney David
Field Gent. William Chapman John Chaplin Christopher Berrisford Thomas Hall Vincent Grantham Francis Grantham
George Whichcote George Nevill Bryan Nevile Christopher Aiscough William Oldfield Esquires The Deane and
Chapter of Lincolne Robert Cawdron George Hall Thomas Cowley John Harvey Esquires Lake George
Fairfax Thomas Young William Thompson Gent. John Hussey Mathew Lister Mathew Trollop Robert Rither
senior Dymocke Walpoole John Fisher John Bishop Esquires Richard Torksey John Pindar George Knight Christopher
Palmer Gent. Sigismond Trafford Francis Durley Peter Short Robert Archer Esquires Benjamin Smith Richard
Cuthbert George Newcomen Gent. Charles Fox Rawston Hart Edward Browne of [Hublin<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] Charles Bates John
Toller George Langton senior George Langton junior Charles Hutton Robert Fisher Francis Anderson Edmond
Anderson Edwin Anderson John Ely Esquires Thomas Aiscough John How John Greene junior Gent. James Ashton
Knott of Hupswell John Towne George Smith William Bonner Gent. Joseph Edmonds Johnson
of Witham Henry Jenkinson Henry Burrell Captaine Pownell Reuben Sparkes John Jay Walter Johnson Esquires
William Wallet William Ambler Francis Corey Gent. Martin Johnson Robert Tirwhitt Esquiers Peter Mapletoft
John Emerson Thomas Harnesse John Butler William Cawthropp Gent. Daniell Deline Robert Saunders Esquires
Adam Bland Richard [Nelthorp<ref idref="n47">47</ref>] John Thorold Isaac Newton Esquires John Burslen Thomas Colinon Thomas
Tegh Major Coney John Smith of Snelland Thomas Williamson Esquires John Burton William Cotton John
Apleyard Francis Aiscough Esquires Thomas Webberly John Key John Evans William Taylour of Heckington
Edward Curteous Lewis Hurst Tomlin of Riby Gent. Anthony Burton Gent. Humphrey Hyde Benjamin
Cuthbert George Clayton Gent. William Stamford Gent. John Micklethwaite junior Thomas Turney Esq[uire] Sir George
Marken John Quinzey John Garland Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s59">
<head>For the City of London</head>
<para id="p123">Sir Thomas Pilkington Knight the present Lord Mayor Sir John Lawrence Sir William Turner Sir William
Hooker Sir James Edwards Sir Robert Clayton Sir Patience Ward Sir John Moore Sir William Pritchard Sir
James Smith Sir Robert Jefferies Sir George Treby Sir Jonathan Raymond Sir Peter Daniell Sir Peter Rich Sir
Thomas Stampe Sir Samuell Dashwood Sir Benjamin Thorowgood Sir [Thomas<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] Kensy Sir William Ashurst Sir
Thomas Lane Sir John Flett Sir Humphrey Edwin Sir John Parsons Sir John Houblon Sir Edward Clarke Sir
Francis Childe Knights John Wildman Richard Levett William Gore Esquires Sir John Cutler Sir Samuell Bernadiston
Sir John Morden Sir Benjamin Ayloffe Sir Richard Temple Sir Henry Ashurst Baronets Sir Thomas Clarges Sir
Benjamin Newland Sir John Mathews Sir James Ward Sir John Lethieulier Sir Thomas Vernon Sir William
Russell Sir Robert Adams Sir Jeremy Sambrooke Sir Mathew Andrews Sir Thomas Fowles Sir Thomas Rawlinson
Sir Gabriell Roberts Sir Simon Lewes Sir William Dodson Sir Bazill Firebrace Sir Francis Massom Sir Joseph
Herne Sir Edward Desbovery Sir William Hedges Sir Ralph Box Sir Thomas Cooke Sir Stephen Evans Knights
Sir John Cope Sir John Browne Sir Nicholas Crispe Sir John Shaw Sir Thomas Chambers Sir Robert Masham
Baronets Thomas Papillon Esq[uire] Doctor Henry Newton Chauncellor of London Sir John Morden Baronet John
Perry Thomas Westerne William Strong Nathaniell Hawes John Machell Esquires Foster Baker
John Fouch Nicholas Carleton William Hooker Jeffery Jefferyes Anthony Sturt Charles Chamberlaine Richard Alye
John Buckworth Paul Wicks John Nicholls Ambrose Istead Arthur Champnyes John Bathurst James Houblon
George Sitwell Charles Thorold Arthur Baron Richard Garth John Kent Charles Duncombe Daniell Sheldon
Thomas Goddard William Ivatt Nathaniell Hornby John Crispe Robert Boddington Nathan Burdett Francis Gosright
Thomas Rider Henry Spelman Doctor Henry Newton Henry Hunter Esquires Thomas Manning Peter Floyer
Richard Normansell Charles Feltham Robert Litlebury Thomas Gardner Henry Lewes Peter Joy John Cooke
William Pellatt William Withers Thomas Blackmore Percivall Gibbourne Nicholas Caplin John Kent John Knapp
John Cooke William Faulkner John Genew Francis Chamberlaine Edward Sherwood William Woodroffe John
Midgley James Oades George Newland Thomas Langham Walter Coventry Daniell Allen William Pett William
Jarrett Francis Dashwood John Freeman Arthur Stavely William Craddocke Samuell Clarke John Morris Isaac Houblon
Robert Masters Richard Acton William Warren Lawrence Dyer Herbert Alwin Thomas Jieve Thomas Wood
Anthony Balam William Newberry Henry Clerke Richard Yerbery Thomas Tuckford Thomas Sandford Samuell
Gerrard Francis Griffith John Johnson Peter Pickering Thomas Dashwood Richard Hoare Nicholas Alexander
Robert Bedingfield Thomas Darwin James Smith Rupert Browne James Wood James Fowles Joseph Hornby
Richard Nicholls Robert Raworth Francis Brerewood Richard Goodall Thomas Salter Samuell Oungley Nicholas
Smith Thomas Collect John Cullum Richard Edmondson Thomas Eyres George Pecke Thomas Watts William
Fitzackerley John Flavell John West John Moore Godfrey Woodward Thomas Crane William Carpenter William
Whitehall Thomas Bearecliffe Abraham Jaggard William Lewen Richard Holder Hugh Stroud John Rawley William
Potts John Fensall Robert Brabourne Robert Whittingham Edward Beaker John Ashby William Stamper Edward
Phillips George Cole James Clement Edmond Prideaux Lieutenant Collonell Peirce Thomas Phelp Henry Crispe
Richard Bristoe Samuell Trotman Esquires John Westcott Sir Erasmus Smith Samuell Somerford Esq[uire] Francis Thacker
Edmond Phillips Esquires Thomas Cuddon Augustin Ballow William Robinson Thomas Firmin.</para>
</section>
<section id="s60">
<head>For the County of Middlesex</head>
<para id="p124">The Right Honourable Sir John Trevor Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons First Lord Commissioner
of the Great Seale of England The Right Honourable Richard Hambden Esq[uire] Chauncellour of Their Majestyes
Court of Exchequer and one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Charles Lord Herbert Marquesse
of Worcester Sonne and Heire Apparent to his Grace the Duke of Beaufort The Right Honourable Edward Russell
Esq[uire] Sonne to the Earle of Bedford Charles Lord Cheney of the Kingdome of Scotland Anthony Lord Faulkland
of the Kingdome of Scotland The Right Honourable Henry Lord Colerain of the Kingdome of Ireland Charles
Lord Brandon Sonne and Heire Apparent to Charles Earle of Maclesfield The Right Honourable Sir William
Rawlinson and Sir George Hutchins Lords Commissioners of the Great Seale of England Sir John Holt Knight
Lord Chiefe Justice of Their Majestyes Court of Kings Bench The Right Honourable Henry Powle Esq[uire] Master
of the Rolls Sir Henry Pollexfen Knight Lord Chiefe Justice of Their Majestyes Court of Common Pleas Sir
Robert Atkins Knight of the Bath Lord Chiefe Baron of their Majesties Court of the Exchequer The Right
Honourable Hugh Boscowen Esq[uire] The Honourable Henry Pagett Esq[uire] The Honourable Sir Robert Howard The
Honourable Craven Howard The Honourable Edward Mountague The Honourable Henry Priestman [Esquires<ref idref="n49">49</ref>] The
Honourable Thomas Newport Esq[uire] Sir Charles Gerard Baronet Sir William Cooper Sir William Roberts Sir
Anthony Craven Sir William Smith Sir Cave James Sir Richard Fisher Sir Paul Whichcott Sir William Barkham
Sir Thomas Pope Blunt Sir Thomas Litleton Sir Richard Nudigate Sir Henry Ashurst Sir John Bancks Sir William
Williams Sir Henry Marwood Sir Richard Onslow Sir Roger Langley Sir John Cutler Sir Phillip Cartright Sir
Samuell Bernardiston Baronets Sir Thomas Clarges Sir William Poultney Sir Walter Clarges Sir Robert Henley
Sir Thomas Bide Sir John Elves Sir James Butler Sir Thomas Row Sir Richard Dounton Sir William Hill Sir
Francis Pemberton Sir Henry Johnson Sir Orlando Gee Sir Theodore De Vaux Sir Thomas Kensey Sir Bazill
Firebrasse Sir William Hedges Sir Mathew Andrews Sir Charles Cotterell Sir Edward Waldoe Sir Thomas Grantham
Sir John Roberts Sir Purbecke Temple Sir William Parkins Sir Goddard Nelthorpe Sir Edward Abney Sir Adam
Oatley Sir James Astrey Sir Thomas Hodgshon Sir Cornwall Bradshaw Sir Michaell Heneage Sir William Ashurst
Sir William Pritchard Sir William Wogan Sir Charles Umfrevill Sir John Trenchard Sir Charles Lee Sir James
Smith Sir Thomas Chambers Sir John Bucknall Sir Edmond Walcupp Sir Francis Childe Sir Thomas Rawlinson
Sir George Treby Their Majestyes Attourney Generall Sir John Sommers Their Majestyes Sollicitor Generall Knights
Peregrine Bertie Charles Mountague Ralph Hawtrey Robert Dormer Richard Onslow Esquires Thomas Dove Brooke
Bridges Esquires Auditors of Their Majestyes Imprest John Phelips Esq[uire] Auditor of Their Majestyes Court of
Exchequer Nicholas Raynton John Wolstenholm William Draper Josua Galliard James Munday William Avery
John Smith Adam Andrewes Edward Harris John Walker of Hadley John Huxley John Bathurst Thomas Austin
William Austin William Tate William Blucke Peniston Whaley Cheeke Gerrard Thomas Francklin Richard Page
John Baggs John Nicholl Lancelott Lake Edmond Prideaux John Carpenter Thomas Nappier George Sitwell Edward
Maplesden Richard Shoreditch John Stannion Lancelott Johnson Richard Bowaker John Baldwin Francis Goston
Roger Jennings John Jennings Francis Merrick Thomas Harrison John Walker of Hillenden James Chadwick
William Mellith James Southaby Henry Hawley Christopher Clitherow William [Glaston<ref idref="n50">50</ref>] Nicholas Grice John
Davenport Richard Parker Robert Beale Robert Newdigate Henry Collins Thomas Pearcehouse Henry Reynell Thomas
Wood Leonard Hammond Charles Duncomb Daniell Fox John Jones Thomas Bridall Thomas Manning Daniell
Proctor John Slater Humphrey Ethrington Henry Barker Esq[uire] Clerke of the Crowne Josias Clarke Robert Sheffeild
Thomas Henslow Thomas Methold John Creed Gregory King Henry Spilman Anthony Caldecott Thomas Webb
Thomas Henslow Thomas Alston Francis Brand Richard Tayler Anthony Nurse Thomas Southern Thomas Greggs
Edward Allen John Raymond Richard Craddock Isaac Honeywood Paul Jodrell Esq[uire] Clerke to the House of Commons
Richard Aston Thomas Harriott Thomas Hall James Dwey Thomas Smith William Culliford Jeffery Nightingall
William Withers John Perry Edward Northy Francis Tyson Reginall Bracknall Thomas Cooke Thomas Casse
Thomas Johnson Lucy Knightley Peter Bundue William Willis Charles Fox George Bourne William Johnson
Nathaniell Owen Esquires Captaine Williams William Wilby Esq[uire] Captaine John North Captaine William Field
George Ford William Wakelin Henry Russell Richard Savill Henry Risby Henry Dethick Joseph Blissett Ralph
Bucknell Esquires John Leneve Thomas Beach William Northey Daniell Sheldon Peter Knight Henry Hassard
Samuell Bluck Richard Milner Narcissus Lutterell Francis Twisden William Bridges Thomas Hobbs Robert Heyton
Esquires William Freeman of St Giles Esq[uire] Thomas Simpson Esq[uire] John Vandenbend John Hungerford John
Plummer William Thursby Esquire Prothonataries of the Court of Common Pleas at Westminster John Cooke
and Thomas Winserd William Tempest Francis Browne Samuell Somerford Edmond Griffin Roger Stoughton Samuell
Bucke William Etterick Esq[uire] Edward Bide Bartholimew Cauxter Ralph Bide Hugh Simpson John Crosse Albian
Chare Thomas Milward Robert Clerkson Foot Onslow Roger Gillengam Charles Bouxton Francis Thacker Edward
Noell Robert Frampton James Chadwicke Richard Haly James Curdrow Thomas Chambers Robert Hastings
Samuell Trotman Richard Holford Leonard Sowersby Samuell Knowles Peter Lugg Gregory King Arthur Bernardiston
Francis Negus Craven Peyton Thomas Owen Joseph Offley Erasmus Smith Esquires William Bird John Methwen
Phillip Mitchell Charles Hawtry Francis Astby Dixon of Fesse Abraham Wareing William Fenn Richard
Lugg William Walker Henry Cave senior Henry Cave junior Nathaniell Lacy Henry Burdett of Tottenham William
Bamfield Richard Cheslin William Webb Thomas Harris Abraham Nelson Robert Skinner John Hooker Ambrose
Isted Anthony Guydott George Edwards Carew Guydott Gentlemen The Commissioners of the Excise for the
time being Henry Lamb Gentleman Nathaniell Hilton John Hastings Richard Adams Gentlemen Hugh Hammersley
John Bradford William Whitacre Anthony Withers Samuell Trotman John Cannon John Bayley John Meridale
Robert Longland Francis Barry James Alter William Warr John Bourne Robert Cowden Gent. Captaine Richard
[Cheyne<ref idref="n51">51</ref>] George Board Nathaniell Montage John Goldsborow Thomas Gromble Gentlemen Captaine John Field
Ralph Cowle Mr Palmer Mr Midleton John Hayley John Fauntheroy Edward Fuller Robert
[Hedding<ref idref="n52">52</ref>] Tanner Arnold John Crosier Peter Bourdeux Peter Lekew Paul Dockminicke William Warr William
Goodenough Thomas Jackson William Blacaller Gentlemen Captaine Batson Henry Nurse John Woodfine John
Brumell Thomas Greeves Thomas Grimble Thomas Wale Thomas Wilcox John Field Robert [Crowden<ref idref="n53">53</ref>] Thomas
Rudd Gentlemen Isaac Foxcroft Esq[uire] Captaine John Nicholson Mr William Snelling Captaine John Andrewes
Collonell Edward Proger Nicholas Barbone Esq[uire] Thomas Owen John Hall Gent. Thomas Glover [of<ref idref="n54">54</ref>] Hackney Esq[uire]
Sir Bartholimew Showers Charles Toll Esquire Charles Fox Esq[uire] John Cash junior Francis Hooper Richard Cheyney
Thomas Thornberry Captaine Edmond Noble Edward Weaver Captaine William Parish Richard Wilday Richard
Auberry William Benson Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s61">
<head>For the City of Westminster and Liberties thereof</head>
<para id="p125">The Right Honourable Richard Hampden Esq[uire] one of Their Majesties most Honourable Privy Councill William
Lord Eland Sonne and Heire Apparent of the Marquesse of Hallifax Edward Lord Cornbury Sonne and Heire
Apparent to the Earle of Clarendon Anthony Lord Faulkland of the Kingdome of Scotland Sir Robert Howard
Knight and Edward Russell Esq[uire] two of Their Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Craven Howard Esquire
Sir John Lowther of Whitehaven Sir Samuell Grimston Baronets Sir Thomas Clarges Sir Joseph Seymour Sir
William Poultney Knights Sir Walter Clarges Baronet Richard Morley Esquire The Honourable Phillip Howard
Esq[uire] Sir John Cutler Baronet Thomas Done Brooke Bridges John Phelips Esquires Sir Roger Langley Baronet
Hugh Squire James Vernon Charles Twitty Bartholimew Fillingham William Lownds Robert Squib Robert Bredon
Humphrey Maston Charles Toll Robert Knott Gent. Charles Bonithon Francis Carew Thomas Watkins Richard
Newman Esq[uire] Ralph Marshall Gent. Sir John Elwes Knight James Sheffeild Esq[uire] Sir Phillip Meadowes Knight
John Creed William Ball John Milner Esquires Richard Milner Gentleman John Roydhouse Gent. Sir John
Nicholas Knight Benjamin Cooling Esq[uire] Wynne William Hewers Esq[uire] Dionesius Andrews Gent. Edmond
Woodroffe Gent. John Cleare Joha Smallbone Nehemiah Arnold Gent. Sir Joseph Williamson Knight Sir Thomas
Litleton Baronet Sir Charles Cotterell Sir Stephen Fox Knights Sir John Cotton Baronet William Harboard Esq[uire]
Sir Thomas Mompesson Sir Cerill Wich Sir Charles Ohara Knights Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath
Sir Robert Pye Baronet Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir William Orpe Sir Christopher Wrenn Knights [Henry Guye
Esq[uire] the honourable Sir Henry Goodricke and Sir Henry Capell Knights<ref idref="n55">55</ref>] Sir James Hayes Knight William Bridgman
Esq[uire] Collonell Thomas Sackvile Richard Rider Gent. Walter Bridall Thomas Neale Bernard Granvile Christopher
Vane Esquires Henry Fredericke Thinne Mathew Locke Michaell Babington John Currance Simon Smith Esquires
Gerrard Cotter Thomas Templeman Morrice Hunt James Chace Josua Drayner George Cooper John Haynes Phillip
Ryley Gent. Collonell Richard Binns Edmund Ogar John Lug Richard Wheeler Richard Lassells Michaell Arnold
Gent. David Crawford Esq[uire] Charles Rampaine Sir Miles Cooke Sir Humphrey Winch Knights Andrew Lawrence
Esq[uire] William Shaw Esq[uire] John Tully Ralph Hutchinson Marke Lawne William Richards Gent. Richard Fitz-gerald
Gent. William Blathwaite Charles Duncombe Richard Paget Charles Mountague Esquires The Honourable Peregrine
Bertie and Charles Bertie Edmund Waller William Cheney Esquires James St Almund Gent. Sir Peter Collaton
Baronet John Pottinger Esq[uire] James Smithsby Charles Knott of St Clements Danes John Clayton of the same
John Worley Edward Yeomans of the same Richard Cooper John Rossington Matthias Cooper Lewis Prescott
John Frost Gent. Simon Smith Merchant John Martin Gent. William Greene (<ref idref="n56">56</ref>) Richard Heybourne Gent. Erasmus
Dryden Gent. Paul Jodrell Clerke of the House of Commons John Hookes Gent. Thomas Browne Francis Negus
Richard Fisher Richard Owen Thomas Linacre Phillip Blundell John England William Bolt Gent. Anthony Row
Roger Gillingham Francis Gwynne Esquires Richard Stephens Augustine Beare Gent. Robert Wood Michaell
Miles Leonard Plucknet Nicholas Martin William Seabrooke Edward Salisbury John Wilson Esquires James Supples
John Blundell Edward Hutchins John Anger John Stone Gent. Doctor Mathew Lister Doctor John Radcliffe
Roger Jennings Esq[uire] Thomas Payne Esq[uire] Richard Dalton George Farnell Esquires John Vigures George Plucknet
Gent. Captaine John Tayler John Clayton of Westminster Spalding Rowland Greenwood Jacques Wiseman
Thomas Thorowton Henry Robbins Gent. George Meggott James Fearne Peter Hume Thomas Bridgeman Charles
Francklin John Hinder Peter Rudge Thomas Jones Samuell Birch Samuell Pryor Gent. Mr Serjeant Trenchard All
the Officers of the Board of Greene Cloath for the time being Sir Robert Marsham Knight Edward Mayne
Robert Wood John Cox of Long Acre Gent. Thomas Newport Esq[uire] John Walker Sir William Wogan James
Butterby Thomas Mansell Thomas Rider Gent. Sir William Cooper Baronet Sir John Bucknell Knight William Baber
Esq[uire] William Blackeller Gent. Sir Thomas Row William Jacob William Read William Willis Gent. Sir Thomas Chambers
Knight Edmond Goodwynne Edmund Fuller Roger Gillingham Esquires Thomas Pitt Esq[uire] John Squib Esq[uire] John
Morley Michaell Miles Gent. Collonell John Fitz-Patricke John Hastings Esq[uire] Thomas Whitefield Gilbert Herring
John Kempe James Francks Gent. Doctor Gideon Harvey Samuell Peacocke Nicholas Pickering Thomas Tukey
Nicholas Collins Nicholas Freeman William Gulson Gentlemen Mordett Creherode James Cuningham Thomas
Harrison William Jarman Gent. Captaine Henry New Eldred Lancelott Lee Esquires Sir Henry
Marwood Baronet Crispe Grange John Desheer of Covent Garden Gent. Henry Priestman James Southerne
Esquires Nicholas Barbone Esq[uire] Edward Progers Esq[uire] The three Prothonataries of the Court of Common Pleas
for the time being Richard Garth Esq[uire] Thomas Browne Sir George Treby Their Majestyes Attourney Generall
Sir John Sommers Their Majesties Sollicitor Generall Thomas Owen Esq[uire] Humphry Hetherington Esq[uire] The
Commissioners of the Excise for the time being Nathaniell Hilton John Hastings Richard Adams Hugh Hammersley
John Bradford William Whiteacre Anthony Withers The Burgesses and Assistants for the City and Liberties of
Westminster for the time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s62">
<head>For the County of Monmouth</head>
<para id="p126">Charles Lord Marquesse of Worcester Sonne and Heire Apparent of the Duke of Beaufort Sir Charles Kemys
Sir Trevor Williams Sir John Morgan Baronets Sir Rowland Gwynne Sir James Herbert Knights Thomas
Morgan of Tredegar Richard Lewis John Williams Henry Probert John Arnold Charles Vane John How Thomas
Morgan of Llanrumney Charles Price Hopton Williams Henry Morgan of Bodwelty Edmond Morgan Edward
Jones Roger Oates George Kemys Edward Perkins John Morgan of Tredegar Lewis Morgan Capell Hanbury
Thomas Jones John Floyer John Walter Robert Gunter Charles Hughs James Morgan of Llandilo Charles
Morgan of Tredegar George Lewis of St Peire John Pritchard of Campson Nicholas Parker Christopher Price
George Harris Walter Williams Thomas Williams Rodericke Guynne Morgan Chambers David Morgan Mathew
Powell Henry Tomkins Richard Roberts John Scudamore of Kentchurch Nicholas Arnold Richard [Scudamore<ref idref="n57">57</ref>]
James Morgan Edward Kemys William Blethin John Lewis of Istenhill Esquires John Cacthmy John Morgan of
Bechlendeg Rowland Williams Matthias Bird Walter Aldey Robert Jones Charles Williams Nehemiah Williams
John Morgan of Winnistow John Cragg Walter Fortune William Morgan Theophilus Reynolds Richard Jones
Walter Cicill Edward Hamlin Gent. of Langston John Jones Roger Williams John Harris of Burgavenny William
Powell of Poole Hall Richard Vaughan Francis Williams Morgan Thomas John Watkins Trevor Merricke William
Evans William Price John Gwillams Francis Pritchard Nathaniell Rogers Sheldon Powell Hugh Harris Ezra
Water William Seys Charles Jones of Magar Henry Ovald William Pritchard of Llangattocke William George
of the same John Morgan of Llandewy James Springett Michaell Bohun. Clarke of Gracedew Henry
Rumsey of Woesnewton Gent. The Mayor of Monmouth The Mayor of Newport The Bayliffe of Abbergavenny The
Portreve of Uske Henry Milborne Esquire John Philpott Thomas Williams Roger Kemys Peregrine Lewis
William Gore Esq[uire] Thomas Foley Esq[uire].</para>
</section>
<section id="s63">
<head>For the County of Norfolke</head>
<para id="p127">Sir Robert Bacon Sir Henry Hobert Sir Robert Drury Sir John Holland Sir Augustine Palgrave Sir John Pettus
Sir Robert Kempe Sir Jacob Astley Knight and Baronet Sir Roger Potts Sir Thomas Ward Sir William Cooke Sir
Edmond Doyley Sir Charles Adams Sir Peter Gleane [Sir Nicholas Gerrard Sir John Mordant<ref idref="n58">58</ref>] Sir Thomas Hare
Baronets Sir Nevill Catlin Sir Francis Guybon Sir William Rant Sir John Turner Sir Cirill Wich Sir Edward
Chisenhall Sir Phillip Skippon Sir Robert Clayton Knights Thomas Knivet Robert Walpoole Richard Verney of
Kirby John [Herbert<ref idref="n59">59</ref>] Edmund Woodhouse John Knivet John Woodhouse James [Heste.<ref idref="n60">60</ref>] Robert Wardell Peircy
Freake John Hearne Joachim Matthews William Stone John Jay Robert Coney Gabriell Armiger Robert Sucklin Phillip
Bedingfield Richard Wyth Francis Gardner John Warkhouse Phillip Astley Charles Legrosse Edward Soame John
Norris Daniell Bedingfield Christopher Crow Robert Wilson Edward Wilson Erasmus Earle Francis Repps John
Repps Charles Wright Riches Browne Henry Negus Robert Hearne Robert Davy Arthur Branthwaite Nathaniell
Simonds Edmund Britiffe George England Edmund Lambe Hatton Berners Robert Day John Aide Thomas Wright
Hugh Hovell Edward Le Strange William Oldfield Clement Hearne Robert Gooch Clement Gooch Thomas
Townshend John Thurston Thomas Bulwer Brigg Fountaine William Branthwait John Cropley Isaac Preston Robert
Bransby Benjamin England Francis Negus Richard Carter John Brewster James Hoste junior Thomas Rant Robert
Doughty Augustin Briggs Samuell Fuller Robert London of Loddon Oliver Neeve John Anguish Mundiford
Spelman Leonard [Mayes<ref idref="n61">61</ref>] Francis Thorisby Gascoin Weld Anthony Freston Thomas Talbott John Richmond Edward
Osborne Gardiner Hewitt John Minga Robert Buxton William Sidley Israell Long Thomas Blowfield Robert
Stileman Francis Dusgate Doctor Pepper John Page Richard Ferrier Lucy Blackman George Vernon Henry Oxburgh
Roger Jennings John Castle Edward Bulwer Robert Jermey John Houghton Brampton Gourdon Jonathan Symonds
William Rudin Thomas Sanders Ralph Hare James Ward Thomas Baysepoole Thomas Crick Charles Turner junior
Brograve John Birkin Benjamin Dethicke Thomas Newman Roger Jennings Denzell Onslow Edward
Earle Christopher Layer Francis Long Thomas Peirson James Hobart Robert Fiske Francis Neve Edmond Anguish
Phillip Vincent Humphry Rant William Stafford.</para>
</section>
<section id="s64">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Norwich</head>
<para id="p128">The Mayor for the time being Robert Davy Esq[uire] Recorder Robert Ward Esq[uire] Steward Thomas Blowfield Esq[uire]
Hugh Bockengam Esquire The two Sheriffes for the time being Thomas Wise Robert Bendish Robert Freeman
John Low Nicholas Helwys Francis Gardiner William Salter Phillip Stebbing John Wrench Thomas Cooke Jeremy
Vinn John Mann Esquires Robert Cooke Leonard Osborne Augustine Briggs Nicholas Bickerdike John Ward John
Levrington William Guybon Michaell Beverley Samuell Workhouse Thomas Postle Lawrence Goodwin Aldermen
Doctor Fairfax Deane of Norwich Doctor Pepper Thomas Townesend Francis Bacon Thomas Bacon John Mingay
Arthur Branthwaite Esquires John Barnham John [Deersley<ref idref="n62">62</ref>] John Minkerell Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s65">
<head>For the Burrough of Great Yarmouth</head>
<para id="p129">The Bayliffes for the time being George England Esquire (<ref idref="n63">63</ref>) Robert Bransby Esq[uire] Peter Caulier George Ward
Thomas England Benjamin England Thomas Bradford John Robbins John Ferrier Nathaniell Simonds Thomas
Godfrey John Gayford Gabriell Ward John Andrews Anthony Ellis senior Richard Ferrier John Burton senior
Thomas Ellis Robert Bernard Benjamin Steadman Henry Thompson Anthony Ellis junior John Gunnell Joseph
Cottman Benjamin Engell Thomas Lovell Aldermen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s66">
<head>For the Burrough of Kings Lynn.</head>
<para id="p130">The Mayor for the time being Sir John Turner Knight Daniell Bedingsfield Esq[uire] Recorder Benjamin Holley
Giles Bridgeman Robert Sparrow John Kidd Edmond Hooke Benjamin Keene Ciprian Anderson Henry Framingham
William Linstead Henry Bell Aldermen Charles Turner Gent. Robert Payne.</para>
</section>
<section id="s67">
<head>For the Burrough of Thetford</head>
<para id="p131">The Honourable William Harbord Esq[uire] Sir John Holland Baronet Sir Francis Guibon Knight Baptist May Esquire
Wormely Hethersett William Cropley John Thurston Charles Wright Thomas Wright Maurice Kendall John
Draper Edmund Winwood Thomas Smith Robert Caudle Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s68">
<head>For the County of Northampton</head>
<para id="p132">Sir Andrew St John Baronet John Parkhurst Esq[uire] William Brownlow Esquire [Gibert<ref idref="n64">64</ref>] Dolben Esq[uire] Sir Thomas
Samwell Baronet Sir William Langham Knight Sir William Egerton Knight of the Bath John Blencow Sergeant at
Law Thomas Andrews Esq[uire] Sir James Langham Knight and Baronet Sir John Holman Baronet The Right
Honourable William Harbord Esq[uire] Sir Benjamin Bathurst Knight Christopher Jeffries Esq[uire] Arthur Brookes Esq[uire]
Thomas Maidwell Esq[uire] Robert Barton Gent. Sir William Farmer Baronet Francis Arundell Esq[uire] Francis Crane Esq[uire]
Thomas Jennings Gent. Samuell Rolt Gentleman Henry Benson Esq[uire] Richard Boteler senior Esq[uire] John Combs Esq[uire]
William Adams of Charwelton Esq[uire] John Winston Esq[uire] Edmond Bromwich Gent. Thomas Bretton Gent. Sir William
Craven Knight Sir Roger Cave Baronet John Browne Esq[uire] Clerke of the Parliaments William Bateman Esq[uire] Edward
Ladkin Esq[uire] John Bridges Esq[uire] Sir James Long Baronet John Weaver William Fleetwood Thomas Mulsho Thomas
Catesby William Wilmore Goddard Pemberton Esq[uire] The Mayor of Higham Ferrers for the time being Sir Rice
Rudd Baronet Thomas Ekins Esq[uire] William Boteler John Wiseman Francis Harvey Thomas Trist William Elmes
Hatton Compton Esquires Jacob Dancer Gent. Henry Rushton Richard Rainsford John Thornton Gerard Gore
Robert Breton Henry Bacon Robert Heselrige Esquires Salathiell Lovell Serjeant at Law Daniell Danvers Doctor
in Physicke Sir John Pickering Baronet Sir Mathew Dudley Baronet Jeffery Palmer of Stoke Doyle Esq[uire] Sidney
Wortley alias Mountague Esq[uire] Lord Fitz Williams the Honourable Charles Bertie Esq[uire] Sir John Elwes
Knight Noah Neale Esq[uire] Henry Neale Esq[uire] John Royley Esquire William Clarke Esq[uire] Thomas Hacke Esq[uire] John
Carrier Gent. John Dickenson Esq[uire] John Wilebore Gent. Thomas Deacon Gentleman Sir Justinian Isham Baronet
Edward Saunders Esq[uire] Harold Kinnesman Esq[uire] John Hendon Esq[uire] Bernard Walcott Thomas Colthurst Esq[uire] Mathew
Orlebar Gent. Francis Lane John Creede Andrew Lant Charles Midleton James Robinson Hanbury of
Kelwash Robert Mansell John Allicocke Thomas Langham Esquires Sir Pope Danvers Sir Robert Dryden
Baronets William Lisle Robert Dormer Samuell Trist John Bagshaw John Creswell John Woodhall Charles Fox
Ambrose Holbech Francis St John Henry Earle of Thomond in the Kingdome of Ireland The Mayor of Brackley
for the time being Robert Fruin Gent. Joseph Haines Francis Morgan George Kendricke Edward Stratford William
Thursby Harry Ekins William Benson Richard Lockwood Christopher Mountague Henry Farmer Henry Edmonds
William Tate Toby Chauncey Esquires Francis Woodhull Gent. Samuell Tryone Esq[uire] John Hodges Gent. Thomas
Jackson Esq[uire] the Mayor of Northampton for the time being Robert Heselrige Esq[uire] John Knight Richard Willoughby
John Silby John Brafield John Clarke Robert Ives John Lucas Richard White.</para>
</section>
<section id="s69">
<head>For the County of Northumberland</head>
<para id="p133">The Right Honourable Charles Lord Morpeth Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Earle of Carlisle The Honourable
Charles Mountague Esq[uire] The Honourable Ralph Gray Esq[uire] Sir Ralph Delavall Sir John Heron Sir William Midleton
Sir Thomas Lorraine Sir Robert Eden Sir William Blacket Sir Francis Lyddell Baronets Sir Ralph Jennison Sir
Robert Fenwicke Sir Richard Neale Sir Francis Blake Knights Ralph Delavall William Foster Phillip Bickerstaffe
Roger Fenwicke Phillip Babington Thomas Foster John Shaftoe John Salkeild Robert Mitford of Sighell Thomas
Forster of Cornwall Thomas Collingwood Thomas Beach John Blackiston John Hindmarsh Robert Bewicke John
Carnaby William Strother of Foberry William Ogle William Carr Michaell Welden Henry Holmes Francis Addison
Charles Howard Joseph Carr Patrecius Crow William Reevely George Delavall ThomasBlenkinshipp Robert Hebron
John Bacon John Blacket Robert Lawson Thomas Allgood Robert Shaftoe George Collingwood Esquires Robert
Lisle John Proctor Richard Forster John Coulson Samuell Salkeild William Ramsey of Brinckbourne William Strother
of Grindon Rigg Francis Forster John Gray of Howicke The Bayliffes of Morpeth for the time being Robert
Fenwicke Ralph Gray of Backworth George Lawson John Fenwicke Ralph Brandling Gilbert Parke George Wilson
Ralph Anderson William Pierson Thomas Grey John Storey Gent. Sir Orlando Gee Knight Robert Mitford of
Mitford Esq[uire] Circies Swinbourne Esq[uire] John Rogers Thomas Burrell of Broome Parke Gent. Robert Lisle of Hazen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s70">
<head>For the Towne and County of the Towne of Newcastle upon Tyne.</head>
<para id="p134">William Ramsey Esq[uire] Mayor Sir Robert Shaftoe Knight Recorder Sir William Blacket Baronet Sir Ralph Carr
Knight Timothy Davison Esq[uire] George Moreton Timothy Robson Nicholas Fenwicke William Aubeny Nicholas Ridley
William Carr William Proctor Thomas Wasse Sheriffes Esquires Aldermen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s71">
<head>For the Burrough of Berwicke upon Tweede</head>
<para id="p135">The Mayor for the time being Sir Francis Blake Knight Samuell Ogle Phillip Babbington Esquires Anthony
Compton John Luck Stephen Jackson Edward Nelson John Sleath Robert Watson Marke Scott Cuthbert Brady
Christopher Francklin William Scott.</para>
</section>
<section id="s72">
<head>For the County of Nottingham</head>
<para id="p136">The Right Honourable Patricius Lord Viscount Chaworth of the Kingdome of Ireland The Right Honourable
William Lord Eland Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Marquesse of Halifax The Honourable Anchitall Grey Esq[uire]
The Honourable William Byron Esq[uire] Sir Thomas Willoughby Sir Thomas Parkins Baronets Sir Scroope How Sir
William Stanhope Knights Francis Pierpoint William Sacheverell Richard Mansfeild Thomas Lewis William Williams
Phillip Laycock Charles Hutchinson Phillip Sherrard Esquires John Kerchavell Peter Broughton junior William
Woolhouse Richard Janes of Eperston Thomas Barret Henry Bainbridge Thomas Sharpe of Barnby Henry Sherbrooke
Gentlemen William Burnell Arthur Warren Richard Slater Gilbert Millington Robert Sherbrooke Francis Mouleneux
Esquires Sir Ralph Knight (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Francis Stringer John Reyner Charles Stanhope William Pinckney Darcy Moulineux John
Digby John Thornhough John White Nicholson of Marnham John Knight Richard Tayler Edward Melish
William Harbord Francis Sandis Jervis Eyre John Clarkson William Simpson Thomas Charlton Esquires Thomas
Bristowe John Storey Jeremiah Halfehead Gentlemen The Mayor of Newarke for the time being The [Six<ref idref="n66">66</ref>]
Senior Aldermen of Newarke Doctor Yarborough Samuell Ellis Timothy Ellis Stow of Newarke
Snell William Clay of Newarke Gentlemen The Bayliffes of Retford for the time being William Lane
William Dunstou Simon Woolby George Wharton Charles Jenners Ward Thomas Sharpe William
Hyde Gentlemen William Sterne Gent. Doctor Cromwell Palmes Hills Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s73">
<head>For the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham.</head>
<para id="p137">John Hawkins Esq[uire] Mayor George Langford Charles Harvey Joseph Turpin Thomas Collins John Hydes John
Crispe Aldermen Francis Pierpoint James Farewell John Dand Richard Mansfield George Gregory Samuell Staples
Esquires William Graves Thomas Trigg Ralph Bennet John Hoe John Sherwin William Drury Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s74">
<head>For the County of Oxford</head>
<para id="p138">Anthony Lord Viscount Faulkland of the Kingdome of Scotland Robert Lord Viscount Tiviott of the Kingdome
of Scotland Mountague Lord Norris Sonne and Heire Apparent to James Earle of Abingdon The Right Honourable
Richard Hampden Chancellor of the Exchequer one of His Majesties most Honourable Privy Councill The
Honourable Henry Bertie Esq[uire], Sir John Cope Sir Robert Jenkinson Sir [Fairmedon<ref idref="n67">67</ref>] Penniston Sir William Walter
Sir Edward Read Sir William Glynne Sir Edmond Fettiplace Sir Litleton Osbaldiston Sir Robert Dashwood Sir
John Holman Sir Thomas Litleton Sir John Doyley Sir Thomas Cobb Sir James Chamberlaine Sir William Rich
Sir Robert Barkham Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Ashurst Baronets Sir Edward
Hungerford Knight of the Bath Sir Edward Norreys Sir Timothy Tyrrell Sir Thomas Tipping Sir James
Hayes Sir Thomas Clayton Sir Thomas Rowe Sir Sebastion Smith Sir William Whitlocke Sir Edmund Warcup
Knights Anthony Hungerford Thomas Tipping Richard Libb Edward Barry John Stone Carlton Stone John
Hampden George Alnutt Henry Alnutt Francis Clarke William Lenthall John Dormer George Chamberlaine
William Cannock Thomas Hoard William Bayley John Croake Harry Cole Henry Heylin Robert Perrot
James Perrott Richard Powell William Pudsey Robert Sheppard Thomas Coghill Henry Hall John Wallis
Adam Springall Robert Jennings Thomas Brightman Simon Harcourt Thomas Wheate Robert Mayott Alexander
Denton Edmond Goodier Joseph Rawlinson Esquires Henry Ailworth Henry Beeson Edward Masters Doctors in
Law Doctor Henry Morris Charles Holloway John West William Oakley Ralph Holt Humphrey Wickham John
[Gunne<ref idref="n68">68</ref>] Lenthall Trotman John Bray John Danvers [Sonnybanke<ref idref="n69">69</ref>] Veysay Roger Price Thomas Woodhall William
Sacheverell Henry Peacocke Samuell Trotman Thomas Crispe of Darnford George Tipping of Draycott James
Herbert Esq[uire]uries William Tipping of Ewelme Esq[uire], Richard Bredioake Lacy Osbaldiston William Blake Bartholomew
Harris John Parsons George Woodward John Wickham Gregory of Horley George Cave Simon
Whorwood [Deane<ref idref="n70">70</ref>] John Carey Thomas Rowney Richard Tayler of Wilscott Francis Knapp Robert
Parsons Henry Streete Henry Stephens Thomas Carter Gilbert Jackson John Scriblehill John Hickford Francis
Greenway Richard Evans Anthony Evans Thomas Greenwood Thomas Napper Richard Thompson Nicholas Busby
Hawkins of Milton Sutton Coghill John Coghill Martin May John Wheeler John Crispe Lawrence
Lord John Croker John Dodwell John Wise of Drayton John Smith Giles Diston Thomas Rolles Richard Croke
Richard Blackhall George Gooding of Latchford John Moreton Robert Standard Bezaliell Knight Gentlemen Francis
Norreys John Nurse Esquires William Jeffy Gent. Sir Henry Fane Knight of the Bath Francis Drake Gent. The
Mayor Aldermen and Towne Clerke of the Towne of Woodstock for the time being The Mayor Steward Recorder
Aldermen and Towne Clerke of Banbury for the time being The Warden of Henley for the time being The
Bayliffes of Chipping Norton Burford and Witney for the time being Arthur Waren Esq[uire], John Croker Gent. John
Winlow Edward Whistler of Gathampton Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s75">
<head>For the University of Oxford</head>
<para id="p139">Doctor Jonathan Edwards Vice Chancellor The Honourable Heneage Finch Esq[uire], The Honourable William Leopald
Finch Warden of All Souls Sir Thomas Clarges Knight Sir Thomas Clayton Warden of Merton Colledge Doctor
Henry Aldrich Deane of Christ Church Doctor Henry Beeston Doctor William Levinz Doctor Robert Say Doctor
Timothy Halton Doctor William Jane Canon of Christ Church Doctor William Levett Doctor John Hamond Doctor
John Hall Doctor Ralph Bathurst Doctor Thomas Turner Doctor [Thomas<ref idref="n71">71</ref>] Bourchire Doctor Richard Lydell The
Proctors for the time being Mr. Benjamin Cooper John Haslewood John Crosse John Fulks George Thompson
Thomas Moore Thomas Bartlett.</para>
</section>
<section id="s76">
<head>For the City of Oxford</head>
<para id="p140">The Mayor for the time being The Honourable Henry Bertie Esq[uire]; Sir Edward Norreys Knight Sir John Cope
Sir Robert Jenkinson Sir John Doyley Sir Robert Dashwood Baronets Sir William Walker Knight John Townesend
Thomas Fifeild and Thomas Eustace Aldermen William Wright Recorder Collonell Henry Cope Tobias Browne
John Bowell John Croney Thomas Hunsden Edward Combs Charles Holloway John Bateman Esquires Charles
Harris Gent&tilde; Edward Prince Towne Clerke Sir Robert Harrison Thomas Bee The Bayliffes for the time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s77">
<head>For the County of Rutland</head>
<para id="p141">The Right Honourable Bennett Lord Sherrard of the Kingdome of Ireland the Honourable John Noell Esq[uire] Sir
Thomas Mackworth Baronet Sir Thomas Barker Baronet William Palmes Bennet Sherrard John Verney Samuell
Browne Eusebius Boswell Charles Halford Christopher Browne Edward Fawkner Edward Hosman Robert Markworth
Anthony Palmer Edward Browne Clement Breton Cornelius Burton John Weaver Charles Tirrell Wellesborne Sill
Armine Bullingham Edward Fawkner junior Marsh of Tinwell John Flavill Richard Snow Thomas
Hayes Esq[uire]uires Richard Mathew Andrew Burton John Baker Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s78">
<head>For the County of Salop</head>
<para id="p142">The Right Honourable Sir John Trevor Knight Speaker of the House of Commons and First Lord Commissioner
for the Custodie of the Great Seale The Honourable Richard Newport Esq[uire], The Honourable Andrew Newport
Esq[uire], Sir Henry Litleton Sir William Levison Gower Sir William Whitmore Sir Humphrey Briggs Sir John Corbett
Sir Francis Lawley Sir Uvedale Corbet Sir Edward Acton Sir Thomas Litleton Sir Job Charlton Sir William
Williams Sir Thomas Woolrich Baronets Sir Thomas Travell Sir William Lacon C hilde Sir Thomas Jones Sir
Adam Oatley Sir Robert Owen Sir William Forrester Knights Jervas Pierpoint William Fowler Francis Charlton
of Apply John Charlton John Walcutt Charles Manwaring Arthur Manwaring Francis Forrester Edward Leighton
Richard Lister Edward Kinaston of Oatley Edward Kinaston of Harley John Kinaston Phillip Prince Henry Herbert
Francis Herbert Edward Owen of Condover George Weld Humphrey Briggs William Oakley Robert Corbet
Thomas Rocke John Coates Richard Moore Walter Wareing Charles Baldwin [Robert<ref idref="n72">72</ref>] Coates Robert Cressett
Robert [Owens<ref idref="n73">73</ref>] Roger Pope senior Roger Pope junior Thomas Lloyd Richard Creswell John Lacon Thomas Oatley
Litleton Powis Henry Newton Francis Charlton of Whitton Thomas Cornwall Bartholomew Lutly Thomas Hanmer
Henry Davenport Eldred Lancelott Leigh Thomas Langley Robert Harley Thomas Child Thomas Spratt William
Williams John Huxley John Chetwin Edward Kerry Orlando Nicholls Richard Mitton Edward Cludd Rowland
Hunt Henry Powell Jonathan Langley Thomas Lister Thomas Lister junior Thomas Edwards Richard Corbett
Robert Clowes William Gower John Tayleur Thomas Burton Thomas Smalman Soudley Eaton Robert Piggott
Thomas Winfield Thomas Mackworth John Edwards of Rorington John Powell Thomas Powell John Warter
Francis Barkley Arthur Weaver James Grove Thomas Jobber Robert Lloyd John Whitehall Henry Mitton William
Hayward Henry Barret Edward Jennings Edward Whitchcott Richard Carew Edward Owen of Pully William
Jones Charles Herbert Ralph Browne Thomas Sandford Job Walker Edward Dunn the younger Thomas Seaverne
William Adams senior William Adams junior The Mayor of Salop for the time being The Mayor of Ludlow
for the time being The Bayliffes of Bridgenorth for the time being The [Bayliffes<ref idref="n74">74</ref>] of Bishops Castle for the time
being The Bayliffe of Wenlocke for the time being The Mayor of Oswestry for the time being John Hill Richard
Hosier Buckly Mackworth Richard Salter Edward Gosnell Roger Griffith Jonathan Scott Collins Woolrich Richard
Muckleston Robert Wood Thomas Owen Charles Kinaston Simon Hanmer John Cole of Shrewsbury Esq[uire] Robert
Gorton Gen&tilde; Thomas Acton Edward Mitton William Leeke Samuell Woolleston Richard Betton Adam Wareing
Richard Deaves William Grosvenor Richard Jenkins Samuell Bowdler John Langley of the Amias Thomas Crompton
Lancelott Stephens John Mason of Much Wenlock John Bright Edward Pully Thomas Hawkes Thomas Sabry
Thomas Hill of Aleaston John Atkinson Doctor of Physicke Timothy Hassall Samuell Sandiford George Chambre
Jonathan Wingfield John Latham George Walker William Kinaston Phillip Cole Thomas Jones Edward Ketleby
junior Sheppard of Bitterly Francis Boycott Richard Ridley Robert Smith John Fowler Thomas
Mason Thomas Hincks William Bridgen Richard Walker Thomas Wickstead Richard Bradley Alexander Midleton
Edward Matthews Humphrey Owen Samuell Hunt John Parker Arthur Tonge John Clarke Richard Jenks of Drayton
Gent. Thomas Jones Councellor at Law.</para>
</section>
<section id="s79">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Bristoll</head>
<para id="p143">Sir John Knight Knight Mayor William Pawlet Recorder Sir Richard Hart Sir Richard Crumpe Sir William
Clutterbooke Sir William Hayman Sir William Merricke Knights Sir William Cann Baronet John Hicks William
Crabb Joseph Creswicke Abraham Saunders William Swimmer Richard Lane Thomas Day William Jackson Arthur
Hart Robert Henley Esquires Edward Fielding William Downeing Esquires Robert Doubting John Yeomans Sheriffes
John Dutton Colt George Hart Nathaniell Driver Edmund Arundell Giles Merricke James Twiford Robert Yate
George Morgan Edward Tocknell John Sandford Samuell Wallis John Hine Thomas Cole John Bubb John
Blackwell John Rumsey Robert Henley Thomas Edwards John Duddlestone Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s80">
<head>For the County of Somersett.</head>
<para id="p144">John Lord Viscount Fitzharding of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Edward Seymour Sir John Sidenham Sir John
Smith Sir Edward Wyndham Sir John Trevillian Sir Francis Warr Sir John St Barbe Sir William Cann Sir
[Haswell<ref idref="n75">75</ref>] Tinte Baronets Sir Edward Phelipps Sir Thomas Bridges Sir William Bassett Sir George Norton Sir
Richard Hart Sir John Knight Sir Charles Carteret Sir William Wogan Their Majestyes Serjeant at Law Sir
Thomas Travell Knights Henry Portman George Horner Edward Gorges Nathaniell Palmer Edward Berkley Hopton
Wyndham John Hunt Henry Bull John Speak John Sanford Alexander Lutterell Edward Clarke Joseph Langton
William Hellyar senior William Hellier junior Henry Rolle Warwicke Bampfield John Piggott Edward [Baber<ref idref="n76">76</ref>] William
Gore William Lacy George Long Thomas Chasin Edmond Windham Baldwin Mallett John Blewet of Helcombe
Thomas Beere of Huntsham Thomas Carew Henry Gould William Ettericke William Strode John Harrington
Richard Morgan Edward Hobbs Charles Steynings Thomas Moore James Prowse Henry Roynon John Champney
Henry Henley Richard Crosse William Coward William Phellips William Helyard of Sea Anthony Stocker Henry
Lyte George Clerke Thomas Strode of Mapperton Anthony Stocker Henry Mompesson Thomas Mompesson Robert
Siderfin Samuell [Gorgers<ref idref="n77">77</ref>] Ferrers. Grisley William Harbin John Blewet of Knowle John How Andrew Crosse James
Cade George Doddington of Doddington George Doddington of Wells George Musgrave senior George Musgrave
junior Robert Long Richard Elsworth Esquires William Davy Esq[uire] Francis Vaughan Richard Lansdowne Thomas
Dike Edward Dike of Kings Brompton William Catford John Worth William Player William Westley William
Hughes Richard Jones of Stowy John Huddy senior John Huddy junior James Twiford Richard Cox Samuell Cable
John Sandis Thomas Gale Roger Leversage John Creswicke William Whitechurch senior William Whitechurch
junior John Burland Samuell Horner John [Strarchy<ref idref="n78">78</ref>] Edmond Bowyer George Prater Francis Holles
Ettericke Cadwallader Jones Nicholas Francis Henry Winter Thomas Sambourne Phillip Bennett Edward Thurstone
John Acourt senior John Acourt junior William Lucy Thomas Ledgingham William Champney Thomas Sumner
of Wellow Samuell Raymond Robert Blake Matthias Hanvill Robert Pearse. Doctor of Phisicke John Blinman of
Willitton Thomas Beach William Lyde senior Cornelius Lyde Edmond Bourne John Everad William Bolton
Blagdon of Wilton Thomas Compton James Blanchard Thomas Langdon Edward Bacon John Keyne
John Mere Henry Proctor Benjamin Gifford of Harsington Thomas Hawker Esquire&sdot; William Bidygood Richard
Wyatt John Frind Francis Hubbard Richard Snow John Smith Nicholas Marshall Thomas Baker Thomas Groves
Thomas Towell.</para>
</section>
<section id="s81">
<head>For the City of Wells</head>
<para id="p145">The Mayor for the time being William Coward Recorder George Doddington Esq[uire] William Hughes William
Westly John Davies Richard Thomas.</para>
</section>
<section id="s82">
<head>For the Burrough of Bridgewater</head>
<para id="p146">The Mayor for the time being Alexander Popham Alderman John Gilbert senior Alderman John Harvey of the
Castle Francis Tuthill Roger Hore.</para>
</section>
<section id="s83">
<head>For the City of Bath</head>
<para id="p147">The Mayor for the time being Robert Peirce Doctor of Phisicke John Masters Walter Gibbs John Bush Robert
Chapman Edward Bushell Benjamin Baber John Stibbs Walter Hicks John Haward Colloby.</para>
</section>
<section id="s84">
<head>For the County of Stafford</head>
<para id="p148">The Right Honourable John Lord Viscount Mazarine of the Kingdome of Ireland The Honourable William Ward
Esq[uire] High Sheriffe for the County of Stafford The Honourable John Grey Esquire The Honourable Henry Pagett
Esq[uire] The Honourable Clotworthy Skeffinton Esquire Sir Thomas Peshall Sir William Levison Gower Sir Thomas
Wilbraham Sir Walter Wortesley Sir Walter Bagott Sir Henry Litleton Sir Edward Litleton Sir Charles Wolseley
Sir Francis Lawley Sir John Bower Sir Thomas Bellott Sir Michaell Biddolph Baronets Sir Bryan Broughton
Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Gough Sir Charles Skrimshire Sir John Floyer Knights Sir Edward Hungerford
Knight of the Bath Walter Chetwind William Chetwind Sir John Turton Knight one of the Barons of the
Exchequer John Chetwind Thomas Broughton Edward Litleton Robert Burdett Robert Wolseley Thomas Lawley
Edward Birch Serjeant at Law Jonathan Cope Richard Dyott Thomas Foley Phillip Foley William Sneyd of Keel
Ralph Sneyd junior Thomas Lane Humphrey. Wirley Robert Leveson Rowland Okeover John Lawton George
Rodney Bridges Thomas Kinnersley Henry Vernon William Crompton John Every Thomas Rudyard John Hoo
William Parker senior George Parker William Parker junior John Swinfen Thomas Birch William Inge Phillip
Hollins Mathew Floyer Phillip Pargiter John Grosvenour Charles Cotes William Cotton Francis Wightwicke senior
Francis Wightwicke junior John Wightwicke William [Twiton<ref idref="n79">79</ref>] John Bagnall Edward Foden Copwood Hollins Francis
Eld Francis Wolferston William Nabbs Richard Piott Thomas Jolliffe William Jolliffe William Milward John
Shilton Lambert Bagot John Newton Henry Leigh Phillip Chetwood Tomins Dickens Daniell Watson John Persehouse
Charles Blount Michaell Noble Esquires Walter Aston Thomas Whitby William Anson John Huntbach James
Wood Peter Warburton William Trafford senior William Trafford junior Thomas Scott Thomas Jevan senior
Leicester Barbour Christopher Lea Samuell Pipe Bernard Whaley Edward Short Michaell Brandrith William Jervis
Samuell Hunt Walter Fowler Jonas Astley Thomas Pigott Browne of Thornes John Amphlett Browne of Shredicote
William Whitby Henry Gilbert Walter Moseley John Baddiley Richard Whitworth Edward Barbour John Young
William Vise John Fenton Thomas Milward James Rudyard Roger Fowke John Goreing Richard Drakeford Henry
Bracegirdle Gentlemen The Mayor of Stafford for the time being Edward Foden Esquire Recorder William Nabbs
Esq[uire] William Feake senior William Feake junior Edward Bird Walter Collins Sampson Birch William Abnet senior
John Williamson Humphrey Perrey Gentlemen The Bayliffes of Tamworth for the time being Sir Edward Litleton
Baronet Leicester Barbour Nicholas Parker Charles Bainton George Alsop Job Beardsley Samuell Beardsley Gentlemen
The Mayor of Newcastle for the time being William Badiley Thomas Hordein William Boughay Samuell Rock
William Midleton William [Lawton<ref idref="n80">80</ref>] Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s85">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Litchfield</head>
<para id="p149">The Bayliffes and Sheriffes for the time being Edmond Hector George Newill Sir Michaell Biddulph Baronet
Sir John Floyer Knight Robert Burditt Richard Dyott Phillip Pargiter Richard Pyott Esquires Thomas Hamond
John Rawlins Richard Wakefield William Walmesley William Marshall William Potts Richard Burnes Robert
Bailey Gent.</para>
</section>
<section id="s86">
<head>For the County of Southampton</head>
<para id="p150">The Right Honourable Sir John Trevor Speaker of the House of Commons and First Lord Commissioner for
the Custodie of the Great Seale The Right Honourable Charles Lord Marquesse of Winchester Lord Chamberlaine
to Her Majestie Sonne and Heire Apparent of Charles Duke of Bolton The Honourable Edward Russell Esq[uire]
The Right Honourable Henry Earle of Sterling in the Kingdome of Scotland The Right Honourable William
Lord Pawlett second Sonne to the Duke of Bolton Richard Earle of Ranelagh of the Kingdome of Ireland The
Honourable James Russell Esq[uire] The Honourable Francis Pawlet Esq[uire] Sir John Mill Sir Hugh [Stewkley<ref idref="n81">81</ref>] Sir Nicholas
Steward Sir John Dillington Sir Hele Hooke Sir John Hobby Sir Robert Worseley Sir Andrew Henley Baronets
Sir Richard Onslow Baronet Sir Charles Windham Sir William Kingsmill Sir Thomas Higgons Sir Robert Sawyer
Sir William Stephens Sir Robert Holmes Sir James Worseley Sir Benjamin Newland Sir Robert Henley Knights
Sir John St Barbe Baronet Richard Norton Thomas Jerveis senior George Pitt senior Thomas Hobby Leonard
Bilson Esquires John Kent Esquire Henry Rolle Gabriell Whistler Ralph Hastings Henry Wallop Henry Dawley
Francis [Morley<ref idref="n82">82</ref>] Fredericke Tilney Richard Holt Richard Whitehead Richard Cobb Charles Cole George Evans
White Titchborne John Smith of Tidworth Esquires John Pollen Richard Bishop Richard Chandler John Wallop
Thomas Bilson William Bishop Charles Morley Samuell Gawden George Bridges Charles Wither George Abbott
John Fawkoner Charles Forrester Thomas Broccas Oliver Cromwell Thomas Jervoise senior John Deane Edward
Chute. Henry Bromfeild John Burrard Robert Smith Henry Compton John Venables Henry Hooke Edward
Fleming Robert Knollis William Bulkley George Stanley Edward Hooper Arthur Hyde Francis Dickens Esquires
Henry Perin Doctor of Phisicke Thomas Miller Richard Stanley Richard Carter Thomas Tutt William Coleman
Henry Tulse Richard Love junior George Pitt junior Benjamin Ruddiard Thomas Wither William Norton Robert
Mitchell Lawrence Jackson Thomas Bulkley William Battin Roger Bartin Robert Barton George Duke Thomas
Smith Thomas Edmonds Thomas Douse of Wallop Thomas Douse of Brooke John Rives of Drayton John Rives
of Bransbury Edward Pile Christopher Stokes Peter Blake Thomas Pile junior Thomas Fitz James Esq[uire] John Lisle
Mathew Bennet William Guidat Samuell Pitman Charles Dingley Esquires Richard Beele Giles Lyford Robert
Love Allen Garway Anthony Guydott Thomas Goddard Edward Rooke Henry Christmas George Wakeford
Gentlemen The Mayor of Winton for the time being Ellis Mewes Esq[uire] Anthony. Yalden Godson Penton John
Purdue Charles Dingley Paul Burrard Roger Jones Richard Good John Conger Thomas Pinke Henry Sharpe
Nicholas Hedger Gentlemen The Mayor of Portsmouth for the time being Lewis Barton Gent. The Bailiffe of
Andover for the time being Thomas Brunker Edward Batten John Blakly John Blowes Thomas [Wiltshaw<ref idref="n83">83</ref>] James
Grove Henry Curle Richard Hill John Stephens Gentlemen The Mayor of Christ Church The Mayor of Newport
for the time being Richard Knight John Worseley Nicholas Lisle John Chapman David Urry of Easton Thomas
Urry of Freshwater Thomas Urry of Gatcombe Esquires Eustace Man Robert Leigh John Bowler John Stephens
of West Cowes Gent. William Fielder Thomas Dore William Knapton Edward Hales of Newport John White
William Pay John Palmer John Hildesley [Esquires<ref idref="n84">84</ref>.]</para>
</section>
<section id="s87">
<head>For the Towne and County of the Towne of Southampton.</head>
<para id="p151">The Mayor for the time being Sir Giles Eyre Knight one of the Justices of the Kings Bench William Bulkley
Esq[uire] John Speede Doctor of Physicke Thomas Cornelius Richard White James Crosse John Lee William Cropp
John Smith Adam de Cardonell Christopher Smith Cornelius Markham Robbert Culliford Thomas Bracebridge
Richard Hunt William Line alias de Gruchye Leonard Cropp Jacob Ward Thomas Everard.</para>
</section>
<section id="s88">
<head>For the County of Suffolke</head>
<para id="p152">Lyonell Lord Huntingtower of the Kingdome of Scotland Sir Adam Felton Sir John Barker Sir John Platers
Sir Robert Kempe Sir Simon Dewes Sir John Castleton Sir Dudley Cutham Sir Henry North Sir Jervase Elwayes
Sir John Rouse Sir Thomas Allen Sir Thomas Barnardiston Sir John Duke Sir Robert Brooke Sir Phillip Parker
Sir Edmond Bacon Sir Samuell Bernardiston Sir Francis Masham Sir Robert Davers Sir Charles Bloyse Sir
William Cooke Baronets Sir Charles Gaudy Sir Robert Rich Knights and Baronets Sir Peyton Ventris Sir John
Poley Sir Thomas Harvey Sir George Wenyeve Sir Nevill Catelin Sir Henry Johnson Sir Phillip Skippon Sir
Joseph Brand Sir Richard Gibbs Sir Cesar Wood alias Cranmer Sir Charles Umfrevill Sir Francis Blundell Knights
William Maynard Ptolemy Tollmash Nicholas Bacon [Thomas Holland<ref idref="n85">85</ref>] Thomas Felton Compton Felton Thomas
Glemham Thomas Knivite Thomas Tolmash Lyonell Playters Henry Heveningham Thomas Cole William Bridgeman
Henry Parker Thomas Theobald William Barker Thomas Waldegrave Francis Barker William Johnson Thomas
Tyrrell Edmond Warner John Hunt Esquires John Robinson John. Thurston Richard Norton Robert Maddokes
Henry Warner Thomas Aldham Richard Hubbard Henry Polly John Brain Thomas Salter Phillip Bedingfield
Robert King Richard Buckingham Hammond L'Estrainge John Scrivener Charles Smith Edward North William Rivat
Thomas Edgar James Calthorpe John Cornwallis Francis Novell alias Smith William Crofts Anthony Crofts John
Wright Edmond Bence Robert Barker Robert Nanton John Corrance Robert Maltiward Thomas Wright Thomas
Roddord Henry Edgar Arthur Bernardiston Laurence Rouse junior Thomas Golding William Glover Thomas
Leamon George Fleetwood John Bence Robert Warrein Jacob Garrard Awbrey Porter John Hervey Henry Goldwell
Christopher Calthorpe Henry Copinger John Jermy of Sproughton John Jermy of Stutton Anthony Wrath Thomas
Tirrell Allen Cotten Edward Alpe Edmund Sheppard John Smith of Parkfield John Hall Thomas Smith William
Cullam Thomas Love Robert Davy Thomas Rivett John Beaumont Thomas Smith Nicholas Bragg William Covell
Hugh Morice John Whiteacre John Hooke Doctor Thomas Carver William Betts Captaine Finn William Poley
Robert Cudon John Catsby John Browne Roger Kerrington Francis Harvey Thomas Neale Thomas Dye Thomas
Else Nicholas Freeman Thomas Hastings John Pells Edward Alston John Hodges John Felton Peter Alderman
John Hunt John Spink Renaldo Pitfield John Gerling Gregory Clarke William Randall Richard Vesey Thomas
Dade Thomas Wright senior Doctor John Bourchier Thomas Barnardiston Samuell Barnardiston Richard Wareing
Thomas Brand John Barker of Wickam Robert Jeney Thomas Bright William Hammond Samuell Clarke William
Cooke Andrew Warner Francis Brewster John Hill Samuell Blackerby Simon Folke Richard Porter Smith
of [Marsford<ref idref="n86">86</ref>] John Brand Esquires Eldred of Saxham John Wild senior Phillip French William Hamond
Joseph Hastings Samuell Baker Isaac Rebow Thomas Owen Thomas Aldridge Charles Close William Lucas
Thomas Keeper Samuell Pacey Thomas Bendish Bartholomew Soame Esquires William Bright Robert Russell
Edward Gaell James Goodwin Thomas Folks John Nicholls senior Francis Heylock Henry Ward Henry North
Lawrence Stistead Richard Phillips John Blumfield Robert Clarke William Tye Richard Margatt William [Fold<ref idref="n87">87</ref>]
Joseph [Wells<ref idref="n88">88</ref>] Nathaniell Simonds Richard Fryer William Neave William Glascocke Anthony Fisher John Craske
junior Robert Chaplin Robert Snelling William Beaumont Captaine Brandling Done of Hadleigh John Artis
senior Richard Freestone [Esquires<ref idref="n89">89</ref>] Captaine Young Thomas Scarlet Andrew Brownesmith Thomas Fothergill
John Pinchback John Buxton Thomas Michill Nicholas Edgar George Watts Richard Jenkinson Thomas Bright
Devereux Edgar.</para>
</section>
<section id="s89">
<head>For the Burrough of Eye</head>
<para id="p153">The Bayliffes for the time being Henry Polly Thomas Davinant Thomas Vincent Esq[uire] Thomas Deye senior
Henry Edgar Thomas Browne Nathaniell Deye Thomas Deye junior Francis Deye Thomas Brampton Thomas
Flowerey Smith Chenerey.</para>
</section>
<section id="s90">
<head>For the Burrough of Sudbury</head>
<para id="p154">The Mayor for the time being Sir Thomas Barnardiston Baronet John Robinson Esq[uire] John Catesby John Parish
Richard Hobard William Cocke Samuell Abbott William Hazell Thomas Hall Samuell Hazell William Fothergill
Robert Chaplin Martin Harris Clement Ray Bernard [Carver<ref idref="n90">90</ref>] Henry Crossman William Hall Robert Gurling
Miles Birkett.</para>
</section>
<section id="s91">
<head>For the Burrough of Dunwich</head>
<para id="p155">The Bayliffes for the time being Sir Robert Rich Knight and Baronet Sir Phillip Skipon Knight John Benefice
John Postle Jeremiah Burlingham William Wetherby Thomas Neale William Betts William Hamond Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s92">
<head>For the Burrough of Ipswich</head>
<para id="p156">The Bayliffes for the time being Richard Pupplett Robert Manning Sir John Barker Sir Charles Bloise Sir
[Peiton<ref idref="n91">91</ref>] Ventris one of Their Majestyes Justices of the Common Pleas Thomas Edgar Recorder Charles Wright
Lawrence Stistead Richard Phillips John Burroughs William Neave William Browne John Blomfield John Wade
Miles Wallis Henry Sparrow William Tye Robert Clarke Towne Clerke.</para>
</section>
<section id="s93">
<head>For the Burrough of Bury St. Edmonds.</head>
<para id="p157">Sir Robert Davers Baronet Henry Goldwell Sir Thomas Harvey Knights Robert Sharpe Richard Preym Aldermen
Martin Spenceley Thomas Holland Esquires Thomas Macro senior Recorder for the time being Thomas Macro
junior.</para>
</section>
<section id="s94">
<head>For the Burrough of Aldborough</head>
<para id="p158">Sir Henry Johnson Knight William Johnson Esq[uire] John Bence Esq[uire] Thomas Neale Esq[uire] John Browne Thomas
Wall Edward Wall Alexander Osborne Hitchengam Wright John Burwood Richard Covell Richard Gardener
Gen&tilde; Richard Burwood.</para>
</section>
<section id="s95">
<head>For the Towne of Orford</head>
<para id="p159">Sir John Duke Baronet Thomas Glemham Thomas Felton Esq Thomas Hastings Joseph Hastings Thomas
Palmer William Morgan.</para>
</section>
<section id="s96">
<head>For the County of Surrey</head>
<para id="p160">The Right Honourable Sir Robert Howard one of His Majesties most Honourable Privy Council The Right
Honourable Sir [Robert<ref idref="n92">92</ref>] Capell Knight of the Bath one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill The
Honourable Heneage Finch The Honourable Francis Coventry The honourable Percy Kirke Esquires Sir Walter
St John Sir Francis Vincent Sir Adam Browne Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir Richard Onslow Sir John Thompson
Sir Lawrence Stoughton Sir Edward Bromfield Sir Edward Evelin Sir William Temple Sir Robert Napper
Sir Richard Atkins Sir William Glynne Sir Joseph Alstone Baronets Sir John Nicholas Knight of the Bath Sir
William Morley Knight of the Bath Sir William Hoskins Sir Mathew Andrews Sir St John Brodericke Sir
Robert Clayton Sir Purbecke Temple Sir Peter Rich Sir James Clarke Sir Christopher Buckle Sir Cornwall
Bradshaw Sir James Butler Sir William Elliott Sir Robert Knightley Sir George Vernon Sir Thomas Temple
Sir Peter Daniell Sir Samuell Dashwood Sir Edward Fruin Sir John Parsons Sir Thomas Vernon Sir Peter
Vandeputt Sir William Hill Sir George Meggott Knights Mr. Serjeant Fuller Thomas Howard George Evelin
William Mountague Hugh Hare Henry St Johns Thomas Vincent Roger James Thomas Turgis Anthony Bowyer
Denzell Onslow White Tichbourne Foote Onslow John Weston Edward Nicholas George Rodney Bridges
John Arnold John Evelin Phillip Hilyard Edward Harvey William Brownlow Baptist May James Zouch George
Woodroffe Nicholas Carew John Milner George Evelin of Nutfield Morgan Randall Ambrose Browne Haestreat
James Sigismond Stidolph George Duncombe Edward Bray John Sands William Hooker Richard Nicholls Shem
Bridges Richard Morley Ambrose Muschampe Peter Hussey Deane Goodwin Phillip Rawley William Harvey
Richard Onslow Christopher Buckle Thomas Lant John Gore Richard Garth Francis Brend William Hatton
Charlton Whitelock Stephen Harvey Robert Gavill John Burgoine John Thynne William Perry William
Vanbrough George Coldham William Nuthall John Love Thomas Newton Nicholas Hookes George Smith William
Haward John Mitchell Thomas Ures Henry Whistler John Wight Peter Delanoy Hatton Thomas
Trapps Henry Ludlow Jeffery Amhurst Henry Lloyd William Bridgman John Heather Martin Folkes John
Turner Samuell Lewen Walter Howland John Pettiward Edward Thurland Thomas Molineux Henry Vincent John
Parsons John Lugg Eldred Lancellott Lee Ellis Crispe Nicholas Wyat William Jenue Nicholas Fenne Captaine
Salmond Benjamin Le Cane Samuell Atkinson William Herster Phillip Forster Major Edward Lane William Eyre
Ralph Snow Samuell Somerford Thomas Cox Robert Saunders Captaine Henry Williamson Richard Kent Samuell
Pett George Coreing Nicholas Waite Robert Douglas Esquires The Mayor and Magistrates of Guilford for the
time being Bailiffes of Kingston for the time being Thomas Wimondesold Maximilian Emely John Austin William
Boothby Timothy Wilson Joseph Lee Robert Moore John Childe Saunders of Toating Josias Dewy
Thomas [Burroughs<ref idref="n93">93</ref>] Urban Hall Samuell Crispe Lawrence March John Spencer Ralph Strake Richard Jewell
Thomas Harris Samuell Walls Captaine Bartholomew Thomas Jordan of Gatwick William Jordan Doctor Budgton
Doctor Rosewell Thomas Jordan Richard Gwynne Henry Johnson Edward Woodward William Summers Peter Norbrow
Robert Bowyer of Richmond Thomas Cusden Gerrat Andrews Simon Smith Richard White Doctor Kelsey Henry Wyatt
John Burchett Peter Hues Vertue Radford George Atwood William Dorrizon John Steere John Eversett Ulisses Blount
John Terry Captaine Wadnall John Simboll Peter Kesterman William Hambley Isaac Cox Leonard Hammond Thomas
Hammond Richard Hammond Daniell Mercer Richard Morgan Henry Bines William Gibbs Christopher Smith Francis
Wilkinson Jonadab Balam William Sherlocke Jonas Sish Daniell Wight Thomas Jordan Daniell Duttees John
Greene Joseph Wood Charles Shorter Vertue Radford Thomas Juxon Thomas Lofield William Allwood Collonell
Peirce Walter Vernon Samuell Atkinson Edward Smith Esquires John Sermon Samuell Hall Benjamin Cracker
John Hadson William Grey John Nicholls Edward Dimbleby William Atwood Thomas Jordan Brewer Benjamin
Tarrant John Allwood John Wood Joseph Shepherd Daniell Wright senior Henry Wilcason Thomas Cox John
Chumney Jacob Packham William Steerie William Rutter John Gerrard John Smith of Camberwell Joseph
Chittey Francis Wilcason.</para>
</section>
<section id="s97">
<head>For the County of Sussex</head>
<para id="p161">Sir John Pelham Sir William Thomas Sir John Fagg Sir Denny Ashburnham Sir Thomas Dyke Sir William
Wilson Sir William Culpeper Sir Richard Shirley Sir Richard Onslow Baronets Sir William Morley Knight of
the Bath Sir Nicholas Pelham Sir James Morton Sir Edward Selwin Sir John Briscow Sir Christopher Conyers
Sir Edward Hungerford Sir James Smith Knights Sir Philip Gell Baronet Thomas Pelham Thomas Sackvile John
Lewknor William Morley Henry Pelham Thomas Nudigate Henry Shelley Nisell Rivers Richard Bridges Thomas
Briggs Doctor at Law William Board George Goreing George Nevill James Butler Thomas Beard John Spence
senior James Graves John Fuller John Baker John Miller Humphry Fowle Simon Smith Phillip Parker Alexander
Staples Richard Onslow Esquires John Burrell Thomas Bromfield Walter Dobell junior William Markwicke John
Board Thomas Burrell Gentlemen Sir Thomas Miller Thomas Osbourne Thomas May John Matchell Thomas
Bickley George Gunter John Breman Richard Farrington Nathaniell Palmer Thomas Palmer William Williams
Peter Gott Henry Apsley Thomas Fruen Edward Dynne Samuell Highland George Courthop Esquires John
Marlott Randolph Tutty Francis Page Thomas Woodier Gent. Walter Roberts William Peckham Thomas Betsworth
Thomas Gray John Apsley William Westbrooke William Garway Thomas White (<ref idref="n94">94</ref>) John Cooke of Petworth Thomas
Garway John Cooke of Goreing John Lee of Plastow Richard Cooper Esquires Henry Bernard Thomas Nash
Edward Staker Oliver Whitby William Paine Humphrey Jewkes Thomas Peckham Thomas Knowles Thomas
Colebrooke Richard Banks Anthony Cruttenden Gent. Robert Hall Gent. Paul Burrard Esq[uire] The Maiors of
Chichester and Arundell for the time being Barnham Powell Charles Goreing John [Cheate<ref idref="n95">95</ref>] Charles Fagg John Miller
Robert Orme Henry Cowper Richard Paine senior Apsley Newton senior John Alford Robert Fagg John Monk
Anthony Eversfeild Esquires William Newton Nathaniell Turner John Gratwick of Jewis John Gratwicke of Etons
Thomas Poole Stephen Humphry William Alderton Thomas Ellis Francis Goater Abraham Chapman Edward
Morley William Cobden Nicholas Best Thomas Shepherd John Hay Samuell White John Wicker John Shelley
William Blaker John Weekes Thomas Fagg Gent. John Peachy of St Peters John Peachy Barrister at Law Esquires
John Styant Robert Thornden Richard Butcher George Oglander William Peachey Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s98">
<head>For Seaford</head>
<para id="p162">The Bayliffe and Jurats for the time being John Conyers Esq[uire] The Bayliffe of Pevensey for the time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s99">
<head>For the County of Warwicke</head>
<para id="p163">The Right Honourable the Lord Viscount Tiviot of the Kingdome of Scotland The Right Honourable the
Lord Digby of the Kingdome of Ireland The Honourable Sir Francis Compton Knight The Honourable Francis
Grevill Esq[uire] The Honourable Thomas Coventry Esq[uire] Sir John Mordant Sir Charles Holt Sir Simon Clarke Sir
Jacob Astley Sir Richard Temple Sir Clement Fisher Sir William Boughton Sir John Bridgeman Sir Charles
Shugburgh Sir John Huband Sir Reginald Foster Sir Bazill Price Baronets Sir William Underhill Sir John
Clopton Sir William Craven Sir Andrew Hacket Sir William Bishop Sir Richard Verney Sir Thomas Rawlinson
Knights Robert Burdett William Bromley Andrew Archer Walter Chetwind Esquires Thomas Rawlins Sergeant at
Law William Peicoe George Lucy Bazill Fielding Robert Somervile Thomas Wagstaffe Seabright Repington Arden
Adderley Henry Parker Arden Baggott Charles Newsham Hercules Beufoy Charles Knotsford William Palmer
Richard Hopkins Thomas [Mariott<ref idref="n96">96</ref>] William [Coaleman<ref idref="n97">97</ref>] Thomas Keate Edward Bentley Hastings Ingram Charles
Jennens William Bolton Edward Clopton Ward Dilke William Dugdale Michaell Biddolph Simon Biddulph John
Gowre Robert Harvey Francis Fisher junior Nathaniell Stoughton Henry Greene. John Stratford John Astley
Humphry Holden Humphrey Boughton Edward Boughton Francis Boughton John Shugburgh James Ludford Edward
Farmer John Combes John Clarke James Prescott Thomas Peeres Esquires George Fulwood John Mariot Thomas
Archer John Newsham Thomas Newsham Ambrose Holbech William Loggins Timothy Stoughton John Apletree
John Stanton Anthony Trotman Robert Wilcox John Andrews Job Beardsley Gentlemen The Maior of Warwicke
for the time being The Mayor of Stratford for the time being The Bayliffes of Tamworth for the time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s100">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Coventry.</head>
<para id="p164">The Mayor for the time being Sir Christopher Hales Sir Thomas Norton Baronets Richard Hopkins Henry
Greene Edward Tailer John Bowater Thomas Hopkins Robert Beake Esquires John Boon Edward Hill Henry
Smith Robert Smith Gentlemen Nathaniell Harriman Francis Harryman Edward Owen Thomas Lawrence
Aldermen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s101">
<head>For the County of Westmerland</head>
<para id="p165">Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir George Fletcher Baronets Sir Daniell Fleming Sir Christopher Phillipson Sir John
Otway Knights Richard Lowther John Dalston Christopher Dalston Thomas Hilton William Fleming Edward
Wilson senior Edward Wilson junior William Sandford Henry Wilson Thomas Fletcher Richard Brathwaite Roger
Moore Edward Musgrave John Fisher John Phillipson John Nevison Hugh Matchell Ephraim Sandford The Mayors
of Apleby and Kendall John Smith Robert Sharpe Thomas [Goodsale<ref idref="n98">98</ref>] Gent. Richard Crackenthorpe Ciprian
Hilton Arthur Scaife Richard Pindar Anthony [Saul<ref idref="n99">99</ref>] John Brougham Thomas Shepard Daniell Fleming Miles
Philipson George Wilson. Thomas Heblethwaite James Simpson James Bird Reginald Dobson John Hall Thomas
Wilson William Birkhead Thomas Cocke.</para>
</section>
<section id="s102">
<head>For the County of Wilts</head>
<para id="p166">Charles Marquesse of Winchester Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Duke of Bolton Edward Viscount Cornbury
Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Earle of Clarendon Anthony Lord Ashley Sonne and Heire Apparent to the
Earle of Shaftsbury Mountague Lord Norris Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Earl of Abingdon Henry Lord
Colraine of the Kingdome of Ireland Anthony Lord Viscount Faulkland of the Kingdome of Scotland The
Honourable Peregrine Bertie Esq[uire] Sir Edward Seymour Sir Walter St John Button Sir Edward Windham
Sir Richard Grubham How Sir Walter Long Sir James Long Sir William Pincent Sir James How. Baronets Sir
Edward Hungerford Sir John Nicholas Knights of the Bath Sir Giles Eyre Knight one of the Justice of Their
Majesties Court of Kings Bench Sir Henry Coker Sir John Ernley Sir John Talbot Sir Thomas Mompesson Sir
George Hungerford Sir Stephen Fox Sir Thomas Escourt Sir Mathew Andrews Sir Eliab Harvey Sir Charles
Rawleigh Sir Edmund Warnford Sir John Collins Sir Richard Hart Sir George Willoughby Sir Thomas Fowles
Sir Jonathan Raymond Sir Charles Hedges Knights The Honourable Goodwin Wharton Francis Pawlett George
Pitt Richard Lewis Alexander Popham senior Alexander Popham junior Robert Hyde Francis Wroughton senior
John Hall Richard How Thomas Hobby John Windham Henry Bainton Thomas Lambert of Bayton Samuell Eyre
Henry Brouncker Thomas Freake of Shrowton Thomas Bennet Edward Nicholas of Manninford Maurice Buckland
Thomas Pitt William Ash Alexander Thistlethwaite Francis Morley Henry St John Charles Fox Edward [Nicholas<ref idref="n100">100</ref>]
of Winterbourne Walter Ernle John Smith of Tidworth John Deane Edward Nicholls of Camins Francis Goddard
Francis Stonehouse William Trenchard Lawrence [Swainton<ref idref="n101">101</ref>] William Daniell Christopher Willoughby Thomas Webb
William Yorke John Glanvill Thomas Baskerville Edward Nott Thomas Chamberlaine George Wroughton Thomas
Goddard Thomas Freake of Hunnington John Bolis John Hawlis William Harvey Thomas Penruddock William
Windham Thomas Windham Walter Grubb John Davenant Henry Chivers Nicholas Bainton Richard Chandler
Richard Jones of Ramsbury John Ash of Haywood John Young Thomas Gunter senior Thomas Gunter junior
James Linch of White Parish Cox Richard Whitehead Lyonell Ducket John Wildman junior Edmond
Lambert John Marvin William Willoughby William Norbourne Thomas Chafin Edward [Seymour<ref idref="n102">102</ref>] Richard Nevill
William George Charles Raymond Charles Tucker Benjamin Gifford John Fitzherbert Edmond Hungerford John
Bennet William Hearst Gabriell Ashby John Wallis Richard Aldworth Herbert Salladine Richard Kent William
Brewer Michaell Ernle Edward Lisle Nevill Maskaline William Player David Thomas Doctor of Phisicke Charles
Yorke Walter Greene John Hippesley Charles Duncombe John Ash of Tefont Edmond Webb John Flower senior
John Bond Thomas Harris Richard Poore John Jacob Edward Duke Captaine Fitzjames Thomas Lambert of
Sarum Anthony Hungerford Thomas Polden Charles Danvers Walter Parker Henry Coker Francis Wroughton
junior Robert Drake Thomas Markes John Gantlet John Bigg Francis Swanton William Greenfield Charles Mitchell
Thomas Rolt William Hitchcocke Henry Pinnell John Curle Charles Pleydall Charles Bowles Robert Grove
senior John Grove of Chisbery Robert Grove John Long Francis Thistlewaite William Beach of [Tidleton<ref idref="n103">103</ref>]
Andrew Duke Charles Stuart Walter Long of Wraxall Robert Wadman Edward Hearst Samuell Trotman William
Hancocke Councellor at Law Fowkes of Knoyle Stringer of Ivy Church George Hill
Thomas Beach John Kent of Boscum Edward Rider Esquire Robert Smith Henry Dennis Oliver Bingley William
Fisher John Bowles Councellor at Law Edward Pleydall Edward Spencer Thomas Knighton Charles Brinsden
Thomas Tainter William Coles Thomas Bennet of Salthrop Thomas [Fipps<ref idref="n104">104</ref>] Henry Fairfax William Hussey Richard
Nevill Brereton Boucher Henry Blake Thomas Grove George Hill Esquire John Mompesson William Hues
Thomas Powell Thomas Hayward Dauntessey Brounker Nicholas Elliott Christopher Gardiner Richard Minifie John
Brooke Nicholas Daniell William Clare Christopher Lippiat John Smith of Alton Mathew Smith Jonathan Hill
John Twogood Walter Sharpe John Flower Henry Watman Edward Medlicott Thomas Hunt of Enford Henry
Eyre of Woodhampton Edmund [Hennings<ref idref="n105">105</ref>] Mathew Smith Francis Goddard of Pirton Henry Southby Thomas White
John Fisher Francis Coles senior Thomas Francklin Robert Bisse Robert Mandrell Thomas Long of Rowden
Thomas Stump Elias Ferris The Mayor of Salisbury for the time being The Mayor of Wilton for the time
being the Mayor of the Devizes for the time being The Mayor of Marleborough for the time being The [Bayliffes<ref idref="n106">106</ref>]
of Chippenham for the time being Christopher Lippier George Willoughby George Davies of Woodford James
Croom Nicholas Hayes Richard Smith of Kennet George Duke of Sarson Humphrey Wall Thomas Hunt of
Marleborough Richard Hilliard of the Devizes Jonathan Rogers of Chippenham Henry Wallis Esquire Peter Temple
Joseph Houlton Gentlemen Joseph Berrio John Lesse Anthony Trotman Genttilde; William Stewkley Esquires Sir
Thomas Earle Charles Danvers Lovelace Bigg Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s103">
<head>For the City of New Sarum and Close of the same.</head>
<para id="p167">The Mayor for the time being Sir Giles Eyre Knight Recorder one of the Justices of Their Majestyes Court
of Kings Bench Sir Thomas Mompesson Sir John Windham Knights Thomas Windham Thomas Hobby Thomas
Pitt William Hearst Christopher Gardner Peter Philips William Smith Thomas Kenton John Prideaux Andrew
Baden Roger Bushell James Herris Faulkner William Viner David Thomas Doctor of Phisicke
Richard Minors Lawrence Swanton Jonathan Hill Gabriell Ashley Edward Hearst Thomas Lambert Herbert
Saladine Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s104">
<head>For the County of Worcester</head>
<para id="p168">The Right Honourable Richard Earle of Bellomont in the Kingdome of Ireland The Honourable Thomas
Coventry Robert Tracy Thomas Watson Henry Foliott Gilbert Coventry Esquires Sir Robert Atkins Knight of
the Bath and Lord Chiefe Baron of Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer Sir Nicholas Lechmere one of the
Barons of Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer Sir Henry Litleton Sir John Packington Sir Francis Russell Sir
Thomas Rowse Sir Edward Seabright Baronets Sir William Keyte Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir James Rushout
Sir Rowland Barkley Sir Harry Conningsby Sir Francis Winnington Sir Thomas Streete Sir Thomas Haslewood
Sir Edward Dineley Sir John Matthews Sir John Sommers Their Majestyes Sollicitor Generall Knights Samuell
Sandys Henry Herbert William Bromley Thomas Foley Richard Dowdeswell Thomas Savage senior Henry Jefferys
George Walsh William Walsh Edwin Sandys Thomas Savage junior Edmond Letchmere Robert Berkley Thomas
Jolliffe Edward Rudge Bridges Nanfan Charles Baldwin Salwey Winnington John Charleton Walter Savage senior
Walter Savage junior Thomas Vernon of Astwood Thomas Cornwall Robert Dormer Robert Foley Francis Sheldon
John Marriott William Hancocke Higgons James Thomas Vernon of Worcester George Dowdeswell John Soley
John Bearcroft John Clatton Robert Wilde Edward Bull Chambers Slaughter Gerard Dannett Richard Nash
junior Allen Cliffe senior Allen Cliffe junior Francis Bromley John Sheldon Richard Freeman Charles Cocks
Edward Stiner Goddard Carter Benjamin Jolliffe Thomas Chetle of the Wallhouse Abell Gower Esquires William
Moore John Apletree Arthur Bagshaw Robert Dowley Thomas Low of Bromsgrove Abraham Cooke Thomas
Bushell Phillip Bearcroft of the Parish of St Swithen Henry Toy Samuell Hunt Thomas Hunt of Ribenhall Edward
Walker William Bird John Emmies Giles Parsons Martin Ballard Thomas Harris Richard Young George Gardiner
Richard Avenant Thomas Hunt of Blockley James Nash Nicholas Wheeler Edward Davies Edward Lench The
Mayor of Evesham The Bailiffs of Droitwich The Bayliffe of Bewdley George Harris Arthur Lowe William Boukey
Richard Norbury.</para>
</section>
<section id="s105">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Worcester</head>
<para id="p169">The Mayor Aldermen and Sheriffe Sir John Sommers William Bromley Sir Rowland Berkley Sir Thomas Streete
Henry Herbert Walter Savage junior Robert Wilde Phillip Bercroft of the Parish of St Swithen Samuell Swift
Edward Cookesey James Higgons John Handy Thomas Smith Nicholas Baker.</para>
</section>
<section id="s106">
<head>For the County of Anglesey</head>
<para id="p170">Richard Lord Bulkey Viscount Cashells in the Kingdome of Ireland Lewis Lord Viscount Dungannon in the
Kingdome of Ireland Thomas Bulkley Robert Bulkley Esquires Sir Hugh Owen Sir William Williams Sir Thomas
Mostin Baronets Sir William Williams Knight and Baronet Thomas Burton John Hooke Nicholas Bagnoll Price
Lloyd Francis Bulkley John Griffith of Carreg Lloyd John Owen Penrhose Owen Bold William Meirick John
Grosvenor Conningsby Williams Owen Hughes Samuell Hanson John Jones Doctor of Divinity John Ellis Doctor
of Divinity Owen Wynne William Robinson William [Griffith<ref idref="n107">107</ref>] of Llanvaiethley Robert Owen of Holyhead William
Morgan John Wynne Thomas Lloyd Henry Jones William Bulkley David Lloyd Lloydiart Hugh Wynne of
Treyerworth Roger Hughes Rowland Wynne Henry Sparrow John Owin Cremlin Thomas Williams [Thomas Williams<ref idref="n108">108</ref>]
Maurice Lewis Francis Lloyd Hugh Williams David Williams Owen Davies of Llandefredog Henry Wynne of
Penheskin Edward Lewis William Jones John Owen Bodiar Richard Edwards John Hill Richard Hughes William
Griffith Thomas Roberts of Castellor Richard Vaughan John Price Owen Roberts Richard Bulkeley Maurice Parry
The Mayor of Beaumaris for the time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s107">
<head>For the County of Brecon</head>
<para id="p171">Charles Lord Marquesse of Worcester Sonne and Heire Apparent of the Duke of Beaufort William Williams Esq[uire]
High Sheriffe Sir Walter Williams Sir Thomas Williams Sir Edward Williams Sir Rowland Gwynne Bushey Mansell
Thomas Morgan John Lewis of Coedmore Richard Williams Jeffery Jefferies Charles Morgan Edward Jones Thomas
Walker John Jefferies Daniell Williams Walter Vaughan John Morgan Marmaduke Gwynne Edward Lewis Phillip
Parry Richard Jeffreys John Stedman Charles Lloyd Lewis Jones Francis Lloyd John Walbeoffe Walter Williams
Robert Lucy William Bowen John Gwynne John Lewis of Langorse William Jones Jasper Meller Reece Price
James Donne Richard Watkins Saunder Saunders Howell Powell Morgan Watkins James Parry Thomas Williams
of Abercamlais Samuell Pritchard Richard Williams of Aberbrane Robert Rumsey Charles Powell Henry Jones
Gwynne Vaughon Bartholomew Games Thomas Powell of Massemaur Marmaduke Lloyd Walter Vaughan of
Tretower Edward Williams Charles Williams of Langinader Edward Games of Kuy Hugh Penry Richard Williams
junior of Aberbrane William Watkins of Pennyworlod Lewis Lloyd Thomas Gwynne Henry Vaughan William
Phillips William Williams of Batle John Maddocks Lewis Havard James Watkins of Shephouse Thomas Bowens
William Lloyd Morgan Price Thomas Jones of Tredwstan John Rumsey Howell Morgan Edward Williams William
Awbrey of Brecon William Watkins John Phillips Edward Price.</para>
</section>
<section id="s108">
<head>For the Towne of Brecon</head>
<para id="p172">The Bayliffe Recorder and Aldermen for the time being Sir Rowland Gwynne Knight Sir Walter Williams
Baronet Jeffrey Jeffryes Thomas Morgan Richard Williams of Cabalva Edward Jones John Jeffreys Charles Morgan
John Walters Daniell Williams William Phillips Saunder Saunders Lodowicke Lewis Henry Jones Esquires William
Winter John Price John Jeffreys Henry Thomas Gentlemen Edward Hughes Esquire William Williams Daniell Price
and Meredith James Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s109">
<head>For the County of Cardigan</head>
<para id="p173">Sir Carbery Price Baronet Sir Thomas Powell Knight Sir Basill Price Baronet John Lewis Hector Phillips
John Vaughan William Powell Thomas Lloid of Castle Howell Charles Lloyd William Herbert Thomas Lloyd
of Bronwyd David Lloyd of Wern John Herbert [David Lloyd Walter Parry<ref idref="n109">109</ref>] Thomas Lewis Daniell Evans John
Lewis of Trood-y-rhyw John Lewis of Gervose David Lloyd of Crinveyn Edward Jones of Llanine Cornelius Le
Brune Richard Lloyd John Phillips James Lloyd Evan Lloyd Hugh Lloyd John Williams Esquires John [James<ref idref="n110">110</ref>]
Edward Price Hugh Lloyd of Llwydiack Jenkin Lloyd David Lloyd of Foes-y-bleidded Stephen Parry Oliver
Howells Morgan Howells David Lewis William Jenkins Hector Morgans John Morris David Howells William Parry
Rees Lloyd of Lovesgrove David Lloyd of Cumbwa John Lloyd of Pantdd Hugh Lloyd of Dall-ys-Chertyr
Rodoricke Richards Evan Evans and Charles Lloyd of Kilforth Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s110">
<head>For the County of Carmarthen</head>
<para id="p174">Sir Edward Mansell Sir Sackville Crowe Sir Rice Rudd Sir William Russell Baronets Sir Rice Williams [Knt<ref idref="n111">111</ref>]
Sir Orlando Gee Sir John Powell Knight one of His Majestyes Justices of the Court of Common Pleas Sir
William Wogan one of His Majestyes Serjeants at Law Richard Vaughan of Taracoed Griffith Rice Thomas
Cornwallis Rowland Gwynne Christopher Midleton Thomas Lloyd of Berthandowell Richard Vaughan of Derthlys
Richard Jones Marmaduke Williams John Williams of Abbercothy John Evans of Trevente Thomas Lloyd of
Altacadnoe Richard Gwynne of Guempa Griffith Lloyd Rawleigh Mansell Edward Mansell Richard Mansell
Roger Manwareing John Tredenham Heny Owens Edward Vaughan William Brigstocke Thomas Brigstock Thomas
Lloyd of Dunneralt Arthur Gwynne John Williams of Talley Thomas Gwynne the elder Edward Jones of
Leathernoiad Henry Lloyd of Llunstepham William Beevans of Pencoed John Phillips of Dolehaid John Williams
of Carmarthen Towne Esquires George Gwynne Anthony Rudd David Gwynne Thomas Manwareing Owen Bowen
Thomas Phillips of Kilsant David Lewis of Lisnevith Henry Vaughan of Place Gwynne William Jones of Colebrooke
William Brigstocke of Abberguilly Walter Morgan Hugh Jones James Phillips Henry Lewis Anthony Williams
Walter Thomas Benjamine Lewis William Davis of Drutfloyne Charles Dalton Thomas Phillips of Llandarogg
Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s111">
<head>For the Towne of Carmarthen</head>
<para id="p175">The Mayor Aldermen and Common Councill of the Towne Sir Edward Mansell Sir Sackvill Crow Sir Rice Rudd
Baronets Sir Rice Williams Knight Rowland Gwynne Griffith Lloyd Edward Vaughan William Brigstock Henry
Lloyd Marmaduke Williams Esquires Thomas Mainwareing Thomas Lloyd Griffith Lewis David Edwards and
George Lewis Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s112">
<head>For the County of Carmarthen</head>
<para id="p176">[Richard<ref idref="n112">112</ref>] Lord Bulkley Viscount Cashells in the Kingdome of Ireland The Right Honourable Edward Russell
Thomas Bulkley Sir John Wynne Knight and Baronet Sir William Williams of Vaynoll Baronet Sir Thomas
Mostin Baronet Sir Robert Owen Knight Thomas Burton John Hooke Nicholas Bagnoll Collonell William Price
Roger Price Griffith Vaughan Robert Wynne William Wynne of the Abbey William Williams George Twesileton
John Jones Doctor of Divinity John Ellis Doctor of Divinity Richard Jones Doctor at Law Owen Wynne of
Glascoed Edward Williams William Madrin George Coitmore James Brunkyre Love Parry John Thomas Owen
Hughes Samuell Hanson Conningsby Williams Robert Hookes Hugh Bodurda William Wynne of Llanunda John
Rowlands Richard Edwards Randell Wynne William Wynne of Werne William Wynne of Glan yr a fan Griffith
Wynne of Stinllin John Wynne Richard Kiffin Griffith Carregg William Griffith of Madrinissa William Lloyd
Hugh Lewis Robert Pugh Owen Wynne Pen y brin Owen Coitmore Humphrey Roberts Robert Griffith Thomas
Fletcher William Williams Griffith Parry John Vaughan Evan Lloyd Penmachno Henry Arthur Hugh Stodart Owen
Roberts John Maurice Thomas Ellis.</para>
</section>
<section id="s113">
<head>For the County of Denbigh</head>
<para id="p177">The Right Honourable Sir John Trevor Knight Speaker of the House of Commons and First [Lord<ref idref="n111">111</ref>] Commissioner
of the Great Seale of England Sir John Wynne Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Powell Sir Richard Midleton
Sir Evan Lloyd Sir Thomas Grosvenor Sir Walter Baggott Baronets Sir Robert Cotton Sir Thomas Mostin Barronets
Sir Francis Compton Sir John Conway Baronets Sir William Williams Knight and Baronet Sir Robert Owen
Sir Jeffery Shackerley Sir Roger Puleston Sir Griffith Jeffryes Knights Edward Vaughan of Llwdiarth Edward
Brereton William Wynne of Melay Robert Davis of Llanerch Robert Wynne of Berthddu Richard Mostin of
Penbid William Williams of Place y ward Kenrick Eyton John Puleston of Pitill John Winn of Forne Thomas
Midleton Eubule Thelwall senior Josua Edisbury Roger Mostin of Brimbo William Robinson of Gwersilt Ellis
Lloyd of Pen-y-lan John Robarts Thomas Carter Eubule Thelwall junior Cadwallader Wynne Robert Price of
Geeler Owen Wynne of Lloyne David Maurice of Pen-y-bont Edward Maurice of Llorran Robert Wynne of
Maesmochnant Sydney Bunner John Wynne of Garthmelio Gent. Robert Griffiths of Brimbo Richard Midleton
Charles Midleton Simon Thelwall of Llanbed'r Thomas Wynne of Difrinalett John Midleton of Gwaynynog
Esquires Edward Griffiths Havod De Wern Gent. John Puleston of Llansillin Edward Wynne of Llan-y-sidd
Peter Ellis Foulke Lloyd of Foxall Ellis Meredith Esquires Eubule Lloyd Captaine John Chambers Richard Eyton
Booth Passnett Edward Lloyd of Place Maddock David Lloyd of Llangollen-vechan Richard-Wynne of Aberkinleth
David Lloyd of Bodnant Roger Midleton of Denbigh Robert Wynne of Garthmelio Robert Edwards of Plasiolin
Edward Lloyd of Dwifani Thomas Lloyd of Cefu Robert Lloyd of Hendrewaloid Peter Foulkes of Ereviate
John Vaughan of the same Gentlemen Sydney Godolphin Hedd Lloyd Esquires Evan Lloyd of Crosyockin Gent.
Thomas Price of Bwlch Humphrey Vale of Place-Yn-Yale Hugh Hughes of Brintanghor Thomas Shaw of Denbigh
The Aldermen and Bayliffes of the Towne of Denbigh for the time being Mr Thomas Harper Mr Robert Knowles
Edward Williams Esq[uire] John Dolben Esq[uire] John Lloyd Thomas Price of Geeler Edward Chambers John Heaton
Robert Roberts Richard Jones Thomas Davies Gent..</para>
</section>
<section id="s114">
<head>For the County of Flint</head>
<para id="p178">The Right Honourable Sir John Trevor Speaker of the House of Commons and first Lord Commissioner of
the Great Seale of England Sir John Hanmer Knight and Baronet Sir John [Conway<ref idref="n113">113</ref>] Sir Evan Lloyd Sir Thomas
Mostin Sir William Glynn Sir Robert Cotton Sir Richard Midleton Baronets Sir William Williams Knight and
Baronet Sir Robert Owen Knight Sir Roger Puleston Knight Collonell Roger Whitley Collonell William Price
Collonell Thomas Whitley Collonell Thomas Salisbury William Hanmer Thomas Carter Thomas Hanmer Robert
Davies William Lloyd John Llangley John Broughton Edward Lloyd of Fathin Richard Mostin Thomas Eyton
George Hope John Hope John Wynne Hugh Griffith Owen Barton Peirce Pennant Thomas Evans Thomas Whitley
Kenrick Eyton Jerrick Eyton Edward Lloyd John Grosvenor Edward Rovenscroft Edward Kinaston Edward Morgan
Richard Parrie William Rutter Thomas Williams Esquires Owen Barton Roger Mostin Ellis Young Lloyd
Twisleton William Griffith Thomas Jones Peter Wynn Roger Jones John Pennant Thomas Foulkes
Josiah Jones Thomas Lloyd Roger Edwards Thomas Lloyd Thomas Critchley Roger Pennant Williams Thomas
Salisbury John Wynn of Farin John Puliston of Pickhill Roger Davies Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s115">
<head>For the County of Glamorgan</head>
<para id="p179">Sir Edward Mansell Sir Edward Stradling Sir Charles Kemys Sir John Awbrey Baronets Sir Richard Bassett
Sir Rowland Gwynne Sir Humphrey Mackworth Sir Humphrey Edwin Knights John Windham Serjeant at Law
Thomas Mansell Thomas Morgan Richard Lewis Marmaduke Gibbs David Jenkins Richard Seys William Herbert
Francis Gwynne Bussey Mansell Thomas Lewis Edward Matthew Charles Matthew William Thomas William
Windham Martin Button Richard Longher William Herbert junior Thomas Button George Bowen Oliver St
John William Matthew William Aubury Thomas Gibbond Reynald Deere Walter Evans Rowland Dawkins William
Seys Edward [Mansell Edward<ref idref="n114">114</ref>] Parkins Edward Turbervill John Llewellin Richard Herbert John Price Esquires
Thomas Rees Thomas Mansell of Penrice Jeremy Dawkins James Gwynne Thomas Price Godwin Herbert William
Phillips John Bassett Thomas Popkins Rowland Hughes Phillip Williams Mathew Seys Richard Williams Roger
Powell Richard Jenkins Anthony Powell Loydarth Anthony Gwynne George Bidder Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s116">
<head>For the Towne of Cardiffe</head>
<para id="p180">Thomas Williams Cradocke Wells William Jones Cradocke Nowell Benjamin Browne William Richards John
Pursell Aldermen and William Thomas Towne Clerke William Jenkins and Richard Lloyd Gentlemen Bayliffes
of the Towne of Cowbridge The Portreeve of Neath The Portreeve of Swansey for the time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s117">
<head>For the County of Merioneth</head>
<para id="p181">Sir Richard Midleton Baronet Sir Hugh Owins Baronet Sir William Williams Knight and Baronet Sir Robert
Owen Knight Griffith Vaughan of Corse ge doll Hugh Nanney of Nanney William Lewis Anwill William Price of
Rhiwlas Edward Vaughan of Llwdirth William Pugh of Matthevern William Wynne of Melay Owen Anwill of
Penrhin Lewis Owens of Penniarth John Lloyd of Abberlavenny William Williams of Place-y-ward Vincent
Corbett John Nanney of Llanvendigett Roger Price of Rhywlas John Vaughan of Glan-y-llin Charles Hughes of
Gwerkley Owen Wynne of Penniwern Edward Meyricke Simon Lloyd Robert Wynne of Maesineuodd Richard
Mostin Richard Mitton Jenkin Vaughan Owen Eyton Meredith Lloyd Anthony Thomas Richard Poole of Caenest
John [Maesmore<ref idref="n115">115</ref>] Thomas Lloyd of Llandeckwin Robert Pugh of Doleymoch William Eyton Robert Price of
Isgroweddan Rowland Price Richard Owens Hugh Tydur of Egrin Esquires Robert Wynne of Garthmeilio Gent.
Mr Robert Nanney of Cefndaudwr Mr Edward Lloyd of Ddwyfain Mr John Morgans of Plasse Mr John Lewis
of Festiniogg Mr John Wynne of Garthmeilio Mr John Lloyd of Chefnfais Mr Henry Mostin Mr William Owins
of Llangar Mr John Humphryes Mr Hugh Hughes Mr Oliver Thomas Mr John Lloyd of Uron Mr Griffith
Roberts of Rhiwgoch Mr Edward Hughes of Towin Mr Hugh Owens of Caerberlin Mr Robert Vaughan of
Caerwnwch Mr William Humphryes Mr Thomas Lloyd of Hendwr Mr Richard Humphryes Mr Griffith Vaughan
of Dole-y-melynllwin Mr John Price of Wingwern Mr Caleb Lloyd Mr Ellis Davies Mr Robert Lloyd of Uran
Mr Rees Pritchard of Llwyngwrill Mr John Edwards of Tonfane Mr Morrice Davies Sir John Wynne Knight and
Baronet Mr Evan Wynne.</para>
</section>
<section id="s118">
<head>For the County of Montgomery</head>
<para id="p182">The Honourable Andrew Newport Esq[uire] Sir John Price Baronet Sir William Williams Knight and Baronet Price
Deveraux William Pugh of Mathavern Edward Lloyd of Bearthlloyd Edward Vaughan John Matthews Mathew
Morgan Richard Moistin John Kiffin Walter Clopton Charles Herbert John Edwards of Rorington Edward Leighton
Edward Barret Arthur Vaughan Thomas Rocke Arthur Deveraux Charles Lloyd of Garth Gabriell Wynne Richard
Lee Phillip Eyton Daniell Whittingham Richard Herbert Richard Stedman Thomas Mason Nathaniell Maurice
Humphrey Kinaston Thomas Lloyd Edward Price Robert Lloyd Arthur Weaver Mathew Price Meredith Morgan
William Williams Evan Glynne Vincent Price Rowland Owen Richard Owens John Thomas Edward Evans Edmond
Lloyd Richard Ingram Humphrey Jones Sidney Biner Sidney Godolphin Esquires Lumley Williams junior Thomas
Jucks Edward Jones Gilbert Jones John Griffiths of Glanhaveren Richard Rock Roger Trevor William Lloyd of
Finnant Richard Price of Gunley Vaughan Deveraux Thomas Griffiths Thomas Hodson Solomon Bowen Humphrey
Lloyd of Gaitree Samuell Lloyd John Griffiths of Bachiee John Vaughan of Mivod John Reed Hugh Derwas
Robert Kinaston Hugh Davis of Colffrin John Davis of the same William Evance of Llanderinio Evan Jones
of Llandlothian Richard Davies of Kenhinva Rees Lloyd of Kowney John Herbert Griffith Robinson William
Peirce Richard Price of Bettus David Meridith of Llanethelan Thomas Gwynne Richard Glynne Price Clune
Rees Lloyd of Cloghun Edward Bowen of Peneralt John Wilson Edward Price of Streetvaylog Edmond Morgan
David of Penegos Rondle Owen Humphrey Owen Evan Jones Roger Jones George Higgins.</para>
</section>
<section id="s119">
<head>For the County of Pembrooke</head>
<para id="p183">The Right Honourable Richard Lord Bulkley Viscount [Cashells<ref idref="n116">116</ref>] in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Erasmus
Phillips Sir Hugh Owen Baronet Sir Gilbert Lort Baronet Sir John Barlow Baronet Sir William Wogan Knight
Their Majestyes Serjeant at Law Hector Phillips Essex Mericke Arthur Owen Rowland Laugharne Edward Phillips
Lewis Wogan of Wiston Lewis Wogan of Boulston Hugh Bowen William Scourfield Walter Midleton John Owen
John Williams David Williams Griffith Dawes Thomas Lloyd John Barlow senior George Lort Arthur Owen
junior Griffith Fawkwell George Bowen William Warren James Lloyd Thomas Corbett William Skerme George
Meare Lewis John Charles Phillips William Wogan junior Henry Walter George Lehunt David Mauris John
Phillips John Lewes Arthur Laugharne Hugh Laugharne John Edwards Erasmus [Corbett<ref idref="n117">117</ref>] John Owen of Berllan
Esquires Robert Williams Lewis Mathews Gwyn Vaughan William Ford senior William Ford junior Owen Ford
William Jones Thomas Jones George Harris John Owen of Priskilly George [Lloyd<ref idref="n118">118</ref>] James Laugharne John
Wogan John Morris George Lewis James Harris Gentlemen The Mayor of Pembrooke for the time being Francis
Rogers Francis Dawes John Coursey Alexander Ford Aldermen of Pembrooke The Mayor of Tenby for the
time being Henry Williams James Lloyd Deveraux Hammond John Morris.</para>
</section>
<section id="s120">
<head>For the County of Radnor</head>
<para id="p184">Sir John Morgan Sir Standish [Hartstronge<ref idref="n119">119</ref>] Sir Edward Williams Sir Rowland Gwynne [Sir Edward Harley<ref idref="n118">118</ref>]
Sir Lacon Child Baronets William Fowler Richard Williams Henry Walcott Thomas Lewis of Harpton senior
Edward Lewis of Manaughty Thomas Lewis of Harpton junior Marmaduke Gwynne Samuell Powell. Thomas
Harley Litleton Powell Henry Probert Edward Price Thomas Vaughan Edward Howerth John Fowler Robert Lucy
James Lloyd Charles Lloyd Charles Creed William Brewster Jeremiah Powell Evan Bowen Hugh Matthews
Esquires Lewis Lloyd Thomas Lewis of Nantgwyett Nicholas Meredith Thomas Lewis of Cumtythwr John Davies
of Coedglasson Thomas Howerth Evan Vaughan William Lloyd Coroners Lemuell Lloyd Andrew Davies William
Tayler Peter Richards Jonas Stephens [Edward<ref idref="n120">120</ref>] Weston Lloyd Weston Henry Bull Henry Vaughan Walter
Vaughan Thomas Powell Edward Phillips Griffith Paine Robert Williams John Witney The Bayliffe and Aldermen
of New Radnor for the time being Robert Price Recorder Griffith Paine Henry Bull John Miles Esquires Robert
Weston Henry Boulter John Davies of the Uronlac Hugh Stephens Esquires John Stephens David Powell Gentlemen
Hugh Lewis of Hendwall Nehemiah Kettleby William Probert Robert Cutler John Walsham Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s121">
<head>For the Towne and County of Haverford West</head>
<para id="p185">The Mayor for the time being Sir Hugh Owen Baronet Sir William Wogan Knight Their Majestyes Serjeant
at Law Arthur Owen Lewis Wogan of Bolston William Wogan junior Richard Howell William Skerme John
Lewis Esquires William Fluerton Doctor of Phisicke Roger Davies Robert Prust senior John Bateman John Fowler
Thomas Payer William Bowen William Browne George Lewis Jacob Wilford Vincent Powell Robert Prust junior
William Bateman junior Thomas Harris Esquires William Bowen Thomas Llewellin Gent.</para>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s122">
<head>III. Commissioners to meet in the several Counties, &amp;c. on or before 15th January next, to execute this Act; and may subdivide themselves.</head>
<para id="p186">And be it further Enacted and Declared That the severall Com[m]issioners aforesaid shall meete together at the
most usuall and common Place of Meeting within each of the said Countyes Rideings Cityes Burroughes Townes
and Places respectively on or before the Fifteenth Day of January next ensueing And the said Commissioners or
soe many of them as shall be present at the said first Generall Meeting or the major part of them are hereby
Authorized and Required to putt this present Act in Execution according to the best of their Judgements and
Discretions And shall then if they see cause subdivide and distribute themselves soe into lesser numbers as two
or more of the said Commissioners may be Appointed for the Service of each Hundred or other Division and as
may best conduce to the Carrying on of Their Majestyes Service hereby required</para>
</section>
<section id="s123">
<head>IV. Commissioners at their Meeting to set down in Writing what Number of Commissioners shall act in each Division, and deliver Copy thereof to Receiver General.</head>
<para id="p187">And for the more Effectuall Performance thereof Bee it Enacted and Declared That the Commissioners at
their aforesaid first Generall Meeting or the major part of them shall Agree and Sett downe in Writeing who
and what number of the said Com[m]issioners shall act in each of the said Divisions or Hundreds and shall deliver
a true Copy of such Writeing to the Receiver Generall to be appointed by Their Majestyes to the end that
there be noe Failure in any part of the due Execution of the Service by this Act required</para>
</section>
<section id="s124">
<head>V. Receiver General to give Commissioners a Receipt for Monies received by him from them.</head>
<para id="p188"><emph type="i">Such Receipt to be a Discharge to Hundred, &amp;c. Commissioners, in their several Divisions, to cause the Proportions charged to be equally assessed; and to appoint Assessors; Duty of such Assessors</emph>.</para>
<para id="p189">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That every Receiver Generall from time to time within
the Space of One Month next after he shall have received the full Summe that shall be Charged on any
Hundred or Division for each particular Payment that is to be made to such Receiver Generall by Vertue of
this Act shall give to the Commissioners that shall act in such Hundred or Division a Receipt under his
Hand and Seale Acknowleding his Receipt of the full Summe Charged upon such Hundred or Division for
such particular Payment which Receipt shall be a full Discharge of such Hundred or Division for such particular
Payment against Their Majestyes Their Heires and Successors And the Commissioners within the severall Divisions
or Hundreds or any Two or more of them are hereby Authorized and Required to cause the said severall
Proportions Charged on the Respective Divisions and on every Parish and Place therein for the said Twelve Months
Assessment to be Equally Assessed and Taxed and to appoint Two or more Assessors in each Parish or Place
for the perfecting thereof who are hereby Required with all Care and Diligence to Assesse the same equally by
a Pound Rate upon all Lands Tenements Hereditaments Annuities Rent Charges and other Rents Parks Warrens
Goods Chattells Stock Merchandizes Offices (other then Military Offices and Offices relateing to the Navy under
the Command of the Commissioners of the Admiralty and Officers within Their Majestyes Household) Tolls Profitts
and all other Estates both Reall and Personall within the Limitts Circuits and Bounds of their respective Parishes
and Places</para>
</section>
<section id="s125">
<head>VI. &pound; 412,925. 14s. 6d. to be paid to Receiver General 25th March 1691.</head>
<para id="p190"><emph type="i">&pound; 412,925. 14s. 6d. Second Payment, 24th June 1691; &pound; 412,925. 14s. 6d. Third Quarterly Payment, 29th Sept. 1691; &pound; 412,925. 14s. 6d. Fourth and last Quarterly Payment, 25th Dec. 1691; Assessors to deliver Copy of Assessment to Commissioners, and Commissioners to sign and seal Two Duplicates thereof, and to deliver One thereof to Collector, which they are to nominate, with a Warrant for the Collection; Commissioners to deliver a Schedule of Sums assessed to Receiver General; Receiver General to transmit the same to the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
<para id="p191">And bee it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Summe of Foure hundred twelve thousand
nine hundred twenty five pounds fourteene shillings and six pence shall be Assessed Collected Levyed and Paid
unto the Receiver Generall of the said severall Countyes who shall be appointed by Their Majestyes on or before
the Five and twentyeth day of March in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety one And the
Summe of Foure hundred twelve thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fourteene shillings and sixpence
being the Second of the said Quarterly Payments on or before the Foure and twentyeth day of June in the said
Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety one And the Summe of Foure hundred twelve thousand nine
hundred twenty five pounds fourteene shillings and sixpence being the Third of the said Foure Quarterly Payments
on or before the Nine and twentyeth day of September in the (<ref idref="n121">121</ref>) Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety
one And the Summe of Foure hundred twelve thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fourteene shillings and
sixpence being the fourth and last of the said Foure Quarterly Payments on or before the five and twentyeth day
of December in the [said<ref idref="n122">122</ref>] Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety one And for the compleating
of the whole Summe Charged as aforesaid and to the end the aforesaid Summes Charged upon the severall and
respective Countyes Rideings Cityes Burroughs Townes and Places may be Equally and Indifferently Assessed
according to the true Intent of this Act and the Money duely Collected and true Account thereof made the said
Assessors are hereby Required to deliver One Copy of their respective Assessments fairely Written and Subscribed
by them unto the said Commissioners And the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them are hereby
Ordered and Required to Signe and Seale Two Duplicates of the said Assessments and the one of them to deliver
or cause to be delivered to one or more Honest and Responsable Person or Persons to be Collector or Collectors
which the said Commissioners are hereby Authorized to Nominate and Appoint for each Parish or Place with
Warrant to the said Collector or Collectors to Collect the said Assessment payable as aforesaid soe as the said
severall Sums may be Paid in to the said Receivers Generall at the respective times aforesaid And the said
Commissioners are hereby Required to deliver or cause to be delivered a Schedule or Note containing the particular
Sums Assessed upon each Parish or Place to the Receiver Generall of each County Rideing City Burrough
Towne or Place respectively to be by him the said Receiver Generall Transmitted into the Kings Remembrancers
Office in the Exchequer which the said Receiver Generall is Required to performe accordingly</para>
</section>
<section id="s126">
<head>VII. Money received by Collectors, paid to Receiver General or his Deputy.</head>
<para id="p192"><emph type="i">Notice by Receiver General to Commissioners of such Payment; Receipt of Receiver General Discharge to Collector; Collectors to pay to Receiver General, &amp;c. Collectors travelling for such Payments; Receiver General to transmit Monies to Exchequer; Salary to Receiver General, &amp;c; Regulations as to Duplicate of Assessment</emph>.</para>
<para id="p193">And bee it further Enacted and Declared by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Money received by the said
Collectors within the respective Divisions or Hundreds shall from time to time be duely Paid to the Receiver
Generall or to his Deputie or Deputies to be appointed under his Hand and Seale whereof Notice under the
Hand and Seale of the Receiver Generall shall be given unto the Commissioners or any Two of them within
the respective Divisions or Hundreds within Ten dayes after the first Generall Meeting and soe from time to
time within Ten dayes after every Death or Removeall of any Deputy (if any such shall happen) and the Receipt
of such Receiver Generall his Deputie or Deputies or any of them shall be a sufficient Discharge unto every
such Collector And the particular Collectors are hereby Required to Pay in all and every the Sums soe Received
by them unto the said Receivers Generall or their Deputie or Deputies for Payment whereof the said Collectors
shall not be obliged to Travell above Ten miles from the places of their Habitations which said Receivers Generall
are hereby Required forthwith to Transmitt or cause to be Paid the Moneys by them Received into the Receipt
of Their Majestyes Exchequer And the Lords Commissioners of Their Majestyes Treasury are hereby Authorized
to allow the said Receiver Generall of each County Rideing City and Towne respectively in case he hath returned
up as aforesaid a Duplicate of the Assessment of each Parish or Place in the County Rideing City or Towne
for which he is appointed Receiver Generall a Salary for his Pains not exceeding Two pence in the Pound upon
the Clearing of his Accompt which Duplicate soe to be returned into the Kings Remembrancers Office in the
Exchequer is intended to containe noe more then the Sums in Grosse to be collected by each Collector and the
severall Names of the said Collectors</para>
</section>
<section id="s127">
<head>VIII. Allowance to Collectors.</head>
<para id="p194"><emph type="i">Collectors may detain Allowance; Allowance to Commissioners Clerks paid by Receiver General</emph>.</para>
<para id="p195">And it is hereby further Enacted and Declared That the Collectors of each Parish or Place which shall be
appointed by vertue of this Act shall upon Collection of the whole Summe appointed to be collected by them
and Payment thereof as is hereby before appointed have and receive for their Paines in Collecting and Paying the
Moneys Three pence in the Pound which the said Collectors are impowered to detaine out of the last Payment
of the Money of their severall and respective Foure Quarterly Payments And the said Reciever Generall upon the
Reciept of the whole Assessments of the County Rideing City or Towne for which he is appointed Reciever
Generall in case he hath recieved the severall Duplicates of each Parish or Place therein and not otherwise shall
Allow and Pay according to such Warrant as shall be in that behalfe given by the said Commissioners or any of
them One halfe peny in the Pound for the Commissioners Clerks for their paines in fair writeing the Assessments
Duplicates and Copies</para>
</section>
<section id="s128">
<head>IX. Persons charged refusing, &amp;c. to pay.</head>
<para id="p196"><emph type="i">Distress; Collectors breaking open Doors, Chest, &amp;c. to call in Constables, &amp;c. who are to aid Collectors; Question upon Distress determined by Commissioners; Persons conveying away Goods, &amp;c; Commissioners may imprison; Except Peers; Tenants may pay Rate and deduct; Landlords to allow Deduction</emph>.</para>
<para id="p197">And bee it further Enacted and Declared That if any Person shall Refuse or Neglect to Pay any Summe of
Money whereat he shall be Rated and Assessed That then it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Collectors
or any of them and they are hereby Authorized and Required to Levy the Summe Assessed by Distresse and
Sale of the Goods of such Person soe Refuseing or Neglecting to Pay and reasonable Charges of Distraining and
Restoreing the Overplus (if any be) to the Owner thereof and to Breake open in the Day time any House and
upon Warrant under the Hands and Seals of Two or more of the said Commissioners any Chest Trunke Box or
other things where any such Goods are and to call to their assistance the Constables Tythingmen and Headburroughs
within the Countyes Rideings Cityes Townes and Places where any Refusall Neglect or Resistance shall be made
which said Officers are hereby required to be Aiding and Assisting in the p[re]misses as they will Answere the contrary
at their Perills And if any Question or Difference happen upon takeing such Distresses the same shall be Ended
and Determined by the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them And if any Person or Persons shall
Neglect or Refuse to Pay his or their Assessment or convey his or their Goods or other Personall Estate whereby
the Summes of Money soe Assessed cannot be Levyed according to this Act then the respective Commissioners or
any Two or more of them are hereby Authorized to Imprison the Person (Except a Peere or Peeres of this
Realme) and him and them in Prison to detaine and keepe untill the Moneys soe Assessed and the Charges for
the bringing in the same be Paid and Satisfied and noe longer And the severall and respective Tennant or Tennants
of all Houses and Lands which shall be Rated by vertue of this Act are hereby Required and Authorized to
Pay such Summe or Sumes or Money as shall be Rated upon such Houses or Lands and to Deduct out of
the Rent soe much of the said Rates as in respect of the said Rents of every such House and Lands the
Landlord should or ought to pay and beare And the said Landlords both mediate and immediate according to
their respective Interests are hereby required to allow such Deductions and Payments upon the Receipt of the
Residue of their Rents</para>
</section>
<section id="s129">
<head>X. Tenant paying acquitted to amount of Payment.</head>
<para id="p198"><emph type="i">If Difference between Landlord and Tenant as to Rate, Commissioners may settle the same; If Over Rate, Appeal to Commissioners; In case Proportions of Rate are not fully assessed, or assessed upon Persons not of Ability; or upon empty House; or if Assessments not paid to Receiver General; Commissioners, Assessors, &amp;c. are to reassess Such new Assessment to be made, &amp;c. as the former Assessment</emph>.</para>
<para id="p199">And it is enacted and declared That every Tennant Paying the said Assesments shall be Acquitted and Discharged
for soe much Money as the said Assesments shall amount unto as if the same had beene actually Paid unto such
Person and Persons unto whome his Rents should have beene Due and Payable And if any Differences shall arrise
betweene Landlord and Tennant or any other concerning the said Rates the said severall Commissioners or any
Two or more of them in their severall Divisions shall and have hereby Power to Setle the same as they shall
thinke fitt And if any Person or Persons shall finde him or themselves Agrieved in that the Assessors have
overrated him or them and shall in Six dayes after Demand made of the Summe of Money Assessed on him or
them Complaine to Two or more of the Commissioners (whereof one of the Commissioners who Signed or
Allowed his or their Assessments to be one) the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them shall have
and have hereby Power within Twelve dayes after the Demand of the Assessment as aforesaid to Relieve such
Person or Persons and to Charge the same on such other Person and Persons as they shall see cause And in case
the Proportions Sett by this Act upon all and every the respective Countyes Rideings Cities Townes and Places
shall not be fully Assessed Levyed and Paid according to the true meaning hereof or if any of the said Assessments
shall be Rated and Imposed upon any Person not being of Ability to Pay the same or upon any Empty or Void
House or Land where the same cannot be Collected or Levyed or that through any Wilfulness Negligence Mistake
or Accident the the said Assessment Charged on each Countie Rideing City Towne or Place by Vertue of this
Act happen not be Paid to the Reciever Generall his Deputy or Deputies of the respective Counties as in this
Act is directed That then in all and every such Cases the severall and respective Commissioners Assessors and
Collectors aforesaid and every of them respectively are hereby Authorized and Required to Assesse or Reassesse
or cause to be Assessed or Reassessed Levyed and Paid all and every such Summe and Summs of Money upon the
respective Counties Rideings Cityes Townes and Places or upon any the Divisions Hundreds and Parishes therein
as to the said Commissioners or such Number of them as by this Act are Authorized to cause the First
Assessment hereby required to be made shall seeme most agreeable to Equity and Justice The said New
Assessment to be Made Collected and Paid in such manner and by such meanes as in this Act for this
Assessment is Declared and Directed</para>
</section>
<section id="s130">
<head>XI. Persons not executing Act. Commissioners may fine not exceeding &pound;20, levied by Distress, paid to Receiver General, and by him into Exchequer.</head>
<para id="p200">And bee it further Enacted and Declared by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any Person or Persons shall
wilfully Neglect or Refuse to Performe his or their Duty in the due and speedy Execution of this present Act the
said respective Commissioners or any Three or more of them have hereby Power to Impose on such Person or Persons
soe refuseing or neglecting their Duties such Fine or Fines as by them shall be thought fitt and to cause the same to
be Levyed by Distresse and Sale of his and their Goods Provided That noe Fine to be Imposed by any of the
said Commissioners shall for any one Offence exceede the summe of Twenty pounds And that all Fines that
shall be Imposed by Vertue of this Act shall be paid to the respective Recievers Generall and by them to the Receipt
of their Majestyes Exchequer</para>
</section>
<section id="s131">
<head>XII. Collector neglecting to pay or detaining Monies.</head>
<para id="p201"><emph type="i">Proceedings by Commissioners; Commissioners so proceeding to appoint a General Meeting of Commissioners; Notice thereof; Collector not paying, Proceedings by Commissioners or such General Meeting</emph>.</para>
<para id="p202">And it is further Enacted and Declared That if any Collector that shall be by Vertue of this Act appointed
for the Receipt of any Sume or Sumes of Money thereby to be Assessed neglect or refuse to pay any Summe
or Sumes of Money which shall by him be recieved as aforesaid and to pay the same as in this Act is directed
and shall detaine in his or their hands any Money recieved by them or any of them and not pay the same as
by this Act is directed the Commissioners of each County Rideing City or Towne respectively or any Two or
more of them in their respective Divisions are hereby Authorized and Impowered to Imprison the Person and
Seize and Secure the Estate both Reall and Personall of such Collector to him belonging or which shall descend or
come into the hands or possession of his Heires Executors or Administrators wherever the same can be discovered
and found and the said Commissioners who shall soe Seize and Secure the Estate of any Collector or Collectors
shall be and are hereby impowered to appoint a time for the Generall Meeting of the Commissioners for such
County Rideing City Towne and Place and there to cause publique Notice to be given at the Place where such Meeting
shall be appointed Ten dayes at least before such Generall Meeting and the Commissioners present at such
Generall Meeting or the major part of them in case the Moneys detained by any Collector or Collectors be not
Paid and Satisfied as it ought to be according to the Directions of this Act shall and are hereby Impowered and
Required to Sell and Dispose of all such Estates which shall be for the Cause aforesaid Seized and Secured or
any part of them and Satisfie and Pay such County Rideing and Place the Summe that shall be detained in the
hands of such Collector or Collectors their Heires Executors and Administrators respectively</para>
</section>
<section id="s132">
<head>XIII. At Expiration of Times for Quarterly Payments, Commissioners are to call Collectors before them, &amp;c. and, in case of Failure, Commissioners to cause same to be levied and paid.</head>
<para id="p203">And it is hereby further Enacted and Declared That at the Expiration of the respective Times in this Act
prescribed for the full Payment of the [said<ref idref="n123">123</ref>] Foure Quarterly Assessments the severall and respective Commissioners
or any two of them within their Division and Hundred shall and are hereby Required to call before them the
Collectors within each respective Division and Hundred to Examine and assure themselves of the full and whole
Payment of the particular Summe and Summes of Money Charged upon the same Division or Hundred and every
Parish and Place therein and of the due Returne of the same into the Hands of the Recievers Generall their
Deputy or Deputyes of the said County Rideing City Towne and Place respectively and by such Receiver Generall
into the Receipt of Their Majesties Exchequer to the end there may be noe failure in the Payment of any part of
the Assessments by vertue of this Act to be Assessed and Paid nor any Arrears remaine Chargeable upon any
the said Counties Rideings Cityes Towns or Places respectively And in case of any failure in the Premisses the
said Commissioners or any two of them are hereby to cause the same to be forthwith Levyed and Paid according
to the true intent and meaning of this Act</para>
</section>
<section id="s133">
<head>XIV. Questions respecting Assessments, &amp;c. in which Commissioners concerned, they have no Voice.</head>
<para id="p204">And it is hereby Enacted and Declared That in case any Controversie arise concerning the said Assessments
or the Dividing Apportioning or Payment thereof which concerns any the Commissioners by this Act appointed
that the Commissioners soe concerned in the said Controversie shall have noe Voice but shall withdraw at the
time of the Debate of any such Controversie untill it be determined by the rest of the Commissioners</para>
</section>
<section id="s134">
<head>XV. Privileged Places or, Persons, &amp;c. not exempt from Assessment.</head>
<para id="p205"><emph type="i">Fee Farm and other Rents, Annuities, &amp;c. liable; Tenants to pay proportionably, indemnified</emph>.</para>
<para id="p206">And bee it further Enacted and Declared That noe Priviledged Place or Person Body Politicke or Corporate
within the Counties Rideings Cities and Townes aforesaid shall be exempted from the said Assessments and Taxes
And that they and every of them and alsoe all Fee-Farme Rents and all other manner of Rents Payments Summe
and Summes of Money or Annuities issueing out of any Lands shall be lyable towards the Payment of every
Summe by this Act to be Taxed and Levyed And all the Tennants are hereby Directed and Authorized to pay
them proportionably according to the Rates and Assessments by this Act Appointed and Directed And all such
Tennants shall be hereby saved and kept harmlesse by Authoritie of this Act from any further Payment of any
such Portion of any such Rent Rents Summs or Annuities to any Person or Persons to whome any such Rent
Rents Sums of Money or Annuities as aforesaid should or ought to be Paid to all Intents and Purposes
whatsoever as fully and amply as if they had Paid the same to any Person or Persons to whome the same is or
are reserved or become due</para>
</section>
<section id="s135">
<head>XVI. Proviso for the Colleges in the Two Universities, in the Colleges of Windsor, Eton, Winchester, and Westminster and for Hospitals, in respect of Sites of the Colleges, &amp;c;</head>
<para id="p207"><emph type="i">Houses held by Lease from Hospitals to be rated at their yearly Value</emph>.</para>
<para id="p208">Provided That nothing contained in this Act be extended to Charge any Colledge or Hall in either of the
two Universities or the Colledges of Windsor Eaton Winton or Westminster or any Hospitall for or in respect
of the Scites of the said Colledges Halls or Hospitalls or any Master Fellow or Scholler of any such Colledge or
Hall or in any Free Schooles or any Reader Officer or Minister of the said Universities Colledges or Schools
or of any Hospitalls or Almshouses for or in respect of any Stipend Wages or Profits whatsoever ariseing or
growing due to them in respect of the said severall Places and Imployments in the said Universities Colledges
Schools Hospitalls or Almshouses nor to Charge any of the Houses or Lands belonging to Christs Hospitall St
Bartholomews Bridewell St Thomas and Bethlem Hospitall in the City of London and Burrough of Southwarke
or any of them for or in respect of any Rents or Revenues payable to the said Hospitalls being to be Recieved
and Disbursed for the immediate Use and Reliefe of the Poore in the said Hospitalls Provided That noe Tennants
that Hold and enjoy any Lands or Houses by Lease or other Grant from any of the said Hospitalls doe Claime
and Enjoy any Freedome Exemption or Advantage by this Act but that all the Houses and Lands which they soe
Hold shall be Rated and Assessed for soe much as they are yearely worth over and above the Rents reserved and
payable to the said Hospitalls</para>
</section>
<section id="s136">
<head>XVII. Person having a House in one Parish, &amp;c. and Goods in another, to be charged for such Goods, &amp;c. where he dwells.</head>
<para id="p209">Provided That where any Person inhabiting within the City of London hath his Dwelling House in one of
the Parishes or Wards therein and hath any Goods Wares or Merchandizes in one or more of the other Parishes
or Wards within the same That then such Person shall be Charged Taxed and Assessed for such his Goods or
Merchandices in the Parish or Ward where he dwelleth and not elsewhere within the said City</para>
</section>
<section id="s137">
<head>XVIII. No Clause in this Act to extend to lessen the Rate.</head>
<para id="p210">Provided neverthelesse That noe Clause or Provisoe in this Act shall extend to the lessening or abatement of
the full Summe appointed by this Act to be Taxed Levyed Collected and Paid but that the same be fully
Assessed Taxed Levyed Collected and Paid in the severall and respective Counties Cities and Townes aforesaid in
such manner and forme and to such uses as herein is before mentioned and declared</para>
</section>
<section id="s138">
<head>XIX. Proceedings in case the assessing by Pound Rate shall be found to obstruct the speedy bringing in of the Assessment.</head>
<para id="p211">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby Enacted and Declared That in case the way or manner of Assessing by
a Pound Rate shall prove any wayes prejudiciall or obstructing to the speedy bringing in of the Assessment or
any part thereof appointed by this Act That then and in all such Cases the respective Commissioners or any
Two of them are hereby Authorized to Order and Direct their respective Assessors who are hereby Required to
Proceede accordingly to Assesse the respective Summes Charged on the respective Counties Rideings Cities
Burroughs Townes and Places mentioned in this Act according to the most just and usuall Rates held and
practiced in such Counties Rideings Cities Burroughs Towns and Places respectively Any thing in this Act to
the contrary thereof contained in any wise notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s139">
<head>XX. Proviso for Contract between Landlords and Tenants as to Payment of Taxes.</head>
<para id="p212">Provided alwayes That nothing in this Act contained shall be construed to Alter Change Determine or make
Void any Contracts Covenants or Agreements whatsoever betweene Landlord and Tennant or any other Persons
touching the Payment of Taxes and Assessments Any thing herein before mentioned to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s140">
<head>XXI. Places used to be assessed to pay as heretofore.</head>
<para id="p213">Provided alwayes and bee it further Enacted and Declared by the Authority aforesaid That for the avoiding of
all Obstructions and Delayes in Collecting the Sums by this Act to be Rated and Assessed all Places Constablewicks
Divisions and Allotments which have used to be Rated and Assessed shall Pay and be Assessed in such County
Hundred Rape and Wapentake as the same have heretofore beene usually Assessed in and not elsewhere</para>
</section>
<section id="s141">
<head>XXII. Action brought touching Execution of this Act.</head>
<para id="p214"><emph type="i">General Issue; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
<para id="p215">And bee it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Action Plaint Suite or Information shall be
Commenced or Prosecuted against any Person or Persons for what he or they shall doe in Pursuance or in
Execution of this Act such Person or Persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall and may Pleade the
Generall Issue (Not Guilty) and upon any Issue joyned may give this Act and the speciall matter in Evidence
And if the Plaintiffe or Prosecutor shall become Nonsuite or forbeare further Prosecution or suffer a Discontinuance
or if a Verdict passe against him the Defendants shall Recover their Treble Costs for which they shall have the
like Remedy as in any Case where Costs by the Law are given to Defendants</para>
</section>
<section id="s142">
<head>XXIII. Receivers General and their Deputies to give Acquittances to Collectors.</head>
<para id="p216"><emph type="i">The-like Provision; Such Acquittance to be a Discharge</emph>.</para>
<para id="p217">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the severall Recievers Generall which
shall be appointed according to this Act their Deputy or Deputyes shall from time to time at every Payment
appointed thereby give unto the severall Collectors within their respective. Precincts upon the Payment of the
whole Summe due at such times of payment from their respective Parishes Constablewicks or Places within each
of their Collections severall Acquittances under their Hands without takeing any thing for the same And that
in like manner at every time of Payment appointed by this Act the Receiver Generall of each County his Deputy
or Deputies shall give unto the severall Collectors aforesaid upon the payment of the whole Summe or any part
thereof due for their Parish or Place respectively at each time of payment aforesaid severall Acquittances under
their Hands and Seals without takeing any thing for the same Which said Acquittance of the Reciever Generall
his Deputy or Deputies shall be a full and perfect Discharge to the Collectors and to such Parish or Place
respectively and to every Person Charged within the said Collectors charge against Their Majesties their Heires
and Successors for the Summe or Summes of Money soe acquitted</para>
</section>
<section id="s143">
<head>XXIV. Where Lands, &amp;c. unoccupied, and no Distress found, Collectors, Constables, &amp;c, may enter and distrain.</head>
<para id="p218"><emph type="i">Proceedings thereon</emph>.</para>
<para id="p219">Provided alwayes and bee it further Enacted That in case any Lands or Houses in any Parish Place or
Constablewick shall be unoccupied and noe Distresse can be found on the same by reason whereof the said
Parish Place and Constablewick are forced to pay and make good the Taxe Assessed upon such Land lying
unoccupied That then it shall and may be lawfull at any time after for the Collectors Constable or Tythingmen
of the said Parish Place or Constablewicke for the time being to Enter and Distraine upon the said Lands or
Houses when there shall be any Distresse thereupon to be found and the Distresse and Distresses being the
proper Goods of the Owner or any Claimeing any Estate Interest or Profitt under him if not Redeemed within
Foure dayes by Payment of the Tax and Charge of the Distresse to Sell rendering the Overplus to the Owner
or Owners of such Distresse And the said Collector Constable or Tythingman is hereby Enjoyned to Distribute
the Money Raised by the said Distresse or Sale thereof proportionably to the Partie who Contributed to the Tax
of the said unoccupied Lands</para>
</section>
<section id="s144">
<head>XXV. Where Wood Lands assessed, and no Distress had, Collectors, &amp;c. may enter, and cut Wood, &amp;c. growing. Buyers of such Wood may sell the same, rendering Overplus to Owner.</head>
<para id="p220">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That where any Woodlands shall be Assessed and noe Distresse can
be had that in such Case it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Collector Constable Headburrough or
Tythingman by Warrant under the Hands and Seals of two or more of the Commissioners of that Hundred or
Division at seasonable times of the Yeare to Cutt and Sell to any Person or Persons soe much of the Wood growing
on the Woodlands soe Assessed as will pay the Assessment or Assessments soe behinde and unpaid and the Charge
incident thereunto And that it shall and may be lawfull for the Person and Persons and his and their Assignes
to whome such Wood shall be Sold to Sell Cutt downe Dispose and Carry away the same to his owne use
rendring the Overplus (if any be) to the Owner Any Law to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s145">
<head>XXVI. Proceedings where Assessment charged on Property not distrainable.</head>
<para id="p221">Provided alwayes and bee it further Enacted That where any Taxe or Assessment shall be Charged or Laid
upon any Tythes Tolls Profitts of Markets Fairs or Fishery or other Annuall Profitts not Distrainable in case
the same shall not be Paid within Fifteene Dayes after such Assessment soe Charged or Laid and Demanded
Then it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Collector Constable or other Officer thereunto appointed by
Warrant under the Hands and Seals of any two or more of the Commissioners Authorized by this Act to Seize
Take and Sell soe much of the said Tythes Tolls and other Profitts soe Charged as shall be sufficient for the
Levying the said Tax and Assessment and all Charges occasioned by such Nonpayment thereof rendring the
Overplus to the Owner (if any be)</para>
</section>
<section id="s146">
<head>XXVII. Receivers General certifying Arrears due where Monies have been received;</head>
<para id="p222"><emph type="i">Penalty to Party; Penalty to Their Majesties.</emph></para>
<para id="p223">And for the better preventing of such unjust Vexations as might be occasioned by such Persons as shall be
appointed Receivers Generall of any the Summes of Money Granted by this Act and to the intent that the
said Receivers Generall may returne a true Account into Their Majestyes Court of Exchequer of such Sums of
Money as shall be Recieved by them and every of them their and every of their Deputie and Deputies Bee it
further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any Receiver Generall shall Returne or Certifie into the said
Court any Summe or Summs of Money to be in Arreare [and<ref idref="n124">124</ref>] unpaid after the same have beene Recieved
either by such Reciever Generall or by his Deputie or Deputies or any of them or shall cause any Person or
Persons to be Sett Insuper in the said Court for any Sum or Sums of Money that hath beene soe Recieved That
then every such Reciever Generall shall forfeit to every person and persons that shall be Molested Vexed or
Dammaged by reason of such unjust Certificate Returne or Setting Insuper the Damages that shall be thereby
occasioned the said Damages to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in which noe
Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed nor any more then one Imparlance and shall alsoe forfeit
to Their Majestyes Their Heires and Successors the Summe that shall be soe unjustly Certified or Returned or
caused to be Sett Insuper</para>
</section>
<section id="s147">
<head>XXVIII. Quarterly Payments to be made to Receivers General, and by them into the Exchequer within 20 Days after the Times before mentioned.</head>
<para id="p224">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That the said Foure Quarterly Payments of One
hundred thirty seven thousand six hundred forty one pounds eighteene shillings and two pence per Mensem
amounting in each Quarter of the Foure Quarters to the Summe of Foure hundred twelve thousand nine
hundred twenty five pounds fourteene shillings six pence shall be Assessed Collected Levyed and Paid to the
Reciever Generall of the severall Counties that shall be appointed by the Times mentioned and expressed in
this Act and shall be paid by the said Recievers Generall into Their Majestyes Receipt of the Exchequer
within Twenty dayes after the said Times mentioned and expressed in this Act</para>
</section>
<section id="s148">
<head>XXIX. Commissioners not liable to Penalties of 25 Car. II. c. 2.</head>
<para id="p225">And bee it further Enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Commissioner or Commissioners who shall be
imployed in the Execution of this Act shall be lyable for or by reason of such Execution to any of the
Penalties mentioned in an Act made in the Five and twentieth Yeare of King Charles the Second Intituled An
Act for Preventing Dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants</para>
</section>
<section id="s149">
<head>XXX. Commissioners to take the Oaths of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 8. which the Commissioners may administer.</head>
<para id="p226">Provided alwayes and bee it Enacted That noe Person shall be capeable of acting as a Commissioner in the
Execution of this Act before he shall take the Oaths appointed by an Act of the last Parliament Entituled An Act
for the Abrogating of the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance and appointing other Oaths Which Oaths it shall
be lawfull for any Two or more Commissioners to Administer And they are hereby Required and Authorized to
Administer the same to any other Commissioner</para>
</section>
<section id="s150">
<head>XXXI. Persons may lend Money to Their Majesties on this Act at &pound;7 per Cent. per Ann.</head>
<para id="p227">Provided alwayes and it is hereby Enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Person and
Persons to Advance and Lend unto Their Majestyes upon the Security of this Act any Summe or Summes of
Money and to have and recieve for the forbearance thereof after the rate of Seven pounds by the Hundred for
One whole Yeare and noe more directly or indirectly</para>
</section>
<section id="s151">
<head>XXXII. Repayment of such Monies how secured. Books provided.</head>
<para id="p228"><emph type="i">Tally of Loan to Lender, and Warrant for Interest; Orders for Repayment registered according to Date of Tally, and paid in course; Monies to come in by this Act liable to satisfy such Loans; No Fee for providing or making Books, &amp;c. or for Payment of Money lent; Penalty; Punishment; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty; Undue Preference by Deputy; Penalty; Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller, not making Payments in due Order; Penalty; How all such Penalties to be recovered</emph>.</para>
<para id="p229">And to the end that all Moneys which shall be Lent unto Their Majesties upon the Credit of this Act may
be well and sufficiently Secured out of the Moneys ariseing and payable by this Act Bee it further Enacted by
the Authoritie aforesaid That there shall be provided and kept in Their Majestyes Exchequer (that is to say)
in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipts one Booke or Register in which all Moneys that shall be paid
into the Exchequer by Vertue of this Act shall be Entered and Registred apart and distinct from all other
Moneys paid or payable to Their Majesties upon any other Branch of Their Majestyes Revenue or upon any
other Account whatsoever And that all and every Person and Persons who shall Lend any Money to Their
Majestyes upon the Credit of this Act and pay the same into the Receipt of the Exchequer shall immediately
have a Tally of Loane strucke for the same and an Order for his Repayment bearing the same Date with his
Tally In which Order shall be alsoe contained a Warrant for payment of Interest for Forbearance after the
Rate of Seven pounds per Cent&umacr; per Ann&umacr; for his Consideration to be paid every Three Months untill Repayment
of his Principall And that all Orders for Repayment of Money shall be Registred in course according to the
Date of the Tally respectively without preference of one before another And that all and every Person and
Persons shall be paid in course according as their Orders shall stand Entered in the said Register Booke soe as
that the Person Native or Forreigner his Executors Administrators and Assignes who shall have his Order or Orders
first Entered in the said Booke of Register shall be taken and accounted as the first Person to be paid upon the
Moneys to come in by Vertue of this Act And he or they who shall have his or their Order or Orders next
Entered shall be taken and accounted to be the second Person to be paid and soe successively and in course And
that the Moneys to come in by this Act shall be in the same Order lyable to the satisfaction of the said respective
Parties their Executors Administrators or Assigns successively without preference of one before another and not
otherwise and not to be divertible to any other Use Intent or Purpose whatsoever And that noe Fee Reward or
Gratuity directly or indirectly be demanded or taken of any [of<ref idref="n125">125</ref>] Their Majestyes Subjects for provideing or makeing
of any such Bookes Registers Entryes View or Search in or for Payment of Money Lent or the Interest as aforesaid
by any of Their Majesties Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputies on Paine of Payment of Treble Damages
to the Partie grieved by the Party offending with Costs of Suite or if the Officer himselfe take or demand any
such Fee or Reward then to lose his Place alsoe And if any undue Preference of one before another shall be
made either in point of Registry or Payment contrary to the true meaning of this Act by any such Officer or
Officers then the Partie offending shall be lyable by Action of Debt or on the Case to pay the Value of the
Debt Damages and Costs to the Partie grieved and shall be forejudged from his Place or Office And if such
Preference be unduely made by any his Deputie or Clerke without direction or Privity of his Master then such
Deputie or Clerke onely shall be lyable to such Action Debt Damages and Costs and shall be for ever after
uncapeable of his Place or Office. And in case the Auditor shall not direct the Order or the Clerke of the Pells
Record or the Teller make Payment according to each Persons due place and order as afore directed then he or
they shall be judged to forfeit and their respective Deputies and Clerks herein offending to be lyable to such
Action Debt Damages and Costs in such manner as aforesaid All which said Penalties Forfeitures Damages and
Costs to be incurred by any of the Officers of the Exchequer or any their Deputies or Clerks shall and may
be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of Their Majestyes Courts of Record at
Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection Priviledge Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint shall be
in any wise granted or allowed</para>
</section>
<section id="s152">
<head>XXXIII. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date the same Day.</head>
<para id="p230"><emph type="i">Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded, no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Orders</emph>.</para>
<para id="p231">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby Declared That if it happen that severall Tallyes of Loane or Orders for
Payment as aforesaid beare Date or be brought the same Day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be Registred
then it shall be interpreted noe undue Preference which of those he Enters first soe he Enters them all the
same Day Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpreted any undue Preference to incurr any Penaltie in point
of Payment if the Auditor Direct and the Clerke of the Pells Record and the Tellers doe pay subsequent Orders
of Persons that come and demand their Money and bring their Order before other Persons that did not come to
demand their Money and bring their Order in their Course soe as there be soe much [Money<ref idref="n126">126</ref>] reserved as will
satisfie precedent Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them (Interest upon Loane being to
cease from the time the Money is soe reserved and kept in Banke for them.)</para>
</section>
<section id="s153">
<head>XXXIV. Orders for Payment of Money lent may be assigned by Indorsement.</head>
<para id="p232"><emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee; Assignee may in like manner assign</emph>.</para>
<para id="p233">And bee it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every person or persons to whome any Moneys
shall be due by vertue of this Act after Order Entred in the Booke of Register aforesaid for payment thereof
his Executors Administrators or Assignes by Indorsement of his Order may Assigne and Transfer his Right Title
Interest and Benefit of such Order or any part thereof to any other which being Notified in the Office of the
Auditor of Receipt aforesaid and an Entry or Memoriall thereof alsoe made in the Booke of Register aforesaid
for Orders (which the Officers shall upon Request without Fee or Charge accordingly make) shall Intitle such
Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the Benefit thereof and Payment thereon And such Assignee
may in like manner Assigne againe and soe toties quoties And afterwards it shall not be in the power of such
person or persons who have or hath made such Assignments to make Void Release or Discharge the same or
any the Moneys thereby due or any part thereof</para>
</section>
<section id="s154">
<head>XXXV. Out of the Monies raised by this Act &pound;1,000,000 applied to the Payment of Seamen and Stores.</head>
<para id="p234"><emph type="i">Office of Ordnance and other necessary Naval Services</emph>.</para>
<para id="p235">And to the intent that the Summe of Ten hundred thousand pounds part of the Moneys to be Raised by
vertue of this Act may be certainly applyed to the payment of Seamen and to the paying for Stores Provisions
and Victualls and for other necessary Uses and Services in and for Their Majesties Navy Royall Bee it Enacted
That out of the Money which shall be Levyed and Paid by vertue of this Act into the Receipt of the Exchequer
as well upon Loane as otherwise the Summe of Ten hundred thousand pounds shall be Applyed and Appropriated
and is hereby Appropriated to and for the payment of Seamen that have Served and shall Serve in Their Majestyes
Navy Royall and to and for the paying for Stores Provisions and Victualls supplyed and to be supplyed and to
and for the Expences of Their Majestyes Office of Ordnance in respect to Navall Affaires and for other necessary
Uses and Services performed and to be performed for the said Navy.</para>
</section>
<section id="s155">
<head>XXXVI.</head>
<para id="p236"><emph type="i">Collector keeping Money in hand, or paying to Person other than Receiver General; Penalty; Receiver General or Deputy paying Monies paid to him to Persons other than the Exchequer, or paying by
Warrant upon Tally of Pro or Tally of Anticipation, &amp;c. to divert Payment into the Exchequer. Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p237">And for the effectuall doeing thereof and that the said Summe of Ten hundred thousand pounds hereby
Appropriated to the Uses aforesaid may not be Diverted or Applyed to any other Purpose And alsoe to the
intent that all the Moneys Given by this Act may be duly paid into Their Majesties Exchequer Bee it further
Enacted That if any Collector of any Parish or Place shall keepe in his Hands any part of the Money by him
Collected for any longer time then is by this Act Directed (other then the Allowance made unto him by this
Act) or shall pay any part thereof to any person or persons other then the Receiver Generall of such County
or Place or his respective Deputie That every such Collector shall forfeit for every such Offence the Summe of
Five pounds And in case any Receiver Generall or his Deputy shall pay any part of the Moneys paid to him
or them by any Collector by vertue of this Act to any person or persons whatsoever (other then the Receipt of
Their Majestyes Exchequer) and that at or within the respective Times limitted by this Act or in case such Receiver
Generall or his Deputy shall pay any part of the said Moneys by any Warrant of the Commissioners of the
Treasury or the Lord Treasurer Under Treasurer or Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being or upon
any Tally of Pro or Tally of Anticipation or other Way or Device whatsoever whereby to divert or hinder the
actuall Payment thereof into the Receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid That then such Receiver Generall shall
for every such Offence of himselfe or his Deputie forfeit the Summe of Five hundred pounds to him or them
that shall Sue for the same in any Court of Record by Bill Plaint or Information wherein noe Essoigne Protection
or Wager of Law is to be allowed</para>
</section>
<section id="s156">
<head>XXXVII. Treasury not to direct Warrant to Collectors, &amp;c. for Payment to Persons other than into Exchequer, nor to Officers of Exchequer for striking of Tally of Pro, &amp;c.</head>
<para id="p238"><emph type="i">Officer not to strike, &amp;c. any such Tally, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p239">And it is hereby further Enacted That the Commissioners of the Treasury or the Lord Treasurer Under
Treasurer or Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being or any of them doe not direct any Warrant to
any of the said Collectors or Receivers Generall or their Deputies for the Payment of any part of the Moneys
hereby Given to any person or persons other then into the Receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid nor shall they
or any of them direct any Warrant to the Officers of the Exchequer for the Strikeing of any Tally of Pro or
Tally of Anticipation nor doe any other Matter or Thing whereby to divert the actuall Payments of the said
Moneys into the Receipt of the Exchequer Nor shall the Officers of the Exchequer Strike or Direct or Record
the Strikeing of any Tally of Pro or Tally of Anticipation upon any of the said Moneys upon any Account or
Warrant whatsoever Nor shall any Teller throw downe any Bill whereby to Charge himself with any of the
said Moneys untill he shall have actually recieved the same</para>
</section>
<section id="s157">
<head>XXXVIII. Officers of Exchequer to keep Accounts of the said &pound;1,000,000 distinct.</head>
<para id="p240"><emph type="i">Regulations as to issuing such Money to Treasurer of the Navy</emph>.</para>
<para id="p241">And bee it hereby further Enacted That the Officers of the Receipt of Their Majestyes Exchequer shall keepe
the said Summe of Ten hundred thousand pounds hereby Appropriated and the Account thereof distinct from all
other Moneys and Account whatsoever And that the Commissioners of the Treasury or the Lord Treasurer
Under Treasurer or [the<ref idref="n127">127</ref>] Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being doe not Signe any Warrant or Order
or doe any other Matter or Thing for the issueing any part of the said Summe of Ten hundred thousand pounds
hereby Appropriated as aforesaid to any person or persons other then the Treasurer of the Navy or his Deputy
for the time being and expressing therein that the same is for the Uses aforesaid, Nor shall the Auditor of the
Receipt draw any Order for the issueing any part of the said Summe of Ten hundred thousand pounds hereby
Appropriated to any person or persons other then the Treasurer of the Navy or his Deputie as aforesaid Nor
shall he Direct or the Clerke of the Pells Record or any Teller make Payment of any of the said Moneys by
vertue of any Warrant or upon any Order or other Way or Device whatsoever other then to the Persons and
for the Uses aforesaid and to be soe mentioned and expressed in such Warrant or Order</para>
</section>
<section id="s158">
<head>XXXIX. Regulations for Treasurer of the Navy as to keeping and issuing the said Sum of &pound;1,000,000.</head>
<para id="p242">And it is hereby further Enacted That the Treasurer of the Navy for the time being shall keepe the said
Sum[m]e of Ten hundred thousand pounds appropriated as aforesaid by Vertue of this Act as the same shall be
paid in to him distinct and apart from all other Moneys and shall Issue and Pay the same by Warrant of the
Principall Officers and Commissioners of the Navy or any Three or more of them and mentioning and expressing
that the same is for the respective Uses for which the same is appropriated as aforesaid and for noe other Use
Intent or Purpose whatsoever Which said Principall Officers and Commissioners of the Navy are to follow therein
the Order and Direction of the Commissioners of the Admiralty or the Lord High Admirall for the time being
for apportioning the same to the respective Uses aforementioned</para>
</section>
<section id="s159">
<head>XL. And for Commissioners &amp;c. of the Navy as to signing Navy Bills, &amp;c. for issuing such Money.</head>
<para id="p243">And it is hereby further Enacted That the Principall Officers and Commissioners of the Navy or any of them
shall not Signe any Warrant or Navy Bill or doe any other Act or Thing for the Issueing and Paying any part
of the said Summe of Ten hundred thousand pounds soe appropriated by this Act to any Use Intent or Purpose
whatsoever other then for the respective Uses for which the same is appropriated as aforesaid and to be soe
mentioned and expressed in such Warrant or Navy Bill</para>
</section>
<section id="s160">
<head>XLI. Officers appointed to receive said &pound;1,000,000, misapplying same;</head>
<para id="p244"><emph type="i">Penalty; How applied</emph>.</para>
<para id="p245">And it is further Enacted That if any of the Officers which are appointed by this Act to recieve the said
Summe of Ten hundred thousand pounds hereby appropriated or any part thereof shall after the Receipt of the
said Money divert or misapply the same or any part thereof by Vertue of any Warrant from the Com[m]issioners of
the Treasury or from the Lord Treasurer or other superiour Officers for the time being contrary to the true
intent of this Act That then such Officer or Officers soe diverting or misapplying the said Money shall forfeit the
like Summe soe diverted or misapplyed Which said Forfeiture shall be Recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint
or Information in any of Their Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster Wherein noe Essoigne Protection or
Wager of Law shall be allowed The one Moyety of which Forfeiture soe to be Recovered shall be to the
Informer or him who shall sue for the same The other Moyety thereof to be distributed to the Poore of the
Parish where such Offence shall be Committed.</para>
</section>
<section id="s161">
<head>XLII. Officers of Exchequer or Navy misapplying the same Monies.</head>
<para id="p246"><emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p247">And bee it further Enacted That if any Officer or Officers mentioned in this Act or in any wise belonging
to the Exchequer or Navy shall willingly and wilfully Offend against this Law or any Clause thereof by diverting
or misapplying any part of the said Summe of Ten hundred thousand pounds appropriated as aforesaid contrary
to the true Intent of the said Act That for any and every such Offence such Officer and Officers soe offending
shall forfeit his Office and Place and is and are hereby Disabled and made Uncapable to hold or execute the said
Office or any other Office whatsoever for the future.</para>
</section>
<section id="s162">
<head>XLIII. No Stay of Prosecution in Actions for Penalties.</head>
<para id="p248">Provided alsoe and bee it Enacted That noe stay of Prosecution upon any Command Warrant Motion or
Order or Direction by Non vult ulterius prosequi shall be had made admitted recieved or allowed by any Court
whatsoever in any Suite or Proceeding by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information or otherwise for the recovery
of all or any the Paines Penalties or Forfeitures upon any Person or Persons by this Act inflicted or therein
mentioned or for or in order to the Conviction or Disability of any person offending against this Act</para>
</section>
<section id="s163">
<head>XLIV. &pound;41,160 already taken up for Navy esteemed Part of said &pound;1,000,000.</head>
<para id="p249">Provided and it is hereby Declared and Enacted That the Summe of Forty one thousand one hundred and
sixty pounds already taken up for the Service of the Navy be taken and esteemed as part of the Summe hereby
Appropriated for the Use of the Navy.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">omitted in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">Soveraignes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n5" number="5">Robarts <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n6" number="6">Scawen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n7" number="7">Cope <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n8" number="8">Slade <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n9" number="9">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n11" number="11">Mickleton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n12" number="12">Rookes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n13" number="13">Fowlis <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n14" number="14">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n15" number="15">Reynolds <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n16" number="16">Chartisepher <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n17" number="17">Robert <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n18" number="18">John <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n19" number="19">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n20" number="20">Reynolds <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n21" number="21">Sprignell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n22" number="22">Barron <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n23" number="23">Merdiath <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n24" number="24">of Brockhampton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n25" number="25">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n26" number="26">Thomas Howorth Robert Payne James Lloyd of the Moore <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n27" number="27">interlined on the Roll and omitted in the Original Act.</note>
<note id="n28" number="28">Realme <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n29" number="29">Joicelin <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n30" number="30">Musters <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n31" number="31">Charles Amhurst Jeffery Amhurst <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n32" number="32">Millerd <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n33" number="33">William <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n34" number="34">Gifford <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n35" number="35">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n36" number="36">Denne <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n37" number="37">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n38" number="38">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n39" number="39">James <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n40" number="40">Bootle <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n41" number="41">Whittacre <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n42" number="42">Jeremy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n43" number="43">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n44" number="44">Bainbrigg <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n45" number="45">Watton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n46" number="46">Horblin <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n47" number="47">Nelhorp <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n48" number="48">James <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n49" number="49">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n50" number="50">Galston <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n51" number="51">Chiny <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n52" number="52">Fedding <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n53" number="53">Cowden <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n54" number="54"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
<note id="n55" number="55">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n56" number="56">Gentleman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n57" number="57">Scudmore <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n58" number="58">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n59" number="59">Harbord <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n60" number="60">Hoste <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n61" number="61">Mapes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n62" number="62">Dersley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n63" number="63">Samuell Fuller Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n64" number="64">Gilbert <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n65" number="65">Knight <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n66" number="66">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n67" number="67">Formedo <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n68" number="68">Gunner <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n69" number="69">Sunnybanke <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n70" number="70">Adeane and no blank <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n71" number="71">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n72" number="72">Charles <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n73" number="73">Owen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n74" number="74">Bayliffe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n75" number="75">Halswell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n76" number="76">Bober <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n77" number="77">Gorges <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n78" number="78">Strachy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n79" number="79">Turton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n80" number="80">Lawson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n81" number="81">Streakley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n82" number="82">Norley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n83" number="83">Wiltshire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n84" number="84">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n85" number="85">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n86" number="86">Marlsford <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n87" number="87">Fowls <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n88" number="88">Weld <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n89" number="89">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n90" number="90">Carter <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n91" number="91">Peyton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n92" number="92">Henry <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n93" number="93">Borrows <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n94" number="94">Junior <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n95" number="95">Cheald <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n96" number="96">Marrot <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n97" number="97">Colemon <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n98" number="98">Godsale <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n99" number="99">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n100" number="100">Nicholls <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n101" number="101">Swainson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n102" number="102">Seymore <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n103" number="103">Fiddletons <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n104" number="104">Phillips <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n105" number="105">Henning <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n106" number="106">Bayliffe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n107" number="107">Griffits <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n108" number="108"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
<note id="n109" number="109">Walter Parry David Lloyd <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n110" number="110">Jones <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n111" number="111">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n112" number="112">Robert <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n113" number="113">Condway <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n114" number="114">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n115" number="115">Marsmore <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n116" number="116">Cassall <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n117" number="117">Corbell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n118" number="118">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n119" number="119">Hartstongue <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n120" number="120">Herbert <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n121" number="121">sayd <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n122" number="122">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n123" number="123">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n124" number="124">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n125" number="125"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
<note id="n126" number="126">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n127" number="127"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


