<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46352" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1690</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An Act for preventing Vexatious Suites against such as acted for Their Majestyes Service in defence of the Kingdome. [Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 12.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that during the Invasion divers Subjects had apprehended suspected Persons, &#x0026;c.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">All Prosecutions, &#x0026;c. against such Subjects made void.; Defendant may plead the General Issue, and recover Double Costs</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS in this present yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and ninety about the time that
the Coasts of this Kingdome were invaded by the French the Lords and others of Their Majestyes most
Honourable Privy Councill diverse Lords Gentlemen and other good Subjects being Magistrates and Officers or
acting in pursuance of their Orders did for Their Majesties Service and the Safety of the Kingdome apprehend
and imprison severall suspected persons and did seize and use Horses and Arms and did cause the greatest part
of the Militia of this Kingdome to be raised continued and maintained otherwise than is authorized by the Acts
made in the Raigne of King Charles the Second in that behalfe and to march and to be quartered in diverse places
upon that occasion That those proceedings in that extraordinary Juncture and the parties concerned therein may
be Indemnified therefore And for the preventing the Trouble and Charges which the said good Subjects might
be putt to by the Prosecution of Their Majestyes Their Heires and Successors or by the means of Vexatious Suits
of any person whatsoever for and by reason of their actings and doeings aforesaid Bee it enacted by the King
and Queens most Excellent Majestyes by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall
and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That all Personall Actions
Suits Indictments Informations and all other Prosecutions whatsoever for or by reason of the premisses be and
are hereby discharged and made void And if any Action or Suite hereby declared to be discharged hath beene
or shall be commenced or prosecuted every person soe sued may plead the Generall Issue and give this Act and
the Speciall Matter in Evidence And if the Plaintiffe shall become Nonsuite or forbeare further Prosecution or suffer
Discontinuance or if a Verdict passe against him the said Defendant shall recover his double Costs for which he
shall have the like Remedy as in case where Costs by Law are given to Defendants.</para>
	</section>
</report>


