<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46357" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1691</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for the better Ascertaining the Tythes of Hemp and Flax. [Rot. Parl, pt. 1. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">4s. per Acre to be paid for Tithe of Flax or Hemp, to be recovered as other Tithen</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">WHEREAS the Sowing of Hemp and Flax is and would be exceeding beneficial to England by reason of
the multitude of People that are and would be employed in the manufacturing of those two materials
and therefore do justly deserve great encouragement And whereas the manner of Tything Hemp and Flax is
exceeding difficult creating thereby grievous chargeable and vexatious Suits and Animosities between Parsons Vicars
Impropriators and their Parishioners For remedying whereof Be.it Enacted by the King and Queens most excellent
Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Com[m]ons in this
p[re]sent Parliament Assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the Second day of February
which shall be in the year of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and one all and all manner of p[er]sons,
that shall sow or cause to be sowne any Hemp or Flax in any Parish or place, in the Kingdom of. England:
Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed shall pay or cause to be paid to every Parson Vicar or
Imp[ro]priator of any such Parish or Place yearely and every yeare for each Acre of Hemp or Flax so sown
pulled or drawn a constant annual som[m]e of. Money not exceeding Four shillings before the same be carried of
the Ground and soe p[er]portionably for more or lesse Ground so sowne and pulled or drawne as aforesaid For
the Recovery of which Sum or Sumes of Money the Parson Vicar or Impropriator shall have the com[m]on and
usual remedy allowed of by the Laws of England</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Modus, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided that this Act or any thing therein contained shall not extend to charge any Lands discharged by
any Modus Decimandi ancient composition or otherwise discharged of Tythes by Law</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Continuance of Act.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided that this Law shall continue for Seaven years and [to the end<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of the next Session of Parliament after
the said Seaven yeares are expired</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">Interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


