<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46351" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1690</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII. An Act for the Raising the Militia of this Kingdome for the Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety and one although the Months Pay formerly Advanced be not Repaid. [Rot. Part. pt. 3. nu. 11.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>13 &#x0026; 14 Car. II. c. 3. &sect; 7. recited.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Recital that upon the late Provision it was necessary to draw out the Soldiers into actual Service; and that the like Occasion may again happen.; If it should be necessary before 25th Dec. 1691 to draw out Soldiers into actual Service, to be declared as herein mentioned.; Lieutenants and Lord Warden of Cinque Ports may draw out Soldiers, and cause Persons charged to provide Pay, although Pay before advanced not reimbursed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS by an Act of Parliament made in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth Yeares of the Raigne of
His late Majesty King Charles the Second Entituled An Act for Ordering the Forces in the severall
Counties of this Kingdome It was (amongst other things) Enacted That in case of Invasions Insurrections or
Rebellions whereby Occasion should be to draw out the Soldiers mentioned and appointed in and by the said Act
into actuall Service the Persons Charged by the said Act with Horses Horsmen and Armes or with Foote Soldiers
and Arms should provide each their Soldier respectively with Pay in Hand not exceeding One Months Pay as
should be in that Behalfe Directed by the respective Lieutenants of the severall Counties and in their absence or
otherwise by their Directions by their Deputies or any Two or more of them For Repayment of which said
Moneys and for Satisfaction of the Officers for their Pay dureing such time not exceeding One Month as aforesaid
as they should be with their Soldiers in such actuall Service It was thereby declared That Provision should be
made for the same by His said Majestie His Heires and Successors out of His or Their Publicke Treasury or Revenue
Neverthelesse it was thereby further Provided and Enacted That in case a Months Pay should be provided and
advanced as aforesaid that noe Person who should have advanced his Proportion thereof should be Charged with
any other like Months Payment untill he or they should have beene Reimbursed the said Months Pay and soe
from time to time the Months Pay by him or them last before provided and advanced as aforesaid And whereas
upon the late Invasion of the Coasts of this Kingdome by the French it was found Necessary for the publicke
Defence and Safety to draw out the said Soldiers into actuall Service and to charge the said Persons to provide
each their Soldiers respectively with Pay in hand although the Months Pay by severall of them before that time
provided and advanced was not nor could be reimbursed And whereas the like occasion may possibly happen
dureing the present Warr Bee it therefore Enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent Majesties by and with
the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament Assembled
and by Authoritie of the same That if at any Time before the Five and twentieth Day of December which shall be
in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and ninety one it shall be found by Their Majesties (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>.) for the
Defence and Safety of this Kingdome to draw out the said Soldiers into actuall Service and the same shall be
Declared or Signified to the respective Lieutenants or Deputy Lieutenants and the Lord Warden of the Cinque
Ports Two antient Towns and their Members or in his absence his Lieutenant or Lieutenants by Their Majestyes it
shall be lawfull for the said Lieutenants or their Deputies or any two or more of them as aforesaid and the Lord
Warden of the Cinque Ports Two ancient Townes and their Members or in his absence his Lieutenant or Lieutenants
in pursuance of such Orders from their Majesties (notwithstanding that One or more Months Pay before that time
advanced be not Reimbursed) to raise and draw out the said Soldiers into actuall Service and to cause the Persons
charged as aforesaid to provide each their Soldier with Pay in hand not exceeding One Months Pay in such manner
as if all the Pay before that time advanced and provided had been fully reimbursed and paid.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">to be necessary <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


