<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46367" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1691</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An Act against corresponding with Their Majesties Enemies [Rot. Parl. pt. 2. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Exporting of any Arms, &amp;c. into France, High Treason.</head>
			<para id="p1">For preventing of Traiterous Correspondence and Co[m]merce with the French King or his Subjects and supplying
them with Warlike or other Stores or Co[m]modities by means of which they may be any way aided or comforted
in carrying on their War against Their Majesties Be it declared and enacted by the King and Queens most excellent
Majesties by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Co[m]mons in this
present Parliament assembled and [by<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the authority of the same That if dureing the present War between Their
Majesties and the French King any person or persons shall send or load or transport or deliver or cause to be
sent or loaden or transported or delivered unto or for the Use of the said French King or any of his Subjects
residing within his Dominions or any Towne or Territory in his possession or into or for any Port or Place within
his said Dominions any Arms Ordnance Powder Bullets Pitch Tarr Hemp Masts Cordage Iron Coales Lead or
Salt-Peter that every person or persons so as aforesaid offending being legally thereof convicted or attainted by due
course of Law shall be deemed declared and adjudged to be a Traytor or Traytors and shall suffer Pains of Death
and alsoe lose and forfeit as in cases of High Treason.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Exporting any other Commodities into France, Premunire.</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">16 R. II. c. 5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">And be it further Enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any person or persons dureing the War aforesaid
shall send or load or transport or deliver or cause to be sent or laden or transported or delivered unto or for
the Use of the said French King or any of his Subjects residing within his Dominions or into or for any Port
or Place within his said Dominions any Goods Wares Merchandizes or Co[m]modities whatsoever other then the
Goods and Co[m]modities herein before particularly menc[i]oned That every p[er]son or p[er]sons so as aforesaid offending
being thereof convicted or attainted by due Course of Law shall incur the Danger Pain and Forfeiture ordained
and provided by the Statute of Premunire made in the Sixteenth yeare of the Reigne of King Richard the
Second.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Going into France without Licence, High Treason.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it further Enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any of Their Majesties Subjects shall from and
after the Tenth day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety one without license
from Their Majesties voluntarily goe or repaire or imbarque in any Vessell with an intent to go into France or
any Dominions of the French [King<emph type="p">1</emph>] and be upon full proof convicted thereof he shall be taken deemed and adjudged
to be guilty of High Treason and shall suffer such Penalties as in case of High Treason.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Persons returning out of France without Leave, Imprisonment.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further Enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any person or persons being Their Majesties
Subjects shall after the Five and twentieth day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
ninety two voluntarily come or returne from France or any of the French Kings Dominions in Europe into England
or any of Their Majesties Dominions in Europe dureing the said War without Their Majesties leave for that purpose
first had and obtained and be thereof convicted by due course of Law shall be co[m]mitted to Prison and there closely
kept without Bail or Mainprize dureing Their Majesties pleasure for any time not exceeding Twelve Months.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


