<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46366" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1691</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII. An Act for the better repairing and amending the Highways and for settling the Rates of Carriage of Goods [Rot. Parl. pt. 1. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">All Laws about Highways to be put in Execution</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas the free and easie intercourse and means of conveying and carrying Goods and Merchandizes
from one Markett Towne to another contributes very much to the advancement of Trade increase of
Wealth and raiseing the value of Lands as well as to the ease and convenience of the Subject in general For
which ends therefore divers good and necessary Laws have been heretofore made for the enlargeing repairing and
amending the Highways and Common Roads of this Kingdom Notwithstanding which Laws the same are not in
many parts sufficiently amended and repaired but remain almost impassible All which is occasioned not only
by reason of some Ambiguities in the said Laws but by want of a sufficient Provision to compel the execution
of the same. For remedy whereof Be it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with
the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled
and by Authority of the same That all and every Law and Statute now in force for or touching the
enlargeing repaireing and amending Highways and Common Roads and every Article and thing in them contained
and not herein and hereby altered or repealed shall be duely put in execution according to the Tenour of the
said Laws and under the Penalties therein contained to be raised levied and disposed of as in and by the said
Laws is directed.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Parishioners annually to make a List of sufficient Persons upon 26th of December.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">List to be returned to two or more Justices on 3d January, &amp;c.; Justices to hold a Special Sessions, where they shall nominate one or more to be Surveyors of the Highways.; Constable to serve the Nomination.; From thenceforth such Nominees to be Surveyors.; Nominee refusing, &amp;c.; Penalty, &pound;5.; Justices may appoint other Persons.; such other Persons refusing, Penalty, &pound;5.; Constables &amp;c. not returning a List; Penalty, 20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from henceforth upon the Six and twentieth day of
December in every yeare unlesse that Day shall be Sonday and then on the Seven and twentieth the Constables
Headboroughs Tythingmen Churchwardens Surveyor or Surveyors of the Highways and Inhabitants in every Parish
shall assemble together and the major part of them as are so assembled shall make a list of the Names of a
competent number of the Inhabitants in their Parish who have an Estate in Lands Tenements or Hereditaments
in their owne right or their Wives of the value of Ten pounds by the yeare or a personal Estate of the value
of One hundred pounds or are Occupiers or Tenants of Houses Lands Tenements or Hereditaments of the yearely
value of Thirty pounds if any such there be Or if there be no such persons in the Parish then the said List to
be of the most sufficient Inhabitants of such Parish and shall returne such List unto two or more of the Justices
of the Peace in or neare the Division of the County in which their Parish lies att a Speciall Sessions to be held
for that purpose within the said Division on the Third day of January next following unlesse it shall happen on
a Sunday and then to be the Fourth of the same Month or within Fifteen days after For which purpose the
said Justices are hereby authorized and required to hold a Special Sessions att some place within that Division
where the Parish lies and to give notice of the time and place where they intend to hold the same to the
Constables Headboroughs Tythingmen Churchwardens and Surveyors of the Highways of every Parish within the
said Division att least Ten days before the holding of the said Sessions And the said Justices shall then and there
out of the said Lists according to their discrecion and the largenesse of the Parish by Warrant under their Hands
and Seales nominate and appoint one two or more as they shall think fitt and approve of being of like sufficiency
as aforesaid to be Surveyor or Surveyors of the Highways of every Parish within the Division or for any
Helmet Precinct Liberty Tything or Town of and in the same Division for the yeare ensuing Which nomination
and appointment shall by the Constables Headboroughs Tythingmen or Surveyors of the Highways for the time
being or some of them be notified to the person or persons so nominated chosen and appointed by the said
Justices within Six days after such nomination by serving him or them with the said Warrant or Warrants or
by leaving the same or a true copy thereof att his or their Houses or usual places of abode And from
thenceforth the person or persons so nominated and appointed shall be Surveyor or Surveyors of the Highways
for the Parish Towne Village Hamlet Precinct or Tything for which he shall have been so nominated chosen and
appointed for the yeare ensueing and shall take upon him and them respectively and duely execute the said Office
according to the Laws and Statutes heretofore made for the enlargeing amending or repaireing of Highways and
also this present Act And if the said persons so nominated and served with the said Warrant shall refuse or
neglect so to do he or they so refuseing and neglecting shall forfeit the Sum of five pounds to be levied on his
or their Goods and Chattels by Distresse and Sale of the same by Warrant under the Hand and Seale of two or
more Justices of the Peace of the same Division or in default thereof any neighbouring Justices of the Peace for
the said County which Warrant the said Justices are hereby impowered and required to make upon Information
of any one credible Witnesse upon Oath the one Moiety of which said Forfeiture shall go to him that shall
informe and the other Moiety for and towards the Repair of the Highways of the same Parish rendring the
Overplus if any be to the Partie or Parties whose Goods shall be distrained the Charges of the Distresse and
Sale being first deducted And in case of such neglect or refusal as aforesaid the said Justices are hereby
impowered to nominate and appoint some other fit person or persons to performe the said Office who upon like
notice of such nomination and appointment shall take upon him or them and duely execute the said Office and if
he or they neglect or refuse so to do shall forfeit the like Sum of five pounds to be levied and disposed of as
aforesaid And if the Constables Headboroughs Tythingmen Churchwardens and Surveyor or Surveyors of the
Highways of any Parish Towne Liberty or Precinct or some of them shall not returne the said List of Names in
such manner as in this Act is directed every of them so neglecting shall forfeit the Sum of twenty shillings to be
levied in the manner and imployed to the Uses aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Laying Timber &amp;c. in the Highway.; Penalty, 5s.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no person or persons whatsoever shall lay in any
Highway not being twenty Foot broad any Stone Timber Straw Dung or other matter whereby the same shall be
[any ways<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] obstructed or annoyed on pain to forfeit for every such offence the Sum of five shillings to be levied
and disposed of as is aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Owner of Land adjoining to take away Timber, &amp;c. lying in the Highway.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Neglecting; Penalty 5 s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any Timber Stone Hay Straw Stubble or other
matter for the makeing of Dung or on any other pretence whatsoever shall be laid in any such Highway as
aforesaid whereby the same shall be any ways obstructed or annoyed the Owners or Possessors of the Lands next
adjoyning to the same shall clear the said Way by removeing the said Timber Stone Hay Straw Dung or other
matter and have take and dispose of the same to his and their owne use And if any such Owner or Occupier of
Lands next adjoyneing to the said Highways shall neglect to cleare the said Ways of the said Nuisances or to
cleanse or scower their Ditches Gutters and Drains adjoyning to the said Highways or cause the Earth taken out
thereof to be carried away and lay sufficient Trunks Tunnels or Bridges where any Cart-ways are into the said
Grounds for the space of Ten days after notice to him her or them given by the said Surveyors or any of them
he she or they so neglecting shall for every such Offence forfeit the Sum of Five shillings to be levied and
disposed of in manner aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Owner not grubbing up Trees, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 5 s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That no Tree Bush or Shrub shall be permitted to [stand
or<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] grow in any Highway not full twenty foot broad but the same shall be cut downe grubbed upp and carried
away by the Owner or Owners of the Land or Soyl where the same doth or shall stand or grow within Ten
days after Notice to him or them given by the said Surveyors or any of them on Pain to forfeit for every neglect
the Sum of Five shillings to be levied and disposed as is aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Possessors of Land adjoining Highways to prune the Hedges.</head>
			<para id="p10">And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Possessors of the Land next adjoyning to such
Highways where they are not Twenty foot broad shall from time to time and att all times keep their Hedges plasht
cut or pruned so as no Tree Bush or Shrub shall stand or grow in such Highway nor any Bough or Branch
be suffered to hang over the same or any part thereof but the said Hedges shall be kept cut and pared right upp from
the Roots and not permitting in any sort to spread into or hang over the Highway or any part thereof to the end
that there may be a free and clear passage for Travellers and all sorts of Carriages loaden without being [any ways<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
prejudiced or obstructed by any Hedges Trees Boughs or Branches whatsoever and that the Sun may freely shine
into the said Ways to dry and amend the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Surveyor to present the State of the Highways to a Justice every Four Months.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.; Defaults published in the Church, and if not amended within 30 Days, Surveyor shall repair them, and be repaid by the Person who ought to repair.; How Surveyor to recover his Disbursements</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And be it further Enacted by the authority aforesaid That every Surveyor of the Highways appointed as in and
by this Act is directed shall within fourteen days next after his first acceptance of the said Office and so from
time to time every foure months dureing his being Surveyor take a view of all the Roads Common Highways
Water-Courses Bridges Cawseys and Pavements within the Parish Towne Village Hamlet Precinct or Tything for
which he is appointed Surveyor that are to be repaired by the said Parish Towne Village Hamlet Precinct or Tything
and shall make a Presentment upon Oath in what state and condition he finds the same respectively to some
Justice of the Peace of the same Division if then resident there otherwise to some neighbouring Justice of the
Peace for the said County and in default thereof shall incur the Penalty aforesaid as if he or they had refused or
neglected to accept and execute the said Office unlesse he shall have some reasonable excuse for omitting the same
to be allowed by two Justices of the Peace of the same Division of the County or in default thereof by the Two
neighbouring Justices And what defaults or annoyances they shall find in any of the said Highways Cawseys
Bridges Ditches Hedges Trees Watercourses Dreyns or Gutters next adjoyning to the same they shall from time
to time the next Sunday immediately after Sermon ended give publick Notice of the same in the Parish Church
and if the same shall not be removed repaired and amended within thirty days after such Notice given that then
the said Surveyor or Surveyors of the said Highways shall within thirty days remove repaire and amend the same
and dispose of the same annoyances to and for the repair of the said Highways and the said Surveyor and Surveyors
shall be reimbursed what Charges and Expences they shall be att in so doing by the parties who should have done
the same And in case the said parties shall upon demand refuse or neglect to pay the said Surveyors their said
charges then the said Surveyors shall apply him or themselves to any Justice of the Peace within the Division of
the County wherein such Highway is and in default thereof to any [neighbouring<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Justice for the said County and
upon his or there making Oath before such Justice of the Notice to the Defaulter in manner aforesaid which Oath
the said Justice is impowered and required to administer that then the said Surveyors shall be repaid all such their
charges as shall be allowed to be reasonable by the said Justice to be levied in manner aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Petty Sessions held every Four Months to receive Presentments, and take Accounts of Surveyors.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Surveyor to pay Surplus Money to Successor.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And be it further Enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Justices of the [Peace<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of every County shall in
their respective Divisions once in foure months hold a special Sessions and shall thereunto summon all the Surveyors
of the Highways within that Division to come before them and shall give them a charge to do their duty and
declare to them what they are obliged to do by virtue of this or any former Act after which the said Surveyors
of the Highways shall make a Presentment to them upon Oath which Oath the said Justices are hereby impowered
to give of the state and condition of the Highways within their respective Parishes Townes Villages Hamlets Precincts
or Tythings for which they are appointed Surveyors and what offences and neglects any are guilty of contrary to
the meaning of this or any other Statute made concerning the Highways or any thing relateing thereunto And
before any Surveyor of the Highways shall go out of or be discharged from his Office he shall att some such special
Sessions of the said Justices to be held as aforesaid give an account upon Oath of all money that has come to his
hands which [ought<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to be employed in amending of the Highways and how he hath disposed of the same And in
case any moneys shall remaine in his hands he shall deliver the same to the Surveyors of the Highways that shall
serve for the same Parish Town Village Hamlett Precinct or Tything for the yeare ensueing and in case of failure
to forfeit the double value of what shall be judged to be in his hands by the said Justices to be levied and
disposed of as is aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Surveyors neglecting Duty; Penalty 40s.</head>
			<para id="p15">And be it further Enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any Surveyor of the Highways after his acceptance
of his said Office shall neglect his Duty in any thing required of him by this Act he shall forfeit for every such
Offence the Sum of Forty shillings to be levied and disposed of as is aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Justices of Peace neglecting Duty.; Penalty &pound;5.</head>
			<para id="p16">And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Justice of the Peace shall neglect or refuse to
do what is required of him by this Act such Justice so neglecting or refuseing shall forfeit the Sum of Five pounds
one moiety whereof shall go to the person that shall sue for the same the other moiety to be employed to and
for the repaire and [amendent<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of the Highways of the Parish where the person who shall sue for the same
inhabits to be recovered in any of Their Majesties Courts of Record by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on
in which no Priveledge Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed or more then one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Surveyors may make new Ditches, &amp;c. in Land adjoining.</head>
			<para id="p17">And be it further Enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Surveyors
of the Highways aforesaid where the Ditches and Drains already made are not sufficient to carry off the Waters that
lies upon the Highways to make new Ditches and Drains in and through the Lands next adjoyning to the said
Highways and keep them scoured cleansed and open and come upon any of the said Lands with their Workmen
for so doeing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Surveyors laying out Money for Gravel, Stones, &amp;c. to be repaid by an equal Rate to be levied by Distress.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">43 Eliz. c. 2</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And whereas divers Parishes and Towneships have not any Gravel Stones Quarries nor any other Materials fitting
or convenient for the amending or repaireing of the Highways within the said Parishes and Towneships by reason
whereof the Surveyors of the Highways of such Parishes and Towneships are forced to lay out their [owne<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] money
for the buying of such Materials as are necessary for that purpose and there being no p[ro]vision made in or by any
Law now in force for the reimbursing the said Surveyors the moneys they have so laid out For remedy whereof
Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That upon notice given by the Surveyor or Surveyors of the
Highways to the Justices of the Peace att their Special Sessions &amp; Oath made of what Sum or Sums of money
he or they have or hath so laid [out<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] &amp; expended upon amending and repairing of the said Highways the Justices of the
Peace or any two of them att their Special Sessions are hereby impowered by Warrant under their Hands and
Seals to cause an equal rate to be made for the reimbursing the said Surveyor or Surveyors the moneys by him
or them laid out as aforesaid upon all the Inhabitants of such Parish or Towneships where such moneys are so
expended according to the rules &amp; methods prescribed in an Act of Parliament made in the Three and fourtieth
yeare of the Reigne of the late Queen Elizabeth intituled An Act for the better relief of the Poor of this
Kingdom which Rate being confirmed and allowed by the said Justices in their Special Sessions shall be collected
and gathered by the said Surveyor or Surveyors of the Highways And if any person or persons refuse to pay
the moneys so assessed on him or them that then the same shall be levied by the said Surveyors by Distresse
and Sale of the Goods and Chattells of the persons so refuseing, rendring to the party the Overplus reasonable Charges
for makeing the said Distresse first to be deducted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Fines of 5 Eliz. c. 13. to be paid to the Surveyor and not returned into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">If Fine unduly laid Complaint to Special Sessions, and Proceedings thereon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And whereas in pursuance of the Statute made in the Fifth yeare of the Reigne of the late Queen Elizabeth
many Parishes and Places are oftentimes presented upon the knowledge and view of a Justice of Peace or
otherwise for not repairing and amending their Highways and the Fines imposed and sett on such p[re]sentments
and other Fines and Issues for not repaireing and amending the Highways are returned into the Court of Exchequer
or other Courts and such Fines and Issues against such Parishes for not amending their Highways are levied on
some particular Inhabitants of such Parishes or Places and there being no provision made for the makeing of a Rate to
reimburse such particular Inhabitants Be it therefore further enacted by the authority aforesaid That no Fine Issue Penalty
or Forfeiture shall hereafter be returned into the Court of Exchequer or other Court but shall be levied and
paid into the Hands of the Surveyors of such Parish or Place to be applyed towards the repaire and amendment
of such Highway And that if any Fine Penalty or Forfeiture imposed on any Parish or Place for not repaireing
the Highways shall hereafter be levied on any one or more of the Inhabitants of such Parish or Place
that then such Inhabitant or Inhabitants shall make his or their Complaint to the Justics of the Peace at their
Special Sessions and the said Justics or any Two of them are hereby impowered and authorized by Warrant
under their Hands and Seales to cause a Rate to be made according to the forme and manner aforesaid for the
reimbursing such Inhabitant or Inhabitants the moneys so levied on him or them as aforesaid which Rate so made
and confirmed by two Justics as aforesaid shall be collected &amp; levied by the Surveyor or Surveyors of the
Highways of such Parish or Place so presented [or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] indicted as aforesaid and the said Surveyor or Surveyors shall
within one month next after the makeing and confirmeing the Rate aforesaid pay unto the Inhabitant or
Inhabitants such money so levied on him or them as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. All Cartways to be Eight Feet wide.</head>
			<para id="p22">And be it Enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Surveyors of the Highways shall and are hereby
required to make every Cart-way leading to any Markett-Towne eight foot wide att the least and as neare as
may be even and level.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Inhabitants within the Weekly Bills, what Carts they may use.</head>
			<para id="p23">Provided always and be it Enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any
Inhabitant of any of the Parishes within the Weekely Bills of Mortality who dwells of from the pavement or uses
his Carts as well off as upon the pavement And to and for any Brewer and to and for any Scavenger or other
person imployed in carrying away the dirt and soyle of the Streets Lanes and Allies to make use of any Cart
Carr or Dray with Wheels shod with Iron and narrower then six inches in the Felleys and drawne with more
then two Horses Any Act of Parliament Law or Usage to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Justices may in Sessions order an Assessment to be made to repair the Ways.</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">Monies raised how employed and accounted for</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That where the Justics of the Peace of any County City
Borough or other place or the major part of them att their General [or<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Quarter Sessions shall be fully satisfied
that the Co[m]mon Highways Causeys Bridgs Streets or Pavements within any Parish Towneshipp Hamlett or other
place within their respective Jurisdiction cannot otherwise be sufficiently amended repaired paved cleansed and
supported by means of the Laws now in force without the help of this present Act in all such cases one or more
Assessement or Assessements upon all and every the Inhabitants Owners and Occupiers of Lands Houses Tenements
and Hereditaments or any Personal Estate usually rateable to the Poor within any such Parish Towneship Hamlett
or other place shall be made levied collected and allowed by such person and persons and in such manner as
the said Justics by their Order att such Sessions shall direct and appoint in that behalf And the money thereby
raised shall be employed and accompted for according to the Orders and Directions of the said Justics for and
towards the amending repairing paving cleansing and supporting such Highways Causeys Streets Pavements
and Bridgs from time to time as need shall require And the said Assessments shall be levied by distresse and sale
of the Goods of every person so assessed (not paying the same within ten days after demand) rendring the
overplus of the value of the Goods so distrained to the Owner and Owners thereof (the necessary charges of making
and selling such distresse being first deducted).</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Assessment not to exceed 6d. in the Pound.</head>
			<para id="p26">Provided neverthelesse and be it enacted That no such Assessment or Assessements to be made in any one
yeare shall exceed the rate of Six pence in the pound of the yearely value of any Lands Houses Tenements and
Hereditaments so assessed nor the rate of Six pence for Twenty pounds in Personal Estate.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Persons aggrieved may appeal to Quarter Sessions.</head>
			<para id="p27">Provided always That if any person or persons shall find him or themselves agrieved with any Assessement or
Rate or other Act by the said Justics of Peace That then it shall be lawfull for the Justics of the Peace at their
General Quarter Sessions or the greater number of them to take such Order therein as to them shall be thought
convenient and the same to conclude and bind all the said Parties.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Limitation of Prosecution.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">No double Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">Provided also That no person shall be punished for any Offence against this Act unlesse such Offender be
p[ro]secuted for the same within Six Months after the Offence co[m]mitted and that no person who shall be punished
for any Offence by virtue of this Act shall be punished for the same Offence by virtue of any other Act or
Law whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Breadth of Horse Cawseys.</head>
			<para id="p30">And be it further enacted and declared by the authority aforesaid That no Horse Causey or Causey for
Horses travelling upon or in any publick Highway be lesse or under Three foot in breadth.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Middlesex Justices may make Rates to pave Kensington.</head>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 8</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p32">And be it Enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Justics of the
Peace of the County of Middlesex att their General Quarter Sessions to make rates for the paving the Towne
of Kensington within the said County (in all such places thereof as they shall think convenient and to amend repair and
cleanse the same) upon old Streets and Houses as well as new in such manner as is directed by one Act made
in the Second yeare of Their Majesties Reigne for paving and cleansing the Streets in the Cities of London and
Westminster.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. No Certiorari on any Order, &amp;c. upon this Act.</head>
			<para id="p33">And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all matters concerning Highways Causeys Pavements and
Bridgs menc[i]ed in this Act shall be determined in the County where the same do lie and not elsewhere And
that no Presentment Indictment or Order made by virtue of this Act shall be removed by Certiorari out of the
said County into any other Court.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Justices once a Year to settle the Rates of Carriages, and to certify the same.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Carrier taking above the Rate; Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">And whereas diverse Waggoners and other Carriers by combination amongst themselves have raised the prices
of carriage of Goods in many places to excessive rates to the great injury of Trade Be it therefore enacted by
the authority aforesaid That the Justics of the Peace of every County and other place within the Realme of
England or Dominion of Wales shall have power and authority and are hereby injoyned and required att their
next respective Quarter or General Sessions after Easter-day yearely to assesse and rate the prices of all Land
Carriage of Goods whatsoever to be brought into any place or places within their respective Limitts and Jurisdictions
by any co[m]mon Waggoner or Carrier and the Rates and Assessements so made to certifie to the several Mayors
and other Chief Officers of each respective Markett Towne within the Limitts and Jurisdic[i]ns of such Justics of
the Peace to be hung upp in some publick place in every such Markett Towne to which all persons may
resort for their informac[i]on And that no such co[m]mon Wagoner or Carrier shall take for carriage of such
Goods and Merchandizes above the Rates and Prices so sett upon pain to forfeit for every such Offence
the Su[m]m of Five pounds to be levied by distresse and sale of his and their Goods by Warrant of any Two
Justices of the Peace where such Waggoner or Carrier shall reside in manner aforesaid to the use of the party
grieved.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Persons prosecuted for executing this Act may plead the General Issue, and have double Costs.</head>
			<para id="p36">And be it further Enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any Action or Suit shall be hereafter co[m]menced
or p[ro]secuted against any person or persons by this Act authorized to put the same in execuc[i]on every person or
persons so sued may plead the General Issue and give this Act and the Special Matter in Evidence And if the
Plaintiff shall become nonsuit or forbear further Prosecution or suffer discontinuance or if a Verdict passe against
him or her the said Deft and Defts shall recover his and their double Costs for which he and they shall have the
like Remedy as in cases where Costs by Law are given to Defts</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">anywise <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">anywise <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">amendment <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


