<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46361" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1691</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act for raising the Militia of this Kingdom for the Year One thousand six hundred ninety and two although the Months Pay formerly advanced be not repaid [Rot. Parl. pt. 1. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>13 &amp; 14 Car. II. c. 3. recited.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Recital that upon the Invasion it was necessary to draw out the Soldiers.; If it shall be found necessary before 25th March 1693 to draw out Soldiery,; Proceedings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act of Parliament made in the thirteenth and fourteenth Yeares of the Reign of His
late Majestie King Charles the Second Entituled An Act for ordering the Forces in the severall Counties
of this Kingdom it was (amongst other things) enacted That in case of Invasions Insurrections or Rebellions
whereby occasion should be to draw out the Souldiers mentioned and appointed in and by the said Act into
actual Service the psons charged by the said Act with Horses Horsemen and Arms or with Foot Soldiers and
Arms should provide each their Souldier respectively with Pay in hand not exceeding One Months Pay as should
be in that behalf directed by the respective Lieutenants of the severall Counties and in their absence or otherwise
by their direction by their Deputies or any two or more of them For repayment of which said Moneys and
for satisfac[t]ion of the Officers for their Pay dureing such time not exceeding one Month as aforesaid as they
should be with their Souldiers in such actual Service it was thereby declared That Provision should be made for
the same by His said Majestie His Heires &amp; Successors out of His or Their publick Treasury or Revenue
Neverthelesse it was thereby further provided &amp; enacted That in case a Months Pay should be provided and
advanced as aforesaid That no person who should have advanced his proportion thereof should be charged with
any other like Months Payment until he or they should have been reimbursed the said Months Pay and so from
time to time the Months by him or them last before provided and advanced as aforesaid And whereas upon the
Invasion of the Coasts of this Kingdom by the French it was found necessary for the publick Defence and Safety
to draw out the said Souldiers into actual Service and to charge the said Persons to provide each their Soldiers
respectively with Pay in hand although the Months Pay by several of them before that time provided &amp; advanced
was not nor could be reimbursed And whereas the like occasion may possibly happen dureing the present War
Be it therefore enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent
of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this p[re]sent Parliament assembled and by authority of the
same That if at any time before the twenty fifth day of March which shall be in the year of our Lord One
thousand six hundred ninety and three it shall be found by Their Majesties to be necessary for the Defence and
Safety of this Kingdom to draw out the said Souldiers into actual Service and the same shall bee declared or
signified to the respective Lieutenants or Deputy Lieuten<emph type="p">ts</emph> and the Lord Warden of the Cinque Ports Two
Ancient Towns and their Members or in his Absence his Lieutenant or Lieutenants by Their Majesties It shall be
lawful for the said Lieutenants or their Deputies or any Two or more of them as aforesaid and the Lord Warden
of the Cinque Ports Two Ancient Towns and their Members or in his absence his Lieutenant or Lieutenants in
pursuance of such Orders from Their Majesties (notwithstanding that One or more Months Pay before that time
advanced be not reimbursed) to raise and draw out the said Soldiers into actual Service and to cause the Persons
charged as aforesaid to provide each their Souldier with pay in hand not exceeding One Months Pay in such manner
as if all the Pay before that time advanced and provided had been fully reimbursed and paid</para>
	</section>
</report>


