<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46369" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1691</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the better ordering and collecting the Duty upon Low Wines and Strong [Waters] and preventing the Abuses therein [Chapter XV. Rot. Parl. pt. 2. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Distiller setting up, &amp;c. brewing Vessel, &amp;c. without Notice to Officer;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the preventing of the Frauds of Distillers Makers and other Retailers of Low Wines Spirits and Strong
Waters Be it enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent Majesties by and with the Advice and
Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons now in Parliament assembled and by Authority of the
same That no co[m]mon Distiller or Maker of Low Wines Spirits or Strong Waters for sale shall att any time
from and after the First day of March One thousand six hundred ninety and one set up make use of or alter
any Tun Cask Washbatch Copper Still or other Vessell for the brewing or makeing of any Worts Wash Low
Wines Spirits or Strong Waters for sale or shall keep or make use of any private or concealed Warehouse
Celler or other Place for the laying of any Wash Low Wines Spirits or Strong Waters for sale without first
giving Notice thereof att the next Office of Excise within the Limitts or Jurisdiction whereof he or they do or
shall inhabit upon pain to forfeit the Sum of Twenty pounds for every Tun Cask Washbatch Copper Still
or other Vessell so set up used or altered and for every private or concealed Warehouse Celler or other Place
so used as aforesaid and that all and every other Person or Persons in whose occupation any House Outhouse
or other place whatsoever is or shall be where any such private or concealed Tun, Cask Washbatch Copper Still or
other Vessell shall be found or discovered shall alsoe forfeit and lose the sum of Twenty pounds one moiety thereof
to Their Majesties Their Heires and Successors and the other moiety to him or them that shall informe or sue for
the same.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Distillers concealing Spirits, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.; 12 Car. II. c. 24.; 15 Car. II. c. 11</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further Enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any co[m]mon Distiller or Maker of Low Wines
Spirits or Strong Waters shall att any time hereafter hide conceal or convey any Low Wines Spirits or Strong Waters
for sale from the sight or view of the Gauger or Gaugers appointed [so<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to take account of the same whereby Their
Majesties shall or may be defrauded of any the duties due for the same that every such co[m]mon Distiller or Maker
of such Low Wines Spirits or Strong Waters for every Gallon of Low Wines Spirits or Strong Waters for sale so
hid concealed or conveyed as aforesaid shall forfeit the sum of five shillings each Gallon all which Penalties to be
sued for recovered [and<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] levied in such manner as by one Act of Parliament made in the Twelfth yeare of the Reigne
of the late King Charles the Second entituled An Act for takeing away the Court of Wards and Liveries and Tenures
in Capite and by Knights Service and Purveyance and for settling a Revenue upon his Majesty in lieu thereof and
alsoe as by one other Act of Parliament made in the Fifteenth yeare of His said Majesties Reigne entituled An
additional Act for the better ordering and collecting the duties of Excise and preventing the abuses therein
or in either of them or by any other Law now in force relateing to the Revenue of Excise on Beer and Ale is
directed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Distiller giving Notice where he lives.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided always That this Act nor any the Forfeitures or Penalties therein contained shall be construed to
extend to any co[m]mon Distiller or other person or persons who shall from and after the said First day of March
One thousand six hundred ninety and one give notice to the Officer of Excise for the Place or Division where
such Distiller or other Person shall live as by this Act is appointed.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Waters <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

