<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46373" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
<subtitle>Chapter IV. An Act for takeing Special Bails in the Countrey upon Actions and Suites depending in the Courts of Kings Bench Co[m]mon Pleas and Exchequer att Westminster [Rot. Parl. pt. 2. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>Chief Justice, &amp;c. may make any Persons, except Attorneys and Solicitors, Commissioners to take Bail in the Country.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">Justices, &amp;c. to receive the Bailpiece upon Affidavit of due Execution; Such Bail to be of the same Effect as if taken debeneesse. Commissioners Fee</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">For the greater ease and benefitt of all persons whatsoever in takeing the Recognizances of Special Bails upon
all Actions and Suites depending or to be depending in any of the Courts of Kings Bench Comon Pleas or
Exchequer at Westminster Be it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the
advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this p[re]sent Parliament assembled and by
the Authority of the same That the Cheif Justice and other the Justices of the Court of Kings Bench for the
time being or any two of them whereof the Cheif Justice for the time being to be one for the said Court of
Kings Bench and the Chief Justice of the Court of Comon Pleas and other the Justices there for the time being or
any Two of them whereof the Chief Justice of the same Court to bee one for the said Court of Cm[m]mon Pleas
and also the Cheife Baron and Barons of the Quoife of the Court of Exchequer for the time being or any Two
of them whereof the Chief Baron for the time being to be one for the said Court of Exchequer shall or may
by one or more Comission or Comissions under the several Seals of the said respective Courts from time to time
as need shall require impower such and so many persons other then com[m]on Attorneys and Sollicitors as they
shall think fitt and necessary in all and every the several Shires and Counties within the Kingdom of England
Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed to take and receive all and every such Recognizance or
Recognizances of Bail or Bails as any person or persons shall be willing or desirous to acknowledge or make before
any of the persons so impowered in any Action or Suite depending or [hereafter<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to be depending [depending<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] in
the said respective Courts or any of them in such manner and forme and by such Recognizance or Bail-peece
as the Justices and Barons of the said respective Courts have used to take the same which said Recognizance or
Recognizances of Bail or Bailpeice so taken as aforesaid shall be transmitted to some or one of the Justices [&amp;<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
Barons of the said respective Courts where such Action or Suite shall be depending who upon Affidavitt made
of the due takeing of the Recognizance of such Bail or Bail peece by some credible person present at the
takeing thereof such Justice or Baron shall receive the same upon payment of such Fees as have been usually
received for the takeing of Special Bails by the Justices and Barons Clerks and other the Officers of the said
respective Courts Which Recognizance of Bail or Bail-peece so taken and transmitted shall be of the like effect
as if the same were taken de bene esse before any of the said Justices [and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Barons for the takeing of every which
Recognizance or Recognizancs of Bail or Bail-piece the person or persons so impowered shall receive only the
Sum or Fee of two shillings and no more</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Power given to Justices, &amp;c. to make Rules for justifying not ordering Appearance of Cognizor.</head>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Proviso for London, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Justices and Barons respectively in the several
Courts shall make such Rules and Orders for the justifying of such Bails and makeing of the same absolute as
to them shall seem meet so as the Cognizor or Cognizors of such Bail or Bails be not compelled to appear in
person in any of the said Courts to justifie him or themselves but the same may and is hereby directed to be
determined by Affidavitt or Affidavits duely taken before the said Comissioners who are hereby impowered and
required to take the same and also to examine the Sureties upon Oath touching the value of their respective
Estates unlesse the Cognizor or Cognizors of such Bail do live within the Cities of London and Westminster or
within Ten miles thereof.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. Justices of Assize may take Bail.</head>
<para id="p5">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That any Judge of Assize in his Circuit shall and may
take and receive all and every such Recognizance and Recognizances of Bail or Bails as any person shall be
willing and desirous to make and acknowledge before him which being transmitted in like manner as aforesaid
shall (without Oath) be received in manner as aforesaid upon payment of the usuall Fees.</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>IV. Persons being Bail in an other Man's Name.</head>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">Death</emph>.</para>
<para id="p7">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That any person or persons who shall (before any person
or persons impowered by virtue of this Act as aforesaid to take Bail or Bails) represent and personate any other
person or persons (whereby the person or persons so represented and personated may be liable to the payment of
any Sum or Sums of money for Debt or Damags to be recovered in the same Suite or Action wherein such
person or persons are represented and personated as if they had really acknowledged and entred into the same
being lawfully convicted thereof shall be adjudged esteemed and taken to be Felons and suffer the pains of Death
and incur such Forfeitures and Penalties as Felons in other cases convicted or attainted do by the Law of
England lose and forfeit.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n4" number="4">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


