<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46372" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for granting to Their Majesties certain Rates and Duties of Excise upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for secureing certain Recompences and Advantages in the said Act menc[i]oned to such Persons as shall voluntarily advance the Su[m]me of Ten hundred thousand Pounds towards carrying on the War against France [Rot. Parl. pt. 2. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>Excise, &amp;c. upon Beer, Ale, and other Liquors, continued for 99 Years</head>
<para id="p1">Wee your most loyal and dutiful Subjects the Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled being sensible of the
great and necessary Expences in which your Majesties are ingaged for carrying on the p[re]sent Warr
against the French King and being desirous to supply the same in such manner as may be least grievous to your
Majesties Subjects Therefore for the incouragment of such Persons as shall voluntarily contribute to the advancing
and paying into your Majesties Exchequer towards carrying on the said Warr any sum or sum of money not
exceeding the Sum of Ten hundred thousand Pounds upon the respective Termes and Recompences hereafter
mentioned wee your Majesties said dutiful Subjects the Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled have given and granted
and do hereby give and grant unto your Majesties the severall additional Rates and Duties of Excise hereinafter
menc[i]oned for and dureing the Terme hereafter expressed and do beseech your Majesties that it may be enacted
and be it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the
Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons. in Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That from
and after the Five and twentieth day of January One thousand six hundred [ninety<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] and two there shall be
throughout the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales and Town of Berwick upon Tweed raised leavyed collected
and paid unto their Majesties their Heires and Successors dureing the space and terme of Ninety [&amp;<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] nine yeares.
from the said Five and twentieth day of January One thousand six hundred ninety and two and no longer for
Beer Ale Cyder and other Liquors herein after expressed by way of Excise over and above all other Duties Charges
and Impositions by any former or other Act or Acts sett and imposed or to be sett and imposed in manner and
forme following (that is to say)</para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">Beer, &amp;c. above 6s. per Barrel, 9d</emph>.</para>
<para id="p3">For every Barrel of Beere or Ale above Six shillings the Barrel exclusive of the Duty of Excise brewed by the
co[m]mon Brewer or any other person or persons who doth or shall sell or tap out Beer or Ale publikely
or privately to be paid by the co[m]mon Brewer or by such other person or persons respectively and so p[ro]portionably
for a greater or lesser quantity over and above all other Duties payable for the same Nine pence</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">Beer and Ale, 6s. or under per Barrel, 3d</emph>.</para>
<para id="p5">For every Barrel of Beer or Ale of Six shillings the Barrel or under brewed by the co[m]mon Brewer or any
other person or persons who shall sell or tap out Beer or Ale publickely or privately to be paid by the said
common Brewer or by such other person or persons respectively as aforesaid and so p[ro]portionably for a greater
or lesser quantity over and above all other Duties payable for the same Three pence</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">Vinegar, English, per Barrel, 1s. 6d</emph>.</para>
<para id="p7">For every Barrel of Vinegar Beer brewed or made of any English Materials by any co[m]mon Brewer or any other
p[er]son for sale to be paid by the Maker thereof and so p[ro]portionably for a greater or lesser quantity over and above
all other Duties [of Excise<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] payable for the same One shilling six pence</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">Vinegar, Foreign, per Barrel, 4s</emph>.</para>
<para id="p9">For every Barrel of Vinegar or Liquor prepared for Vinegar made here for sale that hath run through foreign
Rape or made with or passing through any foreigne Materials or any mixture with foreigne Materials to be paid
by the Maker thereof and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity Four shillings</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">Beer, &amp;c. imported, per Barrel, 3s</emph>.</para>
<para id="p11">For every Barrel of Beer Ale or Mum imported from beyond the Seas and so proportionably for a greater or
lesser quantity to be paid by the Importer before landing over and above the Duties payable for the same Three
shillings</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">Cider, &amp;c. imported, per Tun, 4l</emph>.</para>
<para id="p13">For every Tun of Cyder or Perry imported from beyond the Seas and so p[ro]portionably for a greater or lesser
quantity to be paid by the Importer before landing over and above all other Duties payable for the same Foure
pounds</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">Single Brandy, imported, per Gallon, 6d</emph>.</para>
<para id="p15">For every Gallon of single Brandy Spirits or Aqua vite imported from beyond the Seas to bee paid by the
Importer before landing over and above all other Duties payable for the same Six pence</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">Double Brandy, imported, per Gallon, 1s</emph>.</para>
<para id="p17">For every Gallon of Brandy Spirits or Aqua vite above proof comonly called double Brandy imported from
beyond the Seas to be paid by the Importer before landing over and above all other Duties payable for the same
One shilling</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">Cider, &amp;c. retailed, 1s. 3d. per Hogshead</emph>.</para>
<para id="p19">For all Cyder and Perry made and sold by Retail upon every Hoggshead to be paid by the Retailer thereof
over and above all other Duties payable for the same and soe p[ro]portionably for a greater or leasser Measure One
shilling three pence</para>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">Metheglin, &amp;c. per Gallon, 3d</emph>.</para>
<para id="p21">For all Metheglin or Mead made for sale either by retail or otherwise to be paid by the Maker for every
Gallon Three pence</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Duties collected as by 12 Car. II. c. 24.</head>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">12 Car. II. c. 23; 15 Car. II. c. 11; Duties within the Receipt and Government of Commissioners of Excise</emph>.</para>
<para id="p23">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the severall Rates Duties and Impositions upon Beer Ale
Cyder and other Liquors aforesaid be leavyed collected and payd unto Their Majesties Their Heires and Successors
dureing the said space and terme of Ninety and nine yeares in the same manner and forme and by such rules
ways and meanes and under such penalties and forfeitures as are menc[i]oed in the Act made in the Twelfth yeare
of the Reigne of King Charles the Second entituled An Act for takeing away the Court of Wards and Liveries
and Tenures in Capite and by Knights Service and Purveyance and for settling a Revenue upon His Majesty in
lieu thereof And also in and by another Act made in the Twelfth yeare of the Reigne of the said late King
Charles the Second entituled A Grant of certain Impositions upon Beere Ale and other Liquors for the increase of
His Majesties Revenue dureing his Life And also in and by another Act made in the Fifteenth yeare of the Reigne
of the said late King Charles the Second entituled An additional Act for the better ordering and collecting the Duty
of Excise and preventing the abuses therein or by any other Law in force relateing to the said Revenue of Excise
And that the aforesaid Acts and every Article Rule and Clause therein menc[i]oed as for and concerning only the
Rates Duties and Impositions by this Act granted shall be of full force and effect to all intents and purposes
dureing the said terme of Ninety and nine yeares in like manner as if the same were at large and perticularly
recited and sett downe in the body of this Act And that the said Rates and Duties of Excise by this Act granted
shall from time to time be within the receipt and government of the chief Co[m]missioners and Governors of the
Receipt of the Excise for the time being</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. The Monies to be kept apart, and paid weekly into the Exchequer.</head>
<para id="p24">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Co[m]missioners and Governors for management
and receipt of the Excise at the Head Office in London for the time being shall separate and keep apart all and
every the moneys ariseing by the Rates and Duties of Excise hereby granted as the same shall from time to time
arise or be paid into the said Office of Excise by the Receivors or Collectors of the same or by any other
p[er]son whatsoever And the said Co[m]missioners and Governors of Excise for the time being are hereby required and
strictly enjoyned from time to time to pay weekly (viz) on Wednesday in every week if it be not a Holyday
and if it be then the next day after that is not a Holyday all and every the moneys ariseing by the Rates and Duties of
Excise hereby granted into the Receipt of Their Majesties Exchequer distinct and apart from the other moneys which
the said Co[m]missioners and Governors of Excise shall receive for the use of Their Majesties Their Heires and Successors</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>IV. Books kept in the Exchequer of the weekly Payments.</head>
<para id="p25">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That there shall be p[ro]vided and kept in Their Majesties
Exchequer (that is to say) in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipts one Book in which all the said weekly
moneys which shall be paid into the Exchequer as aforesaid shall be entered apart and distinct from all other
moneys paid or payable to Their Majesties Their Heires and Successors upon any account whatsoever</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>V. Commissioners neglecting to pay, or misapplying Money; Penalty.</head>
<para id="p26">And be it further enacted That if the said Co[m]missioners and Governors of Excise for the time being shall
refuse or neglect to pay into the Exchequer all or any the said weekly sumes appointed to be paid as aforesaid
in such manner as they are before by this Act required to do or shall divert or misaply any of the same then
they for [any<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] such Offence shall forfeit their Offices of Comissioners and Governors for the management and receipt
of the Excise and be incapable of any Office or Place of Trust whatsoever and shall be liable to pay the full
value of any sum or sums so diverted or misapplyed to any person or persons who will sue for the same by any
Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on in any of Their Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster wherein no
Essoign p[ro]tection Wager of Law Priveledge of Parliament or other Priveledge or more then one Imparlance shall
be granted or allowed</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>VI. Duties a Fund for the Purposes herein mentioned.</head>
<para id="p27">And be it further enacted That all the said sums so as aforesaid appointed to be paid weekly into the Receipt
of the Exchequer dureing the said terme of ninety and nine years shall be the yearely fund for the several and
respective purposes herein after mentioned and expressed</para>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>VII. Natives and Foreigners may contribute One Million before May.</head>
<para id="p28"><emph type="i">&pound;100,000 to be yearly distributed till An. 1700, and afterwards &pound;70,000; Contributor of &pound;100 to receive a Share during the Life which he names; Any Person may contribute as many hundreds as he pleases; Lives when to be named; Books to be kept of the Names of the Contributors and Nominees, and the Sums contributed; Books may be inspected without Fee; Contributor, upon Payment of his Money, to have Tally and Order; Order not made void by Removal or Revocation of any Officer; Treasury, &amp;c. not to revoke Orders; The said yearly Funds equally divided amongst Contributors; Proviso for Survivorship amongst Nominees; If the whole Sum of &pound;1,000,000 be not advanced, the Contributors to be paid such Part of the annual Funds as is proportionable to the Advance</emph>.</para>
<para id="p29">And be it further enacted That it shall and may be lawfull for any persons Natives or Foreigners to contribute
towards the advanceing of the said sum of Ten hundred thousand pounds for the purposes aforesaid by paying
into the receipt of Their Majesties Exchequer at any time before the First day of May One thousand six hundred
ninety and three such sum or sums of money and upon such terms respectively as herein after is mentioned and
expressed (that is to say) That out of the moneys ariseing by vertue of this Act the sum of One hundred
thousand pounds yearely until the Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand seaven hundred be separated
and kept apart as the yearely Fund to be divided amongst the persons contributing to the raising the said sum
of Ten hundred thousand pounds and that from and after the said Four and twentieth day of June One thousand
seaven hundred out of the moneys ariseing by vertue of this Act the sum of seaventy thousand pounds be yearely
separated and kept apart as the yearely Fund to be divided as herein after is mentioned That any person who
will become a Contributor shall and may advance the sum of One hundred pounds at the least for which sum
soe advanced he is to name to the Auditor of the Receipt or the Clerk of the Pells in the Exchequer for the
time being his owne or some other Life dureing which he shall be intituled to receive a share or dividend of
the said yearely Fund as hereafter is expressed That every Contributor may advance as many sums of one hundred
pounds as he shall think fitt for which sums soe advanced he is to name to the Auditor of the Receipt or the
Clerk of the Pells for the time being One or more Life or Lives (soe as no more Lives be named than there
are distinct Hundred pounds advanced) dureing which Life or Lives he shall be entituled to receive so many
shares or dividends of the said yearely Funds as there are Hundred pounds by him advanced That all the said
Lives shall be named by the severall Contributors their Executors or Administrators or such as shall be imployed
by them to pay in the said sums within fourteen days after the Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand
six hundred ninety and three That in the said Office of Auditor of the Receipts and in the Office of the Clerk
of the Pells severally there be provided and kept one or more book or books in which shall be fairly entred the
names of all who shall be Contributors and of all persons by whose hands the said Contributors shall pay in
any of the said sums and also the severall sums so paid and the time when the same are respectively paid the
said entry to bee made upon payment of the said sums And also in the said books there shall bee entred the
severall Nominees for whose Lives respectively the severall Dividends of the said yearely Fund shall be payable
at the times when the same shall be nominated as aforesaid To which books it shall be lawfull for the respective
Contributors their Executors Administrators and Assignes from time to time att all seasonable times to have resort
and to inspect the same without fee or reward And as well the said severall Contributors as the said Nominees
shall be described in the said books by their Christian and Sirnames Additions Places of abode and other descriptions
which shall best ascertain the persons And every Contributor upon payment of the sum of one or more Hundred
pounds as aforesaid shall immediately have one or more Tally or Tallies leavied importing the receipt of the
Consideration Money for which the Contributor is to receive one or more shares or dividends of the said yearely
Fund dureing the Life or Lives of the Nominee or Nominees whether such Nominee be the Contributor himselfe
or herselfe or any other person and an Order for payment thereof accordingly bearing the same date with the
Tally Which Orders shall be signed by the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury or any three or more of them now
being or by the Treasurer of the Exchequer or any Three or more of the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the
time being And after the signeing thereof the same shall be firme good valid and effectual in the Law according
to the purport and true meaning thereof and of this Act and shall not be determinable by or upon the deaths
or removeal of any Co[m]missioners or Comissioner of the Treasury or Lord High Treasurer or Treasurer of the
Exchequer or by or upon the determination of the Power or Office of any Comissioner or Comissioners of the
Treasury or Lord High Treasurer or Treasurer of the Exchequer Nor shall any Comissioners of the Treasury or
Lord High Treasurer or Treasurer of the Exchequer now or for the time being have power to revoake countermand
or make void such Orders so signed as aforesaid or any of them And the said respective yearely Funds of One
hundred thousand pounds and seaventy thousand pounds (in case the whole sum of Ten hundred thousand
pounds shall be advanced upon credit of the said Funds) shall be equally divided amongst the Contributors their
Executors Administrators or Assignes dureing the Lives of their respective Nominees in proportion to the sums
by them advanced yearely and every yeare by two equal halfe yearely payments that is to say the Foure and
twentieth day of December and the Foure and twentieth day of June the first payment to be made the Foure and
twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred ninety and three and upon the death of every Nominee the
share or shares of the said Funds which was or were payable dureing his Life shall be equally divided amongst
the rest of the Contributors whose Nominees shall be liveing And so from time to time upon the death of every
Nominee whatsoever share or dividend was payable dureing the Life of such Nominee shall be equally divided amongst
the rest of the Contributors their Executors Administrators and Assignes dureing the Lives of their respective
Nominees so that from time to time the whole respective yearely Funds shall bee divided and paid amongst
the Contributors whose Nominees doe survive until such time as there shall be but seaven Nominees liveing after
which tyme there shall be no more advantage of survivorship but upon the death of every of the said seaven
Nominees a seventh share of the said yearely Funds shall be answered to the use of Their Majesties Their Heires
and Successors And in case the whole sum of Ten hundred thousand pounds shall not by the first day of May
One thousand six hundred ninety and three bee advanced and paid by such Contributors upon the terms aforesaid
that then there shall be divided to and amongst such Contributors as shall before the said first day of May have
advanced and paid as aforesaid towards the same yearely and every yeare by two equal payments as aforesaid so
much only of the said yearly Funds as shall bear proportion to the said sum so advanced after the Rates aforesaid
that is to say so much only of the said yearely Funds as shall dureing the first seaven yeares to co[m]mence from
the said Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety three answer yearely the sum of
Ten pounds for every hundred pounds so advanced and paid And from and after the expiration of the said
seven years during the Lives of the said Nominees and the survivor of them yearely and every yeare by Two
equal payments as aforesaid the sum of seaven pounds for every hundred pounds so advanced and paid to be
divided as aforesaid with the like benefitt and advantage of survivorship as is herein directed in case the whole
sum of Ten hundred thousand pounds shall be advanced and paid upon the terms aforesaid And from and after
the [said<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] first day of May One thousand six hundred ninety and three no Contributors shall advance any further
sums upon the terms and advantages aforesaid</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>VIII. &pound;10 per Cent. allowed Contributor from time of Payment, till the 24th of June.</head>
<para id="p30">And for the encouragement of the Contributors to advance and pay forthwith into the Receipt of the Exchequer
the sums by them intended to bee advanced upon the terms aforesaid it is enacted by the Authority aforesaid
That every such Contributor shall receive out of the said yearely Funds for all moneys by him soe advanced and
paid from the respective days of payment unto the said Four and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred
ninety three Interest for the same at the rate of Ten pounds per Centum per Annum which Interest shall be
mentioned and expressed in the order hereby appointed to be given upon payment of any such sums</para>
</section>
<section id="s9">
<head>IX Contributor may assign or devise his Interest;</head>
<para id="p31"><emph type="i">Entry of Assignment and Will, and Affidavit of Execution, to be filed in the Office of Receipt; Proviso where no Assignment or Devise</emph>.</para>
<para id="p32">And be it further enacted That it shall and may be lawfull for any Contributor his Executors Administrators
or Assignes at any time dureing the Life of his or their respective Nominee by any writeing under hand and
seale or by his or their last Will in writeing to assign or devise any one or more share or shares of the said
Fund payable dureing the Life of any one or more Nominee or Nominees to any person or persons and so toties
quoties. and no such Assignements to be revocable so as an entry or memorandum of such Assignement or Will
be made in Books to be kept for that purpose in the said Office of the Receipt within the space of two Months
after such assignement or death of the Devisor And that upon the produceing such assignement or Will or Probat
thereof in the said Office of Receipt to be entred as aforesaid the party so produceing the same shall bring
therewith an Affidavitt taken before some person authorized to take Affidavitts in causes depending in any of the
Courts at Westminster of the due execution of the said Assignement or Will which Affidavitts shall be severally
filed in the said Office Which said entry or memorandum the said Officers in the said Receipt of the Exchequer
are hereby required to make accordingly and to file the said Affidavitts And in default of such Assignement or
Devise by Deed or Will the Interest of such Contributor shall goe to his Executors and Administrators for the
Life of the Nominee such Nominee being some other person as aforesaid</para>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>X. Guardians, &amp;c. may advance Money for Infants under Twelve.</head>
<para id="p33">And be it further enacted That it shall and may be lawfull for any Guardian or Trustee haveing the disposeall
of the money of any Infant under the age of twelve yeares for the use and benefitt of such Infant to advance
and pay for the purpose aforesaid the sum of One hundred pounds of the moneys of such Infant and shall
thereupon within such time as is herein before appointed for the nameing of Lives name the said Infant to be
a Nominee and such Infant upon payment of the sume shall become a Contributor within the meaning of this
Act and be intituled to have and receive dureing his or her Life a share of the said Funds in such manner and
proportion as any other Contributor And the said Guardian and Trustee as to the said su[m]me of One hundred
pounds soe advanced is hereby discharged</para>
</section>
<section id="s11">
<head>XI. Contributor, upon demanding Half yearly Payment, to bring a Certificate from Minister and Churchwarden of Nominee's Life.</head>
<para id="p34">And to the intent and purpose that all Deceits in receiveing any share of the said yearely Fund may be
prevented and that the full advantage of survivorship may be had be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That
every Contributor his Executors Administrators or Assignes upon their demanding any Halfe yearely payment of
his or their respective shares (unlesse the Nominee appear in person att the said Receipt) shall produce a
Certificate of the Life of his or their [respective<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Nominee signed by the Minister and Church wardens of the
Parish where such Nominee shall be then liveing upon the day when the said Halfe yearely payment shall become
due (if such Nominee shall be then resideing in the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of
Berwick upon Tweed which Certificate the said Minister and Churchwardens are hereby required to make without
fee or reward And the said Certificates shall bee filed in the said Office of Receipt in the Exchequer</para>
</section>
<section id="s12">
<head>XII. Proceedings where Nominee is in Scotland or beyond Sea.</head>
<para id="p35">And be it further enacted That in case any Nominee shall at the time of such demand be resident in Scotland
or beyond the Seas and any one or more of the Barons of the Exchequer for the time being shall certifie
that upon proof to him or them made (which Proof he and they is [&amp; are hereby authorized &amp;<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] required to
take in a summary way) it doth seem probable to him or them that the said Nominee is liveing (which Certificate
is to be given and examination made without any fee or charge the said Certificate being filed as aforesaid shall
be a sufficient Warrant for the payment of the said Halfe yearely share to the respective Contributors their Executors
Administrators or Assignes</para>
</section>
<section id="s13">
<head>XIII. Contributor neglecting to demand, his Half-yearly Payment it goes to the rest.</head>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">Proviso</emph>.</para>
<para id="p37">And be it further enacted That in case any person who by the intent of this Act shall bee intituled to receive
any Halfe yearely payment of his share of the said Funds shall at any time neglect to demand the same in
manner as aforesaid until within twenty days before the next Halfe yearely payment shall become due he shall lose
and forfeit such Halfe yearly payment so neglected to be demanded and the same shall be divided amongst the
Contributors as if his respective Nominee had been dead and soe from time to time upon every default Provided
neverthelesse that if such Contributor shall afterwards make a demand in due time in manner aforesaid for any
following Halfe yearely payment, such Contributor shall for the future have [a<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] share of the said Funds as if such
default had not been made</para>
</section>
<section id="s14">
<head>XIV. Account of the Deaths of Nominees to be made within 20 Days of every Payment.</head>
<para id="p38">And to the intent it may appear and be ascertained upon every Halfe yearely payment unto and amongst what
persons and in what proportions the said Funds are to be distributed Be it enacted That in the said Office of
Auditor of the Receipt every Halfe year within Twenty days before the respective days of payment there shall be
made up an Account of the severall Nominees whose Deaths are come to knowledge and of the severall Contributors
who have made default in makeing demand as aforesaid that so the rest of the Contributors may have the advantage
thereof</para>
</section>
<section id="s15">
<head>XV. Contributor receiving Share after Nominee's Death, and not repaying;</head>
<para id="p39"><emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p40">And be it further enacted That if any person shall receive any one or more Halfe [yearely<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] payments of the
said Funds after the death of any Nominee for whose Life such share was payable it shall be lawful for any
Contributor to require the same to be repaid into the Receipt of the Exchequer for the benefitt of the Contributors
And in case of refusal or neglect to pay in the same within one month after such demand such person so refuseing
or neglecting shall forfeit treble the sum so received to be recovered by Action of Debt in any of Their Majesties
Courts att Westminster in the name of such Contributor who shall make the demand as aforesaid in which Action
no Essoign Protection Priveledge or Wager of Law or more than one Imparlance shall bee allowed</para>
</section>
<section id="s16">
<head>XVI. Officer of the Exchequer to execute Act without Fee.</head>
<para id="p41"><emph type="i">Such Officer offending; Penalty; Full Costs to Plaintiff in Action against such Officer; Proviso respecting Collusion</emph>.</para>
<para id="p42">And bee it further enacted for the better incourageing persons to advance the said sum of Ten hundred
thousand pounds upon the terms aforesaid That all receipts and issues and all other things directed by this Act
to be performed in the Exchequer shall be done and performed by the Officers there without demanding or receiveing
directly or indirectlie any fee gratuity or reward for the same And in case any of the Officers of the Exchequer
shall take or demand any such fee or reward or shall divert or misapply any of the said weekely sums to be
paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer for makeing upp the aforesaid Funds or shall pay or issue out the same
otherwise then according to the intent of this Act or shall not keep Books and Registers and make entries and
do and performe all other things which by this Act they are required to performe every such Officer shall forfeit
his Office and be for the future incapable of any Office or place of Trust whatsoever and shall answer and pay
treble damages with costs of Suite to every Contributor their Executors Administrators and Assignes to be recovered
by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on in any of Their Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster wherein
no Essoign Protection Priviledge of Parliament or other Priveledge Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint
or more than one Imparlance shall be granted or allowed And in the said Action the Plaintiffe upon Recovery
shall have his full Costs one third part of which sum so to be recovered shall be paid into the Receipt of the
Exchequer for the benefitt of the said Contributors and the other two third parts shall be to the use of the
Prosecutor And in case there shall bee any Collusion or faint Prosecution between the Plaintiffe and Defendant
in such Action it shall bee lawfull for any other Contributor to bring another Action wherein hee shall recover
as aforesaid to the uses aforesaid</para>
</section>
<section id="s17">
<head>XVII. Proviso for Officer paying Money upon forged Certificate, except privy.</head>
<para id="p43">Provided always and be it enacted That in case any Officer of the Exchequer shall make payment of any
share or shares of the said Funds upon such Certificate as is before directed such Officer shall not incur any
penalty forfeiture or disability or be liable to any Action of the Contributors for doing thereof although the said
Certificate be forged or false or the said Nominee be dead unlesse the said Officer did know at the time of such
payment that the said Nominee was dead or that the said Certificate was forged or false</para>
</section>
<section id="s18">
<head>XVIII. Contributor to certify Death of his Nominee, and return his Tally,</head>
<para id="p44"><emph type="i">Penalty &pound;10</emph>.</para>
<para id="p45">And be it further enacted That every Contributor his Executors Administrators or Assignes within one month
next after notice of the Death of his or their respective Nominee shall certifie such Death to the Auditor of the
Receipt of the Exchequer for the time being and shall also within three months after such notice deliver or cause
to bee delivered upp to the said Auditor his or their Tally and Order by which hee or they were or was intituled
dureing the Life of such Nominee to receive any share of the [said<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Fund in case such Tally and Order be in his
or their hands or power and in default thereof such Contributor his Executors Administrators and Assignes shall
forfeit the sum of Ten pounds to be recovered by Action of Debt as aforesaid and to bee had and received to
the use of any person who shall sue for the same</para>
</section>
<section id="s19">
<head>XIX. Credit of Loan to make up the Sum of &pound;1,000,000.</head>
<para id="p46">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if the whole sum of Ten hundred thousand pounds be not
advanced and paid into the Exchequer upon this Act before the Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand
six hundred ninety three that then it shall and may be lawfull for Their Majesties or their Officers in the Receipt
of Their Majesties Exchequer by Their Command and Appointment to borrow and take into the said Receipt
for Their Majesties use by way of Loan any Sum or Sums of Money which together with the whole value or
amount of all the Sums of money which shall before the said Foure and twentieth day of June be advanced
and paid upon the Termes and Advantage of Survivorship as aforesaid or upon the Terms hereafter in this Act
mentioned shall not exceed the Sum of Ten hundred thousand pounds Which Sum or Sums so taken upp by
way of Loans hall and may be charged upon [the<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Credit of Their Majesties Exchequer in General and Tallies of
Loan and Orders of Repayment of the same shall be leavied accordingly Which Orders shall be assigneable and
transferrable from one person to another</para>
</section>
<section id="s20">
<head>XX. &pound;7 per Cent. to Lender, and the Charge of the Principal and Interest transferred to the next Parliament Aid; and if no Aid, to next Revenue not already appropriated.</head>
<para id="p47">And it is hereby enacted That all and every Sum and Sums of money so to be borrowed not exceeding as
aforesaid together with the Interest for the same not exceeding the rate of Seaven pounds per Centum per Annum
to bee paid every three months until satisfacc[i]on of the principal or so much thereof as shall not be repaid out
of such moneys as shall be advanced upon the Terms hereafter in this Act menc[i]oned at or after the said Foure
and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety three and before the Twenty ninth day of September
next following (all which said moneys so to be advanced from and after the said Foure and twentieth day of
June and before the said Twenty ninth day of September shall be applied and appropriated and are appropriated
for the dischargeing the several Loans made upon this Act so far as the same will extend) shall be payable and
be paid or satisfied unto the respective Lender or Lenders of the same his her or their Executors Administrators
or Assignes out of any of the next Aids or Supplies to be granted to Their Majesties in Parliament and shall be
transferred and transferrable thereunto as soon as any such aid or supply shall be granted And in case no [such<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]
aid or supply shall be granted to Their Majesties before the Second day of February One thousand six hundred
ninety three then the said Sum and Sums of money so to bee borrowed not exceeding as aforesaid and the
Interest thereof or so much thereof as shall bee not repaid out of the moneys which shall be advanced before
the said Twenty ninth day of September as aforesaid shall be payable and be paid and satisfied to the said
Lender or Lenders his or their Executors Administrators or Assigns respectively by and out of any of Their
Majesties Treasure which from henceforth shall come into be or remain in the Receipt of Their Majesties
Exchequer not being already appropriated to any particular Uses by any Act or Acts of Parliament before this
time made</para>
</section>
<section id="s21">
<head>XXI. If &pound;500,000 only advanced before May, the King may borrow &pound;500,000 more, to be paid out of Money raised betwixt that time and September; if that fall short, next Aid chargeable.</head>
<para id="p48">And be it further enacted That for the better and more effectual supply of Their Majesties present Occasions
that if the Sum of Five hundred thousand pounds part of the said Sum of Ten hundred thousand pounds be
not advanced and paid into the Exchequer upon this Act before the First day of May One thousand six hundred
ninety three that then it shall and may be lawfull for Their Majesties to borrow upon Interest as aforesaid any
Sum or Sums of Money not exceeding Five hundred thousand pounds to be paid out of such other moneys as
shall be advanced upon this Act between the First day of May One thousand six hundred ninety three and the
said Twenty ninth day of September One thousand six hundred ninety three in case the money so advanced shall
be sufficient for the payment thereof or otherwise so much thereof as the same shall extend to pay And the
residue of the said Sum of Five hundred thousand pounds so taken up upon Loan which shall remain unpaid out
of the moneys advanced upon this Act as aforesaid shall be taken and reckoned as part of the said Sum before
directed to be and made payable out of any of the next Aids or Supplies to be granted to Their Majesties in
Parliament or out of Their Majesties Treasure as aforesaid</para>
</section>
<section id="s22">
<head>XXII. If the whole Sum of &pound;1,000,000 be not raised before May, Persons contributing to have the Advantage of &pound;14 per Cent for Life of the Nominee.</head>
<para id="p49"><emph type="i">Time limited for nominating Life; Commencement and times of Payment of Annuities; Lenders to have Tally and Order for Payment; Orders assignable; Monies raised appropriated to Payment of the &pound;14 per Cent. and not divertible.
Penalty; Officers to keep Books, &amp;c; without Fee; Access to Books; Interest after the Rate of &pound;10 per Cent. allowed till September</emph>.</para>
<para id="p50">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in case the whole Sum of Ten hundred thousand
Pounds shall not be advanced by the said Contributors and paid into the Exchequer before the said First day of
May One thousand six hundred ninety and three upon the Terms and Advantage of Survivorship as aforesaid
that then it shall and may be lawfull to and for any person or persons Natives or Foreigners after the said First
day of May One thousand six hundred ninety three and before the Nine and twentieth day of September then
next following to advance and pay into Their Majesties Exchequer any Sum or Sums of Money not exceeding
in the whole (together with what shall have been before the said First day of May advanced by the said Contributors
as aforesaid) the said Sum of Ten hundred thousand pounds upon the Terms following that is to say That every
such person out of the Moneys ariseing by the Rates and Duties of Excise granted by this Act shall have and
receive for every Sum of One hundred Pounds by them respectively advanced and paid a yearely Annuity Rent
or Payment of Fourteen Pounds of lawfull English money (and proportionably for a greater Sum) [and<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] for and
dureing the Life of such person so advanceing or paying the same or dureing any other Life to be nominated
by the person advancing or paying any such Sum as aforesaid the same to be nominated within Six days after
payment of the said Sum Which yearely Annuities Rents or Payments shall co[m]mence from the Nine and twentieth
day of September One thousand six hundred ninety three and shall be paid and payable at the Foure most usuall
Feasts in the year that is to say at the Feasts of the Birth of our Lord Christ the Annunciac[i]on of the Blessed
Virgin Mary the Nativity of Saint John Baptist and the Feast of Saint Michael the Archangel by even and equal
portions And every person on payment of any such Sum or Sums as aforesaid shall imediately have one or
more Tally or Tallies importing the Receipt of the consideration money and orders for payment of the said
Annuities beareing [the same<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Date with the Tally the said Orders to bee signed in the same manner as is in
this Act before menc[i]oned touching Orders to be given to the before menc[i]oed Contributors and not to be
determinable revocable or countermandable as touching the before mentioned Orders is enacted Which said Orders
shall be assigneable and transferable in such and the same manner as is before mentioned touching the said Orders
given to the Contributors as aforesaid upon the Terms and Advantages in this Act first menc[i]oed And all the
moneys ariseing by the Rates and Duties hereby granted over and besides so much as shall bear proportion
after the Rates aforesaid to the whole Sum which shall be advanced by the Contributors before the said First
day of May One thousand six hundred ninety and three) are and shall be appropriated and applied and are
hereby appropriated to and for the payment of the said Annuities or yearelie Rents or Sums after the Rate of
Fourteene Pounds per Annum for every Hundred Pounds advanced as aforesaid according to the true intent and
meaning of this Act and shall not be divertible or diverted to any other use intent or purpose whatsoever under
the like Penalties Forfeitures and Disabilities in respect to all and every the Officers above mentioned as are
before appointed and enacted in case of diverting or misapplying any part of the moneys which ought to be
paid to the Contributors who are to have the advantage of survivorship as aforesaid and the said Officers respectively
are hereby required to keep Books and Registers and make Entries of the Names of all persons who shall advance
any money after the said First day of May as aforesaid and of the several sums so advanced and the times of
paying in the same respectively and the Names of such Persons for whose Lives the several Annuities and
yearely payments are to be payable without Fee or Reward as aforesaid (to which Books all Persons concerned
shall have accesse as aforesaid) All which the said Officers are to do and performe under the like penalties
and forfeitures and disabilities as aforesaid And every Person who shall advance and pay any such Sum as
aforesaid after the said First day of May shall receive out of the money granted by this Act for all moneys
by him so advanced and paid from the respective Days of payment unto the said Nine and twentieth day of
September One thousand six hundred ninety three Interest for the same att the rate of Ten Pounds per Centum
per Annum.</para>
</section>
<section id="s23">
<head>XXIII. Persons contributing upon Sur-vivorship may change it into an Annuity of &pound;14 per Cent. for Life.</head>
<para id="p51"><emph type="i">Memorial thereof, and thereupon Contributor to receive his Annuity</emph>.</para>
<para id="p52">Provided also and be it enacted That if any Contributor who on or before the said First day of May shall
have advanced any Sum or Sums of Money in respect whereof such Contributor shall be entituled to have a
proportionable share of the said yearely Funds with the benefitts of Survivorship as aforesaid shall at any time
after the said First day of May and before the said Nine and twentieth day of September be minded or desirous
(in lieu and satisfacc[i]on of such proportionable share of the said Funds with such benefitts of Survivorship) to
have an yearelie Annuitie Rent or Payment of Fourteen Pounds of lawfull English money for every or any
Sum of One hundred Pounds by such Contributor so advanced to be paid dureing the Life of his her or their
Nominee before menc[i]oed and shall signifie such desire to the said Auditor of the Receipt or the Clerk of the Pells
for the time being that then the said Auditor of the Receipt or Clerk of the Pells shall cause an Entry or
Memorial thereof to be made in a Book or Books for this purpose to be kept in the said Receipt And the
said Entry or Memorial being signed by the said Contributor such Contributor his Executors Administrators and
Assignes dureing the Life of the said Nominee (whether such Nominee shall bee the Contributor or any other
person shall have and receive for every Sum of One hundred Pounds which shall have been so advanced a
yearely Annuitie Rent or Payment of Foureteen Pounds as aforesaid at the Foure Feasts aforesaid by equal
Portions in such manner and with such and the same advantags as if such. Contributor had originally paid in the
moneys by him advanced after the said First day of May One thousand six hundred ninety three</para>
</section>
<section id="s24">
<head>XXIV. Proviso for their Majesties advantage of Survivorship.</head>
<para id="p53">Provided always That after such Entry or Memorial shall bee made in the said Book or Books and signed
by the Contributor as aforesaid all further Payments which should grow due to such Contributor for his proportionable
part of the said yearely Funds shall cease and determine for Their Majesties benefitt Any thing in this Act
contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s25">
<head>XXV. Annual Surplus Money of Duties given to Their Majesties.</head>
<para id="p54">And be it further enacted That in case there shall be any surplus or remainder of the moneys ariseing by
the Rates and Duties granted by this Act at the end of any year dureing the said Terme of Ninety nine years
after all the said several proportions of the said yearely Funds and all and every the Annuities Rents and yearely
Payments and all Interest payable by this Act shall be fully satisfied paid and discharged such surplus or remainder
shall bee to the use of Their Majesties Their Heires and Successors</para>
</section>
<section id="s26">
<head>XXVI. Money lent Tax free.</head>
<para id="p55">And be it further enacted That any moneys lent by or payable to any person or persons upon or by virtue
of this Act shall not be charged or chargeable with any Rates Duties or Impositions whatsoever</para>
</section>
<section id="s27">
<head>XXVII. Grants of Duties to other Uses, &amp;c. void.</head>
<para id="p56">Provided always and it is hereby further declared and enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Grants
or Dispositions of any of the moneys ariseing or which shall be collected by the Authority of this Act hereafter
to bee made by Their [Majesties<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Their Heires or Successors to any other person or persons or in any other manner
or for any longer Terme or Interest then by this Act is appointed shall be and are hereby declared null and void
to all intents and purposes whatsoever</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n5" number="5">his <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n8" number="8"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


