<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46374" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act for granting to Their Majesties certain additional Impositions upon several Goods and Merchandize. for the prosecuting the present War against France [Rot. Parl. pt. 2. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>Certain Duties wanted.</head>
<para id="p1">Wee your Majesties most dutiful and loyal Subjects the Co[m]mons assembled in Parliament for a further
supply of your Majesties extraordinary occasions and the effectual Prosecution of the War against France
have cheerfully and unanimously given and granted and do hereby give [&amp;<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] grant unto your Majesties the
additional and other Rates Impositions Duties and Charges upon the several sorts of Goods and Merchandize to
be imported into the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed or from
thence exported as herein after expressed dureing such time and in such manner and forme as hereinafter
followeth And do humbly pray your Majesties that it may be enacted and be it enacted by the King and
Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporal and
Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That there shall be answered and
paid to their Majesties and their Successors for the several Goods and Merchandizes hereafter mentioned over
and above all Impositions Duties and Charges already imposed and payable upon and for the same in the Book
of Rates of Merchandize by Act of Parliament estalished and the direction therein contained or otherwise the
further Rates and Duties following (that is to say)</para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">Amber Beads.</emph></para>
<para id="p3">For every Hundred pounds value of Amber Beads imported after the First day of March One thousand six
hundred ninety two and before the First day of March One thousand six hundred ninety six Twenty pounds
more then the same are charged within the said Book of Rates and so proportionably for a greater or lesser
quantity</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">Amber Rough.</emph></para>
<para id="p5">For Amber Rough imported within the time aforesaid Ten pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then
the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">Amber Oil.</emph></para>
<para id="p7">For Amber Oyl or Oyl of Amber imported within the time aforesaid Ten pounds for every Hundred pounds
value more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or
lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">Anchovies.</emph></para>
<para id="p9">For Anchovies the little Barrel not exceeding Sixteen pounds of Fish imported within the said time for every
Hundred pounds value Five pounds more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in
proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">Ashes.</emph></para>
<para id="p11">For Ashes called Wood Weed or Soap Ashes imported within the said time Six shillings the last more [then<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the
same is charged with in the said Book of Rates</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">Barbers' Aprons, &amp;c.</emph></para>
<para id="p13">For Barbers Aprons and Checques imported within the said time Eight pence the piece each more then the
same are charged within the said Book of Rates</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">Battery, &amp;c.</emph></para>
<para id="p15">For every Hundred weight of Battery Bashrones or Kettles (containing One hundred and twelve pounds) imported
within the said time Five shillings more then the same are charged within the said Book of Rates and so in
proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">Battery Mettle.</emph></para>
<para id="p17">For every Hundred weight (conteyning One hundred and twelve pounds) of Mettle prepared for Battery imported
within the said time Five shillings more then now is paid for the same by the said Book of Rates and soe in
proportion as aforesaid.</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">Books unbound.</emph></para>
<para id="p19">For every Hundred weight of Books unbound (conteyning One hundred and twelve pounds) imported within
the said time Foure shillings more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and soe in proportion
as aforesaid.</para>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">Lamp Black.</emph></para>
<para id="p21">For Black called Lamp Black imported within the said time Twenty pounds for every Hundred pounds
value more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and soe in proportion for any greater or
lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">Boultel Reins.</emph></para>
<para id="p23">For Boultel Reins imported within the said time Ten pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the
same is charged within the said Book of Rates and soe in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity.</para>
<para id="p24"><emph type="i">Bracelets, &amp;c. of Glass.</emph></para>
<para id="p25">For every Gross of Bracelets or Necklaces of Glasse imported within the said time Two shillings and six
pence more then the same are charged within the said Book of Rates or by any other Statute now in
force.</para>
<para id="p26"><emph type="i">Brass wrought.</emph></para>
<para id="p27">For Brasse wrought imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the
same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for a greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p28"><emph type="i">Buckrams.</emph></para>
<para id="p29">For Buckrums imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the
same are charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity.</para>
<para id="p30"><emph type="i">Hair Buttons.</emph></para>
<para id="p31">For Buttons of Hair imported within the said time Ten pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then
the same are charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p32"><emph type="i">Bristles dressed and undressed.</emph></para>
<para id="p33">For Bristles drest and undrest imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value
more then the same are charged within the said Book of Rates and soe in proportion for any greater or
lesser quantity.</para>
<para id="p34"><emph type="i">Bacon.</emph></para>
<para id="p35">For every pound of Bacon imported within the said time Foure pence</para>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">Calves Skins.</emph></para>
<para id="p37">For Calves Skins imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then
the same are charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p38"><emph type="i">Carpets.</emph></para>
<para id="p39">For Carpets of all sorts imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then
the same are charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p40"><emph type="i">Catlings and Lutestrings.</emph></para>
<para id="p41">For every Grosse of Catlings and Lustrings imported within the said time Eighteen pence the Gross more
then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p42"><emph type="i">Scotch Coals.</emph></para>
<para id="p43">For Coals Scotch imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the
same are charged with in the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p44"><emph type="i">Walking Canes.</emph></para>
<para id="p45">For every Thousand of Canes called Walking Canes imported within the said time Five and twenty shillings
more then is now paid for the same and soe in proportion as aforesaid.</para>
<para id="p46"><emph type="i">Rattans.</emph></para>
<para id="p47">For Canes called Rattans imported within the said time Five shillings the thousand more then is now paid for
the same and soe in proportion as aforesaid.</para>
<para id="p48"><emph type="i">Copper.</emph></para>
<para id="p49">For every Hundred weight of Copper called Rose Brick Copper Coyne and all Cast Copper (containing One
hundred and twelve pounds) imported within the said time Seven shillings and six pence more then the same is
charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p50"><emph type="i">Copper Plates, &amp;c.</emph></para>
<para id="p51">For every Hundred weight of Copper part wrought as Plates Bars Rods or raised (containing One hundred and
twelve pounds imported within the said time Twelve shillings six pence more then is now paid for the same
and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p52"><emph type="i">Copper wrought.</emph></para>
<para id="p53">For every Hundred weight of Copper fully wrought (containing One hundred and twelve pounds) imported
within the said time Seventeen shillings and six pence more then is now paid for the same and so in proportion
as aforesaid</para>
<para id="p54"><emph type="i">Coral Beads and polished Coral.</emph></para>
<para id="p55">For Coral Beads and all polished Coral imported within the said time Twenty pounds for every Hundred
pounds value more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and soe in proportion for any greater
or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p56"><emph type="i">Certain Cotton Manufactures, except Dimities.</emph></para>
<para id="p57">For all Manufactures of Cotton only (except Dimity) not brought from East India or China imported within
the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the same are charged within the said
Book of Rates and so in proportion for [a<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p58"><emph type="i">Couries.</emph></para>
<para id="p59">For every Hundred pounds value of Couries imported within the said time Ten pounds more then is now paid
for the same and so in proportion as aforesaid</para>
<para id="p60"><emph type="i">Elephants Teeth.</emph></para>
<para id="p61">For Elephants Teeth imported within the said time Ten pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then
the same are charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p62"><emph type="i">Flax rough.</emph></para>
<para id="p63">For Flax Rough imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the
same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p64"><emph type="i">Flax wrought.</emph></para>
<para id="p65">For Flax dressed or wrought imported within the said time Fifteen pounds for every Hundred pounds value
more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and soe in proportion for any greater or lesser
quantity</para>
<para id="p66"><emph type="i">Tow.</emph></para>
<para id="p67">For every Hundred pounds value of Tow imported within the said time Five pounds more then the same is
charged with as aforesaid and so in proportion as aforesaid</para>
<para id="p68"><emph type="i">Flannel.</emph></para>
<para id="p69">For every Yard of Flannel imported within the said time Two pence more then the same is charged within
the said Book of Rates.</para>
<para id="p70"><emph type="i">Frieze.</emph></para>
<para id="p71">For every Yard of Frieze imported within the said time Three pence halfe-penny more then the same is charged
within the said Book of Rates</para>
<para id="p72"><emph type="i">Furs.</emph></para>
<para id="p73">For every Hundred pounds value of Furs of all sorts imported within the said time Five pounds more then
the same are charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p74"><emph type="i">Gold and Silver Thread and Wire.</emph></para>
<para id="p75">For Gold and Silver Thread and Wire Counterfeit imported within the said time Five pounds for every
Hundred pounds value more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and soe in proportion for
any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p76"><emph type="i">Carmenia Wool.</emph></para>
<para id="p77">For every pound of Goats Hair called Carmenia Wool imported within the said time Fowre pence more then
the same is charged within the said Book of Rates</para>
<para id="p78"><emph type="i">Goats Hair, common.</emph></para>
<para id="p79">For every Pound of Goats Hair of any other sort imported within the said time Two pence more then the
same is charged within the said Book of Rates</para>
<para id="p80"><emph type="i">Hides dressed and undressed, (Exception.)</emph></para>
<para id="p81">For Hides of all sorts dressed and undressed (except Buff and Losh) imported within the said time Five pounds
for every Hundred pounds value more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in
proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p82"><emph type="i">Buff Hide.</emph></para>
<para id="p83">For every Buff Hide imported within the said time Two shillings more then the same is charged within the
said Book of Rates.</para>
<para id="p84"><emph type="i">Losh Hide.</emph></para>
<para id="p85">For every Losh Hide imported within the said time One shilling more then the same is charged within the
said Book of Rates</para>
<para id="p86"><emph type="i">Hemp Rough.</emph></para>
<para id="p87">For Hemp Rough imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the
same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p88"><emph type="i">Diamonds, &amp;c. Value on Oath.</emph></para>
<para id="p89">For Diamonds Pearls Rubies Emeraulds and all other Jewels and precious Stones imported within the said
time Twenty shillings for every Hundred pounds value to be affirmed by the Oath of the Importer in lieu of
all Impositions and Duties now payable for the same and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity.</para>
<para id="p90"><emph type="i">Foreign Indigo.</emph></para>
<para id="p91">For every Pound of Indico of Forreigne Plantation not being of the growth of any of the Dominions or
Plantations belonging to the Crowne of England imported within the said time Fowre pence more then the same
is charged within the said Book of Rates</para>
<para id="p92"><emph type="i">Plantation Indigo.</emph></para>
<para id="p93">For every Pound of Indico of the growth of the Dominions or Plantations belonging to the Crowne of England
imported within the said time Two pence more then the same is charged with in the said Book of Rates</para>
<para id="p94"><emph type="i">Iron Wares from Ireland; The Duties thereon collected as by 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 4</emph>.</para>
<para id="p95">For all Iron [Iron<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Potts Kettles Backs for Chimneys Iron slit or hammerd into Rods Frying-pans Anvils wrought
single white and black Plates double white and black Plates and all other Iron Wares imported from Ireland
within the said time the same respective Duties as are laid on Iron and Iron Wares imported from any Foreigne
Part by one Act made in the Second yeare of their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for granting to their
Majesties certain Impositions upon all East India Goods and Manufactures and upon all wrought Silks and several
other Goods and Merchandizes to be imported after the Five and twentieth day of December One thousand six
hundred and ninety</para>
<para id="p96"><emph type="i">Shaven and Black Lattin and Round Bottoms.</emph></para>
<para id="p97">For Lattin shaven black Lattin and round Bottoms imported within the said time Ten pounds for every
Hundred pounds value more then the same are charged within the said Book of Rates and soe in proportion for
for any greater or lesser Quantity</para>
<para id="p98"><emph type="i">Leather.</emph></para>
<para id="p99">For Leather of all Sorts imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more
then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and soe in proportion for any greater or lesser
Quantity</para>
<para id="p100"><emph type="i">Lime and Lemon Juice.</emph></para>
<para id="p101">For all Lime and Lemmon Juice imported within the said time twenty pounds for every Hundred pounds value
more then the same are charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser
quantity</para>
<para id="p102"><emph type="i">Litmus.</emph></para>
<para id="p103">For Litmus imported within the same time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the same is
charged within the said Book of Rates and soe in proportion as aforesaid.</para>
<para id="p104"><emph type="i">Lapis Calaminaris.</emph></para>
<para id="p105">For all Lapis Calaminaris exported within the said time Twenty shillings for every Tun over and above all other
Duties payable for the same and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity(<ref idref="n4">4</ref>).</para>
<para id="p106"><emph type="i">Madder.</emph></para>
<para id="p107">For Madder of all sorts imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then
the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity.</para>
<para id="p108"><emph type="i">Orchal.</emph></para>
<para id="p109">For Orchal imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value thereof more then the
same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion as aforesaid</para>
<para id="p110"><emph type="i">Pintadoes, per &pound;100.&pound;5.</emph></para>
<para id="p111">For Pintadoes or Calico Cupboard Cloaths imported within the said time and not brought from East India or
China Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the same are charged within the said Book of
Rates and soe in proportion as aforesaid.</para>
<para id="p112"><emph type="i">Pitch.</emph></para>
<para id="p113">For Pitch imported within the said time not being of the product of any of the Dominions or Plantations of
the Crowne of England or Scotland one moiety more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates.</para>
<para id="p114"><emph type="i">Silver Plate, gilt or ungilt.</emph></para>
<para id="p115">For all sorts of Plate of Silver guilt or unguilt imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred
pounds value more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any
greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p116"><emph type="i">Rice.</emph></para>
<para id="p117">For Rice imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the same is
charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p118"><emph type="i">Rozin; Exception</emph>.</para>
<para id="p119">For Rozin of all sorts imported within the said time (except French Rozin) not being of the product of any of
the Dominions or Plantations belonging to the Crowne of England or Scotland Ten pounds for every Hundred
pounds value more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion as
aforesaid</para>
<para id="p120"><emph type="i">Salt; Exception</emph>.</para>
<para id="p121">For every Weigh of Salt imported within the said time (except such Salt as shall be used in curing of Fish)
Five shillings more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater
or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p122"><emph type="i">Thrown Silk.</emph></para>
<para id="p123">For Silk Thrown of all sorts into the Gum imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds
value more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and soe in proportion for any greater or
lesser quantity.</para>
<para id="p124"><emph type="i">Wrought Silk; Exception.; 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 4</emph>.</para>
<para id="p125">For every Pound of Silk Wrought other then Alamodes and Lustrings imported within the said time Two
shillings more then the same is charged with in the said Book of Rates or by an Act of this present Parliament
made in the Second yeare of their Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for granting to their Majesties certain Impositions
upon all East-India Goods and Manufactures and upon all Wrought Silks and several other Goods and Merchandize
to be imported after the Five and twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred ninety</para>
<para id="p126"><emph type="i">Silk Ferret.</emph></para>
<para id="p127">For Silk Ferret or Floret imported within the said time One moiety more then the same is charged within
the said Book of Rates.</para>
<para id="p128"><emph type="i">Skins.</emph></para>
<para id="p129">For Skins of all sorts imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then
the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity.</para>
<para id="p130"><emph type="i">Tar.</emph></para>
<para id="p131">For all Tarr imported within the said time not being of the product of any of the Dominions or Plantations
belonging to the Crowne of England or Scotland one moiety more then the same is charged within the said
Book of Rates.</para>
<para id="p132"><emph type="i">Tick and Ticking.</emph></para>
<para id="p133">For Ticks [or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Tickings (except Scotish Ticks and Tickings) imported within the said time Five pounds for every
Hundred pounds value more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for
any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p134"><emph type="i">Thread Outnel.</emph></para>
<para id="p135">For every dozen pounds of Thread Outnell imported within the said time Foure shillings more then the same
is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p136"><emph type="i">Tapistry and Dornix; Exception</emph>.</para>
<para id="p137">For all Tapistry and Dornix imported within the said time (except such as are manufactured in or brought from
any part of the French Kings Dominions) Ten pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the same
is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity.</para>
<para id="p138"><emph type="i">Inkle.</emph></para>
<para id="p139">For all [wrought<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Inckle imported within the said time one Moiety more then what is now paid for the
same</para>
<para id="p140"><emph type="i">Pan Tiles.</emph></para>
<para id="p141">For all Pan-Tiles imported within the said time Eight shillings the thousand more then the same are charged
within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion as aforesaid.</para>
<para id="p142"><emph type="i">Dying Wood; Exception</emph>.</para>
<para id="p143">For all sorts of Dying Wood imported within the said time (except Red Wood from Guiney Drugs and
Logwood) Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then the same are charged within the said Book
of Rates and soe in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity.</para>
<para id="p144"><emph type="i">Bees Wax.</emph></para>
<para id="p145">For all Wax called Bees Wax imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value
more then the same is charged within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser
quantity</para>
<para id="p146"><emph type="i">French Wine.</emph></para>
<para id="p147">For every Tun of French Wine imported within the said time Eight pounds above all Duties already charged
thereupon in the [said<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Book of Rates or by any other Law and soe in proportion for any greater or lesser
quantity.</para>
<para id="p148"><emph type="i">French Goods, per &pound;100. &pound;25.</emph></para>
<para id="p149">Upon all French Goods and Merchandize (except Wine Brandy Salt and Vinegar) which shall be imported within
the said time Five and twenty pounds for every Hundred pounds value thereof more then the same are charged
within the said Book of Rates and so in proportion for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
<para id="p150"><emph type="i">Alamodes and Lutestrings.</emph></para>
<para id="p151">For all Silks called Alamodes and Lustrings imported within the said time from any Ports or Places whatsoever
Fifteen pounds for every Hundred pounds value more then is paid for the same by any Law now in force.</para>
<para id="p152"><emph type="i">Lattin, Brass and Copper Wire.</emph></para>
<para id="p153">For all Lattin Brasse or Copper Wire imported within the said time Six shillings the Hundred weight (containing
one Hundred and twelve pounds) above all other Duties payable for the same</para>
<para id="p154"><emph type="i">Goods not in the Book of Rates; Exception; 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c 4</emph>.</para>
<para id="p155">Upon all Goods and Merchandizes not particularly rated in the said Book of Rates paying Duty at value
imported within the said time Five pounds for every Hundred pounds value thereof to be affirmed upon the Oath
of the Importer according to the direction of the said Book of Rates (except Mum and such Goods and
Merchandizes as are particularly charged by this Act or an Act of this present Parliament entituled An Act for
granting to their Majesties certain Impositions upon all East-India Goods and Manufactures and upon all Wrought
Silks and several other Goods and Merchandizes to be imported after the Five and twentieth day of December
One thousand six hundred and ninety</para>
<para id="p156"><emph type="i">Brandy, single.</emph></para>
<para id="p157">For every Gallon of Strong Water Aqua vite or Brandy commonly called single Brandy or Strong Waters imported
within the said time to be paid by the Importer before Landing Two shillings over and above the Duties of Excise
and Customs at any time before the Second yeare of their Majesties Reigne payable for the same</para>
<para id="p158"><emph type="i">Brandy, double.</emph></para>
<para id="p159">For every Gallon of Strong Waters Spirits or Brandy above Proof called double Brandy imported within the said
time to be paid by the Importer before landing Foure shillings over and above the Duties of Excise and Customs
at any time before the second yeare of their Majesties Reigne payable for the same</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Duty upon Brandy, 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 10. made to cease.</head>
<para id="p160">And whereas by one Act made in the Second year of their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for granting to
Their Majesties several additional Duties of Excise upon Beer Ale and other Liquors (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) dureing the space of one
year doth expire It is amongst other things enacted that for every Gallon of single Brandy Spirits or Aqua vite
imported from beyond the Seas should be paid by the Importer before landing over and above the Duties payable
for the same Foure shillings And for every Gallon of Brandy Spirits or Aqua vite above proof comonly called
double Brandy imported from beyond the Seas should be paid by the Importer before landing over and above
the Duties payable for the same Eight shillings Be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said two
Clauses last recited in the said Act menc[i]oed concerning single Brandy Spirits or Aqua vite and Brandy Spirits
or Aqua vite above Proof called double Brandy are and shall be from the First day of March One thousand six
hundred ninety two repealed Any thing in the said last mentioned Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. The aforesaid Rates collected as by 12 Car. II. c. 4.</head>
<para id="p161"><emph type="i">Exception</emph>.</para>
<para id="p162">Provided always and be it enacted That the several Rates and Impositions hereby imposed upon the respective
Goods and Merchandizes aforesaid shall be collected and paid according to the respective Rates and Proportions
herein expressed and be raised leavied collected and paid unto their Majesties dureing the time before mentioned
except where it is otherwise hereby directed in the same manner and forme and by such rules means and ways
and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are menc[i]oed and expressed in one Act of Parliament made in the
Twelfth yeare of the Reigne of King Charles the Second entituled A Subsidy granted to the King of Tonnage
and Poundage and other Sums of Money payable upon Merchandize exported and imported and the Rules
Directions and Orders thereunto annexed or any other Law now in force relateing to the collection of their
Majesties Customes which said Act and Acts and every Article Rule and Clause therein contained shall stand and
be in force for the purposes aforesaid dureing the continuance of this Act.</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>IV. Rates upon Brandy collected as by</head>
<para id="p163"><emph type="i">12 Car. II. c. 24; 15 Car. II. c. 11</emph>.</para>
<para id="p164">And be it further enacted That the several Rates and Duties upon Strong Water Aqua vite or Brandy
comonly called single Brandy or Strong Water and upon (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) Water Spirits or Brandy above Proof called double
Brandy shall be raised levied collected and paid unto their Majesties their Heires and Successors dureing the
time before mentioned in the same manner and forme and by such rules means and ways and under such
Penalties and Forfeitures as are mentioned expressed and directed in one Act of Parliament made in the Twelfth
yeare of the Reign of the late King Charles the Second entituled An Act for taking away the Court of Wards and
Liveries and Tenures in Capite and by Knights Service and Purveyance and for settling a Revenue upon His
Majestie in lieu thereof And alsoe in another Act of Parliament, made in the Fifteenth yeare of his Reigne
entituled An additional Act for the better ordering and collecting the Duty of Excise and preventing the Abuses
therein or in either of them or in any other Law now in force relateing to the Revenue of Excise.</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>V. Merchant to give Security to pay in a Year's time, or &pound;10 per Cent. rebated for present Payment.</head>
<para id="p165"><emph type="i">Proviso for Re-exportation; Rebate to Exporter of Amber Beads, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p166">And be it further enacted That for all additional Duties hereby imposed upon the aforementioned Goods and
Merchandize to be imported as aforesaid the Importer giving Security at the Custom House shall have time not
exceeding Twelve months for the Payment of the same from the Importation to be paid by Four equal and
quarterly Payments or in case such Importer shall pay ready money he shall have after the Rate of Ten Pounds
per Centum of the said Duty for a year abated to him and if the Goods and Merchandizes aforementioned
imported as aforesaid for which the Duties hereby granted paid or secured at the Importation thereof be again
exported by any Merchant English within Twelve months or by Strangers within Nine months after the Importation
then the aforesaid Duty shall be wholly repaid or the Security vacated as to what shall be so exported except all
Brandy for which the aforesaid Duty shall not be repaid Provided neverthelesse that the several Duties charged
by this Act upon all Amber Beads Amber Ruff Coral Beads and Polished Coral and all Cowries shall be repaid
to the Merchant exporting the same within Three years after the Importation thereof Any thing in this Act
contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>VI. Importing Brandy in Vessels not containing 60 Gallons;</head>
<para id="p167"><emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p168">And for preventing the Frauds frequently used in importing of Strong Water Spirits Aqua vite or Brandy in
small quantities whereby the same is more easily conveyed away without payment of the Duties thereof Be it
Enacted That from and after the Five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety three no
Brandy single or double shall be imported from parts beyond the Seas in any Vessel or Cask which shall not
contain Sixty Gallons at the least upon payne of forfeiting the said Brandy or the value thereof so to be imported
as aforesaid whereof one halfe shall be to their Majesties and the other halfe to such Persons as shall informe or
sue for the same to be recovered of the Importer or Proprietor thereof by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or
Information in any of their Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster wherein no Essoign Wager of Law or
Protection shall be allowed nor any more then one Imparlance.</para>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>VII. Separate Account of Duties, and paid weekly into Exchequer;</head>
<para id="p169"><emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p170">And be it further enacted That all and every the Officer and Officers who shall be concerned in levying the
Duties ariseing by this Act do keep a separate and distinct accompt thereof and pay the same in specie into their
Majesties Exchequer weekly and upon neglect and refusal of the same every Officer offending shall be forejudged
from and shall forfeit his Place or Office.</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>VIII. Recital of 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 4.</head>
<para id="p171"><emph type="i">Additional Duty on Raisins and Currants imported</emph>.</para>
<para id="p172">And whereas by the said Act entituled An Act for granting to their Majesties certain Impositions on all East India
Goods and Merchandize and upon all wrought Silks and upon several other Goods and Merchandize to be
imported after the Five and twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred and ninety the Sum of Ten Pounds
is imposed on every Hundred Pounds value of Grocery Ware and Druggs wherein the several sorts of Raisins
mentioned in the said Book of Rates, are included, and likewise the Sum of Five Pounds for every Hundred
Pounds value of Currants which is found by experience to lessen the Importation thereof Wherefore for remedy
thereof and the incouragement of Merchants to import the said Goods Be it enacted That from and after the
Five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety and three and thenceforth dureing the continuance
of the said Act the Sum of Five Pounds only shall be paid for every Hundred Pounds value of Raisins of any
sort to be imported after the said time over and above the Rates thereon charged in the said Book of Rates And
Fifty Shillings and no more for every Hundred Pounds value of Currants imported after the said time and
thenceforth dureing the continuance of the last mentioned Act over and above the Rates charged thereon in the
said Book of Rates (the said Act or any thing therein contained to the contrary notwithstanding the same to be
collected as in and by the said Act is directed and appointed</para>
</section>
<section id="s9">
<head>IX. The Length and Breadth of Calico settled;</head>
<para id="p173"><emph type="i">and Duty paid accordingly</emph>.</para>
<para id="p174">And whereas by the said Book of Rates a value is imposed on every Piece of Calico without mention of the
length whereof such Piece should consist Be it further enacted That noe piece of Calico imported from and after
the First day of March One thousand six hundred ninety two dureing the continuance of the said last recited Act
of the breadth of One yard and a quarter or under shall exceed in length Ten yards And no piece of Calico
imported after the said time dureing the continuance of the said Act above that breadth shall exceed Six yards
And if any piece of Calico shall exceed those lengths the same shall be rated according to the respective length
of Ten yards and Six yards for each piece and pay for the same in that proportion for a greater or lesser
Quantity according to the Sum rated upon each piece of Calico in the said Book of Rates And that the Subsidy
as well as the additional Duties upon Calicoes by the said last recited Act appointed shall be collected and paid
according to that Admeasurement of each peece of Calico so imported from and after the said time and not
otherwise Any thing in the said Book of Rates or in the said Act to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>X. Measure of East-Country-Linen.</head>
<para id="p175">And for the better ascertaining explaining and settling the Measures of East Countrey Linen Be it enacted that all
Linen of Prussia Polonia or any part of the East Countrey (except Russia) above the breadth of three quarters
and halfe quarter of a yard shall pay as broad Germany Linen dureing the continuance of the said last recited Act
And all Whited Hinderlands from the same Countries under that breadth shall pay dureing the said time as
Narrow East Countrey Linen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s11">
<head>XI. 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 6. recited.</head>
<para id="p176"><emph type="i">The present Duty on Coffee and Cocoa imported</emph>.</para>
<para id="p177">And whereas by one Act made in the First year of their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for the charging
and collecting the Duties upon Coffee Tea and Chocolate at the Custom House it is enacted That from and after
the Five and twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred eighty nine Five Pounds and twelve shillings
shall be paid for every Hundred Weight of Coffee imported into any parts within this Kingdom Dominion of
Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed (accounting One hundred and twelve Pounds to the Hundred Weight
over and besides what was then paid or payable for the same at the Custom House And for every Hundred
Weight of Cocoa Nuts imported and containing as aforesaid Eight Pounds and eight Shillings over and besides
what was then paid for the same at the Custom House And for every Pound weight of Tea imported Five
Shillings And for every Pound Weight of Chocolate ready made Five Shillings over and besides what was then
charged on Tea or Chocolate respectively at the Custom House which Duties are so excessive that few of the said
Goods or Merchandize have been entred at the Custom House since the makeing of the said Act or any Duty
answered to their Majesties for the same. Wherefore for reduceing the said Duties to a more reasonable Rate and
Imposition for the incouragement and advancement of Trade and the greater Importation of the said respective
Goods and Merchandizes be it enacted That from and after the said Five and twentieth day of March One
thousand six hundred ninety and three there shall be answered and paid [unto<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] their Majesties for every Hundred
Weight of Coffee imported containing as aforesaid dureing the continuance of the said last mentioned Act the Sum
of Six and fifty Shillings and no more And for ever Pound of Cocao Nuts imported from any of the Dominions
or Plantations belonging to the Crowne of England after the said time during the continuance of the said Act the
Sum of six pence and no more and from any other Countreys or Places after the said time dureing the continuance
of the said Act Eight pence And for every Pound of Tea imported after the said time from any place from
which it may be by Law imported One. Shilling and no more And for every Pound weight of Chocolate ready
made imported after the time aforesaid dureing the continuance of the said Act One Shilling and no more Any
thing in the said last recited Act or any other matter or thing to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.
Provided always That the Rates and Duties hereby appointed to be paid as aforesaid for the said respective
Merchandizes of Coffee Cocoa Nuts Tea and Chocolate shall be paid and answered to their Majesties dureing
the continuance of the said Act over and above the respective Duties charged or chargeable upon every of them
in the said Book of Rates before the makeing of the said Act</para>
</section>
<section id="s12">
<head>XII. Alamodes how to be imported.</head>
<para id="p178"><emph type="i">Notice to Commissioners of Customs; License to be granted; Goods imported without Notice and License; Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p179">Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid for the better encouragement of the Manufacture
of Plain Silks called Alamodes and Lustrings in this Kingdom none of the said Foreigne Silk shall be imported
into this Kingdom after the Five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety and three but upon
Notice first given to the Commissioners or Farmors of their Majesties Customs for the time being of the quality
and quantity with marks numbers and package of such Silks so intended to be imported with the Name of the
Ship and Master or Co[m]mander on which they are to be laden and the Place into which they intend to import the
same and takeing a Licence under the Hands of the Commissioners or Farmers for the time being or any three
of them for the ladeing and importing thereof as aforesaid which Licence they are hereby authorized and required
to grant without any Fee or Reward or any other Charge to the Persons demanding the same Any Law Custom
or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding And in case any of the said Goods shall be imported without such
Notice being first given and Licence taken out as aforesaid the same shall be forfeited one Moiety thereof to
the use of their Majesties their Heires [and<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Successors and the other Moiety to him or them that shall seize or sue
for the same in any of their Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster wherein no Essoyn Priveledge Protection
or Wager of Law nor more then one Imparlance shall be allowed</para>
</section>
<section id="s13">
<head>XIII. Fee to be taken by Officers of the Customs.</head>
<para id="p180">Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Officers of the Customs shall not take or
receive from the Merchant exporting any of the Commodities chargeable by this or any other Act with any additional
Duties above what is chargeable by the Book of Rates any Fee or Reward for passing any Debenture for
repayment of the Duties to be paid back on Exportation according to the said Acts but shall only receive such
Fees as were payable for Debentures for the repayment of the halfe Subsidy according to the Book of Rates and
no more Nor shall any Fee or Reward be taken for any Oath to be administred at any Custom House upon
this Act</para>
</section>
<section id="s14">
<head>XIV. 3 W. &amp; M. c. 1. as to Collectors not being concerned in Elections, and giving Notes of their Gauges, continued.</head>
<para id="p181">And whereas by an Act made in the Third yeare of Their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for granting
to Their Majesties, certain Impositions upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for one yeare it is enacted That no
Collector Supervisor Gauger or other Officer concerned in the charging collecting or manageing the Duty of Excise
shall either by Letter Message or Word of Mouth endeavor to perswade any Elector to give or disswade any
Elector from giving his vote for any person or persons that shall be in nomination to be elected a Member or
Members of Parliament. And whereas by the [said<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Act it is further declared and enacted That true notes in
writeing of the last Gauges made or taken by the said Gaugers shall be left by them with all Brewers Makers
or Retaylers of Beer Ale or other exciseable Liquors respectively or some of their Servants at the time of their
takeing the said Gauges containing the quantity and quality of the Liquors so gauged under the several penalties
in the said Act mentioned Be it declared and enacted That the said Act so far as relates to Elections of Members
to serve in Parliament and leaving true notes in writing of the last Gauges made or taken by the said Gaugers
with the several Penalties respectively relateing thereunto be from and after the First day of March next hereby
revived and shall continue and be in force dureing the continuance of this Act and from thence to the end of
the next Session of Parliament and no longer</para>
</section>
<section id="s15">
<head>XV. Clause of Credit for &pound;510,000.</head>
<para id="p182">And be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any person or
persons Natives or Foreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate to advance and lend to Their Majesties into the Receipt
of Their Exchequer upon the credit of this Act any sum or sums of money not exceeding the sum of Five
hundred and ten thousand pounds in the whole and to have and receive for the forbearance of all such moneys
as shall be lent Interest not exceeding the rate of Eight pounds per Centum per Annum</para>
</section>
<section id="s16">
<head>XVI. Monies to be paid into the Exchequer weekly;</head>
<para id="p183"><emph type="i">How applied</emph>.</para>
<para id="p184">And be it further enacted and ordained by the authority aforesaid That all and every the Officer and
Officers who shall be concerned in the levying collecting and receiveing the Duties ariseing by this Act do keep
a separate and distinct accompt thereof and pay the same in specie into the Receipt of Their Majesties Exchequer
weekly on Wednesday in every Week unlesse it be an Holiday and then the next day after which shall not be
[an<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Holiday and upon neglect or refuseal of the same shall incur the Penalties Forfeitures Damages and Costs as
other the Officers of the Exchequer herein after menc[i]oed shall be liable to Which moneys so paid in shall [be
applied to<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] the uses hereafter mentioned in this Act and no otherwise</para>
</section>
<section id="s17">
<head>XVII. Books to be kept in the Exchequer.</head>
<para id="p185"><emph type="i">Tally of Loan to Lender, and Order and Warrant for Interest; Orders for Repayment registered according to Date of Tally, and paid in course; Monies to come in by this Act liable to satisfy such Loans; No Fee for providing or making Books, &amp;c. or for Payment of Money lent; Penalty; Punishment; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty; By Deputy; Penalty; Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller not making Payments in due Order; Penalty; How all such Penalties are to be recovered</emph>.</para>
<para id="p186">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That there shall be provided and kept in Their Majesties
Exchequer (that is to say) in the Officer of the Auditor of the Receipts one Book in which all moneys that shall
be paid into the Exchequer by vertue of this Act shall be entred and registred apart and distinct from all other
moneys paid or payable to their Majesties upon any account whatsoever And that all and every person and
persons Natives and Foreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate who shall lend any money to their Majesties upon the
credit of this Act and pay the same into the Receipt of the Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally of Loan
struck for the same and an Order for his or their repayment beareing the same date with the Talley in which
Order shall be alsoe contained a Warrant for payment of Interest for forbearance not exceeding the Rates aforesaid
for his or their consideration to be paid every three months until repayment of his or their principal And that
all Orders for repayment of money shall be registred in course according to the date of the Tally respectively
without preference of one before another And that all and every person and persons shall be paid in course
according as their Orders shall stand registred in the said Book so as that the person Native or Foreigner his or
their Executors Administrators or Assigns who shall have his her or their Order or Orders first entred in the
said Book shall be taken and accounted as the first person to be paid upon the moneys to come in by vertue
of this Act And he or they who shall have his or their Order or Orders next entred shall be taken and
accounted to be the second person to be paid and so successively &amp; in course And that the moneys [to<ref idref="n14">14</ref>]
come in by this Act shall be in the same Order liable to the satisfaction of the said respective parties their
Executors Administrators or Assigns successively without preference of one before another and not otherwise and
not to be divertible to any other use intent or purpose whatsoever And that no Fee Reward or Gratuity directly
or indirectly be demanded or taken of any of Their Majesties Subjects for provideing or makeing any such
Books Registers Entries View or Search as aforesaid or in or for the payment of money lent or the Interest as
aforesaid by any of Their Majesties Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputies on pain of payment of treble
Damags to the party grieved by the party offending with costs of Suit. Or if the Officer himselfe take or
demand any such Fee or Reward then to lose his place also And if any undue preference of one before another
shall be made either in point of registry or payment contrary to the true meaning of this Act by any such Officer
or Officers then the party offending shall be liable by Action of Debt or on the Case to pay the value of the of
the Debt Damages and Costs to the party grieved and shall be forejudged from his place or office And if such
preference be unduly made by any his Deputy or Clerk without direction or privity of his Master then such
Deputy or Clerk only shall be liable to such Action Debt Damages and Costs and shall be for ever after
uncapable of his place or office And in case the Auditor shall not direct the Order or, the Clerk of the Pells
record or the Teller make payment according to each persons due place and order as afore directed then he or
they shall be judged to forfeit and their respective Deputies and Clerks herein offending to be liable to such
Action Debt Damages and Costs in such manner as aforesaid All which said Penalties Forfeitures Damages and
Costs to be incurred by any of the Officers aforesaid or any their Deputies or Clerks shall and may be recovered
by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of their Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster wherein
no Essoign Protection Priveledge Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise granted or
allowed.</para>
</section>
<section id="s18">
<head>XVIII. Proviso for Payment of Tallies of same Date.</head>
<para id="p187"><emph type="i">Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded, no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Orders</emph>.</para>
<para id="p188">Provided always and be it hereby declared That if it happen that several Tallies of Loan or Orders for payment
as aforesaid beare date or be brought the same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be registred then it shall be
interpreted no undue preference which of those he enters first so he enters them all the same day Provided
alsoe that it shall not be interpreted any undue preference to incur any penalty in point of payment if the Auditor
direct and the Clerk of the Pells record and the Teller do pay subsequent orders of persons that come and
demand their money and bring their order before other persons that did not come to demand their money and
bring their Order in their course so as there be so much money reserved as will satisfie precedent Orders which
shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon Loan being to cease from the time the money
is so reserved and kept in Bank for them</para>
</section>
<section id="s19">
<head>XIX. Orders for Money assignable.</head>
<para id="p189"><emph type="i">Memorial without Fee; Assignee may assign</emph>.</para>
<para id="p190">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every person or persons to whom any moneys shall
be due by virtue of this Act after Order entred in the Book of Register aforesaid for payment thereof his Executors
Administrators or Assigns by indorsement of his Order may assign and transferr his Right Title Interest and Benefitt
of such Order or any part thereof to any other which being notified in the Office of the Auditor of Receipt
aforesaid and an entry or memorial thereof also made in the Book of Register aforesaid for Orders which the
Officer shall upon request without Fee or Charge accordingly make shall entitle, such Assignee his Executors
Administrators and Assigns to the benefit thereof and payment thereon And such Assignee may in like manner
assign again and so toties quoties And afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person or persons who
have or hath made such Assignments to make void release or discharge the same or any the moneys thereby
due or any part thereof.</para>
</section>
<section id="s20">
<head>XX. &pound;1,226,516 out of Monies raised by this or any other Act of this Session, except c. 1. ante, appropriated to the Navy.</head>
<para id="p191"><emph type="i">Officer misapplying Monies; Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p192">And be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That out of the money which shall be levied and paid into the
Receipt of the Exchequer as well upon Loan as otherwise by virtue of this Act or any other Act of this Session
of Parliament for granting Aids or Supplies to their Majesties other then an Act entituled An Act for granting
to Their Majesties an Aid of Foure shillings in the pound for one yeare for carrying on a vigorous War against
France the Sum of Twelve hundred twenty six thousand five hundred and sixteen pounds ten shillings shall be
applied and appropriated and is hereby appropriated to and for the payment of Officers and Seamen that have
served and shall serve in their Majesties Navy Royal and for the paying for Stores Provisions and Victuals supplied
and to be supplied for the said Navy and to and for the expences of their Majesties Office of Ordnance in respect
to Naval affairs and for other necessary uses and services performed and to be performed in and for the said Navy
and not otherwise And if any Officer any way belonging to Their Majesties Revenue or to the Exchequer Navy
or Ordnance respectively shall wittingly and wilfully divert or misapply any part of the money hereby appropriated
to any other purpose then to the uses hereby directed contrary to the true intent of this Act such Officer and
Officers so offending shall forfeit his and their Office and Place and is and are hereby disabled and made incapable
to hold or execute [any<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] said Office or any other Office whatsoever.</para>
</section>
<section id="s21">
<head>XXI. Foreign Stores sold to the Navy, not charged by this Act.</head>
<para id="p193"><emph type="i">Oath of Contract</emph>.</para>
<para id="p194">Provided neverthelesse and be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That the new or additionall Duties imposed
by this Act shall not extend to affect such Foreigne Stores as have been sold to the use of Their Majesties Navy
by contract with the Navy Board before the First day of January One thousand six hundred ninety two so as
a Certificate be given from the Co[m]missioners of the Navy that such Foreigne Stores have been so contracted for
by them for Their Majesties Service as aforesaid and so as the Importer of the same do make Oath before the
Commissioners appointed to manage the Customs which Oath they are hereby impowered to administer of the truth
of the said Contract and that he will deliver the said Goods into Their Majesties Stores pursuant to the contract
so certified by the Commissioners of the Navy.</para>
</section>
<section id="s22">
<head>XXII. An Oath to be taken by the Commissioners and Officers of the Customs.</head>
<para id="p195">And as well that the Revenue of the Customs may be more duly and regularly answered as to render the
several Imposts granted by this present Act a more effectual supply to Their Majesties be it further enacted by
the authority aforesaid That as well the Commissioners as the Patent Officers and any of their Deputies Clerks or
Servants who have or shall have any imployment in or about Their Majesties Customs shall before the Nineteenth
day of April next or att their respective admissions hereafter to such imployment take their Corporal Oaths for
the true and faithfull execution to the best of their knowledge and power of their several Trusts and Imployments
comitted to their charge and inspection and that they will not take or receive any Reward or Gratuity directly
or indirectly other then their respective Salaries and what is or shall be allowed them from the Crowne or the
regular Fees established by Law for any service done or to be done in the execution of their imployment in the
Customs upon any account whatsoever.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n4" number="4">thereof <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n5" number="5">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n6" number="6">unwrought <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n7" number="7"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
<note id="n8" number="8">for fower yeares from the time that an Act for doubling the duty of Excise upon Beer, Ale, and other Liquors O. and there does not
appear any Act with the above Title in 2 W &amp; M.</note>
<note id="n9" number="9">Strong <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n10" number="10">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n11" number="11">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n12" number="12">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n13" number="13">a <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n14" number="14">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n15" number="15">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


