<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46375" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for raising the Militia of this Kingdom for the yeare [1693] although the Months Pay formerly advanced be not repaid [Chapter VI Rot. Parl. pt. 3.nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 13 &amp; 14 (14) Car. II. c. 3. &sect; 7.</head>
		<para id="p1"><emph type="i">And that upon the Invasion by the French it was found necessary to provide Soldiers with Pay in hand, and that the like Occasion may happen again.; In case of need, Persons charged to provide Pay in hand although Pay before advanced not repaid</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act of Parliament made in the Thirteenth and Foureteenth years of the Reigne of his late
Majesty King Charles the Second entituled An Act for ordering the Forces in the several Counties of
this Kingdom it was (amongst other things) enacted that in case of Invasions Insurrections or Rebellions whereby
occasion should be to draw out the Souldiers mentioned and appointed in and by the said Act into actual service
the persons charged by the said Act with Horses Horsemen and Arms or with Foot Soldiers and Arms should
provide each their Soldier respectively with pay in hand not exceeding one months pay as should be in that
behalfe directed by the respective Lieutenants of the several Counties and in their absence or otherwise by their
direction by their Deputies or any two or more of them for repayment of which said moneys and for satisfaction
of the Officers for their pay dureing such time not exceeding one month as aforesaid as they should be with
their Souldiers in such actual Service It was thereby declared that provision should be made for the same by his
said Majesty His Heires and Successors out of his or their publick Treasury or Revenue Neverthelesse it was
thereby further provided and enacted that in case a months pay should be provided and advanced as aforesaid
that no person who should have advanced his proportion thereof should be charged with any other like months
payment until he or they should have been reimbursed the said months Pay and so from time to time the said
months Pay by him or them last before provided and advanced as aforesaid And whereas upon the invasion of
the Coasts of this Kingdom by the French it was found necessary for the publick defence and safety to draw
out the said Souldiers into actual service and to charge the said persons to provide each their Soldier respectively
with Pay in hand although the months Pay by several of them before that time provided and advanced was not
nor could not be reimbursed. And whereas the like occasion may possibly happen dureing the present War. Be
it therefore enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of
the Lords Spirituall and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled aud by the authority of the
same That if at any time before the Twenty fifth day of March which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred ninety and foure it shall be found by their Majesties to be necessary for the defence and
safety of this Kingdom to draw out the said Souldiers into actual service and the same shall be declared or signified
to the respective Lievtenants or Deputy Lievtenants and the Lord Warden of the Cinque Ports Two Ancient
Townes and their members or in his absence his Lievtenant or Lievtenants by Their Majesties it shall be lawfull
for the said Lievtenants or their Deputies or any two or more of them as aforesaid and the Lord Warden of
the Cinque Ports two Ancient Towns and their Members or in his absence his Lievtenant or Lievtenants in pursuance
of such Orders from their Majesties notwithstanding that one or more months Pay before that time advanced be
not reimbursed to raise and draw out the said Souldiers into actual service and to cause the persons charged as
aforesaid to provide each their Souldier with Pay in hand not exceeding one months Pay in such manner as if all
the Pay before that time advanced and provided had been fully reimbursed and paid.</para>
	</section>
</report>

