<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46378" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
<subtitle>Chapter IX. An Act for reviving two former Acts of Parliament for the repaireing the Highways in the County of Hertford [Rot. Parl. pt. 3.nu.4.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head></head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">15 Car. II. c. I.; 16 &amp; 17 Car. II. c. 10. recited; Toll at Wades Mill revived for 15 Years</emph></para>
<para id="p2">Whereas there was an Act of Parliament made in the Fifteenth yeare of the Reigne of our late Sovereign
Lord King Charles the Second entituled An Act for repairing the Highways within the Counties of Hertford
Cambridge and Huntingdon to be in force for the space of Eleven years from the commencement thereof And
whereas there was afterwards one other Act of Parliament made in the Sixteenth and Seventeenth years of the Reigne
of the said late King Charles the Second entituled An Act for continuance of a former Act for repairing the Highways
within the County of Hertford both which said Acts are some years past expired and the Highways within the said
County of Hertford intended by the said Acts to be repaired are since (by great Burthens and Carriages used to passe
through the same) become dangerous and impassable To the end therefore that the said Highways within the
County of Hertford being the great Roads to the North parts of this Kingdom may be sufficiently repaired and
amended by the provisions mentioned in the said Acts the same being not to be done by the ordinary course of
the Laws and Statutes of this Realme May it please Your Majesties that it may be enacted and be it enacted by
the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and
Temporal and the Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled That the Toll mentioned in the said Acts to be
taken att Wades Mill for the County of Hertford be revived sett upp and taken again in the manner by the said
Acts mentioned to continue for the space of Fifteene years from the passing of this Act and that the moneys.
thereby ariseing be imployed for the repaire of the said Highways within the said County of Hertford according
to the tenor of the said Acts</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. How Toll may cease.</head>
<para id="p3">Provided always That if the said Highways before the expiration of the said terme of Fifteen yeares be in good
and sufficient repair and an adjudication thereof be made at the Assize or General Quarter Sessions to be holden
for the said County (as is provided by the said Statutes of the Sixteenth and Seventeenth years of King Charles
the Second) the Toll shall from thenceforth cease and determine as in the said Act is directed and appointed</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. Proviso for Officers collecting as formerly.</head>
<para id="p4">And it is further enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid and the several Officers and persons impowered
in and by the said Acts to the purposes therein mentioned so far as may any ways concern or relate to the said
County of Hertford shall from henceforth have the like powers and authorities by virtue of this present Act as
they and every of them had by virtue of the said former Acts and that all Clauses Provisions Penalties Forfeitures
and Exceptions whatsoever therein mentioned concerning the collecting paying ingageing or accounting for the said
Toll att Wades Mill be from henceforth by virtue of this Act renewed and putt in execution again dureing the
continuance of this present Act as if they were herein particularly expressed and repeated</para>
</section>
</section>
</report>


