<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46371" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
	<subtitle>An Act [for] that the Inhabitants of the p[ro]vince of York may dispose of their personal Estates [by their Wills] notwithstanding the Custom of that p[ro]vince [Chapter II. Rat. Parl. pt. 2. nu.1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Persons within the Province of York may dispose by Will of all their Personal Estate.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas by custom within the Province of Yorke or other Usage the Widdows and younger Children of
p[er]sons dying Inhabitants of that Province are intituled to a part of the Goods and Chattells of their late
Husbands and Fathers (called her and their reasonable part) notwithstanding any disposic[i]on of the same by their
Husbands and Fathers last Wills and Testaments and notwithanding any Joyntures made for the livelyhood of the
said Widdows by their Husbands in their life time which are competent and according to agreement whereby many
Persons are disabled from makeing sufficient Provision for [their<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] younger Children. For remedy whereof be it enacted
by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Co[m]mons in this p[re]sent Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That from
and after the Six and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety and three it shall and may be lawfull
for any p[er]son or persons inhabiting or residing or who shall have any Goods or Chattells within the p[ro]vince of
Yorke by their last Wills and Testaments to give bequeath and dispose of all and singuler their Goods Chattells
Debts and other p[er]sonall Estate to their Executor or Executors or to such other p[er]son or p[er]sons as the said
Testator or Testators shall think fitt in as large and ample manner as by the Laws and Statutes of this Realm
any Person or Persons may give and dispose of the same within the Province of Canterbury or elsewhere And
that from and after the said Six and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety and three the
Widows Children and other the Kindred of such Testator or Testators shall be barred to claime or demand any
part of the Goods Chattels or other p[er]sonal Estate of such Testators or Testators in any other manner then as by
the said last Wills and Testaments is limitted and appointed Any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary in any
wise notwithstanding</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Widows and Children of Freemen of York and Chester.</head>
			<para id="p2">Provided always That nothing in this Act conteyned shall extend or be construed to extend to the Citizens of
the Cities of York and Chester who are or shall be Freemen of the said respective Cities inhabiting therein or
within the Suburbs thereof at the time of their Death but that every such Citizens Widdow and Children shall
and may have and enjoy such reasonable part and p[ro]portion of the Testators p[er]sonal Estate as she or they might
or ought to have had by the Custom of the p[ro]vince of York before the makeing of this Act</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

