<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46379" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for prohibiting the importation of all Forreigne Haire Buttons [Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>13 &amp; 14 (14) Car. II. c. 13. recited.</head>
<para id="p1"></para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">Reasons for passing this Act; Importing Foreign Hair Buttons; Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p3">Whereas by an Act made in the Fourteenth yeare of the Reigne of His late Majesty King Charles
the Second entituled An Act prohibiting the importation of Foreigne Bone Lace Cutwork Imbroidery Fringe
Band strings Buttons and Needle Work amongst other things in the said Act mentioned all Foreigne Buttons made
of Thread or Silk are prohibited to be imported or sold in the Kingdom of England or Dominion of Wales
And whereas since the makeing of the said Act Hair Buttons are chiefly used and worn and the Button Makers
of England do make better Haire Buttons then any are imported from Forreigne parts and are able to supply
this Kingdom with greater Quantities of them [then<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] they can make use of yet because Buttons made of Haire
are not expressly mentioned in the said Act (although they were thereby intended to be prohibited) many persons
who are Enemies to the Manufactures of this Kingdom taking advantage of the said omission do daily import such
great [Quantities<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of Hair Buttons that the Button Trade of England is very much decayed and many thousands of
poor people that were formerly kept att work in the said Trade are like to perish for want of imployment and all
the other mischiefs mentioned in the said Act which relate to the Button Trade and were thereby intended to bee
remedied are become as great as they were at the time of the makeing of the said Act For redress whereof and
the more effectual prevention of the like mischiefs for the future Be it enacted by the King and Queens most
excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual or Temporal and Commons in this
present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That from and after the Five and twentieth day of
March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and three no Forreigne Buttons made or to be
made of Hair, nor any other Forreigne Buttons whatsoever shall be imported brought in sent or conveyed into the
Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or Port or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed or bartered sold exchanged
or offered to be bartered sold or exchanged upon pain of forfeiting all the said Buttons so imported brought in
bartered sold or exchanged or offered to be bartered sold or exchanged and upon such further and other Pains
Penalties and Forfeitures as are mentioned contained and expressed in the said recited Act one moiety of all which
Forfeitures to be to the use of our Sovereigne Lord and Lady the King and Queen Their Heires and Successors and
the other moiety thereof to the person or persons that shall sue for the same in any of Their Majesties Courts of
Record by Bill Plaint Action of Debt Information or otherwise wherein no Essoign Protection or Wager of Law
shall be allowed.</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Power of Seizure to Justices of Peace.</head>
<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That for the preventing the importing bartering selling
vending or exposing to sale any Forreign Buttons whatsoever the Justices of the Peace within the Kingdom of England
Dominion of Wales or Port or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed within their several and respective Counties Cities
and Towns Corporate have the same Authority and power and the same Authority and Power is hereby given unto
the said Justices to issue forth their Warrants to seize or cause to be seized all Forreign Buttons whatsoever as by
the said Act is given unto them for the seizing of Forreigne Buttons made of thread or silk and other the manufactures
in the said Act mentioned</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


