<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46384" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for continueing certain Acts therein mencioned and for chargeing several Joynt Stocks [Chapter XV. Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Duties upon Wine and Vinegar by 1 Jac. II. c. 3. and continued by 2 W. &amp;M. Sess. 2. c. 5. continued till 24th June 1698</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee your Majesties most dutiful Subjects the Comons in Parliament assembled for a further supply to your
Majesties for the more effectual prosecuting the [p[re]sent<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] War against France have chearfully and
unanimously given and granted unto your Majesties the Impositions and Duties hereafter mentioned for and dureing
the respective Terms hereafter expressed and do beseech your Majesties to accept thereof and that it may be
enacted and be it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of
the same That the several Impositions and Duties upon Wines and Vinegar granted by an Act made in the
First year of the late King James entituled An Act for granting his Majestie an Imposition upon all Wines and
Vinegar imported between the Four and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred eighty five and the
Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety and three Which said Act by an Act of this
present Parliament made in the Second yeare of Their Majesties Reigne was continued from the Three and
twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred and ninety three until the Foure and twentieth day of June
One thousand six hundred ninety six shall be continued from the Three and twentieth day of June One thousand
six hundred and ninety six until the Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred and ninety eight
and no longer And that the said first menc[i]oed Act and all Powers Provisions Penalties Articles and Clauses
therein contained shall continue and be of full force and effect until the said Foure and twentieth day of June
One thousand six hundred and ninety eight and shall be applied practised and executed for the raiseing levying
collecting answering and paying the said Duties hereby continued according to the tenor and intent of this present
Act as fully to all intents and purposes as if all and every the Clauses Matters and Things in the said Act contained
had been again repeated in this Act and particularly enacted.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Duties upon Tobacco and Sugar by 1 Jac. II. c. 4. and continued by 2 W. &amp;M. Sess. 2. c. 5. continued as to Tobacco only till 24th June 1698.</head>
		<para id="p3">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Rates Duties and Impositions for all sorts of
Tobacco granted by an Act made in the First yeare of the Reigne of the late King James entituled An Act for
granting to His Majestie an Imposition upon all Tobacco and Sugar imported between the Foure and twentieth
day of June One thousand six hundred eighty five and the Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand six
hundred ninety three which said Act (as for and concerning the said Duties and smpositions upon Tobacco only)
by an Act of this present Parliament made in the Second yeare of Their Majesties Reign was continued from the
said Three and twentieth day of June in the said yeare One thousand six hundred ninety three vntil the Foure
and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety six shall be continued from the said Three and
twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred and ninety six until the Foure and twentieth day of June One
thousand six hundred and ninety eight and no longer And that the said Act made in the First year of the late
King James for granting the said Impositions upon Tobacco and Sugar as for and concerning Tobacco only and
all Powers Provisions Penalties Articles and Clauses therein contained concerning the said Rates and Duties upon
all sorts of Tobacco shall continue and be of full force and effect until the said Foure and twentieth day of
June One thousand six hunded and ninety eight And shall be applied practised and executed for the raiseing
levying executing answering and paying the said Duties upon Tobacco hereby continued according to the tenor
and intent of this present Act as fully to all intents and purposes as if the said Act and all and every the Clauses
Matters and Things therein particularly contained had been again repeated in this Act and particularly enacted
for this purpose.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Duties upon East India Goods, &amp;c. 2 W. &amp;M. Sess. 2. c. 4. and the said Act continued till 10th Nov. 1697.</head>
		<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the several additional and other Rates Impositions
Duties and Charges upon the several sorts of Goods and Merchandize granted by an Act of this present Parliament
made in the Second yeare of Their Majesties Reign entituled An Act for granting to Their Majesties certain
Impositions upon all East India Goods and Manufactures and upon all wrought Silks and several other Goods
and Merchandize to be imported after the Five and twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred and
ninety And which were thereby to have continuance untill the Tenth day of November One thousand six hundred
ninety five shall be continued from the ninth day of November One thousand six hundred ninety five and shall
be raised levied collected answered and paid vnto Their Majesties Their Heires and Successors vntil the Tenth day
of November One thousand six hundred ninety seven And that the said Act entituled An Act for granting to
Their Majesties certain Impositions upon all East India Goods and Manufactures and upon all wrought Silks and
several other Goods and Merchandize to be imported after the Five and twentieth day of December One thousand
six hundred and ninety and all Powers Provisions Penalties Articles and Clauses therein contained shall continue
and be of full force and effect until the said Tenth day of November One thousand six hundred ninety seven
and shall be applied practised and executed for the raiseing levying collecting answering and paying the said
Duties hereby continued according to the tenor and intent of this present Act as fully to all intents and purposes
as if the said last mentioned Act and all and every the Clauses Matters and Things therein contained had been
again repeated in this Act and enacted particularly (except only as to such part of the said Impositions touching
which other provisions or alterations are or shall be made by any other Act of this present Session of Parliament
which other provisions or alterations are to be observed and to continue dureing the continuance of this
present Act.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>III. Persons may lend Money to Their Majesties not exceeding &pound;500,000 at. &pound;8 per Cent. per. Ann.</head>
		<para id="p5">Provided always and it is hereby enacted That it shall and may lawfull to and for any person and persons
to advance and lend unto Their Majesties as well upon the security of this Act as of the several herein before
mentioned Acts from and after the several and respective sums thereupon respectively charged shall be fully
satisfied and paid any sum or sums of money not exceeding in the whole the sum of Five hundred thousand
Pounds and to have and receive for the forbearance thereof any sum not exceeding Eight pounds by the Hundred
for one whole yeare and no more directly or indirectly.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>IV. Repayment of such Monies how secured. Books provided.</head>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">Tally of Loan to Lender, and Warrant for Interest.; Orders for Repayment registered according to Date of Tally, and paid in course.; Monies to come in by this Act liable to satisfy such Loans.; No Fee for providing or making Books, &amp;c. or for Payment of Money lent.; Penalty.; Punishment.; Undue Preference by Officer, Penalty.; by Deputy, Penalty.; Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller, not making Payments in due Order.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p7">And to the end that all moneys which shall be lent unto Their Majesties upon the creditt of this Act and
of the before mentioned Acts may be well and sufficient secured out of the moneys ariseing and payable by
this Act or by any of the said before mentioned Acts from and after the several Sums charged upon the said
Acts or any of them att any time before the Fifth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety two shall
be respectively answered and paid Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That there shall be provided
and kept in Their Majesties Exchequer (that is to say) in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipts one Book or
Register in which all moneys that shall be paid into the Exchequer by vertue of this Act or any of the before
mentioned Acts shall be entred and registred apart and distinct from all moneys paid or payable to Their Majesties
vpon any other branch of Their Majesties Revenue or any other accompt whatsoever. And that all and every
person and persons who shall lend any money to Their Majesties upon the credit of this Act and pay the same
into the Receipt of the Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally of Loan struck for the same and an Order
for his Repayment bearing the same date with his Tally In which Order shall be also contained a Warrant for
payment of Interest for forbearance after the rate so to be allowed for the same so as such Interest do not
exceed the rate of Eight pounds per centum per annum for his consideration to be paid every three months vntil
repayment of his Principal And that all Orders for repayment of money shall be registred in course according to
the date of the Tally respectively without preference of one before another And that all and every person and
persons shall be paid in course according as their Orders shall stand entred in the said Register Book so as
that the person native or foreigner his Executors Administrators and Assigns who shall have his Order or Orders
first entred in the said Book of Register shall be taken and accounted as the first person to be paid vpon the
moneys to come in by virtue of this Act or any the before mentioned Acts from and after payment of the several
Sums respectively charged upon the said Acts before mentioned and he or they who shall have his or their Order
or Orders next entred shall be taken and accounted the second person to be paid and so successively and in course
And that the moneys to come in by this Act or by the said former Acts shall be in the same order liable to
the satisfaction of the said respective parties their Executors Administrators or Assigns successively without preference
of one before another and not otherwise and not to be diverted to any other use intent or purpose whatsoever
And that no Fee Reward or Gratuity directly or indirectly be demanded or taken of any of Their Majesties Subjects
for providing or makeing of any such Books Registers Entries Views or Search in or for payment of money lent
or the interest as aforesaid by any of Their Majesties Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputies upon pain of
payment of treble damages to the party greived by the party offending with Costs of Suit or if the Officer himselfe
take or demand any such Fee or Reward then to lose his place also And if any undue preference of one before
another shall be made either in point of registry or payment contrary to the true meaning of this Act by any
such Officer or Officers then the party offending shall be liable by Action of Debt or on the case to pay the
value of the Debt Damages and Costs to the party grieved and shall be forejudged from his place or office
And if such preference be unduly made by any his. Deputy or Clerk without direction or privity of his Master
then such Deputy or Clerk only shall be liable to such Action [Debt<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Damages and Costs and shall be for
ever after uncapable of his place or office And in case the Auditor shall not direct the Order or the Clerk of
the Pells Record or the Teller make payment according to each persons due place and order as afore directed
then he or they shall be judged to forfeit and their respective Deputies and Clerks herein offending to be liable
to such Action Debt Damages and Costs in such manner as aforesaid All which said Penalties Forfeitures
Damages and Costs to be incurred by any of the Officers of the Exchequer or any their Deputies or Clerks
shall and may be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on in any of Their Majesties Courts of
Record att Westminster wherein no Essoign Protection Priveledge-Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint
shall be in any wise granted or allowed.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>V. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date the same Day.</head>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded, in what case no undue Preference</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p9">Provided always and be it hereby declared That if it happen that several Tallies of Loan or Orders for
payment as aforesaid bear date or be brought the same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be registred then
it shall be interpreted no vndue preference which of those he enters first so he enters them all the same
day. Provided also That it shall not be interpreted any vndue preference to incur any penalty in point of
payment if the Auditor direct and the Clerk of the Pells record and the Tellers do pay subsequent Orders [of
persons<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] that come and demand their money and bring their Orders before other persons that did not come to
demand their moneys and bring their Orders in their course so as there be so much money reserved as will satisfie
precedent Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon Loan being to cease from
the time the money is so reserved and kept in Bank for them.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VI. Orders for Payment of Money lent may be assigned by Indorsement.</head>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee.; Assignee may assign</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p11">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every person or persons to whom any moneys
shall be due by virtue of this Act after Order entred in the Book of Register for payment thereof his
Executors Administrators or Assigns by indorsement of his Order may assign and transfer his Right Title Interest
and benefitt of such Order or any part thereof to any other which being notified in the Office of the Auditor of
Receipts aforesaid and an entry or memorial thereof also made in the Book of Register aforesaid for Orders
(which the Officers shall upon request without Fee or Charge accordingly make) shall entitle such Assignee his
Executors Administrators and Assigns to the benefitt thereof and payment thereon And such Assignee may in like
manner assign again and so toties quoties and afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person or persons
who have or hath made such Assignements to make void release or discharge the same or any the moneys
thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VII. Five Pounds per Cent. upon East India Stock.</head>
		<para id="p12">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the several Rates and Sums of money herein after
mentioned shall be answered and paid to their Majesties that is to say There shall be answered to their Majesties
the sum of Five pounds for every Hundred pounds of the Joint Stock of the East India Company the said Joint
Stock being valued att the rate of Seven hundred forty foure thousand pounds the same to be paid by the
Governour and Treasurer of the said East India Company by Foure equal quarterly payments the first payment
to be made upon the Five and twentieth day of [May<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] One thousand six hundred ninety and three and to
be deducted from the several persons interessed in the said Joint Stock according to their several shares and proportions
therein upon their next Dividends.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>VIII. Twenty Shillings upon African Shares.</head>
		<para id="p13">And be it further enacted That for every share in the Joint Stock of the Royal African Company according as
the number of shares are now reckoned and computed there shall be answered and paid to their Majesties the
sum of Twenty shillings the same to be paid by the Governor and Treasurer of the said Royal African Company
by Foure equal quarterly payments the First payment to bee made upon the said Five and twentieth day of March
One thousand six hundred ninety and three and to be deducted according to the several shares and proportions of
the Members of the said Company in the Joint Stock thereof upon their next Dividends.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s10">
		<head>IX. Five Pounds upon Hudson's Bay Shares.</head>
		<para id="p14">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That for every share in the Joint Stock of the Hudsons Bay
Company according as the number of shares are now reckoned and computed there shall be answered and paid
to their Majesties the sum of Five pounds the same to be paid by the Governor and Treasurer of the said Hudsons
Bay Company by four equal quarterly payments the first payment to be made vpon the said Five and twentieth
day of March One thousand six hundred ninety and three and to be deducted according to the several shares and
proportions of the Members of the said Company in the Joint Stock thereof upon the next Dividends And in
case the Governors and Treasurers of the said respective Companies shall make default in payment of the said
several Sums or any of them respectively charged on the Stocks of the said Companies att the days and times
aforesaid according to the true intent of this Act the Charter of such Company respectively shall be and is hereby
adjudged to be void.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s11">
		<head>X. Person interested only to swear to Debenture for Drawback.</head>
		<para id="p15">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That from and after the Sixth day of April One thousand
six hundred ninety and three no person be admitted to swear to a Debenture for any Duties to be drawn back
vpon reexportation but he who is the true Exporter as being either interessed in the propriety and hazard of the
Goods on the exportation or as being employed by commission is concerned in the direction of the Voyage so as
to be able to judge that the Goods are really and bona fide exported and not landed nor intended to be re-landed
in the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s12">
		<head>XI. Person insuring to deliver prohibited Goods imported, or Goods without Custom;</head>
		<para id="p16">
			<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p17">And whereas it is found by experience that great quantities of Goods are daily imported from Foreign parts
in a fraudulent and clandestine manner without paying the Customs and Duties due and payable to their Majesties
and the same hath of late been much encreased and promoted by ill men who notwithstanding the Laws already
made do undertake as Insurers or otherwise to deliver such Goods so clandestinely imported at their charge and
hazard into the Houses Ware-houses or Possession of the Owners thereof. For the preventing so great a mischief
be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That all and every person or persons whatsoever who by way of insurance
or otherwise shall undertake or agree to deliver any Goods or Merchandizes whatsoever to be imported from parts
beyond the Seas att any Port or Place whatsoever within this Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or Towne
of Berwick upon Tweed without paying the Customs and Duties that shall be due and payable for the same att
such importation or any prohibited Goods whatsoever or in pursuance of such Insurance Undertakeing or Agreement
shall deliver or cause or procure to be delivered any prohibited Goods or shall deliver or cause or procure
to be delivered any Goods or Merchandizes whatsoever without paying such Duties and Customs as aforesaid
knowing thereof and all and every their Aiders Abettors and Assistants shall for every such offence forfeit and
lose the Sum of Five hundred pounds over and above all other forfeitures and penalties to which they are liable
by any Act already in force</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s13">
		<head>XII. Person who shall be so insured;</head>
		<para id="p18">
			<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;500</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p19">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That all and every person or persons whatsoever who shall
agree to pay any sum or sums of money for the insureing or conveying any Goods or Merchandizes that shall
be so imported without paying the Customs and Duties due and payable att the Importation thereof or of any
prohibited Goods whatsoever or shall receive or take such prohibited Goods into his or their House or Ware-house
or other place onland or such other Goods before such Customs and Duties are paid knowing thereof shall [alsoe<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]
for every such offence forfeit and lose the like Sum of Five hundred pounds the one halfe of the said forfeitures
to be to their Majesties and the other halfe to the Informer or such person or persons as shall sue for the
same.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s14">
		<head>XIII. Insurer discovering;</head>
		<para id="p20">
			<emph type="i">Reward</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p21">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That if the Insurer Conveyer or Manager of such Fraud
be the discoverer of the same he shall not only keep and enjoy the Insurance money or Reward given him and
be discharged of the penalties to which he is liable by reason of such offence but shall also have to his owne
vse one halfe of the forfeitures hereby imposed vpon the partie or parties makeing such Insurance or Agreementor receiving the Goods as aforesaid And in case no discovery shall be made by the Insurer Conveyer or Manager
as aforesaid and the partie or parties insured or concerned in such Agreement shall make discovery thereof he shall
recover and receive back such Insurance money or Premium as he hath paid vpon such Insurance or Agreement and
shall have to his owne use one moiety of the Forfeitures imposed upon such Insurer Conveyer or Manager as
aforesaid and shall also be discharged of the forfeitures hereby imposed upon him or them.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s15">
		<head>XIV. How Penalty recovered.</head>
		<para id="p22">
			<emph type="i">Limitation of Prosecution</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p23">And be it enacted That all the said Penalties and Forfeitures shall be recoverable according to the course of
the Court of Exchequer in like manner as other penalties and forfeitures in like cases are recoverable Provided
That no Penalty hereby inflicted shall be recoverable vnlesse the same be prosecuted within Twelve months after
the time such fact was committed Any thing in this Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s16">
		<head>XV. Application of Duties.</head>
		<para id="p24">
			<emph type="i">4 &amp;5 W. &amp;M. c. 5</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p25">And for preventing doubts touching the application of moneys which shall accrue to their Majesties for the
Custom of Prize Goods Be it declared and directed by the authority aforesaid That all Duties as well Customs as
Imposts and by what Act or Acts soever that shall accrue and be payable to their Majesties at the Custom-House
after the Five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety three for any Goods or Merchandize
taken condemned and sold as prize shall be applied entirely to the credit of an Act of this present Session of
Parliament entituled An Act for granting to their Majesties certain additional impositions upon several Goods and
Merchandize for the prosecuteing the present War against France Any other Act to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">omitted in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">March, in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>

