<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46389" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the better discovery of Judgments in the Courts of Kings Bench Common Pleas &amp; Exchequer att Westminster. [Chapter XX. Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Judgments to be docqueted.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Clerks of King's Bench and Common Pleas to bring Notes of Judgments.; Clerks of the Exchequer to bring like Notes to the Office of Pleas.; Officers of the Courts to docquet Judgments of preceding Terms.; Fee for search.; Officers neglecting Duty,; Penalty &pound;100</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas great Mischiefs and Damages happen and come as well to persons in their Life times but more
often to their Heires Executors and Administrators and alsoe to Purchasers and Mortgagees by Judgments
entred upon Record in Their Majesties Courts att Westminster against the persons Defendants by reason of the
difficulty there is in finding out such Judgments. For remedy whereof be it enacted by the King and Queens
most Excellent Majesties by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the
Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That the Clerke of the Essoignes
of the Court of Co[m]mon Pleas every Clerk of the Doggets of the Court of Kings-Bench and the Master of the
Office of Pleas in the Court of Exchequer for the time being shall before the last day of Easter Terme next
comeing and so in every Easter Terme after make or cause to be made and put into an alphabetical Doggett
by the Defendants names a particular of all Judgments for Debt by Confession Non sum Informatus or Nihil
dicit entred in the said respective Courts of the Terme of Saint Hillary preceding which shall containe the name
and names of the Plantiff and Plantiffs the name and names of the Defendant and Defendants his her or their
place [and<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] places of Abode and Title Trade or Profession (if any such be in the Record of the said Judgment), and
the Debt Damages and Costs recovered thereby and in what County City or Towne the respective Actions were
laid and the Number Roll of the Entry thereof And alsoe that every Clerk of the Judgments and every other
Clerk of the said Court of Co[m]mon Pleas and Kings Bench respectively shall within ten days before the time
aforesaid bring to the respective Clerks of the Doggetts of the said respective Courts Notes in writeing of all the
Judgments by them and every of them respectively entred of the said Terme of Saint Hillary upon Verdicts
Writts of Enquiry Demurer and every other Judgment for Debt or Damags in all things as aforesaid And
alsoe that the Clerk of the Judgments and every other Clerk of the said Court of Exchequer shall within the
times aforesaid bring to the said Master of the said Office of Pleas the like note in writeing of all the like
Judgments by him and them respectively entred of the said Terme in all things as aforesaid to the end the same
may be (by the Clerk of the Essoigns of the said Court of Co[m]mon Pleas the Clerk of the Doggetts of the
said Court of Kings Bench and Master of the Office of Pleas) respectively entred in the respective Doggetts
before mentioned in manner and forme aforesaid And alsoe that the respective Officers and Clerks of the said
respective Courts shall likewise before the last day of the Terme of Saint Michael also next comeing and in
every Michaelmas Terme after make or cause to be made as aforesaid the like Doggetts containeing all such
Judgments in the said respective Courts of the respective Terms of Easter and Trinity then last past and the
names of the Plaintiffs and Defendants Titles and Additions Debt and Damags in all things as aforesaid And
alsoe that the said respective Officers and Clerks of the said respective Courts shall likewise before the last day
of the Terme of Saint Hillary which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and
three and so in every Hillary Terme after make or cause to be made the like Doggett containeing all such
Judgments in the said respective Courts of the Terme of Saint Michael then last past with the names of the
Plaintiffs and Defendants Titles and Additions Debt and Damags in all things as aforesaid And that the said
respective Doggetts shall be fairely put into and kept in Books in Parchment in the respective Offices of the
respective Officers before named to be searched and viewed by all persons att all reasonable times paying to the
respective Officers in whose keeping the said Books respectively shall be for every Terms search for Judgments
against any one person foure pence and no more upon pain that every Clerk of Essoigns of the Court of Co[m]mon
Pleas Clerk of the Doggets of the Kings Bench and Master of the Office of Pleas in the Court of Exchequer
Clerks of the Judgments and every Clerk before mentioned respectively shall for every Terme in which he shall
omit or neglect to do his duty in the premisses forfeit the Sum of One hundred pounds the one moiety to the
party or parties agrieved and the other moiety to him or them who shall sue for the same in any of Their
Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster wherein no Priveledge or Essoigne or Protection of Law shall be
admitted nor any more then one Imparlance.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Judgments not docquetted not to affect Purchasers, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p3">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no Judgment not doggetted and entred in the
Books as aforesaid shall affect any Lands or Tenements as to Purchasers or Mortgagees or have any preferrence
against Heirs Executors or Administrators in their Administration of their Ancestors Testators or Intestates Estates.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Fee to Clerk of the Judgments.</head>
		<para id="p4">And whereas the Clerks of the Judgments of the said respective Courts are to be att great charge and trouble
in the execuc[i]on of this Act for recompence whereof be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid that hereafter there
shall be paid by the Plaintiff or Plaintiffs in every of the said Judgments upon Verdicts Writs of Enquiry
Demurrer and every other Judgment by them respectively to be entred over and above the Fees now due for the
same the Sum of Foure pence and no more.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Continuance of Act.</head>
		<para id="p5">Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That this Act shall continue and be in force for
one yeare from the five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety and three and from
thence to the end of the next Session of Parliament and no longer.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>

