<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46380" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
<subtitle>Chapter XI. An Act for examineing takeing and stateing the publick Accompts of this Kingdom [Rot. Parl. pt.3. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>Commissioners appointed to take the Public Accounts, and all Accounts to be taken under</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">2 W.&amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 11; the said Act revived and continued till April 25, 1694; Treasury to issue Allowances as by the said Act; Power to Commissioners to take Account of Monies as herein directed; 3 W. &amp; M. c. 6</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">For the better takeing stateing and examineing of the publick Accompts of the Nation and that Their Majesties
good Subjects may be the better encouraged more readily and chearfully to sustaine the great burthens upon
them for the prosecution of the War against France and the support and maintenance of Their Majesties Government
Be it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Comons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That
Sir Thomas Clarges Knight Sir Peter Collitton Barronett Sir Samuel Barnardiston Barronett Sir Benjamine Newland
Knight Sir Matthew Andrews Knight Paul Foley Esq[uire] and Robert Harley Esq[uire] or any Four or more of them shall
be and are hereby constituted Commissioners for takeing of the Accompt of all Moneys of the publick Revenue
of the Crowne and all other Accompts which were by one Act of Parliament made in the Second yeare of Theire
Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for appointing and enabling Commissioners to examine take and state the publick
Accompts of [this<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Kingdom to be taken examined or stated by the Commissioners thereby constituted or any Five
or more of them by virtue of the said Act and that the said Act be and is hereby revived continued and in force
from the Foure and twentieth day of April next ensuing to the Five and twentieth day of April which, shall be in
the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety four and shall be executed with all the Powers therein
contained by the Commissioners herein named or any four or more of them And that the Lords Commissioners
of the Treasury or Lord High Treasurer of England for the time being shall and are hereby authorized and required
to issue and pay or cause to be issued and paid the like yearely allowances for payment of Clerks and other
Charges as is in the said Act directed and the like Quarterly Payments to the Co[m]missioners hereby constituted
as in the said Act is appointed to be paid to the Co[m]missioners therein named And the said Co[m]missioners by this
Act constituted as aforesaid or any Foure or more of them shall and have hereby Power to take an Accompt or
Accompts of all Moneys granted to Their Majesties by any Act or Acts of Parliament made in the Third Session
of this present Parliament begun and held att Westminster on the Two and twentieth day of October One thousand
six hundred ninety one or att any other day or time in that yeare and of all moneys that have been or shall
be granted to Their Majesties in this present Session of Parliament and of all other Their Majesties Revenue or
other publick Moneys due or payable to Their Majesties att any time between the Fifth day of November One
thousand six hundred eighty (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) eight and the said Five and twentieth day of April which shall be in the year of
our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety foure not yet accompted for by virtue or in pursuance of the said
first recited Act or the last Clause touching publick Accompts made and enacted in one Act passed in the Third
year of Their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for raiseing Money by a Poll [payable<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] quarterly for One year
for the carrying on a vigorous War against France</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
</section>
</report>


