<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46386" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVII. An Act for the regaining encourageing and settling the Greenland Trade.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Recital that Greenland Trade beneficial; and that neighbouring Nations make Advantage thereby; and that the Merchants have endeavoured to regain the same. 25 Car. II. c. 7. &sect; 1.; 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 4.; Recital of the Circumstances under which the said Trade is now wholly ingrossed by Foreigners.; Recital that for regaining the said Trade a Stock of &pound;40,000 had been subcribed by the Persons herein named.; Power given to the said Persons to raise a Joint Stock of &pound;40,000</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Trade to Greenland and the Greenland Seas in the fishing for Whales there hath been heretofore
a very beneficial Trade to this Kingdom not only in the imploying great numbers, of Seamen and Ships
and consuming great quantities of Provisions but also in the bringing into this Nation great quantities of Oyl
Blubber and Fins. And whereas neighbouring Nations do yearely make great advantage thereby not only supplying
themselves with that sort of Oyl and Fins but by vending into other parts great quantities thereof and particularly
into this Kingdom where the said Trade is now quite decayed and lost. And whereas several Merchants of this
Kingdom did heretofore endeavour to settle and regain the said Trade and for their encouragement therein it was
by an Act of Parliament made in the Five and twentieth yeare of the Raigne of His late Majesty King Charles
the second entituled An Act for the incouragement of the Greenland and Eastland Trades and for the better
secureing the Plantation Trade (amongst other things) enacted That [in regard<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] there was then great want of
Harpinierers and Seamen skilled and exercised in the Trade of Whale fishing it should and might be lawfull for
any Ship or Vessel truely belonging to England Wales or the Towne of Berwick upon Tweed and whereof the
Master should be an Englishman and inhabiting within the Places aforesaid from and after the First day of May
which was in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seventy and three and until the Five and
twentieth day of March which was in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty and three employed
for the catching of Whales dureing such Voyage to be navigated with one moiety of the Harpinierers and one
moiety [of the rest<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of the Mariners only English and yet to pay no further or other Custom for the Oyl
Blubber or Fins caught or imported in such Ship or Vessel then if such Ship or Vessel had been navigated with
Three fourths of the Mariners English Which said Act was by another Act of Parliament made in the Second
yeare of Their present Majesties Reign entituled An Act for granting to Their Majesties a Subsidy of Tonnage
and Poundage and other Sums of Money payable upon Merchandizes exported and imported continued for Four
years. And whereas several Merchants and other Persons of this Kingdom were by the (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) first recited Act
encouraged to fit out and send to the said Greenland Seas some Ships or Vessels for the catching of Whales
whereby some small quantities of Oyl Blubber and Whale Fins were imported into this Kingdom but they not
being able to carry on the said Trade upon their single or separate Interests in regard that the neighbouring
Nations did yearly [send<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] far greater numbers of Ships into those Seas the said Merchants and other Persons
of this Kingdom were forced to desist from following the said Trade which is now wholly ingrossed by Foreigners
And since the expiration and revival of the said Act there hath not been any Ships sent from England to the
said Greenland Seas or any Oyl Blubber or Whale Fins imported into England but such as have been bought of
Foreigners whereby great sums of money are yearely drawne out of England for those Commodities and the
Rates and Prizes which are now paid for the same are now above six times more then heretofore they were and
the said Trade having been for above these Twelve years last past wholly lost to this Kingdom there are very
few or no English Harpinierers or English Seamen skilled and exercised in the said Trade of Whale catching so
that the said Trade cannot now be regained to this Kingdom nor can be carried on by or without the assistance
of foreigne Harpinierers and Seamen or upon the single Interests or Stocks of any particular Persons or by any
other way then by a joynt Stock. And whereas for the regaining enlargeing and encourageing the said Trade a
Stock of Fourty thousand Pounds att least is a necessary Fond to be raised for the regaineing and carrying on
the said Trade whereby it may become beneficial to this Kingdom. And whereas Sir William Scawen Knight
Henry Bertie Robert Hookes John Skinner George Boddington Francis Gosfright Edmond Prideaux Edmond
Harrison John Jurin Edward Buckley Benjamin Steele Mordecai Abbot Robert Michell John Gunston John Knapp
Thomas Skinner William Broughton Robert Bristow Robert Hackshaw John Bridges James Boddington Peter
Percivall Thomas Phipps Charles Michell Samuel Howard Samuel Nash Benjamin Smith Nicholas Cutler Thomas
Chambers Peter Gray James Ball Thomas Kett Humphry Simpson Richard Munford John Plumbe Richard Cook
Peter Godfrey Ambrose Bray Augustine Munford Josiah Ordway Joseph Paice and Thomas Gunston have
undertaken and agreed to raise by Subscriptions amongst themselves the said Stock or Fond of Fourty thousand
Pounds att least to be wholly employed in the regaining manageing and carrying on the said Trade May it please
your most excellent Majesties that it may be enacted. And be it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent
Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present
Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That a joynt Stock of Forty thousand Pounds at least
shall be raised by Subscriptions by the said Sir William Scawen Henrie Bertie Robert Hookes John Skinner
George Boddington Francis Gosfright Edmond Prideaux Edmond Harrison John Jurin Edward Buckley Benjamin
Steel Mordecai Abbot Robert Michell John Gunston John Knapp Thomas Skinner William Broughton Robert
Bristow Robert Hackshaw John Bridges James Boddington Peter Percival Thomas Phipps Charles Michell Samuel
Howard Samuel Nash Benjamin Smith Nicholas Cutler Thomas Chambers Peter Gray James Ball Thomas Kett
Humphry Simpson Richard Munford John Plumbe Richard Cook Peter Godfrey Ambrose Bray Augustine
Munford Josiah Ordway Joseph Paice and Thomas Gunston on or before the First day of May now next
coming and shall be paid to the vse of the Company established by this Act in such manner as by this Act is
directed.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. The said Persons made a Corporation by the Name of the Greenland Company.</head>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">To have a Common Seal, and capable to purchase Lands, &amp;c. not exceeding &pound;100 per Annum</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">And for the better regaining managing and carrying on the said Trade for the public good of this Kingdome
Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Sir William Scawen Henrie Bertie Robert Hookes
John Skinner George Boddington Francis Gosfright Edmond Prideaux Edmond Harrison John Jurin Edward
Buckley Benjamine Steele Mordecai Abbott Robert Michell John Gunston John Knapp Thomas Skinner William
Broughton Robert Bristow Robert Hackshaw John Bridges James Boddington Peter Percivall Thomas Phipps
Charles Michell Samuel Howard Samuel Nash Benjamine Smith Nicholas Cutler Thomas Chambers Peter Gray
James Ball Thomas Kett Humphrey Simpson Richard Munford John Plumbe Richard Cook Peter Godfrey
Ambrose Bray Augustine Munford Josiah Ordway Joseph Paice and Thomas Gunston and all and every other person
and persons being natural borne Subjects of this Realme or persons naturalized or endenizend who shall have
any share or interest in the said Joynt Stock shall be one Body Corporate and Politick in deed and in name
by the name of the Company of Merchants of London tradeing to Greenland And that by the same name of
the Company of Merchants of London tradeing to Greenland they shall have succession and a Common Seal and
that they and their Successors by the name aforesaid shall be able and capable in Law and shall have perfect
power and ability in Law to have purchase receive possesse and enjoy retaine to them and their Successors Lands
Rents Tenements and Hereditaments of what kind nature or quality soever so as the same exceed not the yearely
value of One hundred pounds And also to sell grant demise alien or dispose of the same and by the same
name to sue and implead to be sued and impleaded answer and be answered in any Courts of Record or other
places whatsoever and to do and execute all and singuler other matters and things by the name aforesaid that
to them shall or may appertain to do and all other things whatsoever which any other Body Corporate or Politicke
can or may lawfully doe or execute.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. The Company may trade to Greenland, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">Exception of American Plantations</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said Company of Merchants of London tradeing
to Greenland and their Successors shall dureing the continuance of this Joynt Stock hereby appointed to be
raised have use and enjoy the free Trade and Traffick and shall and may freely traffick and use the trade and
art of Merchandize and catching of Whales by Sea or otherwise to into and from Greenland and [the<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Greenland
Seas and to into and from the several Ports Havens and Places which are scituate lying and being in Greenland
and the Greenland Seas and in all other Seas and Places whatsoever (except in the Seas belonging to their
Majesties Colonies and Plantations in America) and to and from all and every of them without any hindrance
interruption denyall or disturbance whatsoever any Statute Usage or other Cause or Matter whatsoever to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. A Governor, &amp;c. to be chosen.</head>
		<para id="p7">And be it further enacted That a Governor Deputy Governor and Sixteen Committees of the said Company shall
be elected and chosen in manner as hereafter is appointed who shall have the management and direction of the said
Trade and of the Voyages and Affairs of the said Company.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. A Book of Subscriptions, and each Subscriber</head>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">to subscribe not less than &pound;500 nor more than &pound;2,000</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p9">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That a Book for Subscriptions shall be provided within Ten
days after the passing of this Act by the first Five of the aforenamed persons or any Three of them In which said
Book shall be subscribed on or before the said said First day of May now next comeing by all the persons in this Act
before named or the Survivors of them the said Joynt Stock which shall not be lesse then Forty thousand pounds
And that each of the said Subscribers shall not subscribe lesse then Five hundred pounds nor more then Two
thousand pounds.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. Money subscribed how and when to be paid;</head>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">within Four Years</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p11">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That all and every the said persons so as aforesaid subscribeing
shall on or before the said First day of May now next comeing actually and bona fide pay downe unto such person
or persons as the said persons herein before named or the major part of them shall nominate and appoint one
full and entire Fourth part of the severall sums of money by each of them respectively subscribed to the said
Joynt Stock and shall alsoe pay the remainder thereof att such times and in such manner as shall be directed and
appointed from time to time by the Governor or Deputy Governor and Court of Co[m]mittees of the said Company
for the time being so as the whole sum to be subscribed be paid within Foure years next after the said First day
of May.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. Defaulters to enjoy in proportion to Money actually paid.</head>
		<para id="p12">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That all and every person and persons makeing default in
any of the said payments shall im[m]ediately from and after such default have or enjoy no further or other benefitt
or advantage by such Subscription then according and in proportion to such sum or sums of money onely which
such person or persons shall have actually and really paid into the said Joynt Stock as aforesaid.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. Defaulters to forfeit &pound;10 per Cent. of what they have paid.</head>
		<para id="p13">And be it [further<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] enacted by the authority aforesaid That every person or persons who shall make default in
paying any part or proportion of such his Subscription in such manner as by this Act is appointed shall forfeit
and loose to the use and benefitt of the Adventurers in the said Joynt Stock after the rate of Ten pounds for
every One hundred pounds of such sum or sums which he or they shall so neglect or omitt to pay in as aforesaid
to be deducted out of the money paid in by such person makeing default as aforesaid.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>IX. Choice of Governor and Deputy Governor, and Sixteen Committees.</head>
		<para id="p14">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That before the Five and twentieth day of May now next
comeing any Thirteen of them the said persons herein before named shall sum[m]on and call together a General
Court of all the said Subscribers and of all and every other person and persons who shall then have any Share
or Interest in the said Joint Stock who shall and may quietly and freely assemble themselves and meet together
att the time and place so appointed and then and there att their will and pleasure name choose and elect one fit
person who shall have subscribed One thousand pounds or upwards to the said Joynt Stock and actually paid
in one fourth part thereof as aforesaid to be Governor of the said Company And one other fitt person in like
manner who shall have subscribed the Sum of One thousand pounds to the said Joynt Stock and actually paid in
one fourth part thereof as aforesaid to be Deputy Governor of the said Company And also Sixteen other fitt
persons in like manner each of them having severally subscribed the sum of Five hundred pounds or upwards
to the said Joynt Stock and severally paid in one fourth part thereof as aforesaid to be Co[m]mittees of the said
Company the said Governor Deputy Governor and Co[m]mittees to continue in their respective Offices and Places
until the Twentieth day of October which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety
and foure.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s10">
		<head>X. Oath to be taken by Governor and Deputy Governor.</head>
		<para id="p15">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every Governor and Deputy Governor of the said
Company for the time being before they be admitted to the execution of their respective Offices or Places of
Governour and Deputy Governour shall take the following Oath, viz</para>
		<para id="p16">You swear That you shall assist and with all your Power support and maintain the Company of Merchants of
London tradeing to Greenland and the Priveledges of the same haveing no respect to your selfe in derogation
hindrance or prejudice to the good Government Order and Co[m]mon Weale thereof The By-Laws and Ordinances
which shall be made by authority of this Company and which are not repugnant to the Laws of this Kingdom
you shall uprightly and duely execute according to your knowledge thereof And to every person you shall
[administer<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] upright Justice And you shall not engage or oblige the said Company in any wise as Governor or
Deputy Governor of the said Company without agreement and consent of the Court of Committees of the said
Company. So help you Almighty God.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s11">
		<head>XI. Oath to be taken by Committees.</head>
		<para id="p17">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every one of the said Sixteen Co[m]mittees of the said
Company for the time being before they be admitted to the execuc[i]on of their said respective Offices or Places
of Co[m]mittees shall take the following Oath. viz.</para>
		<para id="p18">You sweare to be faithfull and true dureing the time of your place of trust as one of the Co[m]mittees to the
Company of Merchants of London tradeing to Greenland and their Successors the good Estate of the
Adventurers in this present Joynt Stock you shall favour and affect and the Priveledges granted unto them (to
your power) endeavour to maintaine and preserve You shall be carefull to see and provide that an equal and
indiferent hand be carried in the Government of the Company and in the Affaires thereof to all the Adventurers
that shall adventure or put in Stock And that an equal Division from time to time be made to all the Adventurers
according to the proportion of their several Stocks duely paid in. So help you God.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s12">
		<head>XII. Subscriber of less than &pound;500 no Vote, of &pound;500 one Vote, of &pound;1,000 Two Votes.</head>
		<para id="p19">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That no person or persons who shall subscribe lesse or
shall have lesse then Five hundred [pound<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] in the said Joynt Stock shall have any vote or voice att any General
Court of the said Company And that every person or persons who shall subscribe to or shall have in the said
Joynt Stock the sum of Five hundred pounds shall have one vote or voice and no more att any General Court
of the said Company and that every person or persons who shall subscribe to or shall have in the said Joynt
Stock of the said Company the Sum of One thousand pounds shall have two votes or voices att any General
Court of the said Company and no more although he or they shall have subscribed more to or shall have in the
said Stock more then One thousand pounds.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s13">
		<head>XIII. Oath to be taken by Subscribers.</head>
		<para id="p20">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That all and every person and persons who shall subscribe
and pay in any Sum of money into the said Joynt Stock or shall have any Share or Interest in the said Joynt
Stock shall be admitted gratis into the Freedom of the said Company and shall take the Oath of Admission into
the same before the Governor or Deputy Governor or any Five of the Comittees for the time being who are
hereby impowered to administer the same in words following viz</para>
		<para id="p21">You swear that you will assist and with all your power support and maintaine the Company of Merchants of London
tradeing to Greenland; The By Laws and Ordinancs which shall be made by authority of this Company
which are not repugnant to the Laws of this Kingdom you shall according to your knowledge thereof uprightly
and duely keep and obey. So help you God.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s14">
		<head>XIV. Governors, &amp;c. to be chosen annually.</head>
		<para id="p22">
			<emph type="i">Proceedings</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p23">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said Governour [and<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Deputy Governour or any
Five of the Co[m]mittees then in being shall before the said Twentieth day of October in the yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred ninety (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) foure att any time between the First day and the Twentieth day of October then
next following and so annually for every yeare afterwards between the days last menc[i]oned (timely notice thereof
being first given) call a general Court of all the Members of the said Company who shall have subscribed to the
said Joynt Stock the sum of Five hundred pounds or more and paid in one fourth part of their several
Subscriptions as aforesaid and such other proportions of the same as shall be directed and appointed as aforesaid
and shall have severally taken the said Oath of Admission then and there to elect and choose out of the Members
of the said Company so qualified as aforesaid One Governor One Deputy Governor and Sixteen Co[m]mittees of the said
Company to serve for one whole yeare next ensueing his and their respective Elections And if the said Governor
or Deputy or any of the Co[m]mittees for the time being shall happen to die before the expiration of the said yeare
for which he or they shall be so elected that then and from thenceforth it shall and may be lawfull to and
for the said Governor or Deputy Governour or Five of the Co[m]mittees to su[m]mon and call together a General
Court of the Adventurers aforesaid and then and there to choose into the place or places of him or them so
dyeing other fit person or persons qualified as aforesaid to continue in their respective Offices or Places dureing
the remainder of such yeare.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s15">
		<head>XV. Governor, Deputy Governor and Committees to take the Oaths of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 8.</head>
		<para id="p24">
			<emph type="i">By whom such Oaths are to be administered</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p25">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every Governor Deputy Governor and Co[m]mittees of
the said Company besides the said Oaths already appointed to be taken by them respectively shall alsoe take the
[Oath<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] appointed to be taken instead of the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance by a late Act of Parliament [mad<ref idref="n10">10</ref>]
in the First yeare of their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy and
Allegiance and appointing other Oaths And that the said first Governor to be elected shall take the said Oaths
hereby appointed to be taken by the Governor of the said Company for the time being before the [said<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]
persons herein before named or any nine of them who are hereby impowered to administer the same And the first
Deputy Governor shall take the said Oaths hereby appointed to be taken by the Deputy Governor of the said
Company for the time being before the said first Governor who is hereby impowered to administer the same And the
said first Sixteen Co[m]mittees shall each of them severally take the said Oaths appointed to be taken by the said
Sixteen Co[m]mittees for the time being before the said first Governor or the said Deputy Governour who are hereby
impowered to administer the same And that every succeeding Governor shall take the Oaths appointed to be taken
by the said Governour of the Company for the time being before the last preceding Governor or any Five or more
of the last preceding Co[m]mittees who are hereby impowered to administer the same And every succeeding Deputy
Governour shall take the Oaths appointed to be taken by the Deputy Governor of the said Company for the time
being before the Governor or in case of his death or absence before any Five of the last preceding Co[m]mittees
who are hereby impowered to administer the same And every Member of the succeeding Co[m]mittees for the time
being shall take the said Oaths appointed to be respectively taken by the Sixteen Co[m]mittees of the said Company
for the time being before the Governour or Deputy Governor for the time being or any Five or more of the
preceding Committees who are hereby impowered to administer the same.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s16">
		<head>XVI. General Courts and Committees how to be called.</head>
		<para id="p26">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That from and after the said Twentieth day of May next
ensuing all and every the General Courts and Co[m]mittees of the said Company hereby established shall be from
time to time called and summoned by order of the said Governour or Deputy Governour or any Five or more
of the said Co[m]mittees for the time being Att all which General Courts and Courts of Co[m]mittees beforementioned
the Governour for the time being shall be present or in his absence the Deputy Governour for the time being
and in case of equality of Votes or Voices shall have a casting Voice.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s17">
		<head>XVII. The Subscribers at a Court may make Bye Laws.</head>
		<para id="p27">
			<emph type="i">Notice of calling a Court.; Bye-Laws to be observed, and not to be repugnant to Law</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p28">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for all the Members
of the said Company who shall have subscribed Five hundred pounds or more to the said Joynt Stock and shall
have paid in one fourth part of their respective Subscriptions and such other proportions of the same as shall be
directed or appointed as aforesaid and all and every other person and persons who shall have the sum of Five
hundred pounds in the said Joynt Stock and shall have taken the said Oath of Admission from time to time and att
all times dureing the continuance of the said Joynt Stock to assemble themselves att a General Court (timely
notice thereof being first given as aforesaid by the Governour or Deputy Governour or [any<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Five of the said
Co[m]mittees for the time being) And that they or the major part of them being so assembled whereof the Governour
[or the<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Deputy Governour for the time being to be one shall and may make ordain and constitute such and
so many reasonable By-Laws Constitutions and Ordinancs as to them or the greater part of them then and there
present shall seem necessary and convenient for the good Government of the said Company and of all Co[m]manders
Mariners and all other Officers Servants and Persons by them employed in any of their Ships and Voyages and
for the better preservation and improvement of the said Trade or Traffick and the same By-Laws Constitutions
Orders and Ordinancs so made to put in [use<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] accordingly and att their Will and Pleasure from time to time
to change revoke and alter the same as occasion shall be or require Which said By-Laws Constitutions Orders
and Ordinancs so as aforesaid to be made shall be duely kept and observed under the pains and penalties therein
limitted so always as the said By-Laws Constitutions Orders and Ordinancs be reasonable and not contrary
or repugnant to the [Laws<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] Statutes or Customs of this Kingdom or to any of the Regulations contained in
this Act.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s18">
		<head>XVIII. The Sales of Goods to be public once a Year at least, and by Inch of Candle.</head>
		<para id="p29">
			<emph type="i">No Lot more than &pound;300.; The Monies arising from Sales to be faithfully applied</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p30">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That dureing the Continuance of this said joynt Stock no
private Contract for the Sale of any Goods or Merchandizes shall be made by the said Company to any Member
or Members of the said Company or any other Person or Persons whatsoever But that all Goods and Merchandizes
belonging to the said Company shall be sold openly and publickely by Inch of Candle att their publick Sales
which shall be once in every yeare att the least Of which Sales publick Notice shall be given upon the Royal
Exchange in London att least Three Weeks before And that no Lott of any Goods or Merchandizes belonging to
the said Company shall be put up or exposed to Sale the value of which shall exceed Three hundred Pounds
in the Allotment thereof And that all Moneys ariseing by the sale of any Goods or Merchandizes of the said
Company shall be faithfully and bona fide accompted for and applied to the publick and co[m]mon benefitt and
advantage of the general joynt Stock of the said Company and of all and every the Persons therein interested
rateably and according to every Persons Proportion and Share thereof and not to the private advantage of any
particular Person or Persons whatsoever.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s19">
		<head>XIX. Dividends to be in Money.</head>
		<para id="p31">
			<emph type="i">Shares may be assigned by Entry in a Book kept for that Purpose, and may be devised.; Book open to inspection.; Transfers made otherwise, void</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p32">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Dividends hereafter to be made of the Profits
ariseing by the said Trade shall be made in money and not otherwise. And be it further enacted That it shall
and may be lawfull to and for all and every Person and Persons who shall have any Share or Interest in the
said joynt Stock to sell assigne and transfer such his or their Share or Interest or any part thereof by and in
the Books of the said Company to be for that purpose provided to any Person or Persons being natural born
Subjects of this Realme or Persons naturalized or endenized And that all and every such Sale and Assignment
when so as aforesaid made and entred and not otherwise shall be good and effectual in the Law against all and
every such Person and Persons his and their Executors and Administrators who shall so as aforesaid assigne and
transfer any such Share and Interest in the said joynt Stock And [that<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] the said Book or Books for the
assigneing and transferring the said joynt Stock shall lie open from time to time for the view of all Persons
concerned And all Alienations Transfers or Assignments made after any other manner shall be void excepting for
such Stock onely which shall happen to be devised to any Person by Will or shall come to him by being
Executor or Administrator to any Person deceased.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s20">
		<head>XX. No person to sell a greater Share than he really hath.</head>
		<para id="p33">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall not be lawfull for any Person or Persons
att any time to agree for contract bargain or sell any or other or greater Sum Share Interest or part of the said
joynt Stock then such Su[m]m Share Interest or Part only as such Person or Persons shall actually and bona fide be
possessed of and have standing in his or their owne name in the said Companies Books att the time of such
Agreement Contract Bargaine or Sale made.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s21">
		<head>XXI. Sales not perfected within Ten Days void.</head>
		<para id="p34">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Agreements Contracts Bargaines or Sales for any
Share Interest or Part of the said joynt Stock which shall not be performed compleated and executed and transferred
within Ten days next after the makeing of such Agreement Contract Bargaine or Sale are and shall be null and
void to all intents and purposes whatsoever as if the same had never been made</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s22">
		<head>XXII. Ships to Greenland may be navigated with One Third English;</head>
		<para id="p35">
			<emph type="i">and yet not to pay any further Custom</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p36">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for the said Company
hereby established and for all and every the Ships and Vessells belonging to or employed by the said Company
and truely belonging to England Wales or the Towne of Berwick upon Tweed and whereof the Masters shall be
Englishmen and inhabiting within the Places aforesaid and for no other Ship or Vessell whatsoever from and after
the First day of May in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety three and until the First (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) of
October which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and seven employed for the
catching of Whales in the Greenland Seas and other the Seas and Places aforesaid dureing such their Voyages to
be navigated with one third of the Mariners English att the least and yet [to pay<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] no further or other Custom
for the Oyle Blubber or Fins caught and imported in such Ships or Vessels then if such Ships [or Vessels<ref idref="n13">13</ref>]
had been navigated with three fourths of the Mariners English Any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary in any
wise notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s23">
		<head>XXIII. Greenland Ships not to have the Benefit of this Act, unless victualled for the said Voyage, and proceed direct.</head>
		<para id="p37">
			<emph type="i">To be attested by Collector</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p38">Provided always and it is hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no English Ship or other
Vessel belonging to England Wales or the Towne of Berwick upon Tweed and which shall belong to and be
employed by the said Company in the catching of Whales in the Greenland Seas and other the Seas and Places
aforesaid and importing Whale Oyle or Blubber or other Fish Oyl or Whale Fins of Greenland or those Seas or
other the Seas and Places aforesaid shall enjoy any Benefitt or Priviledge by this Act unlesse such Ship or Vessell
did proceed on her Voyage for Greenland and those Seas or for other the Seas or Places aforesaid from
England or Wales or the Towne of Berwick upon Tweed and was victualled for the said Voyage in some
of those Places to be attested by the Collector of the Port where the same Ship or Vessell was victualled.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s24">
		<head>XXIV. Corporation to continue for 14 Years.</head>
		<para id="p39">Provided always That this Act and the said joynt Stock shall continue and the said Company shall have and
enjoy the said Traffick and Trade to and from Greenland and the Greenland Seas and other the Seas and Places
aforesaid for the Terme of Fourteen yeares to be accounted from the First day of October in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred ninety three and no longer.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s25">
		<head>XXV. This Act a Public Act.</head>
		<para id="p40">Provided also and be it further enacted That this Act shall be and is hereby declared to be a publick Act of
Parliament and shall be so taken and acknowledged by all and every Their Majesties Judges in all and every Their
Majesties Courts att Westminster and by all and every other Their Majesties Subjects whatsoever.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">minister <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">pounds <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n7" number="7">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n8" number="8">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n9" number="9">Oaths. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n10" number="10">made <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n12" number="12">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n14" number="14">ure <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n15" number="15">omitted in the King's Printer's Copy.</note>
		<note id="n16" number="16">day <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


