<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46381" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
<subtitle>Chapter XII. An Act to make Parishioners of the Church united Contributors to the Repairs and Ornaments of the Church to whome the Union is made [Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>17 Car. II. c. 3. recited.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">If Two Churches be united, and one of them demolished, the Parishioners of that Church shall pay toward the Repairs of the other; Process</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act of Parliament made in the Seventeenth year of the Reign of King Charles the
Second of blessed Memory provision was made for the uniting Churches in Cities and Towns Corporate
And forasmuch as it is highly reasonable that Parishioners of Parishes whose Churches are demolised and either
before or [afterward<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] united to other Churches should be Contributors towards the Repairs and other Parochial
Charges of such other Church to which by virtue of the said Act they are united. Therefore be it enacted by
the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and
Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That where any
Churches heretofore have been or hereafter shall bee united by virtue of the said Act and one of the said Churches
so united was att the time of such Union or shall afterwards be demolished that in all such cases as often as the Church
which was or shall be made the Church Presentative and to which the Union was or shall be made, shall be out
of Repair or there shall be need of decent Ornaments for the performance of Divine Service therein that the
Parishioners of the Parish whose Church shall then be down or demolisht shall bear and pay towards the charges
of such Repairs and decent Ornaments such share and proportion as the Archbishop or Bishop that shall make
such Union shall by the same Union direct and appoint and for want of such Direction and Appointment then
one third part of such charges of the Repairs and decent Ornaments which shall be made or provided And the
same shall be rated taxed and levied and in default thereof such Processe and Proceedings shall be had and
made against him or them as if it were for the Reparation and finding decent Ornaments for their owne Parish
Church if no such Union had been made Any Law Custom Usage or Opinion to the contrary heretofore
notwithstanding.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">afterwards <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
</section>
</report>


