<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46388" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for preventing Suits against such as acted for Their Majesties Service in Defence of the Kingdom.  [Chapter XIX. Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that the Lords of the Council, &amp;c. have acted beyond their Power in Defence of the Kingdom.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">All future Actions against them for acting void.; In Actions begun General Issue may be pleaded.; Double Costs</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in this present yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and two it was notoriously
knowne that there was great preparations for an Invasion intended from France the Lords of the Council
and those that have acted by their Authority having apprehended and imprisoned several suspected persons and
seized and used Horses and Armes and caused some part of the Militia of this Kingdom to be raised continued
and maintained otherwise then is authorized by the Acts made in the Reigne of King Charles the Second in that
behalfe and to march and be quartered in diverse places upon that occasion that those proceedings in that extraordinary
Juncture and the parties concerned therein may be indempnified therefore and for the preventing the trouble and
chargs which the said good Subjects might be put to by the prosecution of Their Majesties Their Heires and
Successors or by the meanes of Suites of any person whatsoever for and by reason of their actings and doeings
aforesaid Be it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of
the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That
all personal Actions Suits Indictments Informations and other Prosecutions whatsoever for or by reason of the
Premisses be and are hereby discharged and made void And if any Action or Suit hereby declared to be discharged
hath been or shall be co[m]menced or prosecuted every person so sued may plead the general Issue and give this
Act and the Special Matter in Evidence And if the Plaintiffe shall become Nonsuit or forbeare further Prosecution or
suffer discontinuance or if a Verdict passe against him the said Defendant shall recover his double costs for which
he shall have the like remedy as in case where Costs by Law are given to Defendants</para>
	</section>
</report>

