<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46391" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for regulateing Proceedings in the Crowne Office of the Court of King's Bench att Westminster. [Chapter XXII. Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Persons having Grants by Charter inrolled, not bound to plead them to an Inquisition.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Having Grants of Felon's Goods, &amp;c. not bound to inrol the whole.; Fee.; After Inrolment, not bound to plead Grant to Inquisition</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For rectifying the Proceedings in the Crowne Office in Their Majesties Court of Kings Bench and for the
greater ease of all Their Majesties Subjects who shall hereafter be prosecuted in the same be it enacted by
the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and
Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That no Corporation
Lord or Lords of Mannors or other person or persons having grants by Charter or other good Conveyancs who
have inrolled and had the same allowed in and by the said Court shall hereafter be compelled to plead the same
to any Inquisition returned by any Coroner any custome or usage to the contrary notwithstanding And if there
be any Corporations Lord or Lords of Mannors or other person or persons who now have or hereafter shall have
such Charters or Grants from the Crowne for Felons goods Deodands and othe Forfeitures such Corporations
Lords of Mannors and other persons shall not be compelled to inroll their whole Charters and Grants but
[bring in<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the same to the Clerk of the Crowne of the said Court he shall inroll and enter upon record so much
thereof as may expresse and set forth the Grants of such Felons Goods Deodands and Forfeitures and no more
for doeing whereof he shall have and receive twenty shillings for his fee and entry thereof and no more And
from and after such inrollment no Corporation Lord of Mannor or other person or persons Grantees of such
Goods or Forfeitures shall be compelled to plead the same in the said Court to any inquisition thereafter filed
therein touching any Goods found thereby any usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Clerk of the Crown issuing Process after Inrolment,</head>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any Clerk of the Crowne of the said Court shall
hereafter issue out any processe against any Corporation Lord of Mannor or other person or persons Grantees of
such Felons Goods Deodands and other Forfeitures after inrollment or entry as aforesaid the said Clerk of the
Crowne shall for every offence forfeit and pay to the Corporation or party grieved thereby the su[m]m of five pounds
to be recovered by bill plaint or informac[i]on in any of Their Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster wherein
no essoign priveledge protection or wager of Law shall be admitted nor any more then one Imparlance.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Clerk of the Crown not punishable for issuing Process against Heirs, &amp;c. before they have entered or pleaded their Title.</head>
		<para id="p5">And whereas divers persons having Grants of Felons Goods and Deodands and inrolled and pleaded as aforesaid
do many times alien and convey their Interests therein to other person or persons or by their last [Will<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] doe
devise the same or by their deaths such Estates do descend to theire Heires whereby the Clerk of the Crowne of
the said Court is rendred uncapable to discerne where such Interest lyes until the person or persons to whom
such Estates are conveyed devised or descended shall come into the said Court and make entry of such their
claime as aforesaid be it therefore hereby further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Clerk of the Crowne of
the said Court for the time being nor any succeeding Clerke there shall incurr any penalty mentioned in this Act for
issueing processe against any person or persons who shall not upon every purchase of the Title of such Felons
Goods and Deodands inrol and plead the same purchase in the said Court nor against any Devisee of the like
Estate who shall not likewise inroll or plead such Devise nor against any Heire who shall not in like manner
inroll his or her right by descent to the same and until after such pleas have been allowed of and approved by
the said Court nor whereby any inquest of any Coroner or Coroners the goods of any Felon or Felons or Deodands
shall be by such inquest not found to be in the hands of such Purchaser Devisee or Heire or their respective
Officer or Officers in trust for them respectively.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. A Proclamation at the Time of the Exigent in Criminal Cases to be delivered Three Months before Return.</head>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">31 Eliz. c. 3</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p7">And whereas it is agreeable to justice that Proceedings to Outlaries in Criminal Causes should be as publick and
notorious as in Civil Causes because the consequences to persons outlawed in Criminal Causes are more fatal and
dangerous to them and their posterities then in any other causes be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid
That upon the issueing of any Exigent out of any of Their Majesties Courts against any person or persons for
any Criminal matter before Judgment or Conviction there shall (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) issue [out<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] a Writt of Proclamation beareing the same
test and returne to the Sheriff or Sheriffs of (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) County City or Towne Corporate where the person or persons in
the Record of the said Proceedings is or are menc[i]oned to be or inhabit according to the forme of the Statute
made in the One and thirtieth yeare of the Reigne of the late Queene Elizabeth of blessed memory which Writt
of Proclamation shall be delivered to the said Sheriff or Sheriffs three months before the returne of the same.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. Continuance of Act.</head>
		<para id="p8">[Provided always and be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That this Act shall continue and be in force for
three years from the Five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety three and from thence
to the end of the next Session of Parliament and no longer.<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">bringing <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">Wills <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">alsoe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">This Proviso is annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
	</section>
</report>

