<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46397" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1693</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for the importation of fine Italian Sicilian and Naples Thrown Silke; [Rot. Parl. pt. 2. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">2 W. &amp; M. Sess 1. c. 9. &sect; 2.; 12 Car. II. c. 18.; Italian Silk may be imported</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act made in the Second yeare of their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for the
discourageing the importation of Throwne Silk (amongst other things in the said Act contained) the
bringing in of Throwne Silk of the growth or production of Italy Sicily or the Kingdom of Naples is prohibited
unlesse imported in such Ships or Vessells and navigated in such manner as in and by an Act made in the
Twelfth yeare of the Reigne of King Charles the Second entituled An Act for the encouragement and increasing
of the Shipping and Navigation is directed or allowed and brought from some of the Ports of those Countries or
Places whereof the same is of the Growth or Production and which shall come directly by Sea and not otherwise.
And whereas by the Act of Navigation Italian and Sicilian Thrown Silk may be brought from any Port or Place
of Europe and that it hath been found by experience that the importation of Italian Sicilian and Naples Silk by
the ways prescribed by the said recited Act (in regard of the great difficulties and hazard occasioned by the present
War with France is greatly prejudicial and if longer continued will endanger the losse of the Silk Manufactory of
this Nation be it therefore enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and
consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority
of the same That from and after the Twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred ninety and three it
shall and may be lawfull to and for any person or persons who do or shall reside in their Majesties Dominions to
import or bring into this Kingdom from any Port or Place whatsoever (excepting the Ports of France) dureing the
pressent Warr with France and Three months after fine Throwne Silk of the growth or production of Italy Sicily
or Naples any thing in the said recited Acts to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Coarse Silk, &amp;c. not to be imported.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided always That this Act nor any thing herein contained shall extend to give liberty to bring over land
and import any Italian throwne Silke that shall be courser then a sort thereof knowne [&amp; distinguished<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] by the
name of Third Bolonia Nor any Sicilian Throwne Silk that shall be courser then a sort thereof knowne and distinguished
by the name of Second Orsoy nor any sorts of Silks co[m]monly called Frams of the growth of Italy Sicily or
Naples nor any other Throwne Silk of the growth or production of Turkey Persia East-India or China under the
penalty and forfeiture of all such Throwne Silk as shall be brought over land and imported contrary to the purport
true intent and meaning of this Act one Moyety whereof shall be to the use of the King and Queens Majesties
their Heirs and Successors and the other moyety to such person or persons as shall seize informe or sue for the
same to bee recovered by Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on in any of their Majesties Courts of Record wherein noe
Essoign Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. All Italian Silk to be brought to the Custom-house, London.</head>
			<para id="p5">And for the better and more effectual execuc[i]on of this Act and to prevent the importac[i]on of any sort of
Thrown Silke contrary to the true intent and meaning hereof be it further enacted and declared That all such fine
Italian Sicilian and Naples Thrown Silks as are allowed to bee imported by this Act wheresoever landed shall be
brought to their Majesties Customhouse London to the intent that noe [other<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] sort may be imported over land
then those only allowed by this Act under the penalties and forfeitures before menc[i]oed and recited any thing to
the contrary hereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


