<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46396" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1693</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for repealing such parts of several former Acts as prevent or prohibit the importacion of Forreign Brandy Aqua vite and other Spirits and Bacon except from France [Chapter II. Rot. Parl. pl. 2. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 4 &amp; 5 (4) W. &amp; M. c. 5.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">4 &amp; 5 (4) W. &amp; M. c. 3.; and that the Grant thereby was ineffectual by reason of Importation by virtue of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 34. being prohibited.; 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 34. &sect; 8. prohibiting Importation of Brandy, repealed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by one Act of Parliament made in the Fourth and Fifth yeares of their Majesties Reigne entituled
An Act for granting to their Majesties certaine additional impositions upon several Goods and Merchandizes
for the prosecuteing the present Warr against France the Commons assembled in Parliament amongst other Duties
and Charges by the said Act granted to their Majesties upon Goods and Merchandizes imported after the first day
of March One thousand six hundred ninety two and before the first day of March One thousand six hundred
ninety six did grant to their Majesties for every Gallon of Strongwaters Aqua vite or Brandy comonly called
Single Brandy or Strongwaters imported within the said time to bee paid by the Importer before landing Two
shillings over and above the Duties of Excise and Customs att any time before the Second yeare of their Majesties
Reigne payable for the same And for every Gallon of Strongwaters Spirits or Brandy above proof called Double
Brandy imported within the said time to be paid by the Importer before landing Foure shillings over and above
the Duties of Excise and Customs att any time before the Second yeare of their Majesties Reigne payable for the
same And by one other Act in the same yeare made entituled An Act for granting to theire Majesties certaine
Rates and Duties of Excise upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for secureing certaine recompences and advantages
in the said Act menc[i]oed to such persons as shall voluntarily advance the su[m]m of Ten hundred thousand pounds
towards carrying on the Warr against France the said Commons did grant to their Majesties for every gallon of
Single Brandy Spirits or Aqua vite imported from beyond the Seas to be paid by the Importer before landing
over and above all other Duties payable for the same Six pence And for every Gallon of Brandy Spirits or
Aqua vite above proof commonly called Double Brandy imported from beyond the Seas to be paid by the
Importer before landing over and above all other Duties payable for the same One shilling which [Grant<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] contrary
to the intenc[i]on of the said Co[m]mons became ineffectual to their Majesties for that all importac[i]on of Brandy was
by one Act of Parliament made in the First yeare of their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for prohibiting all
Trade and Comerce with France prohibited to be imported into England and Ireland and the Dominions and
Islands therein named from and after the Foure and twentieth day of August in the yeare of oure Lord One
thousand six hundred eighty nine. For remedy whereof and that the Revenue ariseing by the said Grants may
be for the future answered to their Majesties according to the purport of the said first recited Acts be it enacted
by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and
Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same that one clause in
the said Act for prohibiting of all trade and co[m]merce with France in these words (that is to say) And be it further
enacted that no sort of Brandy Aqua vite or [other<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Spirits [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] distilled waters of any Kingdom Countrey or
place whatsoever shall after the said Foure and twentieth day of August bee imported into the Kingdoms of
England or Ireland aforesaid [Dominions<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] or Islands aforesaid under paine of forfeiture thereof as alsoe of the Ship
or Vessel wherein the same shall be imported is and shall be [by<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] virtue of this Act from the First day of this
present Session of Parliament repealed any thing in the said Act for prohibiting all trade and commerce with
France or any other Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The Duties of 4 &amp; 5 (4) W. &amp; M. c. 5. extended.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Spirits to be imported as by; 4 &amp; 5 (4) W. &amp; M. c. 25</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided always and be it enacted That the Duties of Two shillings and Foure shillings a Gallon upon Single
Brandy and Double Brandy respectively imposed by the said first recited Act above the Duties of Excise and
Customes att any time before the Second yeare of their Majesties Reigne payable for the same was thereby
intended and shall be construed to extend to such Duties as were then payable for the same by any Statute then
in force and not otherwise And that no sort of Brandy Aqua vite or other Spirits shall be imported from France
into this Kingdom or any of the Dominions and Territories thereunto belonging by virtue of this Act other then
as the same is provided and enacted to be imported by one Act of this present Parliament made in the said
Fourth and Fifth yeare of their Majesties [Raigne<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] entituled An Act for continuing the Acts for prohibiting all
trade and commerce with France and for the encouragement of Privateers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Recital that by 4 &amp; 5 (4) W. &amp; M. c. 5. Duty upon Bacon imported, was granted.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">18 Car. II. c. 2.; 20 Car. II. c. 7.; Duty on Bacon imported, continued</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And whereas there was further granted to their Majesties by the said first recited Act Foure pence for every
pound of Bacon imported within the time limited by the said Act which could not be answered to their Majesties
because the importac[i]on of Bacon is prohibited by One Act of Parliament made in the Eighteenth yeare of the
Reigne of the late King Charles the Second entituled An Act against importing Cattel from Ireland and other
parts beyond the Seas and Fish taken by Forreigners And by one other Act made in the twentieth yeare of his
said late Majesties Reigne entituled An additional Act against the importac[i]on of Forreigne Cattle be it enacted by
the authority aforesaid that the [said<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] su[m]m of Foure pence for every pound of Bacon imported granted to their
Majesties by the said Act shall be paid and answered to their Majesties from the First day of this present Session
of Parliament for and dureing the continuance of the said Act any thing in the said recited Acts of the Eighteenth
and Twentieth of the said King Charles the Second or any other Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Grants <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Dominion <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

