<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46392" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIII. An Act for the more easie discoverie and conviction of such as shall destroy the Game of this Kingdome.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Laws against Game not hereby repealed to be executed.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas diverse good and necessary Laws have been heretofore made for the better preservation of the
Game notwithstanding which Laws or for want of the due execuc[i]on thereof the Game of this Kingdome
hath been very much destroyed by many idle persons who afterwards betake themselves to Robberies Burglaries
or other like offences and neglect theire lawfull imployments. For remedy whereof and the more effectual
preservation of the Game be it enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent Majesties by and with the advice
and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the
authority of the same That all and every Law and Statute now in force for the better preservation of the Game
and every article and thing in them contained and not herein and hereby altered or repealed shall be duely put
in execuc[i]on according to the tenor of the said Laws and under the penalties therein contained to be raised levied
and disposed of as in and by the said Laws are directed.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Constable by Warrant from a Justice may search Houses of suspected Persons as by 3 &amp; 4 (3) W. &amp; M. c. 10.</head>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">If Hare, &amp;c. be found, and Owner not giving good Account, to be convicted by a Justice; Penalty.; Distress.; If no Distress, Imprisonment, &amp;c.; Unqualified Person having Greyhounds, &amp;c.; Penalty.; How convicted</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That for the more easie conviction of such Offenders as
by the said Laws are prohibited every Constable Headborough and Tythingman being thereunto authorized by
Warrant of one or more Justice of the Peace under his or their hands and seales shall and may have full power
and authority and is hereby required to enter into and search (in such manner and with such power as in and
by An Act for the more effectual discovery and punishment of Deer Stealers made in the Third and Fourth yeares
of Their present Majesties Reigne is provided in case of Venison or Skin of any Deer or Toyles) the House or
Houses Outhouses or other places belonging to such Houses of suspected persons not qualified as aforesaid And
in case any Hare Partridge Phesant Pidgeon Fish Fowle or other Game shall (upon such search or otherwise) be
found the Offender shall be carried before some Justice of Peace of the same County Riding or Division And if
such person doe not give a good account how hee came by such Hare Partridge Pheasant Pidgeon Fish Fowle
or other Game such as shall satisfie the said Justice or else shall not in some convenient time to be sett by the
said Justice produce the party of whom hee bought the same or some other credible person to depose upon oath
such sale thereof that then such person not giving such good account nor produceing [any<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] such Witnesse as
aforesaid shall be convicted by the said Justice of such Offence and upon such Conviction shall forfeit for every
Hare Partridge Phesant Pidgeon Fish Fowle or other Game any su[m]m not under five shillings and not exceeding
[the sume of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] twenty shillings to be ascertained by the said Justice one moiety thereof to be paid to the Informer
and the other moiety to the Poor of the Parish where the Offence was co[m]mitted the same to be levied by
distresse and sale of the Offenders goods by warrant under the hand and seale of the Justice before whom the
Offender shall be convicted rendring the overplus if any be And for want of distresse the Offender or Offenders
shall be co[m]mitted to the House of Correction for any time not exceeding one month and not lesse then ten days
there to be whipt and kept to Hard Labour And in case any person or persons not qualified by the Laws of this
Realme so to do shall have keep or use any Bows Greyhounds Setting Dogs Ferritts Coney Dogs Hayes Lurchers
Netts Tunnels Lowbels Hare-Pipes Snares or any other Instruments for destruction of Fish Fowle or other Game and
shall be thereof convicted upon such evidence as aforesaid the person or persons so convicted shall forfeit and be
subject to the same pains and penalties as are hereby directed to be inflicted upon the person or persons who shall
be found to have any Hare, Partridge Phesant Pidgeon Fish Fowle or other Game as aforesaid and if any person
or persons so produced or charged with the said Offence shall not before the same Justice give such evidence of his
innocence as aforesaid he shall be convicted thereof in the same manner as the person or persons first charged
therewith is hereby directed to be and soe from person to person until the first Offender shall be discovered.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Gamekeepers authorized by 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 25. &sect; 2. may oppose Persons in the Night.</head>
		<para id="p4">And to the end all Keepers and Gamekeepers mentioned in and duely authorized according to the Act made in
the Reigne of the late King Charles the Second may be indempnified in the execuc[i]on of the said Office be it
enacted that all Lords of Man[n]ors or other Royalties or any person or persons authorized by them as Game-keepers
shall and may within their respective Man[n]ors or Royalties oppose and resist such Offender in the night time in
the same manner and be equally indempnifyed for soe doeing as if such fact had been co[m]mitted within any ancient
Chase Parke or Warren inclosed whatsoever.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Persons not Owners of Fisheries, not to keep Nets, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">Owner of Fishery may seize Nets, &amp;c. used in his Fishery, and Persons authorized by him or other Persons by Warrant may search for Nets, and seize and dispose of them</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">And whereas diverse idle disorderly and mean persons have and keep Nets Angles Leaps Piches and other
Engines for the takeing and killing of Fish out of the Ponds Waters Rivers and other Fisheries to the damage of
the Owners thereof be it therefore enacted by the authority aforesaid That no person or persons whatsoever shall
and may att any time or times from and after the Five and twentieth day of March which shall be in the yeare
of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety three have or keep any Net Angle Leap Piche or other Engine for
the takeing of Fish (other then the Makers and Sellers thereof for their better conveniency in the sale of the same
And other then the Owner [&amp;<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Occupier of [any<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] River or Fishery for the time being) And moreover that it shall and
may be lawfull not onely for the Owner or Occupier of any River or Fishery and alsoe for all and every other person
and persons by him or them for that purpose appointed to seize detaine and keep to his and their owne use and
uses all and every Net Angle Leap Piche and other Engine which he or they shall find used or laid or in the
custody or possession of any person or persons whatsoever [fishing in any River or Fishery whatsoever<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] without
the consent of the Owner or Occupier thereof but alsoe for any person or persons whatsoever (being thereunto
authorized by Warrant under the hand and seale of any Justice of the Peace of the same County Division Burrough
Towne Corporate or any other place in the day time) to search the houses outhouses or other places of any person
or persons hereby prohibited to have or keep the same as shall be supected to have or keep in his or their
custody or possession any Nett Angle Leap Piche or other Engine aforesaid and the same and every or any of
them to seize detaine and keep to his and their owne use and uses or otherwise to cutt in peices or destroy as
things by this Act prohibited to be kept by persons of their degree.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. Proviso for Fishermen, &amp;c. lawfully authorized.</head>
		<para id="p7">Provided always that this Act or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be construed to extend to
abridge any Fisherman or his Apprentice or Apprentices lawfully authorized to fish in Navigable Rivers or Waters
with lawfull nets and engines but that every of them shall and may (according to the laws and orders made
and to be made and settled for the good order rule and government of such Navigable Rivers and Waters use the
trade of Fishing as they lawfully might have done before the makeing of this Act any thing in this Act contained
to the contrary [in any wise<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. No Certiorari on Conviction, excep Party convicted give &pound;50 Securit to pay Costs.</head>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">No double Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p9">And whereas diverse Offenders duely convicted do comonly p[ro]cure Writts of Certiorari to remove such convictions
into superiour Courts att Westminster in hopes thereby to discourage and weary out such persons injured by great
delays expences and incertainties be it therefore enacted That no Certiorari shall be allowed to remove any conviction
made or other proceeding of for or concerning any matter or thing in this Act unlesse the partie or parties
against whom such conviction shall be made shall before the allowance of such Certiorari become bound to the
person or persons prosecuteing in the su[m]m of Fifty pounds with such sufficient Sureties as the [Justice or<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Justices
of the Peace before whom such Offender was convicted shall think fitt with condition to pay unto the said
Prosecutors (within one month after such conviction confirmed or Procedendo granted) their full Costs and Charges
to be ascertained upon their Oaths And that in default thereof it shall be lawfull for the said Justice and Justices
and others to proceed to the due execuc[i]on of such conviction in such manner as if no Certiorari had been
awarded. Provided That where any Offender shall be punished by force of this Act (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) hee shall not be prosecuted
nor incurr the penalty of any other Law or Statute for the same Offence.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. In Actions for executing Act,</head>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">General Issue may be pleaded.; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p11">Provided [alwaies<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] That if any Action Bill Plaint or Suite shall att any time after the said Five and twentieth
day of March be co[m]menced or brought against any person or persons whatsoever for or by reason of any matter
or thing which hee or they shall doe in pursuance of this Act it shall and may be lawfull to and for the person
or persons so sued or prosecuted to plead the General Issue and give this Act or any other special matter in
evidence And if the Verdict shall passe with the Defendant or Defendants in such Action or the Plaintiff or Plaintiffs
become nonsuit or suffer any [discontinuance<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] thereof that in [any<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] such case such Defendant or Defendants shall
have his or their treble costs which he or they shall have sustained in defence of such Action or Suit for which
the said Defendant or Defendants shall have the like remedy as in other cases where costs by the Laws of this
Realme are given to the Defendants.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. Inferior Tradesmen, &amp;c. hunting.</head>
		<para id="p12">
			<emph type="i">Penalties, and Trespass also lies</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p13">And whereas great mischiefs doe ensue by inferiour Tradesmen Apprentics and other dissolute persons-neglecting
their Trades and Employments who follow Hunting Fishing and other Game to the ruine of themselves and
damage of their Neighbours For Remedy whereof Be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any such
person as aforesaid shall presume to hunt hawke fish or fowle (unlesse in company with the Master of such
Apprentice duely qualified by law) such person or persons shall be subject to the penalties of this Act and shall
or may be sued and prosecuted for their wilfull Trespasse in such their comeing on any persons land and if
found guilty thereof the plaintiffe shall not only recover his damages thereby sustained but his full Costs of suit
Any former law to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>IX. Burning Ling, &amp;c. upon Heaths.</head>
		<para id="p14">
			<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p15">[Provided always and be it enacted That for the better preserving the red and black Game of Growse co[m]monly
called Heath Cocks or Heath Polts no person whatsoever on any Mountaines Hills Heaths Moors Forests Chases
or other Wasts shall presume to burne between the second day of February and Twenty fourth of June any
Grig Ling Heath Furz Gosse or Ferne upon pain that the offender or offenders shall be committed to the
House of Correction for any tyme not exceeding one month and not lesse then ten days there to be whipt and
kept to hard labour.<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">a <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">that <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">discountenance, in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">every <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n7" number="7">This Proviso is annexed in a separate Schedule to the Original Act.</note>
	</section>
</report>


