<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46395" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1693</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for granting to Their Majesties an Aid of Foure Shillings in the Pound for One yeare for carrying on a vigorous War against France [Rot. Parl. pt. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>All Persons for Personal Estate</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">(Exception); to pay 4s. in the Pound; that is, 24s. for every &pound;100 worth</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee Your Majesties most dutiful and loyal Subjects the Co[m]mons assembled in Parliament acknowledging with
all humility and thankfulnesse Your Majesties abundant care of our Preservation and being deeply sensible
of that extraordinary Charge and Expence with which Your Majesties present occasions are to be supported for
the necessary Defence of Your Realms and the Prosecution of a vigorous War against France both by Sea and
Land have chearfully and unanimously given and granted and do hereby give and grant unto Your most excellent
Majesties the Rates and Assessments herein after menc[i]oed to be raised and levied in manner following and do
most humbly beseech Your Majesties that it may be enacted. And be it enacted by the King and Queens most
excellent Majesties by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and of the Co[m]mons
in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That Their Majesties shall have and receive
the Rates and Assessments hereafter menc[i]oed of and from every Person Spiritual and Temporal of what Estate
or Degree soever he or they be which said Rates or Assessments shall be taxed assessed levied and paid into Theire
Majesties Receipt of the Exchequer according to the Tenor of this Act and in manner and forme following that is
to say that all and every Person and Persons Bodies Politick and Corporate Guilds and Fraternities within this
Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed having any Estate in ready moneys
or in any Debts whatsoever oweing to them within this Realm or without or having any Estate in Goods Wares
Merchandizes or other Chattells or personal Estate whatsoever within this Realm or without belonging to or in
trust for them (except and out of the Premisses deducted such su[m]ms of money as he or they do bona fide owe
and such Debts oweing to them as shall be adjudged desperate by the Co[m]missioners appointed by this Act And
also the Stock upon Lands and such Goods as are used for houshold stuff) shall yeild and pay unto Their
Majesties Foure shillings in the Pound according to the true yearly value thereof for one yeare (that is to say)
for every Hundred pounds of such ready money and debts and for every Hundred pounds worth of such Goods
Wares Merchandizes or other Chattells or other personal Estate the sum of Foure and twenty shillings and so
after that rate for every greater or lesser su[m]m or [quantity<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to be assessed levied and collected in manner hereafter
menc[i]oed</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Public Offices, (Exception of Military Officers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and certain Persons of the Ordnance,); to pay 4s. in the Pound</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons Co[m]missioner or
Co[m]missioners having useing or exercising any publick Office or Employment of Profit (such Military Officers who
are or shall be in muster by the Muster Master General of the Army or in pay in Their Majesties Army or
Navy in respect of such Offices only excepted (other then Governors Deputy or Lieutenant Governors of any
Their Majesties Garrisons Forts or Castels for their Salaries or pay for the same Governments) And alsoe except
such persons in Their Majesties Ordnance whose Salaries doe not exceed One hundred pounds per Annum) and
all and every their Agents Clerks Secundaries Substitutes and other inferiour Ministers whatsoever shall yield and
pay unto Their Majesties the su[m]m of Foure shillings for every Twenty shillings which he or they do receive in
One yeare by virtue of any salary gratuity bounty-money reward fees or profitts to him or them accrewing for
or by reason or occasion of their several offices or employments to be assessed imposed levied and collected in
such manner as hereafter is menc[i]oed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">All Manors, Lands, &amp;c.; as well within ancient Demesne as other Liberties, charged with 4s. in the Pound.; Bodies Politic, &amp;c. having Manors, &amp;c.; to pay 4s. in the Pound; as if let at a Rack Rent, without respect to present Rents, or Monies laid out on Improvements or Repairs, Taxes, &amp;c.; to be paid quarterly</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And to the end a further Aid and Supply for Their Majesties occasions may be raised by a charge upon all
Lands Tenements and Hereditaments with as much equality and indeferrence as is possible by a Pound Rate of
Foure shillings for every Twenty shillings of the true yearly value for One yeare and noe longer be it further
enacted by the authority aforesaid That all and every Mannors Messuags Lands and Tenements as alsoe all
Quarries Mines of Coale Tin or Lead Copper Mundick-Iron or other Mines Iron Works Salt Springs and Salt
Works all Allom Mines or Works all Parks Chases Warrens Woods Underwoods Coppices and all Fishings Tythes
Tolls Annuities and all other yearely Profitts and all Hereditaments of what nature or kind soever they be scituate
lying and being happening or ariseing within the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick
upon Tweed or within any the Counties Cities Boroughs Townes Divisions Ridings Hundreds Lathes Wapentakes
Parishes and Places thereof as well within ancient Demesne and other Liberties and Priveledged Places as without
shall be and are hereby charged for One yeare only and no longer with the su[m]m of Foure shillings for every
Twenty shillings of the full yearely value and so in proportion for any greater or lesser value and all and every
person and persons Bodies Politick and Corporate Guilds Mysteries Fraternities and Brotherhoods whether Corporate
or not Corporate having or holding any Mannors Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments or other the Premisses
shall yeild and pay unto Their Majesties the su[m]m of Foure shillings for every Twenty shillings by the yeare
which the said Manors Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and other the Premisses are now worth to be
leased if the same were truely and bona fide leased or demised att a Rack Rent and according to the full true
yearely value thereof without any respect had to the present Rents reserved for the same if such Rents have
been reserved upon such Leases or Estates made for which any Fine or Income hath been paid or secured or
have been lessened or abated upon considerac[i]on of money laid out or to be laid out in improvements and without
any respect had to any former Rates or Taxes thereupon imposed or makeing any abatement in respect of
Reparations Taxes Parish Duties or any other charges whatsoever which said su[m]m of Four and twenty shillings
for the yearely profitt of every Hundred pounds value of all Personal Estates as aforesaid and Foure shillings
for every Twenty shilings by the yeare of the said true yearely value of all other the Premisses
shall be assessed levied and collected in manner hereafter menc[i]oed and shall be paid into the Receipt of
Their Majesties Exchequer by Foure Quarterly Payments the first payment thereof to be made upon the Six
and twentieth day of March which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and
foure.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso where Lands subject to Rent Charges, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Landlords may deduct 4s. in the Pound,; to be allowed by Persons entitled to such Rent Charges, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And whereas many of the Mannors Messuags Lands Tenements Tythes Hereditaments and Premisses intended
by this Act to be charged with the Pound Rates as aforesaid stand incumbred with or are subject and liable to
the payment of several Rent-charges or Annuities issueing out of the same or to the payment of diverse Fee-farme
Rents Rents Service or other Rents thereupon reserved or charged by reason whereof the true Owners and
Proprietors of such Manors Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses do not in truth receive to
their owne use the true yearely value of the same for which neverthelesse they are by this Act charged to pay
the full Pound Rate of Foure shillings for every Twenty shillings of the true yearly value It is therefore declared
and enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Landlords Owners and
Proprietors of such Mannors Messuags Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses as are charged with the
Pound Rate as aforesaid to abate and deduct [&amp; to<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] retaine and keep in his or their hands Foure shillings in
the Pound for every Fee farme Rent or other annual Rent or Payment charged upon or issueing out of the
Premisses or any part thereof or thereupon reserved And all and every person and persons who are or shall be
any way intituled to such Rents and annual payments are hereby required to allow such deductions and payments
upon the receipt of the residue of such moneys as shall be due and payable to them for such Rents or annual
payments reserved or charged as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Commissioners under 4 W. &amp; M. c. 1.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">to be Commissioners for executing this Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That for the better [ordering assessing<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] levying and collecting
of the several su[m]ms of money so as aforesaid limitted and appointed to bee paid and for the more effectual putting
of this present Act in execu[i]n all and every the persons that were named and appointed Co[m]missioners of and
for the execu[i]n of the Act made in the Fourth year of Their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for granting
to Their Majesties an Aid of Foure shillings in the pound for One yeare for carrying on a vigorous War against
France and shall be qualified according to the directions of this Act shall be Co[m]missioners for putting in execu[i]n
this present Act and the powers therein contained within all and every the several and respective Counties
Riding Cities Cinque Ports [Towns Boroughs<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] and Places for which they were appointed Co[m]missioners in the
aforesaid Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Commissioners to meet in the several Counties, &amp;c. upon the 20th Feb. 1693;</head>
			<para id="p11"><emph type="i">and may subdivide themselves</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said Co[m]missioners so as aforesaid nominated and
appointed shall (in the respective Counties Ridings Cities Boroughs Divisions Towns and Places (for which they
are appointed Co[m]missioners respectively) meet together att the most usual and co[m]mon place of meeting within each
of the said Counties Cities Boroughs Divisions Towns and Places respectively upon the Twentieth day of February
which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety &amp; three and the said Co[m]missioners
or so many of them as shall be present att the said first General Meeting or the major part of them are
hereby authorized and required to put this present Act in execu[i]n according to the best of their judgments and
discretions and shall then if they shall see cause subdivide and distribute as well themselves as other Co[m]missioners
then not present for the execu[i]n of this Act into lesser numbers so as Three or more of the said Co[m]missioners
may be appointed for the service of each Hundred or other Division and so as may best conduce to the carrying
on of Their Majesties service hereby required.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Commissioners at their Meeting to set down in Writing what Number of Commissioners shall act in each Division; and deliver Copy thereof to Receiver General.</head>
			<para id="p13">And for the more effectual performance hereof be it enacted and declared by the authority aforesaid That the
Co[m]missioners att their first General Meeting or the major part of them present shall agree and sett down in
writeing who and what number of the said Commissioners shall act in each of the said Divisions or Hundreds
neverthelesse not thereby to restrain the said Co[m]missioners from acting as Co[m]missioners in any other
part of the County or place for which they are nominated and deliver a true copy of such writing to the
Receiver General to the end that there be no failure in any parte of the due execuc[i]on of the service by this Act
required.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Commissioners to direct Precepts to Inhabitants, &amp;c. requiring them to appear; then to read the Rates, and charge them how to make Certificates, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Persons absenting; Penalty.; At or after such General Meeting Commissioners to direct Warrants for Assessors; and to prefix a Day and Place to bring in Certificates of Names of Persons and of Personal Estate, Offices, &amp;c.; Assessors to inform themselves by all lawful Ways of the full yearly Value of Manors and Hereditaments; and then to assess 4s. per Pound of full yearly Value; and to bring at time prefixed a Certificate of Assessment; and to return Collectors; for whose Payment to the Head Collectors, Parish to be answerable.; Assessors neglecting or refusing to serve, or making Default; Penalty; Distress; charged upon Receiver General.; Every Assessor, before he acts, to take the Oaths of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 8.</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said Co[m]missioners shall direct their several or
joynt Precept or Precepts to such Inhabitants High-Constables Petty Constables Bayliffs and other like Officers and
Ministers and such number of them as they in their discretion shall think [most<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] convenient requireing them to
appear before the said Co[m]missioners att such place and time (not exceeding Ten days) as they shall appoint And
att such their appearances the said Comissioners shall openly read or cause to bee read unto them the Rates and
Assessments in this Act mentiond and alsoe openly declare the effect of their Charge to them and how and in
what manner they ought and should make their Certificates and how they ought to proceed in the execu[i]n of
this Act according to the Rates aforesaid And if any High Constables Petty-Constables Bayliffs Inhabitants or
other Officers or Ministers to whom any Precept shall be directed shall absent themselves without lawfull excuse
to be made out by the oaths of Two credible Witnesses (which oaths the Co[m]missioners or any Two of them are
hereby impowered to administer) or if any person appearing shall refuse to serve then every such person soe
makeing default or refuseing to serve shall for every time of such default or refusal forfeit and lose unto Their
Majesties such su[m]ms as the Co[m]missioners or so many as shall be present or the major part of them being present
shall think fitt not exceeding the su[m]m of Five pounds nor lesse then Fourty shillings And att and after such
General Meeting had and Charge given as aforesaid the said Co[m]missioners shall take care that Warrants be issued
forth and directed to Two att the least of the most able and sufficient Inhabitants of each Parish Townshipp or
Place within the respective Divisions thereby appointing and requireing them to be Assessors of all and every the
Rates and Duties by this Act imposed and shall therein also appoint and prefix a certain day and place for the
said Assessors to appeare before them and to bring in their Certificates in writing of the names and sirnames of
every person dwelling and residing within the limitts of those places with which they shall be charged and of
the substance and values of every of them in ready money debts goods chattels or other personal estate whatsoever
(except before excepted) or in publick offices or imployments of profitt And the said Assessors are therein also
to be required and are hereby injoyned to ascertain and informe themselves by all lawfull ways and means they
can of the true and full yearely value of all Mannors [Lands Messuages<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] and Tenements as alsoe of all Quarries
Mines of Coal Tin or Lead Copper Mundick or other Mines Iron Works Salt-Works Salt Springs Allom Mines
and Works Parks Chases Warrens Woods Underwoods and Coppices and all Fyshings Tyths Tolls Annuities and
other yearely profitts And of all Hereditaments of what nature or kind soever scituate lyeing and being happening
or ariseing within the limitts of those places with which they shall be charged And being so thereof ascertained
they are to assess all and every the said Mannors Messuages Lands Tenements and Premisses before appointed to be
charged after the rate of Foure shillings for every Twenty shillings of the full yearely value as the same are let
for or worth to be lett att the time of assessing thereof as aforesaid And to bring with them att the time and
place so as aforesaid prefixed for their appearance a Certificate in writeing of the said Assessment And shall then
alsoe returne the names of Two or more able and sufficient persons liveing within the limitts and bounds of
those Parishes Towneships Constablewicks or Places where they shall be chargeable respectively to be Collectors of
the moneys to bee paid to Their Majesties by this Act for whose paying in to the Head Collector in manner
hereafter mentioned such moneys as they shall be charged withall the Parish or Place wherein they are so imployed
shall be answerable And if any Assessor soe as aforesaid appointed or to be appointed shall neglect or refuse
to serve or shall make default att the time appointed for his appearance (not having a lawfull excuse to be
witnessed by the oaths of Two credible Witnesses which the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them
have power to administer) or shall not performe his duty every such Assessor shall for every such neglect refusal
or default forfeit and lose unto Their Majesties such su[m]m as the Co[m]missioners or so many of them as shall be
present or the major part of them shall think fitt not exceeding [the<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] su[m]m of Twenty pounds nor under the su[m]m
of Ten pounds to be levied by distresse and sale of the Offenders Goods and Chattells in like manner as by this
Act is appointed for levying the several Rates and Assessments herein mentioned in case of neglect or refusal of
payment and to be charged upon the respective Receivers General together with the said Rates and Assessments
And every Assessor so as aforesaid appointed or to be appointed shall before he take upon him the execuc[i]on
of the said Imploym[en]t: take the oaths mentioned and required to be taken by an Act made in the Parliament held
in the first yeare of Their Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for the abrogateing the oaths of Supremacy and
Allegiance and appointing other oaths and alsoe take an oath to be administred in these words following, You
shall swear well and truely to execute the duty of an Assessor and to cause the Rates and Duties imposed by an
Act entituled An Act for granting to Their Majesties an aid of Four shillings in the pound for [One yeare for<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]
carrying on a vigorous War against France to be duely and impartially assessed according to the best of your skill
and Knowledge and therein you shall spare no Person for Favour or Affection nor any Person grieve for Hatred
or Ill-will. So help you God. (Which Oaths any Two or more of the Co[m]missioners in the County City or Place
where the said Assessment is to be made have hereby power and are hereby required to administer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Certificates of Assessments to be returned to the Commissioners before 5th Day of March 1693, unless they give further time.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">On Return of Certificates.; Commissioners or any Three may examine Presenters.; If Commissioners suspect that Persons, &amp;c. are omitted, or the Value of Lands.; they may summmon Party to be examined.; Persons summoned not appearing; Penalty.; Commissioners may examine into Value of Premises, and set Rates accordingly.; Assessors to give one Copy of Assessments to Commissioners.; who are to sign and seal Duplicates; One delivered to Sub-collectors.; others to Head Collectors and Receivers General.; Commissioners to cause Extracts of Sums charged, &amp;c. to be certified into Exchequer before 20th Day of March, or within 30 Days after.; King's Remembrancer, within Three Months, to transcribe Duplicates, &amp;c. and transmit to the Auditor of Exchequer, who is to enter the same</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Rates and Assessments upon all ready Monies
Debts Goods Chattells Personal Estates and Publick Offices and Imployments of Profitt charged by this Act shall
be ascertained and the Certificates thereof returned to the Commissioners upon or before the Fifth day of March
One thousand six hundred ninety and three unlesse the Commissioners shall think fitt to give a further time
And alsoe the taxations and assessments of the Pound Rate of Foure shillings in the pound of the yearely value
of all Manors Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses charged by this Act shall be made
and ascertained and the several and respective Certificates thereof returned into the Co[m]missioners upon or before
the Fifth day of March aforesaid unlesse the Commissioners shall think fitt to give further time And upon returne
of any such Certificate the Co[m]missioners or any Three or more of them shall and may (if they see cause) examine
the p[re]senters thereof And if the said Co[m]missioners or any three or more of them within their several Limitts att
the time of the returne of the certificates as aforesaid or within Twenty days after shall know or have good
cause to suspect that any person or persons or any the Manors Messuages Lands or other the Premisses which ought
to be mentioned and charged in the said Certificates is or are omitted or that any person or persons in the
said Certificates mentioned is or are of a greater Estate or that any the said Manors or other Premisses are of a
greater yearely value then in the said Certificate is menc[i]oed the said Co[m]missioners or any three or more of them
shall have power to su[m]mon such person or persons and the Owners and Possessors of such Ma[n]nors or other
Premisses to appear before them att a day and place prefixed to be examined touching the Matters aforesaid And
if the person or persons su[m]mmoned to be soe examined shall neglect to appeare (not having a reasonable excuse
for such his default every person soe makeing default shall pay to their Majesties double the su[m]m hee should
or ought to have been set att or rated And moreover the Commissioners or the major part of so many of
them as shall be present shall have power by all lawfull ways and means to examine into the estate of such
person and the value of such Premisses chargeable by this Act and to sett such Rate or Rates upon the same
as shall be according to the true intent of this Act And the said Assessors are hereby required to give one
Copy of their Certificates or Assessm[ent]: fairely written and subscribed by them unto the said Co[m]missioners by
whom they were appointed and the said Co[m]missioners or any two or more of them are hereby ordered and required
to cause the said several and respective Assessments to them delivered (when by them approved of or altered
according to the true intent of this Act) to be fairely written and to sign and seale several Duplicates or Copies
of the said Assessment and one of them so signed and sealed forthwith to deliver or cause to be delivered unto
the Subcollectors and shall likewise deliver or cause to be delivered other Copies thereof so signed and sealed
unto the Head Collectors and Receivers General according to their several [respective<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] collections and receipts
And moreover the said Co[m]missioners shall cause a true Copy or Extract of the whole sums assessed and charged
within every Hundred Lathe Wapentake Parish Ward or Place rated or assessed in pursuance of this Act and of
the whole su[m]ms rated or assessed upon Personal Estates Offices or Imployments to be certified and transmitted
into their Majesties Court of Exchequer under the hands and seals of any two or more of the Commissioners but
without nameing the persons in such their Certificates And this the said Commissioners shall cause to be done
upon or before the Twentieth day of March then next ensuing or within Thirty days after (all appeals to them
made being first determined) And the Kings Remembrancer in the Exchequer for the time being shall and is
hereby required within Three Months after the duplicates of the last payment shall be tra[n]smitted to him to
transcribe all the Schedules and Duplicates of the su[m]ms returned to him from and for every respective County
Riding City and Towne and every Hundred Wapentake Parish Division Town and Place therein in a Book of
Parchment in Alphabetical Order and in a faire legible Hand Writeing and within Three Months after the same
shall be so by him received to transmitt all and every the same Schedules and Duplicates to the Office of
Writer of the Tallies co[m]monly called The Auditor of the Receipt of the Exchequer who is hereby likewise
authorized and required to enter the same in the like Alphabetical Order in another Book of Parchment fairely
written to bee provided for that purpose.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Commissioners to issue Warrants to Sub-collectors for levying, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Sub-collectors to levy and collect according to their. Duplicates, and to make Demand of Rates of Parties, or at last Place of Abode.; Head Collectors to hasten Sub-collectors.; In case of Neglect of Sub-collectors, Levy by Distress.; Head Collectors to pay in to Receiver General on or before the 20th of March.; Receiver to pay into Exchequer on or before 26th March 1694.; Time for the Second Quarterly Payment.; Head Collectors to pay to Receiver General, who is to pay into the Exchequer.; Time for the Third Quarterly Payment.; Head Collectors to hasten Sub-collectors, and to proceed by Distress.; Head Collector to pay to Receiver General.; Receiver General to hasten Head Collectors, and pay into Exchequer.; Time for the last Quarterly Payment.; Head Collectors to pay to Receiver General, who is to pay into Exchequer.; All Persons concerned in the execution of this Act to use Diligence, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Commissioners or any Two or more of them
shall issue out their Warrants or Estreats to the Subcollectors under their Hands and Seals thereby requiring
them to levy and collect one fourth part of the Rates and Assessments in respect of their Personal Estates Offices
and Imployments and alsoe one fourth part of the Pound Rate charged upon all Mannors Messuages Lands
Tenements and Hereditaments and Premisses as aforesaid And the said Subcollectors are hereby required and
enjoyned to levy and collect the same according to the Duplicates thereof by them received and according to the
intent and directions of this Act and to make demand of the said Rates and Assessments upon Personal Estates
Offices and Imployments of the Parties themselves if they can be found or otherwise att the place of their last abode
and to pay the same unto their respective Head Collectors on, or before the Fifteenth day of March One
thousand six hundred ninety three or within Twenty days after And the said Head Collectors are to hasten the
said Subcollectors And in case the same shall not be collected by reason of neglect or failure of Duty of the said
Subcollectors the said Head Collectors are to levy by warrant under the hands and seals of any two or more of
the said Co[m]missioners by distresse upon the Subcollectors respectively such sum and su[m]ms of money as by him and
them ought to have been paid and is or are not paid by reason of his failure in doeing his duty according to the
directions of this Act And every Head Collector is hereby required to make payment of what shall be so levied
or received unto the Receiver General of the said County City or Place upon or before the Twentieth day of March
aforesaid or within Twenty days after And the Receiver General is likewise required to call upon and hasten the
said Head Collectors and to pay what hee shall receive from the said Head Collectors unto their Majesties Receipt
of Exchequer upon or before the Six and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety foure or within
Twenty days after to the end the First payment of the said Rates and Assessments may by that time be fully
answered and paid into their Majesties And the Subcollectors shall also levy the Second quarterly payment of
the said Rates and Assessments charged as aforesaid upon or before the Second day of June then next ensueing or
within Twenty days after and shall alsoe pay the same in to the Head Collectors upon or before the Ninth day of
June aforesaid or within Twenty days after And the said Head Collectors shall make payment thereof to the Receivers
General of the said County City or Place upon or before the Sixteenth day of June aforesaid or within Twenty
days after And the said Receiver General is alsoe required to make payment of all which hee shall so receive into
Their Majesties Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the Five and twentieth day of June aforesaid or within Twety
days after to the end that the second payment of the Rates and Assessments so charged as aforesaid may by that
time be fully answered and paid into Their Majesties And the said Subcollectors are alsoe required and enjoyned
to levy one other quarterly payment of the said Rates and Assessments charged as aforesaid upon or before the
Fourth day of September then next ensueing and shall alsoe pay the same unto the said respective Head Collector
on or before the Twelfth day of September aforesaid or within Twenty days after And the said Head Collectors
are to hasten the said Subcollectors And in case the same shall not be collected by reason of neglect or failure of
duty in the said Subcollectors the Head Collectors [are<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] to proceed against them by distresse in like manner and by
like Warrant as aforesaid And every Head Collector is hereby required to make payment of what shall be so levied
or received unto the Receiver General of the said County City or Place upon or before the Twentieth day of
September aforesaid or within Twenty days after And the Receiver General is likewise required to call upon and
hasten the said Head Collectors and to pay what hee shall receive from the said Head Collectors into Their Majesties
Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the Nine and twentieth day of September aforesaid or within Twenty days
after to the end that the third payment of the said Rates and Assessments may by that time be fully answered
and paid into their Majesties And the Subcollectors shall alsoe levy one other quarterly payment of the said Rates
and Assessments charged as aforesaid upon or before the Third day of December then next ensueing or within
Twenty days after and shall also pay the same unto the said Head Collectors upon or before the Tenth day of
December aforesaid or within Twenty days after And the said Head Collectors shall make payment thereof to the
Receiver General of the said County City or Place upon or before the Seventeenth day of December aforesaid or
within Twenty days after And the said Receiver General is likewise required to make payment of all which he
shall so receive into their Majesties Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the Five and twentieth day of December
aforesaid or within Twenty days after to the end that the fourth and last quarterly payment of the said Rates and
Assessments so charged as aforesaid may by that time be fully answered and paid in to their Majesties And all
Co[m]missioners Collectors and Receivers are hereby required and enjoyned to apply themselves with all diligence to
the most speedy and effectual execu[i]n of their several and respective Duties and to use their utmost endeavors
that all Estates herein charged may equally pay the Rates and Assessments according to the direction of this Act
that so their Majesties Service herein may not be delayed or hindred [throug<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] any of their wilful neglect or
default.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Head Collector's Receipt a discharge to Sub-collector.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Sub-collector to have Threepence in the Pound.; Head Collector to pay to and be appointed by Receiver General.; Sub-collector travelling.; Receiver General's Acquittance a Discharge, who is to pay into Exchequer.; Allowance to Receiver General</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And it is further enacted and declared by the authority aforesaid That the Monies received by the Subcollectors
within their respective Divisions or Hundreds shall from time be duely paid to the Head Collectors whose
Receipt shall be a sufficient discharge unto every such Subcollector which Subcollector for gathering the said
particular su[m]ms shall retaine in his Hands for every Twenty shillings by him soe paid Three pence as a
reward for his pains and service And the said Head Collectors shall accordingly pay over the said monies
unto the Receiver General of each County City or Place respectively in manner aforesaid which Head Collector
or Collectors shall be nominated and appointed by the Receiver General of the respective Counties which
said Receiver General shall be answerable for all such sums of money as shall be by him or them [received or
collected<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] And that noe Subcollector shall be forced to travel above the space of Ten miles for the payment
of the said monies that shall be by him collected or received And the said Receiver Generals Acquittance shall
be a sufficient discharge unto every such Head Collector And the Receiver General shall pay the whole sum
by him received into the Receipt of their Majesties Exchequer in such manner and att or before such days
and times as are herein before limitted and shall have an allowance of Two pence in the pound for all
monies which shall be by him paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer upon or before the times prefixt in
this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Commissioners Clerks to have 1d. per Pound for writing Warrants, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p22">And for the careful writeing and transcribing the said Warrants Certificates Estreats and Duplicates in due time
it is further enacted That the Commissioners Clerks who shall respectively performe the same shall by Warrant under
Two or more of the Commissioners hands have and receive from the respective Receivers General One peny in the
pound of all such moneys as he or they shall have received by virtue of such Warrants and Estreats who are
hereby appointed and allowed to pay the same accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Persons neglecting to pay Rates; Collectors to distrain,</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">and to keep the Distress Four Days at Owner's Charge; then to be appraised and sold, and Overplus restored.; Breaking open Houses, Chests, &amp;c. in the Day-time. Calling to Assistance Constables, &amp;c.; Tenants to pay Rates, and to deduct out of Rent; Landlord to allow such Deductions</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And be it further enacted and declared That if any person or persons shall refuse [or neglect<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] to pay any
sum or su[m]ms of money whereat he or they shall be rated and assessed that then it shall and may be lawfull to and
for the said Collectors or any of them and [hee<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] and they is and are hereby authorized and required for non
payment thereof to levy the su[m]m or su[m]ms so rated and assessed by distresse and sale of the Goods and Chattells
of such person so refuseing or neglecting to pay by his or their Goods or Chattells or to distrain upon the Messuages
Lands Tenements and Premisses so charged with any such su[m]m or sums and the Goods and Chattells then and
there found and the distresse so taken to keep by the space of Foure days at the Costs and Charges of the
Owners thereof and if the said Owner do not pay the su[m]m or sums of money so rated and assessed within the
space of the said Foure Days then the said Distresse to be appraised by Two or Three Inhabitants where the same
shall be taken or other sufficient persons and to be sold by the Collectors for the payment of the said money And
[the<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Overplus comeing by such sale (if any be over and above the charges of takeing and keeping of the
distresse) to be immediately returned to the Owner thereof And moreover it shall be lawfull to break open (in the
Day time) any House and (upon Warrant under the Hands and Seals of Two or more of the said Co[m]missioners)
any Chest [Trunk<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Box or other things where any such Goods are calling to their assistance the Constable
Tythingmen and Headboroughs within the Counties Cities Towns and Places where any refusal neglect or resistance
shall be made Which said Officers are hereb required to be aiding and assisting in the Premisses as they will
answer the contrary att their peril and the several and respective Tenant or Tenants of all Houses Lands Tenements
and Hereditaments which shall bee rated by virtue of this Act are hereby required and authorized to pay such
sum or su[m]ms of money as shall be rated upon such Houses Lands Tenements or Hereditaments and to deduct
out of the Rents soe much of the said Rates as in respect of the said Rents of every such House Lands
Tenements or Hereditaments the Landlord should or ought to pay and beare And the said Landlords both mediate
and immediate according to their respective interests are hereby required to allow such deductions in payments
upon the receipt of the residue of their Rents.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Tenant paying acquitted.</head>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Persons aggrieved may complain to Commissioners, who may examine on Oath.; Commissioners to meet to determine Appeals</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">And it is enacted and declared That every Tenant paying the said Assessments shall be acquitted and discharged
for soe much money as the said Assessments shall amount unto as if the same had been actually paid unto such
Person and Persons unto whom his Rents should have been due and payable And if any Person or Persons so
rated or charged doe find him or themselves agrieved with such [assessing<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] or rateing and do within Ten days
after demand made of the su[m]m or su[m]ms of money assessed on him or them complain to the Co[m]missioners the said
Co[m]missioners or any Three or more of them so as the major part of the Comissioners who signed or allowed
his or their Rates be present shall have and have hereby power with Ten days next after such Complaint
particularly to examine any Person or Persons upon his or their Oath touching the value of his or their real or
personal Estate and other the matters aforesaid and upon due examinac[i]on and knowledge thereof allow abate
defaulk encrease or enlarge the said Assessment and the same so allowed abated encreased or enlarged shall be
levied and shall be certified or estreated into the Exchequer in manner aforesaid and to that end the said
Co[m]missioners are hereby required to meet together for the determining of such Complaints and Appeals accordingly
and for this end to expresse in their Warrants to the Collectors the times and Places for determining Appeals
and Appeals once heard and determined to bee final without any further Appeal upon any pretence whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Assessor, &amp;c. neglecting or refusing to do his Duty; Commissioners to fine not exceeding &pound;20, nor under &pound;10.; Distress.; Fines paid to Receiver General, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p27">And be it further enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid That if any Assessor Collector Receiver or
other Person appointed by the said Co[m]missioners shall wilfully neglect or refuse to performe his or their duty in
the due and speedy execuc[i]on of this present Act or if any Assessor shall wittingly or willingly under rate or
assesse att an under value any Person or Thing chargeable by this Act the said respective Co[m]missioners or any
Three or more of them have hereby power to impose on such Person or Persons soe refuseing neglecting or not
performeing their Duties such Fine or Fines as by them shall be thought fitt so as the same exceed not the su[m]m of
Twenty Pounds nor to be under the sum of Ten Pounds which said Fines shall not bee taken off or discharged
but by the consent of the majority of the Co[m]missioners who imposed the same but shall be levyed by Warrant under
the Hands and Seals of the said Co[m]missioners or any Two of them by distresse and sale of the Goods and
Chattells of the Offenders and in default of Goods and Chattels the Offenders to be co[m]mitted (by Warrant under
the Hands and Seals of the said Co[m]missioners) to Prison there to remaine till payment of the said Fines And that
all Fines that shall be imposed by virtue of this Act shall bee paid to the respective Receivers General and by
them into the Receipt of their Majesties Exchequer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Collector not paying Money received by him;</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Imprisonment, and Real and Personal Estate liable.; Commissioners seizing Estate, to call a General Meeting of Commissioners on Notice; Proceedings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">And it is further enacted and declared That if any Collector [that<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] shall (by virtue of this Act be appointed
for the receipt of any su[m]ms of money thereby to be assessed) neglect or refuse to pay any su[m]m or sums of
money which shall be by him received as aforesaid and to pay the same as in and by this Act is directed and shall
detain in his or their hands any money received by them or any of them and not pay the same att such time
time as by this Act is directed the Co[m]missioners of each County Riding City or Towne respectively or any Two
or more of them in their respective Divisions are hereby authorized and impowered to imprison the Person and
seize and secure the Estate both real and personal of such Collectors to him belonging or which shall descend or
come into the Hands or Possession of his Heirs Executors or Administrators wheresoever the same can be
discovered and found And the said Co[m]missioners who shall so seize and secure the Estate of any Collector or
Collectors shall be and are hereby impowered to appoint a time for the General Meeting of the Co[m]missioners for
such County Riding City Towne or Place and there to cause publick notice to be given att the Place where such
Meeting shall be appointed Six days att least before such General Meeting And the Co[m]missioners present att
such General Meeting or the major part of them in case the moneys detained by any such Collector or Collectors
be not paid or satisfied as it ought to be according to the Directions of this Act shall and are hereby impowered
and required to sell and dispose of all such Estates which shall be for the cause aforesaid seized and secured or
any part of them and to satisfie and pay into the Hands of the Receiver General the su[m]m that shall
be so detained in the Hands of such Collector or Collectors their Heirs Executors or Administrators
respectively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Commissioners to call before them Collectors, and examine touching full Payment of Assessments;</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">and in case of Failure, to levy</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">And it is hereby further enacted and declared That att the expira[i]n of the respective times in this Act
prescribed for the full payment of the said Foure Quarterly Payments the several and respective Co[m]missioners or
any Two or more of them within their Division and Hundred shall and are hereby required to call before them the
Collectors within each respective Division Hundred Parish and Place to examine and assure themselves of the full
and whole Payment of the particular sum and su[m]ms of money chargd within and upon the same Division Hundred
and every Parish and Place therein and of the due returne of the same into the Hands of the Receivers General
their Deputy or Deputyes of the said County Riding City Towne or Place respectively and by such Receiver
General into the receipt of their Majesties Exchequer to the end there may be no failure in the payment of any
part of the Assessment by virtue of this Act to be assessed and paid And in case of any failure in the Premisses
the said Co[m]missioners or any Two or more of them are hereby to cause the same to be forthwith levied and paid
according to the true intent and meaning of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. If Controversy concerning assessing Commissioners, Commissioners concerned to withdraw; in default, Commissioners present may fine not exceeding &pound;20.; All Questions determined by Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p32">And it is hereby enacted and declared That in case any Controversie arise concerning the said Assessment or
the dividing apportioning or payment thereof which concerns any the Co[m]missioners by this Act appointed that
the Comissioners so concerned in the said Controversie shall have noe voice but shall withdraw att the time of the
Debate of any such Controversie until it be determined by the rest of the Co[m]missioners And in default thereof
that the Co[m]missioners then present shall have power and are hereby required to impose such Fine and Fines as to
them shall be thought fitt upon such Co[m]missioners so refuseing to withdraw not exceeding the su[m]m of Twenty
Pound and to cause the same to be levied and paid as other Fines to bee imposed by this Act are to be levied
and paid And all Questions and Differences that shall arise touching any the said Rates Assessments or Levies
or the collecting thereof shall be heard and finally determined by the Co[m]missioners in such manner as by this
Act is directed upon Complaint thereof made to them by any Person or Persons thereby agrieved without further
trouble or suit in Law.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Proviso for Colleges, &amp;c. in the Universities, the Colleges of Windsor, Eton, Winchester, and Westminster; and for Hospitals in respect of Sites of Colleges, &amp;c.; and for Christ's Hospital and other Hospitals and Almshouses.; Proviso for Hospitals, &amp;c. whose Revenues do not exceed &pound;20.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided That nothing contained in this Act shall extend to charge any College or Hall in either of the Two
Universities or the Colleges of Windsor Eaton Winchester or Westminster or the Corpora[i]n of the Governors of
the Charity for relief of poor Widows and Children of Clergymen or the College of Bromley or any Hospital
for or in respect of the Scites of the said Colleges Halls or Hospitals or any Master Fellow or Schollar of any
such College or Halls or any Reader Officer or Minister of the said Universities Colleges or Halls or any Masters
or Ushers of any School for or in respect of any Stipend Wages or Profitts whatsoever ariseing or growing due
to them in respect of the said several Places and Employments in the said Universities Colleges or Schools or
to charge any of the Houses or Lands belonging to Christs Hospital Saint Bartholomews Bridewell Saint Thomas
and Bethlehem Hospitall in the City of London and Borough of Southwark or any of them or the said Corpora[i]n
of the Governours of the Charity for relief [of<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] poor Widows and Children of Clergymen or the College of
Bromley nor to extend to charge any the Almsmen or Almswomen or other poor Persons inhabiting within any
other Hospitall or Almshouse for or in respect of any Rents or Revenues payable to them or any such of them
for their immediate use and relief whose annual maintenance and Profitts shall not exceed in the whole the summe
of Twenty Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Tenants of Hospitals rated for what the Lands are worth above Rents reserved.</head>
			<para id="p34">Provided that noe Tenants of any Lands or Houses by Lease or Grant from the said Corporac[i]on or any of the
said Hospitalls or Almshouses do claime or enjoy any freedom or exemp[i]n by this Act But that all the Houses
and Lands which they so hold shall be rated and assessed for so much as they are yearely worth over and above
the Rents reserved and payable to the said Corpora[i]n or to the said Hospitals or Almshouses to be received and
disbursed for the immediate support and relief of the Poor in the said Hospitals and Almshouses.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Persons dwelling in one Parish, &amp;c. and Goods in another, to be assessed where they dwell.</head>
			<para id="p35">Provided alsoe that where any Person inhabiting within the City of London or any other Cities or Townes
Corporate hath his Dwelling-House in one of the Parishes and Wards therein and hath any Goods Wares or
Merchandizes chargeable by this Act in one or more of the other Parishes or Wards in the same City that then
such Persons shall be charged taxed and assessed for such his Goods and Merchandizes in the Parish or Ward
where hee dwelleth and not elsewhere in the said City.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Places assessed in the County, &amp;c. where usually assessed.</head>
			<para id="p36">Provided and be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That for the avoiding all obstructions and
delays in assessing and collecting the su[m]ms which by this Act are to bee rated and assessed all Places Constablewicks
Divisions and Allotments which have used to bee rated and assessed shall pay and bee assessed in such County
Hundred Rape Wapentake Constablewick Division Place and Allotment as the same hath heretofore usually been
assessed and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Proviso for Contracts between Landlord and Tenant as to Payment of Taxes.</head>
			<para id="p37">Provided always That nothing in this Act contained shall be construed to alter change determine or make void
any Contracts Covenants or Agreements whatsoever between Landlord and Tenant or any others touching the
Payment of Taxes or Assessments Any thing herein before men[i]ed to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. If Action for executing Act, General Issue, may be pleaded.</head>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">Treble Costs.; Receivers General to give Head Collectors Receipt; gratis.; Head Collectors to give Receipts gratis to Sub-collectors.; Sub-collectors to deliver a Schedule to Head Collectors of Defaulters where there is no Distress; which Schedule is to be delivered to Receivers General, and returned by him into the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Action Plaint [Suit<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] or Information shall
be co[m]menced or prosecuted against any Person or Persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in execu[i]n
of this Act such Person or Persons (soe sued in any Court whatsoever) shall and may plead the General Issue
(not guilty) and upon any Issue joyned may give (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) and the Special Matter in Evidence and if the Plaintiff or
Prosecutor shall become nonsuit or forbear further Prosecution or suffer a discontinuance or if a Verdict passe against
him the Defendants shall recover their Treble Costs for which they shall have the like remedy as in any case
where Costs by the Law are given to Defendants And the said Receivers General shall give Acquitancs (gratis)
to the said Head Collectors for all moneys of them received And the said Head Collector shall alsoe give
Acquitancs (gratis) to the Subcollectors for all such moneys as shall be paid them in pursuance of this Act
And the said Subcollectors shall make and deliver to the said Head Collectors a perfect Schedule fairely written in
Parchment under their Hands and Seals signed and allowed by any Two or more of the respective Co[m]missioners
containing the Names Sirnames and Places of Abode of every Person within their respective Collections that shall
make default of Payment of any of the su[m]ms that shall be rated or assessed or such Person by virtue of this Act
where noe sufficient distresse is to bee found nor other satisfaction made and not otherwise and the su[m]m and su[m]ms
charged on every such Person the same Schedule to bee delivered by the Head Collectors to the Receiver General
of the County City or Place respectively to be by him returned into Their Majesties Court of Exchequer whereupon
every Person soe makeing Default of Payment may be charged by Processe of the said Court according to the
course of the Court of Exchequer in such Cases.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Where Lands, &amp;c. unoccupied, and no Distress nor Person of Owner found, the Name of Owner certified into Exchequer;</head>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">which Certificate is to be a Charge, and Process to issue</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">Provided always and be it further enacted That in case any Lands or Houses in any Parish or Constablewick
shall lie unoccupied and no Distresse can be found on the same nor the Person of the true Owner or Proprietor
can be found within the County wherein such House or Land lyeth by reason whereof the Rate and Assessment
upon such unoccupied House and Lands cannot be levied that then upon complaint made thereof to the Co[m]missioners
for the County where such Case shall happen to be the said Co[m]missioners or any Two or more of them shall
certifie into Their Majesties Court of Exchequer the name of the Person whose Lands or House so lieth unoccupied
together with the su[m]m thereupon assessed and the Parish or Place where such Land or House lieth which Certificate
is hereby declared to be a sufficient charge upon the Person and Land or House therein named and shall make
the Person Debtor to Their Majesties for the su[m]m so assessed and the Court of Exchequer shall issue out Processe
thereupon against the Body Goods and all other the Lands of such Debtor untill the su[m]m so assessed be fully
and actually levied and paid to Their Majesties.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Where Woodlands assessed, and no Distress, Wood may be cut and sold.</head>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">Buyers may cut and carry away</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p43">Provided always and be it enacted That where any Woodlands shall be assessed and noe distresse can be
had that in such case it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Collector Constable Headborough or Tythingman
by Warrant under the Hands and Seals of two or more of the Co[m]missioners of that Hundred or Division at
seasonable times of the yeare to cutt and sell to any Person or Persons soe much of the Wood growing on the
Woodlands (Timber Trees excepted) so assessed as will pay the Assessment or Assessments to be behind and
unpaid and the charge incident thereunto And [that<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] it shall and may be lawfull for the Person and Persons
and his and their Assigns to whom such Woods shall be sold to fell cut downe and dispose and carry away
the same to his owne use rendring the Overplus (if any be to the Owner Any Law to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Where Rates on Tithes, &amp;c. not paid, Officer may seize, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p44">Provided always and be it further enacted That where any Tax or Assessment shall be charged or laid upon
any Tythes Tolls Profitts of Marketts Faires or Fishery or other annual profitts not distrainable in case the same
shall not be paid within Fifteen days after such Assessment so charged or laid and demanded then it shall and
may be lawfull to and for the Collector Constable or other Officer thereunto appointed by Warrant under the
Hands and Seals of Three or more Co[m]missioners authorized by this Act to seize take and sell so much of the
said Tythes Tolls and other Profitts so charged as shall be sufficient for the levying of the said Tax and Assessment
and all Charges occasioned by such nonpayment thereof rendring the Overplus to the Owner if any bee.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Receiver General certifying Monies to be due when the same have been paid, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p46">And for the better preventing of such unjust vexations as might be occasioned by such Persons as shall be
appointed Receivers General of any of the su[m]ms of money granted by this Act And to the intent that the said
Receivers General may returne a true account into Their Majesties Court of Exchequer of such sums of money
as shall be received by them and every of them their and every of their Deputy and Deputies be it further
enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any such Receiver General returne or certify into the said Court any
sum or su[m]ms of money to be in Arrear or unpaid after the same have been received either by such Receiver
General or by his Deputy or Deputies or any of them or shall cause any Person or Persons to bee sett Insuper
in the said Court for any su[m]m or su[m]ms of money that hath been soe received that then every such Receiver
General shall be liable to pay to every Person and Persons that shall be molested vexed or damaged by reason
of such unjust Certificate returne or setting Insuper Treble the Damages that shall be thereby occasioned the said
Damages to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informa[i]n in which noe Essoign Protection or Wager
of Law shall be allowed nor any more then one Imparlance and shall also forfeit to Their Majesties Their Heires
and Successors double the su[m]m that shall be so unjustly certified or returned or caused to bee sett Insuper.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Parents and Guardians to pay Rates imposed on Infants; and upon Neglect, &amp;c. to be proceeded against as other Defaulters.</head>
			<para id="p47">
				<emph type="i">Sums paid allowed upon their Accounts</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p48">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That where any Person or Persons chargeable with any
Rates or Assessments by this Act imposed shall be under the Age of One and twenty yeares in every such case the
Parents Guardians and Tutors of such Infants respectively upon default of Payment by such Infants shall be and
are hereby made liable to and charged with the Payments which such Infants ought to have made And if such
Parents Guardians or Tutors shall neglect or refuse to pay as aforesaid it shall and may be lawfull to proceed
against them in like manner as against [any<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] other Person or Persons making default of Payment as herein is
mentioned And all Parents Guardians and Tutors makeing Payment as aforesaid shall be allowed all and every
the su[m]ms paid for such Infants, upon his or their Accounts.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Persons to be rated for Offices at Places where executed, and for Personal Estates where resident.</head>
			<para id="p49">
				<emph type="i">Persons out of the Realm rated for Personal Estate where last resident within the Realm</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p50">And be it further enacted That every Person rated or assessed for his Office or Employment shall be rated and
pay for his said Office and Employment in the County City or Place where such Office or Employment is executed
And every Person who is or shall be rated for or in respect of any personal Estate to him any way belonging
shall be rated att such Place where he or she shall be resident att the time of the execu[i]n of this Act And
all Persons not being Houshoulders nor having a certain Place of Residence shall be taxed att the Place where they
shall be resident att the time of the execucon of this Act And if any Person who ought to be taxed by virtue
of this Act for or in respect of his personal Estate shall att the time of his Assessment be out of the Realm such
Person shall be rated therefore in such County City or Place where hee was last abiding within the Realme.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Persons having Goods, &amp;c. in any County, (other than the County wherein they live) rated in County where Goods are.</head>
			<para id="p51">
				<emph type="i">Persons to be rated for Lands, &amp;c. in Place where situate</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p52">Provided That where any Person shall have any Goods Wares or Merchandizes in any County or Counties
other then the [Countie<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] where he shall be resident or had his last residence it shall be lawfull to rate or
assess such Person for such Goods Wares [&amp;<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] Merchandizes in the County or Counties where the same shall
be And every Person who shall be rated or assessed as aforesaid for or in respect of any Mannors Messuages
Lands Tenements or Hereditaments shall be rated and assessed in the Place where such Messuages Manors Lands
Tenements and Premisses respectively doe lye and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Persons in respect of several Places of Residence being doubly charged for Personal Estate, upon Certificate and Oath thereof to be discharged for so much.</head>
			<para id="p53">
				<emph type="i">Persons who by Fraud shall escape being taxed, doubly charged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p54">Provided always That if any Person or Person by reason of his or their having several Mansion-houses or
Places of Residence or otherwise shall be doubly charged by occasion of this Act for or in respect of his or their
personal Estate then upon Certificate made by two or more of the Co[m]missioners for the County Riding City or
Place of his or their last personal Residence under their Hands and Seals of the su[m]m or su[m]ms charged upon him
or them and in what capacity or respect he or they were soe charged (which Certificate the said Co[m]missioners are
required to give without Delay Fee, or Reward) and upon Oath made of such Certificate before any one Justice
of the Peace of the County or Place where the said Certificate shall be made (which Oath the said Justice of
Peace is hereby authorized and required to administer) then the Person and Persons so doubly charged shall for
soe much as shall be soe certified be discharged in every other County City or Place And if any Person that
ought to bee taxed by virtue of this Act for or in respect of his personal Estate shall by changing his place of
Residence or by any other fraud or covin escape from the Taxation and not be taxed and the same be proved
before the Co[m]missioners or any Two of them or before any Justice of the Peace in the County Riding City or
Place where such Person dwelleth or resideth att any time within One yeare next [ensuing<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] after such Tax
made every Person that shall soe escape from the Taxation and Payment shall be charged (upon proof thereof)
att the double value of soe much as hee should or ought to have been taxed att by this Act the said double value
upon Certificate thereof made into the Exchequer by the Comissioners or Justices (before whom such proof shall
bee made to bee levied of the Goods Lands and Tenements of such Person.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Householders to give Account of Lodgers to Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p55">And for the better discovery of personal Estates be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every
Housholder shall upon the Demand of the Assessors of the respective Parishes or Places give an Account of the
Names and Qualities of such Persons as shall sojourne or lodge in their respective Houses under the Penalty of
forfeiting to Their Majesties the su[m]m of Twenty pounds to be levied and recovered in such manner as other Penalties
in this Act menc[i]oned are to be levied and recovered</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. Commissioners within their Division to rate each other for their Personal Estates and Offices.</head>
			<para id="p56">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to assess the Assessors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p57">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Commissioners that shall be within any County
City or Place within the resspective Limitts or the major part of them shall rate tax and assess every other
Co[m]missioner joyned with them for and in respect of the ready money [Debts<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] Goods Chattells and personal
Estate of such Co[m]missioners And alsoe for and in respect of the Offices and Employments of Profitt which att the
time of such Examina[i]n shall be held and enjoyed by such Co[m]missioners so as the residence and usuall dwellingplace of such Co[m]missioner soe to be taxed be within the Division of such Co[m]missioners by whom hee is taxed and
so as the Office and Employment held and enjoyed by such Co[m]missioner so to be taxed be likewise to be exercised
within the Division or Limitts of such Co[m]missioners by whom hee is [to bee<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] taxed and the Co[m]missioners
within their Division shall alsoe assesse every Assessor within their Division for all and singuler the Premisses for
which by this Act hee ought to bee rated or assessed And as well all su[m]ms assessed upon every the said
Co[m]missioners and Assessors as the Assessments made and sett by the Assessors aforesaid shall be written estreated
levied and gathered as the same should and ought to have been if such Co[m]missioners had not been named
Co[m]missioners.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. Shares in New River, Thames, Hyde Park, or Mary-le-bone Waters.</head>
			<para id="p58">
				<emph type="i">Interest in the King's Printing House, &amp;c.; assessed by Commissioners appointed for London; and the Sums paid by the Treasurers, &amp;c. of the said Waterworks</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p59">And be it further enacted and ordained by the Authority aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons
having any Share or Shares or Interest in any fresh Streame or running Water brought to the North parts of
London co[m]monly called The New River or in the Thames Water-works or in the Hide Parke or Marybone
Waters or any Rents or Profits ariseing thereby And all Person and Persons having any Share or Interest in
the Stock or Stocks of Printing of Books in or belonging to the House co[m]monly called The Kings Printing
House shall pay for the same the su[m]m of Foure shillings for every Twenty shillings of the full yearely Value
thereof And they and all Companies of Merchants in London charged by this Act shall be assessed by the
Co[m]missioners nominated and appointed for the said City or any Three of them for their respective Shares and
Interests aforesaid and the aforesaid Joynt Stock and Stocks and the same shall be paid by the Governors and
respective Treasurers of the said respective Companies and by the Tresurers or Receivers of the said River Waters
and Water-works and Stock for printing and be deducted att and out of their next Dividend.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Proviso for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey, and Guernsey.</head>
			<para id="p60">Provided alsoe That this Act shall not extend to the Inhabitants of Scotland Ireland Jersey or Guernsey for
and concerning any such Personal Estate which they or any to their use have within the Places aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. Any Two Commissioners may require Account from Receivers General;</head>
			<para id="p61">
				<emph type="i">and may levy</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p62">And it is further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Co[m]missioners or any Two or more of them
may and shall from time to time call for and require an Account from the respective Receivers General of all
the moneys received by them of the said Collectors and of the payments thereof into Their Majesties Receipt
of Exchequer according to the direction of this Act and in case of any failure in the Premisses the said Co[m]missioners
or any two or more of them are hereby required to cause the same to be forthwith levied and paid according
to the true intent and meaning of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. No Privilege of Exemption from Subsidies, &amp;c. shall extend to Rates granted by this Act.</head>
			<para id="p63">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no Letters Patents granted by Their Majesties or any
of Their Royall Progenitors to any Person or Persons Cities Boroughs or Towns Corporate within this Realme of
any manner of Liberties Priveledges or Exemp[i]ns from Subsidies Tolls Taxes Assessments or Aids shall be
construed or taken to exempt any Person or Persons City Borough or Town-Corporate or any of the Inhabitants
of the same or in the Tower of London from the Burthen and Charge of any su[m]m or su[m]ms of money granted
by this Act but that all and every such Person and Persons City Borough and Towne Corporate shall pay their
proportions of all Rates and Assessments by this present Act imposed Any such Letters Patents Grants or Charters
or any Clause of Non obstante matter or thing therein contained or any Law Statute Custom or Prescription to
the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. Inhabitants in Cities, &amp;c. not compellable to be Assessors, &amp;c. out of Limits.</head>
			<para id="p64">Provided alsoe That no Person inhabiting in any City Borough or Towne Corporate shall be compelled to be
any Assessor or Collector of or for any part of the Rates and Assessments hereby granted in any Place or Places
out of the limitts of the said City Borough or Town-Corporat</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. Landlords to pay on Houses where Foreign Ministers reside.</head>
			<para id="p65">Provided always and be it enacted That every Rate Tax or Assessment which shall be made or imposed by
virtue of this Act in respect of any House or Tenement which an Ambassador Resident Agent or other Publick
Minister of any Foreigne Prince or State now doth or hereafter shall inhabitt or occupy shall be paid by the Landlord
or Owner of the said House or Tenements respectively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Proviso respecting Nomination of Assessors and Collectors in Extra-parochial and privileged Places.</head>
			<para id="p66">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in all priveledged and other Places being Extraparochial
or not within any the Constablewicks or Precincts of the respective Assessors to be appointed by virtue of this
Act (although in any monthly or other Tax they have not been assessed or rated heretofore) the said Co[m]missioners
or any Two or more of them shall and are hereby required to nominate and appoint Two fitt Persons living in
or neare the said priveledged or other Places as aforesaid to be Assessors for the said Places and to make and
returne their said Assessments in like manner as by this Act is appointed in any Parish Tything or Place And
alsoe to appoint One or more Collectors who are hereby required to collect and pay the same according to the
Rates appointed by this Act for collecting and paying all su[m]ms of money payable by this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. Commissioners not liable to Penalties of 25 Car. II. c. 2.</head>
			<para id="p67">Provided always and be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That noe Co[m]missioner or Co[m]missioners
who shall be employed in the Execu[i]n of this Act shall be liable for or by reason of such execu[i]n to any of
the Penalties men[i]ned in an Act made in the Five and twentieth yeare of the Reigne of King Charles the Second
for the preventing of Dangers [which<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] may happen from Popish Recusants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>XLIII. Commissioners to take the Oaths of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 8.; which Commissioners may administer.</head>
			<para id="p68">Provided always and be it enacted That no Person shall be capable of acting as a Co[m]missioner in the execu[i]n
of this Act before hee shall have taken the Oaths appointed by an Act of Parliament made in the First yeare of
Their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for the abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance and appointing
other Oaths which Oaths it shall be lawfull for any Two or more of the Co[m]missioners to administer and are
hereby required to administer to any other Co[m]missioners.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>XLIV. Papist of 16 and upwards, not having taken the Oaths, to pay double.</head>
			<para id="p69">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That [every<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Papist or reputed Papist being of the Age
of Sixteen years and upwards who shall not have taken the Oaths mencoed and required to bee taken by the
said last menc[i]oed Act shall yeild and pay unto their Majesties double the su[m]ms and rates which by force or virtue
of any Clause in this Act before menc[i]oed or contained hee or she should or ought to pay or be charged with
to be assessed levied and collected answered recovered and paid in such manner by such ways and means and
according to such Rules and Directions and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are before in this Act expressed
or appointed for and concerning the above menc[i]oed Rates and su[m]ms which are hereby intended to be doubled
as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>XLV. Proviso where within 10 Days after Meeting of Commissioners he shall take the Oaths.</head>
			<para id="p70">Provided neverthelesse That if any such Papist or reputed Papist within Ten days after the first Meeting of
the said Co[m]missioners in the respective Counties or Places where hee or shee ought to bee taxed or assessed according to
the intent of this present Act shall take the said Oaths before Two or more of the said Co[m]missioners (which Oaths
the said Comissioners are hereby impowered to administer) that in such case hee or shee shall not be liable to bee
doubly assessed as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>XLVI. Persons of 16 and upwards, who shall not have taken the Oaths before Execution of Act, and being summoned, shall refuse to take them, or neglect to appear before Commissioners, to pay double.</head>
			<para id="p71">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Person being of the Age of Sixteen yeares
or upwards and being within this Realme att the time of the execuc[i]on of this Act who shall not before that
time have taken the Oaths menc[i]oed and required to bee taken by the said Act entituled An Act for the abrogating
of the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance and appointing other Oaths And upon Su[m]mons by Warrant under
the Hand and Seal of any Two or more of the Co[m]missioners appointed by this Act shall refuse to take the said
Oaths att the time appointed in the said Warrant or shall neglect to appeare att such time before the Co[m]missioners
in order to take the said Oaths (which Oaths the said Co[m]missioners or any Two or more of them are hereby
required and impowered to administer shall yield and pay unto Their Majesties double the su[m]ms and rates which
by force or virtue of any Clause in this Act before menc[i]oed or contained he or she should or ought
to pay or be charged with in manner as is before in this present Act appointed touching Papists or reputed
Papists.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>XLVII. Gentlemen who by 3 W. &amp; M. c. 6. paid double, or have been returned into Exchequer for Non-payment, not appearing before the Commissioners to take the Oaths, to pay double.</head>
			<para id="p72">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Gentleman or soe reputed or owning or
writing himselfe such or being above that Quality who by virtue of an Act made in the Third yeare of theire
Majestys Reigne entituled An Act for raising money by a Poll (<ref idref="n18">18</ref>) quarterly for One yeare for carrying on a vigorous
War against France did pay or ought to have paid double the su[m]ms charged by the said Act or were or ought to
have been returned into the Exchequer for non-payment thereof who shall not voluntarily appeare before the said
Co[m]missioners or any Two or more of them within Ten days after the first Meeting of the said Co[m]missioners in
the respective place or places where hee ought to bee taxed or assessed and take the said Oaths appointed by the
said Act made in the first yeare of their Majesties Reigne (which Oaths the said Co[m]missioners or any Two or
more of them are hereby impowered and required to administer and to make an Entry or Memorandum thereof in
some Book to bee kept for that purpose) such Person shall be charged with and pay double the su[m]ms which by
force or virtue of this Act hee should or ought to have paid to be assessed levied collected answered recovered
and paid in such manner by such ways and means and according to such Rules and Directions and under such
Penalties and Forfeitures as are before in this Act expressed or appointed for or concerning the above mentioned
rates and su[m]ms which are herbey intended to be doubled as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>XLVIII. Commissioners to summon Persons suspected to appear and take the Oaths.</head>
			<para id="p73">And be it further enacted That any one or more of the Co[m]missioners appointed by this Act upon Informac[i]on
given or upon any cause of suspicion in that behalfe shall and are hereby required and enjoyned to cause
every person suspected or against whom such information shall be given to be su[m]moned to appeare to take the
said Oaths as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>XLIX. Proviso for Quakers subscribing the Declaration of Fidelity 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 18.</head>
			<para id="p74">Provided neverthelesse That whereas certaine persons Dissenters from the (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) of England Co[m]monly called
Quakers and now knowne to be such do scruple the taking of any Oath it shall be sufficient for [every<ref idref="n17">17</ref>]
such person to make and subscribe the declarac[i]on of Fidelity contained in an Act made in the Parliament
held in the First yeare of their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for exempting their Majesties Protestant
Subjects dissenting from the Church of England from the penalties of certain Laws which Declarac[i]on any
Two or more of the Co[m]missioners appointed for the execuc[i]on of this Act are hereby impowered and required
to take and every such person so doeing shall not be liable to or chargeable with any of the double Rates
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s50">
			<head>L. No Person liable to Pound Rate whose Lands are under &pound;20.</head>
			<para id="p75">Provided that no poor Person shall be charged with or liable unto the Pound Rate imposed by this Act upon
Lands Tenements or Hereditaments whose Lands Tenements or Hereditaments are not of the yearely value of
Twenty Shillings in the whole.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s51">
			<head>LI. Chancery Officers within the Liberty of the Rolls to be there assessed.</head>
			<para id="p76">Provided always That the Right Hono[ra]ble the Master of the Rolls the Masters of Chancery Six Clerks Clerks
of the Petty Bag Examiners Registers Clerks of the Inrollment Clerks of the Affidavitts and Subpena Office and
all others the Officers of the Court of Chancery that execute their Offices within the Liberty of the Rolls shall
be there assessed for their respective Offices and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s52">
			<head>LII. Collectors keeping Monies collected in their Hands; or paying other than to Head Collectors or Receiver General;; Penalty &pound;10.; Head Collector so offending:; Penalty &pound;40.; Receiver General or Deputy paying to any Person other than the Exchequer, or upon Tally of Pro, &amp;c.; Penalty &pound;1,000.</head>
			<para id="p77">Be it further enacted That if any Collector of any Parish or Place shall keep in his hands any part of the
money by him collected for any longer time then is by this Act directed (other then the Allowance made unto him
by this Act) or shall pay any part thereof to any Person or Persons other then to the Head Collector or Receiver
General of such County or Place or his respective Deputy that every such Collector shall forfeit for every such
Offence the su[m]m of Ten Pounds And in case any Head Collector shall keep in his Hands any part of the
money paid to him by any Collector by virtue of this Act for any longer time then is by virtue of this Act
directed or shall pay any part thereof to any Person or Persons other then the Receiver General of such County
or Place or his Deputy every such Head Collector shall forfeit for every such Offence the su[m]m of Fourty Pounds
And in case any Receiver General or his Deputy shall pay any part of the moneys paid to him or them by
any Collector by virtue of this Act to any Person or Persons whatsoever (other then the receipt of Their Majesties
Exchequer and att or within the respective times limited by this Act) or in case such Receiver General or his
Deputy shall pay any part of the said moneys by any Warrant of the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury or the Lord
Treasurer Under Treasurer or Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time being or upon any Tally of Pro or
Tally of Anticipation or other way or device whatsoever whereby to divert or hinder the actual payment thereof
into the receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid that then such Receiver General shall for every such Offence of
himself or his Deputy forfeit the su[m]m of One thousand Pounds to him or them that shall sue for the same in
any Court of Record by Bill Plaint or other Informac[i]on wherein no Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law is
to bee allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s53">
			<head>LIII. Treasurer not to direct Warrant for Payment of Monies otherwise than into the Exchequer; or to the Officers of Exchequer for striking Tally of Pro, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p78">
				<emph type="i">nor Officers of Exchequer to strike any such Tally, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p79">And it is hereby further enacted That the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury or the Lord Treasurer Under Treasurer
or Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time being or any of them do not direct any Warrant to any of the said
Head Collectors or Receivers General or their Deputy for the payment of any part of the moneys hereby given
to any Person or Persons other then into the receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid Nor shall they or any of
them direct any Warrant to the Officers of the Exchequer for the strikeing of any Tally of Pro or Tally of
Anticipation nor doe any other matter or thing whereby to divert the actuall payment of the said moneys into
the receipt of the Exchequer Nor shall the Officers of the Exchequer strike or direct or record the striking of
any Tally of Pro or Tally of Anticipation upon any of the said moneys upon any Account or Warrantt whatsoever
nor shall any Teller throw down any Bill whereby to charge himselfe with any of the said moneys untill hee shall
have actually received the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s54">
			<head>LIV. No Non vult, &amp;c. or other Stay of Prosecution, in any Suit against Offenders.</head>
			<para id="p80">Provided also and be it enacted That noe stay of Prosecution upon any Co[m]mand Warrant Motion or Order or
Direction by non vult ulterius prosequi shall be had made admitted received or allowed by any Court whatsoever
in any Suit or Proceeding by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on or otherwise for the recovery of all or
any the Pains Penalties or Forfeitures upon any Person or Persons by this Act inflicted or therein mentioned or
for or in order to the conviction or disability of any Person offending against this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s55">
			<head>LV. No Person to be Commissioner in any County, or in London or Westminster, who did not pay under 3 W. &amp; M. c. 6.</head>
			<para id="p81">
				<emph type="i">nor in any other Place, unless he so paid, or paid 10s. Quarterly as a Tradesman worth &pound;300</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p82">Provided alsoe and bee it enacted That noe Person shall be capable of acting as a Co[m]missioner in the execuc[i]on
of this Act for any County or Riding or the Cities of London or Westminster unlesse hee was assessed and did
pay to Their Majesties the su[m]m of Twenty Shillings Quarterly towards the Rates and Assessments granted by an
Act made in the Third yeare of their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for raiseing money by a Poll payable
quarterly for One yeare for the carrying on a vigorous Warr against France or the su[m]m of Foure Pounds to
the Act made in the Fourth yeare of Their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for review of the Quarterly Poll
granted to their Majesties in the last Session of this present Parliament And alsoe that no Person shall be capable
of acting as a Co[m]missioner in execuc[i]on of this Act for any other City or in any Borough Towne or Cinque
Port or the Counties thereof respectively unlesse hee was assessed and did pay to their Majesties the su[m]m of
Twenty Shillings Quarterly as aforesaid or was assessed and did pay to their Majesties the su[m]m of Ten Shillings
Quarterly (as a Tradesman worth Three hundred Pounds) towards the said Quarterly Poll or the su[m]m of Fourty
Shillings to the said Act for review of the said Quarterly Poll.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s56">
			<head>LVI. Such Tradesman may be a Commissioner for a City though nominated for the County.</head>
			<para id="p83">Provided always That every Person who did pay to their Majesties the su[m]m of Ten Shillings Quarterly (as a
Tradesman worth Three hundred Pounds) toward the said Quarterly Poll may be capable of acting as a
Co[m]missioner for and within any City Borough or Town Corporate whereof hee is an Inhabitant although hee was
nominated a Co[m]missioner for the County att large in which such City Borough or Towne Corporate is scituate
unlesse Commissioners were particularly appointed by the said Act for such City Borough or Towne Corporate</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s57">
			<head>LVII. When not Commissioners enough for any City, &amp;c. Commissioners for County may act.</head>
			<para id="p84">Provided neverthelesse That in case there shall not be a sufficient number of Co[m]missioners for any City Towne
and County of the same Borough Towne and Cinque Port (for which by this Act Co[m]missioners are particularly
appointed) capable of acting according to the qualifications aforesaid for putting this Act in execuc[i]on that in
every such case any of the Co[m]missioners appointed for the County att large within which such Cities Towns and
Counties of the same Borough Towne or Cinque Port doth stand or which is next adjoyning thereto may [act<ref idref="n20">20</ref>]
as Co[m]missioners in the execution of this Act within such City Towne and County of the same Borough Towne
or Cinque Port.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s58">
			<head>LVIII. In case there be not a sufficient Number of Commissioners capable of acting for any County, Their Majesties may constitute under the Great Seal so marry Persons, being resident, as have Real Estates of &pound;100 per Ann. in the Countries, to be Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p85">Provided alsoe and be it further enacted That in case there shall not be a sufficient number of the persons
nominated to be Co[m]missioners for any County who shall be capable of acting as Co[m]missioners according to the
qualifications in this Act before mentioned that in every such case it shall be lawfull for Their Majesties to issue
or cause to be issued one or more Co[m]mission or Co[m]missions under the Great Seale of England and thereby to
nominate constitute and appoint such and so many persons being resident and having real Estates of the value
of One hundred Pounds a yeare in the said respective Counties for which they shall be respectively nominated to
be Co[m]missioners for putting this present Act in execuc[i]on in the said Counties respectively which said Co[m]missioners so to
bee nominated and appointed for the said Counties respectively shall have such and the same Powers for putting
this Act in execuc[i]on in the said respective Counties and under the same Rules and Directions as any other
Co[m]missioners nominated or appointed by this Act any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s59">
			<head>LIX. Person after Assessment removing to a Place where he was not rated for Personal Estate, Commissioners to summon and rate, unless Certificate that he was assessed and had paid.</head>
			<para id="p86">And for the more effectuall charging all Personal Estates Be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That if after
the Assessments on Personal Estates directed by this Act shall be made any person shall come to inhabit or reside
in any Division or Place where such Person was not rated or taxed for Personal Estate the Co[m]missioners acting
within such Division or Place are hereby required and impowered to su[m]mon such Person before them and unlesse
hee or she shall produce a Certificate made according to the Directions of this Act whereby it shall appeare that
hee or shee was assessed and had actually paid all the precedent Quarterly Payments in some other place for his
or her Personal Estate the said Co[m]missioners shall and are hereby required to cause such Person to be assessed
for his or her personal Estate and cause the same or such Quarterly Payments thereof as shall be (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) unassessed
and unpaid to be assessed levied and paid according to the true intent and meaning of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s60">
			<head>LX. Proviso respecting King's Bench Prison, &amp;c. and the Marshalsea;</head>
			<para id="p87">
				<emph type="i">to be charged in the Parish of St. George in Southwark</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p88">Provided always That the Prison of the Kings Bench the Prison-House Lands Gardens and the co[m]mon side
and all the Rents Profitts and Perquisitts of the Office of the Marshall of the said Kings Bench Prison lying and
being in the Parish of Saint George the Martyr in the Borough of Southwarke and County of Surrey and alsoe
the Prison House Lands and Gardens of the Prison of the Marshall of the Marshalsea Prison and all Offices
Perquisites and Profitts of the Marshalsea Court and Prison lying and being alsoe in the said Parish of Saint
George in the Borough of Southwark and County of Surrey shall be charged and assessed to this Assessment in
the said Parish [in the said Parish<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] of Saint George and Borough of Southwark and not elsewhere any thing to
the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s61">
			<head>LXI. Commissioners acting before taking the Oaths; Penalty &pound;500.</head>
			<para id="p89">Provided always and be it enacted That if any Person hereby named a Co[m]missioner shall presume to act as a
Co[m]missioner in the execuc[i]on of this Act before hee shall have taken the Oaths which by this Act hee is required
to take and in the manner hereby prescribed hee shall forfeit to their Majesties the su[m]m of Five hundred
Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s62">
			<head>LXII. Where Owners of Lands are liable to be doubly charged as Papists or otherwise, for not taking the Oaths, Owners only charged and Tenants discharged.</head>
			<para id="p90">Provided always and bee it enacted That where the Owners of any Lands Tenements and Hereditaments are
liable to bee doubly charged as Papists reputed Papists or otherwise by reason of their not having taken the
Oaths according to the intent of this Act in every such case such Owners only shall be charged with and shall
pay the said double rates And the respective Tenants of such Lands Tenements and Hereditaments are hereby
discharged of and from the same any Covenant for payment of Taxes or other Agreement to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s63">
			<head>LXIII. Waterworks in Southwark charged in Surrey.</head>
			<para id="p91">Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all the Waterworks in the Borough of
Southwarke shall be rated and assessed by the Co[m]missioners and Assessors of the County of Surrey and
not by the Co[m]missioners or Assessors for the City of London any thing herein before contained to the contrary
thereof notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s64">
			<head>LXIV. Persons may lend Money to Their Majesties on this Act at &pound;7 per Cent. per Ann.</head>
			<para id="p92">Provided always and it is hereby enacted That it shall and may bee lawfull to and for any person or persons
Natives or Foreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate to advance and lend unto Their Majesties upon (<ref idref="n23">23</ref>) security of this
Act any su[m]m or su[m]ms of money and to have and receive for the forbearance thereof any su[m]m not exceeding Seven
[pound<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] by the Hundred for one whole yeare and [noe<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] more directly or indirectly and that noe money soe
lent upon the security of this Act shall bee rated or assessed by virtue of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s65">
			<head>LXV. Repayment of such Monies how secured.</head>
			<para id="p93">
				<emph type="i">Books provided.; Tally of Loan to Lender, and Warrant for Interest.; Orders for Repayment registered according to Date of Tally, and paid in course.; Monies to come in by this Act liable to satisfy such Loans.; No Fee for providing or making Books, &amp;c. or for Payment of Money lent.; Penalty.; Punishment.; Undue Preference by Officer;; Penalty.; Undue Preference by Deputy;; Penalty.; Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller, not making Payments in due Order;; Penalty.; How all such Penalties to be recovered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p94">And to the end that all moneys which shall be lent to their Majesties on the credit of this Act may be well
and sufficiently secured out of the money ariseing and payable by this Act Be it further enacted by the authority
aforesaid That there shall be provided and kept in Their Majesties Exchequer (that is to say in the Office of the
Auditor of the Receipts one Book and Register in which all moneys that shall be paid into the Exchequer by virtue
of this Act shall be entred and registred apart &amp; distinct from all other moneys paid or payable to their Majesties
upon any other branch of their Majesties Revenue or upon any other account whatsoever And that all and every
person and persons who shall lend any money to their Majesties upon the credit of this Act and pay the same
into the Receipt of the Exchequer shall im[m]ediatly have a Tally of Loan struck for the same and an Order
for his or their repayment beareing the same date with his or their Tally In which Order shall be contained a
Warrant for payment of Interest for forbearance thereof not exceeding Seven pounds per centum per annum for
his or their considerac[i]on to bee paid every three months until repayment of his or their Principal And that all
Orders for repayment of money shall be registred in course according to the date of the Tally respectively without
preferrence of one before another And that all and every person and persons shall be paid in course according
as their Order shall stand entred in the said Register Book so as the persons natives or foreigners his or their
Executors Administrators or Assigns who shall have his or their Order or Orders first entred in the said Book
of Register shall bee taken and accounted the first person or persons to bee paid upon the moneys to come
in by virtue of this Act And hee or they who shall have his or their Order or Orders next entred shall bee taken
and accounted to bee the second person to bee paid and so successively and in course And that the
moneys to come in by this Act shall bee in the same order liable to the satisfaction of the said respective parties
their Executors Administrators and Assigns respectively and successively without preferrence of one before another
and not otherwise and not to be divertible to any other use intent or purpose whatsoever And that no Fee
Reward or Gratuity directly or indirectly be demanded or taken of any their Majesties Subjects for providing or
making of any such Books Registers Entries Views or Search in or for payment of money lent or the interest
thereof as aforesaid by any of Their Majesties Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputies upon pain of paying
treble damages to the party agrieved by the party offending with Costs of Suit or if the Officer himself take
or demand any [such Fee<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] or Reward then to lose his place alsoe And if any undue preferrence of one before
another shall be made either in point of registry or payment contrary to the true meaning of this Act by any
such Officer or Officers then the party offending shall be liable (by Action of Debt or on the case) to pay the
value of the Debt Damages and Costs to the party agrieved and shall be forejudged from his place or office
And if such preferrence be unduely made by any his Deputy or Clerk without direction or privity of his Master
then such Deputy or Clerk onely shall be liable to such Action Debt Damages and Costs and shall be forever after uncapable of his place or office And in case the Auditor shall not direct the Order or the Clerk of
the Pells record or the Teller make payment according to each persons due place and order as afore directed
then hee or they shall be adjudged to forfeit and their respective Deputies and Clerks herein offending to bee liable
to such Action Debt Damages and Costs in such manner as aforesaid All which said Penalties Damages
Forfeitures and Costs to bee incurred by any of the Officers of the Exchequer or any their Deputies or Clerks
shall and may be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on in any of Their Majesties Courts of
Record att Westminster wherein noe Essoign Protection Priveledge Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint
shall bee in any wise granted or allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s66">
			<head>LXVI. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p95">
				<emph type="i">Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded, no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Orders</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p96">Provided always and be it hereby declared That if it happen that several Tallies of Loan or Orders for
payment as aforesaid beare date or be brought the same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be registred then
it shall be interpreted no undue preference which of those be entred first soe hee enters them all the same
day. Provided alsoe That it shall not bee interpreted any undue preference to incur any penalty in point of
payment if the Auditor direct and the Clerk of the Pells record and the Tellers do pay subsequent Orders of
persons that come and demand their moneys and bring their Orders before other persons that did not come to
demand their money and bring their Order in their course so as there bee so much money reserved as will satisfie
precedent Orders which shall not bee otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon Loan being to cease from
the time the money is so reserved and kept in Bank for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s67">
			<head>LXVII. Orders for Payment of Money lent may be assigned by Indorsement.</head>
			<para id="p97">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee.; Assignee may in like manner assign</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p98">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every person or persons to whom any money shall be due by
virtue of this Act after Order entred in the Book of Registry aforesaid for payment thereof his or their Executors
Administrators or Assigns by endorsement of his or their Order may assign and transferr his or their right title interest
and benefitt of such Order or any part thereof to any other which being notified in the Office of the Auditor of
the Receipt aforesaid and an entry or memorial thereof alsoe made in the Book of Register aforesaid for Orders
which the Officers shall upon request without Fee or Charge accordingly make shall intitle such [Assignee<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] his
and their Executors Administrators and Assigns to the benefitt thereof and payment thereon and such Assignee
may in like manner assign again and so toties quoties and afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person
or persons who have or hath made such Assignments to make void release or discharge the same from any
the moneys thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s68">
			<head>LXVIII. &pound;118, 506. 5s. 10d. which in pursuance of 4 W. &amp; M. c. 3.</head>
			<para id="p99">
				<emph type="i">and Letters of Privy Seal of the 14th Sept. 1693, were lent to Their Majesties; and &pound;293, 692. 17s. 10d. which, in pursuance of 4 W. &amp; M. c. 14. and of Letters of Privy Seal of Aug. 10, 1693, were lent to Their Majesties; not having been repaid;; and all Sums not exceeding &pound;400, 000 which may be lent to Their Majesties pursuant to Letters of Privy Seal of 27th Nov. 1693; and all Orders of Loan of the said Sums, to be transferred and registered in course,; without taking Receipts from the Parties,; and paid out of the Monies arising by this Act,; at &pound;7 per Cent. per Ann. on &pound;118, 506. 5s. 10d.; at &pound;8 per Cent. on &pound;293, 692. 17s. 10d.; Auditor of the Receipt to make Memorandums of Transfer.; Orders for Money may be assigned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p100">Provided always and be it further enacted That all every the principal su[m]ms of money not exceeding in the
whole the su[m]m of One hundred and eighteen thousand five hundred and six Pounds Five Shillings and Ten Pence
which in pursuance of an Act lately made entituled An Act for granting to their Majesties certaine rates and
Duties of Excise upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for secureing certaine Recompences and Advantages in the said
Act menc[i]oned to such Persons as shall voluntarily advance the su[m]m of Ten hundred thousand Pounds towards
the carrying on the Warr against France and of their Majesties Letters of Privy Seale beareing date the Fourteenth day
of September One thousand six hundred ninety three made in pursuance of the said Act have been lent or shall
bee lent to their Majesties att the receipt of Exchequer not having been repaid And all and every the principal
su[m]ms of money not exceeding in the whole the su[m]m of Two hundred ninety three thousand six hundred ninety
two Pounds Seventeen Shillings and Ten Pence which in pursuance of the Act of Parliament lately made entituled
An Act for the Review of the Quarterly Poll and of their Majesties Letters of Privy Seale beareing date the Tenth
day of August One thousand six hundred ninety three made in pursuance of the said Act have been lent or
shall bee lent to their Majesties att the Receipt of Exchequer not having been repaid And all and every the
principal su[m]ms of money not exceeding in the whole the su[m]m of Foure hundred thousand pounds which after the
Seventeenth day of November One thousand six hundred ninety three have been lent or shall bee lent to their
Majesties att the said Receipt pursuant to their Majesties Letters of Privy Seale beareing date the Twenty seaventh
day of November One thousand six hundred ninety three for or towards maintenance of their Majesties Fleet for
the yeare One thousand six hundred ninety foure And all and every the Orders of Loan for the said several and
respective principal su[m]ms shall bee in the first place transferred to and placed upon the register appointed to bee
kept by this Act and shall be registred thereupon in such course and order as the Loans thereof respectively in
point of time were made att the said Receipt which transferences shall and may bee and are hereby required to
bee made by virtue of this Act without makeing any Issues or takeing any Receipts from the Parties in order to
transferr the said Loans And that the principal moneys upon the said Orders soe transferred shall be payable and
paid to the Lender or Lenders of the same his her or their Executors Administrators or Assigns out of the moneys
ariseing by virtue of this Act in the same course and order according to which they are hereby appointed to bee
transferred and with preference to the Loans which any person or persons shall make hereafter on credit of this
present Act And that the Interest after the rate of Seven pounds per Centum per Annum due or to bee due
for the said principal su[m]ms not exceeding One hundred and eighteen thousand five hundred and six pounds five
shillings and Ten pence and Foure hundred thousand pounds and after the rate of Eight pounds per centum per
annum due or to be due for the said principal su[m]ms not exceeding Two hundred ninety three thousand six
hundred ninety two pounds seventeen shillings and ten pence to be transferred as aforesaid shall be paid and
satisfied out of the moneys ariseing by this Act until the respective times of the satisfaction of the Principal and
that the Auditor of the said Receipt upon the transferring of the said Loans or the orders for the same as aforesaid
shall make memorandums in the margent of the books where the same stand entred importing the transferrence
thereof and that they are to bee paid out of the moneys ariseing by virtue of this Act And that any person or
persons who are or shall be entituled to any moneys to bee paid by such orders to bee transferred (<ref idref="n28">28</ref>) afore said shall
or may assigne over the same to any other person or persons which assignments shall be good and effectual
in Law and so toties quoties any thing in the said former Acts or in this present Act to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s69">
			<head>LXIX. Out of the Monies levied under this Act, &pound;1,000,000 including &pound;400,000 borrowed, appropriated to Navy and Ordnance; the Remainder of such Monies appropriated to the Land Service and Incidents of the War</head>
			<para id="p101">And it is hereby further enacted by the authority aforesaid That out of the [moneys<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] that hath or shall belevied
or paid by virtue of this Act into the Receipt of the Exchequer as well upon Loans as otherwise the sum of Ten
hundred thousand pounds including therein the su[m]m of Foure hundred thousand pounds already borrowed and to
bee borrowed for the use of the Navy as is herein before declared shall and is hereby appropriated for the services
of the Navy and Ordnance performed and to be performed And that all other money which shall be levied and
paid by virtue of this Act into the Receipt of the Exchequer as well upon Loans as otherwise other then the
principal su[m]ms herein before appointed to bee transferred to this Act and the Interest thereof And alsoe the sum
of Ten hundred thousand pounds appropriated for the services of the Navy aforesaid shall be applied and appropriated
and is hereby appropriated to and for the payment of Their Majesties Land Forces and Armys and the paying for
Arms Ammunition and other Charges incident to the Warr and not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s70">
			<head>LXX. The Rules and Directions of I W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 1. as to certain Provisions herein mentioned,</head>
			<para id="p102">
				<emph type="i">revived and put in Ure in respect of the monies hereby appropriated</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p103">And for the more effectual doeing thereof and that the su[m]ms by this Act appropriated may not be diverted or
applied to any other purpose then is hereby declared and intended be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That
the Rules and Directions appointed and enacted in one Act made in the First yeare of Their Majesties Reigne
entituled An Act for a Grant to Their Majesties of an Aid of Two shillings in the Pound for One yeare for the
speedy payment of money thereby granted into the Receipt of the Exchequer by the Collectors and Receivers and
for distribution and application thereof and keeping distinct Accounts of the same and all other Provisions Pains
Penalties and Forfeitures thereby enacted in case of diversion of any money thereby appropriated are hereby revived
and enacted to be in force and shall be practised applied executed and put in ure for and concerning the
distribution and application of the said su[m]ms hereby appropriated as fully amply and effectually as if the same
were here particularly repeated and reenacted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s71">
			<head>LXXI. Certain Ships of War to be appointed by the Admiralty to certain Stations for protecting the Trade.</head>
			<para id="p104">And for the better secureing the Trade of this Kingdom be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That
over and above the Ships of Warr for the Line of Battle and for Convoys to remote parts att least Foure Ships
of the Third Rate Sixteen Ships of the Fourth Rate Thirteen Ships of the Fifth Rate and Ten Ships of the
Sixth Rate shall be from time to time directed and appointed by the Lord High Admiral of England or
Co[m]missioners for executeing the said Office for the time being to such proper stations as they shall deem meet
to cruize for secureing the Merchant Ships in their goeing out and returneing home.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s72">
			<head>LXXII. Admiralty may appoint Cruizers to the Line of Battle.</head>
			<para id="p105">Provided always and be it enacted That nothing in this Act contained shall restrain or be construed to restrain
the Lord High Admiral of England or the Commissioners for executing the office of the Lord High Admiral of
England for the time being from directing any of the Ships appointed by this Act to be Cruisers to bee employed
in the Line of Battle in cases of great necessity.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s73">
			<head>LXXIII. All Money issued for Naval Stores and Provisions, (except for Victuals) to be paid in course according to the Dates of the Bills, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p106">
				<emph type="i">The like Regulation as to further Part of Monies issued and paid for the Ordnance.; Comptroller of the Navy and Storekeeper of the Ordnance to keep Books for Register of Bills, &amp;c.; Undue Preference in Registry or Payment.; Action.; Penalties how recovered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p107">Provided always and be it enacted That out of the moneys hereby appropriated to and for the payment of
Officers and Seamen that have served and shall serve in Their Majesties Navy Royal and to and for the paying
for Naval Stores other then for Victuals and Provisions and to and for the expences of Their Majesties Office
of Ordnance in respect of Naval Affairs and for other necessary uses and services performed and to be performed
for the said Navy all such part thereof as shall be issued and paid by the Tresurer of the Navy by warrant of
the principal Officers and Co[m]missioners of the Navy or any Three or more of them for Naval Stores and Provisions
shall be paid in course to every person or persons or the Assigns to whom any such money is or shall be due
according to the dates of the Bills or Contracts registred for the same and not otherwise And that out of all
such further part of the said moneys as shall be issued and paid to the Lieutenant and principal Officers of the
Ordnance or the Paymaster thereof or his Deputy for the expence of Their Majesties Ordnance as to Naval Affairs
and by them or the said Paymaster respectively to any person or persons for ammunition or any other use or
service relateing to the Office of the Ordnance shall be in like manner paid in course to every person and persons
or their Assigns respectively according to the respective dates of the Bills and Contracts for the same and not
otherwise And the Comptroller of the Navy and Storekeeper of the Ordnance are hereby respectively required to
keep One or more book or books in their respective Offices wherein all Bills and Contracts in referrence to the
Navy and Office of the Ordnance (for such Bills and Contracts respectively as aforesaid) shall be duely registred
and all and every such person or persons concerned therein may have recourse thereunto without paying any fee
or reward for soe doeing And if any preferrence of one before another shall be made either in point of registry
or payment contrary to the true meaning of this Act either by the said Treasurer of the Navy or Paymaster of
the Ordnance or Comptroller of the Navy or Storekeeper of the Ordnance or any of them or their respective
Deputies or Clerks then the Parties offending shall be liable by Action of Debt or on the Case to pay double
the value of the Debt Damages and Costs to the Party grieved All which said Penalties Damages and Costs to
be incurred by the persons aforesaid or any of them respectively shall and may be recovered by the said party
grieved by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on in any of Their Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster
wherein no Essoign Protection Priviledge Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise
granted or allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s74">
			<head>LXXIV. Boards of Ordnance or Navy Board upon extraordinary Occasions may pay Imprest Money.</head>
			<para id="p108">Provided neverthelesse that it shall and may be lawfull for the said Lieutenant and principal Officers of the
Ordnance and the Officers of the Navy-board upon any emergent or extraordinary occasions to pay any of the
said money appropriated by this Act to any person or persons upon account by way of Imprest any thing herein
contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s75">
			<head>LXXV. Paying subsequent Bills, if first demanded, no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Bills.</head>
			<para id="p109">Provided also That it shall not be construed any preferrence to incur any Penalty in point of payment in
course as aforesaid if the said Treasurer of the Navy or Paymaster of the Ordnance or their Deputies respectively
do pay subsequent Bills of Persons which come and demand their money and bring their warrant or order in
their course for the same soe as there be soe much money reserved as will satisfie precedent Bills or Contracts
registred as aforesaid which shall not [otherwise be<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] disposed of but kept for them in the said respective Offices.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s76">
			<head>LXXVI.</head>
			<para id="p110">
				<emph type="i">Receiver General neglecting, &amp;c. to return Duplicates of Sums assessed;; Penalty &pound;50;; and Disability.; Remembrancer neglecting, &amp;c. to transcribe Schedules, &amp;c. of Sums returned;; Auditor of the Receipt not entering Schedules, &amp;c.;; Penalty &pound;100; and Disability</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p111">And whereas the Receivers General by this Act appointed by the time limitted as aforesaid to returne a true
copy or extract of the whole su[m]m assessed and charged within every Hundred Riding Lathe Wapentake Parish
Ward or place rated or assessed in pursuance of this Act together with the su[m]ms assessed upon personal Estates
Offices or Employments and to transmitt the same into their Majesties Court of Exchequer And the Kings
Remembrancer is also required to transcribe the schedules and duplicates of the said su[m]ms to him returned in a
Parchment Book in alphabetical order to be by him transmitted to the Office of Writer (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>) of the Tallies co[m]monly
called Auditor of the Receipt of the Exchequer who is thereupon likewise required to enter the same in [a<ref idref="n32">32</ref>]
Parchment Book in the like alphabetical order be it further enacted That if any Receiver General by this Act
appointed shall neglect or refuse to returne duplicates of the su[m]ms assessed and charged in the County Riding
Hundred Lathe Wapentake Parish Ward or places whereof hee is Receiver General within the time hereby limitted
and to returne the same into their Majesties Exchequer to the Office of the Kings Remembrancer then every such
Receiver General shall forfeit the su[m]m of Fifty pounds to any that will sue for the same and be thenceforth
incapable of any Office or place of Trust in their Majesties service And if the Kings Remembrancer for the time
being shall neglect or refuse within the times hereby appointed to transcribe the schedules and duplicates of the
su[m]ms so to him returned in a book of Parchment in alphabeticall order as hereby required and transmitt the
same to the office of the said Writer of the Tallys And if the said Writer of the Tallys commonly called Auditor
of the Receipt shall not enter the same in alphabetical order in another Parchment Book as hereby directed they
and every of them respectively offending shall forfeit the su[m]m of One hundred pounds to any that will sue for
the same and be thenceforth incapable of any office or place of trust in their Majesties service which said forfeitures
by any Receiver General Kings Remembrancer or Auditor of the Receipt shall be recovered by Action of Debt
Plaint or Informac[i]on in any of their Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster wherein no Essoigne Protection
or Wager of shall be allowed nor any more then One Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s77">
			<head>LXXVII. Auditor, &amp;c. receiving Fee Farm Rents, &amp;c. due to the Crown, to allow 4s. in the Pound to the Party paying; Penalty &pound;10 and Loss of Office.</head>
			<para id="p112">Provided alsoe and be it enacted That all and every. Auditor Reeve Receiver and their Deputies who receive
any. Fee-farme Rents or other chief Rents due to their Majesties or the Queen Dowager or to any other person
or persons claimeing by any. Grant or Purchase from or under the Crowne shall allow Foure shillings in the
pound according to the true intent and meaning of this Act to the Party and Partyes so paying the same without
any fee for such allowance upon the penalty of forfeiting the su[m]m of, Ten pounds and loseing their respective
places and offices if they faile therein.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s78">
			<head>LXXVIII. Proviso for Rectors, &amp;c. residing upon Rectory; &amp;c. not exceeding &pound;30 per Ann.</head>
			<para id="p113">Provided neverthelesse and it is hereby further enacted That nothing in this Act contained shall extend to
charge or tax any Rector or Vicar who has the cure of souls and actually resides upon his Rectory or Vicaridge
(upon the account of such his Rectory or Vicaridge only) unlesse his Rectory or Vicaridge does really and truely
exceed the value of Thirty pounds by the yeare or unlesse hee has more then One Rectory or Vicaridge.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s79">
			<head>LXXIX. Officers of Universities not appearing before the Commissioners to take the Oaths of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 8.</head>
			<para id="p114">
				<emph type="i">to pay 8s. in the Pound of their Profits; to be levied as other Monies by this Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p115">Provided always and be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every Master and Fellow of every
Colledge and Hall (who are now resident in this Kingdom) and every Reader and Officer and Minister of either
of the Universities shall voluntarily appear before the said Commissioners or any Three or more of them before
the time limitted for returning the Assessments to bee made by virtue of this Act bee expired and take the Oaths
required and menc[i]oned to bee taken by an Act made in the first yeare of their Majesties Reigne entituled An
Act for the abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance and appointing other Oaths which Oaths the said
Co[m]missioners are hereby impowered and required to administer and make an entry and memorandum thereof in some
book to bee kept for that purpose and upon neglect or not appeareing and takeing the said Oaths as aforesaid
Eight shillings in the pound of the profitts which he or they [may<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] have received had hee or they taken the said
oaths for or by reason of all and every stipend wages salary or profitts whatsoever ariseing or growing due in respect
of the said several places or imployments in the said Universities Colleges or Halls shall be actually paid to their
Majesties for the use of the Warr [to<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] be levied collected and received in such manner as the rest of the money
given by this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s80">
			<head>LXXX. Nothing herein to confirm Persons not taking the said Oaths.</head>
			<para id="p116">Provided always that nothing herein contained shall extend or be construed to extend to confirme any of the
said persons who have or shall neglect or refuse [to take the said oaths<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] in such manner as is herein before
appointed in their respective places [and<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] employments.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s81">
			<head>LXXXI. Tenants of Lands of Colleges paying Taxes, &amp;c. not discharged from paying the same.</head>
			<para id="p117">Provided always that nothing contained in this Act shall be construed or taken to discharge any Tenant of
any of the Houses or Lands belonging to the said Colledges Halls Hospitals Almshouses or Schools or any of
them who by their leases or other contracts are and do stand obliged to pay and discharge all Rates Taxes and
Impositions whatsoever but that they and every of them shall be rated and pay all such Rates Taxes and
Impositions any thing in this Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">quanty <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">assessing ordering <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Boroughs Townes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Messuages Lands <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">through <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">collected or received <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">this Act <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">payable <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">Church <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">then <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">Pounds <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">not <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">Assignees <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">as <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">Money <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">be otherwise <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">might <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


