<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46390" pubid="352" publish="ture">
	<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for delivering Declaracions to Prisoners. [Chapter. XXI. Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Inconvenience of the present Course of Practice.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Prisoner in Custody charged and detained for want of Sureties for Appearance.; Within what Time Plaintiff may declare.; Prisoner not appearing to Declaration, Judgment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by the course of Practise in the respective Courts of Record att Westminster after the Plaintiff o<emph type="p">r</emph>
Plaintiffs in any Writt issued out of any of the said Courts have been att great charge to arrest the
Defendant or Defendants upon such Writ and the Defendant or Defendants for want of sufficient bail are often
co[m]mitted to goal and unlesse the Plaintiffe or Plaintiffs shall before the end of Two Terms next after such arrest
cause such Defendant or Defendants by Writt of Habeas Corpus to be removed to be charged in the said respective
Courts with Declarac[i]ons of the cause of such action or actions such prisoner or prisoners are upon a co[m]mon Bail
or appearance by Attorney discharged from their Imprisonment to the great prejudice of the Plaintiffs. For remedy
whereof be it enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the
Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the
same That if now or att any time after the Five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety and
three any Defendant or Defendants be taken or charged in custody att the suit of any person or persons upon any
Writ or Writs out of any of the said Courts att Westminster and imprisoned or detained in prison for want of
sureties for their appearance to the same the Plaintiff or Plaintiffs in such Writ or Writs shall and may by virtue of
this Act before the end of the next Terme after such Writ or Processe shall be returnable declare against such
prisoner or prisoners in the respective Court or Courts out of which the Writ or Writs shall issue whereupon
the said prisoner or prisoners shall be taken and imprisoned or charged in custody and shall or may cause a true
copy thereof to be delivered to such prisoner or prisoners or to the Goaler or Keeper of the prison, or Goaler in
whose custody such prisoner shall be and remain; to which Declarac[i]on or Declarac[i]ons the said prisoner or prisoners
shall appeare and plead And if such prisoner or prisoners shall not appeare and plead to the same the Plaintiff
or Plaintiffs in such cases shall have Judgment [in such manner<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] as if the prisoner or prisoners had appeared in
the said respective Courts and refused to answer or plead to such Declaration.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. In the King's Bench, Declaration to allege in Custody of what Sheriff, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p3">[And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That in all Declarac[i]ons against any prisoner or prisoners
detained in prison by virtue of any Writt or Processe issued or to be issued out of the Court of Kings Bench
it shall be alledged in custody of what Sheriff Bailiff or Steward of any Franchise or other person having the
returne and execution of Writts such prisoner or prisoners shall be att the time of such declaration by virtue of
the Processe of the said Court att suit of the Plaintiffs which allegation shall be as good and effectuall to all
intents and purposes as if such prisoner or prisoners were in the custody of the Marshal of the Marshalsea of
our Sovereigne Lord and Lady the King and Queen.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">omitted in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">This Clause annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
	</section>
</report>

