<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46394" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1692</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for continuing the Acts For prohibiting all Trade and Commerce with France and for the encouragement of Privateers. [Chapter XXV. Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 34. 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 14. continued for Three Years.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas an Act made in the first yeare of their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for prohibiting all
Trade and Co[m]merce with France And also another Act made in the second yeare of their Majesties
Reigne entituled An Act for the more effectual putting in execuc[i]on an Act entituled An Act for prohibiting all
Trade and Comerce with France will expire att the end of this present Session of Parliament unlesse some
Provision bee made in that behalfe Be it enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with
the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled
and by the Authority of the same that the said two Acts and every Clause Article Matter and Thing in them
contained except what is altered and otherwise provided for by this present Act shall continue and be in force
dureing the terme of three yeares if the present warr with France shall soe long last to be accounted from the
end of this present Session of Parliament and from thence to the end of the next Session of Parliament after the
expiration of the said three yeares.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Prizes to be put into the Commissioners Hands till judged Prize.</head>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Bail may be given for perishable Goods</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">And whereas it would much tend to the annoying and damageing their Majesties Enemies and to the better
secureing the Trade and Commerce of this Kingdom if greater numbers of Ships were equipp'd and set out in
warlike manner by their Majesties Subjects To which end it is requisite that all fitting encouragement
should be given to all Merchants Owners and Setters out of and all the Officers Marriners and Seamen
co[m]manding and serving in any private Man of Warr for the seizeing surprizeing and takeing of Ships and Vessels
belonging to their Majesties Enemies yet neverthelesse effectual provision ought alsoe to bee made that under
pretence of Prize Goods noe evil minded Persons may by collusion carry on any Trade with France contrary to
the true intent of the before mentioned Acts Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid that all Ships and Vessels
with their ladings and all Goods and Merchandizes that shall be taken or seized as Prize either by their Majesties
Ships of Warr or by any Ships sett forth as Privateers or otherwise shall be imported and brought into some of
their Majesties Ports of this Kingdom and immediately without breakeing of Bulk put into the possession of their
Majesties Commissioners for Prizes or their Officers or Agents in the said Port who together with two or more
such Persons as the Officers or Mariners of the respective Ships shall intrust and alsoe such Person or Persons as
shall be appointed by the Co[m]missioners of the Customs in that behalfe are to take care of and preserve the
same from imbezelments until such time as the same shall be adjudged lawfull Prize [except where it shall appear
to the Judge of the Admiralty that the Goods taken are perishable in which case the said Judge shall take Bail
for such Goods in order to the sale thereof as hee might have done before the makeing of this Act yet so as to
be subject to such manner of sale and distribution as is particularly provided by this Act.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. When Ship adjudged Prize, Goods prohibited to be imported to be put in the King's Warehouse.</head>
		<para id="p4">And be it further enacted That notwithstanding any thing in the before menc[i]oned Acts or either of them
contained if any Goods Merchandizes or other Things which by the said Acts or either of them are prohibited to
be imported into the Kingdom of England or Ireland Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed or
Isles of Jersey Guernsey Alderney Sark or Isle of Man shall be really and bona fide without any manner of fraud
or collusion taken as Prize by any private Ships of Warr duely commissioned in that behalfe or by any of their
Majesties Ships of Warr and shall be adjudged good and lawfull Prize as aforesaid it shall be lawfull for their
Majesties Co[m]missioners for Prises or their Officers or Agents in the same Port as soon as may be after that the
same shall be adjudged Prize as aforesaid to cause the said Goods or Co[m]modities to be entred and to bee landed
and brought into their Majesties Warehouse of such Port where such Goods or Merchandizes shall bee imported
there to remaine and to bee safely and entirely kept and preserved until the same shall be sold in manner as
hereafter is directed.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Prize Goods to be publicly sold by Inch of Candle.</head>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">Notice of Sale</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">And be it further enacted that as soon as conveniently may bee after the said Goods Merchandizes or other
things shall bee adjudged Prize and landed as aforesaid the same shall be by the Commissioners for Prizes or their
Officers or Agents in the Presence of such Persons as shall be intrusted by the Commissioners of the Customs
and by the Owners Officers and Mariners of such Shipp of Warr publicly and openly sold by Inch of Candle
to the best advantage (publick notice being first given by the space of fourteen days att the Markett Crosse or
other most publick place of the said Port as alsoe upon the Exchange in the Port of London of the Quantity or
Quality of the Goods Merchandizes and Things to be sold and of the time and place of sale.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. Proceeds subject to Payment of Custom and then divided as herein mentioned.</head>
		<para id="p7">
			<emph type="i">Proceedings as to such Proceeds where Prize taken by Privateer</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p8">And be it further enacted that out of the proceed of such sale the subsidy of Tonnage and Poundage and all
other Duties and Impositions payable to their Majesties for such Goods Merchandizes and Things shall be deducted
and answered to their Majesties and the neat proceed of the said sale after such deductions in case where such
Prize was taken by any private Man of Warr shall be divided into five parts of which foure parts shall be
answered (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) to the Persons [interested<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] in the Privateer or Privateers which took the said Prize and the other
fifth part shall be answered and paid to their Majesties their Heirs and Successors And in case any such Prize
was taken by any private Man of Warr the Shipp or Vessell so surprized or taken as Prize and all the Arms
Am[m]unition Tackle Cables Anchors Sails and Furniture thereof shall bee had taken and enjoyed by the Persons
[interested<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] in the private Man of Warr which took the same And in case such Prize was taken by any of their
Majesties Ships of Warr the said neat proceed thereof after such sale as aforesaid and after the Duties and Impositions
payable to their Majesties deducted as aforesaid shall be divided into three equal parts one third part whereof shall
be answered and paid to the Commander or Captaine Mariners and Seamen surprizeing and takeing the same to
be distributed according to the usual Custom of the Sea for shareing of Prizes or such declarac[i]ons or orders as
have been or shall bee made by their Majesties in that behalfe.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. Proviso as to Division of the Crew's Share of such Proceeds.</head>
		<para id="p9">Provided that one third part thereof shall be distributed amongst the Ships Crew one third part to bee paid
to the Treasurer of their Majesties Navy for relief of sick and wounded Mariners and Seamen and the Widows
Children and impotent Parents of Persons slaine in their Majesties Service att Sea and the other third part to
the use of their Majesties their Heires and Successors And in case such Prize was taken by any Merchant Shipp
or Shipps employed in their Majesties Service the neat proceed thereof after such sale as aforesaid and after the
Duties Impositions and Customs to their Majesties deducted as aforesaid shall be divided into three equal parts one
third part to be answered and paid to the Captaine Officers Mariners and Seamen surprizeing and takeing the same
one third part to the use of their Majesties their Heire and Successors and the other third part shall bee paid to
the Tresurer of their Majesties Navy for the time being to be disposed of for the purposes aforesaid.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. Captains, &amp;c. embezzling Goods, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">Penalty.; Proof how and before whom made.; Penalty how distributed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p11">Provided always and be it enacted that if any Captains or other Officers Mariners or Seamen who shall
take such Prize or Prizes as aforesaid shall imbezel purloine conceal or convey away or put on shore or cause
or procure to be imbezelled purloined concealed or conveyed away or put on shore any part or parcell of such
Goods or Merchandizes in any place whatsoever other then their Majesties Warehouses of the said Ports as
aforesaid such Person so offending shall forfeit and lose the whole share benefitt and advantage which otherwise
hee might or ought to have had in the Prize whereof the Goods &amp; Merchandizes so imbezelled concealed or
conveyed away or put on shore were part or parcel upon proof thereof made by one or more witnesses upon Oath
before the Co[m]missioners of the Customs in the Port of London (if such Goods and Merchandizes shall bee so
imbezelled or put on shore in the said Port or in any place within the view or knowledge of any of the Officers
of their Majesties Customs belonging to the Port of London) and before the chief Magistrate of the place in the
presence of the chief Officer of the Port in any other Port where such Prize Goods shall be imported which
Oath the said Co[m]issioners of the Customs in the Port of London and the chief Magistrate respectively are
hereby required and impowered to administer and to heare and determine the said Matter without delay And
one moiety of the said Wares and Merchandizes shall be to the use of the informer and shall be delivered to
him by Warrant of the said Co[m]missioners of the Customs in the Port of London or of the chief Magistrate of the
place signed and sealed in the presence of the chief Officer of the Customs in such Port respectively and the other
moiety shall be to the use of their Majesties their Heires and Successors.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. Person concerned in Prize to see the Accounts.</head>
		<para id="p12">
			<emph type="i">Fee</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p13">And it is hereby further enacted that any Person Seaman or other concerned in any Prize shall and may att any
seasonable time be permitted to see and peruse the accompts of any Prize that hee or they may bee satisfied
whether the shares have been rightly distributed and the Commissioners for Prizes and their Officers are hereby
required to shew or cause to be shewn unto such Person or Persons such accounts for their perusal and to take
no more Fee or Reward for the same then one shilling for one account att one time.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>IX. Privateers taking French Ships by Collusion.</head>
		<para id="p14">
			<emph type="i">Privateer and her said Prize adjudged Prize to the Crown.; If by Man of War.; Penalty &pound;1000. on Captain and Disability, and Prize adjudged Prize to the Crown</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p15">And be it further enacted that in case any Shipp or Vessell or any Goods or Merchandizes of the growth
product or manufacture of the Dominions or Territories of the French King shall be taken by any Privateer through
consent or clandestinely or by collusion such Ship and Vessel and such Goods and Merchandizes and alsoe the
Shipp Tackle Apparel Furniture and Ammunition of such Privateer shall upon proof thereof to bee made in their
Majesties Court of Exchequer or in the Court of Admiralty be declared and adjudged to be good Prize to their
Majesties and one moiety thereof shall bee to the use of their Majesties their Heires and Successors and the other
moiety to the use of such Person who shall discover the same and the Bond given by the Captaine of such
Privateer shall be and is hereby adjudged to be forfeited to their Majesties And in case any such Shipp Vessel
or any Goods or Merchandizes as aforesaid shall be taken by any Man of Warr through consent clandestinely or
by collusion of the Co[m]mander or Captaine such Co[m]mander or Captaine shall forfeit the su[m]m of One thousand
Pounds one moiety thereof to the use of their Majesties their Heires and Successors and the other moiety to the
use of such Person who shall discover the same to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on in
any of their Majesties Courts of Record wherein noe essoign protection priveledge or wager of Law nor any more
then one imparlance shall be allowed and such Captaine or Officer shall forfeit his Command or Imployment and
shall be and is hereby disabled and made incapable of any Office or Imployment under their Majesties dureing the
space of seven yeares And the said Goods and Merchandize and the Shipp Tackle Apparel Furniture
Guns and Ammunition so taken by collusion shall be and is hereby adjudged to bee good Prize to their
Majesties.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s10">
		<head>X. One Tenth Part of such last mentioned Prize to be disposed of by Admiralty for Medals, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p16">Provided always and be it further enacted that in all cases where the said Prize shall not be taken by any
private Man of Warr one tenth part thereof after such sale and deduction of their Majesties Customs as aforesaid
[and before any division of the p[ro]ceed thereof shall bee made as aforesaid<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] shall be paid to the Treasurer of the
Navy for the time being which said tenth part shall be separated and kept apart by the said Tresurer of the
Navy and shall be disposed of from time to time by Warrant of the Co[m]missioners for executeing the Office of
Lord High Admiral or Lord High Admiral for the time being for Medals and other Rewards for Officers Mariners
and Seamen in their Majesties Service att Sea who shall be found to have done any signal or extraordinary
Service.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s11">
		<head>XI. Taking, &amp;c. a French Ship of War. Reward.</head>
		<para id="p17">And for the better encouragement of Officers Seamen and Mariners to annoy the Enemy and to attempt and
take or destroy Ships of Warr and of force belonging to the Enemy Be it further enacted That in case any of
their Majesties Ships of War or any private Man of War shall take in fight as Prize or shall sink fire or by any
other means destroy any Shipp of Warr or any private Man of Warr belonging to the French King or his
Subjects or in the Service of the French King they shall receive and have as a reward for such Service for each
piece of Ordnance whether Iron or Brasse in any such Ship of Warr or private Man of Warr so taken or
destroyed Ten Pounds to bee paid by the Commissioners for Prizes out of their Majesties share of Prizes.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s12">
		<head>XII. Commissioners for Prizes not paying Reward;</head>
		<para id="p18">
			<emph type="i">Incapacity</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p19">[Provided always and be it enacted That if the Co[m]missioners for Prizes shall not pay any su[m]m or su[m]ms of
money or give a Bill or Bills payable out of the first money that comes to their hands to the persons interested
in Private Men of Warr for the reward hereby given them of ten pounds a gun by the space of three days
after the same ought by the true intent of this Act to be paid and demand thereof made free of all Charges
Fees and Deductions whatsoever in such case the said Co[m]missioners shall be made incapable of any Office in their
Majesties Service for the future.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s13">
		<head>XIII. Shares, &amp;c. here given in lieu of Shares in Prize taken in Fight, &amp;c. 13 Car. II. Stat. 1. c. 9.</head>
		<para id="p20">And be it further enacted and declared That the shares proportions and rewards by this Act given to the
respective Comanders Officers and Seamen shall be in lieu and full satisfaction of all shares in prizes taken in
fight as well as otherwise dureing this present Warr Any thing in an Act made in the thirteenth yeare of the
Reigne of the late King Charles the Second entituled Articles and Ordinances for the regulateing and Government
of his Majesties Navy Ships of Warr and Forces by Sea or any Declara[i]on or Order of their Majesties to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s14">
		<head>XIV. Captains, &amp;c. embezzling Goods taken as Prize.</head>
		<para id="p21">
			<emph type="i">Penalty.; If an Officer, Penalty &pound;500. and Incapacity for 7 Years</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p22">And be it further enacted That if any Captaine or Officer or any other person by his co[m]mand or direction or
any Seaman Soldier or other person serving in their Majesties Navy or in any Privateer shall take to him or
themselves or imbezel any Money Plate Goods Lading or Tackle or other things upon or above the Gun Deck or
any other part or place whatsoever in any Ship taken or seized on for Prize or retaken from the Enemy the
party offending shall lose and forfeit the Shares Proportions and Rewards to him allowed by this Act And alsoe
in case such person be an Officer hee shall forfeit the su[m]m of Five hundred pounds (whereof one moiety shall
be to their Majesties and the other moiety to him who shall sue for the same in [any<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] of their Majesties Courts
att Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection Priveledge Wager of Law or more then one Imparlance shall be
allowed) for every such offence and such Officer shall be uncapable of any Office or Imployment under their
Majesties dureing the space of seven yeares It being the true intent of this Act that all Goods upon or above
the Gun Deck and elsewhere shall in all places be preserved intire from Imbezelments and shall not be pillaged
in any case whatsoever.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s15">
		<head>XV. Prizes taken in the Streights may be carried to Cadiz, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p23">Provided always and be it enacted That where any Ship or Vessel shall be taken as Prize in the Mediterranean
Sea or within the Straits of Gibraltar it shall be lawfull for the Captors to carry such Ship or Vessel into the
Port of Cadiz or Alicant in Spain or the Port of Messina in Sicilly or the Port of Naples and to put the same
into the possession of such person or persons as is or are shall be authorized by their Majesties to receive and
preserve the same there to remaine and be kept without Imbezelment until the same shall be by the Court of
Admiralty of England adjudged lawfull Prize or cleared and discharged or otherwise legally disposed of such Captors
being hereby required with all possible speed to transmitt the Original Papers taken in such Shipp or Vessel or
attested Copies thereof to the said Court.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s16">
		<head>XVI. Prizes in the West Indies or America may be carried to any English Port there.</head>
		<para id="p24">And be it further enacted That where any Ship or Vessel shall be taken as Prize in the West Indies or
America it shall be lawfull for the Captors to carry such Ship or Vessel into any of their Majesties ports in any
of their Islands or Plantations there and to put the same into the possession of the chief Governour of such
respective Islands or Plantations there to remaine and bee kept as aforesaid until the same shall be condemned
or discharged or otherwise lawfully disposed of as aforesaid by such persons as shall be, lawfully Commissioned
in that behalfe.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s17">
		<head>XVII. Prizes in the East Indies, &amp;c. to any English Port there.</head>
		<para id="p25">And be it further enacted That in case any Shipp or Vessel shall be taken as Prize in the East Indies or in
any place beyond the Cape of Good Hope it shall be lawful for the Captors to carry such Shipp or Vessel into
any port or place where any English Factory is established and to put the same into the possession of the Governour
or Chief Person of the said Factory to be preserved as aforesaid until Condemnation by such persons as shall be
lawfully commissioned in that behalfe.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s18">
		<head>XVIII. Prize taken by Privateer, not having French Commodities, paying Customs, to go to Owner of Privateer.</head>
		<para id="p26">And be it further enacted That where any Ship or Vessel shall be taken as Prize by any Private Man of Warr
in which Ship or Vessel there shall be noe Goods or Merchandizes of the growth production or manufacture
of the Dominions of the French King and the same shall appeare upon landing thereof as aforesaid and due
proof made that then after lawfull Condemnation of such Prize and payment of Customs and other duties to theire
Majesties payable for such Goods and Merchandizes the persons interested in such Private Man of War shall have
the said Ship Goods and Merchandizes to their owne use without deduction for Tenths or any other part or
proportion thereof payable to their Majesties or to the Lord High Admiral of England.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s19">
		<head>XIX. Prizes taken in Ports given to their Majesties.</head>
		<para id="p27">And for preventing abuses practised by Privateers in pretending to take as Prize Ships or Vessels being within
their Majesties Ports Rivers or Havens be it enacted That where any Ship or Vessel shall be taken in any of
their Majesties Ports Havens or Rivers by any Privateer such Prize upon Condemnation thereof shall be and
belong wholly and entirely to their Majesties as a perquisite [to<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] the Admiralty of England and the said Captors
to have such part or proportion thereof only as Their Majesties shall think fitt to allow.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s20">
		<head>XX. Ship retaken from the French shall be restored to the Owner, paying certain Monies in lieu of Salvage.</head>
		<para id="p28">
			<emph type="i">Regulations as to Payment and Division of Monies in lieu of Salvage</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p29">Provided always and be it enacted That if any Ship Vessel or Boat taken as prize or any Goods therein shall
appeare and be proved in the Court of Admiralty to be belonging to any of their Majesties Subjects of England
Scotland or Ireland or any of the Dominions and Territories thereunto belonging remaineing and continueing
under their Majesties protection and obedience which were before taken or surprized by the Subjects of the
French King or any of Their Majesties Enemies and afterwards againe surprized and retaken by any of their
Majesties Ships of Warr or any Private Man of War or other Ship Vessel or Boat under their Majesties
protection or obedience that then such Ships Vessels Boats and Goods and every such part and parts thereof
as aforesaid belonging to such Their Majesties Subjects shall be adjudged to be restored and shall be by Decree
of the said Court of Admiralty accordingly restored to such former Owner or Owners or Proprietors he or they
paying for and in lieu of Salvage if taken by one of Their Majesties Ships of Warr an eighth part of the true
value of the Ships Vessels Boats and Goods respectively so to be restored which Salvage shall be answered and
paid to the Captaines Officers and Seamen in the said Man of War to be divided in such manner as before in
this Act is directed touching the Share of Prizes belonging to the Captaines Officers and Seamen where Prizes
are taken by any of Their Majesties Ships of War And if taken by a Privateer or other Ship Vessel or Boat
after having been in the possession of the Enemy twenty foure houres an eighth part of the true value of the said
Ships Vessels Boats and Goods and if above Twenty foure houres and under Forty eight a fifth part thereof
[&amp; if above Forty eight houres &amp; under Ninety six a third p[er]te thereof<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] and if above Ninety six houres a moiety
thereof All which payments to be made to any Privateer or other Ship Vessel or Boat shall be without any
deductions and if such Ship so retaken shall appeare to have been after the taking by the Enemy by them sett
forth as a Man of War the former Owners or Proprietors to whom the same shall be restored shall be adjudged
to pay and shall pay for Salvage the full moiety of the true value of the said Ship so taken and restored without
deduction as aforesaid Any law custom or usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s21">
		<head>XXI. Boat or Vessel exporting Wool taken by Privateer forfeited. How divided.</head>
		<para id="p30">And be it further enacted That in case att any time dureing the continuance of this Act any Boat or Vessel
laden with Wool or whereupon Wool is laden with intent to transport the same contrary to Law shall be taken
by any Private Man of War on due Proof thereof upon Tryal or Proceeding had in their Majesties Court of
Exchequer the Persons interested in such Private Man of War shall have to their owne use one full Moiety of
the said Vessel and Goods the other Moiety to be to the use of their Majesties their Heires and Successors Any
law or statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s22">
		<head>XXII. Admirals to express the Purport of this Act in their Instructions.</head>
		<para id="p31">And to prevent all pretence of Ignorance of the Matters contained in this Act by any Captains Officers or
Seamen serving in any of Their Majesties Ships of War or Private Ships of War the Lord High Admiral or
Co[m]missioners for executing the Office of Lord High Admiral for the time being is and are hereby required to
expresse all things by this Act directed to be observed concerning Prizes and the Shares Proportions and Rewards
of and for the same in the Instructions by them from time to time given dureing the continuance of this Act to
all Captains and Co[m]manders of any of Their Majesties Ships of War and to all Commanders of any Private Ship
of War by them authorized dureing that time.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s23">
		<head>XXIII. French Goods imported to be sued for as by</head>
		<para id="p32">
			<emph type="i">13 &amp; 14 (14) Car. II. c. 11.; and secured and sold as Prize Goods</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p33">And for the incouragement of such persons duely authorized by the Co[m]missioners of Their Majesties Customs
as shall make discovery and seize any Goods of the Growth Manufacture or Product of France imported into
any of their Majesties Dominions contrary to the true intent and meaning of this present Act be it enacted by
the Authority aforesaid That all such Goods so imported and seized shall be sued for and prosecuted in their
Majesties Court of Exchequer in such manner and forme as is provided by an Act made in the (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) Fourteenth
yeare of the Reigne of the late King Charles the Second entituled An Act for preventing of Frauds in their
Majesties Customs two thirds of the said Goods to be for the Use of their Majesties their Heires and Successors
(they defraying the Charges of the Prosecution of such Goods) and One third to the Prosecutor and no composition
to be made for their Majesties part upon any pretence whatsoever All the said Goods to be secured and sold
in such manner as Prize Goods are by this Act appointed to be secured and sold Any law or statute to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s24">
		<head>XXIV. Commissioners of Prizes detaining Shares.</head>
		<para id="p34">
			<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p35">Provided always and be it enacted That if the Co[m]missioners of the Prizes or Co[m]missioners of the Customs shall
detain in their Hands the Shares and Proportions belonging to the Persons interested in any Private Man of War
by the space of Two days after the same ought by the true intent of this Act to be paid and demand thereof
made free of all Fees Charges and Deductions [whatsoever<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] except Warehouse Room and Two Pounds per
Centum for all other Charges in such case the persons offending shall forfeit double the Su[m]m so detained to be
recovered together with Costs of Suit by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on wherein no Essoign Protection
Priveledge or Wager of Law or more then one Imparlance shall be granted.</para>
		<para id="p36">PRIVATE ACTS</para>
		<para id="p37">1. An Act for the Sale of the Estate of Anthony Eyre Esq[uire] deceased for Payment of his Debts. and Portions
for his Children.</para>
		<para id="p38">2. An Act for vesting the Estate real and personal late of Henry Hawley in Trustees to be sold or otherwise
disposed for the benefitt of his Daughters and Heires Susanna and Mary who are both Infants.</para>
		<para id="p39">3. An Act for cleareing and removeing some Doubts which may arise in an Act of Parliament entituled An
Act for the vesting several Mannors Lands and. Rents in the County of Lincoln. Berks and Devon in Trustees
to be sold for the buying other Mannors and Lands to be settled for the same or the like Uses as those to
be sold are now settled.</para>
		<para id="p40">4. An Act to enable Sir John Wentworth Baronett an Infant under the age of One and Twenty yeares to
make a Joynture out and Settlement of his Mannors and Lands in the Counties of York in the County of the
City of York and Westmorland.</para>
		<para id="p41">5. An Act for the more speedy and effectual execution of the Trust created by the Will of Sir Anthony Browne
Baronett deceased and of a Decree in Chancery thereupon.</para>
		<para id="p42">6. An Act to enable Alexander Popham Esq[uire] to settle a Joynture upon his Wife and to make Provision for
younger Children upon Receipt of 12000<ref idref="n9">9</ref>: Portion to be applyed for Payment of his Debts.</para>
		<para id="p43">7. An Act to enable Sir George Parker of Ratton in the County of Sussex Baronett, to make a Settlement upon
his Marriage notwithstanding his Minority.</para>
		<para id="p44">8. An Act to enable William Wake Gent. and William Wake Doctor in Divinity to make Leases for Lives or
Yeares within the Manor of Shapwick in the County of Dorsett.</para>
		<para id="p45">9. An Act for the rectifying a mistake in a certaine Act of this present Parliament passed in the yeare
1691 entituled An Act to vest certaine Lands of William Molineux Gent. in Trustees for raiseing, the sum
of 2000<emph type="p">1</emph>: for paying the Portions to his younger Brothers and Sisters pursuant to a Decree in the Court
of Chancery.</para>
		<para id="p46">10. An Act for the enabling Sir William Mannock Baronett to charge his Estate for the raiseing his younger
Children portions.</para>
		<para id="p47">11. An Act for the settling the Mannor of Kings Noth for the enableing Barnham Powel Esq[uire] to make
provision for his younger Children.</para>
		<para id="p48">12. An Act to enable Ralph Macclesfeild to sell lands for payment of debts and makeing provision for his
Wife and Children.</para>
		<para id="p49">13. An Act for dividing the Chappelries of North Chappel and Dungton from the Parish of Petworth and
erecting them into new Parishes and for settling the Advowsons and Rights of Patronage of the Rectories of
Petworth North Chappell Dungton Clewer Farnham, Royal Worplesdon Kirby Overblowes. and Catton and the
Vicaridge of Long Horsley.</para>
		<para id="p50">14. An Act for the sale of certaine Mannors Messuages Lands and Hereditaments late the Estate of Francis
Osbaston Esq[uire] deceased for the payment of his debts and legacies and raiseing Ten thousand pounds for the portion
of Mary Osbaston his Daughter chargeable upon the said Estate.</para>
		<para id="p51">15. An Act to enable Sir Thomas Wroth Baronett to make a Joynture and Settlement upon his Marriage and
to make a Provision for his Sister notwithstanding his being under the age of One and twenty yeares.</para>
		<para id="p52">16. An Act for the settling a Joynture on the Wife of Anthony Danby Esq[uire] and for makeing provision for
his Brothers and younger Children and for payment of his debts.</para>
		<para id="p53">17. An Act for confirmeing the sale of certain Woodlands in the County of Southampton and certain Articles
of Agreement made between Isaac Wollaston and Richard Wollaston Esq[uire]s.</para>
		<para id="p54">18. An Act for the more speedy and effectuall excuc[i]on of the Trust created by the Will of Henry Baynton
Esq[uire], deceased and for raiseing a Portion for his Daughter.</para>
		<para id="p55">19. An Act to enable Richard Walthall Esq[uire] to sell Lands for the payment of portions and debts.</para>
		<para id="p56">20. An Act for the better assurance of the Manor of Woodlands and Hundred of Knoulton unto Edward
Seymour Esq[uire].</para>
		<para id="p57">21. An Act to enable Trustees to sell part of the Lands and Tenements of Matthew Pitt Esq[uire] and Robert
Pitt Gent. for the payment of debts and to settle the rest of the lands upon the said Matthew and Robert and
the Wife of the said Robert and their Issue.</para>
		<para id="p58">22. An Act for settling the Estate of Francis Boyle Lord Viscount Shannon in the Kingdom of Ireland.</para>
		<para id="p59">23. An Act to enable Humphrey Lord Bishop of Bangor to make a lease of Bangor House with the
Appurtenncs in the Parish of S<emph type="p">t</emph>: Andrews Holborn London for a competent term of years in order to the new
building and improveing the Rent thereof for the benefitt of his successors.</para>
		<para id="p60">24. An Act for vesting the Mannor of Barcroft otherwise Thonocke otherwise Lowthonock Hinton otherwise
Hengton and other Lands in the County of Lincolne Isle of Ely and Counties of Cambridge and Norfolk in
Trustees for the payment of the debts of Thomas Towers Esq[uire] and makeing provision for his Wife and Daughter.</para>
		<para id="p61">25. An Act to enable Thomas Goodwin the younger to sell lands for the payment of debts and makeing
provision for his Wife and Children.</para>
		<para id="p62">26. An Act to enable Roger Price Esq[uire] to sell some part of his Estate for payment of portions to the
Daughters of John Price Esq[uire] deceased.</para>
		<para id="p63">27. An Act to enable Sir John Williams of Langibby Castle in the County of Monmouth Barronett to sell
the Manors of Ewyas Lacy Walerstone and Trescaillan and other lands in the County of Hereford and the Mannor
of Carwent and other lands in the County of Monmouth for payment of his debts.</para>
		<para id="p64">28. An Act for the sale of such interest as Thomas Broomhall Infant hath in the Office of Warden of
the Fleet and in Thirteen Houses adjoyneing and in an Office of the custody and keeping of the Palace att
Westminster for the more effectual payment of debts.</para>
		<para id="p65">29. An Act for exchanging of several small parcells of land in the Parish and Mannor of Fulham belonging
to the Bishoprick of London and part of the Bishoprick of London for other lands of the like value to Charles
Earle of Monmouth and his Heires.</para>
		<para id="p66">30. An Act for the naturalizeing of Henry Sheibell and others.</para>
		<para id="p67">31. An Act for settling and confirming the Mannors and lands in Hameldon in the County of Rutland as they
are now enjoyed and have been for divers yeares last past pursuant to an Agreement for encloseing and exchangeing
of lands there.</para>
		<para id="p68">32. An Act for the sale of lands by Sir Robert Smith and settling other lands of greater value to the same
uses in lieu thereof.</para>
		<para id="p69">33. An Act for the vesting a messuage and lands in Trustees to be sold for the payment of the debts of
Abraham Hinde deceased.</para>
		<para id="p70">34. An Act to enable Abel Atwood to sell some lands to pay debts and make provision for younger Children.</para>
		<para id="p71">Anno Regni 5&deg; GULIELMI &amp; MARI&AElig;, A. D. 1693.</para>
		<para id="p72">STATUTES made in the Fifth Session of Parliament,
Begun to be holden at Westminster, on the Twentieth Day of March,
In the FIFTH Year of the Reign of K. WILLIAM and Q. MARY.</para>
		<para id="p73">Er Rotulo Parl&iacute;ament&iacute; de Anno regn&iacute; Gul&iacute;elm&iacute; et Mar&iacute;ae, Du&iacute;nto.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">This Exception is annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">and paid <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">interressed <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">This Proviso is annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n7" number="7">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n9" number="9">Thirteenth and, in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
	</section>
</report>

