<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46404" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for Relief of the Orphans and other Creditors of the City of London. [Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The City Lands charged with &pound;8,000 per Ann. for the Orphans.; Except certain Hospitals</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens of the City London (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) have been and are answerable for and
chargeable with all moneys of the Orphans of the said City from time to time paid into the Chamber of the
said City But by reason of sundry accidents and publick calameties are now become indebted to the said Orphans
and other Creditors for principal money and interest thereof in a much greater su[m]m of money then they are able
to satisfie and and pay unlesse some assistance bee given them for the same Be it therefore enacted by the King
and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal
and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That for and towards the
raiseing a perpetual Fond to pay the yearely interest of Foure Pounds for every Hundred Pounds principal money
and of all the said interest thereof due to any Orphan of the said City or the Executors Administrators or Assigns
of any such Orphan unto the Five and twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred ninety three such
interest to be computed from the time it was first payable unto the Five and twentieth day of December One
thousand six hundred eighty three att Five Pounds for the interest of every Hundred Pounds for One yeare
and from the Five and twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred eighty three unto the Five and
twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred ninety three att Three Pounds for the interest of every
Hundred Pounds for one yeare and proportionably for any greater or lesser su[m]m (the interest already received for
such principal money to be deducted) And alsoe to pay the like yearely interest of Foure Pounds for every
Hundred Pounds of the principal money and Interest thereof to be computed as aforesaid due upon Bond Bill
or Note lyable to pay interest between the Five and twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred fifty
and five and the said Five and twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred ninety three or any other
the Creditor or Creditors of the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens or the Executors Administrators or Assigns
of any such Creditor or Creditors on the said Five and twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred
ninety three from the Chamber of the said City or from the Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens thereof and so
proportionably for any greater or lesser su[m]m all and every the Man[n]ors Messuages Lands Marketts and Faires and
other the Hereditaiments Revenues and Income whatsoever of and belonging to the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and
Citizens in possession or reverc[i]on and the improvements that shall or can be made thereof (except the Manors
Messuages Lands Estates Possessions and Revenues of and belonging to Christs Hospital Saint Bartholemew
Bridewell Saint Thomas and Bethlehem Hospitals or any other Hospital in or belonging to the said City of London
or Borough of Southwark and such as are chargeable with and for the repaires of London-Bridge) shall be and
are hereby declared to be yearely charged for ever from and after the Foure and twentieth day of June One
thousand six hundred ninety foure for and towards the raiseing thereout the full and cleare annual su[m]m of Eight
thousand pounds for ever free from all deductions for any Impositions whatsoever which said yearely su[m]m shall
be annually raised and paid out of all and every the said Manors Lands Tenements Hereditaments and other
Revenue whatsoever of and belonging to the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens (except before excepted) and
shall be and is hereby appropriated towards the raiseing such a perpetual Fond and to be applied as aforesaid.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Aqueducts charged.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That all the Aqueducts and right of bringing and conveying
water belonging to the said Mayor Commonalty and Citizens and all the Improvements that shall be att any
time made thereof and all the rents profitts and benefitts whatsoever which do or shall att any time hereafter
arise by any Aqueducts or right of bringing and conveying water which do or shall belong to the said Mayor
Commonalty and Citizens (other then such water as shall be for the supply of the publick Conduits Hospitals
Halls and Prisons in the said City) shall from and after the said Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand
six hundred ninety foure forever be appropriated and applied towards the payment of the said Interest
money.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. &pound;2,000 yearly upon Personal Estates.</head>
			<para id="p5">And for and towards the raiseing such a perpetual Fond and so to be applied as aforesaid Be it further
enacted by the authority aforesaid That from and after the said Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand
six hundred ninety foure the said Mayor Commonalty and Citizens shall and may and they are hereby required
yearely to raise the su[m]m of Two thousand pounds by an equal proportionable assessment upon the personal Estates
of the several Inhabitants within the said City and the liberties thereof to be yearely assessed collected received
and paid or in default of payment distrained for in such manner as the said Mayor Commonalty and Citizens in
their Common Council assembled or otherwise shall from time to time annually direct and appoint.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Grant of Lights for 21 Years, for &pound;600 yearly, to Persons herein named.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Appropriation of the Money during and after the Term</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said Mayor Commonalty and Citizens shall on
or before the said Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety foure demise or grant to
Sir Charles Hara Knight John Stanyon Esq[uire] Phillip Neve Esq[uire] and John Lillye Gen'&tilde; and all other the persons
concerned and interested in the Glass Lights co[m]monly called or knowne by the name of Convex Lights a lease
or licence for the sole use of the publick Lights to be used in all publick places within the said City and the
Liberties thereof for the terme of One and twenty yeares to be computed from the said Foure and twentieth day
of June One thousand six hundred ninety foure reserving the yearely rent of Six hundred pounds in such manner
and by and under such other articles covenants and agreements for payment of the said rent or makeing void
the said lease in default thereof or otherwise as by and between the said Mayor Commonalty and Citizens and
the said persons above mentioned are or shall be agreed on for that purpose by certain articles made or to be
made in that behalfe Which said yearely su[m]m of Six hundred pounds shall be and is hereby appropriated towards
raiseing the said Fond and Payment of the said interest money as aforesaid From and after the determination of
which lease all and every the rents profitts and benefitts whatsoever which the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and
Citizens shall or may att any time lawfully make by farming or granting licence or licences to any person or
persons whatsoever for the lighting the Streets within the said City or the Liberties thereof by such ways and
meanes as the said Mayor Commonalty and Citizens shall think most proper shall be and are hereby declared
and enacted to be for ever appropriated and applied to and for the uses aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Tax upon binding Apprentices.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Books to be kept by Companies;; may be inspected without Fee.; Warden, &#x0026;c. not transmitting Monies received to Chamberlain;; Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And for the further and greater increase of the said Fond Be it enacted That from and after the said Foure
and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety foure every person being free of any of the respective
Companys within the said City of London and the Liberties thereof who shall take or receive any Apprentice shall
bind his Apprentice before the Master or Wardens of such Company whereof the Master is a Member or one
of them or their sufficient Deputy in that behalfe which said Apprentice att the time of his binding shall pay to
the said Master or Wardens or one of them or their sufficient Deputy the su[m]m of Two shillings and six pence
All and every which said su[m]m and su[m]ms of Two shillings and six pence the said Master and Wardens or their
Deputy shall transmitt and pay to the Chamberlain of the [said<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] City of London twice in the yeare (viz<emph type="p">t</emph>:) on
the Fifteenth day of December and Eighteenth day of June to be employed for the uses aforesaid And all and
every Master Warden or Wardens of the said respective Companies shall from time to time provide and keep in
their Co[m]mon Halls one or more Book or Books of Vellom or Parchment in which every such sum of Two
shillings and six pence shall be sett downe and entred by the said Master or Wardens or their respective Deputie
or Deputies and the name of the Apprentice who paid the same And it shall and may be lawfull to and for
every person and persons to have free accesse unto and view the said Books att all times between the houres of
nine and twelve in the forenoon without any fee or reward to be taken for the view or inspection thereof And
for every sum of money which such Master Warden or Wardens or their Deputies shall receive and shall not be
transmitted to the said Chamberlaine att the times herein before appointed such Master Warden or Wardens shall
forfeit the sum of Five pounds the said respective Forfeitures to be recovered in the name of the Chamberlaine
of the said City for the time being in any Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on to be co[m]menced in any of
their Majesties Courts of Record wherein noe Essoign Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed and shall
be applied towards raiseing the Fond aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. 5s. upon Admission to Freedom.</head>
			<para id="p10">And be it further enacted That towards the raiseing the said Fond every person who shall be admitted from and
after the said Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety foure to be a Freeman of the
said City shall att the time of his admission pay unto the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens of the said City
the su[m]m of Five Shillings Which several above-menc[i]oed su[m]ms of Two shillings and six pence and Five shillings
shall from and after the said Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety foure be paid
over and above the usual and accustomed Fees for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. 4s. per Tun upon Wines imported into London.</head>
			<para id="p11">And be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That a duty of Foure shillings per Tun shall be and is
hereby imposed and laid upon all sorts of Wines whatsoever which from and after the said Foure and twentieth
day of June One thousand six hundred ninety foure shall be imported into the Port of the said City of London
or the Members thereof by way of Merchandize over and above the present Duties charged or chargeable thereupon
and so proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity which said duty shall from time to time for ever be paid
by the Importer thereof unto the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens and is hereby appropriated towards raiseing
the said Fond and so to be applied as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Collector appointed by Mayor, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Duty levied as by; 12 Car. II. c. 4</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And for the better collecting the said duty from all and every person or persons whatsoever as well free as
unfreemen of the said City Be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That one or more sufficient person or persons
shall from time to time be appointed by the said Mayor and Court of Aldermen of London for the time being
by an Order of the said Court to collect and receive the said duty dureing the pleasure of the said Court And
the said Imposition of Foure shillings per Tun shall be raised levied collected and paid to the said collector or
collectors or his or their deputy and deputies in the same manner and forme and by such rules rates ways
and meanes and under such penalties and forfeitures as are provided menc[i]oed and expressed in one Act of
Parliament made in the Twelfth yeare of the reign of King Charles the Second entituled A Subsidy granted to
the King of Tonnage and Poundage and other su[m]ms of money payable upon merchandize exported and imported
for the paying recovering collecting or seizeing the Duty of Tonnage thereby granted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Duty upon Coals brought into London.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">4d. for Metage.; 6d. per Chaldron over the said Metage, and all other Duties on Coals and Culm; and for Coals sold by the Ton, 6d. per Ton;; how and when paid;; Receipt, without Fee, to Person paying Duty.; levied as by 19 Car. II. c. 3. which is to be in force.; Duties received paid into the Chamber</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">And for a further Increase of the said Fond be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That for all sorts of Coals
which shall be imported or brought into the Port of the said City of London or the River of Thames within the
Liberty of the said City upon the same River to be sold by the Chaldron or Tun there shall be paid by way of
imposition thereupon according to the Rates and Duties herein after mentioned (that is to say), For all such sort
of Coals or Culm as are usually sold by the Chaldron for [for<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] every Chaldron thereof which shall be imported from
and after the said Foure and Twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety foure the su[m]m of Foure
pence Meetage for ever over and above what is now lawfully paid for the Meetage thereof which said su[m]m shall
bee paid in like manner as the present Duty for Meetage is or hath been accustomed to bee paid and from time
to time be paid to the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens of the said City by the Officer and Officers receiving
the said Meetage. And for all such sort of Coals or Culm which shall be imported into the said Port or Members
thereof from and after the Nine and twentieth day of September which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One
thousand and seven hundred (over and above all other Impositions and Duties and the abovemenc[i]oed su[m]m of Foure
[pence<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the further su[m]m of Six pence for every Chaldron thereof. And for such sort of Coals as are sold by
the Tun for every Tun thereof containeing Two thousand weight the like su[m]m of Six pence which said Imposition
of Sixpence shall continue from the said Nine and twentieth day of September for and dureing the Terme of
Fifty yeares and noe longer And the said Impositions of Six pence for every Chaldron of Coals shall from time
to time dureing the continuance of the said Imposition be answered and paid unto the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and
Citizens by the Master Owner or Owners or other person or persons takeing Charge of any Ship or Vessel
whereupon the same shall be laden before they [shall<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] break Bulk or have a Meeter assigned for the measuring
or weighing any Coals aforesaid to be delivered from on board such Shipp or Vessel the same to bee paid att
such place or places as by the said Mayor and Court of Aldermen shall from time to time be appointed within
the said City or Liberties thereof for the Receipt thereof, upon Receipt whereof the Party appointed to receive the
same shall without delay fee or reward deliver a Receipt to the person or persons who shall pay the said Duty
or Duties Which Receipt shall for soe much be a sufficient discharge And that the said imposition of Six pence
per Tun or Chaldron shall by virtue of this Act be collected and levied in such sort and manner in all and every
respect as in and by one Act made in the Nineteenth yeare of the Reigne of the late King Charles the Second
entituled An Act for the rebuilding the City of London the Imposition of Coals thereby granted was to be collected
and levied and all and every the powers authorities directions and provisions in or by the said Act menc[i]oned or
provided for the levying collecting and recovering thereof or the penalties thereby imposed or for the ordering or
regulateing the Proceedings of the said Coal Meeters or others in discharge of their respective Offices and Duties
or for the preventing of Fraud and Covin and for the discovery of the just quantity of all sorts of Coals to be
imported as aforesaid shall remain and be in force and by virtue of this present Act shall and may be exercised
and put in Ure for the collecting levying and recovering the said Duty of Six pence according to the purport
and effect of the aforesaid Act and under the same Penalties in all and every respect and that for and dureing
all the time by this Act limitted and appointed for the payment of the said imposition as if the same were expresly
menc[i]oed in this present Act with referrence to the said imposition thereby imposed All which moneys so to be
received upon account of the said respective impositions of Foure pence and Six pence or by any other additional
duty in case of concealment thereof as by the aforesaid Act is appointed and all other the su[m]ms of money hereby
appointed as part of the said Fond shall from time to time be paid into the Receipt of the Chamber of the City
of London and shall be and is hereby appropriated towards the raiseing such a Fond as aforesaid and applied
towards the discharge of the said Debts.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Officers concerned in the Receipt of the Duties to give Security.</head>
			<para id="p16">And be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That all and every Officer and Officers or other person or persons
whatsoever concerned or to be concerned in the receipt of any of the su[m]ms by this Act appropriated to the uses
aforesaid before hee or they shall be admitted to take upon him or them the execuc[i]on of any the said Office
or Offices he or they shall be bound with sufficient Sureties to the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens for the
just and faithful execuc[i]on of such Office or Employment in such reasonable su[m]m or su[m]ms as by the said Mayor
or Court of Aldermen shall be thought fitting with respect to this present Act and to the trust hereby reposed
in such Officer or Officers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. On the Determination of the said Duty of 6d. City Lands charged with &pound;6,000 per Annum more.</head>
			<para id="p17">And to the intent that the said Fond may be perpetual be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That
from and after such time as the aforesaid imposition of Six pence hereby laid shall cease and determine all and
every the Mannors Messuages Lands Tenements Marketts Faires and the Duties thereof and all other the Revenues
of and belonging to the said City of London in possession or reversion shall stand and be charged with the full
yearely su[m]m of Six thousand pounds (over and above the said yearely su[m]m of Eight thousand pounds) and is
hereby appropriated and enacted to be applied to the same Uses to which the said yearely sum of Eight thousand
pounds is herein before made lyable.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. In what manner Monies raised by this Act to be applied.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Salaries and other Deductions.; Orders for applying the Monies contrary to this Act, void</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That all and every the aforesaid yearely and other Rents
and Payments Issues Profitts Duties Impositions su[m]m and su[m]ms of money whatsoever by this Act appointed to
be raised charged paid collected had received or made by out of or for any the matters or things or by any
the ways or meanes herein before menc[i]oed shall (deducting thereout such necessary and reasonable salaries and
allowances as the said Mayor and Court of Aldermen shall think fitt to allow to any person or persons whom
they shall employ for the collecting receiving or paying the same) from time to time forever in the first place be
applyed by the Maior Co[m]monalty and Citizens of the said City for the payment of the annual su[m]m of Foure
pounds of lawfull money for the interest of every One hundred pounds and proportionably for a greater or lesser
su[m]m of the abovemenc[i]oed respective Debts and all the Interest thereof due on the said Five and twentieth day
of December One thousand six hundred ninety three to any Orphan of the said City or the Executors Administrators
or Assignes of any such Orphan and alsoe for the payment of the like yearely Interest of Foure pounds for every
Hundred pounds principal money and the interest thereof to be computed as aforesaid due att any time between
the said Five and twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred fifty five and the said Five and twentieth
day of December One thousand six hundred ninety three upon Bond Bill or Note liable to pay interest from the
said Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens unto any person or persons whatsoever or to soe much thereof only as the
said moneys by this Act appointed to be raised and paid as aforesaid shall yearely amount unto to satisfy and
pay towards the said interest to the said Orphans and other the said Creditors of the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and
Citizens or their respective Executors Administrators or Assigns equally in proportion to their respective Interests
the said payments to be made twice in every yeare. (that is to say) on the Feast [Dayes<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] of Saint Thomas the
Apostle and Saint John the Baptist or within Foureteen days after the first payment thereof to be made on the
Feast [day<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] of Saint Thomas the Apostle which shall bee in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
ninety foure or within Fourteen days after And the said moneys or any part thereof shall not be applied issued
or paid to any use intent or purpose whatsoever by vertue of any Order or Warrant whatsoever other then for
the use aforesaid but all Orders and Warrants for issueing paying or disposing any of the said moneys contrary
to the true intent and meaning of this Act shall be utterly void.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. The Provision herein made declared to be a full Discharge of the Debt due from the City to the said Orphans and other Creditors.</head>
			<para id="p20">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Provision hereby made for payment of the said
Interest money for ever shall be and is hereby declared to be in full satisfaction and discharge of and for the
Debts due from the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens of the said City of London to the said Orphans and
others their [said<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Creditors and of and from all Interest due or to be due for the same unto the Five and
twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred ninety three And that all and every the said Orphans and
Creditors or their respective Executors Administrators or Assignes shall according to usual Custom acknowledge
satisfacc[i]on of their respective Debts paying to the Officers concerned such fees onely as the Mayor and Court
of Aldermen for the time being shall direct and appoint not exceeding Thirteen shillings and foure pence for
every Thousand pounds And the said Mayor Commonalty and Citizens of the said City of London and their
Successors are and shall be hereby acquitted and discharged of and from the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Books of Receipts and Disbursements to be kept by the Chamberlain;</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">free Access thereto without Fee.; Accompts to be audited yearly upon Oath.; Allowance to Auditor.; Accompts so audited, allowed by the Court of Aldermen</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And to the end the said moneys may be duely applied to the uses aforesaid for which the same are by this
Act appointed and appropriated be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That there shall from time to
time be provyded and kept by the said Chamberlaine for the said City of London for the time being one or more
book or books of vellom or parchment in which all moneys to be received by any the ways or meanes herein
before menc[i]oed shall from time to time as the same shall bee received bee entred or sett downe and for what
the same was received And alsoe one other [like<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] book or books wherein the accompts of all payments and
disbursements out of the same shall be likewise entred expressing the time when the occasion for which and
the name of the person or persons to whom the same were soe paid and disbursed And that it shall and may
be lawfull to and for all and every person and persons to have free access unto and view of the said respective
books of receipts and disbursements att all times between the Houres of Nine and Twelve in the Forenoon without
any fee or reward to be taken for the view or inspection thereof And that the receipts and payments of all the
moneys aforesaid by the said Chamberleyne of the said City or other Officer who shall be appointed by the said
Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens to receive or issue out the said moneys be audited yearely upon oath before one
of the Auditors of the Imprest for the time being (which oath the said Auditors respectively are hereby required
to administer) between the Feast days of Saint Michael the Archangel and Saint Thomas the Apostle And the said
Auditor shall have and receive of the Chamberleyne of the City of London for the time being the su[m]m of twenty
shillings and noe more for every thousand pounds the said accompts shall amount unto the which accompts so
auditted shall be signed by the said Auditor and be allowed alsoe by the said Mayor and Court of Aldermen
and fairely entred and remain in the Chamber of the said City to bee perused and viewed as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Chamberlain or others misapplying the Money;</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And be it further enacted That if any Chamberlain of the said City of London or other person aforesaid shall
after receipt of any of the said moneys divert or misapply the same or any part thereof contrary to the true intent
and meaning of this Act That then such Officer or person so diverting or misapplying the said money shall forfeit
treble the su[m]m so misapplied which said Forfeitures shall be recovered by any the said Orphans or other Creditors
their Executors Administrators or Assignes that shall sue for the same by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on
in any of their Majesties Courts of Record wherein noe Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Chamberlain, &#x0026;c. to give a Note of what is owing to Orphans, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Debt transferrable.; Transfer to be registered.; Assignce entitled, and may in like manner assign</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Chamberlain and Co[m]mon Serjeant of the said City
shall upon request give unto every of the said Orphans and Creditors and to their respective Executors Administrators
or Assigns a Bill or Note in writeing of the Principal Debt and Interest oweing to such Orphan or Creditor and
to their respective Executors Administrators or Assigns And that any person or persons to whom any money shall
be payable by virtue of this Act may by writeing under his or their respective Hands and Seales assign and transferr
his her or their Right or Interest in and [by<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] such moneys payable by vertue of this Act or any parte thereof to
any person or persons whatsoever which being entred or registred in a Book to be kept by the said Mayor and
Court of Aldermen for that purpose (which they are hereby enjoyned to keep) and the Note or Bill of the said Debt
soe given as aforesaid being delivered upp to the Officer appointed by the said Court of Aldermen for that purpose
who shall thereupon give his Note or Bill in writing of the Debt so assigned to the party or parties to whom
such Assignment shall bee made such Assignee or Assignees his or their Executors Administrators or Assignes shall
be entituled to the benefitt thereof and of all moneys payable thereon and such Assignee or Assignees may in like
manner assign again and so toties quoties and afterwards it shall not be in the power of any such person or persons
who have made such Assignments to make void release or discharge the same or the moneys thereby assigned or
any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. No Person compellable to pay Money belonging to Orphans, into the Chamber.</head>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Process upon Recognizance</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p28">Provided always and be it enacted That noe person or persons whatsoever shall att any time be compelled or
obliged by vertue of any custome within the said City or by any Order or Process of the Court of Orphans or
otherwise howsoever to pay or deliver into the Chamber of the said City of London any su[m]m or su[m]ms of money
or personal estate due or to be due or belonging to any Orphan or Orphans of any Freeman of the said City any
Law or Usage for inforcing the same notwithstanding. Provyded always that nothing herein contained shall be
deemed or construed to extend to impeach make void or prevent Process upon any Recognizance already given
according to the Custome of the said City,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Corporation Lands charged, if Mayor, &#x0026;c. misapply Monies appropriated by this Act.</head>
			<para id="p29">And be it further enacted That if any of the said su[m]m or su[m]ms by this Act appropriated or any part thereof
shall happen to be misapplyed or converted to any other use then as aforesaid by the said Corporation of the
Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens of London for the time being or any of their Officers or any other person by colour
of any warrant or authority by from or under them that then in such case the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens
shall and may be answerable for the same out of the Revenue of the said Corporac[i]on in any Action to be brought
by any of the said Orphans or other Creditors their Heires or Assigns which said su[m]m so recovered shall goe
and be to and for the uses aforesaid in like manner as the same if not misapplyed should or might have been
excepting the costs of such suit which shall be to and for the benefit of him her or them so sueing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Fines, &#x0026;c. upon the Mayor, &#x0026;c. cannot be acquitted.</head>
			<para id="p30">Provided always and be it enacted That all Amerciaments Fines Issues or Distresses against the said [Corporation
of the said<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens and their Successors respectively had charged or levied in or upon
account of such Suit or Actions brought shall be applied to the uses aforesaid and to noe other use whatsoever
nor shall the same be pardoned acquitted or discharged by any Letters of Signett Privy Seale or Great Seale of
their Majesties their Heires or Successors or otherwise howsoever any Law or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Orphans hereafter may take Advantage of this Act;</head>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">and Mayor &#x0026;c. may order Chamberlain to pay, on Notice.; Persons to whom Money paid, to give a Discharge</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p32">Provided always and be it enacted That when and as often as any application shall bee made to the said
Mayor and Court of Aldermen for the time being on behalfe of any Orphan or Orphans of the said City by
the Executors or Administrators of the Father of such Orphans to pay in and lodge any su[m]m or su[m]ms of money
of or belonging to such Orphan or Orphans in the said Chamber and to have the benefitt of the said provision
hereby made it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Mayor and Court of Aldermen and they are hereby
impowered and directed to order the Chamberleyne of the said City for the time being to pay off the like sum
to such person or persons entituled to the said yearely payments as aforesaid as they think fitt not being Orphans
under the Age of One and twenty yeares and giveing Three months notice to or for the person or persons soe
to be paid off and discharged att the end of which Three months upon payment or tendring of the said moneys
due for Interest and Principal too or for the person or persons to whom such notice shall bee given according
to the provision hereby made att the Office of the said Chamberlaine in Guildhall London then and from thenceforth
the annual su[m]m or su[m]ms of money payable to such person or persons to whom such notice payment or tender shall
be made or given shall cease and determine and the same shall become due and payable to or for the use of
such Orphan or Orphans who shall have paid in the moneys for the same and shall be registred accordingly and
be assignable as aforesaid Neverthelesse the moneys soe tendred shall be paid to such person and persons upon
their demand of the same and assigneing [and<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] giveing a discharge for the same it being hereby enacted and declared
that the provision hereby made shall be and remaine a perpetual Stock or Fond for the benefitt of the Orphans
of the said City successively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Orphans that have already transferred may redeem in Three Years Time.</head>
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">Interest at the Rate of &pound;8 per Cent. per Ann</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p34">And be it further enacted and declared That all such of the said Debts due to any of the said Orphans
as have been att any time before the said Five and twentieth day of December assigned or granted or covenanted
to bee assigned or granted or for which any authority hath heretofore been given or granted by any of the said
Orphans their Husbands Executors or Administrators to any person or persons to receive the same or any part
thereof to the use of such person so authorized or any other person besides such Orphan shall and may be
redeemed and are hereby declared to bee redeemable by the said Orphans or their Husbands or their respective
Executors or Administrators on payment of the said Principal sum of money paid in considerac[i]on of makeing the
said assignment grant covenant or authority together with the charges and Interest for the same from the time
of the payment thereof after the rate of Eight pounds per Centum per Annum for One yeare discounting for
what hath been received for or in respect of the said Debt by any such person to whom such assignm<emph type="p">t</emph>: or authority
was made or given and upon paym<emph type="p">t</emph>: or tender of the said Principal money Interest and Charges such grant
assignement or authority and all covenants and agreements concerning the same shall bee void. Provided neverthlesse
that such redemption as aforesaid bee made within the space of three yeares from and after the end of this present
Session of Parliament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII.</head>
			<para id="p35">
				<emph type="i">Bonds to Agents void.; Mayor, &#x0026;c. to pay Agents.; Agent offending; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p36">And whereas diverse persons pretending as Agents and Sollicitors to obtaine the payment of the Orphans Debts
by Act of Parliament or otherwise have induced many Orphans and others for them to enter into obligations
agreem[en]t contracts subscriptions or other securities for payment of large portions of their Debts whensoever it
should be recovered which may amount to very great su[m]ms. Be it therefore enacted by the authority aforesaid
That all such bonds obligations agreements contracts subscriptions and other securities so entered into shall bee
null and void and that it shall be lawfull for the Mayor and Court of Aldermen of the City of London out of the
Revenue settled by this Act for relief of the Orphans and other Creditors to allow and pay unto such Agents
and Sollicitors what they judge may be reasonable which su[m]ms shall be allowed in the account of the said
Revenue and in case any such Agents or Solicitors shall demand or receive any more money upon accompt of
or from any of the said Orphans then what shall bee soe adjudged due to them respectively they shall respectively
forfeit treble the su[m]m they shall soe receive to be recovered together with Costs of Suit by such person or
persons who shall sue for the same by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of their Majesties Courts
of Record att Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection Priveledge or Wager of Law shall be allowed nor any
more then one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Proviso for New River;</head>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">and for York Buildings Water.; 2 W. &#x0026; M. Sess. 2. c. 24. pr.; Proviso for Pipes</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p38">Provided that this Act shall not extend to the New River water nor the proffitts and p[er]quisitts thereof.
Provided neverthelesse that nothing in this Act contained shall be construed or taken to hinder or obstruct the
Governour and Company of Undertakers for raiseing the Thames water in York Buildings or their Assignes from
takeing or draweing water out of the River of Thomas or from laying or repaireing their Pipes or Branches
according to an Act of Parliament in that behalfe made but that they may still enjoy all their Rights and Titles
by the said Act provided and may still continue to take the said Thomas water and to lay and repaire their Pipes
as they might have lawfully done before the makeing of this Act any thing herein contained to the contrary thereof
in any wise notwithstanding. Provided alsoe that neither the said Governour and Company of Undertakers for
raiseing the Thames water in York Buildings or their Assigns nor the said Mayor and Co[m]monalty and Citizens or
their Assigns do or shall disturb obstruct or hinder each other in laying repaireing or amending such their
respective Pipes or Branches or to do or cause to be done any prejudice or damage to each others Pipes or
Branches.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Proviso for Shadwell Water.</head>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">3 W. &#x0026; M. c. 37</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p40">Provided that nothing in this Act shall be construed or taken to hinder or obstruct the Governour and
Company of the Water-works and Waterhouses in Shadwell or their Successors of any right or title to take
and receive water out of the River of Thames nor to hinder or obstruct them in laying Pipes and Branches in
the Streets and open Passages or holding useing exerciseing or enjoying all or any such right title estate powers
priveldges and advantages whatsoever as by one Act of this present Parliament entituled An Act for incorporateing
the Proprietors of the Water-works in the parish of Saint Paul Shadwell in the County of Middlesex and for
the encourageing carrying on and settling the said Waterworks or by any other lawfull ways and means they
and their Successors doe now enjoy the same or as they may or might enjoy the same as if this present Act had
never been made any thing contained herein to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Proviso for Water-works of Thomas Morrice at London Bridge.</head>
			<para id="p41">Provided that this Act or any thing herein contained shall not extend to the Water-works of Master Thomas
Morrice att or neare London Bridge which hee holdeth and enjoyeth by vertue of a grant made to Peter Morrice
his late Grandfather from the Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens of the City of London for the terme of Five
hundred yeares by Indenture under their Co[m]mon Seale dated the Foure and twentieth day of November in the
Five and twentieth yeare of the reigne of the late Queen Elizabeth nor any of the profitts and benefitts ariseing
or accrewing thereby nor to make the same liable or appropriate the same or any part thereof to the payment of
the said Interest moneys or Fond hereby intended other then the rent reserved upon the said lease</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Proviso for S. Hutchinson, he paying a Share in the Convex Lights.</head>
			<para id="p42">Provided always and be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that if Samuel Hutchinson Gentleman or his
assignes shall pay to the Partners in the Convex Lights before the Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand
six hundred ninety five his and their full proportion of money for stock for his and their shares as the other
Partners have paid and do within the same[time<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] agree and covenant under his and their hands and seales to
stand to and performe all such contracts and agreements as are or shall be made by the said Partners then he
the said Samuel Hutchinson his Executors Administrators and Assignes shall and may have hold and enjoy the
same interest and benefitt in the premisses as any of the said Partners do or may att any time hold and enjoy
the same according to their respective proportions.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Persons sued for executing Act may plead General Issue.</head>
			<para id="p43">
				<emph type="i">Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p44">And be it further enacted that if any action plaint suit or information shall be commenced or prosecuted against
any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in persuance or in the execution of this Act such person
or persons shall or may plead the Generall Issue thereunto and upon Tryal of any Issue joyned may give this
Act and the special matter in evidence and if the Plaintiff or Prosecutor shall become nonsuit or forbeare further
prosecution or suffer discontinuance or if a verdict passe against him the Defendant or Defendants shall recover
their Costs for which hee or they shall have the like remedy as in any case where Costs by Law are given to
Defendants:</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. This Act a Publick Act.</head>
			<para id="p45">Provided always and be it enacted by the authority aforesaid that this present Act shall bee accepted taken and
reputed to bee a General Act of Parliament of which all and every the Judge and Judges of this Kingdom in
all Courts shall take notice on all occasions whatsoever as if it were a Publick Act of Parliament relateing to the
whole Kingdome Any thing herein contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Money retained for City Charges for Seven Years, not exceeding &pound;2,000 yearly.</head>
			<para id="p46">And whereas the residue of the Revenue belonging to the said Mayor and Co[m]monalty and Citizens over and
above what is hereby appointed to and for the use of the said Orphans and Creditors will not be sufficient until
further improvements can be made to answer and defray the expences necessary for supporting the Government
and publick charges of the said City Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that for the space of Seven
yeares co[m]mencing from the nine and twentieth day of September last past it shall be lawful for the Mayor and
Court of Aldermen to retaine and apply and for the Chamberlaine to issue and pay towards the necessary expences
or charges any su[m]m or su[m]ms not exceeding in the whole the su[m]m of Two thousand pounds yearely out of the
moneys hereby appointed to and for the use of the said Orphans and Creditors as aforesaid Any thing in this
Act contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Money retained to be repaid.</head>
			<para id="p47">
				<emph type="i">City Lands charged with Re-payment.; Exception of certain Hospitals</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p48">Provided neverthelesse and be it enacted by the authority aforesaid that if after the deduction and allowance
of the said Two thousand pounds per annum for the use and support of the Government of the said City of
London dureing the said terme of Seven yeares there shall not be raised and paid to the Orphans and Creditors
by this Act intended to bee provided for out of the residue of the rents issues and profitts of the several Provisions
and Fonds above menc[i]oed so much money as will fully satisfie [all<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] the said Orphans and Creditors interest for
all their several and respective debts after the rate of Foure pounds per Centum per Annum dureing the said
whole terme of Seven yeares that then and in such case the said Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens of the said City
of London for the time being shall repay into the hands of the Chamberlain of London for the time [being<ref idref="n10">10</ref>]
within Seven yeares after the expiration of the said terme the whole and full su[m]m of Foureteene thousand pounds
or see much thereof as they shall have made use of for the support of the Government by Two thousand pounds
per Annum or such lesse yearely su[m]m as shall be proportionable to what they shall have soe made use of until
the same or soe much thereof as shall make good the deficiency that shall appeare in the satisfaction of the
interest of all the said moneys due to the said Orphans and other Creditors att the rate aforesaid by reason of
applying the said Two thousand pounds per Annum or any part thereof to the use of and for the support of the
Government of the said City for the terme aforesaid shall be satisfied And for secureing the repayment thereof
as aforesaid all and every the estate rents revenues interest perquisites profitts and emoluments of any sort (except
the mannors messuages lands estates possessions and revenue of and belonging to the said Hospitals in or
belonging to the said City of London or Borough of Southwark and such as are chargeable with and for the repaires
of London Bridge) which att the expirac[i]on of the said terme of Seven yeares shall belong unto the said Mayor
Co[m]monalty and Citizens thereof in their politick or publick capacity only shall bee and are hereby charged and
made subject and liable thereunto.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


