<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46402" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for the explaining and for the more effectual execution of a former Act for the relief of poor Prisoners. [Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu.1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 2 W. &#x0026; M. Sess. 2. c. 15.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that several Sheriffs, &#x0026;c. cannot take the Oath thereby prescribed; and that many poor Prisoners are in a deplorable Condition.; 2 W. &#x0026; M. Sess. 2. c. 15.; Sheriffs, &#x0026;c. Oath abolished</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS by [an<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Act of Parliament made in the second yeare of their Majesties Reigne entituled An Act
for relief of poor Prisoners for debt and damags it is (among other things) enacted That the Sheriffs
Goalers or Keepers of Prisons should swear that the Prisoner to be discharged was really and truely his Prisoner
in his custody without fraud or deceit att or upon the eight and twentieth day of November in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred and ninety. And whereas several of the said Sheriffs Goalers or Keepers of
Prisons were not then Sheriffs Goalers or Keepers of the Prisons to which they now belong so that they cannot
take the Oath prescribed by the said Act whereby and by the artifice of the said Sheriffs Goalers or Keepers
of Prisons and other persons enemies to the said poor Prisoners a great nmber of the said poore [prisoners that are
in a more<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] deplorable condition and deserve to be relieved by the said Act and were really and truely Prisoners
att the day referred to in the said Act though the said Sheriffs Goalers or Keepers of the respective Prisons have
refused to swear for them either out of a pretended scruple of conscience that they cannot take the said Oath or
because they had not money enough to give them. For remedy whereof Be it enacted by the King and Queens
most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons
in this present Parliament assembled and by Authority of the same That the aforesaid Acts be revived and
that the said Oath in the said Act of Parliament contained shall for the future be abolished and instead thereof
the Oath herein after mentioned shall be the Oath to be tendred to the Sheriffs Goalers and Keepers of Prisons.</para>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">New Oath</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">I A. B. do swear That I have examined the Comittments or Books belonging to the said Prison and that by
them it doth appeare that. I. S. was really and truely a Prisoner in the custody of the then Goaler or Keeper
of the Prison of. D. [Prison<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] in the County of. C. without [any<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] fraud or deceit by me or any other to my
knowledgeor belief att or upon the Eight and twentieth day of November in the yeare of our Lord God One
thousand six hundred and ninety.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Sheriff refusing the Oath.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.; Quarter Sessions may examine the Matter upon Oath;; and to discharge Prisoner, if truly a Prisoner</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That in case any Sheriff Goaler or Keeper of Prison shall
refuse to take the said Oath hereinbefore appointed to be taken [he being thereto required unlesse it shall appeare
by the Comitments and Books belonging to the said Prison that the person for whom such Oath is required was
not really and truely a prisoner in the custody of the said Goaler and Keeper according to the tenour of the Oath
abovemenc[i]oed and that otherwise the said Goaler or Keeper Goalers or Keepers for his or their so refuseing to
take such Oath shall forfeit and pay to such prisoner so about to be discharged and released from prison and
thereby detained the value of such debt or debts for which hee or she shall be imprisoned to be recovered by
Action of Debt in any of their Majesties Courts of Record And<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] that then and in that case upon complaint of
the prisoner the Justices of the Peace of the County City or Towne where the prison lies att their Quarter Sessions
shall have power to examine the said matter upon Oath of any other persons which Oath they are hereby
impowered and required to administer And if it shall appeare upon the said examination to them or the major
part of them there present that the said prisoner was really and truely a prisoner on the said Eight and twentieth
day of November in the said yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred and ninety that then the said
Justices or the major part of them may and shall discharge the said prisoner and prisoners so as they may have
the full benefitt of the said Act of Parliament notwithstanding the Sheriffs Goalers or Keepers refusal of the
said Oath any thing in the said Act of Parliament for relief of poor prisoners to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Sheriff or other Officer taking above 6s. 6d.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That noe Sheriff Goaler or Keeper of Prison or person
any ways interessed therein nor any Clerk of the Peace or other Officer directly or indirectly by himselfe or any
other shall take of any prisoner to be discharged by virtue of this Act any Chamber Rent Fee or Reward whatsoever
for all or any matter or thing relateing to his said discharge above the su[m]m of six shillings and six pence in the
whole upon paine of forfeiting the value of the debt to be recovered as aforesaid and upon [further<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] paine of
being proceeded against as Extortioners any Law Act of Parliament or Usage to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Justices, Clerks, &#x0026;c. taking Fee for signing Warrant, or undue Fee for Copy of Causes; Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p9">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That no Justice of the Peace his Clerk or Servant shall
take of any Prisoner for signing his warrant and su[m]mons any Fee or Reward whatsoever nor any Clerk of the
Papers or other Officer that shall make out any Copies of Causes for the said Prisoner shall take for any
such Copy of Causes above the sum of Foure pence upon pain to be proceeded against as Extortioners as
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Debts since 28th Nov. 1690.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided always and be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That noe Debtor shall by virtue of this or the
aforesaid Act be discharged of and from any debt contracted by such Debtor since the Eight and twentieth day
of November which was in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and ninety.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">one <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">added in a separate Schedule to the Original Act.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


