<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46406" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII. An Act to take away the Processe for the Capiatur Fine in the several Courts att Westminster. [Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Capias pro Fine taken away.; Fine turned into Costs</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS there are diverse suits and actions of trespasse ejectment assault and false imprisonment brought
by party against party in the respective Courts of Law att Westminster and upon judgement entred against
the defendant or defendants in such suits or actions the respective Courts aforesaid doe (ex officio) issue out
processe against such defendant and defendants for a fine to the Crowne for a breach of the peace thereby co[m]mitted
which is not ascertained but is usually compounded for a small su[m]m of money by some Officer in each of the
said Courts but never estreated into the Exchequer which Officers or some of them doe very often outlaw the
defendants for the same to their very great damage. For remedy whereof Be it enacted by the King and Queens
most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords spiritual and temporal and the Co[m]mons in
this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That from [thenceforth<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] noe Writt or Writts
co[m]monly called Capias pro Fine in any of the said suits or actions in any of the said Courts shall bee sued out
or prosecuted against any of the said defendant or defendants or any [other<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] processe thereupon but the same fines
and all former fines yet unpaid are and shall hereby be remitted and discharged for ever Yet neverthelesse the
plaintiff or plaintiffs in every such action shall (upon signeing judgement therein over and above the usual Fees
for signeing thereof) pay to the proper Officer who signeth the same the su[m]m of Six shillings and eight pence
in full satisfaction of the said fine and all fees due for or concerning the said fine to bee distributed in such
manner as fines and fees of this kind have usually been and not otherwise which said Officer and Officers shall
make an increase to the plaintiff or plaintiffs of soe much in their Costs to bee taxed against the said defendant
and defendants.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">henceforth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">further <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


