<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46403" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IX. An Act for repeal of a Clause in the Statute of the Fifth yeare of Queen Elizabeth (containing diverse Orders
for Artificers and others) which relates to Weavers of Cloath [Rot. Part. pt. 3. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 5 Eliz. c. 4. &sect; 32.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The said Clause repealed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WBHEREAS by an Act of Parliament made in the Fifth yeare of the Reigne of Queen Elizabeth entituled An
Act containing diverse Orders for Artificers Labourers Servants in Husbandry and Apprentices It is enacted
in these words following Provided always and be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that noe person or
persons useing or exerciseing the art or mystery of a Woollen Cloath Weaver other then such as be inhabiting
within the Counties of Cumbland Westmerland Lancaster and Wales Weaving Frizes Cottons or Housewifes Cloath
onely making and weaving Woollen Cloath co[m]monly sold or to be sold by any Cloathman or Clothier shall take
and have any Apprentice or shall teach or in any wise instruct any person or persons in the Science
Art or Occupac[i]on of Weaving aforesaid in any Village Towne or Place (Cities Towns Corporate and Markett
Towns only excepted) unlesse such person bee his son or else that the Father or Mother of such Apprentice or
Servant shall att the time of the taking of such person or persons to be an Apprentice or Servant or to be instructed
have Lands or Tenements or other Hereditaments to the clear yearely value of Three pounds att the least of an
estate of inheritance or freehold to be certified under the Hands and Seals of Three Justices of the Peace of the
Shire or Shires where the said Lands Tenements or other Hereditaments do or shall lye. The effect of the
Indenture to be registred within Three months in the Parish where such Master shall dwell and to pay for such
registring Foure pence upon pain of forfeiture of Twenty shillings for every month that any person shall otherwise
take any Apprentice or sett any such person on work contrary to the meaning of this Article. Now forasmuch as
such part of the said Act before recited hath been found to be very inconvenient and a great prejudice to the
Cloathing Trade May it please your most excellent Majesties That it may be enacted and be it enacted by the
King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal
and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That soe much of the said
Act as is before recited be and is hereby declared to be repealed null and void to all intents and purposes as if
the same had never been made.</para>
	</section>
</report>


