<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46407" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An Act to repeal the Statute made in the Tenth yeare of King Edward the Third for finding sureties for the good abearing by him or her that hath a pardon of Felony. Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 6.</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Recital of 10 Edw. III. c. 3.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">10 Edw. III. c. 3. repealed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas by one Act made att the Parliament holden in the Tenth yeare of the Reigne of King Edward
the Third itt was amongst other things enacted That in case the King should grant any Charters of
Pardon of Manslaughter Robbery Felonies and other trespasses against the peace That within three months after the
makeing the same they that should have the said Charters should come and find (before the Sheriffs and Coroners
of the Counties where the Felonies were done) Six good and sufficient Mainpernors for whom the said Sheriffs
and Coroners would answer That they from thenceforth should beare themselves well and lawfully And that
the mainprizes should bee sealed with their seales and returned into Chancery within Three weeks after the end
of the said Three months And that if they that should have such Charters would in time to come aid themselves
thereby and should not find such mainprizes or after such mainprize found should beare themselves otherwise
against the peace then they ought their Charters should bee holden for none Which Statute hath been found very
inconvenient in relation to diverse persons who have been esteemed fitt objects of mercy And therefore the said
Statute hath been seldome putt in practice but for the most part hath been dispenced withal in the Charters of
Pardons that were granted in former Reignes. And forasmuch as by one Act made in the First yeare of their
now Majesties Reigne entituled An Act for declareing the Rights and Liberties of the Subject and settling the
succession of the Crowne it was enacted. That from and after that Session of Parliament noe dispensation by Non obstante
of or to any Statute or any part thereof should bee allowed but that the same should bee held void and of none effect
whereby diverse of their Majesties Subjects are rendred lesse capable of their Majesties mercy then before it beeing
very difficult if not impossible to find six substantial persons who will adventure to bee bound for the good behaviour
of any person needing a pardon dureing his Life. Bee it therefore enacted by the King and Queens most excellent
Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords spiritual and temporal and Commons in Parliament
assembled and by the authority of the same That the said Act made in the Tenth yeare of King Edward the
Third and every article and Clause therein shall bee and are repealed and annulled and are hereby declared to
bee repealed and annulled to all intents and purposes whatsoever.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Persons pardoned, even Feme Coverts and Infants, to give Security for good Behaviour for Seven Years.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided neverthelesse and bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any Charter of Pardon bee pleaded
by any person for any Felony the Justices before whom such Pardon shall bee pleaded may att their discretion
remand or co[m]mitt such person to prison there to remaine until hee or shee shall enter into a recognizance with
two sufficient sureties for his or her being of the good behaviour for any time not exceeding seven yeares.
Provided that if any such Charter of Pardon bee pleaded by a Fem Covert or Infant such Fem Covert or Infant
may find two sufficient sureties who shall enter into a recognizance for him or her being of the good behaviour
as is aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


