<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46411" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVII. An Act for the Exportation of Iron, Copper and Mundick Mettal. [Rot. Parl. pt. 6. nu.[<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]]</subtitle>
			<section id="s1">
			<head></head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Reciting 28 Edw. III. c 5. 33 Hen. VIII. c. 7. 2 (2 &amp; 3) Edw. VI. c. 37.; Iron, &amp;c. may be exported</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas by several Statutes the one made in the Eight and twentieth yeare of the Reigne of Edward the
Third and the other in the Three and thirtieth yeare of the Reigne of King Henry the Eighth and another
in the Second yeare of the Reigne of Edward the Sixth late Kings of England Iron Copper and Bell Mettal are
prohibited to bee exported out of this Realme under several penalties in the said Statutes respectively contained
For the better encouragement of the workeing of Copper mines within their Majesties Dominions Be it therefore
enacted by the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords
Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That
from and after the Five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety foure it shall and may bee
lawfull to and for any person or persons whatsoever Bodies Politick or Corporate to shipp and export all and
all manner of Iron Copper or Mundick Mettal out of this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne
of Berwicke upon Tweed [(except unto or for the use of the French King or any of his Subjects resideing within
his Dominions or in to or for any Port or Place within his said Dominions dureing the present Warr between
their Majesties and the French King<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] paying the Duties and Customs by Law payable for the same the said recited
Statutes or any other Statute Law or Usage to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Pot Metal, &amp;c. excepted.</head>
			<para id="p3">[Provided that this Act shall not extend to the exportation of any Pott-mettall Gun-mettal or Shruff-mettal
or any old mettal or any mixture therewith or of any Copper or other mettal then what is made of English
Ore onely.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">No number is mentioned on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


