<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46417" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for appointing and enableing Commissioners to examine take and state the Publicke Accompts of the Kingdome [Chapter XXIII Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Commissioners for taking the Public Accounts.</head>
		<para id="p1"><emph type="i">2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 11. 4 &amp; 5 (4) W. &amp; M. c. 11.; revived and continued.; Treasury to issue Money for Salaries, &amp;c.; Power to Commissioners to take Account of Monies granted by c. 1. ante, and of other the Revenue; pursuant to 3 W. &amp; M. c.6</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the better takeing stateing and examining of the Publicke Accompts of theire Majesties treasure and
the better encouragement of theire Majesties good Subjects to sustaine the greate payments upon them for
the prosecuc[i]on of the p[re]sent warr against France and the supporte of theire Majesties Governement Be it enacted
by the King and Queenes most excellent Majesties by and with the advise and consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Co[m]mons in this p[re]sent Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That Robert
Harley Esquire Sir Thomas Pope-Blunt Baronett Paul Foley Esquire Sir Thomas Clarges Knight Charles Hutchinson
Esquire Sir Edward Abney Knight and Sir James Houblon Knight shall be and are hereby constituted Co[m]missioners
for examining takeing and stateing of the accompts of all money of the Publicke Revenue of the Crowne and
all other Accompts which were by one Act of Parliament made in the Second yeare of their Majesties Raigne
entituled An Act for appointing and enableing Co[m]missioners to examine take and state the publicke accompts of the
Kingdome And one other Act made in the Fourth and Fifth yeares of theire Majesties Raigne entituled An Act
for examining takeing and stateing the Publicke Accompts of this Kingdome to be taken examined and stated by
the Co[m]missioners by the said Act constituted or any Five or more of them respectively appointed by virtue of the
said Acts or either of them And that the said Acts be and are hereby revived and continued and in force from
the Four and twentieth day of Aprill in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety four to the Five
and twentieth day of Aprill which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and five
and shall be executed with all the powers therein contained by the Co[m]missioners herein named or any Four or
more of them; And that the Lords Co[m]missioners of the Treasury or Lord High Treasurer of England for the time
being shall and are hereby authorized and required to issue and pay or cause to be issued and paid the like yearely
allowances for payment of Clerks and other charges as are in the first recited Act directed And the like quarterly
payments to every of the said Co[m]missioners hereby constituted as are appointed to be paid to the Co[m]missioners
therein named; And the said Co[m]missioners by this Act constituted as aforesaid or any Four or more of them shall
and have hereby power to take an accompt of all moneys granted to theire Majesties by one Act made in this
p[re]sent Session of Parliament entituled An Act for granting to theire Majesties an Aide of Four shillings in the
pound for one yeare for carrying on a vigorous Warr against France And of all other moneys that have beene
or shall be granted to theire Majesties in this p[re]sent Session of Parliament; And of all other theire Majesties
treasure or other publicke money due or payable to theire Majesties on the Fifth day of November One thousand
six hundred eighty eight or att any time betweene the said Fifth day of November and the said Five and
twentieth day of Aprill which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety five not yet
accompted for by virtue or in pursuance of the said recited Acts or either of them or the last Clause touching
publicke accompts made and enacted in one Act made in the Third yeare of theire Majesties Raigne entituled
An Act for raiseing Money by a Poll payable quarterly for One yeare for the carrying on a vigorous Warr
against France:-</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners to take Oath.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further enacted, That two of the said Co[m]missioners first named in this Act before they enter upon
the execuc[i]on of the same shall take an Oath before the Chancellor of the Exchequer or Master of the Rolls
for the time being which they and either of them are hereby authorized and required to administer to them the
tenor whereof shall be as followeth (that is to say:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>Form of Oath.</head>
			<para id="p4">I. A. B. doe sweare that according to the best of my skill and knowledge I shall faithfully impartially and truly
demeane my selfe in examining and takeing the accompts of all such su[m]me or su[m]mes of money and other
things brought or to be brought before me in execuc[i]on of one Act entituled An Act for appointing and enableing
Co[m]missioners to examine take and state the Publicke Accompts of the Kingdome according to the tenor and
purport of the said Act:-</para>
			<para id="p5">And every other of the said Co[m]missioners in the Act named before he enters upon the execuc[i]on of the said
Act shall likewise take the same Oath before the said two Co[m]missioners herein first named who are hereby
authorized to administer the same unto them after they shall themselves have taken the said Oath as aforesaid:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>III. Commissioners to summon Commissioners, &amp;c. of certain Transport Ships to account.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alsoe and be it enacted That it shall and may be lawfull for the Co[m]missioners appointed by this
Act and they are hereby required to summon the Co[m]missioners appointed for the Transport Shipps for the Warr
of Ireland or any other Contractors for the same as alsoe the severall Owners and Proprietors of the said Transport
Shipps and theire Executors or Assignes to state the accompts and adjust the Debte due for the said Transport
Shipps which accompt soe stated they are to prepare against the next Sessions of Parliament:-</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

