<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46419" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the better discipline of theire Majesties Navy Royall [Chapter XXV Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Offences against 13 Car. II. Stat. 1. c. 9. triable in the King's Bench.</head>
		<para id="p1">For the regulateing and better Government of theire Majesties Navyes Shipps of Warr and Forces by Sea
wherein under the providence and protecc[i]on of God the wealth safety and strength of this Kingdome is soe
much concerned Be it enacted by the King and Queenes most excellent Majesties by and with the Advise and
Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Co[m]mons in this p[re]sent Parliament assembled and by the
Authority thereof That all Offences (contrary to one Act made in the Thirteenth yeare of the Raigne of King
Charles the Second entituled An Act for the establishing Articles and Orders for the regulateing and better
Government of his Majesties [Navy<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Shipps of Warr and Forces by Sea) which shall be co[m]mitted after the Four
and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety four may be prosecuted tryed and determined in theire
Majesties Court of Kings Bench att Westminster or before Justices of Oyer and Terminer to be constituted by
theire Majesties Comission which said Court or Courts are hereby impowered to hold cognizance thereof by
Informac[i]on or Indictment and to proceede upon heare try and determine the same according to the course of the
Co[m]mon Lawe of this Realme and upon Convicc[i]on of the Party accused by confession or verdict or otherwise to
inflict such penalties as are appointed in the said Act for the respective offences therein menc[i]oned:-</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Offences out of the Realm laid in England.</head>
			<para id="p2">And be it further enacted That where any of the said offences shall be co[m]mitted out of this Realme in such
case the same may be alleadged and laid in any County within this Realme:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. No Person triable by both King's Bench and Court Martial.</head>
			<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Continuance of Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwaies That noe person who shall be tryed in a Court Martiall shall for the same offence be againe
tryed by virtue of this Act nor shall any person tryed by virtue of this Act be for the same offence tryed againe
by a Court Martiall:- Provided alsoe that this Act shall continue in Force for Three yeares and from thence to
the end of the next Session of Parliament:-</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Navy's <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

