<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46413" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for raiseing the Militia of this Kingdome for the yeare [1694] although the Moneths Pay formerly advanced be not repayed:  [Chapter XIX. Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reciting 13 &amp; 14. Car. II. c. 3. &sect; 7.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reciting that upon the Invasion by the French, it was necessary to draw out the Soldiers, &amp;c. with Pay in Hand; And that the like Occasion may happen during the present War.; If found necessary before 25th March, 1695, Lieutenants, &amp;c. may draw out Soldiers with Pay in Hand, although Pay before advanced be not reimbursed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS by an Act of Parliament made in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth yeares of the Raigne of His
late Majestie King Charles the Second entituled An Act for ordering the Forces in the severall Counties
of this Kingdome It was (amongst other things) enacted That in case of Invasions Insurrecc[i]ons or Rebellions
whereby Occasion should be to drawe out the Soldiers mentioned and appointed in and by the said Act into
actuall Service the persons charged by the said Act with Horses Horsemen and Armes or with Foote Soldiers and
Armes should provide each theire Soldier respectively with pay in hand not exceedeing One Months Pay as should
be in that behalfe directed by the respective Lieutennants of the severall Counties and in theire absence or otherwise
by theire direcc[i]on by theire Deputies or any Two or more of them for repayment of which said moneys and for
satisfacc[i]on of the Officers for theire Pay dureing such time not exceedeing One moneth as aforesaid as they should be with
theire Soldiers in such actuall Service itt was thereby declared That Provision should be made for the same by his said
Majestie his Heires and Successors out of his or theire publicke Treasury or Revenue:- Neverthelesse itt was thereby
further provided and enacted That in case a Moneths Pay should be provided and advanced as aforesaid that noe person
who should have advanced his proporc[i]on thereof should be charged with any other like moneths Payment untill he or
they should have beene reimbursed the said months Pay and soe from time to time the said months Pay by him or
them last before provided and advanced as aforesaid:- And whereas upon the Invasion of the Coasts of this
Kingdome by the French it was found necessary for the publicke Defence and Safety to drawe out the said Soldiers
into actuall Service and to charge the said persons to provide each theire Soldier respectively with Pay in Hand
although the months pay by severall of them before that time provided and advanced was not nor could be
reimbursed:- And whereas the like occasion may possibly happen dureing the p[re]sent Warr Be it therefore enacted
by the King and Queenes most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Co[m]mons in this p[re]sent Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same. That if att any
time before the Five and twentieth day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and
five it shall be found by theire Majesties to be necessary for the Defence and Safety of this Kingdome to drawe
out the said Soldiers into actuall Service and the same shall be declared or signified to the respective Lieuetennants
or Deputy Lieutennants and Lord Warden of the Cinque Ports Two antient Townes and theire Members or
in his absence his Lieutenant or Lieutennants by theire Majesties it shall be lawfull for the said Lievtennants or
theire Deputies or any Two or more of them as aforesaid and the Lord Warden of the Cinque Ports Two
antient Townes and theire Members or in his absence his Leiutenant or Lieutenants in pursuance of such Orders
from theire Majesties notwithstanding that one or more months Pay before that time advanced be not reimbursed
to raise and drawe out the said Soldiers into actuall Service and to cause the persons charged as aforesaid to
provide each theire Soldier with Pay in Hand not exceedeing One months Pay in such manner as if all the Pay
before that time advanced and provided had beene fully reimbursed and paid:-</para>
	</section>
</report>

