<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46412" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for enableing theire Majesties to make Grants Leases and Copies of Offices Lands and Hereditaments Parcell of theire Dutchy of Cornwall or annexed to the same and for Confirmacion of Leases and Grants already made:. [Chapter XVIII. Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Grants made by King Charles Second, &amp;c. of any Parcel of the Dutchy of Cornwall, good.; Grants to be for 31 Years, or determinable upon Three Lives.; Not dispunishable of Waste.; Usual Rent.; If no usual Rent, then reasonable Rent to be reserved</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas many of the Lands belonging to the Dutchy of Cornwall have beene granted by Lease to the
Tenants some for the terme of one two or three lives and some for divers yeares determinable upon one
two or three lives and others for thirty one yeares or under which Leases are desired to be renewed by many
of the said Tenants:. And whereas severall yeares next following after the happy restaurac[i]on of his late Majestie
King Charles the Second diverse increased Rents were reserved as well upon the said Leasehold Lands as upon
many Coppy-hold Estates of the said Dutchy for the improvement of that Revenue whereof the Tenants made
complaint to his said late Majestie who was graciously pleased that they might compound for the dischargeing of
the said increased rents and be restored to the old rents formerly paid for theire respective Tennants and Lands:.
Now to the end the same may be accordingly effected and the Tenants may be encouraged to renew theire
Leases and Estates and thereby the better enabled to repaire theire Houses and provide for theire Families and
to improve theire Lands holden of the said Dutchy Be it enacted by the King and Queenes most excellent Majesties
by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Co[m]mons in this p[re]sent Parliament
assembled and by the authority of the same That all Leases and Grants made by his said late Majestie King Charles
the Second or by the late King James or by theire p[re]sent Majesties since theire happy accession to the Crowne or
to be made within Seaven yeares next ensueing by Letters Pattents or Indentures under the Greate Seale of
England or Seale of the Court of Exchequer or by Copy of Court Roll according to the customes of the respective
Mannors of the said Dutchy or thereunto annexed of any Offices Messuages Parks Lands Tenements or Hereditaments
parcell of the said Dutchy of Cornwall or annexed to the same (other then of Honours Lordshipps or Mannors)
shall be good and effectuall in Lawe according to the purport and contents of the same Copies Leases and Grants
against our said Soveraigne Lord and Lady the King and Queene theire Heires and Successors and against all
and every other person and persons that shall att any time hereafter have inheritt or enjoye the said Dutchy by
force of any Act of Parliament or by other limitac[i]on whatsoever:. Provided alwaies that every such Lease or Grant soe
made or to be made be not for more then one two or three lives or for thirty one yeares or under or for
some terme of yeares determinable upon one two or three lives and not above: And if such Leases or Grants
be made in reversion or expectancy that then the same together with the estate in possession doe not exceede
three Lives or the terme of [one and thirty<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] yeares and not in any wise dispunishable of Wast and soe as upon
every such Lease the ancient or most usuall rent or more or such rent as hath beene reserved yeilded or paid
for the same Lands for the greater parte of Twenty yeares next before the yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred and sixty hath beene and shall be reserved due and payable to him or her that shall have
the Inheritance or other Estate of the said Dutchy and where noe [such<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Rent hath beene reserved or payable
That then upon every such lease there shall be reserved a reasonable Rent not being under the Twentieth parte
of the cleere yearely value of the Messuages Parks Lands Tenements or Hereditaments conteined in such Lease
and all Leases and Grants otherwise made or to be made shall be null and void:-</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Covenants, &amp;c. to bind Reversioners.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further ordained and enacted by the authority aforesaid That all Covenants Condic[i]ons Reservac[i]ons
and other Agreements conteined in every Lease Grant or Copye of Court-Roll made or to be made as aforesaid
shall be good and effectuall in Lawe according to the words and contents of the same as well for and against
them to whome the reversion of the same Lands Tenements or Hereditaments shall come as for and against them
to whome the interest of the said Leases Grants or Copies shall come respectively as if our Soveraigne Lord
and Lady the King and Queenss Majesties att the time of makeing such Covenants Condic[i]ons and Reservac[i]ons
and other Agreements were seized of an absolute Estate in Fee Simple in the same Lands Tenements or
Hereditam<emph type="p">te</emph>.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Saving to all their Rights, except King, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p4">Saveing alwaies to all and every person and persons Bodies Politicke and Corporate theire Heires and Successors
Executors Administrators and Assignes (other then to our said Soveraigne Lord and Lady the King and Queene
and theire Heires and the Duke and Dukes of Cornwall for the time being and his and theire Heires and all and
every person and persons that shall hereafter have inheritt or enjoy the said Dukedome of Cornwall by force of
any Act of Parliament or other limitac[i]on whatsoever) all such Rights Titles Estates Customes Interests Tenures
Claimes and Demands whatsoever of what nature kinde or qualitye soever of in to or out of the said Offices
Lands Tenements or Hereditaments or any of them as they or any of them had or ought to have had
before the makeing of this Act to all intents and purposes and in as large and ample manner and forme as if
this Act had never beene had or made, this Act or any thing herein conteined to the contrary notwithstanding:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Tenants compounding for the increased Rent and paying according to Composition, old Rent only to stand.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that in case any of the Lease-hold or Copye-hold Tennants
of the said Dutchy shall att any time within Seaven yeares next ensueing compound or agree with the Lord High
Treasurer of England or Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time being or Chancellor and Undertreasurer of
the Exchequer for the time being or with any other person or persons that the Lord High Treasurer or [the<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time [being<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] or Chancellor of the Exchequer shall authorize nominate and
appointe for the takeing off and dischargeing of any increased Rent reserved as aforesaid according to such rules
and direcc[i]ons as in that behalfe shall be given in Writeing under the Hands of the said Lord Treasurer
Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time being or Chancellor of the Exchequer for the time being; Then upon
such Composic[i]on soe made and the money thereby ariseing duely p&acirc;id to the Receiver Generall of the said
Dutchy according to the tenor and contents of such Composic[i]on and Agreement and accordingly inrolled before
the Auditor of the p[re]misses from thenceforth such increase Rent shall cease and become void and the old Rent
only or such other Rent as in pursuance of this Act shall be directed in or by such Composic[i]on or Agreement shall
be charged on all and every such Tenements Lands and other Hereditaments for which such Composic[i]on
Agreement Payment and Inrollment shall be soe made and none other any reservac[i]on condic[i]on or other matter
whatsoever to the contrary notwithstanding:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Fees for Grants of small Value.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Officers offending; Penalty to the Party; Further Penalty, &pound;20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And whereas within the County of Cornwall there are severall Tenements belonging to the said Dutchy of
small value soe that the charge of passeing Letters Patents under the Greate Seale or Leases under the Seale of
the Exchequer and Grants by Copie of Court Roll may discourage the Tenants from renewing soe often as
otherwise they would doe Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that the wholl Fees reward and charges
to be paid received or taken for the prepareing writeing draweing obtaineing makeing passeing or perfecting of
any such Lease or Grant and for the petic[i]on answere reference reporte particular Certificate Contract Warrant
Inrollment and Entry thereof and for every other matter and thing relateing thereunto or touching or concerneing
the obtaineing passeing and perfecting any Lease or Grant of such small Tenements in the said County of
Cornwall (where the Fine or Value of such Lease or Grant to be made or renewed shall not exceede the su[m]me
of Eighty pounds) shall not exceede the su[m]me of Tenne pounds for every Lease and Fower pounds for every
Copie (over and besides the said Fine or Value) the said respective su[m]mes not exceedeing Tenne pounds and
Four pounds to be paid distributed and divided unto and amongst the severall and respective Officers and Clerks
of the Exchequer and Stewards of the Honours and Mannors of the said Dutchy concerned and employed in the
prepareing passeing and perfecting of such Lease or Grant respectively in such proporc[i]on as the Fees of Leases
or Grants within the said Dutchy formerly and hitherto were and are received And if any of the said Officers
Clerks and Stewards shall demand take and receive any greater or other fee or reward or shall doe or attempte
or cause to be done or attempted any thing contrary hereunto such Officer Clerke and Steward shall forfeite and
lose for every such Offence to the Party greived in that behalfe soe much money as any such Officer Clerke or
Steward shall demand receive and take contrary to this Act; and alsoe shall lose and forfeite the su[m]me of Twenty
pounds whereof the one moietie shall be to theire Majesties and the other moietie to the party greived in that
behalfe to be recovered by Acc[i]on of Debte or Informac[i]on in any of the Courts att Westminster in which noe
Priviledge Essoigne Imparlance or Protecc[i]on shall be admitted or allowed:-</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Thirty-one <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

