<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46414" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for granting to theire Majesties severall Rates and Duties upon Tunnage of Shipps and Vessells and upon Beere Ale and other Liquors for secureing certaine Recompenses and Advantages in the said Act mentioned to such Persons as shall voluntarily advance the summe of [£1,500,000] towards the carrying on the Warr against France:- [Chapter XX. Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Tonnage upon Ships given for Four Years.</head>
		<para id="p1">Wee your Majesties most dutifull and loyall Subjects the Co[m]mons assembled in Parliament for the further
Supply of your Majesties extraordinary Occasions for and towards the necessary Defence of your Realmes
doe humbly p[re]sent your Majesties with the further Gift of the Impositions Rates and Duties herein after
mentioned And doe beseech your Majesties that it may be enacted and be it enacted by the King and Queenes
most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Co[m]mons
in this p[re]sent Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same that for and dureing the terme of Four yeares
comenceing from the First day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and four
there shall be throughout the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede raised
levied collected and paid unto and for the use of theire Majesties theire Heires and Successors for and upon the
Tunnage of all Shipps and Vessells wherein att any time or times and for every time dureing the said terme of
Four yeares there shall be imported any Goods or Merchandizes into this Kingdome of England Dominion of
Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede from any the Parts Places or Countryes hereafter menc[i]oned or wherein
dureing the said terme there shall be carryed coastwise from any Port Member or Creeke in the Kingdome of
England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede unto any [other<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Port Creeke or Member
within the same Kingdome Dominion Port or Towne the severall and respective Rates Imposic[i]ons Dutyes and
su[m]mes of money herein after mentioned (that is to say).</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Several Rates. East Indies, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">For every Tun of the Burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes
from the East Indies or any parts southward or eastward of Cabo bona Speranza the su[m]me of Thirty shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Italy, Turkey</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p5">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes
from any Ports or Places in Italy or Turkey the su[m]me of Fifteene shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">Portugal, Spain</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p7">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes
from any Ports or Places in Portugall or Spaine the su[m]me of Ten shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">West Indies</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p9">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes
from any the Plantations Lands or Places in the West Indies the su[m]me of Ten shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">Holland, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p11">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes
from Holland or any the United Provinces or from the Netherlands or Flanders the su[m]me of Three shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p12">
			<emph type="i">Norway, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p13">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes
from Norway Hamborough or the Balticke Sea or from any the Eastland Countries or from any other Ports or
Places North of Holland the su[m]me of Five shillings.</para>
		<para id="p14">
			<emph type="i">Ireland, Scotland</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p15">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes from
Ireland or Scotland the su[m]me of Two shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p16">
			<emph type="i">Mediterranean</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p17">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes
from any Port or Place in the Mediterranean Sea (not otherwise charged in this Act) the su[m]me of Fifteene
shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p18">
			<emph type="i">Guinea, Africa</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p19">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes
from the parts or coasts of Guinea or Africa without the Streights the su[m]me of Twenty shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p20">
			<emph type="i">Hudsons Bay</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p21">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes
from Hudsons Bay or any place within the limitts of that Companies Charter the su[m]me of Twenty [shilling:-<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
		<para id="p22">
			<emph type="i">Canaries</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p23">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes
from the Canaries Madera's or any the Westerne Islands the su[m]me of Ten shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p24">
			<emph type="i">Greenland, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p25">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell importing Goods Wares or Merchandizes
from any Ports or Places in Greenland Muscovia or Russia the su[m]me of Ten shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p26">
			<emph type="i">Coasters</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p27">For every Tun of the burthen or contents of any Shipp or Vessell used or imployed in the Coasting Trade
from Port to Port in England Wales or Berwicke upon Tweede the su[m]me of Six pence:-</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Tunnage paid upon Arrival at a Port.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Master, &amp;c. of Ship importing or of Coaster, upon Arrival to pay the Tax or give Security.; Allowance on present Pay.; Landing, &amp;c. before Duty paid, &amp;c.; Ship forfeited, and Master, &amp;c. liable to pay the Duties</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said severall rates dutyes and su[m]mes of money
herein before mentioned and hereby imposed upon the Tunnage of Shipps or Vessells shall be accounted taken
and paid according to the measure of such Shipps or Vessells which shall be made and taken by theire Majesties
Officers in the respective Ports or Places where they shall arrive and that the Master or Owners or Freighters
of all such Shipps or Vessells importing Goods inwards or carrying Goods Coastwise as aforesaid shall upon
every arrivall of any such Shipps or Vessells att the Port or Place of theire discharge or unladeing in England
or Wales or att the (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Port of Berwicke upon Tweede cause and procure such Shipps or Vessells to be entered in
the Customehouse of or belonging to such Port or Place and att the time of such entry and before any Goods
or Merchandizes shall be unladen out of any such Shipps or Vessells shall either pay downe in ready money to
theire Majesties Officers of the Customes in such Port or Place for the use of theire Majesties the said duties
and su[m]mes of money due and payable for the Tunnage of all such Shipps or Vessells or else shall give good and
sufficient securitye by Bond to theire Majesties with sureties to be approved by the said Officers of the Customes
to pay the said duties and su[m]mes to theire Majesties use within the space of one month next after the cleareing
of the Shipp; And where the duties shall be paid downe the Parties paying the same shall have an
allowance by way of rebate or deducc[i]on out of the same after the rate of Ten pounds per Centum per Annu[m]
for every hundred pounds which such duties soe paid downe shall amount unto And in case any Goods Wares
or Merchandizes imported or carryed coast-wise as aforesaid shall be unshipped to be laid on land before the
duties or su[m]mes of money before mentioned due or payable for the Tunnage of such Shipps or Vessells importing or
carrying Goods coastwise as aforesaid shall be paid downe or secured as aforesaid That then every such Shipp
or Vessell out of which any such Goods or Merchandizes shall be unladen before payment made or security given
for the said duties together with the Gunns Tackle Ammunic[i]on and Apparell of the same shall be forfeited and
lost one moiety of which forfeitures shall be to theire Majesties theire Heires and Successors and the other moiety
to such person or persons as shall seize sue or informe for the same to be recovered in any of theire Majesties
Courts of Record att Westminster by acc[i]on of debt bill plaint or informac[i]on wherein noe essoigne protecc[i]on or
wager of Lawe shall be allowed. And over and besides the said forfeitures the Master Owners and Freighters of
every such Shipp shall be lyable and chargeable to theire Majesties theire Heires and Successors for the said Duties
of Tunnage which shall not be paid or secured as aforesaid:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Tax upon Importer to be borne, Two Thirds by the Merchant and One Third by the Owner.</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Owners of Coasters to pay the whole</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">And be it further enacted by the authoritye aforesaid That the aforesaid respective Dutyes upon the Tunnage of
Shipps or Vessells importing Goods or Merchandizes from parts beyond the Seas or from Scotland shall be paid
and born by the Merchant-Freighters and by the Master and Owners of such Shipps or Vessells by way of
average amongst themselves (that is to say) two third parts thereof shall be born by the Merchants and Freighters
of such Shipps or Vessells in proporc[i]on according to theire respective Shares or Interests of or in the Freight
and the other third parte to be born by the Masters or Owners of such Shipps or Vessells who are hereby
required and enjoyned to beare and pay the same accordingly And the said Duty of Tunnage of Shipps or
Vessells used in or imployed in the Coasting Trade from Port to Port as aforesaid shall be paid and born by the
Master or Owners of such Shipps or Vessells:.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Ships from Greenland only chargeable for Goods really imported.</head>
			<para id="p32">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That all Shipps belonging to the Company of
Merchants of London tradeing to Greenland importing Oyle Blubber Whale Fins or any other Merchandize from
thence shall pay ten shillings per Tun only for such Oyle Blubber Whale Fins and other Merchandize as shall be
really and bona fide brought home in any of the said [Companies<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Shipps and not be obliged to pay according to
the measure of the shipping Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. The like as to Ships from Newfoundland.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That all Shipps tradeing to Newfoundland
importing Traine Oyle or any other Merchandize from thence shall pay Ten shillings per Tun only for such
Traine Oyle or other Merchandize as shall be really and bona fide brought home and not be obliged to pay
according to the measure of the shipping. Any thing herein conteined to the contrary notwithstanding:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. In case of Peace, Ships from France, how charged.</head>
			<para id="p34">Provided alwaies and be it further enacted That if a Peace shall be made and declared betweene their Majesties
and the French King att any time dureing the continuance of the Duty charged by this Act upon the Tunnage
of Shipps and Vessells then and in such case all Shipps and Vessells importing any Goods or Merchandize from
any of the French Kings Territories in Europe without the Streights shall pay the like Duty of Tunnage as any
Shipps or Vessells importing Goods from Portugall are charged with by this Act over and above all other Dutyes
payable for such Shipps and Vessells:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Lime, Sand, &amp;c. from Port to Port.</head>
			<para id="p35">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That this Act nor any thing therein conteined
shall not extend to charge or lay any Duty upon any Barge employed in carrying Sand Lime or Slate stone
from Port to Port within the Kingdome of England and Dominion of Wales for or in respect of any such ladeing
only; Any thing herein before contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Ships how measured.</head>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">What the true Contents of Tonnage</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">And be it further enacted and declared That all Shipps and Vessells importing Goods and Merchandize from
Foreign parts as well as all Coasting Vessells liable to the payment of the Dutyes of Tunnage by this Act imposed
shall be gauged and measured according to the rule printed with the Booke of Rates published in the yeare
One thousand six hundred seaventy one (that is to say) every single deck'd Shipp or Vessell shall be measured
by the length of the Keele taken within board (soe much as she treads upon the Ground) and the breadth to be
taken within board by the Midshipp Beame from Planke to Planke and the depth of the Hold from the Planke
belowe the Kelsey to the under parte of the Decke Planke; And for a Two-Deckt Shipp (which carryes Goods
betweene Decks) the depth of her Hold to be taken from the Plank belowe the Kelsey to the under parte of
the Upper Deck Plank and the length and breadth as before then multiply the length by the breadth and the
Product thereof by the depth and divide the wholl by Ninety four and the Quotient will give the true contents
of the Tunnage according to which method and rule all Shipps and Vessells shall be measured and the severall
Duties of Tonnage thereby be computed and collected accordingly any Custome Practice or Usage to the contrary
notwithstanding:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Reciting 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 10.</head>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">3 &amp; 4 W. &amp; M.; Excise Duty upon Beer, Ale, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">And whereas by an Act of Parliament made in the Second yeare of theire Majesties Raigne entituled An Act
for granting to theire Majesties severall additionall duties upon Beere Ale and other Liquors for Four yeares from
the time that an Act for doubling the duty of Excise upon Beere Ale and other Liquors dureing the space of
One yeare doth expire it was enacted That from and after the Seaventeenth day of November in the yeare of
our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and one there should be throughout theire Majesties Kingdome of
England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede raised levied collected and paid unto theire
Majesties theire Heires and Successors dureing the space and terme of Four yeares and noe longer for Beere Ale
Cyder and other Liquors therein mentioned by way of Excise over and above all other Dutyes Charges and
Imposic[i]ons by any former Act or Acts which should be then unexpired set and imposed in such manner as
therein is mentioned which Rates and Duties aforesaid by Act of Parliament made in the Third and Fourth yeares
of theire now Majesties Raigne are continued untill the seaventeenth day of May One thousand six hundred and
ninety seaven:- Be it further enacted That for the further encouragement of such persons who shall voluntarily
contribute towards the raiseing and paying into theire Majesties Exchequer any su[m]e or su[m]mes not exceedeing in
the whole the sume of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds upon the severall termes and recompenses herein after
menc[i]oned that from and after the seaventeenth day of May which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred ninety and seaven there shall be throughout theire Majesties Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales
and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede raised levyed collected and paid unto theire Majesties theire Heires and
Successors for Beere Ale Cyder and other Liquors herein after expressed by way of Excise over and above all
Dutyes Charges and Imposic[i]ons by any former Act or Acts then unexpired sett and imposed one moiety or
halfe parte of the severall Rates and Duties of Excise granted by the said last mentioned Act in manner and
forme followeing (that is to say):-</para>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">Beer, &amp;c. above 6s., 9d</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">For every Barrell of Beere or Ale above Six shillings the Barrell exclusive of the Duty of Excise brewed by
the Co[m]mon Brewer or any other person or persons who doth or shall sell or tapp out Beere or Ale publickly
or privately to be paid by the Co[m]mon Brewer or by such other person or persons respectively and soe proportionably
for a greater or lesser quantity over and above the Dutyes payable for the same Nine pence:-</para>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">Beer, &amp;c. 6s. or under, 3d</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">For every Barrell of Beere or Ale of Six shillings the Barrell or under brewed by the Co[m]mon Brewer or any
other person or persons who shall sell or tapp out Beere or Ale publickly or privately to be paid by the Co[m]mon
Brewer or such other person or persons respectively as aforesaid and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser
quantity over and above the Dutyes payable for the same Three pence:-</para>
			<para id="p44">
				<emph type="i">Vinegar 1s. 6d. English</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p45">For every Barrell of Vinegar or Vinegar Beere brewed or made of any English Materialls by any Co[m]mon Brewer
or any other person for sale to be paid by the Maker thereof and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity
over and above the Dutyes of Excise payable for the same One shilling six pence:-</para>
			<para id="p46">
				<emph type="i">Vinegar, Foreign, 4s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p47">For every Barrell of Vinegar or Liquor prepared for Vinegar made here for sale that hath run through Rape
or made with or passeing through any Foreign materialls or any mixture with Foreign materialls to be paid by
the maker thereof and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity Four shillings:-</para>
			<para id="p48">
				<emph type="i">Beer, Mum, &amp;c. imported, 3s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p49">For every Barrell of Beere Ale or Mum imported from beyond the Seas or from the Islands of Guernsey or
Jersey and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity to be paid by the Importers before landing over and
above the Dutyes payable for the same Three shillings:-</para>
			<para id="p50">
				<emph type="i">Cyder, &amp;c. imported, per Ton, &pound;4</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p51">For every Tun of Cyder or Perry imported from beyond the Seas and soe proportionably for a greater or
lesser quantity to be paid by the Importers before landing over and above the Dutyes payable for the same Four
Pounds:-</para>
			<para id="p52">
				<emph type="i">Brandy Single, per Gallon, 6d</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p53">For every Gallon of Single Brandy Spiritts or Aqua-Vite imported from beyond the Seas to be paid by the
[Importers<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] before landing over and above the Dutyes payable for the same Six pence:-</para>
			<para id="p54">
				<emph type="i">Brandy Double, 1s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p55">For every Gallon of Brandy Spiritts or Aqua-Vite above proofe co[m]monly called Double Brandy imported from
beyond the Seas to be paid by the Importer before landing over and above the Dutyes payable for the same One
shilling:-</para>
			<para id="p56">
				<emph type="i">Cyder retailed, per Hogshead, 1s. 3d</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p57">For all Cyder and Perry made and sold by retaile upon every Hogshead to be paid by the Retailer thereof
over and above the Dutyes payable for the same (and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser measure One
shilling Three pence:-</para>
			<para id="p58">
				<emph type="i">Mead, &amp;c. per Gallon, 3d</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p59">For all Metheglin or Meade made for sale whether by retaile or otherwise to be paid by the Maker for every
Gallon Three pence:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. How to be levied,</head>
			<para id="p60">
				<emph type="i">as by 12 Car. II. c. 24.; c. 23.; 15 Car. II. c. II</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p61">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said severall Rates Dutyes and Impositions upon Beere
Ale Cyder and other Liquors aforesaid be levyed collected and paid unto theire Majesties theire Heires and
Successors in the same manner and forme and by such rules wayes and meanes and under such Penalties and
Forfeitures as are mentioned in the Act made in the Twelveth yeare of the Raigne of King Charles the Second
entituled An Act for takeing away the Court of Wards and Liveryes and Tenures in Capite and by Knights
service and purveyance and for settleing a Revenue upon his Majestie in lieu thereof and alsoe in and by another
Act made in the Twelfth yeare of the Raigne of the said [late<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] King Charles the Second entituled A Grant
of certaine Impositions upon Beere Ale and other Liquors for the increase of his Majesties Revenue dureing his
Life and alsoe in and by another Act made in the Fifteenth yeare of the Raigne of the said late King Charles
the Second entituled An additc[i]onall Act for the better ordering and collecting of the Duty of Excise and P[re]venting
the Abuses therein. Or by any other Lawe in force relateing to the said Revenue of Excise and that the aforesaid
Acts and every Article Rule and Clause therein menc[i]oned as for and concerneing only the Rates Duties and
Imposic[i]ons upon Beere Ale and other Liquors by this Act granted shall be of full Force and Effecte to all Intents
and Purposes in like manner as if the same were att large and particularly recited and sett downe in the body
of this Act:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Commissioners of Excise and Customs to keep these Duties apart,</head>
			<para id="p62">
				<emph type="i">and to pay the Money into the Exchequer weekly</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p63">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Comissioners and Governors for management
and receipt of the Excise and the Comissioners and other Officers of the Customes respectively att the Head Office
in London for the time being shall seperate and keepe aparte all and every the moneys ariseing by the severall
Rates and Duties by this (<ref idref="n7">7</ref>) granted as the same shall from time to time arise or be paid into the said Office
of Excise or unto the Receiver Generall of the Customes for the time being respectively by the Receivers or
Collectors of the same or by any other person whatsoever and the Comptroller of the Excise and the Comptroller
of the Customes for the time being or theire respective Deputies shall keepe a perfect and distinct account in
Books fairely written of all the Rates and Duties ariseing by this Act to which all persons shall have free accesse
att all seasonable times without Fee or Charge and the said Comissioners and Governors of Excise and the said
Comissioners of the Customes for the time being are hereby required and stricktly enjoyned from time to time to
pay weekely (videlicet) on Wednesday in every weeke if it be not a Holyday and if it be then the next day
after that is not a Holyday all and every the moneys ariseing by the Rates and Duties hereby granted into the
Receipte of theire Majesties Exchequer distinct and aparte from the other moneys which the said Comissioners and
Governors respectively shall receive for the use of theire Majesties theire Heires and Successors:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. A weekly Account kept in the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p64">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That there shall be provided and kepte in theire Majesties
Exchequer (that is to say) in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt one Booke in which all the said weekely
moneys which shall be paid into the Exchequer as aforesaid shall be entered aparte and distinct from all other
moneyes paid and payable to theire Majesties theire Heires and Successors upon any account whatsoever:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Commissioner neglecting or misapplying Monies.</head>
			<para id="p65">
				<emph type="i">Loss of Office.; Incapacity.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p66">And be it further enacted That if the said Comissioners and Governors respectively for the time being shall
refuse or neglect to pay into the Exchequer all or any the said weekely su[m]mes appointed to be paid as aforesaid
in such manner as they are before by this Act required to doe or shall divert or misapply any parte of the
same or if such Comptroller shall neglect his duty in keepeing such Accompts as aforesaid then he or they for
any such Offence shall forfeite theire respective Offices or Places and be incapable of any Office or Place of Trust
whatsoever and such Comissioner or Comissioners in such case offending shall be liable to pay the full value of
any su[m]me or su[m]mes soe diverted or misapplyed to any person or persons who will sue for the same by any Acc[i]on
of Debte Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on in any of theire Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster wherein noe
Essoign Protecc[i]on Wager of Lawe Priviledge of Parliament or other Priviledge or more then one Imparlance shall
be granted or allowed:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Their Majesties may order Salaries, &amp;c. out of the Duties.</head>
			<para id="p67">Provided alwaies and be it enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for theire Majesties theire Heires
and Successors out of the said Dutyes ariseing by the Tunnage of Shipps and Vessells to cause such su[m]me and
su[m]mes of money to be expended and paid from time to time for Sallaries or other incident Charges as shall be
necessary in and for the receiveing collecting levying or manageing of the same Duties upon the Tunnage of
Shipps and Vessells dureing the said terme herein by this Act granted Any thing in this Act conteined to the
contrary notwithstanding:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Excise Office and Comptroller continued in London.</head>
			<para id="p68">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Head Office of Excise which is now established
within the City of London shall be continued and be within the said City or Ten Miles thereof for ever and a
sufficient number of Co[m]missioners therein from time to time shall be continued or appointed by theire Majesties
their Heires and Successors to governe and manage the Receipte of Excise and to performe and execute the
severall matters and things hereby enjoyned to be done and executed by such Co[m]missioners and that in like
manner there shall be continued and be within the said City or Ten Miles thereof for ever by the appointement
of theire Majesties theire Heires and Successors a Comptroller of Excise to keepe the Accompts before
mentioned:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. &pound;140,000 to be a yearly Fund.</head>
			<para id="p69">
				<emph type="i">The rest of the Revenue charged if Duties fall short.; Treasury to cause Deficiency to be made good</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p70">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That yearely and every yeare reckoning the first yeare to
begin from the first day of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and
four the full su[m]me of One hundred and forty thousand pounds by or out of the moneyes to arise by the said
severall Dutyes upon the Tunnage of Shipps and Vessells and by the said Rates and Dutyes of Excise hereby
granted or any of them and to be brought into the Receipte of the Exchequer by weekely payments as aforesaid
(in case the said weekely payments shall extend thereunto) shall be the whole and entire yearely Fund and in
case the said weekely payments shall not amount to One hundred and forty thousand pounds per Annu[m] then the
said weekely moneyes or payments soe farr as the same will extend shall be parte of the yearely Fond for and
towards the answering and paying of the severall and respective Annuities herein after menc[i]oned and for other the
purposes hereafter in this Act expressed and in case the said Dutyes upon the Tunnage of Shipps and Vessells
and the said Rates and Dutyes of Excise by this Act granted or any of them shall att any time or times appeare
to be soe [lowe or deficient<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] in the produce of the same as that within one yeare to be reckoned as aforesaid the
weekely payments upon the same Rates or Dutyes or any of them shall not amount to soe much as One hundred
and forty thousand pounds or to soe much as shall be sufficient to discharge and satisfie the said severall and
respective Annuityes and other Benefitts or Advantages by this Act appointed or intended to be paid within or
for the same yeare respectively that then and soe often and in every such case the Comissioners of theire Majesties
Treasury and the Under Treasurer of the Exchequer [now being &amp; the Treasurer and Under Treasurer of the
Exchequer<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] or Comissioners of [the<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Treasury for the time being are hereby straitly enjoyned and required by
virtue of this Act and without any further or other Warrant to be sued for had or obteined from theire Majesties
theire Heires or Successors in this behalfe to cause every such deficiency to be made good by applying issueing
or paying soe much of any Treasure or Revenue belonging or to belong to theire Majesties theire Heires or
Successors (not being appropriated to any particular use or uses by any Act or Acts of Parliament) towards the
dischargeing or paying off the said Annuities or other Benefitts or Advantages appointed to be paid by this Act
as together with the moneyes which shall have beene brought into the said Receipte of or for the said severall
Rates or Duties hereby granted shall be sufficient to pay off and discharge (<ref idref="n10">10</ref>) all the moneyes which within the same
yeare respectively shall be growen due or ought to be paid upon the said Annuities or other Benefitts or Advantages
according to the true intent and meaneing of this present Act:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. The &pound;140,000 to be kept apart in the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p71">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That for the better raiseing and paying into the Receipte
of the Exchequer the su[m]me of Twelve hundred thousand pounds parte of the su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand
pounds the yearely sume of One hundred and forty thousand pounds ariseing by and out of the Duties and
Imposic[i]ons granted by this Act shall be kepte separate and aparte in the said Receipte of Exchequer to be paid
over from time to time unto such person and persons and in such manner proporc[i]on and forme as is herein after
directed:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Their Majesties may make Commissioners to take Subscriptions for &pound;1,200,000.</head>
			<para id="p72">
				<emph type="i">Yearly Sum of &pound;100,000 annually appropriated to the Subscribers.; Auditor of the Exchequer to set apart Five Seventh Parts of the Weekly Payments for the Subscribers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p73">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for theire Majesties
by co[m]mission under the Greate Seale of England to authorize and appointe any number of persons to take and
receive all such voluntary subscripc[i]ons as shall be made on or before the first day of August which shall be in
the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety four by any person or persons Natives or Foreigners
Bodies Politicke or Corporate for and towards the raiseing and paying into the Receipte of Exchequer the said
su[m]me of Twelve hundred thousand pounds parte of the su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds and that the
yearely su[m]me of One hundred thousand pounds parte of the said yearely su[m]me of One hundred and forty thousand
pounds ariseing by and out of the said Duties and Imposic[i]ons before menc[i]oned shall be applyed issued and
directed and is hereby appropriated to the use and advantage of such person and persons Bodies Politicke and
Corporate as shall make such voluntary subscripc[i]ons and payments theire Heires Successors [and<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Assignes in the
proporc[i]on hereafter menc[i]oned (that is to say) that each weekely or other payment ariseing by and out of the
Duties and Imposic[i]ons granted by this Act shall by the Auditor of the Receipte of Exchequer from time to time
as the same shall be paid in be seperated and divided into Five seaventh parts and Two seventh parts which is
according to the proporc[i]on of the said yearely su[m]me of One hundred thousand pounds to the said yearely su[m]me
of One hundred and forty thousand pounds which Five seventh parts of the said severall payments ariseing by
and out of the Duties and Imposic[i]ons granted by this Act and soe sett apart is and are hereby intended
and appropriated for and towards the payment and satisfacc[i]on of the said yearely su[m]me of One hundred
thousand pounds and shall from time to time be issued and paid as the same shall come into the said
Receipte of Exchequer to the uses and advantages of such Subscribers and Contributors theire Heires Successors
or Assignes as shall subscribe and contribute for and towards the raiseing and paying into the (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Receipte of
Exchequer the su[m]me of Twelve hundred thousand pounds parte of the said su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand
pounds:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Their Majesties may appoint Rules for transferring;</head>
			<para id="p74">
				<emph type="i">and may make the Subscribers a Corporation,; subject to Redemption</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p75">And be it further enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for theire Majesties by Letters Patents under
the Greate Seale of England to limitt directe and appointe how and in what manner and proporc[i]ons and under
what rules and direcc[i]ons the said su[m]me of Twelve hundred thousand pounds parte of the said su[m]me of Fifteene
hundred thousand pounds and the said yearely su[m]me of One hundred thousand pounds parte of the said yearely
su[m]me of One hundred and forty thousand pounds and every or any parte or proporc[i]on thereof may be assigneable
or transferrable assigned or transferred to such person or persons only as shall freely and voluntarily accepte of
the same and not otherwise and to incorporate all and every such Subscribers and Contributors theire Heires
Successors or Assignes to be one Body Corporate and Politick by the name of The Governor and Company of
the Banke of England and by the same name of The Governor and Company of the Banke of England to have
perpetuall succession and a Co[m]mon Seale and that they and theire Successors by the name aforesaid shall be able
and capable in Lawe to have purchase receive possesse enjoye and retaine to them and theire Successors Lands
Rents Tenements and Hereditaments of what kinde nature or quality soever And alsoe to sell grant demise alien
or dispose of the same And by the same name to sue and implead and be sued and impleaded answere and
be answered in Courts of Record or any other place whatsoever and to doe and execute all and singuler other
matters and things by the name aforesaid that to them shall or may appertaine to doe subjecte neverthelesse to
the proviso and condic[i]on of Redempc[i]on herein after menconed:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Proportionable Part of the Fund upon Part of the Sum advanced.</head>
			<para id="p76">
				<emph type="i">The &pound;100,000 annual redeemable after 1705, upon a Year's Notice, and Corporation to cease</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p77">Provided alwaies and it is hereby further enacted That in case the whole su[m]me of Twelve hundred thousand
pounds parte of the said su[m]me of Fifteen hundred thousand pounds shall not be advanced and paid into the
Receipte of Exchequer before the First day of January which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred ninety four That then the Subscribers and Contributors for and towards the raiseing and paying of
the said su[m]me of Twelve hundred thousand pounds parte of the said su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds
theire Heires Successors and Assignes shall only have and receive soe much and such parte and proporc[i]on to the
said su[m]me and su[m]mes soe respectively paid and advanced as shall be after the rate of Eight pounds per Centum
per Annu[m] And that att any time upon Twelve months notice after the First day of August which shall be in
the yeare of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and five upon repayment by Parliament of the said su[m]me of
Twelve hundred thousand pounds parte of the said su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds or such parte thereof
as shall be paid and advanced as aforesaid unto the respective Subscribers and Contributors of the said su[m]me of
Twelve hundred thousand pounds parte of the said su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds or such parte
thereof as shall be paid and advanced theire Heires Successors [and<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Assignes and of all the arreares of the said
yearely payments of One hundred thousand pounds parte of the said yearely payments of One hundred and forty
thousand pounds or such proporc[i]onable parte thereof according to the su[m]me which shall be paid and advanced
as aforesaid then and from thenceforward the said yearely payments and every of them of One hundred thousand
pounds parte of the said yearely payments of One hundred and forty thousand pounds or such proporc[i]onable
parte as aforesaid and every parte thereof and the said Corporac[i]on shall absolutely cease and determine, any thing
herein conteined in any wise to the contrary notwithstanding:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Officers of the Exchequer required to pay as before,</head>
			<para id="p78">
				<emph type="i">without Fee</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p79">And for the better and more speedy payment of the said yearely su[m]me of One hundred thousand pounds parte
of the said yearely su[m]me of One hundred and forty thousand pounds in the proporc[i]ons herein before menc[i]oned
and appointed the Co[m]missioners of theire Majesties Treasury and the Under-Treasurer of the Exchequer now being
and the Lord High Treasurer and Under-Treasurer or Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time being are hereby
strictly enjoyned and required by virtue of this Act and without any further or other Warrant to be sued for
had or obteined from theire Majesties theire Heires or Successors to direct theire Warrants yearely for the payment
of the said yearely su[m]mes of One hundred thousand pounds to the Contributors of the said su[m]me of Twelve hundred
thousand pounds in the manner and proporc[i]ons as is herein before directed and appointed; and the Auditor of
the Receipte of Exchequer and all other Officers of the Exchequer now and for the time being are hereby directed
and enjoyned to issue the said moneyes soe sett aparte for the uses before menc[i]oned from time to time without
any fee or reward in the manner and proporc[i]ons before menc[i]oned and under the like penalties forfeitures and
disabilities as are hereafter inflicted upon any Officer for diverting any money appropriated or applyed by
this Act:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. None shall subscribe more than &pound;20,000.</head>
			<para id="p80">
				<emph type="i">One Fourth Part to be paid at the Time of the Subscription.; Residue not paid before January, the One Fourth Part forfeited</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p81">Provided alwaies and be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That noe person or persons Bodyes
Politicke or Corporate shall by themselves or any other person or persons in trust for him or them subscribe or
cause to be subscribed for and towards the raiseing and paying the said su[m]me of Twelve hundred thousand
pounds any su[m]me or su[m]mes of money exceedeing the su[m]me of Twenty thousand pounds and that every such
Subscriber shall att the time of such subscripc[i]on pay or cause to be paid unto the Co[m]missioners who shall be
authorized and appointed for takeing and receiveing subscripc[i]ons as aforesaid one full forth parte of his or theire
respective subscripc[i]ons and in defaulte of such payments as aforesaid every such subscripc[i]on shall be utterly
void and null And that the residue of the said subscripc[i]ons shall be paid into the Receipte of theire Majesties
Exchequer as theire Majesties shall directe before the said First day of January next And in defaulte of such
payments that then the fourth parte first paid as aforesaid shall be forfeited to and for the benefitt of theire
Majesties theire Heires and Successors:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. No Person before 1st July next to subscribe more than &pound;10,000.</head>
			<para id="p82">[Provided alsoe and be it enacted That it shall not be lawfull to or for any person or persons Natives or
Foreigners Bodyes Corporate or Politicke att any time or times before the First day of July next ensueing to
subscribe in his her or theire owne name or names or in any other name or names in trust for him her or
them for and towards the raiseing and paying into the Receipte of the Exchequer the said su[m]me of Twelve
hundred thousand pounds parte of the said su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds any su[m]me or su[m]mes
exceedeing in the whole the su[m]me of Tenne thousand pounds; any thing in this Act conteined to the contrary
in any wise notwithstanding:-<ref idref="n14">14</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Not to be a Corporation except a Moiety be advanced before 1st August.</head>
			<para id="p83">
				<emph type="i">Subscribers, how they may transfer over, if Moiety not advanced.; Proportionable Part to be a Fund only for securing Money paid under this Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p84">Provided alwaies and be it declared and enacted to be the true intent and meaneing of this Act that in case
the whole su[m]me of Twelve hundred thousand pounds or a moiety thereof be not subscribed on or before the
First day of August One thousand six hundred ninety four as aforesaid that then the powers and authorities in
this Act for erecting a Corporac[i]on as aforesaid shall cease and determine any thing herein conteined to the contrary
notwithstanding. And in such case soe much of the said yearely su[m]me of One hundred thousand pounds as
shall belong to the said Subscribers according to the meaneing of this Act shall be transferrable and may be
from time to time transferred by the respective persons soe subscribing advanceing and paying any parte of the
said Twelve hundred thousand pounds into the Exchequer or theire respective Heires Successors or Assignes to
any person or persons whatsoever by any writeing or writeings under the hand and seale of the person or persons
transferring the same attested by two or more credible Witnesses and entered within Twenty dayes after the
sealeing thereof in a Booke or Bookes to be for that purpose kepte in the said Exchequer by theire Majesties
Remembrancer for the time being (for the entering whereof nothing shall be paid) which entries the said
Remembrancer is from time to time upon request directed to make; and such parte of the said yearely su[m]me of
One hundred thousand pounds as shall by this Act be due to the said Subscribers shall not att any time or times
hereafter be made use, of or be a fond or security for or lyable or applyed to raise pay or secure any more
further or other su[m]me or su[m]mes of money whatsoever save only such money as shall in pursuance of and according
to the intent of this Act be advanced and paid into their Majesties Exchequer within the time by this Act limited
for the same:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Corporation shall not borrow above &pound;1,200,000, except upon Parliament Funds.</head>
			<para id="p85">
				<emph type="i">If Corporation, borrow more, particular Members are proportionably charged.; Debt lies against particular Members.; Covenants to the contrary void</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p86">And it is hereby further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said Corporac[i]on soe to be made shall
not borrowe or give security by Bill Bond Covenant or Agreement under theire Co[m]mon Seale for any more
further or other su[m]me or su[m]mes of money exceedeing in the whole the su[m]me of Twelve hundred thousand pounds
soe that they shall not owe at any one time more then the said su[m]me unlesse it be by Act of Parliament upon
Fonds agreed in Parliament; and in such case only such further su[m]mes as shall be soe directed and allowed to
be borrowed by Parliament and for such time only untill they shall be repaid such further su[m]mes as they shall
borrowe by such authority and if any more or further or other su[m]me or su[m]mes of money shall be borrowed
taken up lent or advanced under theire Co[m]mon Seale or for payment of which any Bond Bill Covenant or Agreement
or other Writeing shall be made sealed or given under the Co[m]mon Seale of the said Corporac[i]on soe to be made
then and in such case all and every person and persons who shall be a member or members of the said
Corporac[i]on his and theire respective Heires Executors and Administrators shall in his and theire respective private
and personall capacities be chargeable with and lyable in proporc[i]on to theire severall Shares or Subscripc[i]ons to
the repayment of such moneyes which shall be soe borrowed taken up or lent with Interest for the same in
such manner as if such Security had beene a security for payment of soe much money and Interest for the same
sealed by such respective member or members of the said Corporac[i]on and delivered by him or them as theire
respective Acts and Deedes in proporc[i]on to theire severall Shares or Subscripc[i]ons as aforesaid and that in every
such case an Acc[i]on of Debt shall and may be brought comenced prosecuted and mainetained in any of theire
Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster by the respective Creditor or Creditors to whom any such Security
under the Co[m]mon Seale of the said Corporac[i]on shall be [made<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] or his or theire respective Executors or
Administrators against all and every or any one or more of the persons who shall be members of the said
Corporac[i]on or any of theire respective Heires Executors or Administrators in proporc[i]on to theire respective Shares
or Subscripc[i]ons as aforesaid and therein recover and have judgment for him or them in such and the like manner
as if such security were respectively sealed by the respective person or persons who shall be soe sued or his or
theire respective Ancestor or Testator or Intestate and by him and them executed and delivered as his or theire
respective Acts and Deedes any condic[i]on covenant or agreement to be made to the contrary thereof in any wise
notwithstanding. And if any condic[i]on covenant or agreement shall be made to the contrary the same shall be and
is hereby declared to be void any thing herein conteined or any Lawe or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding and
in such Acc[i]on or Acc[i]ons soe to be brought noe Priviledge Protecc[i]on Essoign or Wager of Lawe nor any more
then one Imparlance shall be allowed:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Corporation not to trade.</head>
			<para id="p87">
				<emph type="i">Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p88">And to the intent that theire Majesties Subjects may not be oppressed by the said Corporac[i]on by theire
monopolizing or ingrosseing any sort of Goods Wares or Merchandizes Be it further Declared and Enacted by the
authority aforesaid That the said Corporac[i]on to be made and created by this Act shall not att any time dureing
the continuance thereof deale or trade or permitt or suffer any person or persons whatsoever either in trust or
for the benefitt of the same to deale or trade with any of the Stock-moneyes or Effects of or any [wise<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] belonging
to the said Corporac[i]on in the buying or selling of any Goods Wares or Merchandizes whatsoever and every
person or persons who shall soe deale or trade or by whose order or direcc[i]ons such Dealeings or Tradeing shall
be made prosecuted or managed shall forfeite for every such Dealeing or Tradeing and every such order and
direcc[i]ons treble the value of the Goods and Merchandize soe traded for to such person or persons who shall
sue for the same by Acc[i]on of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on in any of theire Majesties Courts of Record at
Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protecc[i]on nor other Priviledge whatsoever nor any Injuncc[i]on Order of restrainte
nor Wager of Lawe shall be allowed nor any more then one Imparlance:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. In what Things they may nevertheless deal.</head>
			<para id="p89">Provided that nothing herein conteined shall any wayes be construed to hinder the said Corporac[i]on from dealeing
in Bills of Exchange or in buying or selling Bullion Gold or Silver or in selling any goods wares or merchandize
whatsoever which shall [be<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] really and bona fide be left or deposited with the said Corporac[i]on for money lent and
advanced thereon and which shall not be redeemed att the time agreed on or within three moneths after or from
selling such goods as shall or may be the produce of Lands purchased by the said Corporac[i]on:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. The Bills of the Corporation assignable.</head>
			<para id="p90">
				<emph type="i">Assignee may sue</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p91">[Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That all and every Bill or Bills obligatory
and of creditt under the Seale of the said Corporac[i]on made or given to any person or persons shall and may by
Indorsement thereon under the hand of such person or persons be assigneable and assigned to any person or
persons who shall voluntarily accepte the same and soe by such Assignee toties quoties by indorsement thereupon
and that such Assignement and Assignements soe to be made shall absolutely vest and transferre the Right and
Property in and unto such Bill or Bills Obligatory and of Creditt and the moneyes due upon the same and that the
Assignee or Assignees shall and may sue for and mainetaine an acc[i]on thereupon in his owne name:-<ref idref="n18">18</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Corporation purchasing Crown Lands, or lending Money upon Funds not having Loan of Credit;</head>
			<para id="p92">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p93">Provided alwaies and it is hereby further enacted That if the Governor Deputy Governor the Directors
Managers Assistants or other Members of the said Corporac[i]on soe to be established shall upon the account of the
said Corporac[i]on att (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) time or times purchase any Lands or Revenues belonging to the Crowne or advance or
lend to theire Majesties theire Heires or Successors any su[m]me or su[m]mes of money by way of Loan or Anticipac[i]on
on any parte or parts branch or branches fond or fonds of the Revenues now granted or belonging or hereafter
to be granted or belonging to theire Majesties theire Heires or Successors other then (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) such fond or fonds parte or
parts branch or branches of the said Revenues only on which a creditt of Loan is or shall be granted by Parliament
that then the said Governor Deputy Governor Directors Managers or Assistants or other Members of the said
Corporac[i]on who shall consent agree to or approve of the advanceing or lending to theire Majesties theire Heires
or Successors such su[m]me or su[m]mes of money as aforesaid and each and every of them soe agreeing consenting or
approveing and being thereof lawfully convicted shall for every such offence forfeite treble the value of every such
su[m]me or su[m]mes of money soe lent whereof one fifth parte shall be to the Informer to be recovered in any of
theire Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster by acc[i]on of Debt Bill Plainte or Informac[i]on wherein noe
Protecc[i]on Wager of Lawe Essoign Priviledge of Parliament or other Priviledge shall be allowed nor any more then
one Imparlance and the residue (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) towards publicke uses as shall be directed by Parliament and not otherwise:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Fines upon the Corporation not pardoned by Letters of Signet, &amp;c. and may be detained out of the annual Fund.</head>
			<para id="p94">Provided alwaies and be it enacted That all Amerciaments Fynes and Issues against the said Corporac[i]on and
theire Successors had charged or estreated in or upon account of any [suites<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] or acc[i]on to be prosecuted or brought
against them shall not be pardoned acquitted or discharged by any Letters of Signet Privye Seale or Greate Seale
of theire Majesties theire Heires or Successors or otherwise howsoever and in case any such Amerciaments Fynes
or Issues shall be estreated into theire Majesties Exchequer against the said Corporac[i]on upon any Processe for
nonappeareance att the suite of any person or persons that then it shall and may be lawfull to and for the
Officers of theire Majesties Exchequer for the time being who are hereby directed to pay the said yearely su[m]me
of One hundred thousand pounds to the said Corporac[i]on to detaine soe much money as the said Amerciaments
Fynes or Issues shall amount unto out of the said yearely su[m]me of One hundred thousand pounds payable to
the said Corporac[i]on:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Exchequer Officers may pay off Judgments against the Corporation.</head>
			<para id="p95">
				<emph type="i">Receipt of Plaintiff a Discharge</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p96">And be it further enacted That if att any time hereafter any person or persons shall obtaine any Judgment or
Judgements in any Court of Lawe againste the said Corporac[i]on for any Debte or su[m]me of money and shall bring
execuc[i]on or execuc[i]ons thereupon unto the said Officers of theire Majesties Exchequer that then it shall and may
be lawfull to and for the said Officers of the said Exchequer to pay and they are hereby required to pay the
said su[m]me or su[m]mes of money in the said execuc[i]ons menc[i]oned to the Plaintiffe or Plaintiffes therein named or theire
Assignes whose Receipte shall be a sufficient discharge for the same; and that the said Officers of the [said<ref idref="n23">23</ref>]
Exchequer shall and may detaine soe much of the said yearely su[m]me of One hundred thousand pounds as the
said Debt or Debts shall amount unto:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Recital of 5 &amp; 6 W. III. c.7.</head>
			<para id="p97">
				<emph type="i">Members of Parliament may be concerned in the Corporation</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p98">And whereas by an Act of this p[re]sent Session of Parliament entituled An Act for granting to theire Majesties
certaine Rates and Dutyes upon Salt and upon Beere Ale and other Liquors for secureing certaine recompences
and advantages in the said Act menc[i]oned to such persons as shall voluntarily advance the su[m]me of Tenne hundred
thousand pounds towards carrying on the Warr againste France Itt is enacted That noe Member of the House of
Co[m]mons shall att any time be concerned in the farmeing collecting or manageing any su[m]me or su[m]mes of money
Duties or other Aids by the said Act or any other Act of Parliament granted or to be granted to theire Majesties
excepte the persons in the said Act excepted; and whereas some Doubts may arise whether any Member or
Members of Parliament may be concerned in the Corporac[i]on to be erected in pursuance of this Act Be it therefore
declared and enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Member or
Members of the House of Co[m]mons to be a Member or Members of the said Corporac[i]on for the purposes in
this Act menc[i]oned any thing in the said recited Act conteined to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Persons may contribute towards the raising &pound;300,000, for which they shall receive yearly su[m]ms for One, Two, or Three Lives.</head>
			<para id="p99">
				<emph type="i">Tallies how levied.; 4 &amp; 5 W. &amp; M. c. 3. &sect; 8.; Order irrevocable and transferrable.; Duties appropriated to the Payment.; Officer, &amp;c. misapplying.; How Penalties sued for.; Register to be kept of Contributors and Nominees.; Penalty on Officer not executing Act.; Interest at &pound;10 per Cent. till 29th September</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p100">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for any persons Natives
or Forreigners to contribute towards the advanceing of the su[m]me of Three hundred thousand pounds other parte
of the said su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds by paying into the Receipte of theire Majesties Exchequer att
any time before the nine and twentieth day of September One thousand six hundred ninety and four any su[m]me
or su[m]mes of money not exceedeing in the whole the su[m]me of Three hundred thousand pounds upon the termes
following (that is to say) that every such person his Executors Administrators or Assignes out of the Rates and
Dutyes granted by this Act shall have and receive for every su[m]me of One hundred pounds soe by them respectively
advanced and paid such yearely Annuity Rent or Payment as herein after is directed (that is to say) That if such
Contributor shall advance and pay his money upon one life only then he shall have and receive a yearely Annuity
Rent or Payment of Fourteene pounds of lawfull English money for every Hundred pounds and soe proporc[i]onably
for a greater su[m]me for and dureing the life of such person soe advanceing and paying the same or dureing
any other Life to be nominated by the person advanceing or paying any such su[m]me; and in case [any<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]
Contributor shall thinke fitt upon payment of his money to have an Annuity for two lives then he shall have
an yearely Annuity Rent or payment of Twelve pounds of lawfull English money for every One hundred pounds
and soe proporc[i]onably for a greater su[m]me advanced for and dureing two lives and the life of the Survivor of
them to be nominated as aforesaid; and in case such Contributor shall thinke fitt upon payment of his money to
have an Annuity for Three lives then he shall have and receive a yearely Annuity Rent or Payment of Tenne
pounds of lawfull English money for every hundred pounds soe by him advanced and paid or after that rate for
and dureing the terme of three lives and the life of the Survivor of them to be nominated by the person or persons
soe paying the same as aforesaid that all and every the said lives shall be named by the severall Contributors
theire Executors or Administrators or such as shall be employed by them to pay in the said su[m]mes within Thirty
dayes after the Nine and twentieth day of September One thousand six hundred ninety and four which yearely
Annuities Rents or Payments shall co[m]mence from the said Nine and twentieth day of September and shall be paid
and payable quarterly att the four most usuall Feasts of the yeare (that is to say) the Feast of the Nativity of
our Lord Christ the Feaste of the Annunciac[i]on of the Blessed Virgin Mary the Feaste of [the Nativity<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] of St John
Baptist and the Feaste of St Michaell the Arch-angell by even and equal porc[i]ons And every person on payment
of any such su[m]me or su[m]mes as aforesaid shall imediately have one or more Tallye or Tallyes importing the receipte
of the considerac[i]on money and orders for the payment of the said Annuities beareing the same date with the Tally;
[the said Tallyes to be levyed and<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] the said Orders to be signed in the same manner as in and by an Act of
this p[re]sent Parliament entituled An Act for granting to theire Majesties certaine Rates and Dutyes of Excise upon
Beere Ale and other Liquors for secureing certaine recompences and advantages in the said Act menc[i]oned to such
persons as shall voluntarily advance the su[m]me of Tenne hundred thousand pounds towards carrying on the Warr
againste France is menc[i]oned and directed touching Tallyes and Orders to be given to the Contributors for Annuities
upon the said Act; and the said Orders not to be determinable revocable or countermandable as touching the
afore-menc[i]oned Orders in the said recited Act is enacted which said Orders shall be assigneable and transferrable
in such and the same manner as is menc[i]oned in the said recited Act touching Orders given to the Contributors
in the said Act menc[i]oned And all the Rates and Duties by this Act granted or soe much thereof as are and
shall be sufficient for the purposes aforesaid are and shall be appropriated to and for the payment of the said
Annuities of Inheritance and Annuities for lives after the severall and respective rates aforesaid according to the
true intent and meaneing of this Act and shall not be diverted or divertible to any other use intent or purpose
whatsoever under the like penalties forfeitures and disabilities in respect to all and every the Officers and other
persons in the [said<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] recited Act menc[i]oned as are in the said Act appointed and enacted in case of diverting or
misapplying any [parte<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] of the moneys which ought to be paid to the Contributors upon the said Act; and the
said penalties and forfeitures shall be sued for prosecuted recovered and paid in such manner and forme as the
penalties in the said recited Act are appointed to be sued for prosecuted recovered and paid in which suite no
Protecc[i]on Priviledge of Parliament or other Priviledge Wager of Lawe or more then one Imparlance shall be allowed
And the said Officers are hereby required to keepe Bookes and Registers and make entries of the names of all
persons who shall advance any moneys before the said Nine and twentieth day of September as aforesaid and of the
severall su[m]mes soe advanced and the times of paying in the same respectively and the names of such persons for
whose lives the severall Annuityes or yearely payments are to be payable without fee or reward in such manner
as in the said recited Act is menc[i]oned; to which Bookes all persons concerned shall have accesse as in the said
Act [is alsoe<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] directed All which the said Officers are to doe and performe under the like Penalties and Forfeitures
and Disabilities as in the said recited Act [is<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] menc[i]oned And every person who shall soe advance and pay any
such su[m]me as aforesaid before the said Nine and twentieth day of September as aforesaid shall receive out of the
money granted by this Act for all money soe advanced by him and paid from the respective dayes of payment
unto the said Nine and twentieth day of September as aforesaid Interest att the Rate of Tenne pounds per
Centum per Annu[m]:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. Annuity free from Tax.</head>
			<para id="p101">And be it further enacted That any moneys payable to any person or persons upon or by virtue of this Act
shall not be charged or chargeable with any Rates Dutyes or Imposic[i]ons whatsoever:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. Guardian may advance Infant's Money.</head>
			<para id="p102">
				<emph type="i">Infant to be made Nominee</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p103">And be it further enacted That it shall and may be lawfull for any Guardian or Trustee haveing the disposall
of the money of any Infant under the age of one and twenty yeares for the use and benefit of such Infant to
advance and pay the su[m]me of one hundred pounds of the moneys of such Infant either upon an Annuity of
Inheritance or upon Annuity for life or lives upon the respective termes and recompences herein menc[i]oned att
the election of such Guardian or Trustee And in case such Guardian or Trustee shall pay any such sume upon
an Annuity for life he shall thereupon within such time as is herein before appointed for the nameing of lives
name the said Infant to be a Nominee and such Infant upon payment of the su[m]me shall become a Contributor
within the meaneing of this Act and be entituled to have and receive a proporc[i]on as any other Contributor; And
the said Guardian and Trustee as to the [said<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] su[m]me of One hundred pounds soe advanced is hereby discharged:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Contributor upon Receipt to bring Certificate of Nominee's Life from Minister, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p104">
				<emph type="i">or Certificate from Justice of Peace, of Contributor's Oath of Nominee's Life.; No Fee for Oath, &amp;c.; False Oath, Perjury.; If Nominee in Scotland, &amp;c.; Certificate from Baron of Exchequer.; Receiving after Nominee's Death.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p105">And to make the payment of the Annuityes more easy to the severall Contributors upon this Act Be it enacted
that every Contributor upon this Act upon the termes of haveing an Annuity for One Two or Three Lives his
or her Executors Administrators or Assignes upon theire demanding any Payments of his her or theire respective
Shares of the said Fond unlesse the Nominee or Nominees or one of them appeare in person att the said Receipte
shall produce a Certificate of the life of his her or theire respective Nominee or Nominees or one of them signed
by the Minister and Church-wardens of the Parish where such Nominee shall be then liveing or otherwise it shall
and may be lawfull to and for every Contributor his or [theire<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] Executors Administrators or Assignes att his her or
theire Elecc[i]on to make Oath of the truth of his her or theire respective Nominees life or the life of one of them
upon the day when the said payment shall become due before one or more Justices of the Peace of the respective
County Rideing City Towne or Place wherein such person (att the time of makeing the said Oath) shall reside
which Oath he or they are hereby impowered to administer and the said Justice or Justices shall make (<ref idref="n32">32</ref>) Certificate
thereof for which Oath and Certificate noe Fee or Reward shall be required and the said Certificate shall be filed
in the said Office of Receipte in the Exchequer; And if any person shall be guilty of (<ref idref="n33">33</ref>) false Oath or forgeing
any Certificate touching the p[re]misses and being thereof lawfully convicted he shall incurr the paines and penalties
to be inflicted upon persons who co[m]mit wilfull Perjury or Forgery; And in case any Nominee shall att the time
of such demand be resident in Scotland or beyond the Seas and any one or more of the Barons of the Exchequer
for the time being shall certifie that upon Proofe to him or them made (which Proofe he and they is and are
hereby authorized and required to take in a summary way) it doth seeme probable to him or them that the said
Nominee is liveing which Certificate is to be given and Examinac[i]on made without Fee or Charge the said
Certificates being filed as aforesaid shall be a sufficient Warrant for makeing the said payment to the respective
Contributors or Advancers theire Executors Administrators or Assignes; And if any person or persons shall receive
one or more Payments upon his her or theire Annuitie or Annuityes for any time beyond the death of his her
or theire Nominee or Nominees when the same ought to cease such person or persons shall forfeite treble the
value of the moneys soe by (<ref idref="n34">34</ref>) her or them received the one halfe thereof to theire Majesties theire Heires and
Successors and the other halfe to him or them who will sue for the same by Acc[i]on Suite Bill or Informac[i]on
in which no Essoign Protecc[i]on Priviledge or Wager of Law or more then one Imparlance shall be allowed:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. If &pound;1,200,000 be not raised upon the Fund, what is short may be raised upon Lives.</head>
			<para id="p106">And it is hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in case the whole su[m]me of twelve hundred
thousand pounds shall not be subscribed and paid into the Exchequer as aforesaid; that then soe much of the
said yearely su[m]me of One hundred thousand pounnds hereby intended to answere the recompence for the same
as by such deficiency shall by this Act be undisposed shall and may be and is hereby applied and appropriated
(soe far as the same will amount) to pay to any person and persons who shall advance and pay any su[m]me or
su[m]mes of money, into the Exchequer on or before the First day of February which shall be in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and four on account to have an Annuity or Annuities for One Two or
Three Lives such respective su[m]me and su[m]mes for such respective Life or Lives according to such [rates<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] and
proporc[i]ons and for such time and under such Rules and Direcc[i]ons as are herein before contained with relac[i]on to
such as shall advance and pay the said three hundred thousand pounds:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. What falls short of &pound;1,500,000 raised before October, may be raised by Loan.</head>
			<para id="p107">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if the whole su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds
be not advanced and paid into the Exchequer upon this Act before the First day of October One thousand six
hundred ninety four that then it shall and may be lawfull for theire Majesties or theire Officers in the Receipte
of theire Majesties Exchequer by theire Co[m]mand and Appointement to borrow and take into the said Receipte for
theire Majesties Use by way of Loan any su[m]me or su[m]mes of money which together with the whole value or amount
of all the su[m]mes of money which shall before the said First day of October be contributed or advanced as
aforesaid shall not exceede the su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds which su[m]me or su[m]mes soe taken up
by way of Loan shall and may be charged upon the Creditt of theire Majesties Exchequer in generall and Tallyes
of Loan and Orders of Repayment of the same shall be levyed and drawne accordingly which said Orders shall
be assigneable and transferable from one person to another:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. Eight per Cent. per Ann. allowed upon Loan.</head>
			<para id="p108">
				<emph type="i">If the Duties fall short, Loan raised out of next Aids.; If no Aid before 2d February 1694, then paid out of the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p109">And it is hereby enacted That all and every su[m]me and su[m]mes of money soe to be borrowed not exceedeing
as aforesaid together with Interest for the same not exceedeing the Rate of Eight pounds per Centum per Annu
to be paid every three months untill satisfacc[i]on of the principall shall be payable and satisfied unto the respective
Lender or Lenders of the same his her or theire Executors Administrators or Assignes out of the moneys which
shall afterwards arise and be brought into the Exchequer by or for Contribuc[i]ons upon this Act soe far as the
same will extend; And in case the money soe ariseing by this Act shall not be sufficient for the paying thereof
then the said Loans which shall remaine unsatisfied [with<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] the Interest for the same shall be repaid out of the next
Aids or Supplyes to be granted to theire Majesties in Parliament and shall be transferred and transferrable
thereunto as soone as any such Aide or Supply shall be granted to theire Majesties; And if noe such Aids or
Supplyes shall be granted to theire Majesties before the Second day of February One thousand six hundred ninety
four then the said su[m]me and su[m]mes of money soe to be borrowed not exceedeing as aforesaid and the Intereste
thereof shall be payable and be paid and satisfied to the Lender or Lenders his her or theire Executors Administrators
or Assignes respectively by and out of any theire Majesties Treasure which from thenceforth shall come into be or
remaine in the Receipte of theire Majesties Exchequer not being already appropriated to any particular Uses by any
Act or Acts of Parliament before this time made:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. &pound;1,000,000 formerly appropriated to the Navy and Ordnance, c. 1. ante.</head>
			<para id="p110">
				<emph type="i">5&pound;1,500,000 more to the Navy and Ordnance, c. 7. ante, or other Act of this Session; All other Money to the Army and other War Charges</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p111">And whereas by an Act of this p[re]sent Session of Parliament entituled (An Act for granting to theire Majesties
an Aide of Four shillings in the Pound for one yeare for carrying on a vigorous Warr against France) the
su[m]me of Tenne hundred thousand pounds includeing therein the su[m]me of Four hundred thousand pounds already
borrowed for the use of the Navy is by the said Act appropriated for the Services of the Navy and Ordnance
as parte of the Supplyes granted this Session for the payment of Wages for Services done and to be done and
for the paying for Victualls supplyed and to be supplyed for the said Navy and for and towards the paying for
other necessary Provisions and Stores supplyed and to be supplyed and for the Ordnance of the said Navy Royall
and for the Wages of the yards and other Services of the Ordinary of the said Navy:- Now to the intent the
whole su[m]me granted this p[re]sent Session of Parliament for the uses aforesaid may be thereunto appropriated Itt is
hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid that out of the money that hath or shall be levyed by virtue
of this Act or of another Act of this present Session of Parliament entituled An Act for granting to theire
Majesties certaine Rates and Dutyes upon Salt and upon Beere Ale and other Liquors for secureing certaine
Recompences and Advantages in the said Act menc[i]oned to such persons as shall voluntarily advance the su[m]me of
Tenne hundred thousand pounds towards carrying on the Warr against France or of any other Act of this
present Session of Parliament by which any Aids shall be granted to theire Majesties towards the carrying on the
said Warr and which shall be paid into the Exchequer aswell upon Loans as otherwise (excepte only the money
appropriated to pay the Recompences in this and the before recited Act) the su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand
pounds over and above the said su[m]me of Tenne hundred thousand pounds in the first recited Act appropriated
shall be and is hereby appropriated for the Services of the Navy and Ordnance performed and to be performed
And that all other money which shall be levyed and paid by virtue of this or any other Act of this p[re]sent Session
of Parliament not appropriated by this or the first recited Act to the use of the said Navy or to pay the Recompences
in this and the other recited Act into the Receipte of the Exchequer aswell upon Loans as otherwise shall be
applyed and appropriated to and for the payment of theire Majesties Land Forces and Armies Ordnance Ammuc[i]on
and other Charges incident to the Warr and not otherwise:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Half of this or any other Tax, except Land Tax, charged with the &pound;1,500,000. c. 5. ante.</head>
			<para id="p112">And for the more effectuall doeing thereof be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the halfe of all
money that hath or shall be levied or paid into the Receipte of the Exchequer by virtue of this Act or any other
Act of this p[re]sent Session of Parliament (excepte the said first recited Act and excepte what is appropriated by
this or the other recited Act to pay the Recompences of those who have or shall voluntarily advance moneys as
aforesaid; And excepte alsoe [another<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] Act entituled An Act to supplye the deficiency of the money raised by a
former Act entituled An Act for granting to theire Majesties certaine Rates and Dutyes of Excise upon Beere
Ale and other Liquors for secureing certaine Recompences and Advantages in the said Act menc[i]oned to such persons
as shall voluntarily advance the su[m]me of Tenne hundred thousand pounds towards the carrying on the Warr against
France) shall be applyed to answere the said su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds hereby appropriated to the
use of the said Navy untill the same shall be paid and satisfied:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. Particular Sums for Wages, &amp;c. of Navy, Marines, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p113">And it is hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That out of the su[m]me of Fifteene hundred thousand
pounds hereby appropriated and out of the said su[m]me of tenne hundred thousand pounds in the before recited Act
appropriated for the use of the Navy the su[m]me of Eleven hundred fifty six thousand nine hundred ninety four
pounds shall be applyed to pay the Wages to Officers and Seamen and other Services belonging according to the
Course of the Navy to the Head of Wages performed and to be performed And alsoe to pay the Officers and
Soldiers of the two Marine Regiments And that the su[m]me of twelve hundred fifty seven thousand two hundred
sixty and six pounds be applyed for and towards the paying for Victualls and necessary Provisions and Stores
and other extraordinary Services of the Navy and Ordnance supplyed and performed or to be supplyed or performed:
And that the su[m]me of Eighty five thousand seven hundred and forty pounds be applyed for and towards paying
the Wages of the yards and other ordinary Services of the said Navy:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>XLIII. Rules, Penalties, &amp;c. of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 1. applied.</head>
			<para id="p114">And that the su[m]mes by this Act appropriated may not be diverted or applyed to any other purpose then is
hereby declared and intended be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the rules and direcc[i]ons appointed
and enacted in one Act made in the first yeare of theire Majesties Raigne entituled An Act for a Grant to theire
Majesties of an Aid of Two Shillings in the Pound for one yeare for the speedy payment of money thereby
granted into the Receipte of the Exchequer by the Collectors and Receivers and for distribuc[i]on and applicac[i]on
thereof and keepeing distinct Accompts of the same; and all other Provisoes Paines Penalties and Forfeitures
thereby enacted in case of diversion of any money thereby appropriated are hereby revived and enacted to be in
force and shall be practised applyed executed and putt in ure for and concerneing the distribuc[i]on and applicac[i]on
of the said su[m]mes hereby appropriated as fully amply and effectually as if the same were here particularly repeated
and re-enacted:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>XLIV. Recital of Utility of Manufacture of Silks.</head>
			<para id="p115">
				<emph type="i">Alamodes, &amp;c. to be marked and sealed by the Custom-House Officers.; No Fee for marking, &amp;c.; Lustrings, &amp;c. imported and not sealed;; Penalty.; 1. W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 34.; Counterfeiting Mark;; Penalty &pound;500</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p116">And whereas there is lately sett up in this Kingdome a very profitable manufacture of Silke Stuffs called
Lustrings and Alamodes never before made in this Realme for the which greate su[m]mes of money of the Nation
were heretofore exported into France; and to the intent that noe discouragement may be given to soe usefull a
Trade wherein many [hundreds<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] of theire Majesties Subjects are employed by preventing all Frauds and Deceits to
the Revenue of theire Majesties Customes by fraudulently importing such Silkes without paying legall Duties for
the same Be it enacted by the authority aforesaid that the Co[m]missioners of theire Majesties Customes for the time
being shall and are hereby authorized and required from time to time from and after the end of this Session of
Parliament to marke and seale or cause to be markt and sealed all the said Lustrings and Alamodes which now
are imported and in the hands of any person or persons whatsoever and alsoe of all the said Stuffs soe called
which shall be hereafter imported and to keepe an Entry and Registry thereof in the Custome House in a Booke
to be for that Purpose provided And that all which are already imported shall be soe markt sealed and registered
within Twenty dayes of the said time for which there shall be noe Fee or Reward paid; And all such Lustrings
and Alamodes which shall be hereafter imported from the time aforesaid shall be soe markt sealed and registered
without any Fee as aforesaid before they be delivered out of the Custome House warehouse where they shall
be respectively imported and entered; And all such Lustrings and Alamodes which shall be att any time after
the Fifteenth day of May One thousand six hundred ninety four imported and not soe sealed and markt shall be
forfeited and the Importers or Possessors thereof subject to such and the like penalties and forfeitures as Importers
of French Goods by one Act made in the First yeare of theire Majesties Raigne entituled An Act for prohibiting
all Trade and Comerce with France to be recovered as therein [is<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] directed; And if any person or persons shall
alter or counterfeite the Marke or Seale Marks or Seales used and to be used for the Purposes aforesaid the
Offender shall forfeite the su[m]me of Five hundred pounds to any that will sue for the same by Bill Plainte or
Informac[i]on in any of theire Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protecc[i]on or Wager
of Law shall be allowed nor any more then one Imparlance:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>XLV. Recital of c. 1. ante.</head>
			<para id="p117">
				<emph type="i">Certificate to Parliament by Admiralty of the Stations of the Cruizers appointed by the said Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p118">And whereas it is enacted in one Act of this p[re]sent Session of Parliament entituled An Act for granting to
theire Majesties an aid of Four shillings in the pound for One yeare for carrying on a vigorous Warr against
France That for the better secureing the Trade of this Kingdome over and above the Shipps of Warr for the Line
of Battell and for Convoys to remote parts att the least Four Shipps of the Third Rate Sixteene Shipps of the
Fourth Rate Thirteene Shipps of the Fifth Rate and Tenne Ships of the Sixth Rate shall be from time to time
directed and appointed by the Lord High Admirall of England or Co[m]missioners for executeing the said Office for
the time being to such proper Stations as they shall deeme mete to cruise for secureing the Merchant Shipps in
theire goeing out and returneing home:- Wherefore that it may the better appeare how the said Service is
performed wherein the security of Trade and the safety of these Realmes is soe much concerned Be it enacted by the
authority aforesaid That the Lord High Admirall of England or [the<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] Co[m]missioners for executeing the Office of
Lord High Admirall of England for the time being shall and are hereby respectively required to exhibitt to the
Co[m]mons assembled in Parliament att the next Session of this or any other Parliament which shall happen after
the First day of August One thousand six hundred ninety four a Certificate in writeing under his or theire
Hands respectively of the Shipps by him or them respectively sett out in pursuance of the said recited Clause
expressing therein the Names and Rates of the Ships sett out and the times when by him or them respectively
ordered as alsoe the Stations to which they were directed and the Times how long they were continued att Sea in
that Service:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>XLVI. One Penny per Pound allowed to the Exchequer Officers.</head>
			<para id="p119">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Officers of the Receipte of theire Majesties
Exchequer shall and may receive and take for theire Fees One penny in the pound and noe more for all or any
the su[m]me or su[m]mes of money to be issued or paid to any theire Majesties Garisons or other Land Forces and Armies
and other charges incident to the same out of the money ariseing by this or any other Act and Grant of this
Session or any other Session of Parliament dureing this present Warr to be distributed in such proporc[i]on as the
Lord Treasurer or Lords Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time being shall appointe:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>XLVII. Officers in the Excise not to interfere in Choice of Members.</head>
			<para id="p120">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;100.; and Disability</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p121">And to the end the greate dutyes of Excise and the powers given for the collecting and levying the same may
not be employed for the influenceing of elecc[i]ons of Members to serve in Parliament which elecc[i]ons by the
Constituc[i]on of this Governement ought to be free and uncorrupt Be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That
from and after the First day of May [in the yeare of our Lord<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] One thousand six hundred ninety four noe
Collector Supervisor Gauger or other Officer or Person whatsoever concerned or employed in the chargeing
collecting levying or manageing the dutyes of Excise or any branch or parte thereof shall by word message or
writeing or in any other manner whatsoever endeavour to perswade any Elector to give or diswade any Elector
from giveing his vote for the choice of any person to be a Knight of the Sheire Citizen Burgesse or Baron of
any County City Burrough or Cinque Port to serve in Parliament and every Officer or other person offending
therein shall forfeite the su[m]me of One hundred Pounds one moiety thereof to the Informer and the other moiety
to the Poore of the Parish where such Offence thall be co[m]mitted to be recovered by any person that shall sue
for the same by Acc[i]on of Debte Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on in any of theire Majesties Courts of Record att
Westminster in which noe Essoign Protecc[i]on Priviledge or Wager of Lawe or more then one Imparlance shall be
allowed; And every person convict on any such Suite of the said Offence shall thereby become disabled and
incapable of ever beareing or executeing any Office or Place; concerneing or relateing to the duty of Excise or any
other Office or Place of Trust whatsoever under theire Majesties theire Heires or Successors:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>XLVIII. Note of Gauge delivered to the Brewer, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p122">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p123">And it is hereby declared and enacted That true Notes in Writeing of the last Gauges made or taken by the
Gaugers shall be left by them with all Brewers Makers or Retailers of Bere Ale or other exciseable Liquors
respectively or some of theire Servants att the times of takeing theire said Gauges containeing the quantity and
quality of the Liquors soe gauged upon the penaltie of Five pounds for every Offence or Neglect of the said
Gauger or Gaugers to be recovered by any person that shall sue for the same by Acc[i]on of Debte Bill Plainte or
Informac[i]on in any of theire Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster in which noe Essoigne Protecc[i]on Priviledge
or Wager of Lawe nor more then one Imparlance shall be allowed:-</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Shillings <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Town or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Companies <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Importer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Act <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">deficient or lowe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">and shall compleatly pay off and discharge <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">wayes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">on <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">to be disposed of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">suite <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">such <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">omitted in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">also is <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">are <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">her <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">a <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">a <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">him <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">rate <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">one other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">hundred <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

