<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46418" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for building good and defensible Shipps  [Chapter XXIV Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Builders of Threedecked Ships to have a Tenth Part of the Goods they export or import for first Three Voyages.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas the Wealth and Safety of this Nation are much concerned in the Number and Strength of
Shipping; Now for the better Encouragement of building good and defensible Shipps Be it enacted by the
King and Queenes most excellent Majesties by and with the Advise and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and Co[m]mons in this p[re]sent Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That all and every
person or persons that shall within the space of Tenne yeares from and after the first day of May One thousand
six hundred ninety four build or cause to be built within any of theire Majesties Dominions any Shipps or Vessells
of Three Decks reckoning the Orlop for one with a Fore-Castle Quarter-Decke and Round-house and Six Foote
betweene each Decke from Planke to Planke [theire Hawrses to be betweene Decks; the said Shipps to be of noe
lesse then Four hundred and fifty Tunne and to have noe lesse then Ten Ports of a side betweene Decks <ref idref="n1">1</ref>] mounted
with two and thirty Peices of Ordnance [close of which eighteene to be betweene Decks the said Guns upon the
Lower Deck to be Demy-Culverine of thirty hundred weight att least, upon the Upper Deck Fore-castle and Steerage
to be alsoe Demy-Culverine of two and twenty hundred weight att leaste and those in the Cuddy to be six hundred
weight att least<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] and other Amunic[i]on [proportionable<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]; shall for the first three Voyages which the said Shipp or Shipps
shall make from theire Majesties Dominions to any Forreigne parts have and receive to theire owne proper use and
benefitt one tenth parte of the Customes [co[m]monly called or knowne by the name of the Subsidye of Tunnage and
Poundage<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] that shall be paid to theire Majesties for all such Goods and Merchandizes as shall be exported and
imported on the said Shipp or Shipps to and from this Kingdome and the Co[m]missioners and Officers of theire
Majesties Customes are hereby impowered and required to pay the same to the Owner and Owners of the said
Shipp or Shipps accordingly:-</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Ships made less defensible after Three Voyages forfeited.</head>
			<para id="p2">[Provided alwaies That if att any time after the end of the said three first Voyages any of the said Shipps or
Vessells soe to be built as aforesaid shall be altered or putt into another forme of building whereby they shall
become or be made lesse defensible then they were att first building that then every such Shipp or Vessell with
all the Gunns Tackle Amuc[i]on and Apparell thereof shall be forfeited and lost the one moiety to their Majesties
theire Heires and Successors and the other moiety to the Informer to be recovered in any of theire Majesties Courts
of Record by Acc[i]on of Debte Bill Plainte or Informac[i]on.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">proportionably <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

