<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46415" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXI. An Act for granting to theire Majesties severall Dutyes upon Velum Parchment and Paper for Four Yeares towards carryyng on the warr against France:- [Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Duty upon Things written and ingrossed for 4 Years.</head>
		<para id="p1">Wee your Majesties most dutifull and loyall Subjects the Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled haveing entered into
a due and serious considerac[i]on of the extraordinary occasions which oblige your Majesties to a greate and
present expence for the necessarye defence of your Realmes and being desireous to raise such Aids and Supplyes
as may be proporc[i]onable to these occasions doe humbly present your Majesties with the Free Guifte of the Rates
and Dutyes herein after menc[i]oned; and doe beseech your Majesties that it may be enacted:- And be it enacted by the
King and Queenes most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall
and Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled and by authority of the same That from and after the Eight and twentieth
day of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety [and<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] four there shall be
throughout theire Majesties Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede raised
collected and paide unto theire Majesties theire Heires and Successors dureing the terme of Four yeares and noe
longer for the severall and respective things herein after menc[i]oned which shall be written or ingrossed dureing the
terme aforesaid over and above the Rates Dutyes and Su[m]mes of money now due and payable to theire Majesties or
to any Person or Persons Bodyes Politicke or Corporate whatsoever for the same the severall and respective Rates
Imposic[i]ons Dutyes Charges and Su[m]ms of Money herein after expressed in manner and forme followeing (that is to
say:-)</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Letters Patent, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">For every Skin or Peice of Velum or Parchment on which any Grants or Letters Patents under the Great Seale
of England or the Seale of the Dutchy or County Pallatine of Lancaster or of any Honour Dignity Promoc[i]on
Franchise Libertye or Priviledge to any Person or Persons Bodies Politicke or Corporate or Exemplifications of the
same shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Forty Shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Pardons</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p5">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum Parchment or Sheete of Paper on which any pardon of or for any crime or
offence or of any su[m]me of money or forfeiture whatsoever or on which any warrant of repreive or relaxacon from
any Fines Corporall Punishments or other Forfeiture shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Forty Shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">Grants of Money from the Crown</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p7">For every Skinn of Velum or Parchment or sheete of Paper upon which any grant from theire Majesties of any
su[m]me of money exceedeing One hundred pounds which shall passe the Greate Seale or Privy Seale (not directed
to the Greate Seale) shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Forty shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">Grants of Office</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p9">For every Skinn of Velum or Parchment or for every sheete of Paper upon which any grant of any Office or
Employment which shall be above the value of Fifty pounds per annu[m] shall be written or ingrossed the su[m]me of
Forty shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">Grants of Lands, Leases, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p11">For every Skin of Velum or Parchment on which any grant of Lands in fee Lease for yeares or other grant
of profitt not herein particularly charged shall passe the Greate Seale of England the Seale of the Exchequer the
Seale of the Dutchy or County Pallatine of Lancaster [or(<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Privy Seale<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] (not directed to the Greate Seale) shall
be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Forty shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p12">
			<emph type="i">Presentations; Proviso as to value of Benefice</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p13">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or sheete of Paper upon which any presentac[i]on or donac[i]on
which shall passe the Greate Seale of England or upon which any collac[i]on to be made by any Arch-Bishopp or
other Bishopp or any presentac[i]on or donac[i]on to be made by any patron whatsoever of or to any benefice dignity
or spirituall or ecclesiasticall promotion whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Forty shillings
(Provided such benefice dignity or promotion be of the yearely value of Tenn pounds or above in the Kings
Bookes:-)</para>
		<para id="p14">
			<emph type="i">Degrees in the Universities, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p15">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete or Piece of Paper upon which any register entry
testimoniall or certificate of any degree taken in either of the two Universities or Four Inns of Court shall be
ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Forty shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p16">
			<emph type="i">Dispensations</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p17">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper on which any dispensac[i]on to hold two
ecclesiasticall dignities or benefices or both a dignity and a benefice or any other dispensac[i]on or Facultie from
the Lord Arch-Bishop of Canterbury or the [Master of the<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Faculties for the time being shall be ingrossed
or written the su[m]me of Forty shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p18">
			<emph type="i">Admittance of Attornies, Proctors, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p19">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment Sheete or Piece of Paper upon which any admittance of any
Fellowe of the Colledge of Physitians or of any Attorney Clerke Advocate Proctor Notary or other Officer or
Officers in any Courte whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Forty shillings:</para>
		<para id="p20">
			<emph type="i">Appeals</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p21">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which any Appeale from the Court
of Admiralty Arches or the Prerogative Courts of Canterbury or Yorke shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of
Forty shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p22">
			<emph type="i">Conveyances, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p23">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) Sheete of Paper upon which any Conveyance Surrender
of Grants or Offices Release or other Deede whatsoever which shall be enrolled of record in any of the Courts
att Westminster or in any other Court of Record whatsoever or by any Custos Rotolo[rum] or Clerke of the Peace
shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Five shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p24">
			<emph type="i">Writs of Covenant</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p25">For every Peice of Velum or Parchment upon which any Writt of Covenant for levying of Fynes shall be
ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Five shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p26">
			<emph type="i">Recoveries</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p27">For every Peice of Velum or Parchment upon which any Writt of Entry for suffering a Co[m]mon Recovery shall
be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Five shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p28">
			<emph type="i">Exemplifications</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p29">For every Skinn of Velum or Parchment upon which any Exemplificac[i]on of what nature soever that shall passe
the seale of any Courte whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Five shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p30">
			<emph type="i">Decrees in Chancery, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p31">For every Skinn of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which any Decree or Dismission made by
or in the Court of Chancery Exchequer Court of the County Palatine or Dutchy of Lancaster Courts of the
Countyes Palatine of Chester Durham or other Court of Equity whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the
su[m]me of Six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p32">
			<emph type="i">Licences</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p33">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which any Instituc[i]on or Lycence that
shall passe the seale of any Arch-Bishopp or Bishopp Chancellor or other Ordinary or any Ecclesiasticall Court
whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Five shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p34">
			<emph type="i">Writs of Error, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p35">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which any Writt of Error
Certiorari Habeas Corpus or Appeale (excepte to the Delegates) shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Five
shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p36">
			<emph type="i">Significavits</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p37">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which any Significavit pro corporis
deh[i]ac[i]one shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Five shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p38">
			<emph type="i">Admiralty Sentences, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p39">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete or Peice of Paper upon which any Sentence that
shall be given in the Court of the Lord High Admirall of England or the Cinque Ports exerciseing Admiralty
Jurisdicc[i]on or upon any Attachment that shall be made out of any of the said Courts of Admiralty or any
relaxac[i]on of any such Attachment shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Five shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p40">
			<emph type="i">Marriage Certificates, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p41">For every Skinn or Peice of Vellum or Parchment or Sheete or Peice of Paper upon which any Licence for or
Certificate of Marriage or any Letters of Mart shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Five shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p42">
			<emph type="i">Probates of Wills, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p43">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment Sheete or Peice of Paper upon which any Probate of a Will
or Letters of Administrac[i]on for any Estate above the value of Twenty pounds shall be ingrossed or written the
su[m]me of Five shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p44">
			<emph type="i">Recognizances, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p45">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment Sheete or Peice of Paper upon which any Recognizance StatuteStaple or Statute-Merchant shall be ingrossed or written and entered of record in any Court or Office the su[m]me
of Five shillings:-</para>
		<para id="p46">
			<emph type="i">Postea, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p47">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment upon which any Record of Nisi prius or Postea shall be ingrossed
or written the su[m]me of Two shillings and Six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p48">
			<emph type="i">Judgments</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p49">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Paper upon which shall be ingrossed or written any Judgment
whatsoever which shall be signed by the Master of any Office or his deputy or secondary or by any Prothonotary
or his Secondary Deputy or Clerke or any other Officer belonging to any of the Courts att Westminster who have power
or usually doth or shall signe Judgments the su[m]me of Two shillings and Six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p50">
			<emph type="i">Commissions out of Ecclesiastical Court</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p51">For every Skin or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which any Co[m]mission issueing out of
any Ecclesiasticall Court not herein otherwise particularly charged shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Two
shillings and six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p52">
			<emph type="i">Monitions, &amp;c; Exception</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p53">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which any Warrant Monic[i]on or
Personall Decree in any Court of Admiralty or the Cinque Ports shall be ingrossed or written or upon which
any beneficiall Warrant or Order under theire Majesties Signe Manuall (excepte Warrants or Orders for [the service
of<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] theire Majesties Navy Army and Ordnance) shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Two shillings and six
pence:-</para>
		<para id="p54">
			<emph type="i">Special Bail</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p55">For every Peice of Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any Speciall Bayle to be taken in any of the Courts
att Westminster or before any of the Judges of the said Courts or in any other Court whatsoever that shall be filed
in any of the said Courts shall be ingrossed or written and for every Peice of Velum Parchment or Paper upon
which shall be ingrossed or written any Appearance upon such Speciall Baile the su[m]me of One shilling:-</para>
		<para id="p56">
			<emph type="i">Bills, Answers, &amp;c. in Equity</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p57">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment upon which shall be ingrossed or written any Bill Answere
Replicac[i]on Rejoynder Interrogatories Deposic[i]ons taken by Co[m]mission or any other Pleadings whatsoever in the
Courts of Chancery Exchequer Dutchy Court and County Palatine Courts or other Courts of Equity the su[m]me of
One shilling:-</para>
		<para id="p58">
			<emph type="i">Admissions into Companies, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p59">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment and for every Sheete or Peice of Paper upon which any
Admission into any Corporac[i]on or Company or any Matriculac[i]on in either of the Two Universities, or any
Admission into any of the Inns of Court or Inns of Chancery shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of One
shilling:-</para>
		<para id="p60">
			<emph type="i">Affidavits, &amp;c. Exception</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p61">For every Peice of Parchment or Paper upon which any Affidavitt shall be ingrossed or written (excepte Affidavitts
taken pursuant to the severall Acts made in the Thirtieth and Two and thirtieth yeares of the Raigne of King
Charles the Second for burying in Wollen and excepte such Affidavitts as shall be taken before the Officers of
theire Majesties Customes or any Justice or Justices of the Peace or before any Co[m]missioners appointed or to be
appointed by any Act of Parliament for the assessing or levying any aids or Duties granted or to be granted
to theire Majesties and which Affidavitts shall be taken by the said Officers of the Customes Justices or Co[m]missioners
by virtue of theire authority as Justices of the Peace or Co[m]missioners respectively and not otherwise) the su[m]me of
Six pence:- And for every Peice of Parchment or Paper upon which any Copy of such Affidavitt as is herein
before charged that shall be filed or read in any Court whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of
Six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p62">
			<emph type="i">Indentures, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p63">For every Skin or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which shall be ingrossed or written
any Indenture Lease or Deede Poll not hereby otherwise charged the su[m]me of Six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p64">
			<emph type="i">Writs (Exception.)</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p65">For every Peice of Velum or Parchment or Peice of Paper upon which any Originall Writt (excepte such Originall
on which a Writt of Capias issues) Subpena, Bill of Middlesex Latitat Writt of Capias Quo minus Writt of Dedim<emph type="p">s</emph>
Potestatem to take Answeres examine Witnesses or appointe Guardians and any other Writt whatsoever or any other
Processe or Mandate that shall issue out of or passe the Seales of any of the Courts att Westminster Courts of
the Greate Sessions in Wales Courts in Counties Palatine or any other Court whatsoever holding plea where the
debt or damage doth amount to Forty shillings or above or the thing in demand is of that value shall be ingrossed
or written the sum of Six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p66">
			<emph type="i">Entries of Actions, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p67">For every Peice of Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any Entry of any Acc[i]on in the Mayors and Sheriffs
Courts of London and in Courts in all Corporac[i]ons and other Courts whatsoever out of which noe Writts
Processe or Mandates issue holding Plea where the Debte or Damage doth amount to Forty shillings or above
shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p68">
			<emph type="i">Common Bail; When such Common Bail to be filed; Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p69">For every Peice of Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any Co[m]mon Baile to be filed in any Court whatsoever
and upon which any appearance that shall be made upon such Baile shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of
Six pence: which appearance or co[m]mon Baile the Defendant shall cause to be entered or filed within Eight dayes
after the Returne of the Processe on which the Defendant was arrested upon Penalty of Five pounds to be paid
to the Plaintiffe for which the Court shall imediately award Judgment whereupon the Plaintiffe may take out
Execuc[i]on:-</para>
		<para id="p70">
			<emph type="i">Rules of Court</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p71">For every Peice of Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any Rule or Order made or given in any of the
Courts att Westminster either Courts of Lawe or Equity shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p72">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Rules</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p73">For every Peice of Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any Copy of such Rules or Orders entered or the
Copies of any other Records or Proceedeings in any of the said Courts att Westminster not hereby otherwise
charged shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p74">
			<emph type="i">Citations, Inventories, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p75">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which shall be ingrossed or written
any Citac[i]on or Monic[i]on made in any Ecclesiasticall Court or any Libell or Allegac[i]on Deposic[i]on Answere Sentence
or Finall Decree or any Inventory exhibited in any Ecclesiasticall Courte [or<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Courts of Admiralty or Cinque Ports
or whereupon any Copies of them respectively shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p76">
			<emph type="i">Charterparty, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p77">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which any Charter-party Policy of
Assureance Passport Bond Release Contract or other Obligatory Instrument or any Protest Procurac[i]on Letter of
Attorney or any other Notariall Act whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of Six pence:-</para>
		<para id="p78">
			<emph type="i">Declarations, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p79">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which any Declarac[i]on Plea
Replicac[i]on Rejoynder Demurrer or other Pleadings whatsoever in any Court of Lawe shall be ingrossed or written
the su[m]me of One penny:- And for every Skinn or Piece of Velum or Parchment upon which any Copy thereof
shall be written or ingrossed the su[m]me of One penny:-</para>
		<para id="p80">
			<emph type="i">Depositions in Equity; Exception</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p81">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which any Deposic[i]ons taken in
the Court of Chancery or other Court of Equity (excepte the Paper Draughts of Deposic[i]ons taken by virtue of
any Co[m]mission before they are ingrossed) which are not herein before charged or upon which any Copy of any
Bill Answere Plea Demurrer Replicac[i]on Rejoynder Interrogatories Deposic[i]ons or other Proceedeings whatsoever in
any Courte of Equity shall be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of One penny:-</para>
		<para id="p82">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Wills</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p83">For every Skinn or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheete of Paper upon which a Copy of any Will shall
be ingrossed or written the su[m]me of One penny:-</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Officers of Courts to set down upon the Writ the Day and Year, and enter it upon the Remembrance.</head>
			<para id="p84">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;10</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p85">And for preventing Abuses co[m]mitted by arresting Persons without any Writt or Legall Processe to justifie the
same by meanes whereof the Duty hereby given to the Crowne upon such Processe will be lost Be it enacted by
the authority aforesaid That from and after the said Eight and twentieth day of June every Officer or Clerke
belonging to the Courte of Kings-Bench Co[m]mon Pleas or Exchequer who shall signe any Writt or Processe before
Judgment to arrest any person or persons thereupon shall att the signeing thereof sett downe upon such Writt or
Processe the day and yeare of his signeing the same which shall be entered upon the Remembrance or in the
Booke where the Abstracte of such Writt or Processe shall be entered upon paine to forfeite the su[m]me of Tenne
pounds for every Offence or Neglect of such Officer or Clerke aforesaid to be recovered by any person who shall
sue for the same in any of theire Majesties Courts of Record by Acc[i]on of Debte Bill Plainte or Informac[i]on
wherein noe Wager of Lawe Protecc[i]on or Essoign or more then one Imparlance shall be allowed:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Bills of Exchange, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p86">[Provided alwaies that this Act or any thing therein conteined shall not extend to charge any Bills of Exchange
Accompts Bills of Parcells Bills of Fees or any Bills or Notes (not sealed) for payment of money att sight or
upon demand or att the end of certaine dayes of payment:-<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Probate of Will, &amp;c. of Soldier and Seaman.</head>
			<para id="p87">Provided that nothing in this Act conteined shall extend to charge the Probate of any Will or Letters of
Administrac[i]on of any Co[m]mon Seaman or Soldier who shall be slaine or dye in theire Majesties Service a Certificate
being produced from the Captaine of the Shipp or Vessell or Captaine of the Troope or Company under whome
such Seaman or Soldier served att the time of his death and Oath made of the Truth thereof before the proper
Judge or Officer by whome such Probate or Administrac[i]on ought to be granted which Oath such Judge or Officer
is hereby authorized and required to administer and for which noe Fee or Reward shall be taken:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. King may appoint Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p88">
				<emph type="i">Place of Head Office; Commissioners may appoint Officers; Six several Marks to be provided by Commissioners; The Marks may be changed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p89">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that for the better and more effectuall levying collecting
and paying unto theire Majesties theire Heires and Successors the severall [&amp; respective<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] duties hereby granted Itt
shall and may be lawfull for theire Majesties theire Heires and Successors under the Greate Seale of England
from time to time to nominate and appointe such persons as they shall thinke fitt to be Co[m]missioners or Officers
for the severall purposes herein after menc[i]oned And that the Co[m]missioners soe to be appointed shall keepe theire
Head Office in some convenient place within the Cityes of London or Westminster And the said Co[m]missioners
or the major parte of them are hereby impowered under theire Hands and Seales to appointe such other inferior
Officers for the markeing or stamping of Velum Parchment and Paper or for the better collecting and levying
the dutyes hereby granted to theire Majesties as they in theire discrec[i]ons shall thinke fitt: And the said Co[m]missioners
shall by the space of Thirty dayes before the said Eight and twentieth day of June which shall be in the yeare of
our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety four provide Six severall Markes or Stamps differing from each other
for the severall and respective dutyes hereby granted with which severall Markes or Stamps all Velum Paper and
Parchment upon which any of the severall and respective things herein before charged shall be ingrossed or written
shall be stampt and impressed (that is to say) One Stampe or Marke with which all Velum Paper and Parchment
herein before charged with the payment of Forty shillings for every Skinn Peice or Sheete shall be stampt or
markt: And one other Stampe or Marke with which all Vellum Parchment and Paper herein before charged
with the payment of Five shillings for every Skinn Sheete or Peice as aforesaid shall be marked and stamped:
One other Marke or Stampe with which all Vellum Parchment and Paper charged as aforesaid with the payment
of Two shillings and Six pence for every Skinn Sheete or Peice shall be markt and stampt and soe respectively
a different [Marke<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] or Stampe with which all Velum Paper and Parchment herein before charged with the payment
of the severall dutyes of Twelve pence Six pence and One penny shall be severally and differently markt and
stampt which said severall Markes and Stamps shall be published by Proclamac[i]on to be issued under the Greate
Seale of England a convenient time before the said Eight and twentieth day of June to the end that all persons
may have due notice thereof; And that the said Markes and Stamps or any of them shall or may be altered or
renewed from time to time as theire Majesties theire Heires or Successors shall thinke fitt soe as publicke Notificac[i]on
thereof be given by Proclamac[i]on as aforesaid:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Impression to be durable.</head>
			<para id="p90">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said Co[m]missioners in provideing the said Markes
or Stamps shall take care they be soe contrived that the Impression thereof may be durable and soe as the same
may be leaste lyable to be forged or counterfeited:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Parchment, &amp;c. to be stamped before written.</head>
			<para id="p91">And be it further enacted That all Vellum Parchment and Paper hereby intended to be charged with the
severall and respective dutyes aforesaid shall before any of the matters or things herein before menc[i]oned shall be
thereupon ingrossed or written be brought to the Head Office aforesaid or some other Sub-Co[m]missioner or Officer
to be appointed by the Co[m]missioners as herein is directed for that purpose to be stamped and marked and the said
Co[m]missioners Sub-Co[m]missioners and Officers aforesaid are hereby impowered and required forthwith upon demand
to them made by any person or persons to stampe or marke any quantities or parcells of Velum Parchment or
Paper he or they paying to such Officer or Officers as shall be appointed in that behalfe the respective dutyes
hereby directed to be paid for the same to stampe and marke the same accordingly without any other Fee or
Rewarde which Stampe or Marke shall be a sufficient discharge for the severall and respective Dutyes hereby
granted upon the said Velum Parchment or Paper which shall be soe stampt or markt:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Officer stamping before Duty paid.</head>
			<para id="p92">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p93">And be it further enacted That if any Co[m]missioner or other Officer to be appointed as aforesaid shall fix any
such Marke or Stampe to any Velum Parchment or Paper before the severall and respective dutyes thereupon
charged by this Act shall be duely answered and paid or be secured to be paid to theire Majesties use he shall
for every such Offence forfeite the su[m]me of One hundred Pounds one moiety thereof to theire Majesties and the
other moiety to him or them that shall informe or sue for the same in any of theire Majesties Courts of Record
by Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on wherein noe Essoigne Protecc[i]on Wager of Lawe or more then one Imparlance shall
be allowed:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Writing upon Paper before stamped, or stamped with too low a Duty;</head>
			<para id="p94">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;500; Officer, &amp;c. offending; Penalty; Attorney offending, Disability; No Instruments, &amp;c. written before Paper stamped good, till &pound;5 paid to the King and Money for the Stamp; Such Deed, &amp;c. not Evidence; Receipt for the same produced on Oath; Counterfeiting Stamp or selling, Felony</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p95">And be it further enacted That if any person or persons shall ingrosse or write or cause to be ingrossed or
written upon any Velum Parchment or Paper any of the matters or things for which the said Velum Parchment
or Paper is hereby charged to pay any Duty before such time as the said Velum Parchment or Paper shall be
marked or stamped as aforesaid or upon which there shall not be some Stampe or Marke resembling the same
or shall ingrosse or write or cause to be ingrossed or written any matter or thing upon any Velum Parchment
or Paper that shall be marked or stamped for any lower duty then the duty by this Act payable for what shall
be soe ingrossed or written such person soe offending shall for every such Offence forfeite the su[m]me of Five hundred
pounds one moiety thereof to theire Majesties and the other moiety to him or them that will informe or sue for
the same as aforesaid; And in case any Clerke Officer or Person who in respect of any publicke Office or
Employment is or shall be entituled or entrusted to make ingrosse or write any Records Deedes Instruments or
Writengs by this Act charged to pay a Duty as aforesaid shall be guilty of any Fraude or Practice to deceive
theire Majesties of any dutye by this Act payable by makeing ingrosseing or writeing any such Record Deede
Instrument or Writeing or causeing the same to be made ingrossed or written upon Velum Parchment or Paper
not marked or stamped according to this Act or upon which there shall not be some Stampe or Marke resembling
the same or upon Velum Parchment or Paper marked or stamped with any Marke or Stampe which he shall knowe
to be counterfeited or by ingrosseing or writeing any such Deede Instrument or other Writeing upon Velum
Parchment or Paper that shall be marked or stamped for a lower duty as aforesaid That then every such Clerke
Officer or Person soe guilty of any such Fraude or Practice and being thereof lawfully convicted shall (over and
above the penaltye aforesaid) forfeite his Office Place or Employment respectively and be disabled to hold or enjoye
the same for the future And if any Attorney belonging to any Courte whatsoever shall be guilty of any such
Fraude or Practice as aforesaid and be convicted thereof he shall be disabled for the future to practice as an Attorney;
And if any Deede Instrument or Writeing whatsoever by this Act charged with the payment of a duty as aforesaid
shall contrary to the true intente and meaneing thereof be written or ingrossed by any person or persons whatsoever
(not being a knowne Clerke or Officer who in respecte of any publicke Office or Imployment is or shall be
entituled to the makeing writeing or ingrosseing the same) upon Velum Parchment or Paper not marked or stamped
according to this Act or upon Velum Parchment or Paper marked or stamped for a lower duty as aforesaid that
then and in every such case there shall be due answered and paid to theire Majesties (over and above the dutye
aforesaid) for every such Deede Instrument or Writeing the su[m]me of Five pounds; And no such Record Deede
Instrument or Writeing shall be pleaded or given in Evidence in any Court or admitted in any Courte to be good
usefull or availeable in Lawe or Equitye untill aswell the said duty as the said su[m]me of Five pounds shall be
first paid to theire Majesties use and a Receipte produced for the same under the Hand or Hands of some of
theire Majesties Officers which shall be appointed to receive the dutyes above menc[i]oned and untill the Velum
Parchment or Paper on which such Deede Instrument or Writeing shall be written or made shall be marked or
stamped with a lawfull Marke or Stampe and theire Majesties Officer or Officers last menc[i]oned are hereby enjoyned
and required upon payment or tender of the said duty and su[m]me of Five pounds unto him or them to give a
Receipte for the same and to marke or stampe the said Velum Parchment or Paper with the Marke or Stampe
that shall be proper for such Deede Instrument or Writeing respectively and if any person or persons whatsoever
shall att any time or times hereafter counterfeite or forge any Stampe or Marke to resemble any Stampe or Marke
which shall be provided or made in pursuance of this Act or shall counterfeite or resemble the Impression of the
same upon any Velum Parchment or Paper thereby to defraude theire Majesties theire Heires and Successors of
any the dutyes hereby granted or shall utter vend or sell any Velum Parchment or Paper with such counterfeite
Marke or Impression thereupon knowing such Marke or Impression to be counterfeited then every such person soe
offending being thereof convicted in due Forme of Lawe shall be judged a Felon and shall suffer Death as in
cases of Felony without the Benefitt of Clergye:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Commissioners may appoint Observers in every Court, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p96">
				<emph type="i">Judges may make Orders; Officers to take an Oath</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p97">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the Co[m]missioners to be constituted by theire Majesties
theire Heires or Successors under the Greate Seale of England as aforesaid shall and may appointe a fitt person to
attend in any Courte or Office to take notice of the Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any the matters or
things aforesaid shall be ingrossed written or putt and of the markes or stamps thereupon and of all other matters
and things tending to secure their Majesties dutyes ariseing by this Act and that the Judges in the several Courts
and such others to whome it may appertaine att the requeste or requests of the said Co[m]missioners to be appointed
by theire Majesties as aforesaid or of any two or more of them shall make such Orders in the respective Courts
and doe such other matters and things for the better secureing of the said dutyes as shall be lawfully and
reasonably desired in that behalfe; And that every person who shall be co[m]missionated by theire Majesties and
every person to be employed by or under those comissionated by their Majesties for the markeing or stamping of
Velum Parchment or Paper as aforesaid before his acting in the markeing or stamping of the said Velum Parchment
or Paper shall take the Oath followeing (that is to say):-</para>
			<para id="p98">
				<emph type="i">The Oath</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p99">I A. B. doe swear That I will faithfully execute the trust reposed in me pursuant to an Act of Parliament entituled
An Act for granting to theire Majesties severall dutyes upon Velum Parchment and Paper for Four yeares towards
carrying on the Warr against France; without fraud or concealement and shall from time to time true account
make of my doeing therein and deliver the same to such person or persons as theire Majesties theire Heires or
Successors shall appointe to receive such account; and shall take noe fee reward or profitt for the execuc[i]on or
performance of the said Trust or the bussinesse relateing thereunto from any persons other then such as shall be
paid or allowed by theire Majesties theire Heires or Successors or by the Co[m]missioners of theire Majesties Treasury
or three of them now being or by the Treasurer of the Exchequer or three or more of the Co[m]missioners of the
Treasury for the time being:-</para>
			<para id="p100">
				<emph type="i">By whom administered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p101">Which Oath shall and may be administred to any such Co[m]missioner or Co[m]missioners by any Two or more of
the same Co[m]missioners which shall be appointed under the Greate Seale as aforesaid And any of the said Co[m]missioners
shall and may administer the like Oath (mutatis mutandis) to the Sub-Co[m]missioners or other persons which shall
be employed under them in the said businesse of marking or stamping:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Commissioners to observe the Orders of the Treasury;</head>
			<para id="p102">
				<emph type="i">to take care all Parts of the Kingdom have Parchment, &amp;c. at the usual Rates</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p103">And be it enacted That the said Co[m]missioners or Officers to be appointed by theire Majesties as aforesaid and
all Sub-Co[m]missioners and Officers to be employed or intrusted by or under them as aforesaid shall from time to
time in and for the better execuc[i]on of theire several Places and Trusts observe and performe such rules methods
and orders as they respectively shall from time to time receive from the said Co[m]missioners of the Treasury now
being or from the Treasurer of the Exchequer or Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time being And that the
said Co[m]missioners to be appointed by theire Majesties as aforesaid shall take especiall care that the severall parts
of this Kingdome and the Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede shall from time to [time<ref idref="n9">9</ref>]
be sufficiently furnished with Velum Parchment and Paper stamped or marked as aforesaid soe as theire Majesties
Subjects may have it in theire elecc[i]on to buy the same of the Officers or Persons to be employed by the said
Co[m]missioners att the usuall or most co[m]mon rates above the said Duty or to bring theire owne Velum Parchment
or Paper to be stampt as aforesaid or to furnish themselves or others that shall have done the same:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Proviso for Paupers.</head>
			<para id="p104">Provided alwaies and it is hereby further enacted That none of the rates imposic[i]ons or su[m]mes of money
before in this Act expressed shall be raised levyed collected or paid or payable unto theire Majesties by virtue
of this Act by any person or persons that shall be admitted to sue [or defend<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] in forma pauperis:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Records, &amp;c. writ as usual.</head>
			<para id="p105">And to the end theire Majesties may not be defrauded of any the dutyes hereby granted be it enacted
that all Records Writts Pleadings and other Proceedeings in Courts of Lawe and Equity and all Deedes Instruments
and Writeings whatsoever hereby charged shall be ingrossed and written in such manner as they have beene usually
accustomed to be written or are now written:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Upon Renewal of Marks those that have Paper marked by them shall have it changed within 60 Days.</head>
			<para id="p106">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;100; Paper not brought in within that time of no Use; Writing on such Paper; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p107">Provided alwaies and be it further enacted that as often as theire Majesties theire Heires or Successors shall
thinke fitt to alter or renewe the said Markes or Stamps or any of them it shall be lawfull for all persons who
shall att that time have in theire custody or possession any Velum Parchment or Paper marked with the Marke
or Stampe which shall be soe altered or renewed and upon which none of the matters or things hereby charged
shall be ingrossed or written att any time within the space of sixty dayes after such intenc[i]on of renewing or
altering shall be published by Proclamac[i]on as aforesaid to bring or send such Velum Parchment or Paper unto the
said Co[m]missioners to the Head Office in London or Westminster or to such other Officers as shall be appointed
as aforesaid; And the said Co[m]missioners and Officers respectively are hereby required to deliver or cause to be
delivered unto the severall persons who shall soe bring and deliver any quantity of Velum Parchment or Paper
the like quantity of Velum Parchment or Paper and as good in quality stampt with such newe Stampe or Marke
without demanding or takeing directly or indirectly for the same any su[m]me of money, or other considerac[i]on
whatsoever under the penalty of forfeiteing for every offence One hundred pounds to be sued for recovered and
divided in such manner as the other penalties in this Act are directed to be sued for recovered and divided; And
in case any person shall neglect or refuse within the time aforesaid to bring or cause to be brought and delivered
unto the said Co[m]missioners or Officers as aforesaid any such Velum Parchment or Paper the same is hereby declared
to be of noe [other<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] effecte or use then if it had never beene stampt and that all matters or things which
shall after that time be ingrossed or written thereon shall be of noe other effecte then if they had beene ingrossed
or written on Velum Parchment or Paper not marked or stampt at all And all persons who shall ingrosse or
write any the matters or things hereby charged on such Velum Parchment or Paper after the said time shall
forfeite and suffer as herein before is enacted for persons writeing or ingrosseing on Velum Parchment or Paper not
markt or stampt:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Credit of Loan for &pound;330,000 at &pound;8 per Cent.</head>
			<para id="p108">And be it enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any person or persons
Natives or Forreigners Bodies Politicke or Corporate to advance and lend to theire Majesties into the Receipte of theire
Exchequer upon the creditt of this Act any su[m]me or su[m]mes of money not exceedeing the su[m]me of Three hundred
and thirty thousand pounds in the whole and to have and receive for the forbearance of all such moneyes as
shall be lent interest not exceedeing the rate of Eight pounds per Centum per Annu[m]:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Officers to keep distinct Account and make weekly Payment.</head>
			<para id="p109">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p110">And be it further enacted and ordained by the authority aforesaid that all and every the Officer and Officers
who shall be concerned in the levying collecting and receiveing the dutyes ariseing by this Act doe keepe a
seperate and distinct account thereof and pay the same in specie into the Receipte of theire Majesties Exchequer
weekely, on Wednesday in every weeke unlesse it be an holy-day and then the next day after which shall not be
an holy-day; and upon neglect or refusall of the same shall incurr the penalties forfeitures damages and costs as
other the Officers of the Exchequer herein after menc[i]oned shall be lyable to which moneyes soe paid in shall be
applyed to the uses hereafter menc[i]oned in this Act and noe otherwise:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Distinct Books of Receipts in the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p111">
				<emph type="i">Tally and Order to the Lender; Orders registered and paid in course; Monies not to be diverted; Officer taking Fee or paying out of course; Penalty; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty; by Deputy; Penalty; Auditor, &amp;c. offending; Penalty; Penalties how recovered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p112">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that there shall be provided and kepte in theire Majesties
Exchequer (that is to say) in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt one booke in which all moneyes that shall
be paid into the Exchequer by virtue of this Act shall be entered and registered aparte and distincte from all other
moneyes paid or payable to theire Majesties upon any account whatsoever; and that all and every person and
persons Natives or Forreigners Bodyes Politicke or Corporate who shall lend any money to theire Majesties upon the
creditt of this Act and pay the same into the Receipte of the Exchequer shall imediately have a Tally of Loan
struck for the same and an Order for his or theire repayment beareing the same date with the Tally in which
Order shall [also be<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] contained a warrant for payment of interest for forbearance not exceedeing the rates aforesaid
for his or theire considerac[i]on to be paid every three months untill the repayment of his or theire principall;
And that all Orders for repayment of money shall be registered in course according to the date of the Tally
respectively without p[re]ference of one before another; And that all and every person and persons shall be paid in
course according as theire Orders shall stand registered in the said booke soe as that the person Native or Forreigner
his or theire Executors Administrators or Assignes who shall have his her or theire Order or Orders first entered
in the said Booke shall be taken and accounted as the first person to be paid upon the moneys to come in by
virtue of this Act and he or they who shall have his or theire Order or Orders next entered shall be taken
and accounted to be the second person to be paid and soe successively and in course; and that the moneys to
come in by this Act shall be in the same order lyable to the satisfacc[i]on of the said respective Parties theire
Executors Administrators or Assignes successively without p[re]ference of one before another and not otherwise and
not to be divertible to any other use intent or purpose whatsoever And that noe Fee Reward or Gratuity directly
or indirectly be demanded or taken of any of theire Majesties Subjects for provideing or makeing any such Bookes
Registers Entries [Views<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] or Search as aforesaid or in or for the payment of moneye lent or the interest as aforesaid
by any of theire Majesties Officer or Officers theire Clerks or Deputyes on paine of payment of treble damages
to the party greived, by the party offending with Costs of Suite or if the Officer himselfe take or demand any
such Fee or Reward then to lose his place alsoe; And if any undue p[re]ferrence of one before another shall be
made either in pointe of registry or payment contrary to the true meaneing of this Act by any such Officer or
Officers then the party offending shall be lyable by Acc[i]on of Debt or on the Case to pay the value of the debt
damages and costs to the party greived and shall be forejudged from his place or office; And if such p[re]ference
be unduely made by his Deputy or Clerke without direcc[i]on or privitye of his Master then such Deputy or
Clerke only shall be lyable to such Acc[i]on Debt Damages and Costs and shall be for ever after uncapable of
his place or office And in case the Auditor shall not directe or the Clerke of the Pells record or the Teller
make payment according to each persons due place and order as afore directed then he or they shall be judged
to forfeite and theire respective Deputies and Clerks herein offending to be liable to such Acc[i]on Debt Damages
and Costs in such manner as aforesaid; All which said penalties forfeitures damages and costs to be incurred
by any of the Officers aforesaid or any theire Deputyes or Clerks shall and may be recovered by Acc[i]on of
Debt Bill Plainte or Informac[i]on in any of theire Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster wherein noe
Essoign Protecc[i]on Privilege Wager of Lawe Injuncc[i]on or Order of Restrainte shall be in any wise granted or
allowed:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. What shall not be Preference.</head>
			<para id="p113">Provided alwaies and be it hereby declared That if it happen that severall Tallyes of Loan or Orders of Payment
as aforesaid beare date or be brought the same day to the Auditor of the receipte to be registered then it shall
be interpretted noe undue p[re]ference which of those he enters first soe he enters them all the same day:- Provided
alsoe that it shall not be interpreted any undue p[re]ference to incurr any penaltye in point of payment if the
Auditor direct and the Clerke of the Pells record and the Teller do pay subsequent Orders of persons that come
and demand theire moneye and bring theire Order before other persons that did not come and demand theire money
and bring theire Order in their course soe as there may be soe much money reserved as will satisfie p[re]cedent
Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kepte for them (interest upon Loan being to cease from the
time the money is soe reserved and kepte in Banke for them):-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Orders assignable.</head>
			<para id="p114">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee; Assignee may assign</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p115">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every person or persons to whome any moneys shall
be due by virtue of this Act after Order entered in the Booke of Register aforesaid for payment thereof his
Executors Administrators or Assignes by endorsment of his Order may assigne and transferre his Right Title
Interest and Benefitt of such Order or any parte thereof to any other which being notified in the Office of the
Auditor of Receipte aforesaid and an Entry or Memoriall thereof alsoe made in the Booke of Register aforesaid for
Orders which the Officer shall upon Request without Fee or Charge accordingly make) shall entitule such Assignee
his Executors Administrators or Assignes to the Benefitt thereof and payment thereon; And such Assignee may in
like manner assigne againe and soe toties quoties and afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person or
persons who have or hath made such Assignments to make void release or discharge the same or any the moneys
thereby due or any parte [there<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Provision for Salaries.</head>
			<para id="p116">Provided alwaies and be it enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for theire Majesties theire Heires
and Successors out of the dutyes ariseing by this Act to cause such su[m]me and su[m]mes of money to be expended
and paid from time to time for Salaries and other incident Charges as shall be necessary in and for the receiveing
collecting levying or manageing of the same duties dureing the said terme therein by this Act granted any thing
in this Act conteined to the contrary notwithstanding:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Proclamation of Renewal to be within 20 Days.</head>
			<para id="p117">
				<emph type="i">Penalty upon Officers not publishing it</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p118">Provided alwaies and be it further enacted That as often as theire Majesties theire Heires or Successors shall
thinke fitt to alter the said Stamps or any of them that the Proclamac[i]on which is hereby directed to be made for
giveing to all persons due notice thereof shall within Twenty dayes after the date thereof be sent to the Mayor
Cheife Magistrate or other Head Officer of every City Corporac[i]on Borough and Markett Towne throughout the
Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede which Officers respectively shall
cause the same to be published to the Inhabitants of such City Corporac[i]on or Towne either on the next markett
day or next Sunday in the Church imediately after the time of Divine Service upon paine of forfeiting the su[m]me
of Two hundred pounds to be sued for by Accon of Debt Bill Plainte or Informac[i]on in any of theire Majesties
Courts of Record att Westminster wherein noe Essoign Protecc[i]on Wager of Lawe Priviledge or more then one
Imparlance shall be granted or allowed the one moiety of which Forfeiture to be to theire Majesties the other
moietye to such person who shall sue for the same:-</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. The Auditor of the Imprest to take the Accounts of the Commissioners, &amp;c. annually upon Oath.</head>
			<para id="p119">
				<emph type="i">The Accounts declared before the Treasurer, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p120">And be it enacted That the Co[m]missioners Receiver or Receivers Generall or other person or persons who are
or shall be respectively employed in the directing receiveing collecting or paying the severall Imposic[i]ons upon
Paper and Parchment and other Duties by this Act granted shall and are hereby required betweene the Eight and
twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety five and the Nine and twentieth Day of September
following and soe from yeare to yeare yearely att those times dureing the continuance of this Act to exhibitt theire
respective Accounts thereof to theire Majesties Auditors of the Imprest for the time being or one of them who
shall and are hereby from time to time respectively authorized to examine upon Oath the said Co[m]missioners
Receiver or Receivers Generall or other Person or Persons Accomptants which shall be employed in raiseing
receiveing or collecting the said Imposic[i]ons and Dutyes of what su[m]me or su[m]mes of money was or were by them
or any of them respectively raised collected or received within the time of such theire Accounts and likewise
what parte thereof [was<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] by them or any of them paid into theire Majesties receipte of Exchequer or by virtue
of any Warrant of Privye Seale or Warrant of the Lord High Treasurer or Co[m]missioners of theire Majesties
Treasury for the time being otherwise paid and to whome and for what service or services; And in makeing the
said Accounts to and before the said Auditors or one of them they are to produce proper Vouchers for every
su[m]me or su[m]mes of money soe by them or any of them raised received and paid according to the antient methods
of the Exchequer; And to the end that it may appeare upon Record what the su[m]mes amounted to in the yeare
for which such account or accounts are or shall be respectively made and what thereof was paid and to whome
and for what use and service uses and services as aforesaid and what remaines unpaid and rests insuper upon each
[respective<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Receiver and Collector the (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) accounts soe to be taken by every of the said Auditors respectively is
and are to be declared before the Lord Treasurer or Lords Co[m]missioners of the Treasury and Chancellor of the
Exchequer now and for the time being according to the Course of the Exchequer in such Cases:-</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">be also <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">View <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">thereof <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">account or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


