<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46410" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVI. An Act for the Importation of Salt-Petre for One Yeare [Rot. Parl. pt. 6. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Saltpetre importable in English Bottoms.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Selling Saltpetre for above &pound;70 per Ton; ; Penalty.; Duty as from the East Indies</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Forasmuch as in time of Warr especially care ought to bee taken that there may bee a sufficient quantity
of Salt-Petre in this Kingdome for the use of their Majesties Ships of Warr and Army and alsoe that
Merchants may bee furnished with Gunpowder for the use of their Ships att reasonable rates Be it. enacted by
the King and Queens most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and
Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That it shall and
may bee lawfull for any of their Majesties Subjects to import and bring Salt-Petre into this Kingdome from any
Place or Countrey now in amity with their Majesties for the space of One yeare to bee computed from and after
the Five and twentieth day of March which shall bee in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety
foure any Law or Statute heretofore made to the contrary notwithstanding Provided such Salt-Petre bee brought
in onely in such Ships or Vessells as are English built and noe other. Provided That noe person or persons
importing Salt-Petre by virtue of this Act nor any retailer shall sell any part of the Salt-Petre soe to bee imported
att above the price of Seventy pounds per Tun not exceeding Eighteen per Centum refraction upon the penalty
of Fifty pounds per Tun and so for any greater or lesser quantity to bee recovered by action of debt bill
plaint or information in any of their Majesties Courts att Westminster wherein noe essoign protection priveledge
or wager of law shall bee allowed nor any more then one imparlance the one moiety thereof to bee for the use of
their Majesties and the other moiety for the informer. Provided alsoe that the Salt Petre which shall bee imported
by virtue of this Act shall pay to their Majesties the same duty as if the same were directly imported from
the East-Indies.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Mingling Saltpetre and selling at above &pound;70 per Ton;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">or bartering for above that rate; ; taken to be an undue Sale</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And for preventing all Frauds which may bee used in selling any Salt-Petre imported by virtue of this Act
att above the rate of Seventy pounds per Tun Bee it enacted That if any person or persons shall mingle any
Salt-Petre imported by virtue of this Act with any other Salt-Petre and sell the same soe mingled att above the
rate of Seventy pounds per Tun or shall by way of barter or exchange take or agree to take any other
Co[m]modity for Salt-Petre imported by virtue of this Act (whether by it selfe or mingled with other Salt Petre)
in any manner soe as to have or receive for the same more then the rate of Seventy pounds per Tu[n]n accounting
the Co[m]modity so taken in exchange att the then current price that the sale of such Salt-Petre soe mingled and
alsoe such barter or exchange shall each of them bee construed and taken to bee a sale contrary to this Act.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


