<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46421" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act for the frequent Meeting and calling of Parliaments. [Rot. Parl. pt. 1. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>Parliament to be held once in Three Years at the least.</head>
<para id="p1">Whereas by the ancient Laws and Statutes of this Kingdome frequent Parliaments ought to bee held
And whereas frequent and new Parliaments tend very much to the happy union and good agreement of the
King and People Wee your Majesties most loyal and obedient Subjects the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and
Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled doe most humbly beseech your most excellent Majesties that it may
bee declared and enacted in this present Parliament and it is hereby declared and enacted by the King and Queens
most excellent Majesties by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in
this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That from henceforth a Parliament shall bee
holden once in Three years att the least.</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Writs to be issued once in Three Years.</head>
<para id="p2">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That within Three yeares att the farthest from and after
the Dissolution of this present Parliament and soe from time to time for ever hereafter within Three yeares att the
farthest from and after the determination of every other Parliament Legal Writts under the Great Seal shall bee
issued by directions of your Majesties your Heires and Successors for calling assembling and holding another new
Parliament.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. No Parliament to continue longer than Three Years.</head>
<para id="p3">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That from henceforth noe Parliament whatsoever that shall
att any time hereafter bee called assembled or held shall have any continuance longer then for Three yeares onely
att the farthest to bee accounted from the day on which by the Writts of Su[m]mons the said Parliament shall bee
appointed to meet.</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>IV. Present Parliament to cease 1st Nov. 1696.</head>
<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That this present Parliament shall cease and determine on
the First day of November which shall bee in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety six
unlesse their Majesties shall think fitt to dissolve it sooner.</para>
</section>
</section>
</report>


