<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46428" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
<subtitle>Chapter IX. An Act for appointing and enableing Commissioners to examine take and state the Publick Accounts. [Rot. Parl. pt. 3. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">Names of Commissioners for taking the Public Accounts.; 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 11.; 4 &amp; 5 (4) W. &amp; M. c. 11.; 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 23.; The said Acts, so far as not hereby altered, revived and continued for One Year.; Treasury to issue and pay Allowances to Clerks, &amp;c. as by 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 11.; Commissioners to take Accounts of Monies granted by c. 3. ante, and of all other Monies granted in the present Session, and of all other Public Money payable as herein mentioned,; unaccounted for in pursuance of the aforesaid Act, or the last Clause in 3 W. &amp; M. c. 6</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">For the better knowledge exa[m]i[n]ac[i]on and stating the Accounts of the Receipts Issues and Distribution of
the Publick Revenue of the Crowne of England and the Dominions and Territories thereunto belonging and
the due Encouragement of the People of this Realme to pay the Taxes and Payments by Act of Parliament
imposed on them for the maintenance and prosecution of the present Warr against France and the Support of
His Majesties Government. Bee it enacted by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent
of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of
the same That Robert Harley Esq[uire] Sir Thomas Clarges Knight Henry Boyle Esq[uire] Charles Hutchinson Esq[uire] Sir
Thomas Pope Blount Barronett Sir John Thompson Barronett and Paul Foley Esq[uire] Speaker of the House of
Commons shall bee and are hereby constituted Commissioners for examining taking and stating [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the Accounts
of all money of the said Publick Revenue of the Crowne and all other Accounts which were by one Act of
Parliament made in the Second Yeare of the Reigne of King William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for
appointing and enabling Commissioners to examine take and state the publick Accounts of the Kingdome And
one other Act made in the Fourth and Fifth Yeares of the Reigne of King William and Queen Mary intituled
An Act for examining taking and stating the publick Accounts of this Kingdom And one other Act made in
the Fifth and Sixth Yeares of their said Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for appointing and enableing Commissioners
to examine take and state the publick Accounts of the Kingdome to bee taken ex&amacr;&imacr;ed and stated by the respective
Commissioners by the said Acts or any of them constituted or any Five Foure or more of them respectively
authorized by virtue of the same or any of them And that the said Acts &amp; every Clause Matter and Thing
therein contained not hereby altered shall bee and are hereby revived and continued in full force and virtue to
all intents constructions and purposes whatsoever from the Foure and twentieth day of April in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred ninety five to the Five and twentieth day of April which shall bee in the yeare
of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and six And shall bee executed with all the powers and authorities
in them and every of them respectively contained by the Commissioners herein named or any Foure or more of
them And that the Lords Commissioners of the Tresury or Lord High Tresurer of England for the time being
shall and are hereby authorized and required to issue and pay or cause to bee issued and paid the like yearely
allowances for payment of Clerks and other Charges as are in the first recited Act directed and the like
quarterly payments to every of the said Commissioners hereby constituted as are appointed to bee paid to the
Commissioners therein named And the said Co[m]missioners by this Act constituted as aforesaid or any Foure or
more of them shall and are hereby impowered to take Accounts of all moneys granted to His Majestie by one
Act made in this p[re]sent Session of P[er]liament intituled An Act for granting to His Majestie an Aid of Foure
Shillings in the pound for One Yeare and for applying the yearely su[m]m of Three hundred thousand pounds
for Five yeares out of the Duties of Tunnage and Poundage and other su[m]ms of money payable upon Merchandizes
exported and imported for carrying on the Warr against France with vigour and of all other moneys that have
been or shall bee granted to His Majesty in this present Session of Parliament And of all other His Majesties
Treasure or other publick money due or payable to their said Majesties on the Fifth day of November One
thousand six hundred eighty eight or to their said Majesties or either of them att any time between the said Fifth
day of November and the said [Twenty fifth<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] day of April which shall bee in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred ninety and six not yet accounted for by virtue or in pursuance of the said recited Acts or either of
them or the last Clause touching publick Accounts made and enacted in one Act made in the Third yeare of
the Reigne of their said Majesties King William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for raising money by a Poll
payable quarterly for one yeare for the carrying on a vigorous War against France.</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Two of the said Commissioners, before they execute the Office, to take the following Oath; and the other Commissioners to take the same Oath before the said Two Commissioners.</head>
<para id="p3">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That Two of the said Commissioners first named in this
Act before they enter upon the Execution of the same shall take an Oath before the Chancellor of the Exchequer
or Master of the Rolls for the time being which they and either of them are hereby respectively authorized and
required to administer to them the Tenor whereof shall bee as followeth (that is to say.<br/>
I. A. B. doe sweare That according to the best of my Skill and Knowledge I shall faithfully impartially and truely
demeane my selfe in examining and taking the Accounts of all such su[m]m or su[m]ms of money and other
things brought or to bee brought before mee in execution of one Act intituled An Act for appointing and
enableing Commissioners to examine take and state the publick Accounts according to the tenor and purport of
the said Act.<br/>
And every other of the said Commissioners hereby constituted before hee enters upon the Execution of the said
Act shall likewise take the same Oath before the said Two Commissioners herein first named who are hereby
authorized and required to administer the same unto them after they shall themselves have taken the said Oath as
aforesaid.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">Five and twentieth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


