<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46425" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for granting to his Majesty certaine rates and duties upon Marriages Births and Burials and upon Batchelors and Widowers for the terme of Five yeares for carrying on the Warr against France with Vigour. [Chapter VI. Rot. Parl. pt. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Duties upon Burials for Five Years</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee your Majesties most dutiful and loyal Subjects the Commons in Parliament assembled from a deep
sence of the many great occasions which engage your Majesty in many extraordinary expences for the
necessary defence of your Realmes and the prosecution of a Warr against France with Vigour have cheerfully and
unanimously given and granted unto your Majestie as an additional supply and aid the rates duties impositions
and su[m]ms of money herein after mentioned And wee most humbly beseech your Majesty that it may bee enacted.
and bee it enacted by the Kings most excellent Majesty by and with the advice and consent of the Lords
Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That
from and after the first day of May in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred ninety [and<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] five for
and dureing the terme of five yeares to commence and bee accounted from the said first day of May and noe longer
there shall be raised levied and paid to his Majesty his heires and successors (over and above all other duties
whatsoever) for and upon the burial of all persons who shall bee buried within the said terme of five yeares att
any place within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed the several
and respective duties and su[m]ms of money herein after mentioned (that is to say.)</para>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Duty on Burials of of all Persons; and further, on the Burial of a Duke; Duchess</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">For and upon the burial of every person the su[m]m of Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p5">And for and upon the burial of every person of the degree of a Duke of England Scotland or Ireland the su[m]m
of Fifty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p6">And for and upon the burial of every Dutchesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes the like su[m]m of Fifty
pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p7">
			<emph type="i">Marquess and Marchioness</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p8">And for and upon the burial of every person of the degree of a Marquesse or Marchionesse of any of the
said Three Kingdomes the su[m]m of Forty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p9">
			<emph type="i">Earl and Countess</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p10">And for and upon the burial of every person of the degree of an Earle or Countesse of any of the said Three
Kingdomes the su[m]m of Thirty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p11">
			<emph type="i">Viscount and Viscountess</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p12">And for and upon the burial of every person of the degree of a Viscount or Viscountesse of any of the said
Three Kingdomes the su[m]m of Five and twenty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p13">
			<emph type="i">Baron and Baroness</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p14">And for and upon the burial of every person of the degree of a Baron or Baronesse of any of the said Three
Kingdomes the su[m]m of Twenty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p15">
			<emph type="i">Eldest Son of a Duke, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p16">And for and upon the burial of every eldest son of a Duke of any of the said Three Kingdomes or his wife
the su[m]m of Thirty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p17">
			<emph type="i">Younger Son of a Duke, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p18">And for and upon the burial of every younger son of a Duke of any of the said Three Kingdomes or his
wife the su[m]m of Five and twenty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p19">
			<emph type="i">Eldest Son of a Marquis, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p20">And for and upon the burial of every eldest son of a Marquesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes or his wife
the su[m]m of Five and twenty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p21">
			<emph type="i">Younger Son of a Marquis, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p22">And for and upon the burial of every younger [son<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of a Marquesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes
or his wife the su[m]m of Twenty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p23">
			<emph type="i">Eldest Son of an Earl, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p24">And for and upon the burial or every eldest son of an Earle of any of the said Three Kingdomes or his wife
the su[m]m of Twenty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p25">
			<emph type="i">Younger Son of an Earl, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p26">And for and upon the burial of every younger son of an Earle of any of the said Three Kingdomes or his
wife the su[m]m of Fifteen pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p27">
			<emph type="i">Eldest Son of a Viscount, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p28">And for and upon the burial of every eldest son or a Viscount of any or the said Three Kingdomes or his wife
the su[m]m of Seventeen pounds [and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Tenne shillings over and above the said Foure shillings.</para>
		<para id="p29">
			<emph type="i">Younger Son of a Viscount, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p30">And for and upon the burial of every younger son of a Viscount of any of the said Three Kingdomes or his
wife the su[m]m of Thirteen pounds six shillings and eight pence over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p31">
			<emph type="i">Eldest Son of a Baron, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p32">And for and upon the burial of every eldest son of a Baron of any of the said Three Kingdomes or his wife
the su[m]m of Fifteene pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p33">
			<emph type="i">Younger Son of a Baron, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p34">And for and upon the burial of every younger [sonn<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of a Baron of any of the said Three Kingdomes or his
wife the su[m]m of Twelve pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p35">
			<emph type="i">Unmarried Daughter of a Duke;</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p36">And for and upon the burial of every unmarried daughter of a Duke of any of the said Three Kingdomes the
su[m]m of Five and twenty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p37">
			<emph type="i">of a Marquis;</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p38">And for and upon the burial of every unmarried daughter of a Marquesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes
the su[m]m of Twenty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p39">
			<emph type="i">of an Earl</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p40">And for and upon the burial of every unmarried daughter of an Earle of any of the said Three Kingdomes the
su[m]m of Fifteene pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p41">
			<emph type="i">of a Viscount</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p42">And for and upon the burial of every unmarried daughter of [a<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Viscount of any of the said Three Kingdomes
the su[m]m of Thirteen pounds six shillings and eight pence over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p43">
			<emph type="i">of a Baron</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p44">And for and upon the burial of every unmarried daughter of a Baron of any of the said Three Kingdomes the
su[m]m of Twelve pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p45">
			<emph type="i">Widow of a Duke</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p46">And for and upon the burial of every widdow of a Duke of any of the said Three Kingdomes the su[m]m of
Fifty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p47">
			<emph type="i">of a Marquis</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p48">And for and upon the burial of every widdow of a Marquesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes the su[m]m of
Forty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p49">
			<emph type="i">of an Earl</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p50">And for and upon the burial of every widdow of an Earle of any of the said Three Kingdomes the su[m]m of
Thirty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p51">
			<emph type="i">of a Viscount</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p52">And for and upon the burial of every widdow of a Viscount of any of the said Three Kingdomes the su[m]m
of Five and twenty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p53">
			<emph type="i">of a Baron</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p54">And for for and upon the burial of every widdow of a Baron of any of the said Three Kingdomes the su[m]m of
Twenty pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p55">
			<emph type="i">On the Burial of a Baronet, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p56">And for and upon the burial of every person of the degree of a Baronett of any of the said Three Kingdomes
or of Nova Scotia or his wife the su[m]m of Fifteene pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p57">
			<emph type="i">Knight of the Bath, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p58">And for and upon the burial of every person that is a Knight of the Order of the Bath or his wife the su[m]m
of Fifteene pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p59">
			<emph type="i">Knight Bachelor, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p60">And for and upon the burial of every person who is a Knight Batchelor or his wife the su[m]m of Tenne pounds
over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p61">
			<emph type="i">King's Sergeant</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p62">And for and upon the burial of every Serjeant att Law being the Kings Serjeant the su[m]m of Twenty pounds
over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p63">
			<emph type="i">Wife of King's Sergeant</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p64">And for and upon the burial of the wife of every Kings Serjeant the su[m]m of Tenne pounds over and above
the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p65">
			<emph type="i">Sergeant at Law</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p66">And for and upon the burial of every other Serjeant att Law the su[m]m of Fifteen pounds over and above the
said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p67">
			<emph type="i">Wife of a Sergeant</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p68">And for and upon the burial of every such other Serjeants wife the su[m]m of Seven pounds and Tenne shillings
over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p69">
			<emph type="i">An Esquire, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p70">And for and upon the burial of every person of the degree of an Esquire or soe reputed or owneing or writeing
himselfe such or his wife the su[m]m of Five pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p71">
			<emph type="i">A Gentleman, or his Wife</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p72">And for and upon the burial of every Gentleman or reputed Gentleman or owneing or writeing himselfe such
or his wife the su[m]m of Twenty shillings over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p73">
			<emph type="i">Younger Children of Baronets, &amp;c. and their Wives</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p74">And for and upon the burial of every younger child of Barronetts Knights of the Bath Knights Batchelors
Serjeants att law Esquires or Gentlemen or reputed Esquires or Gentlemen or owneing or writeing themselves
such and their wives the su[m]m of Twenty shillings over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p75">
			<emph type="i">Widow, of a Baronet</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p76">And for and upon the burial of every widdow of a Baronett the su[m]m of Fifteen pounds over and above the
said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p77">
			<emph type="i">of a Knight of the Bath</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p78">And for and upon the burial of every widdow of every Knight of the Bath the su[m]m of Fifteene pounds over
and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p79">
			<emph type="i">Widow of a Knight Bachelor</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p80">And for and upon the burial of every widdow of a Knight Batchelor the su[m]m of Tenne pounds over and
above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p81">
			<emph type="i">of the King's Sergeant</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p82">And for and upon the burial of every widdow of every Serjeant att Law being the Kings Serjeant the su[m]m
of Tenne pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p83">
			<emph type="i">of a Sergeant at Law</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p84">And for and upon the burial of every widdow of every other Serjeant att law the su[m]m of Seven pounds and
Tenne shillings over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p85">
			<emph type="i">of an Esquire</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p86">And for and upon the burial of every widdow of an Esquire or reputed Esq[uire] or soe owneing or writeing
himselfe as such the su[m]m of Five pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p87">
			<emph type="i">of a Gentleman</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p88">And for and upon the burial of every widdow of every Gentleman or reputed Gentleman or soe owneing or
writeing himselfe as such the su[m]m Twenty shillings over and above the the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p89">
			<emph type="i">on the Burial of an Archbishop</emph>,</para>
		<para id="p90">And for and upon the burial of every person of the order and degree of an Arch-Bishopp the su[m]m of Fifty
pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p91">
			<emph type="i">or his Wife or Widow</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p92">And for and upon the burial of every Arch-Bishopps wife or widdow the su[m]m of Tenne pounds over and above
the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p93">
			<emph type="i">of a Bishop</emph>,</para>
		<para id="p94">And for and upon the burial of every person of the degree and order of a Bishopp the su[m]m of Twenty
pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p95">
			<emph type="i">or his Wife or Widow</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p96">And for and upon the burial of every wife or widdow of every Bishopp the su[m]m of Five pounds over and
above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p97">
			<emph type="i">of a Dean</emph>,</para>
		<para id="p98">And for and upon the burial of every person of the degree of a Deane of any Cathedral or Collegiate Church
the su[m]m of Tenne pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p99">
			<emph type="i">or his Wife or Widow</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p100">And for and upon the burial of every wife or widdow of every Dean the su[m]m of Two pounds tenne shillings
over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p101">
			<emph type="i">of an Archdeacon</emph>,</para>
		<para id="p102">And for and upon the burial of every person of the degree of an Arch-Deacon the su[m]m of Two pounds tenne
shillings over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p103">
			<emph type="i">or his Wife or Widow</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p104">And for and upon the burial of the wife or widdow of every Arch-Deacon the su[m]m of Twenty shillings over
and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p105">
			<emph type="i">of a Canon or Prebendary</emph>,</para>
		<para id="p106">And for and upon the burial of every person of the degree of a Canon or Prebendary of any Cathedral or
Collegiate Church the su[m]m of Two pounds tenne shillings over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p107">
			<emph type="i">or his Wife or Widow</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p108">And for and upon the burial of the wife or widdow of every Canon or Prebendary the su[m]m of Twenty shillings
over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p109">
			<emph type="i">of a Doctor of Divinity, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p110">And for and upon the burial of every Person of the degree of a Doctor of Divinity Law or Physick the su[m]m of
Five pounds over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p111">
			<emph type="i">or Wife or Widow</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p112">And for and upon the burial of the wife or widdow of every such Doctor of Divinity Law or Physick the su[m]m
of Twenty shillings over and above the said Foure shillings</para>
		<para id="p113">
			<emph type="i">of Sons and Daughters of Archbishops, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p114">And for and upon the burial of every son or daughter of an Arch-Bishopp [Bishopp<emph type="p">1</emph>] Deane Arch Deacon Canon
Prebendary Doctor of Divinity Law or Physick the su[m]m of Twenty shillings over and above the said Foure
shillings</para>
		<para id="p115">
			<emph type="i">of Persons having a Real Estate of &pound;50 per Annum, or Personal Estate of &pound;600 and upwards; or their Wives, Widows, or Children</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p116">And for and upon the burial of every person haveing a real estate of the value of Fifty pounds per annum or
upwards or a personal estate of the value of Six hundred pounds or upwards and not otherwise hereby charged
under any of the ranks orders qualifications or degrees herein before mentioned the su[m]m of Twenty shillings over
and above the said Foure shillings And for and upon the burial of the wife or widdow child or children of every
such person haveing such real or personal estate as aforesaid the su[m]m of Tenne shillings over and above the said
Foure shillings</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The said Duties payable by Heirs, &amp;c. before any other Debts;</head>
			<para id="p117">
				<emph type="i">levied by Distress; By whom Duties on Burial of Infants, paid; on the Burial of Wives</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p118">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the several and respective duties and su[m]ms of money
granted as aforesaid upon the burials of the several persons before mentioned as the same shall severally become
due and payable shall bee answered and paid to his Majesty his Heires and Successors for the aforesaid terme of
Five yeares by the respective heires executors or administrators of every such person soe buried as aforesaid before
any other debts or duties whatsoever And in default of payment thereof to the Collectors of the said duty upon
demand the same shall bee charged upon and levied by distresse upon the lands tenements and hereditaments or
the goods and chattels of the persons soe buried in such manner as herein after is directed and the respective
duties hereby charged upon the burial of any person who shall att the time of his or her death be under the
age of One and twenty yeares shall bee answered and paid by the father of such person (if liveing att the time
of the death of such person under age) and if the father bee then dead by the mother if she bee then liveing or
otherwise by the Guardian Trustee Executor or Administrator of such person and the duty charged upon the burial
of any wife shall bee paid by the husband of such wife.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Duties on Births for Five Years.</head>
			<para id="p119">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That from and after the said First day of May for
and dureing the terme of Five yeares and noe longer there shall bee raised levied and paid to his Majesty his
Heires and Successors for and upon the birth of every person (except as herein after is excepted) who shall bee
borne within the said terme of Five yeares att any place within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or
Towne of Berwick upon Tweed the several and respective duties and su[m]ms of money herein after mentioned (that
is to say.)</para>
			<para id="p120">
				<emph type="i">Duty on Births of all Persons, (Exception)</emph>,</para>
			<para id="p121">For and upon the birth of every person and child (except the child or children of such as receive Alms) the
sum of Two shillings</para>
			<para id="p122">
				<emph type="i">and further on the Birth of Eldest Son of a Duke; and every other Child, &amp;c. by any other Husband</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p123">And for and upon the birth of every eldest son of every person of the degree of a Duke of England Scotland
or Ireland or of his wife by any other husband after his death the su[m]m of Thirty pounds over and above the
said Two shillings And for and upon the birth of every other son or daughter of such Duke or his wife by
any other husband after his death the sum of Five and twenty pounds over and above the said Two shillings</para>
			<para id="p124">
				<emph type="i">the Eldest Son of a Marquis, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p125">And for and upon the birth of every eldest son of every person of the degree of a Marquesse of any of the
said Three Kingdomes or of his wife by any other husband after his death the su[m]m of Five and twenty pounds
over and above the said Two shillings</para>
			<para id="p126">
				<emph type="i">and every other Child, &amp;c.</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p127">And for and upon the birth of every [other<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] son or daughter of such Marquesse or of his wife by any
other husband after his death the su[m]m of Twenty pounds over and above the said Two shillings</para>
			<para id="p128">
				<emph type="i">of the Eldest Son of an Earl; and every other Child, &amp;c.</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p129">And for and upon the birth of every eldest son of every person of the degree of an Earle of any of the said
Three Kingdomes or of his wife by any other husband after his death the su[m]m of Twenty pounds over &amp; above
the said Two shillings And for and upon the birth of every other son or daughter of such Earle or of his
wife by any other husband after his death the su[m]m of Fifteene pounds over and above the said Two shillings</para>
			<para id="p130">
				<emph type="i">of the Eldest Son of a Viscount; and every other Child, &amp;c.</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p131">And for and upon the birth of the eldest son of every person of the degree of a Viscount of any of the said
Three Kingdomes or of his wife by any other husband after his death the su[m]m of Seventeen pounds Tenne
shillings over and above the said Two shillings And for and upon the birth of every other son or daughter of
such Viscount or of his wife by any other husband after his death the su[m]m of Thirteen pounds six shillings and
eight pence over and above the said Two shillings</para>
			<para id="p132">
				<emph type="i">of the Eldest Son of a Baron; and every other Child, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p133">And for and upon the birth of every eldest son of every person of the degree of a Baron of any of the said
Three Kingdomes or of his wife by any other husband after his death the sum of Fifteen pounds over and above
the said Two shillings And for and upon the birth of every other son or daughter of such Baron or of his
wife by any other husband after his death the su[m]m of Twelve pounds over and above the said Two shillings</para>
			<para id="p134">
				<emph type="i">the Eldest Son of a Baronet, &amp;c.</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p135">And for and upon the birth of every eldest son of every person of the degree of a Barronett Knight of the
Order of the Bath or Knight Batchelor the su[m]m of Five pounds over and above the said Two shillings</para>
			<para id="p136">
				<emph type="i">of the Eldest Son of a Sergeant, &amp;c.</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p137">And for and upon the birth of every eldest son of a Serjeant att Law Esquire or Gentleman the su[m]m of Twenty
shillings over and above the said Two shillings</para>
			<para id="p138">
				<emph type="i">of Younger Children of Baronets, &amp;c.</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p139">And for and upon the birth of every younger son or daughter of Baronetts Knights of the Bath Knights
Batchelors Serjeants att Law Esquires or Gentlemen or soe reputed or owneing or writeing themselves as such the
su[m]m of Twenty shillings over and above the said Two shillings</para>
			<para id="p140">
				<emph type="i">of Children of Archbishops, &amp;c.</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p141">And for and upon the birth of every son or daughter of an Arch-Bishopp Bishopp Deane Arch-Deacon Canon
Prebendary Doctor of Divinity Law or Physick the sum of Twenty shillings over and above the said Two
shillings</para>
			<para id="p142">
				<emph type="i">of Children of Persons of Real Estate of &pound;50 per Annum, and Personal Estate of &pound;600 and upwards</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p143">And for and upon the birth of every son or daughter of every person haveing a real Estate of the value of
Fifty pounds per Annum or upwards or a personal Estate of the value of Six hundred pounds or upwards and
not hereby otherwise charged under any of the Ranks Orders Qualifications or Degrees herein before mentioned
the su[m]m of Tenne shillings over and above the said Two shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The above Duties answered;</head>
			<para id="p144">
				<emph type="i">by the Father; the Mother; or the Guardian</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p145">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said several and respective su[m]ms of money soe
imposed as aforesaid for and upon the birth or births of any child or children within the Kingdom or the
Dominion or Towne aforesaid shall bee charged upon and answered and paid unto his Majesty his Heires and
Successors for the aforesaid terme of Five yeares by the father if liveing att the time of the birth of any such
child or children and if hee shall bee dead att the time of such birth by the mother of such child or children
soe borne And in case of the death of such father and mother att the time of the birth by such person or
persons who shall take upon him her or them the guardianshipp or care of such child or children soe borne to
bee reimbursed again in the first place out of the real or personal Estate of such child or children soe borne (if
any) to bee levyed in such manner as is herein after directed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Duties on Marriages for Five Years.</head>
			<para id="p146">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said First day of May for and
dureing the said terme of Five yeares there shall bee raised levyed and paid to his Majesty his Heires and Successors
for and upon every marriage of any persons (except as herein after is excepted) who shall bee married within
the said terme of Five yeares and noe longer att any place withing the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales
and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed the several and respective duties and sums of money herein after mentioned
(that is to say)</para>
			<para id="p147">
				<emph type="i">Duty on Marriages of all Persons, (Exception), and further on the Marriage of a Duke; of a Marquis</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p148">For and upon the respective marriage of every person (except such as receive Alms) the su[m]m of Two shillings
and six pence</para>
			<para id="p149">
				<emph type="i">further on the Marriage of a Duke</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p150">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of a Duke of England Scotland or Ireland the
su[m]m of Fifty pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p151">
				<emph type="i">of a Marquis</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p152">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of a Marquesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes
the su[m]m of Fourty pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p153">
				<emph type="i">of an Earl</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p154">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of an Earle of any of the said Three Kingdomes
the sum of Thirty pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p155">
				<emph type="i">of a Viscount</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p156">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of a Viscount of any of the said Three Kingdomes
the su[m]m of Five and twenty pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p157">
				<emph type="i">of a Baron</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p158">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of a Baron of any of the said Three Kingdomes
the su[m]m of Twenty pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p159">
				<emph type="i">of the eldest Son of a Duke</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p160">And for and upon the marriage of every eldest son of a Duke of any of the said Three Kingdomes the su[m]m of
Thirty pounds over and above the said Two shillings six pence</para>
			<para id="p161">
				<emph type="i">of the younger Son of a Duke</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p162">And for and upon the marriage of every younger son of such Duke the su[m]m of Five and twenty pounds over
and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p163">
				<emph type="i">of the eldest Son of a Marquis</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p164">And for and upon the marriage of every eldest son of a Marquesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes the su[m]m
of Five and twenty pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p165">
				<emph type="i">of the younger Son of a Marquis</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p166">And for and upon the marriage of every younger son of such Marquesse the su[m]m of Twenty pounds over and
above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p167">
				<emph type="i">of the eldest Son of and Earl</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p168">And for and upon the marriage of every eldest son of an Earle. of any of the said Three Kingdomes the
sum of Twenty pounds over and above the said Two shillings [and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] six pence</para>
			<para id="p169">
				<emph type="i">of the younger Son of an Earl</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p170">And for and upon the marriage of every younger son of such Earle the su[m]m of Fifteene pounds over and
above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p171">
				<emph type="i">of the eldest Son of a Viscount</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p172">And for and upon the marriage of every eldest son of a Viscount of any of the said Three Kingdomes the
su[m]m of Seventeene pounds and tenne shillings over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p173">
				<emph type="i">of the younger Son of a Viscount</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p174">And for and upon the marriage of every younger son of such Viscount the su[m]m of Thirteen pounds six
shillings and eight pence over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p175">
				<emph type="i">of the eldest Son of a Baron</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p176">And for and upon the marriage of every eldest son of a Baron of any of the said Three Kingdomes the su[m]m
of Fifteene pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p177">
				<emph type="i">of the younger Son of a Baron</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p178">And for and upon the marriage of every younger son of such Baron the su[m]m of Twelve pounds over and above
the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p179">
				<emph type="i">of a Baronet</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p180">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of a Baronett of any of the said Three
Kingdomes or of Nova Scotia the su[m]m of Fifteene pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six
pence</para>
			<para id="p181">
				<emph type="i">of a Knight of the Bath</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p182">And for and upon the marriage of every person that is a Knight of the Order of the Bath the su[m]m of Fifteene
pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p183">
				<emph type="i">of a Knight Bachelor</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p184">And for and upon the marriage of every person that is a Knight Batchelor the su[m]m of Tenne pounds over and
above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p185">
				<emph type="i">of the King's Sergeant at Law</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p186">And for and upon the marriage of every Serjeant att Law being the Kings Serjeant the su[m]m of Twenty pounds
over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p187">
				<emph type="i">of every other Serjeant</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p188">And for and upon the marriage of every other Serjeant att Law the su[m]m of Fifteene pounds over and above
the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p189">
				<emph type="i">of an Esquire</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p190">And for and upon the marriage of every Esquire or reputed Esquire or owneing or writeing himselfe to bee
such the su[m]m of Five pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p191">
				<emph type="i">of a Gentleman</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p192">And for and upon the marriage of every Gentleman or reputed Gentleman or owning or writing himselfe
to bee such the su[m]m of Twenty shillings over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p193">
				<emph type="i">of the younger Son of a Baronet, &amp;c.</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p194">And for and upon the marriage of every younger son of a Baronett Knight of the Bath Knight Batchelor
Serjeant att Law Esquire or Gentleman or reputed Esquire or Gentleman or writing or owneing themselves as
such the su[m]m of Twenty shillings over and above the said Two shillings and sixpence</para>
			<para id="p195">
				<emph type="i">of an Archbishop</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p196">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of an Arch-bishopp the su[m]m of Fifty pounds
over and above the said Two shillings and sixpence</para>
			<para id="p197">
				<emph type="i">of a Bishop</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p198">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of a Bishopp the su[m]m of Twenty pounds over
and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p199">
				<emph type="i">of a Dean</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p200">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of a Deane of any Cathedral or Collegiate
Church the su[m]m of Tenne pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p201">
				<emph type="i">of an Archdeacon</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p202">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of an Arch-Deacon the su[m]m of Two pounds
and Tenne shillings over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p203">
				<emph type="i">of a Canon or Prebendary</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p204">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of a Canon or Prebendary of any Cathedral
or Collegiate Church the sum of Two pounds and Tenne shillings over and above the said Two shillings and
six pence</para>
			<para id="p205">
				<emph type="i">of a Doctor of Divinity, Law, or Physick; or Sons of Archbishops, &amp;c.</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p206">And for and upon the marriage of every person of the degree of a Doctor of Divinity Law or Physick the
su[m]m of Five pounds over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p207">
				<emph type="i">of Sons of Archbishops, &amp;c.</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p208">And for and upon the marriage of every son of an Arch-Bishopp Bishopp Deane Arch-Deacon Canon
Prebendary Doctor of Divinity Law or Physick the su[m]m of Twenty shillings over and above the said Two shillings
and six pence</para>
			<para id="p209">
				<emph type="i">of every Person having a Real Estate of &pound;50 per Ann. or a Personal Estate of &pound;600 and up wards; of the Son of every such Person</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p210">And for and upon the marriage of every person having a real estate of the value of Fifty pounds per annum
or upwards or a personal estate of the value of Six hundred pounds or upwards and not otherwise hereby charged
[und<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] the several dignities ranks orders qualifications or degrees herein before mentioned the su[m]m of Twenty
shillings over and above the said Two shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p211">
				<emph type="i">of the Son of every such Person</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p212">And for and upon the marriage of every son of every such person or persons haveing such real or personal
estate as aforesaid the su[m]m of Tenne shillings over and above the said Two shillings and six pence.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. The said Duties to be paid by the Husband.</head>
			<para id="p213">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the several and respective duties and su[m]ms of money
soe to bee raised and paid by marriages as aforesaid as the same shall severally become due and payable shall
bee charged upon and answered and paid to his Majesty his heires and successors for the aforesaid terme. of Five
yeares by the husband upon demand.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Duties on Bachelors above 25 Years (Exception), for Five Years.</head>
			<para id="p214">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every person inhabiting and residing or which shall
inhabitt and reside in the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed being a
Batchelor. above the age of Five and twenty yeares (except such as receive Alms) shall from and after the said First
day of May dureing the said terme of Five yeares or soe long time thereof as hee shall continue a Batchelor and
noe longer pay to his Majestie his Heires and Successors the sum of One shilling yearely.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Duty on Widowers having no Child (Exception), for Five Years.</head>
			<para id="p215">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every person inhabiting and resideing [in<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] or which shall
inhabitt and reside in the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed being
a Widdower and haveing noe Child or Children (except such as receive Almes) shall from and after the said First
day of May dureing the said terme of Five yeares or soe long time thereof as hee shall continue a Widdower and
noe longer pay unto his Majesty his Heires and Successors the su[m]m of One shilling yearely.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. A further Duty on Bachelors and Widowers above. 25 Years, being</head>
			<para id="p216">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That from and after the said First day of May all and
every person and persons of the several orders ranks degrees and qualifications herein after mentioned inhabiting
and residing or which shall happen to inhabit and reside in the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales and
Towne of Berwick upon Tweed being Batchelors above the age of Five and twenty yeares or Widdowers without
any Child or Children shall pay to his Majesty his Heires and Successors yearely dureing the said terme of Five
years or for soe long time thereof as they shall continue unmarried and noe longer the several and respective
duties and su[m]ms of money hereinafter menc&otilde;ed over and above the said yearely su[m]m of One shilling (that is
to say.)</para>
			<para id="p217">
				<emph type="i">a Duke</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p218">Every person of the degree of a Duke of England Scotland or Ireland the yearely su[m]m of Twelve pounds and
Tenne shillings</para>
			<para id="p219">
				<emph type="i">a Marquis</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p220">And every person of the degree of a Marquesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes the yearely su[m]m of Tenn
pounds</para>
			<para id="p221">
				<emph type="i">an Earl</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p222">Every person of the degree of an Earle of any of the said Three Kingdomes the yearely su[m]m of Seven pounds
and Ten shillings</para>
			<para id="p223">
				<emph type="i">a Viscount</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p224">Every person of the degree of a Viscount of any of the said Three Kingdomes the yearely su[m]m of Six pounds
and Five shillings</para>
			<para id="p225">
				<emph type="i">a Baron</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p226">Every person of the degree of a Baron of any of the said Three Kingdomes the yearely su[m]m of Five pounds</para>
			<para id="p227">
				<emph type="i">eldest Son of a Duke</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p228">Every eldest son of a Duke of any of the said Three Kingdomes the yearely su[m]m of Seven pounds and Ten
shillings</para>
			<para id="p229">
				<emph type="i">younger Son of a Duke</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p230">Every younger son of such Duke the yearely su[m]m of Six pounds and Five shillings</para>
			<para id="p231">
				<emph type="i">eldest Son of a Marquis</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p232">Every eldest son of a Marquesse of any of the said Three Kingdomes the yearely su[m]m of Six pounds and Five
shillings</para>
			<para id="p233">
				<emph type="i">younger Son of a Marquis</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p234">Every younger son of such Marquesse the yearely su[m]m of Five pounds</para>
			<para id="p235">
				<emph type="i">eldest Son of an Earl</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p236">Every eldest son of an Earle of any of the said Three Kingdomes the yearely su[m]m of Five pounds</para>
			<para id="p237">Every younger son of such Earle the yearely su[m]m of Three pounds and fifteen shillings</para>
			<para id="p238">
				<emph type="i">younger Son of an Earl</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p239">Every eldest son of a Viscount of any of the said Three Kingdomes the yearely su[m]m of Foure pounds seven
shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p240">
				<emph type="i">younger Son of a Viscount</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p241">Every younger son of such Viscount the yearely su[m]m of Three pounds six shillings and eight pence</para>
			<para id="p242">
				<emph type="i">younger Son of a Viscount; eldest Son of a Baron</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p243">Every eldest son of a Baron of any of the said Three Kingdomes the yearely su[m]m of Three pounds fifteen
shillings</para>
			<para id="p244">
				<emph type="i">younger Son of a Baron</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p245">Every younger son of such Baron the yearely su[m]m of Three pounds</para>
			<para id="p246">
				<emph type="i">a Baronet</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p247">Every person of the degree of a Baronett of any of the said Three Kingdomes or of Nova Scotia the yearely
su[m]m of Three pounds and fifteene shillings</para>
			<para id="p248">
				<emph type="i">Knight of the Bath</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p249">Every person that is a Knight of the Order of the Bath the yearely su[m]m of Three pounds [and<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] fifteene
shillings</para>
			<para id="p250">
				<emph type="i">a Knight Bachelor</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p251">Every person who is a Knight the Batchelor the yearely su[m]m of Two pounds ten shillings</para>
			<para id="p252">
				<emph type="i">Bachelor</emph>:</para>
			<para id="p253">Every Serjeant att Law being the Kings Serjeant the yearely su[m]m of Five pounds</para>
			<para id="p254">
				<emph type="i">The King's Sergeant</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p255">Every other Serjeant att Law the yearely su[m]m of Three pounds fifteene shillings</para>
			<para id="p256">
				<emph type="i">a Sergeant at Law; an Esquire</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p257">Every Esquire or reputed Esquire or owning or writing himselfe to bee such the yearely su[m]m of One pound
five shillings</para>
			<para id="p258">
				<emph type="i">a Gentleman</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p259">Every Gentleman or reputed Gentleman or soe owning or writeing himselfe to bee such the yearely su[m]m of
Five shillings</para>
			<para id="p260">
				<emph type="i">an Archbishop</emph>:</para>
			<para id="p261">Every person of the degree of an Arch-Bishopp the yearley su[m]m of Twelve pounds and ten shillings</para>
			<para id="p262">
				<emph type="i">a Bishop</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p263">Every person of the degree of a Bishopp the yearely, su[m]m of Five pounds</para>
			<para id="p264">
				<emph type="i">a Dean</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p265">Every person of the degree of a Deane of any Cathedral or Collegiate Church the yearely su[m]m of Two pounds
and ten shillings</para>
			<para id="p266">
				<emph type="i">an Archdeacon</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p267">Every person of the degree of an Arch-Deacon the yearely su[m]m of Twelve shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p268">
				<emph type="i">a Canon or Prebendary</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p269">Every Canon or Prebendary of any Cathedral or Collegiate Church the yearely su[m]m of Twelve shillings [and<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]
six pence.</para>
			<para id="p270">
				<emph type="i">Doctor of Divinity, Law, and Physic</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p271">Every person of the degree of a Doctor of Divinity Law or Physick the yearely su[m]m of One pound and five
shillings</para>
			<para id="p272">
				<emph type="i">a Son of an Archbishop, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p273">Every son of an Arch-Bishopp Bishopp Dean Arch-Deacon Canon Prebendary Doctor of Divinity Law or
Physick the yearely su[m]m of Five shillings</para>
			<para id="p274">
				<emph type="i">Persons of Real Estate of &pound;50 per Ann. or of Personal Estate of &pound;600 and upwards; Sons of such Persons</emph>,</para>
			<para id="p275">Every other person haveing a real estate of the value of Fifty pounds per annum or upwards or a personal estate of
the value of Six hundred pounds or upwards and not charged under any of the orders ranks degrees or
qualifications aforesaid the yearely su[m]m of Five shillings</para>
			<para id="p276">
				<emph type="i">Sons of such Persons; Duty to be paid Half-yearly</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p277">And every son of such person haveing such real or personal estate the yearely su[m]m of Two shillings and Six
pence which said several and respective yearely su[m]ms hereby charged shall bee paid by Two equal halfe yearely
payments att the Two most usual feasts in the yeare (that is to say) att the feasts of Saint Michael the Arch-angel
and the Annunciation of the Blessed Virgin Mary.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. No Person to be doubly charged.</head>
			<para id="p278">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted That noe person shall by virtue of this Act bee doubly charged for or
in respect of the several titles honours or degrees but that every such person shall be charged and chargeable
for such title honour or degree onely as is highest rated by this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Commissioners under c. 3. ante, to be Commissioners for executing this Act.</head>
			<para id="p279">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to meet upon 30th April; and may divide themselves; and to direct Precepts to Inhabitants, &amp;c. requiring them to appear; then to read the Rates, and charge them; and to prefix a Day and Place to bring in Certificate of Names of Persons chargeable,; and the Sums they ought respectively to pay upon Burials, &amp;c; Penalty; and to return Collectors for the First Year; Parish to be answerable for their Payments; Assessor, before he acts, to take the Oaths of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 8. and also the following Oath</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p280">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That for the better execution of this Act and for the
ordering and levying of the several su[m]ms of money soe as aforesaid limitted and appointed to bee paid the persons
nominated and appointed to bee Commissioners for putting in execution an Act, of this present Session of Parliament
intituled An Act for granting to his Majestie an aid of Foure shillings in the pound for One yeare and for
applying the yearely su[m]m of Three hundred thousand pounds for Five yeares out of the Duties of Tonnage and
Poundage and other su[m]ms of money payable upon merchandizes exported and imported for carrying on the warr
against France with vigour shall bee Commissioners for putting in execution this present Act and the powers
therein contained within all and every the severall and respective Counties Ridings Cities Boroughs Cinque-Ports
Townes and places for the First yeare of the said terme of Five yeares for which the duties hereby imposed are
granted Which said Commissioners in order to the speedy execution of this Act shall (in their respective Counties
Cities Boroughs Townes and places for which they are appointed Commissioners) respectively meet together att
the most usuall or common place of meeting within such of the said Counties Cities Boroughs Townes and places
respectively att or before the Thirtieth day of April One thousand six hundred ninety five and the said Commissioners
or soe many of them as shall bee present at the First general meeting or the major part of them may by their
consents and agreements divide as well themselves as other the Commissioners not then present for the execution
of this Act in Hundreds Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Wards Townes and other places within their limitts priveledged or
not priveledged in such manner as to them (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) seem meet And shall direct their several or joint precept or precepts to such
inhabitants and such number of them as they in their discretions shall think most convenient to bee Presenters and
Assessors requiring them to appeare before the said Commissioners att such time and place as they shall appoint
not exceeding. Ten days And att such their appearances the said Commissioners or soe many of them as shall
meet shall openly read or cause to bee read unto them the several Rates and Duties in this Act mentioned and
openly declare the effect of their charge unto them and how and in what manner they ought and should make
their certificates and assessments according to the several Rates aforesaid And shall then and there prefix another
day to the said persons to appeare before the said Commissioners and bring in their certificates in writeing of the
names sirnames estates degrees titles and qualifications of all and every the persons dwelling or residing within the
limits of those places with which they shall bee charged dividing them into several columns as they are in quality
estate and qualification and the names of all other persons chargeable by this Act and the su[m]ms they are or ought
[to pay respectively<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] upon burials births or marriages and for their being unmarried according to the rules and
directions of this Act without concealment love favour dread or malice upon pain of forfeiture of any su[m]m not
exceeding Five pounds to bee levied as by this Act is appointed And shall alsoe then returne the names of Two
or more able and sufficient persons within the bounds or limits of those parishes or places where they shall bee
Assessors respectively to be Collectors of the several Rates and Duties granted to His Majestie by this Act which
shall grow due and payable within the First yeare of the said terme of Five yeares For whose paying unto the
Receiver General to bee appointed by his Majestie his Deputy or Deputies in manner following such moneys as
they shall bee charged withall the parish or place by whom they are soe imployed shall bee answerable And every
Assessor soe as aforesaid appointed or to bee appointed shall before hee take upon him the execution of the said
imployment take the oaths mentioned and required to bee taken by an Act made in the Parliament held [in<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] the First
yeare of the reigne of King William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for the abrogating the oaths of Allegiance
and Supremacy and appointing other oaths and alsoe take an oath to bee administred in these words following.</para>
			<para id="p281">You shall swear well and truely to execute the duty of an Assessor and to cause the Rates and Duties imposed
by an Act intituled An Act for granting to his Majestie certaine Rates and Duties upon marriages births and
burials and upon Batchelors and Widowers for the terme of Five yeares for carrying on the warr against France
with vigor to bee duely and impartially assessed according to the best of your skill, and knowledge and therein
you shall spare noe person for favour or affection nor any person grieve for hatred or ill-will.</para>
			<para id="p282">
				<emph type="i">Which Oaths Two Commissioners may administer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p283">Which oaths any Two or more of the Commissioners in the County City or Place where the said assessment is
to bee made have hereby power and are hereby required to administer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Certificates of Assessments to be returned to the Commissioners, before 13th of May 1695.</head>
			<para id="p284">
				<emph type="i">On Return of Certificates, Three Commissioners may issue Warrants for Collection; Collectors to demand Rates, and pay same to Receiver General, who is to hasten Collectors; and in default, to levy by Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p285">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Rates and Assessments charged by this Act shall
bee ascertained and the certificates thereof returned to the Commissioners att or before the Thirteenth day of May
One thousand six hundred ninety five And upon the delivery and returning of such Certificates or Assessments
unto the said Commissioners they or any Three or more of them shall forthwith issue out and deliver their warrants
or estreats to such Collectors as aforesaid for the speedy collecting and levying of the said Assessments as they
shall respectively become due and payable and all moneys and rates due thereupon according to the intent and
directions of this present Act of all which the said Collectors are hereby required to make demand of the parties
chargeable therewith or att the places of their last abode within Tenn days after the said Duties hereby granted
shall respectively become due and payable And to pay in the same within Twenty days after the receipt thereof
att such place as the Commissioners shall appoint unto the respective Receiver General his Deputy or Deputies who
are hereby impowered and required to call upon and hasten the Collectors to the said payment And in default of
such payment to levy by warrant under the hands and seales of any Two or more of the Commissioners upon the
Collectors by distresse and sale of his and their goods and chattells such su[m]m and sums of money as hee hath
received and as ought by him to have been paid and is not paid by reason of his failure in doing his duty
according to the direction of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Duplicate of Assessment delivered to Receivers General, who are to pay into Exchequer Half-yearly, or oftener if required by Treasury.</head>
			<para id="p286">
				<emph type="i">On Return of Certificates, Three Commissioners may examine Presenters; If Commissioners suspect the Value, or that Persons, &amp;c. are omitted, they may summon Party; Persons summonednot appearing; Penalty; Power to Commissioners to examine into the Degrees of Persons charged; Allowance to Receiver General</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p287">And bee it further enacted That a true duplicate of the said Assessments bee in convenient time made out and
delivered unto the respective Receivers General so as every of them may bee duely charged to answer their respective
collections and receipts And that the respective Receivers General shall pay the several sums of money by them
received by virtue of this Act into His Majesties Exchequer by Halfe yearely payments att the two most usual
feasts of the yeare (that is to say) the feast of Saint Michael the Arch-Angel and the feast of the Annunciation
of the Blessed Virgin Mary or sooner or oftner if thereunto required by the Commissioners of His Majesties
Tresury or by the High Tresurer or Commissioners of the Tresury for the time being And upon the returne of
any such certificate the said Commissioners or any Three or more of them shall and may if they see cause examine
the presenters thereof And if the said Commissioners or any Three or more of them within their several limitts
shall att the time of the returne of the certificates or within Twenty days after have certaine knowledge or
vehemently suspect that any person or persons who ought to bee mentioned in the said certificates is or are omitted
or that any person or persons in the said certificate mentioned is or are of a higher degree or quality or of a
greater estate then in the said certificate is mentioned or is otherwise undercharged or not duely charged according
to the direction of this Act the said Commissioners or any Three or more of them shall have power to summon
such person or persons to appeare before them att a day and place prefixed to bee examined touching the rates
and duties aforesaid or touching other matters which may any way concerne the premisses And if any person
or persons summoned to bee soe examined shall neglect to appeare having not a reasonable excuse for such his
default every person soe making default shall pay unto his Majestie double the sum of the rate hee should or
ought to have been sett att And moreover the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them shall have
power by all lawfull ways and meanes to examine and enquire into the degrees ranks qualifications and estates of
such persons as are charged by this Act and to sett such rate or rates upon every such person or persons as
shall bee according to the true intent and meaning of this Act And the said Receiver General shall have an
allowance of Two pence in the pound for all moneys which shall bee by him paid into the Receipt of the
Exchequer And that every Collector shall have Three pence in the pound for what money hee shall pay to the
Receiver General his deputie or deputies.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Commissioners' Clerks to have 1d. per Pound for writing Warrants, &amp;c. ; Persons neglecting, &amp;c. to pay Rates.</head>
			<para id="p288">
				<emph type="i">Collector to distrain, and to keep the Distress Four Days at Owners Charge; then, if no Payment, appraised and sold, and Overplus restored; Officer breaking open Houses, &amp;c. in the Day-time, to call to his Assistance Constables, &amp;c. who are to be aiding; Persons appointed to pay Duties neglecting, &amp;c. If no Distress, Commissioners or Justices may imprison; Persons aggrieved after Notice of Assessment may complain, and Commissioners may abate or increase Assessment, and then estreat Assessment into Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p289">And for the careful writing and transcribing the said warrants estreats and duplicates in due time bee it
further enacted That the Clerks of the Commissioners who shall respectively performe the same shall by warrant
under Two or more of the Commissioners hands have and receive from the respective Receivers General their
deputy or deputies One peny in the pound of all such money as hee shall have received by virtue of such
warrants or certificates who is hereby appointed and allowed to pay the same accordingly And if any person or
persons shall refuse to pay the several sum and su[m]ms and proportions appointed by this Act for such person to pay
upon demand made by the Officer or Collector of the place according to the precept or estreats to him delivered
by the Commissioners appointed by this Act itt shall and may bee lawfull to and for such Officer or Collector
who are hereby thereunto authorized and required for Non payment thereof to distraine the person or persons soe
refusing by his or their goods or chattells and the distresse soe taken to keep by the space of Foure days att the
costs and charges of the owners thereof and if the said Owner doe not pay the respective sums of money due by
this Act within the said Foure dayes then the said distresse to bee appraised by Two or more of the inhabitants
where the said distresse is taken and there to bee sold by the said Officer for payment of the said money and
the overplus coming by the said sale (if any bee) over and above the charges of taking and keeping the said
distresse to bee immediately restored to the owner thereof And moreover it shall and may bee lawfull to break
open (in the day time) any House and (upon warrant under the hands and seales of Two or more of the said
Commissioners) any chest trunk box or other things where any such goods are calling to their assistance the
Constable Tythingman and Headborough within the Counties Cities Townes and places where any refusal neglect
or resistance shall bee made which said Officers are hereby required to bee aiding and assisting in the premises
as they will answer the contrary att their Peril And if any person or persons appointed to pay any of the duties
charged by this Act shall refuse or neglect to pay the said su[m]m or su[m]ms soe appointed to bee paid by the space
of Ten Days after demand as aforesaid where noe sufficient distresse can or may bee found whereby the same
may bee levied in every such case Two or more of the Commissioners or Two Justices of the Peace by this Act
appointed for any such City County or Place are hereby authorized by Warrant under their Hands and Seals to
committ such person or persons to the Common Goal there to bee kept without Bail or Mainprize until payment
shall bee made And if any person certified assessed or rated find him or her selfe agrieved with such assessing or
rating and doe within Ten Days after Notice of such Assessments given as herein after is directed by reading
thereof in the Church complaine to the said Commissioners who signed or allowed their Rate they or any Three
or more of them shall and may within Ten days next after such Complaint particularly examine the party soe
complaining upon his or her Oath of his or [her<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Rank Degree Qualification or Estate and upon due Examination
or Knowledge thereof abate defalk encrease or enlarge the said Assessment and the same soe abated encreased or
enlarged shall bee estreated by them into the Exchequer in manner aforesaid And to that end the said Commissioners
are hereby required to meet together for the determining of such Complaints and Appeals accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Justices of Peace of Counties to be Commissioners during the last Four Years.</head>
			<para id="p290">And bee it further enacted That for the better and more effectual putting in execution of this Act the Justices
of the Peace of the several and respective Counties Ridings Cities Townes Boroughs and Places within the
Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed shall and are hereby appointed
Commissioners for and dureing the foure last yeares of the said terme of five yeares for which the duties imposed
by this Act are granted who are hereby authorized and required from time to time to putt in execution the
several powers and authorities hereby granted them according to the several directions of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. At the End of each of the Five Years Collectors to cause a Copy of Assessment signed by them, with the necessary Alterations and Names of Collectors for the succeeding Year, to be delivered to Two or more Justices;</head>
			<para id="p291">
				<emph type="i">Justices to peruse the same, and if they suspect that Persons are omitted who ought to be named in Certificate or that the Quality, or Estate is not truly stated, then they may summon such Persons. Such Persons neglecting to appear, to pay double; and the said Justices may examine into the Degrees and Estates of such Persons; and may enlarge or abate Assessment; Justices after Examination to sign and allow Assessments, and appoint Collectors, and deliver such Assessment to them; Collectors to act, under Penalties herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p292">And bee it further enacted for the better and more equal chargeing the duties ariseing by this Act that att the
end of every yeare of the said terme of five yeares for which the said duties are hereby granted the Collectors for
the next preceding yeare shall cause a copy of the respective assessments given to them and of the collection made
by them for such Division Parish or Place for which they were appointed Collectors respectively to bee fairely
written and signed by them but with such alterations therein as shall bee necessary by reason of the death change
of quality or degree or removal of any person or persons or otherwise and att the bottom thereof shall write or
cause to bee written the names of two or more of the most substantial inh[ab]itants of the respective Cities Townes
Boroughs Divisions or Places for which they were Collectors [whom<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] they in their judgement shall think fitt to bee
appointed Collectors of the said duties within the said Cities Boroughs Towns Divisions or Places respectively for
the ensueing yeare and the said Collectors are hereby appointed and required to deliver or cause to bee delivered
the said assessment soe fairely written and signed by them together with the names of the persons nominated by
them as fitt to bee Collectors for the yeare ensueing or a true duplicate thereof signed as aforesaid unto two or
more Justices of the Peace for the respective Counties Ridings Cities Townes Divisions or Places for which they
were appointed Collectors respectively within the space of ten days after the end of every yeare of the said terme
of five yeares for which the duties mentioned in this Act are granted which Justices of the Peace are hereby
authorized and required strictly to peruse the same and examine the presenters thereof and if the said Justices
or any two of them within their several Limits or Divisions shall att the time of the delivery of such Certificates or
Assessments or within ten days after have certaine knowledge or have cause to suspect that any person or persons who
ought to bee mentioned in the said certificates or assessments is or are omitted or that any person or persons in the said
[certificates<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] mentioned is or are of a higher degree or quality or of a greater estate then in the said certificate is
mentioned or is otherwise undercharged or not duely charged according to the direction of this Act the said
Justices or any two of them shall have power to summon such person or persons to appeare before them att a
day and place prefixt to bee examined touching the rates and duties aforesaid or touching other matters which
may any ways concern the premisses And if any person or persons summoned to bee soe examined shall neglect
to appeare not haveing a reasonable excuse for such his default every person soe makeing default shall pay unto
his Majesty double the su[m]m of the rate he should or ought to have been sett att And moreover the said Justices
of the Peace to whom such certificates or assessments shall bee delivered or any two of them or any other two
Justices of the Peace of the respective Counties where such assessment shall bee made shall have power and are
hereby required by all lawfull ways and meanes to examine and enquire into and concerning the several degrees
ranks qualifications and estates of such persons as are chargeable by this Act and thereupon to enlarge alter abate
or diminish the said assessments soe delivered to the said Justices soe that such rate or rates may bee sett and
imposed upon every such person or persons as shall bee according to the true intent and meaning of this Act
And the said Justices of the Peace or any three or more of them shall after such perusal and examination thereof
sett their hands to the said respective assessments testifying their allowance thereof and shall likewise no[m]iate and
appoint two of the persons named in the said certificate or assessment to bee Collectors for the respective Divisions
&amp; Places for which they were soe presented and shall forthwith deliver or cause to bee delivered such assessment
soe by them allowed of unto the respective persons by them nominated to bee Collectors for the yeare ensuing who
are hereby strictly enjoyned and required to collect and pay the several rates and duties soe rated and assessed
according to the directions herein before contained for and touching the Collectors of the said duties hereby
granted and under the several penalties and forfeitures hereby inflicted upon Collectors for neglect or not performance
of their duty.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Collectors, within Six Days after Delivery of Assessment or Certificates to them, to deliver same or a Copy to the Parson; Penalty &pound;5; who is to read the same on the next Sunday in the Church, on the like Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p293">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that the [said<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] several and respective Collectors of the
duty granted by this Act shall every yeare dureing the continuance thereof within the space of six days after
the respective assessments or certificates shall bee to them delivered deliver over the same or a true copy thereof
unto the respective Parson Vicar Rector or Curate for the respective Parish Divisions or Places for which they are
appointed Collectors under the penalty of forfeiting the su[m]m of Five pounds to his Majestie And the said Parsons
Rectors Vicars and Curates are hereby required under the like penalty of Five pounds to bee forfeited to his
Majestie for every offence on the next Lords day commonly called Sunday after the receipt thereof openly and
publickly to read or cause the same to bee read in the Church immediately after divine service in the morning
to the end that every person thereby rated or charged may have notice of such rate or charge and if hee or
they find him or themselves agrieved thereby they may complaine and appeal according to the directions of
this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. During the last Four Years, on Complaint made within Ten Days after such Reading in Church, the Justices who allowed the Rate and the other Justices in Quarter Sessions may examine Party complaining on Oath as to his Rank and Estate, and may thereupon increase or abate Assessment and deliver the same to the Collectors, who are to act thereon under the Penalties herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p294">
				<emph type="i">Collectors and Receivers General to pay Monies collected; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p295">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that dureing the foure last yeares of the said terme of
five yeares for which the duties imposed by this Act are granted upon complaint made by any person or persons
rated or assessed by virtue of this Act to the Justices of the Peace who signed or allowed his or their rate or
assessment within Ten days after such notice as aforesaid given by reading the respective rates and assessments in
the Church as before is directed the said Justices who signed or allowed the said rates or any Two of them
together with the other Justices of the said County Riding City or Place where such assessment was made are
hereby impowered att their next Quarter Sessions after such complaint particularly to examine the parties soe
complaining upon his or her Oath of his or her rank degree qualification or estate and upon due examination or knowledge
thereof to abate encrease defalk or enlarge the said assessments or any of them and the same soe abated encreased
or enlarged shall bee certified and delivered by them unto the respective Collectors of the said Duties for their
better direction in the collecting thereof who are hereby required to collect and pay the same according to the
directions of this Act under the several penalties and forfeitures hereby inflicted upon Collectors for neglect of or
not performing their Duty And a true Duplicate thereof shall bee in convenient time by them made out and
delivered unto the respective Receivers General soe as every of them may bee duely charged to answer their
respective collections and receipts And the said Collectors and Receivers General are hereby required to pay all
and every the su[m]ms which shall bee by them collected or received att any time dureing the continuance of this
Act att such times and places and in such manner and under such penalties &amp; forfeitures for non payment thereof
as herein before is directed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Appeals determined, final.</head>
			<para id="p296">And bee it further enacted That all appeals once heard and determined by virtue of this Act shall bee final
without any further appeal upon any pretence whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Persons in Holy Orders to keep a Register of Marriages, Christenings, and Burials;</head>
			<para id="p297">
				<emph type="i">Free Access thereto without Fee; Penalty &pound;100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p298">And bee it further enacted for the better levying and collecting the duties granted by this Act That all Persons
in Holy Orders Deans Parsons Deacons Viccars Curates and their or any of their Substitutes doe within their
respective Parishes Precincts and Places take an exact and true account and keep a register in writing of all &amp;
every person or persons married buried christened or borne in his or their respective Parishes or Precincts or in
such common Burying-places as their respective Parishioners are usually buried in to which book or register the
Collectors for the respective Parishes and Places and all other persons concerned shall have free accesse to view
the same att all seasonable times without any fee or reward And if any such Parson or Minister shall refuse or
neglect to keep a true register thereof as before is directed such Parson or other Minister soe offending shall
forfeit the su[m]m of One hundred pounds to bee recovered by such person as shall sue for the same in any of his
Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster by any action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information wherein noe Essoign
Wager of Law or Protection shall bee allowed and wherein the Prosecutor shall recover his full Costs the moiety
of which forfeiture shall bee to the use of the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors and the other moiety to
the persons who shall informe and sue for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Parents to give Notice of Birth within Five Days to Collectors.</head>
			<para id="p299">
				<emph type="i">Collector to give Certificate to Parent; Child born dead, Certificate thereof to be produced to Collector; Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p300">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Parents of every Child which shall bee borne
att any time within the said terme of Five yeares or one of them shall within Five days after such Birth give
notice to the Collectors or one of them of the Parish or Place where such Child was borne and of the Christian
Name of such Child and the day of its Birth And the said Collectors or one of them shall thereupon give a
Certificate in writing under his or their hands unto such Parent testifying that such notice was given without fee
and reward for the same And in case any Child shall bee borne dead then one of the Parents thereof shall bring
a Certificate under the hands of Two or more persons testifying the same unto the said Collectors or one of them
and in case any Parent shall neglect to give notice as aforesaid hee shall forfeit the su[m]m of Forty shillings one
moiety thereof to the Kings Majestie and the other moiety to the Informer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Letters Patent, &amp;c. of Exemption from Subsidies, &amp;c. not to exempt from the Duties granted by this Act.</head>
			<para id="p301">
				<emph type="i">All Non obstantes in such Letters Patent void</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p302">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That noe Letters Patents granted by the Kings Majestie or any
of his Royal Progenitors or to bee granted by his Majestie to any person or persons Cities Boroughs or Townes
Corporate within this Realme of any manner of Liberties Priveledges or Exemptions from Subsidies Tolls Taxes
Assessments or Aids shall bee construed or taken to exempt any person or persons City Borough or Towne
Corporate or any the Inh[ab]itants of the same from the burthen or charge of any su[m]m or su[m]ms of money granted
by this Act And all Non Obstantes in such Letters Patents made or to bee. made in bar of any Act or Acts
of Parliament for the supply or assistance of his Majestie are hereby declared to bee void and of none effect
[And<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] such Letters Patents Grants or Charters or any Clause of Non Obstante or other matter or thing therein
contained or any Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Parents, Guardians, &amp;c. liable for Infants;</head>
			<para id="p303">
				<emph type="i">such Parents, &amp;c. neglecting to pay, Proceedings against them; Allowance of such Payment to Parents, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p304">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That where any person or persons chargeable with any
rates or assessments by this Act imposed shall bee under the age of one and twenty yeares in every such case
the Parents Guardians and Tutors of such Infants respectively upon default of payment by such Infants shall bee
and are hereby made liable to and charged with the payments which such Infants ought to have made And if
such Parents Guardians or Tutors shall neglect or refuse to pay as aforesaid itt shall and may bee lawfull to proceed
against him in the like manner as against any other person or persons making default of payment as herein is mentioned
and all Parents Guardians and Tutors making payment as aforesaid shall bee allowed all and every the su[m]ms. paid
for such Infants upon his or their accounts</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Lodgers and Servants taxed where refident;</head>
			<para id="p305">
				<emph type="i">Absentees where last abiding in the Realm</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p306">And bee it further enacted That every person rated or assessed by virtue of this Act shall bee rated att such
place where hee or she shall bee resident att the time of the execution of this Act and all persons not being
Housholders nor having a certaine place of abode and all Servants shall bee taxed att the place where they shall
bee resident att the time of the execution of this Act and if any person who ought to bee taxed by virtue of
this Act shall att the time of this assessment bee out of the Realme such person shall bee rated therefore in such
County City or Place where hee was last abiding within the Realme.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Persons in respect of several Places of Residence being doubly charged for Personal Estate, upon Certificate and Oath thereof, to be discharged for so much;</head>
			<para id="p307">
				<emph type="i">Persons who by Fraud shall escape being taxed, doubly charged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p308">Provided That if any Person or Persons by reason of his or their having several Mansion Houses or Places of
Residence or otherwise shall bee doubly charged by occasion of this Act then upon Certificate made by any two
or more of the Commissioners for the County Riding City or Place of his or their personal Residence under
their Hands and Seales of the su[m]m or su[m]ms charged upon him or them and in what capacity or respect hee
or they were soe charged which Certificate the said Commissioners are required to give without delay fee or
reward And upon Oath made of such Certificate before any Justice of the Peace for the County or Place where
the said Certificate shall bee made (which Oath the said Justice of Peace is hereby authorized and required to
administer) then the Person or Persons soe doubly (<ref idref="n17">17</ref>) shall for soe much as shall bee soe certified bee discharged
in every other County City or Place And if any other Person that ought to bee taxed by virtue of this Act
shall by changing (<ref idref="n18">18</ref>) place place of residence or by any other fraud or covin escape from the taxation and not bee
taxed and the same bee proved before the Commissioners or any Two of them or before any Justice of the Peace
in the County Riding City or Place where such Person dwelleth or resideth att any time within Three Months
next ensueing after such tax made every Person that shall soe escape from the taxation and payment shall bee
charged upon proof thereof att double the value of soe much as hee should or ought to have been taxed att by
this Act and the said double value (upon Certificate thereof made into the Excheq[ure] by the Commissioners or
Justices before whom such Proof shall bee made) to bee levied of the Goods Lands and Tenements of such
Person.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Householders to give Account of Lodgers to Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p309">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p310">And for the better discovery of all such persons as are charged by virtue of this Act bee it further enacted
by the Authority aforesaid That every Housholder shall upon the demand of the Assessors or Collectors of the
respective Parishes or Places give an Account of the Names Degrees Qualifications and Estates of such Persons as
shall sojourne or lodge in their respective Houses under the Penalty of forfeiting to His Majestie the su[m]m of Five
Pounds to bee levied and recovered in such manner as other Penalties in this Act mentioned are to bee levied and
recovered.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Heir paying Duties on Burial, or if same levied on Lands descended, Heir may recover from Executor.</head>
			<para id="p311">Provided always and bee it further enacted That if the Heire of any Person dying shall pay the Duties charged
by this Act upon the burial of such person or if the said Duties shall bee levied by virtue of this Act upon the
Lands Tenements or Hereditaments descended to such Heir from the person upon whose burial the said Duties
became due that then such Heire his Executors or Administrators shall bee intituled to recover soe much from
the Executors or Administrators of such Person out of Assetts of the said Testator or Intestate by Action of Debt
to bee brought in any of His Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Collectors keeping Monies collected in their Hands;</head>
			<para id="p312">
				<emph type="i">Imprisonment of Persons, and Estates Real and Personal seized; and Commissioners may appoint a Meeting on Notice; and if Monies so detained be not satisfied, Commissioners present at such Meeting may sell Estates so seized for Payment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p313">And it is further enacted and declared That if any Collector that shall by virtue of this Act bee appointed for
the Receipt of any su[m]ms of money thereby to bee assessed shall neglect or refuse to pay any su[m]m or su[m]ms of
money which shall bee by him received as aforesaid and to pay the same as in and by this Act is directed and
shall detaine in his or their Hands any money received by them or any of them and not pay the same att such
time as by this Act is directed the Commissioners of each County Riding City or Towne respectively or any
Two or more of them in their respective Divisions are hereby authorized and impowered to imprison the person
and seize and secure the Estate both real and personal of such Collectors to him belonging or which shall
descend or come into the hands or possession of his Heires Executors or Administrators wheresoever the same can
bee discovered and found And the said Commissioners who shall soe seize and secure the estate of any Collector
or Collectors shall bee and are hereby impowered to appoint a time for the general meeting of the Commissioners
for such County Riding City Towne or Place and there to cause publick Notice to bee given att the place where
such meeting shall bee appointed Six days att least before such general meeting And the Commissioners present
att such general meeting or the major part of them in case the moneys detained by any such Collector or
Collectors bee not paid or satisfied as it ought to bee according to the directions of this Act shall and are hereby
impowered and required to sell and dispose of all such Estates which shall bee for the cause aforesaid seized
and secured or any part of them and to satisfy and pay into the Hands of the Receiver General the su[m]m that
shall bee soe detained in the hands of such Collector or Collectors their Heires Executors or Administrators
respectively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Places assessed in the County, &amp;c. where usually assessed.</head>
			<para id="p314">Provided and bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That for the avoiding all obstructions and
delays in assessing and collecting the sums which by this Act are to bee rated and assessed all Places Constablewicks
Divisions and Allotments which have used to bee rated and assessed shall pay and bee assessed in such County
Hundred Rape Wapentake Constablewick Division Place and Allotment as the same hath heretofore usually been
assessed in and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Commissioners within their Division to rate each other for their Personal Estates and Offices; Commissioners to assess the Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p315">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Commissioners that shall bee within any County
City or Place within the respective limits or the major part of them shall rate and assesse every other Commissioner
joyned with them for or in respect of the Rates and Duties hereby granted soe as the residence [or<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] usuall dwelling
place of such Commissioner soe to bee assessed bee within the division of such Commissioners by whom hee is
assessed And the Commissioners within their divisions shall alsoe assesse every Assessor for all and singuler the
Premisses for which by this Act hee ought to bee rated and assessed And as well all sums assessed upon every
the said Commissioners and Assessors as the Assessments made and sett by the Assessors aforesaid shall bee
levied and gathered as the same should and ought to have been if such Commissioners had not been named
Commissioners.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Inhabitants in Cities, &amp;c. not compellable to be Assessors out of Limits.</head>
			<para id="p316">Provided alsoe That noe Person inhabiting in any City Borough or Towne Corporate shall bee compelled to
bee any Assessor or Collector of or for any part of the Rates &amp; Assessments hereby granted in any place or
places out of the limits of the said City Borough or Towne Corporate.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Proviso respecting Nomination of Assessors and Collectors in Extraparochial and Privileged Places.</head>
			<para id="p317">And bee it further enacted That in all priveledged and other places being Extraparochial and not within the
Constablewicks or Precincts of the respective Assessors to bee appointed by virtue of this Act the said Commissioners
or any Two or more of them shall and are hereby required to nominate and appoint Two fitt persons living in
or neare the said priveledged or other places as aforesaid to bee Assessors for the said places and to make and
returne their said Assessments in like manner as by this Act is appointed in any Parish Tything or Place and alsoe
to appoint Two or more Collector or Collectors who are hereby required to collect and pay the same according
to the Rates appointed by this Act for collecting and paying all su[m]ms of money payable by this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. No Stay of Prosecution in Actions for Penalties.</head>
			<para id="p318">Provided alsoe and bee it enacted That noe stay of Prosecution upon any Command Warrant Motion or Order
or Direction by non vult ulterius prosequi shall bee had made admitted received or allowed by any Court
whatsoever in any Suit or Proceeding by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information or otherwise for the Recovery
of all or any the Pains Penalties or Forfeitures upon any Person or Persons by this Act inflicted or therein mentioned
for or in order to the Conviction or Disability of any Person offending against this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. If after Assessment made any Person shall come to reside where he was not rated, and shall not produce Certificate of having paid, Commissioners to assess.</head>
			<para id="p319">And for the more effectual charging all Persons chargeable with any of the Duties ariseing by virtue of this
Act Bee it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if after the Assessments directed by this Act shall bee made
any Person shall come to inhabit or reside in any Division or Place where such Person was not rated or taxed
the Comissioners acting within such Division or Place are hereby required and impowered to su[m]mon such person
before them And unlesse hee or she shall produce a Certificate made according to the Directions of this Act
whereby it shall appeare that hee or she was assessed and hath paid the Duties ariseing by such Assessment in
some other Place the said Comissioners shall and are hereby required to cause such Person to bee assessed and
the money ariseing by such Assessment to bee levyed and paid according to the true intent and meaning of
this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. Assessor, &amp;c. neglecting or refusing to do his Duty, Commissioners to fine, not exceeding &pound;20.</head>
			<para id="p320">
				<emph type="i">Two Commissioners may require Account from Receiver General, and may levy; If Controversy concerning Commissioners, Commissioners concerned to withdraw; All Questions determined by Commissioners; Receivers General to give Head Collectors Receipts gratis; Collectors to deliver a Schedule to Receiver General of Defaulters; and returned by him into the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p321">And bee it further enacted That if any Assessor Collector or other Person appointed by the Commissioners
shall wilfully neglect or refuse to performe his Duty in the due [and speedy<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Execuc[i]on of this Act the said
respective Com[m]issioners or any Three or more of them may and shall by virtue of this Act impose on such
Person or Persons soe refuseing or neglecting their Duties any fine not exceeding the su[m]m of Twenty pounds for
any one Offence the same to bee levied and certified as aforesaid and charged upon the respective Receivers
General amongst the rest of the Rates aforesaid And the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them may
or shall from time to time call for and require an Account from the respective Receivers General of all the moneys
received by them of the said Collectors and of the Payment thereof into His Majesties Exchequer according to the
directions of this Act And in case of a failure in the premisses the said Commissioners or any Two or more
of them are hereby required to cause the same to bee [forthwith<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] levyed and paid according to the true intent
and meaning of this Act And in case of any controversie ariseing between the said Commissioners concerning
the said Rates or Assessments the Co[m]missioners that shall bee concerned therein shall have noe Voice but shall
withdraw dureing the debate of such controversie until it bee determined by the rest of the Commissioners And
all questions and differences that shall arise touching any of the said Rates Taxes Assessments or Levies shall
bee heard and finally determined by Three or more of the Commissioners upon complaint thereof to them made
by any person or persons thereby grieved without further trouble or suit in Law And the said Receiver General his
Deputy or Deputies shall, give acquittances gratis to the said Collectors for all moneys of them received in pursuance
of this Act which acquittances shall bee a full discharge to the said Collectors respectively And the said Collectors
shall make and deliver to the said Receivers General their Deputy or Deputies a perfect Schedule fairely written
in Parchment under their Hands and Seals signed and allowed by any Two or more of the said respective
Commissioners containing the names and sirnames and places of abode of every person as well Peer as Commoner
within their respective collection that shall make default of payment of any of the su[m]ms that shall bee rated or
assessed on such person for such rate or duty by virtue of this Act and the su[m]m and su[m]ms charged on every
such person the same to bee by him returned into his Majesties Exchequer whereupon every person soe making
default of Payment may bee charged by processe of the Court according to the course thereof in that behalfe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Constables to be aiding in executing Act, and to obey Precepts of Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p322">Provided always and bee it enacted That all Constables Headboroughs Tythingmen and other his Majesties
Officers shall and are hereby required and enjoyned to bee respectively aiding and assisting in the execution of
this Act and to obey and execute such Precepts or Warrants as shall bee to them directed in that behalfe by the
respective Commissioners hereby appointed or any Two or more of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. In Action for executing Act General Issue may be pleaded.</head>
			<para id="p323">
				<emph type="i">Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p324">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any Action Plaint Suit or Information shall bee
commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what hee or they shall doe in pursuance or in
execution of this Act such person or persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall or may plead the General
Issue not guilty and upon any issue joyned may give this Act and the special matter in evidence And if the
Plaintiffe or Prosecutor shall become nonsuit or forbeare further prosecution or suffer discontinuance or if a Verdict
passe against him the Defendant and Defts shall recover their treble costs for which they shall have the like remedy
as in any cases where costs by the Law are given to Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. Monies collected to be paid by particular Collectors to Receiver General; of which be is to give Notice to Commissioners, as herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p325">
				<emph type="i">Receipt of Receiver General, &amp;c. a Discharge to Collector</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p326">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That all moneys due and payable by this Act shall bee
paid by the particular Collectors of the respective Counties Cities Boroughs Townes Parishes and Places who shall
collect the same unto such Receiver General as shall by his Majestie bee appointed to receive the same or the
Deputie or Deputies of such Receiver General to bee appointed under his hand and seale whereof notice shall bee
given by the Receiver General unto the Co[m]missioners or any Two of them within their respective Divisions within
Tenne Days after their first General Meeting and soe from time to time within Ten days after every death or
removal of any deputy if any such shall happen And the receipt of such Receiver General his Deputy or
Deputies or any of them shall bee a sufficient discharge unto every such Collector.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. Proviso as to Collectors travelling to pay.</head>
			<para id="p327">And bee it further enacted That the particular Collectors for payment of any su[m]ms by them received unto
such Receiver General or his Deputy shall not bee obliged to travel above ten miles from the place of their
habitations.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. Receiver General returning Rates to be in Arrear, or setting Insuper, when Rates have been paid;</head>
			<para id="p328">
				<emph type="i">Penalty to Party; Penalty to the King</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p329">And for the better preventing such unjust vexations as might bee occasioned by such persons as shall bee appointed
Receivers General of any of the su[m]ms of money granted by this Act and to the intent the Receivers General may
returne a true account into his Majesties Court of Exchequer of such su[m]s of money as shall bee received by them and
every of them their and every of their deputie and deputies Bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that
if any such Receiver General shall returne or certifie unto the said Court any su[m]m or su[m]ms of money to bee in
arrear or unpaid after the same have been received either by such Receiver General or his Deputy or Deputies
or any of them or shall cause any person or persons to bee sett insuper in the said Court for any su[m] or su[m]ms
of money that hath been soe received that then every such Receiver General shall forfeit to every person and
persons that shall bee molested vexed or damaged by reason of such unjust certificate returne or setting insuper
treble the damages that shall bee thereby occasioned the said damags to bee recovered by Action of Debt Bill
Plaint or Information in which noe Essoin Protection or Wager of Law shall bee allowed nor any more then one
Imparlance and shall alsoe forfeit to his Majestie his heires and successors double the su[m] that shall bee soe
unjustly certified or returned or caused to bee sett insuper.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Commissioners not liable to Penalties of 25 Car. 11. c. 2.</head>
			<para id="p330">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That noe Commissioner or Commissioners who shall bee
employed in the execution of this Act shall bee liable for or by reason of such execution to any of the penalties
mentioned in an Act made the five and twentieth yeare of King Charles the Second for the preventing of dangers
which may happen from Popish Recusants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. Penalties how levied.</head>
			<para id="p331">Provided alwaies and bee it enacted that all penalties and forfeitures to bee incurred for any Offences against
this Act for which there is noe particular way of levying herein before prescribed or appointed shall bee levied by
warrant under the hands and seales of two or more of the respective Co[m]missioners of the Division or Place where
any such Offence was or shall bee committed by distresse and sale of the Goods of the Offender rendring the
overplus to the owner thereof after a deduction of reasonable charges for distraining the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>XLIII. Collector neglecting, &amp;c. to deliver Copy or Duplicate of Assessment signed, and Names of Collectors; Penalty &pound;20.</head>
			<para id="p332">Provided [alwayes<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] and bee it enacted That if any Collector appointed by virtue of this Act to collect the
duties hereby granted shall neglect or refuse to deliver a copy or duplicate fairely written and signed by him of
the assessment by which hee collected the said duties together with the names of two or more of the Inhabitants of
the Parish or Place for which hee was Collector to bee appointed Collectors for the yeare next ensueing att such
time and in such manner as herein before is directed every Collector soe offending shall forfeit the su[m]m of twenty
pounds to his Majestie to bee recovered and levied in such manner as herein is directed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>XLIV. Duty on Burial of Person relieved under Statute for Relief of Poor to be paid by Churchwardens of Parish where such Person was last relieved, and allowed in Account; on Default, Distress and Punishment.; Demand at the House where Person died a good Demand.</head>
			<para id="p333">Provided always &amp; bee it enacted that the several duties &amp; su[m]ms. of money due and payable by this Act for
and upon the burial of any person who in his life time and att the time of his death was relieved where hee
inh[ab]ited by virtue of any Act of Parliament made for relief of the poor shall bee paid &amp; answered to his
Majestie by the Churchwardens and Overseers of the Poor for that Parish or Place where such person was last
relieved or maintained out of such money as they shall receive for the relief of the Poor of their respective Parishes
or Places and shall bee allowed the same upon their accounts and in default of payment the said Churchwardens
and Overseers shall bee lyable to bee distrained upon and otherwise prosecuted and punished in such manner as
any other persons neglecting or refuseing to pay the duties payable by them upon demand are hereby made lyable
to bee distrained upon or prosecuted. Provided always that a demand att the house where the person died upon
whose burial any duty is payable by this Act [of<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] the money due for such burial shall bee construed and
deemed to bee a good demand thereof by virtue of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>XLV. Recital that poor Parishes would be burthened if liable for Duty on Burials of Persons receiving Alms.</head>
			<para id="p334">
				<emph type="i">Churchwardens to deliver on Oath to Mayor, &amp;c. a List of poor Persons buried in the preceding Year on whom the Duty is payable; and, on Delivery thereof, Mayor, &amp;c. to cause the Duties paid to be raised on the Cities, &amp;c. in general with other Charges for the Relief of the Poor, and thereout to repay the said Churchwardens, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p335">And whereas in Cities Corporations and other great Townes where there are more Parishes then one and
the poor people in the same doe generally live in the skirts or outsides of such Cities Corporations &amp; other
great Towns and in case such poor parishes should by virtue of this Act bee lyable to pay the tax laid
upon the burial of every person which received alms within their respective Parishes it would bee extreamely
burthensome For remedy whereof bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid that the Churchwardens and Overseers
of every Parish in every City or Corporation or Liberties or Suburbs thereof and of every great Towne who have
more Parishes then one as aforesaid shall dureing the continuance of this Act upon or before the Tenth day of
May in every yeare deliver unto the Mayor Chief Magistrate or Head Officer or Officers of every such City
Corporation or great Towne a schedule or list in writing which shall containe the name of every poor person
buried in their respective Parishes within the yeare preceding and for whose burial they paid the duty imposed by
this Act upon delivery whereof such Churchwardens Overseers of the Poor or some of them shall make Oath
before the said Mayor Justice of the Peace Chief Magistrate or Head Officer of the truth of the said Schedule or
List (which oath they are respectively hereby impowered to administer) and after delivery of such Schedules or
Lists in manner aforesaid the said Mayors Chief Magistrates or other Head Officers shall respectively cause all
the said su[m]ms soe paid by the said respective Churchwardens or Overseers of the Poor upon the burial of every such
poor person in the said several Schedules mentioned to bee taxed upon the several Cities Corporations and great
Townes in general with other charges for relief of the Poor and in the like manner and within Two months
after the same shall bee assessed shall cause payment to bee made to the respective Churchwardens and Overseers
of the Poor for the Yeare preceding of all such su[m]m and su[m]ms of money as they respectively paid in their respective
parishes for the burial of poor persons in the same Yeare.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>XLVI. Receivers General &amp;c. to deliver their Accounts yearly, between 1st May and 1st November, to the Auditors of the Imprest, who are to examine Accountants upon Oath;</head>
			<para id="p336">
				<emph type="i">and in making such Accounts the said Receivers, &amp;c. are to produce proper Vouchers; Such Accounts to be declared according to the Course of the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p337">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That such Receiver or Receivers General or other person
or persons who is or shall bee imployed in the receiving collecting or paying the several duties upon marriages
births and burials and alsoe upon Batchelors and Widdowers by this Act granted shall and are hereby required
between the First day of May One thousand six hundred ninety six and the First day of November following
and soe from yeare to yeare yearely att those times dureing the continuance of this Act to deliver in
their respective accounts thereof to his Majesties auditors of the imprests for the time being or one of
them who shall bee and are hereby from time to time respectively authorized to examine upon Oath the said
Receiver or Receivers General or other person or persons Accomptants which are or shall bee imployed in raiseing
receiveing and collecting the said duties of what su[m]m or su[m]ms of money was or were by them or any of them
respectively raised collected or received within the time of such their accounts and likewise what part thereof was
by them or any of them paid into the receipt of his Majesties Exchequer or by virtue of any Warrant of Privy
Seal or Warrant of the Lord High Tresurer or Co[m]missioners of his Majesties Tresury for the time being otherwise
paid and to whom and for what Service or Services And in making the said accounts to and before the said
Auditors or one of them they are to produce proper vouchers for every su[m]m or su[m]ms of money soe by them or
any of them raised received and paid according to the ancient methods of the Exchequer to the end it may appeare upon
record what the same amounted to in a yeare for which such account or accounts shall bee made and what thereof
was paid and to whom and for what use and service uses and services as aforesaid and what remains unpaid and
rests insuper upon each respective Receiver and Collector And such account or accounts soe to bee taken by
the said Auditor is and are to bee declared before the Lord Tresurer or Lords Co[m]missioners of the Tresury and
Chancellor of the Excheq now and for the time being according to the course of the Exchequer in such
cases.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>XLVII. Proviso as to Marriages in Places exempt from Visitation.</head>
			<para id="p338">
				<emph type="i">Parson, &amp;c. unduly marrying any Persons; Penalty &pound;100.</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p339">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That noe person shall bee married att any place pretending
to bee exempt from the visitation of the Bishop of the Diocesse without a licence first had and obtained except
the Banns shall bee published and certified according to Law And that every Parson Vicar and Curate who shall
marry any persons contrary to the true intent and meaning hereof shall forfeit the su[m]m of One hundred pounds
to bee recovered by action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of his Majesties Courts of Record one moiety
whereof to the King his Heires and Successors and the other moiety to the Informer who shall sue for the same
and shall for the second offence bee suspended ab officio &amp; beneficio for the space of Three yeares.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>XLVIII. Proviso for Fellows, &amp;c. in the Universities.</head>
			<para id="p340">And whereas the Fellows; Students Scholars and Exhibitioners of the Foundations or Endowments of any College
or Hall in the Two Universities are by the Statutes in their respective Colleges and Halls to bee displaced from
their Places and maintenance therein if they shall marry bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That the rates
and taxes by this Act imposed or to bee imposed on Batchelors shall nor extend to such Fellows Students or
Scholars of Houses or Scholars having Exhibitions in any such Colleges or Halls any thing herein contained to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>XLIX. Master or Mistress of Family in which Infant shall die to pay the Duty on Burial of Infants not residing with their Parents at the time of their Death; on default, Distress.</head>
			<para id="p341">
				<emph type="i">Such Master or Mistress so paying may recover the Amount of such Payment from the Estate of the Infant, or from the Father or Guardian, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p342">Provided always and bee it further enacted That where any person under the age of One and twenty yeares
shall not bee resident att the time of his or her death with his or her Father or Mother That in such case the
Master or Mistrisse of the Family or House where such person shall dye shall pay the several duties and su[m]ms
of money which shall become due and payable by virtue of this Act for and upon the burial of such person
And in default of payment the said duties and su[m]ms of money shall bee levyed by distresse and sale of the goods
and chattells of such Master or Mistresse or otherwise as by this Act is directed touching the duties, payable by
virtue thereof And such Master or Mistresse paying such duties as aforesaid shall and is hereby intituled to deduct
and retaine soe much as hee or shee shall soe pay out of the estate of such person soe dying in his or her hands
And in case such Master or Mistresse shall not have sufficient estate in his or her hands belonging to the person
deceased then such Master or Mistresse shall and is hereby intituled to demand &amp; recover soe much money as hee
or she shall soe pay from the Father of such person if living and if there [shall<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] bee noe Father living then
from such person who was or took upon him or her selfe to bee Guardian or Trustee of such Child by action
of debt to bee brought in any of his Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Wager
of Law or Protection shall bee allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s50">
			<head>L. Upon a Burial for which a Duty of 20s. is payable (Exception) the Party liable to pay to deliver to Collector a Certificate of the Name, Title, &amp;c. of such deceased Person, and of the Parents.</head>
			<para id="p343">
				<emph type="i">Such Certificate to be transmitted to Receiver General, who is to deliver same to Officer of Arms, to be filed in the College of Arms</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p344">And for the better preserving the Genealogies Descents and Alliances of the Nobility and Gentry bee it further
enacted by the authority aforesaid That upon the burial of every person or persons of any the degrees ranks titles
or qualities aforementioned for which a duty of Twenty shillings or upwards is charged by this Act (except such
persons as are charged onely for or in respect of their having Fifty pounds per annum or Six hundred pounds
personal estate) the party lyable to pay the said duty shall deliver or cause to bee delivered to the Collector or
Collectors appointed by this Act a Certificate in Writing under his or her hand and seale engrossed in Parchm
or otherwise expressing the name sirname title quality office and employment (if any) of such deceased person with
the age time of death place of burial marriages and issue and the ages of such issue together with the names sirnames
titles and qualities of the parents of such deceased persons which Certificates shall bee transmitted to the Receiver
General his deputy or deputies who shall deliver them to the Kings Heraulds and Pursuivants of Arms And the
said Officers of Arms shall thereupon forthwith number schedule and digest the same in alphabetical order in Books
to bee provided for that purpose and shall file upp the Originals in the College of Arms for publick use and
shall bee answerable for the keeping thereof without any Fee or Reward for soe doeing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s51">
			<head>LI. Clause for Loan of &pound;650,000; at Interest at &pound;8 per Cent. per Ann.</head>
			<para id="p345">And bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may bee lawfull to and for any person or
persons natives or Foreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate to advance and lend to his Majestie into the receipt of
his Exchequer upon the creditt of this Act any su[m]m or su[m]ms of money not exceeding the su[m]m of six hundred
and fifty thousand pounds in the whole and to have and receive for the forbearance of all such moneys as shall
bee lent interest not exceeding the rate of Eight pounds per centum per annum.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s52">
			<head>LII. Officers to keep distinct Accounts of Duty.</head>
			<para id="p346">And bee it further enacted and ordained by the authority aforesaid That all and every the Officer and Officers
who shall bee concerned in the levying collecting and receiving the duties ariseing by this Act doe keep a seperate
and distinct account thereof and the same shall from time to time bee brought and paid into the Receipt of the
Excheq[uer].</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s53">
			<head>LIII. Books provided.</head>
			<para id="p347">
				<emph type="i">Tally or Loan to Lender and Warrant for Interest, payable every Three Months; Orders for Repayment registered according to Date of Tally and paid in course; Monies to come in by this Act liable to satisfy such Loans; No Fee for providing or making Books, &amp;c. or for Payment of Money lent; Penalty; Punishment; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty, and loss of Office; By Deputy; Penalty and Incapacity; Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller not making Payments in due Order; Penalty; How all such Penalties to be recovered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p348">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That there shall bee provided and kept in his Majesties
Excheq[uer] (that is to say) in the Office of the auditor of the Receipts one Book in which all moneys that shall
bee paid into the Excheq[uer] by: virtue of this Act shall bee entred and registred apart and distinct from all other
moneys paid or payable to his Majestie upon any account whatsoever And that all and every person and persons
Natives or Foreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate who shall lend any money to his Majestie upon the creditt of
this Act &amp; pay the same into the Receipt of the Excheq[uer] shall im[m]ediately have a Tally of Loan struck for the
same and an order for his or their repayment beareing the same date with the Tally in which order shall bee alsoe
contained a Warrant for payment of interest for forbearance not exceeding the rates aforesaid for his or their
consideration to bee paid every Three months until the repayment of his or their principal And that all Orders
for repayment of money shall bee registred in course according to the date of the Tally respectively without
preferrence of one before another And that all and every person and persons shall bee paid in course according as
their orders shall stand registred in the said Book soe as that the person Native or Foreigner his or their
Executors Administrators or Assignes who shall have his her or their order or orders first entred in the said Book
shall bee taken and accounted as the first person to bee paid upon the moneys to come in by virtue of this Act
And hee or they who shall have his or their order or orders next entred shall bee taken and accounted to bee
the second person to bee paid and soe successively and in course And that the moneys to come in by this Act
shall bee in the same order liable to the satisfaction of the said respective Parties their Executors Administrators
or Assignes successively without p[re]ferrence of one before another and not otherwise and not to bee divertible to
any other use intent or purpose whatsoever and that noe fee reward or gratuity directly or indirectly bee demanded
or taken of any of his Majesties Subjects for providing or makeing of any such Books Registers Entries View or
Search as aforesaid or in or for the payment of money lent or the interest as aforesaid by any of his Majesties
Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputies on pain of payment of treble damags to the party grieved by the party
offending with Costs of Suit or if the Officer himselfe take or demand any such fee or reward then to lose his
place alsoe and if any undue p[re]ferrence of one before another shall bee made either. in point of registry or payment
contrary to the true meaning of this Act by any such Officer or Officers then the party offending shall bee lyable
by action of debt or on the case to pay the value of the debt damages and costs to the party [greved<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] and shall
bee forejudged from his place or office And if such preferrence bee unduely made by any his Deputy or Clerk
without direction or privity of his Master then such Deputy or Clerk onely shall bee liable to such Action Debt
Damages, and Costs and shall bee for ever after uncapable of his Place or Office And in case the Auditor shall
not direct or the Clerk of the Pells record or the Tellers make payment according to each persons due place and
order as before directed then hee or they shall bee judged to forfeit and their respective Deputies and Clerks
herein offending to bee lyable to such Action Debt Damages and Costs in such manner as aforesaid all which
said penalties forfeitures damages and costs to bee incurred by any of the Officers aforesaid or any their deputies
or clerks shall and may bee recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of his Majesties
Courts of Record att Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection Priveledge Wager of Law Injunction or Order
of Restraint shall bee in any wise granted or allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s54">
			<head>LIV. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p349">
				<emph type="i">Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded, no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Orders</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p350">Provided always and bee it hereby declared That if it shall happen that several Tallies of Loan or Orders for
Payment as aforesaid beare date or bee brought the same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to bee registred then
it shall bee interpreted (<ref idref="n25">25</ref>) noe undue preference which of those hee enters first soe hee enters them all the same day.
Provided alsoe that it shall not bee interp[re]ted any undue preference to incurr any penalty in point of payment if
the Auditor direct and the Clerk of the Pells record and the Teller pay subsequent orders of the persons that
come and demand their money and bring their orders in their course soe as there may bee soe much money
reserved as will satisfie precedent orders which shall not bee otherwise disposed but kept for them (interest upon
Loan being to cease from the time the money is soe reserved and kept in Bank for them.)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s55">
			<head>LV. Orders for payment of money lent may be assigned by Indorsement.</head>
			<para id="p351">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee; Assignce may in like manner assign</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p352">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every person or persons to whom any moneys shall
bee due by virtue of this Act after order entred in the book or register aforesaid for payment thereof his
executors administrators or assignes by endorsement of his order may assigne and transferr his right title interest
and benefitt of such order or any part thereof to any other which being notified in the office of the Auditor of
the receipt aforesaid and an entry or memorial thereof alsoe made in the book of register aforesaid for orders
(which the Officers shall upon request without fee or charge accordingly make) shall entitle such Assignee his
Executors Administrators or Assignes to the benefitt thereof and payment thereon and such Assignee may in like
manner assigne again and soe toties quoties And afterwards it shall not bee in the power of such person or
persons who have or hath made such Assignements to make void release or discharge the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s56">
			<head>LVI.</head>
			<para id="p353">Provided always and bee it enacted That it shall and may bee lawfull to and for his Majestie his heires and
successors out of the duties ariseing by this Act to cause such su[m]m and sums of money to bee expended and paid
from time to time for salaries and other incident charges as shall bee necessary in and for the receiving collecting
levying or manageing of the same Duties dureing the said terme therein by this Act granted Any thing herein
contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s57">
			<head>LVII. Quakers, Papists, whether Popish Recusant Convicts or not, and Jews, and other Persons living together as Man and Wife, liable to Duty, and to be levied as in all other Cases.</head>
			<para id="p354">
				<emph type="i">Notice by the Man to Collector, of such Marriage; Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p355">Provided always and bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That all persons comonly called Quakers
or reputed such and all Papists or reputed Papists whether they are Popish Recusants Convict or not and all Jews
or any other persons who shall cohabitt and live together as man and wife shall and are hereby made lyable to
pay the several &amp; respective duties and su[m]ms of money payable upon marriages according to their respective
degrees titles orders and qualifications as they ought to have paid by virtue of this Act if they had been married
according to the Law of England which duties and su[m]ms of money shall bee collected levied and paid in such
manner and subject to such rules and directions and under such penalties and forfeitures as are in this Act specified
and conteined for and concerning payment of the several and respective duties payable upon marriages any thing
herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding. And upon every pretended marriage which shall bee made by
any such person within the said terme of five yeares according to the method and forms used amongst them the
man soe entring into such pretended state of matrimony shall within five days after give notice thereof to the
Collectors or one of them of the Parish or Place where hee lives and in default of giving such notice hee shall
forfeit the su[m]m of five pounds one moiety thereof to the Kings Majesty the other moiety to the informer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s58">
			<head>LVIII. Validity not hereby given to such Marriage.</head>
			<para id="p356">Provided always That nothing herein contained shall bee construed to make good or eff[ect]ual in Law any such
marriage or pretended marriage but that they shall bee of the same force and virtue and noe other as they would
have been if this Act had never been made.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">under <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">shall <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">respectively to pay <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">who <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">certificate <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">interlined on the Roll, but omitted in the Original Act.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">charged <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">his <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">grieved <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

