<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46423" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IV. An Act for exempting Apothecaries from serving the offices of Constable Scavenger and other Parish and Ward
Offices and from serving upon Juries. [Rot. Parl. pt. 1. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Apothecaries are compelled to serve on Juries, &amp;c. and of Letters Patent of Jac. I.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Apothecaries within London and Seven Miles of the City, that are free, exempt from Offices; Remedy for Apothecaries who may be chosen</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Art of [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Apothecary is of great and general use and benefitt by reason of their
constant and necessary assistance to his Majesties subjects which should oblige them solely to attend the
duty of their professions yett by reason that they are compelled to serve several Parish Ward and Leet Offices
in the places where they live and are frequently summoned to serve on Juries and Enquests which take upp
great part of their time they cannot performe the trusts reposed in them as they ought nor attend the sick
with such diligence as is required. And whereas King James the First by his Letters patents under the Great
Seale of England did incorporate the Apothecaries exerciseing that art within London and Seven miles compasse
by the name of the Master Wardens and Society of the art and mystery of Apothecaries of the city of London.
Bee it therefore enacted by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords
Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That
all and every person and persons useing and exerciseing or that hereafter shall use and exercise the art of an
Apothecary within the said City of London and Seven miles thereof being free of the said society and who already
have been or hereafter shall bee duely examined of his skill in the said mistery and shall bee approved of for
the same and every of them for soe long as hee or they shall use and exercise the said Art and noe longer shall
and may att all times hereafter bee freed and exempted from the several offices of Constable Scavenger Overseer
of the Poor and all other Parish Ward and Leet Offices and of and from the being putt into or serving upon
any Juries or Enquests and if att any time hereafter any such person or persons useing the said art and being
qualified as aforesaid shall bee chosen or elected into any of the said Offices or returned required or appointed
to serve in any Jury Leet or Enquest or bee disquieted or disturbed by reason thereof that then such person or
persons produceing a testimonial under the common seal of the said Corporation of such his examination approbation
and freedom to the person or persons by whom hee shall bee soe elected or appointed or by or before whom
hee shall be [soe<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] summoned returned or required to serve or hold any of the said offices or duties shall bee
absolutely discharged from the same and such nomination election returne and appointment shall bee utterly void
and of none effect any order custom law or statute to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Country Apothecaries, who have served Seven Years, exempted from Offices.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">5 Eliz. c. 4; Apothecaries already chosen not exempted</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That all persons useing and exerciseing or that hereafter
shall use and exercise the said Art of an Apothecary within any other parts of this Kingdome Dominion of
Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed and who have been brought upp and served or hereafter shall bee brought
upp and serve in the said Art as an Apprentice by the space of Seven yeares according to the Statute of the
Fifth of Queen Elizabeth shall likewise from henceforth bee freed and exempted from all and singuler the Offices
and Duties aforesaid within the several Counties Cities and Places where they live and inhabitt for soe long as
hee or they shall [use and<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] exercise the said Art and noe longer and if any person or persons soe qualified
shall bee elected or chosen into any of the said Offices or returned to serve in any Jury Leet or Enquest such
nomination election returne and appointment shall bee void unlesse such person or persons shall voluntarily consent
and agree to hold such Office or serve upon such Jury Leet or Enquest. Provided always that nothing herein
contained shall bee construed to exempt or excuse any Apothecary that is or shall before the comencement of this
Act bee elected or appointed to serve any of the said Offices from serving in the said Offices for the usual time
for which hee was soe elected and appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Continuance of Act.</head>
			<para id="p5">[Provided always that this Act shall continue for the space of Seven yeares and from thence to the end of
the next Session of Parliament and noe longer.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the oil.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


