<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46429" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the better Admeasurement of Keels and Keel-Boats in the Port, of Newcastle &amp; the Members thereunto belonging. [Chapter X. Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1"><emph type="i">Recital of 9 H.V. Stat. 1. c. 10. and 30 Car.II: Stat. 1.c. 8. &sect;2. and that new Frauds had arisen.; Commissioners to be appointed from time to time for marking Keels, &amp;c; Admeasurement how and where to be made; Weight and Contents of Wains and Carts of Coals regulated</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by two several Statutes heretofore made the one in the Ninth yeare of the Reigne of King
Henry the Fifth intituled Keels that carry Coals att New-castle shall bee measured and marked And the
other in the Thirtieth yeare of our late Sovereign Lord King Charles the Second intituled An Act for the
Admeasurement of Keels and Boats carrying Coals For the remedy of deceits therein complained off. (amongst other
things) itt was thereby enacted that Commissioners should from time to time bee appointed by his said late Majestie
his Heires and Successors for the admeasuring and marking all and every the Keels and other Boats and Wains
and Carts used or in any time thereafter to bee used for the carriage of Coals in the Port of New-castle upon
Tyne Sunderland upon the River Weare Culler-Coates Seaton-Sluce Blyth-Nooke and all and every of the Members
Havens Creeks and Places whatsoever to the said Port of New-castle belonging upon the Forfeiture that every
Keel Boat Wain or Cart which should thereafter carry Coals in any of the aforesaid Places before they shall bee
admeasured and marked as aforesaid should bee forfeited together with the Coals laden upon them Notwithstanding
which diverse new frauds deceits and abuses have of late arisen and are dayly practised to the diminution of
his Majesties Customes and the great prejudice &amp; damage of the buyers and sellers of Coals. For remedy
whereof Bee it enacted by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords
Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That
Commissioners shall from time to time bee appointed by his Majestie his Heires &amp; Successors for the admeasuring
and marking all and every the Keels Pan-Keels and Pan-Boats and other Boats and Wains and Carts used or in
any time hereafter to bee used for the Carriage of Coals in the Port of New-castle upon Tyne Sunderland upon
the River Weare Culler-Coats Seaton-Sluce Blyth-Nooke and all other Places within the Counties of Northumberland
and Durham and all and every the Members Havens Rivers Creeks and Places whatsoever to the said Port of
New-castle and Counties aforesaid belonging Which said admeasurement shall bee by a dead weight of Lead or
Iron or otherwise as shall seem meet to the said Commissioners or any Three of them allowing Three and fifty
hundred weight to every Chaldron of Coals Which said Keels Boats Waines or Carts shall bee admeasured and
marked att the times and places and in manner hereafter mentioned Any thing in the said former Acts to the
contrary notwithstanding. Provided always That the Weight or Contents of Coals loden or carried by every
such Wain shall bee off the weight or content of Seventeen hundred weight and an halfe and the weight or
contents of Coals loden or carried by every such Cart shall bee of the weight or content of Eight hundred and
three quarters And that Three such Waines or Six such Carts shall bee reckoned and allowed for one Chaldron
and noe more And that noe other [Carts or Wains<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] are hereby intended to bee admeasured or marked but onely
such Wains or Carts as now are or hereafter shall bee imployed in carrying Coals to the Staiths to bee directly
putt from the Staiths into the Ships and noe others.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners to give Three Days' notice of time and place of Admeasurement.</head>
			<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Keels, &amp;c. to be marked and nailed; Wains and Carts to be marked and nailed; Persons thereto appointed to take an Oath; Owners neglecting, &amp;c; Penalty; Regulation as to Time and Place of such admeasuring, marking, and nailing</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said Commissioners or any three or more of them
shall cause all and every of the said Keels Boats Wains and Carts to bee admeasured accordingly and shall give
three days notice of the time and place of such admeasurement to the Owner or Owners thereof and cause the
said Keels and Boats soe admeasured to bee marked and nailed on each side the stem and sterne and midshipp
thereof or otherwise as they the said Commissioners or any Three of them in their discretion shall direct and the
said Wains and Carts to bee marked and nailed on the head and sides of the said Waines Carts or otherwise as
the said Commissioners or any Three of them shall direct or by such persons as [they<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] shall bee by them thereunto
appointed which persons soe appointed shall take an oath before the said Commissioners or any Three of them
for the true and impartial performance and discharging the same which oath the said Commissioners are hereby
impowered to administer and if the owner or owners of such Keels or Boats Wains or Carts shall after such
notice neglect or refuse to have their said Keels Boats Wains or Carts soe admeasured they and every of them
shall incurr the penalty hereafter mentioned. Provided that noe such Keel or Boat bee admeasured marked or nailed
but between the Five and twentieth day of March and the Nine and twentieth day of September in any yeare
nor shall bee admeasured marked or nailed to carry more then ten such chaldrons of Coals att any one time
and that all such Keels and Boats belonging to the Port of New-castle shall bee admeasured marked and nailed
at the New Key of the said Port and that the Keels and Boats belonging to the River Wear shall bee admeasured
marked and nailed att Lambton Staiths upon the said River and not elsewhere and that all the Keels and Boates
belonging to Culler-coates Seaton-sluce Blyth-nooke and all other places within the said Counties of Northumberland
and Durham as alsoe all Wains and Carts to bee admeasured and marked by virtue of this Act shall bee
admeasured and marked att such times and places as the said Commissioners or any Three of them shall
direct.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Keels, Wains, &amp;c. carrying Coals before they are marked and nailed, unless by Default of Commissioners, forfeited together with the Coals therein.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every Keel Boat Wain or Cart which from and after
the Foure and twentieth day of July which shall bee in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred
ninety and five shall carry any Coals in any of the Places aforesaid before they shall bee admeasured marked and
nailed as aforesaid by Three Commissioners or more of them shall bee and are hereby declared to bee forfeited
together with the Coals that shall bee laden upon them (unlesse the same shall happen by default of the said
Commissioners) one moiety of all which forementioned forfeitures shall bee to the Kings Majestie his heires and
successors the other moiety to him or them that shall discover or sue for the same in any of his Majesties
Courts of Record by Bill Plaint or Information wherein noe Essoign Protection (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) or Wager of Law shall bee allowed
any Statute Law or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The Marks on Keels, Wains, &amp;c. removed or altered;</head>
			<para id="p6"><emph type="i">Penalty &pound;10. Distress; If no sufficient Distress, Imprisonment in County Gaol for Three Months. How Penalty applied; Such Keels, Wains, &amp;c. remeasured. marked, and nailed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That in case after the [admeasurement<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] marking and nailing
of any Keel Boat Wain or Cart the mark shall bee removed or altered whereby to frustrate the intent and meaning
of this Act that every person and persons that shall have a hand in or bee privy to the doeing thereof and shall
upon proof thereof by one or more credible witnesses before any one or more Justice or Justices of the Peace of
the Counties where the said offence shall happen to bee com[m]itted &amp; convicted thereof such person or persons soe
as aforesaid convicted shall forfeit the su[m]m of Ten pounds to bee levied upon his or their Goods and Chattels by
distress and sale thereof by warrant under the hand and seale of the said Justice or Justices rendring the overplus
(if any) to the partie or parties distrained upon and for want of sufficient distresse the parties soe offending shall
by like warrant bee committed to the common Gaol of the said County where the offence shall bee committed
there to remaine for the space of Three months without bail or mainprize one halfe part of the said forfeiture
to his Majestie his heires and successors and the other halfe part thereof to such person or persons as shall make
such discovery and alsoe that after any such offence as aforesaid committed by altering or removing any of the
marks or nails that shall bee sett upon any such Keels Boats Wains or Carts by virtue of this Act that from
thenceforth and soe. often as any such offence shall bee comitted as aforesaid the said Co[m]missioners or any Three
of them or such person or persons as shall bee by them appointed shall have authority and are hereby authorized
and impowered to admeasure mark and nail the said Keels Boats Wains and Carts anew according to the
directions hereby before given.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Waines or Carts <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2"><emph type="i">O</emph> omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Imparlance <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">admeasuring <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

