<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46433" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
<subtitle>Chapter XIV. An Act for continuing several Laws therein mentioned [Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>3 W. &amp; M. c. 9. made perpetual.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">4 &amp; 5 W. &amp; M. c. 24; 4 &amp; 5 W. &amp; M. c. 24. &sect; 13.</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">Whereas divers temporary laws which by experience have been found beneficial and useful are neare
expireing therefore for continuing the same bee it enacted by the Kings most excellent Majesty by and
with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Co[m]mons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the authority of the same That the Act made in the Third yeare of the reigne of King William
and Queen Mary intituled An Act to take away. Clergy from some offenders and to bring others to punishment
which by [an<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Act made in the Fourth and Fifth yeares of the (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) said King and Queen intituled An Act for
reviving continuing and explaining several Laws therein mentioned which are expired and neare expireing was
explained &amp; was to continue and bee in force for Three yeares from the Thirteenth day of February One thousand
six hundred ninety two and from thence to the end of the next Session of Parliament and noe longer [together
with the explanation thereof in the said Act made in the said Fourth and Fifth yeares<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] shall bee and the same is
and are hereby continued and shall bee in force and bee made perpetual.</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. 3 &amp; 4 (3) W. &amp; M. c. 14. made perpetual.</head>
<para id="p3">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That an Act made in the Third and Fourth yeares of the
reigne of the said King and Queen intituled An Act for relief of Creditors against fraudulent devises which was
to continue and bee in force for Three yeares and to the end of the next Session of Parliament after the
expiration of the said Three yeares and noe longer shall bee and is hereby continued and shall bee in force and
to bee made perpetual.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. 4 &amp; 5 W. &amp; M. c. 20. continued for One Year.</head>
<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That an Act made in the Fourth and Fifth yeares of the
said King and Queen intituled An Act for the better discovery of Judgments in the Courts of Kings-Bench
Common Pleas and Exchequer att Westm[m] which was to continue and bee in force for one yeare and from the
Five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety and three and from thence to the end of the
next Session of Parliam[en]t and noe longer shall bee and is hereby continued and shall bee in force for the space
of one yeare more and from thence to the end of the next Session of Parliament &amp; noe longer.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">another <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">of the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


