<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46434" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>An Act to indempnifie Sir Thomas Cooke from Actions which hee might bee liable to by reason of his discovering to whom hee paid and distributed several summs of money therein mencioned to bee received out of the Treasure of the East-India Company or for any prosecution for such distribution. [Chapter XV. Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		
		<para id="p1000"><emph type="i">Recital that it appears that Sir Thomas Cooke received of the East India Company's Stock &pound;77,258 and &pound;90,000; that a true Discovery of the Application thereof is necessary; and that the said Sir Thomas Cooke had offered to make the same on Indemnity.</emph></para>
		<para id="p1"><emph type="i">Indemnity to Sir Thomas Cooke on his making such Discovery on Oath as to the said &pound;90,000, and as to &pound;67,000, Part of the said &pound;77,258.</emph></para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas it appeares by the books of the East-India Company that Sir Thomas Cooke Knight in the yeare
One thousand six hundred ninety and three being then Governor of the said Company did receive out
of the Stock and Treasure belonging to the same the sum of Seventy seven thousand two hundred fifty and eight
pounds and hath alsoe received out of the Stock and Treasure of the said Company the further su[m]m of Ninety thousand
pounds. And whereas a true discovery of the distribution and application of the said several su[m]ms of money will
bee of publick use &amp; service and is necessary to the vindicateing the Justice and Honor of the Government and
the said Sir Thomas Cooke hath voluntarily offerd to make such discovery soe as hee may bee indempnified in such
manner as is hereafter mentioned and p[ro]vided Bee it therefore enacted by the Kings most excellent Majesty by and
with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled
and by the authority of the same That if the said Sir Thomas Cooke shall on or before the Three and twentieth day of
April One thousand six hundred ninety five make a true and full discovery upon Oath [before a Committee of
the Lords and Commons to bee appointed by each House for that purpose (which Oath the said Committee are
hereby impowered to administer)<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] how and in what manner and to what persone or persons and to what particular
uses intents and purposes and on what account the said su[m]m of Ninety thousand pounds and the sum of Sixty
seven thousand pounds part of the said [su[m]me of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Seventy seven thousand two hundred fifty eight pounds have
been distributed paid applied disposed and made use of then the said Sir Thomas Cooke shall not by reason or
means of such discovery bee liable to any action or suit of any person or persons whatsoever other than the said
East-India Company nor shall such discovery or confession bee allowed or given in evidence against him in or upon
any action or suit other then as aforesaid And alsoe shall bee and is hereby declared pardoned and indempnified
for any Crime hee [may bee<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] guilty of [guilty of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] in the distribution payment application or disposal of the said
money to any person other then to himselfe.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Sir Thomas Cooke, on or before 1st Sept. 1695, to discharge himself, or to discover on Oath how he has applied &pound;10,258, Residue of the said &pound;77,258.</head>
			<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Indemnity in such Case to Sir Thomas Cooke.</emph></para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said Sir Thomas Cooke shall on or before the
First day of September One thousand six hundred ninety five either discharge himselfe upon Oath to the Commissioners
appointed for stating and taking the Publick Accounts of this Kingdome of and concerning the su[m]m of Ten thousand
two hundred fifty eight pounds [residue of the said Seventy seven thousand two hundred fifty eight pounds<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] or
discover upon Oath to the said Co[m]missioners how and in what manner and to what person or persons and to
what particular uses intents and purposes and on what account the said su[m]m of Ten thousand two hundred fifty
eight pounds hath been distributed paid applied disposed or made use of [And in such case the said Sir Thomas
Cooke shall not by reason or meanes of such discovery or dischargeing himselfe upon Oath bee liable to any action
or suit of any person or persons whatsoever other then the said East-India Company nor shall such his discharging
himselfe or discovery bee allowed or given in evidence against him in or upon any action or suit other then as
aforesaid And alsoe shall bee and is hereby declared pardoned for any Crime hee may have been guilty off in
the distribution paym[en]t. application or disposeal of the said moneys to any person (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) then to himselfe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Report of the said Discovery laid before Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p5">And it is hereby further enacted by the authority aforesaid That a report of the said discovery and confession
shall by the Members of each House respectively (who are of the said Committee bee forthwith laid before each
House in Writing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. If Sir Thomas Cooke do not make such Discovery on or before 23d April, then to remain a Prisoner in the Tower till he make the same.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided always and bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That if the said Sir Thomas Cooke shall not
on or before the said Three and twentieth day of April make such true and full discovery in manner aforesaid
That then and in such case bee the said Sir Thomas Cooke shall from thenceforth by virtue of this Act continue
and remaine a Prisoner in the Tower of London until bee shall have made such true and full discovery upon Oath
before the Commissioners appointed for taking and stating the Publick Accounts of this Kingdome or any Foure
of them who are hereby impowered and required to send for and examine the said Sir Thomas Cooke and to
administer the said Oath and to report such discovery and confession under their hands and seales to both Houses
of Parliament att their next Meeting.<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">may have been <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4"><emph type="i">O</emph> omits.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">annexed to the Original Act in separate Schedules.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

