<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46435" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVI. An Act to prevent Exactions of the Occupiers of Locks and Weares upon the River of Thames westward and for
ascertaining the Rates of Water-carriage upon the said River. [Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Recital that the Thames and Isis have always been navigable, that divers Locks, &amp;c. have been on Toll, and that the Tolls have been greatly raised, and Abuses committed by Bargemen.; Power to Justices of Peace of Wilts, Gloucester, &amp;c. as Commissioners in Quarter Sessions, to set the Rates for passing the Wears, &amp;c. upon Thames and Isis, and to make Orders therein, and concerning the Navigation and Behaviour of Bargemen, &amp;c.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whreas the Rivers of Thames and Isis have time out of mind been navigable from the City of London
to the Village of Bercott in the County of Oxford and for diverse yeares last past from the said Village of
Bercott westward somewhat farther then Letchlade in the County of Gloucester. And whereas for the benefitt and
convenience of the Navigation there have been and are diverse Locks Weares Bucks Winches Turnpikes Dams
Floodgates and other Engines in upon or neare adjoyning to the said Rivers the Tennants or Occupiers whereof
antiently took and still ought to take a moderate and reasonable price from the owners of all Barges Boats or
other Vessells haveing occasion to make use of the same or of their assistance for or in their passage but have
of late yeares raised their prices soe high that the price of the Water-carriage on those Rivers by reason thereof
has been alsoe very much raised. And whereas diverse abuses have heretofore been committed by the Bargemen
in their Navigation upon the said Rivers. For remedy whereof bee it therefore enacted by the Kings most excellent
Majestie by &amp; with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present
Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That from and after the First day of May which shall bee
in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety five the Justices of the Peace for the time being of
the [of the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] several Counties of Wiltes Gloucester Oxford Berks and Bucks within their respective Counties for ever
hereafter shall bee and are hereby declared to bee Comissioners for the putting in execution [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the powers and
authorities herein after mentioned (that is to say) the said Commissioners or any Five of them shall have full
power and authority from time to time att their respective General Quarter Sessions of the Peace upon due
ex&amacr;&imacr;c[i]on of the matter in controversie upon Oath to make orders and constitutions for settling and ascertaining
reasonable rates and prices to bee taken from the Owners of all Barges Boats or Vessels by the Tenants or Occupiers
of all such Locks Weares Bucks Winches Turnpikes Dams Floodgates or other Engines within their said respective
Counties for the help and assistance which such Barges Boats or Vessels may or shall receive thereby or by meanes
thereof in their passage upon the said Rivers regard being had as well to the antient rates which have been taken as
the necessary charges of repairing such Locks Wears Bucks Winches Turnpikes Floodgates and other Engines and
alsoe to constitute and appoint all such other necessary rules and orders concerning the said Navigation and alsoe
concerning such Locks Weares Bucks Winches Turnpikes Dams (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) and other Engines within their said respective
Counties and the shutting penning opening drawing use or management thereof for the benefitt and safety of the
said Navigation and concerning all Barges Boats or Vessells passing by through or with the helpe of the same and
the behaviour of all Bargemen Boatmen and Watermen belonging to or working in such Barges Boats or Vessells
soe as to prevent such abuses which have been frequently heretofore committed by them in the Navigation as to
the said Comissioners or any Five of them shall seem meet.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Power to the said Justices of Peace in Sessions to settle the Rates of Water Carriage upon Thames, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Taking more than Rate assessed; Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That from and after the said First day of May the said
Justices of the Peace or any Five of them in their respective General Quarter Sessions next after Easter-Day
yearely shall have power and authority and they are hereby enjoyned and required to assesse and rate the prices
of the carriage of all sorts of Goods whatsoever from any place in their said respective Counties to any other
place or places upon the said Rivers in such Boats Barges or Vessells and shall give publick notice in Writing
to the Mayor or other Head Officer in every Markett Towne within their said respective Counties of the rates
and prices soe sett and assessed and of all other rates and prices which shall bee rated and assessed by virtue of
this Act And if any Owner or Proprietor of any such Barge Boat or Vessell shall att any time after such Notice
take for the Water-carriage of any Goods or Merchandizes above the rates and prices soe sett as aforesaid or if
any person or persons whatsoever shall break or act contrary to any rules orders or constitutions which shall bee
made in pursuance of this Act every such person soe offending shall for every offence forfeit the su[m]m of Five
pounds to bee recovered by the party grieved with double costs of suit in any action of debt bill plaint or
informac[i]on to bee commenced or prosecuted in any of his Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster wherein noe
essoigne protection or wager of Law shall bee allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Justices of Assize for Oxfordshire may vacate Orders made by the said Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Limitation of Complaint</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">Provided neverthelesse and bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any person or persons whatsoever
shall bee agrieved by reason of any such rules [order<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] constitutions or assessments soe as aforesaid to bee made
by the said Commissioners or any Five of them it shall and may bee lawfull to and for the Justices of Assize
of the said County of Oxford for the time being upon complaint made by such person or persons grieved within
the space of One yeare next after the making of such rules orders constitutions or assessments to confirme
vacate or alter the same in such manner as shall bee thought most convenient.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Orders by Justices of Peace to be registered in Sessions, and to continue for Seven Years, and thence till new Orders made by Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided alsoe and bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That all such rules orders constitutions
and assessments other then of the rates for carriage which shall bee made by the said Commissioners or any Five
of them in pursuance of this Act shall bee written in parchment and signed by the said Commissioners or any
Five of them and bee kept amongst the records of the Session of the Peace of that County within which the
same shall bee made And the said rules orders constitutions and assessments other then of the rates for carriage
soe signed by the said Commissioners or confirmed or altered on such appeal as aforesaid shall continue in force
from the making the same by the said Commissioners or the confirmation or alteration thereof by the said Justices
of Assize for Seven yeares and from thence until some new order rule constitution or assessment shall bee made
in the same case by the said Commissioners or any Five of them every which new order rule constitution or
assessment shall bee subject to the like appeal as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Locks, &amp;c. adjudged to be in County where they pay the Poors' Rate.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided always That if att any time after the said First day of May any doubt shall bee made amongst the
aid Commissioners in what County any such locks weares bucks winches or other engines are or shall bee then
and in every such case for preventing of all such disputes every such lock weare buck winch or other engine
hall bee adjudged and taken to bee in that County and subject to the jurisdiction of the Commissioners of that
County within which the same are taxed or rated to the Church or Poor.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Jurisdiction to Commissioners between Bercott and Oxford.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Provison for Powers given to Commissioners under 21 Jac. I. c. 32. Subjea to Appeal. Proviso for Death or Removal of Commissioners</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">Provided alsoe That nothing herein contained shall bee construed to give any manner of jurisdiction to any of
the said Commissioners to putt in execution any of the powers or authorities hereby granted [or directed between
y<emph type="p">e</emph> said village of Bercott &amp; y<emph type="p">e</emph> city of Oxford nor to repeale or impeach y<emph type="p">e</emph> powers or authorities granted<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] to the
Com[m]issioners in and by an Act made in the One and twentieth yeare of the reigne of King James the First
intituled An Act for making the River of Thames navigable for barges boats and lighters from the village of Bercott
in the County of Oxford unto the University and City of Oxford but that the said Commissioners or the more part of
them by virtue thereof and of this Act shall have power and authority from time to time with such consent as in
the said first recited Act is required to ordaine and make orders, and constitutions for the good and orderly usage
of the passage by water on the River of Thames betwixt the City of Oxford and the village of Bercott and for
all locks weares or turnpikes thereof made or to bee made and maintained att the charge of the University and
City of Oxford or otherwise and for the reparation and amendments thereof And for all boats boatmen passengers
wharfs carriages and rates for carriages by or through the said passage And to sett lay doe and execute all
things concerning the same as in the said first recited Act are ordained and directed subject neverthelesse to such
an appeal as is therein mentioned And alsoe that upon the death or removal of any of the present Co[m]missioners
for executing the said recited Act the surviving Commissioners for the University and City of Oxford respectively
may att any time hereafter by virtue hereof nominate and elect any person they think fitt to bee a Com[m]issioner
and with them to execute all and every the powers in the said recited Act according to the true intent and
meaning thereof and of this present Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for the City of London.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alsoe That nothing herein contained shall bee construed to impeach or lessen any jurisdiction power
or authority of the Mayor Co[m]monalty and Citizens of the City of London or of any other Body Politick or
Corporate or other person or persons whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Bargemasters chargeable for any Mischief done to Locks, &amp;c. by their Bargemen, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Damages and Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And for the better preventing the damags and mischeifs frequently done and co[m]mitted by the rude and disorderly
persons rowing and manageing the said barges and that the owners of such barges may bee more careful to prevent
the same bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That every Bargemaster and Owner of any Barge or Boat
shall bee and is hereby made answerable and responsible for any damage or mischief that shall bee done by his
barge or boat or the whole or any of the crew of his bargemen to any [of the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] weares locks bucks winches
turnpikes dams floodgates and other engines in and upon the said River And the said Bargemasters or Bargeowners
shall and may bee sued and prosecuted for the same and if found guilty the Pltiffe shall not onely recover his
damages thereby sustained but his full costs of suit any former law or usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Continuance of Act.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided always That this Act shall continue and bee in force for the terme of Nine yeares and from thence
to the end of the next session of Parliament and noe longer.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Floodgates <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">orders <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


