<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46438" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for imprisoning Sir Thomas Cook Sir Bazill Firebrace Charles Bates Esq. and James Craggs and restraining them from aliening their estates. [Chapter XIX. Rot. Parl. pt. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that an Act of Parliament and Charter relating to the East India Company had been obtained with the Privity of Sir Thomas Cooke and others and that they had not made any full Discovery relating thereto.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The said Persons committed to the Tower</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS by several informations and examinations taken before certaine Committees of both Houses
dureing this present Session of Parliament it doth appeare [That<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] there have been diverse practices (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) by
corrupt meanes [to procure<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] a Charter and an Act of Parliament to bee granted and passed relateing to the East
India Company And Sir Thomas Cooke Knight Sir Bazill Firebrace Knight Charles Bates Esq[uire] and James Craggs
have been privy to the same and haveing not upon their examinations hitherto made a full or satisfactory discovery
concerning the premisses, Now to the end that their persons and estates may bee secured so as to answer and
bee liable to justice in Parliament Bee it enacted by the Kings most excellent Majesty by and with the advice
and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in Parliament assembled and by authority of the
same That the said Sir Thomas Cooke Sir Bazill Firebrace Charles Bates and James Craggs shall bee and are
hereby committed to the Tower of London there to remaine in custody without bail or mainprize until the end
of the next Session of Parliament unlesse they shall sooner bee discharged by his Majesty by the consent of the
Two Houses of Parliament.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. And disabled during such Commitment from aliening their Estates, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">except for Subsistence</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said Sir Thomas Cooke Sir Bazill Firebace Charles
Bates and James Craggs shall from and after the First day of May in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred ninety and five dureing the time in which they shall or ought to bee detained in custody by virtue of
this Act bee disabled from aliening settling charging or incumbring any of their lands tenements or hereditaments
otherwise then by their last wills and testaments in case they shall happen to die within the said time And
alsoe shall dureing the [said time<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] bee disabled from conveying or granting of any of their personal estate in trust
for themselves their wives or children and alsoe from otherwise disposeing of any of their personal estate except
for the subsistance of themselves and their families or for paying such just debts as are or shall bee due or
contracted before the Three and twentieth day of April in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
ninety and five and except perishable goods.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Power to dispose by Will.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided that this Act shall not extend to disable them from disposeing of any of their estates by their last
wills and testaments in case they shall happen to die dureing the time aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Sir Bazill Firebrace giving a Portion with his Daughter.</head>
			<para id="p6">[Provided always That the said Sir Bazill Firebrace may give with his daughter in marriage such portion and
provision as hee hath already agreed to give not exceeding the value of Twenty thousand pounds Any thing
herein contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">to procure <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">time aforesaid <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

