<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46437" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVIII. An Act for granting to his Majestie certaine duties upon glasse wares stone and earthen bottles coals and
culme for carrying on the Warr against France [Rot. Parl. pt. 5. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Duties laid upon Glass Wares, and Stone and Earthen Bottles made here or imported, for Five Years.</head>
		<para id="p1">Wee your Majesties most dutiful and loyal Subjects the Co[m]mons [in Parliament assembled<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] for a further supply
of your Majesties extraordinary Occasions for and towards the necessary defence of your Realmes and
carrying on of the Warr against the French King doe humbly present your Majestie with the gift of the Impositions
Rates and Duties herein after mentioned And doe beseech your Majesty that it may bee enacted. And bee it
enacted by the Kings most excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and
Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That for and
dureing the terme of Five yeares commencing from the Nine and twentieth day of September in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred ninety five there shall bee raised levyed collected and paid unto and for the use
of his Majesty for and upon all glass and glasse wares and for and upon all stone and earthen bottles which att
any time or times within or dureing the said terme of five yeares shall bee made within this Kingdom of England
Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed or imported or brought into the same the several and
respective impositions rates duties and su[m]ms of money herein after mentioned over and above all such customes
and duties as are already payable for or upon the importation of any such commodities (that is to say.)</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Quart Bottles, &#x0026;c. of Glass, Stone, or Earth, per Dozen, 12d</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">For all quart bottles of green glasse flask glasse or any other kind of glasse whatsoever and for all glasse
Bottle works whatsoever co[m]monly called or reputed quarts whether the same bee or shall bee plaine or marked
or called rounds squares receivers retorts bolt-heads still-heads bodies handle-bottles or any other kind of glasse
bottles or bottle-works whatsoever And for all stone and earthen bottles and bottle-works of what kind soever
commonly called or taken for quarts a piece (flint glasse bottles excepted) which att any time or times within or
dureing the said terme of Five yeares shall bee made within the said Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales
or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed or which (not being made or manufactured within the same Kingdome Dominion
or Towne aforesaid) shall bee imported or brought into the same the su[m]m of Twelve pence of lawfull English
money for every Dozen reckoning Twelve to the Dozen and noe more and after that rate for a greater or lesser
number.</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Pint Bottles, &#x0026;c. of Glass, Stone, or Earth, per Dozen, 6d</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p5">For all pint bottles or bottle-works co[m]monly called or reputed for pints of glasse stone or earth (flint glasse
bottles excepted) which att any time or times within or dureing the aforesaid terme shall bee made within the
Kingdome Dominion or Towne aforesaid or bee imported or brought into the same there shall bee paid the su[m]m
of Six pence of like money for every such Dozen and after that rate for a greater or lesser number.</para>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">Bottles less than Pints, and more than Quarts in Proportion to those before mentioned</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p7">For all such bottles and bottle-works of glasse stone or earth holding lesse then pints or more then quarts
a piece (flint glasse bottles excepted) which att any time or times within or dureing the aforesaid terme shall bee
made within the Kingdome Dominion or Towne aforesaid or imported or brought into the same there shall bee
paid in like money for every such dozen a certaine duty which shall beare the same proportion to the measure
or bignesse of such bottells or bottle works as the su[m]m of Twelve pence beares to the measure or bignesse of the
said quart bottles or the su[m]m of Six pence beares to the measure or bignesse of the said pint bottles and after
that rate for a greater or lesser number than twelve.</para>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">Flint Bottles, Coach-glass, &#x0026;c. &pound;20 per Cent</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p9">For all flint glasse-bottles and all glasses and glasse works of flint or that shall bee flint mixed with christall
or other ingredients and made in a furnace commonly called a flint or christal furnace And for all looking
glasse plates coach glasse plates and [and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] all other sort of plate glasse or glasse plates made or manufactured within
the Kingdom Dominion or Towne aforesaid or which shall bee imported as aforesaid into the same (not being
otherwise charged by this Act) there shall bee paid a duty to bee computed after the rate of Twenty pounds for
every hundred pounds of the true and real value of the same.</para>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">Window Glass, &pound;10 per Cent</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p11">For all window glasse or glasse made in tables or otherwise proper to bee used in glazed windows which att
any time or times dureing the said terme shall bee made or manufactured in this Kingdom Dominion or Towne
aforesaid or which shall bee imported into the same there shall bee paid a duty to bee computed after the rate of
Tenne pounds for every hundred pounds of the true and real value thereof.</para>
		<para id="p12">
			<emph type="i">All Glass not mentioned, &pound;15 per Cent</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p13">And for all other sorts of glasses glasse works and glasse wares of what nature or kind soever (not herein
before particularly charged) which att any time or times dureing the said terme shall bee made or manufactured in
the Kingdom Dominion or Towne aforesaid or which shall bee imported as aforesaid there shall bee paid a duty
to bee computed after the rate of Fifteen pounds for every Hundred pounds of the true and real value of
the same.</para>
		<para id="p14">
			<emph type="i">Duties to be paid by Maker and Importer</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p15">All which said rates or duties by this Act imposed for and upon such of the said commodities as shall bee
made in this Kingdome Dominion or Towne aforesaid shall bee paid by the respective maker [or<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] makers of the same
and for such of the said commodities as shall bee imported or brought in as aforesaid shall bee paid by the
respective importer or importers thereof over and above such duties as are already payable upon such importation.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Duties for Goods imported to be paid by Importer before landing. Landing before Entry and Duties paid, or without Warrant;</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the duties hereby sett on all the said forreigne and
imported commodities of glasse stone or earth shall bee from time to time satisfied and paid by the importer or
importers of the same in ready money upon his or their entry or entries made and before the landing thereof
And that in case such forreigne or imported commodities of the kinds before mentioned shall bee landed or putt
on shore out of any shipp or vessell from beyond the seas before due entry bee made thereof in the Custom
House in the port or place where the same shall bee imported and the duties hereby imposed shall bee fully
satisfied and paid or without any warrant for the landing and delivering of such imported commodities of the
kinds aforesaid first signed by the Commissioners Collectors or other proper Officer or Officers of his Majesties
Customs respectively that all such imported co[m]modities of the kinds aforesaid as shall bee soe landed or putt on shore
or delivered contrary to the true intent and meaning hereof or the value of the same shall bee forfeited and
lost and shall or may bee recovered of the importer or proprietor thereof to witt One moiety of the same to
the use of his Majesty his heires and successors the other moiety to the use of him or them that will seize the
said commodities or sue for the same or the value thereof by action of debt bill suit or information wherein noe
essoigne protection wager of law or more then one imparlance shall bee granted or allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Duties to be managed by Commissioners of the Customs.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Receivers to pay into the Exchequer distinct; Goods paying ad valorem Duty valued on Oath of Importer; Duties levied as Poundage</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And it is hereby further enacted That the said duties on such of the said commodities as shall bee imported
as aforesaid shall bee from time to time under the management and government of the Commissioners of his
Majesties Customes for the time being who shall cause the same from time to time to bee (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) levied collected and
paid by his Majesties Officers of the Customs to the hands of the Receiver or Receivers General of the Revenue
of the Customes And such Receiver [or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Receivers General for the time being shall answer and pay the moneys
ariseing thereby into his Majesties Exchequer distinct and apart from all other branches within his or their receipts
And for such of the said enumerated commodities imported as aforesaid the duties whereof are hereby appointed
to bee paid according to the value of the same the respective Customer or Collector or other person Officer or
Officers of the Customes for the time being shall receive and levy such duties hereby imposed according to the
value and price of such goods to bee esteemed upon the oath of the Merchant or Importer And such oath
shall bee administred and all other matters done for ascertaining recovering and levying the said duties hereby
granted upon the values of the said imported commodities in the same manner and forme as are now lawfully
used and practised in cases where goods pay the subsidy of poundage or other duties ad valorem upon the
importation thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Commissioners to be appointed for managing the Duties on Home Goods.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Duty (Exception) to be paid into the Exchequer; Treasury have Power to set Rules to the Officers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And for the beeter ascertaining the duties by this Act charged and imposed upon such of the said commodities
of glasse earth and stone as shall bee made and manufactured in England Wales or Towne of Berwick as aforesaid
And for the better raiseing levying and collecting of the same according to the true meaning of this Act Be it
further enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may bee lawfull to and for his Majestie his Heires
or Successors or to and for the Commissioners of the Tresury or any three or more of them now being or the
High Tresurer of England or any three or more of the Commissioners of the Tresury for the time being in writing
to commissionate or appoint such persons as they shall think fitt from time to time to bee the Commissioners
or Surveyors for the said duties who shall hereby have power to substitute deputies or inferior officers under them
for the purposes aforesaid and shall cause all the moneys ariseing by the said duties (except the necessary charge in
manageing or collecting of the same) to bee brought and paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer from time
to time to his Majesties use And the said Commissioners of the Tresury or any Three or more of them now
being or the High Tresurer of England or any Three or more of the Commissioners of the Tresury for the time
being are hereby impowered from time to time to sett downe settle and prescribe such orders rules and instructions
for the better guidance of the said officers or any of them in and for the ascertaining charging and collecting of
the duties hereby imposed or intended to bee imposed upon the said commodities manufactured in England Wales
and Towne of Berwick as aforesaid as shall bee most conduceing and agreeable to the ends and intent of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. The Value of Home Goods paying ad valorem Duties, how ascertained.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Power to Officers to add &pound;20 per Cent. to Value if the Crown appears to be defrauded</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And it is hereby, declared and enacted that the values of such of the said commodities [made<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] in England
Wales or the Towne of Berwick as by this Act are to pay the duties ad valorem shall in all cases bee taken to
bee so much as such commodities shall bee worth to bee sold as soon as they are perfectly made or fitt for
use And in case any dispute or controversie shall att any time or times arise touching the valuation of any such
commodities between the maker or makers thereof and his Majesties officer or officers (which said officer and officers
are to bee under such orders and instructions as are before mentioned) in all and every such case and cases the value
of such goods shall bee esteemed by the affidavitt of such maker or makers to bee made in writing before any
of his Majesties Justices of the Peace (who are hereby impowered to take the same) and to bee delivered to the
said officer or officers who shall thereupon have power by this Act (if he thinks his Majesty to bee apparently
defrauded) to take such goods att the value specified in such affidavitt) and Twenty per centum more for his
Majesties use paying down ready money to the maker for the same Which ready money soe paid downe shall
bee allowed upon the accounts to bee made to his Majesty for the Duties aforesaid and the goods in such cases
shall bee sold and disposed of for his Majesties best advantage and profitt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Makers to give Three Days Notice of kindling their Fires, Penalty &pound;10;</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">and to make Entries of Quantities within Twenty-four Hours after Goods made; Duties to be paid within Three Months; Removing Goods without Permit (to be signed by Officer gratis;) Penalty; &pound;10 per Cent. for present Payment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And it is hereby further enacted by the authority aforesaid That all and every the maker or makers of the
said manufactures of glasse earth or stone or any of them before hee she or they doe kindle any fire or fires
for the makeing or working of the said manufactures shall give notice thereof to some of his Majesties Officers
within three days before such fire shall bee kindled under the penalty of Tenne pounds for every default in not
giving such notice to bee forfeited the one moiety thereof to the use of his Majesty and the other moiety thereof
to him or them that shall sue for the same as aforesaid And that the respective makers or proprietors of the
said glasse wares and of the said stone and earthen bottles whilst their several fires are burning and as often as
they shall make any of the manufactures of [stone glasse<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] or earth as aforesaid shall from time to time within
twenty foure houres after the drawing or perfect makeing of any such manufactures as aforesaid make true entries
with his Majesties officer or officers as shall bee appointed to attend such works respectively or give them true
accounts in writing daily of the several quantities of such manufactures as shall bee soe by them respectively
made setting downe fully and truely the several quantities of such goods that shall bee made every day distinctly
by their several kinds as they ought to pay by this Act And shall upon the drawing or perfect makeing of
any such commodities as aforesaid or within three months after pay his Majesties duties by this Act payable for
the same And shall likewise have a permission signed by some one of the said Officers to carry away every or
any parcel of such commodities before such time as the same shall bee removed or carried away from the warehouse
or other place where such goods shall bee first putt after their being drawne under the several penalties and
forfeitures herein after mentioned Which warrants the said Officers are hereby required to give gratis unto the
said makers or proprietors of such glasse stone or earthen commodities upon paying the said duties hereby granted
or secureing the same to bee paid within the said three months And if any such maker or makers att the time of
such entry shall pay downe the duty hereby imposed hee or they shall bee allowed for such prompt payment
after the rate of Tenne pounds per Centum per Annum upon every su[m]m soe to bee paid for the said time of
Three months.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Officer may search Glass-house, &#x0026;c. in the Day-time.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">Goods not entered, or concealed, forfeited, and may be seized</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that it shall and may bee lawfull to and for the said
Officer and Officers soe to bee appointed as aforesaid att all seasonable times in the day time to search and see
what quantities of the said co[m]modities are makeing in any glasse-house or kilne [or<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] what quantities thereof shall
bee in any ware-house or other place belonging thereunto And if any maker or makers owner or owners of
any of the said commodities of glasse earth or stone shall endeavour to defraud his Majesty of any duties by this
Act payable either by not makeing due entries or giving account as aforesaid or by removeing or carrying away
any such commodities from the warehouse or other place where the same shall bee first putt after drawing or
perfect makeing as aforesaid before his Majesties duties shall bee paid or secured and a permission given for
carrying away such goods as aforesaid or shall fraudulently hide or conceal any of the said commodities to the
intent to deceive his Majesty of his just dues for the same that then and in every such case the goods for
which noe such entry or account shall bee made or given or that shall bee soe unlawfully removed or carried
away or fraudulently hid or concealed shall bee forfeited and shall and may bee seized by any the Officer or
Officers aforesaid to his Majesties use.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. No Fee for Entries, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p28">Provided always and it is hereby enacted that noe Fee or Reward shall bee had or taken by any of the said
Officers from any of the said makers for the entries accounts or permissions aforesaid or any of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. No Duty for imperfect Goods.</head>
			<para id="p29">Provided alsoe that if any of the said glasse stone or earthen manufactures shall upon the drawing thereof
from the leer arch or kilne bee forthwith broken because they appeare to bee imperfectly made noe duty shall
grow due for the same by virtue of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Duties repaid upon Exportation.</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Oath on such Repayment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">Provided alsoe that if any person or persons shall export beyond the Seas any of the said manufactures or
commodities of glasse stone or earth that then upon oath made that the duties first due and payable to his Majesty for
the same by this Act were duely paid or secured and upon security to bee first given that the goods shall not
bee relanded in England Wales or Berwick which oath shall and may bee administred and the said security taken
by the Customer or Comptroller of the Port where such exportation shall bee had the duties which shall have
been paid for such of the said commodities soe exported shall bee repaid or soe much shall bee discharged upon
the security before given for the same Any thing in this Act before mentioned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Furnaces and Utensils charged with the Duties, in whose Hands soever they may be.</head>
			<para id="p32">
				<emph type="i">Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p33">And it is hereby further enacted that all and every the furnaces and other utensils for makeing of any the
said manufactures of glasse earth or stone in whose hands soever they shall come or howsoever they shall bee
claimed shall bee liable and subject to and are hereby charged with all and singular the arrears or duties which
shall be owing to his Majestie for any of the said commodities in the makeing whereof such furnaces or utensils
have been imployed and (in case of non payment thereof) shall and may bee distrained seized and sold for the
same by any his Majesties officers aforesaid who shall render the overplus of the moneys ariseing thereby (after
payment of the duty with reasonable charges) to the owner or owners of the said furnaces or utensills.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Duties upon Coal or Culm brought into any Port for Five Years.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Particular Rates</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that for all sorts of Coals and Culm (except Charcoal
made of wood) which from and after the said Nine and twentieth day of September in the yeare of our Lord
one thousand six hundred ninety five shall bee water-borne or shall bee laid on board any shipp or vessell to bee
carried imported or brought or which shall bee carried imported or brought in any shipp or vessell into any
port or place in the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed from any port
or place within the said Kingdom Dominion or Towne of Berwicke or from the Kingdome of Scotland in or dureing
the space of Five yeares commencing from the said Nine and twentieth day of September there shall bee paid and
answered unto his Majesty his Heires and Successors (over and besides all other impositions duties and su[m]ms of
money in any wise due or payable for the same) the several and respective impositions rates duties and su[m]ms of
money following (that is to say.)</para>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">Coals per Chaldron 58</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">For every Chaldron of all such sorts of Coals as are usually sold by measure reckoning Six and thirty bushels
to the Chaldron Winchester measure the su[m]m of Five shillings.</para>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">Culm per Chaldron 1s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">And for every Chaldron of Culme reckoning Six and thirty bushells to the Chaldron Winchester measure the
su[m]m of One shilling.</para>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">Coals sold by Weight, per Ton 58</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">And for every Tun of all sorts of Coals usually sold by weight imported or carried in any shipp or vessell from
any part of England or Wales or from Scotland into any other part or place in England or Wales reckoning Twenty
hundred weight to each Tun the su[m]m of Five shillings.</para>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">Duties to be paid in the Port of Importation before breaking Bulk; and before Meter appointed; Receipt for the same without Fee; Coals or Culm unshipped before Duties paid, Coals and Ship forfeited</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">Which said several impositions rates duties and su[m]ms of money aforesaid shall from time to time dureing the
said terme of Five yeares be answered and paid att the respective ports and places of Importation or landing of the
said Coals and Culme unto his Majesty his Heires and Successors or to such Officer or person as shall by his
Majesty his Heires or Successors or by the Commissioners of his Majesties Customes or any Foure or more
of them for the time being under their hands and seales bee thereunto appointed by the master owner or owners
or other person or persons haveing or takeing the charge of any shipp or vessel on which any (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) Coals or Culme
shall bee laden or wherein they shall bee imported carried or brought before bulk of the said shipp or vessell
shall bee broken or any the said Coals or Culme unladen and before any meeter measurer or weigher shall bee
appointed for the [weighing or measureing<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] thereof upon receipt whereof the party appointed to receive the same
shall without delay fee or reward deliver a receipt under his hand to the person or persons who shall pay the said
duty which receipt shall for soe much bee a sufficient discharge of all which shipps and vessells and of
the coals and culme therein imported or brought due entries shall from time to time bee made in the Custom
House of or belonging to such port or place where such importation shall bee made (if any Custome House
[shall<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] bee there) or else in the Custome House of the next port or place where such importation shall bee
and in case any of the said Coals or Culme shall bee unshipped to bee laid on land before the impositions duties
or su[m]ms aforesaid respectively due for the same shall bee paid or secured that then aswell the said Coals and
Culme soe unshipped as alsoe the shipp or vessell out of which the same shall bee soe unshipped with all her
guns tackle furniture and ammunition shall bee forfeited and lost one moiety of which forfeitures shall bee unto
his Majesty his Heires and Successors and the other moiety to such person or persons as shall seize sue or informe
for the same to bee recovered in any of his Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster by action of debt bill
plaint or informac[i]on wherein noe essoigne protection or wager of law shall bee admitted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. The King, or Four Commissioners of the Customs, may appoint Meters and Weighers, who are to certify the Measure and Weight of the Coals;</head>
			<para id="p44">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;100. Paying Duty for less than certified; Penalty; Remedy for such Penalty and Duties; On Post-Entry and Payment within Six Days, Penalty discharged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p45">And to the end that the said impositions and duties may bee duely answered and paid without fraud or covin
and for the better levying and collecting thereof and for the discovery of the just quantities of all sorts of coals
and culme to bee water-born imported or unladen as aforesaid bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid that
it shall and may bee lawfull to and for his Majesty his heires or successors or to or for any foure or more
of the said Commissioners of the Customes for the time being by writeing under their hands and seales from time
to time to assigne and appoint within each Port or Place within the said Kingdome of England Dominion of
Wales, or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed such and soe many meeters weighers and measurers of the said coals
and culme as shall within the terme aforesaid bee imported brought or landed in such Port or Place wherein
or for which such meeters weighers or measurers shall bee assigned or appointed as aforesaid who shall from time
to time measure and weigh all such coals and culme soe imported or brought and when and as soon as any such
shipp or vessell shall bee unladen shall forthwith deliver a true certificate in writing under his or their hand or
hands unto the person or persons appointed to receive the said impositions or duties within such Port or Place
of the sorts quantities and numbers of chaldrons or tuns of coals or culme respectively which shall bee measured
or weighed and delivered from on board any such shipp or vessell under the penalty of One hundred pounds
And in case it shall appeare by such certificate or otherwise that there was on board any such shipp or vessell
a greater number of chaldrons or tuns of coals or culm than for which the said impositions or duties hereby
imposed shall have been answered and paid as aforesaid that then in every such case there shall bee paid unto
his Majesty his heires and successors by the master or owners of such shipp or vessell for every chaldron or tun
of coals or culm soe concealed over and above the impositions and duties aforesaid the su[m]m of Ten shillings For
which in case of refusal to pay the same such shipp or vessell with the tackle furniture and apparel thereof or
any part thereof shall and may bee attached and detained by the officer or officers for the time being in such
Port or Place appointed to receive the said impositions or duties or to measure or weigh the said coals or culm
until payment thereof and to sell the said shipp or vessel tackle furniture and apparel or any part thereof in case
all the said impositions duties or payments before mentioned for the said concealed coals or culme shall not bee
paid and satisfied with reasonable costs and charges for such attaching detaineing and selling rendring the overplus
Which sale shall bee good and effectual in the law. Provided neverthelesse that if the Importer upon such
certificate delivered in by the measurer or weigher shall within the space of Six days after the delivery of such
shipp or vessel give in his post-entry and satisfie and pay the whole duty for the surplusage of the said Coals
or Culme appeareing upon the unladeing of such shipp or vessell then upon such payment the penalty aforesaid
shall bee discharged.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Officers to keep a Book of Accounts, and to return the Money to the Receivers of the Customs, who are to return it into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p46">And for the manifestation of the truth and certainty in the premisses Bee it further enacted by the Authority
aforesaid that the Officers to bee appointed in each Port and Place for the receiving of the said Impositions or
Duties and for the weighing and measuring of the said Coals and Culm shall respectively keep one or more
Book or Books for every such Port or Place wherein they shall respectively enter downe a true account of all
such su[m]ms of money which shall bee paid or received for or upon account of the said Impositions or Duties
and of all the payments and disbursements of the same And alsoe a true account of the numbers of Chaldrons
and Tuns of Coals and Culme soe imported and unladen in any such Port or Place and of the respective sorts
thereof And the moneys ariseing by the Impositions and Duties aforesaid are to bee paid unto the Receiver or
Receivers Generall of the Customs for the time being and by them to bee paid and returned into the Receipt
of his Majesties Exchequer for his Majesties use where the same shall bee kept and entred in Books distinct and
a part from any other branch of his Majesties Revenue.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Allowance of Seamen to Coal Ships;</head>
			<para id="p47">
				<emph type="i">Officer impressing them; Penalty &pound;10; and Incapacity</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p48">And for the encouragement of all such Shipps or Vessells as shall bee imployed in bringing Coals for supplying
the City of London and other Ports of this Kingdome att more reasonable rates then dureing this Warr they
have hitherto been Bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That from and after the said Nine and twentieth
day of September there shall bee allowed yearely from the Fifteenth day of April until the First day of January
free from impressing to every Master of any Shipp or Vessel imployed in the Coal Trade two able Seamen (such
as the Master shall nominate) for every Shipp or Vessell under One hundred Tun and one for every Fifty Tun.
for every Shipp or Vessel of One hundred Tun and upwards burthen according to the measurement [with<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] such
Shipp or Vessell shall appeare to bee of by a Certificate which shall bee produced from the Custome House of
what number of Tuns such a Shipp or Vessell hath paid for by an Act for laying a Duty on Tunnage of
shipping And if any Captaine Lieutenant or other Officer shall by any Authority whatsoever presume to impresse
or take any of the men allowed by this Act such Captaine Lieutenant or other Officer shall forfeit to the
Master or Owner of such Shipp or Vessell Ten pounds for every man hee shall soe impresse or take to bee
recovered with Costs of Suit by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of his Majesties Courts of
Record wherein noe Essoigne Protection Privedge Wager of Law Injunction or Order of restraint shall bee in
any wise granted or allowed and shall alsoe bee made incapable of holding any Place Office or Imployment in any
of his Majesties Ships of Warr.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Duty on Coals exported.</head>
			<para id="p49">And whereas the imposition upon Coals exported to Forreigne Parts is soe great that it is almost a prohibition
to the great diminution of his Majesties Customs the lessening of the English Navigation and the exportation of
Coals beyond the Seas For remedy whereof Bee it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Coals exported
beyond the Seas in Forreigne Bottoms shall dureing the continuance of this Act only pay Tenne shillings the
Chaldron and in English Bottoms onely Three shillings the Chaldron Any Law to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. A Clause of Loan for &pound;564,700 upon this Act at &pound;7 per Cent.</head>
			<para id="p50">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That from and after the Tenth day of May One thousand
six hundred ninety five it shall and may bee lawfull to and for his Majesty or his Officers in the Receipt of his
Exchequer by his command and appointment to borrow and take into the said Receipt att interest for his Majesties
use by way of loan any su[m]m or su[m]ms of money which together with the whole value or amount of all the su[m]ms
of money which shall bee collected levied and paid by virtue of this Act shall not exceed in the whole the
su[m]m of Five hundred sixty foure thousand seven hundred pounds Which su[m]m of su[m]ms of money soe to bee
taken upp or borrowed shall and may bee charged upon the Creditt of his Majesties Exchequer in general and
Tallies of Loan and Orders for repayment of the same shall bee levied accordingly Which Orders shall bee
assignable and transferrable from one person to another.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII.</head>
			<para id="p51">
				<emph type="i">If this Supply fails, the next Aid charged; if no Aid given before Feb. 2. Exchequer charged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p52">And it is hereby enacted and declared That all and every su[m]m and su[m]ms of money so to bee borrowed not
exceeding as aforesaid together with the interest for the same not exceeding the Rate of Seven pounds per
Centum per Annum to bee paid every Three Months until satisfaction of the principal shall bee payable and bee
paid or satisfied unto the respective lender or lenders of the same his her or their Executors Administrators or
Assignes out of the moneys ariseing by this Act soe far as the same shall extend And soe much as the said
Act shall fall short or bee deficient for paying the same shall bee payable and bee paid [and<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] satisfied unto the
respective lender or lenders of the same his her or their Executors Administrators or Assignes out of any the next
Aids or Supplies to bee granted to his Majestie in Parliament And shall bee transferred and transferrable thereunto
as soon as any such Aid or Supply shall bee granted And in case noe such Aid or Supply shall bee granted
to his Majesty before the Second day of February One thousand six hundred ninety five then the said su[m]m and
su[m]ms of money soe to bee borrowed not exceeding as aforesaid and the Interest thereof shall bee payable and
bee paid and satisfied to the said lender or lenders his her or their Executors Administrators or Assignes respectively
by and out of any of his Majesties Treasure which from thenceforth shall come into bee or remaine in the Receipt
of his Majesties Exchequer not being already appropriated to any particular uses by any Act or Acts of Parliament
before this time made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Nine Ships, Part of the Forty-three Ships appointed to cruise by 5 &#x0026; 6 W. &#x0026; M. c. 1. to guard the Coal Trade.</head>
			<para id="p53">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That Nine of the Shipps of Warr part of the Forty
three which by an Act of this present Session of Parliament were appointed to cruise in several Stations to guard
the [costs<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] and trade of this Kingdome are hereby appointed to cruise or convoy (that is to say) Six on the
Northerne Coast and Three on the Westerne Coast in such Stations as shall bee directed by the Lord High
Admiral of England or Commissioners for executing the Office of Lord High Admiral of England for the
time being for the better protecting and preserving such Shipps and Vessels as shall bee imployed in the Coal
Trade.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Three Months Time for paying the Duties on Security.</head>
			<para id="p54">
				<emph type="i">Duties repaid upon Exportation</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p55">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That there shall bee allowed to every Master or Owner
of any Shipp or Vessel Three months time for the payment of the Duty imposed by this Act good and sufficient
Security being given for the same such as the Collector or other Cheif Officer of the Port or Place where such
goods shall bee imported or brought shall approve off or if such Master or Owner shall pay present money
there shall bee allowed him after the rate of Ten pounds per Centum per Annum for such prompt payment
And if any of the Coals for which the Duty hereby granted paid or secured att the importation thereof bee againe
exported to any other place of this Kingdome or to any parts beyond the Seas then the aforesaid Duty shall bee
wholly repaid or the security vacated upon due proof thereof in usual forme.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Appropriation of the Monies arising by this and by c. 6. ante.</head>
			<para id="p56">And it is hereby further enacted by the authority aforesaid That out of the money that shall bee levied or
paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer as well upon Loans as otherwise by virtue of this Act and alsoe by one
other Act of this present Seffion of Parliament intituled An Act for granting to his Majesty certaine Rates and
Duties upon marriages births and burials and upon Batchelors and Widowers for the term of Five yeares for carrying
on the Warr against France the su[m]m of Foure hundred forty eight thousand seven hundred and twelve pounds
shall bee and is hereby appropriated for the services of the Navy and Ordnance for Sea Service performed and
to bee performed and for pay of the Officers and Soldiers of the Two Marine Regiments (that is to say) out of
this present Act Two hundred thousand pounds and out of the last recited Act the su[m]m of Two hundred forty
eight thousand seven hundred and twelve pounds And that all other moneys which shall bee levied and paid
by virtue of this and the aforesaid Act into the Receipt of the Exchequer as well upon Loans as otherwise
shall bee applied and appropriated and is hereby appropriated to and for the payment of his Majesties
Land Forces and Armies and the paying for arms ammunition and other charges incident to the warr and
not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Rules in 1 W. &#x0026; M. Sess. 2. c. 1. to be observed as to Execution of this Act.</head>
			<para id="p57">And for the more effectual doeing thereof and that the su[m]ms by this Act appropriated may not bee diverted or
applied to any other purpose then is hereby declared and intended Bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That
the rules and directions appointed and enacted in One Act made in the First yeare of his Majesties Reigne intituled
An Act for a grant to their Majesties of an aid of Two shillings in the pound for One yeare for the speedy
payment of money thereby granted into the Receipt of the Exchequer by the Collectors and Receivers and for
distribution and application thereof and keeping distinct accounts of the same and all other provisions pains penalties
and forfeitures thereby enacted in case of diversion of any money thereby appropriated are hereby revived and
enacted to bee in force and shall bee practised applied executed and putt in ure for and concerning the distribution
and application of the said su[m]ms hereby appropriated as fully amply and effectually as if the same were here
particularly repeated and re-enacted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Metage of Coals to be taken as it now is, and Account on Oath.</head>
			<para id="p58">Provided always and bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the weight meetage and admeasurement
of all Coal or Culme brought to or landed in the Port of London or in any other Port or Place where there
are sworne Coal Meeters shall bee taken by such Coal Meeters for the time being as now it is and they to give
an account thereof upon Oath in manner aforesaid Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary in any
wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Recital that French Alamodes are unduly imported and sold.</head>
			<para id="p59">
				<emph type="i">Trading in Alamodes, &#x0026;c. not having the Custom-House Mark; Penalty &pound;100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p60">And whereas notwithstanding the seals and marks that are appointed and used by the Commissioners of his
Majesties Customes upon forreigne blank Alamodes and Lustrings in order to prevent frauds and the seal and
seals alsoe used by the Lustring Company ill men doe daily import fraudulently great quantities of French Alamodes
and Lustrings in this Realme and doe utter and sell the same by which means alsoe they have opportunities to
export Wooll and Moneys out of England to the great prejudice of this Nation. For remedy whereof bee it enacted
by the authority aforesaid that noe person or persons shall presume to deal or sell buy or sell againe or send beyond
sea any black Alamodes or Lustrings unlesse they have the seal or seals mark or marks which are already used
for forreigne goods att the Custome House or the seale and mark alsoe used by the Lustring Company for the
goods manufactured by them in England under the forfeiture of all such unqualified goods and alsoe shall forfeit
the su[m]m of One hundred pounds for every offence One halfe to the use of his Majesty his Heires and Successors
and the other halfe to the use of such person or persons who shall sue for the same to bee recovered by
action of debt bill plaint [or<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] information or otherwise in any of his Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster
wherein noe essoigne protection priveledge or wager of law shall bee allowed and noe more then One
imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Buyer of Goods discovering the Seller, discharged, and to have Half the Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p61">And bee it alsoe enacted by the authority aforesaid That if the Buyer of such goods not sealed according to
law shall within Twelve months after such offence committed discover the person or persons of whom hee shall
buy the same hee shall not onely bee discharged of the Penalty to which hee is hereby liable but shall alsoe have
and receive to his owne use one moiety of the su[m]m hereby imposed upon the party or parties that shall sell or
dispose of any such Alamodes and Lustrings without the seal or marks aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Counterfeiting or misapplying the Mark;</head>
			<para id="p62">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p63">And bee it further enacted That if any person or persons shall alter counterfeit or misapply any of the seals
or marks now used and hereby required to bee used for the purposes aforesaid such Offender shall forfeit the su[m]m
of One hundred pounds to such person or persons who shall sue for the same to bee recovered in like manner
as is herein before mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Recital of 5 &#x0026; 6 W. &#x0026; M. c. 22. &sect; 4, 5. and, of certain Doubts therein as to renewing Licences to Stages.</head>
			<para id="p64">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners for the Hackney Coaches have no Power to grant Licences for longer Time than June 1695</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p65">And whereas upon the Act made the last session of Parliament intituled An Act for licensing and regulateing
Hackney Coaches and Stage Coaches the Comissioners being thereby enabled to license Stage Coaches and it being
enacted That no Licence continue longer then for One yeare from the date thereof And it being alsoe enacted
by the said Act That noe person shall presume to drive or lett to hire any Stage Coach or Coach Horses without
haveing such leave or licence as the said Act directs it hath been doubted whether the said Comissioners might
make new licences for Stage Coaches after the determination of the first and soe to continue for the terme of
One and twenty yeares and what was intended by the general [prohition<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] of Stage Coaches (not haveing such licences)
without haveing any restraint or limitation of time For explaineing of which doubts Bee it enacted and it is hereby
further enacted by the authority aforesaid that nothing in the said Act contained shall extend or bee construed any
way to impower any Comissioners that are or shall bee appointed by virtue of the said Act to make or grant any
licence to any person or persons whatsoever to drive or lett to hire any Stage Coach or Coach Horses to continue
or bee in force after the Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety five. And it is hereby
declared and enacted that all leases and licences heretofore made and which are to continue after the said Foure and
twentieth day of June as for all the time after the said Foure and twentieth day of June shall bee and are hereby
declared null and void to all intents and purposes whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Indemnity to Commissioners for Mistakes under the said Act.</head>
			<para id="p66">And it is hereby further enacted and declared That nothing in the said Act contained shall extend or bee
construed to bee any prohibition whereby any person shall bee restrained from driveing or letting to hire any Stage
Coach or Coach Horses from and after the said Foure and twentieth day of June And if the said Commissioners
or any of them by reason of the obscurity of the said Act have made any mistake by granting or giveing licences
to drive or lett to hire Stage Coaches or Coach horses to continue longer or after the said Foure and twentieth
day of June for soe doeing they and every of them are hereby indempnified.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">assembled in Parliament <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">raised <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">glasse stone <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">such <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">measuring or weighing <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">which <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Coafts <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">Prohibition <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


