<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46430" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
<subtitle>Chapter XI. An Act for the more effectuall suppressing prophane Cursing and Swearing. [Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. I.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1"><head>Recital of 21 Jac. I. c. 20.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">Persons swearing; Penalties according to the Degrees of the Persons</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">Whereas it is found by experience that an Act of Parliament made in the One and twentieth yeare of the
reigne of King James the First entituled An Act to prevent and reforme prophane [cursing and swearing<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
hath proved ineffectual to the suppressing (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) those detestable sins by reason of some deficiencies in the said
Act Bee it therefore enacted by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the
Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the
same That if any person or persons shall (after the Foure and twentieth day of June in the yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred ninety five) prophanely sweare or curse in the presence or hearing of any Justice of
Peace of the County Riding or Division or of the Mayor or other Head Officer or Justice of Peace for
any City or Towne Corporate where such offence is or shall bee committed or that shall [thereof bee<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] convicted by
oath of one witnesse or by the confession of the party offending before any Justice of Peace of the County or
Mayor or Bayliffe or other Chief Officer or Justice of Peace of such City or Towne Corporate where the
said offence shall bee co[m]mitted that then for every such offence the party soe offending shall forfeit and pay to
the use of the poor of the Parish where such offence or offences shall bee co[m]mitted the respective su[m]ms herein
after menc[i]oconed (that is to say) Every servant day labourer common soldier and co[m]mon seaman One shilling and
every other person Two shillings and in case any of the persons aforesaid shall after conviction offend a second
time such person shall forfeit and pay double and if a third time treble the su[m]m respectively by him or her to
bee paid for the first offence.</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Penalties to be levied by Distress.</head>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">If no Distress, Offender to be put in the Stocks; Offender under 16 not paying the Penalty, to be whipped</emph>.</para>
<para id="p4">And it is hereby further enacted That upon neglect or refusal of payment of the said forfeiture any Justice of
Peace of the County Riding or Division or Mayor or other Head Officer or Justice of Peace of any City or Towne
Corporate where the said offences shall bee co[m]mitted shall and are hereby authorized and required to direct and
send his warrant to the Constable Tythingman Church warden or Overseer of the Poor of the Parish where the
offence shall bee committed or where the Offender shall inhabitt thereby commanding them or some one or more
of them to levy by distresse and sale of the Goods of the offender the su[m]m soe forfeited for the use of the Poor
of the Parish as aforesaid and in case noe such distresse can bee had then every such offender being above the
age of Sixteen yeares shall by warrant under the hand and seale of the said Justice of Peace or other Officer
as aforesaid bee publickly sett in the stocks for the space of one houre for every single offence and for any number
of offences whereof hee shall bee convicted att one and the same time then two hours and if the party offending
bee under the age of Sixteen years and shall not forthwith pay the said forfeitures then hee or shee shall by
warrant as aforesaid bee whipped by the Constable or by the Parent Guardian or Master of such Offender in the
presence of the Constable.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. Justice of Peace, &amp;c. not executing the Act; Penalty &pound;5.</head>
<para id="p5">And bee it further enacted That if any Justice of the Peace or Chief Magistrate shall wilfully and wittingly
omitt the performance of his duty in the execution of this Act hee shall forfett the su[m]m of Five pounds the one
moiety to the use of. the informer to bee recovered by Action Suit Bill or Plaint in any of his Majesties
Courts att Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law shall bee allowed nor any more then one
Imparlance.</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>IV. Action for executing Act, General Issue, &amp;c.</head>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
<para id="p7">And it is hereby further enacted That if any action or suit shall bee co[m]menced or brought against any Justice
of Peace Constable or other Officer or Person whatsoever for doeing or causing to bee done any thing in pursuance
of this Act concerning the said offences the [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Defendant in such Action may plead the General Issue and give
the special matter in evidence And if upon such Action verdict bee given for the defendant or the Plaintiffe become
nonsuit or discontinue his Action then the Defendant shall have treble costs.</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>V. Limitation of Actions.</head>
<para id="p8">Provided always and it is hereby enacted That noe person shall bee prosecuted or troubled for any offence
against this Statute unlesse the same bee proved or prosecuted within Ten days next after the offence
committed.</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>VI. Act to be read Four Times a Year in Churches.</head>
<para id="p9">And it is further enacted by the authority aforesaid That this Act shall bee publickly read Foure several times
in the yeare in all Parish Churches and all publick Chappells by the Parson Vicar or Curate of the respective
Parishes or Chapples immediately after Morning Prayer on Foure several Sundays (that is to say) the Sunday next
after the Foure and twentieth day of June the Nine and twentieth day of September the Five and twentieth day
of December &amp; the Five and twentieth day of March under the pain of Twenty shillings for every such omission
or neglect.</para>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>VII. Justices, &amp;c. to register Convictions, and certify to Quarter Sessions.</head>
<para id="p10">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Justice of Peace Mayor or other Head Officer
shall register in a Book to bee kept for that purpose all the convictions made before him upon this Act and the
time of making thereof and for what offence and shall certifie the same to the next general Quarter Sessions of
the Peace for the said County or Place where the offences are committed to bee there kept upon record by the
respective Clerks of the Peace to bee seen without fee or reward.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">swearing and cursing <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">be thereof <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n4" number="4"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


