<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46432" pubid="352" publish="true">
<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An Act for raiseing the Militia of this Kingdome for the Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety five and for repealing the Statute of the Second &amp; Third Yeare of King Edward the Sixth intituled An Act against shooting in Hail-Shot [Rot. Parl. pt. 4. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head></head>

<para id="p1000"><emph type="i">Recital of 13 &amp; 14 Car. II. c. 3. &sect; 7. and that upon the Invasion by the French, it was necessary to draw out Soldiers, though Month's Pay not reimbursed.</emph></para>
<para id="p1">Whereas by an Act of Parliament made in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth yeares of the reigne of his late
Majesty King Charles the Second intituled An Act for ordering the Forces in the several Counties of this
Kingdom itt was (amongst other things) enacted That in case of Invasions Insurrections or Rebellions whereby
occasion should bee to draw out the Soldiers mentioned and appointed in and by the said Act into actual Service (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>)
persons charged by the said Act with Horses Horsemen and Arms should provide each their Soldier respectively
with pay in hand not exceeding One months pay as should bee in that behalfe directed by the respective
Lieutenants of the several Counties and in their absence or otherwise by their direction by their deputies or any
Two or more of them for repayment of which said moneyes &amp; for satisfaction of the Officers for their pay dureing
such time not exceeding One month as aforesaid as they should bee with their Soldiers in such actual Service itt
was thereby declared that provision should bee made for the same by his said Majestie his Heires and Successors
out of his or their publick Treasury or Revenue Neverthelesse it was thereby further provided and enacted That
in case a months pay should bee provided &amp; advanced as aforesaid that noe pson who should have advanced his
proportion thereof should bee charged with any other like months payment until hee or they should have been
reimbursed the said months pay &amp; soe from time to time the said months' pay by him or them last before provided and
advanced as aforesaid. And whereas upon the invasion of the Coasts of this Kingdom by the French it was found
necessary for the publick defence and safety to draw out the said Soldiers into actual Service and to charge
the said persons to provide each their Soldier respectively with pay in hand although the months pay by several
of them before that time provided (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) was not nor could bee reimbursed.</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Power given to raise the Militia, notwithstanding the Month's Pay formerly advanced be not repaid.</head>
<para id="p2">And whereas the like occasion may possibly happen dureing the present Warr Bee it therefore enacted by the
Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the
Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That if att any time before the
Five and twentieth day of April which shall bee in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety
six it shall bee found by his Majestie to bee necessary for the defence and safety of this Kingdome to draw out the
said Soldiers into actual Service and the same shall bee declared or signified to the respective Lieutenants or Deputy
Lieutenants and the Lord Warden of the Cinque-Ports Two ancient Townes and their Members or in his absence
his Lieutenant or Lieutenants (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) in pursuance of such Orders from his Majestie notwithstanding that One or more
months pay before that time advanced bee not reimbursed to raise and draw out the said Soldiers into actual
Service and to cause the persons charged as aforesaid to provide each their Soldier with pay in hand not exceeding
One months pay in such manner as if all the pay before that time advanced and provided had been fully reimbursed
and paid.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. Recital of 2 &amp; 3 Edw. VI. c. 14.</head>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">The said Act repealed</emph>.</para>
<para id="p4">And whereas by an Act made in the Second and Third yeares of the reigne of Edward the Sixth late King of
England intituled An Act against the shooting of Hailshot whereby [it is amongst other things<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] enacted that noe
person under the degree of a Lord of the Parliament should shoot in any place any Hailshot or any more pelletts
then One att any one time upon paine to forfeit for every time [that he or they should soe offend<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Ten pounds
and imprisonment of his Body dureing Three months Which said Act however usefull in those days hath not
for many yeares last past been putt in execution but became uselesse and unnecessary yett neverthelesse several
malicious persons have of late prosecuted several Gentlemen qualified to keep and use Guns upon the said Act.
For remedy whereof Bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That the said Act and every article clause and thing
therein contained shall bee and is hereby repealed and made void to all intents and purposes whatsoever.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">and advanced <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">by his Majestie it shall be lawfull for the said Lieutenants or their Deputies or any three or more of them as aforefaid and the
Lord Warden of the Cinque Ports two ancient Townes and their Members or in his absence his Lieutenant or Lieutenants <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n4" number="4">amongst other things it is <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


