<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46439" pubid="352" publish="true">
	<title>William and Mary, 1694</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XX. An Act for the Kings most gracious general and free pardon. [Rot. Parl. pt. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>A Pardon of all Crimes to all Subjects.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Pains of Death, &amp;c; not hereafter excepted; before and unto 29th April 1695</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WILLIAM. R.<br/>
The Kings most excellent Majesty observing that his Royal inclination to mercy (which hath appeared as well
by a most general and free pardon as by many particular instances of grace extended to such as had made
themselves obnoxious to the Laws) hath not had soe good an effect as might justly bee expected but on the
contrary diverse obstinate and incorrigible persons have been thereby rather encouraged and emboldened to enter
into treasonable and seditious designes and practices hath heretofore upon mature deliberation found it necessary in
order to the peace and quiet of his Kingdomes and the happy estate of his good Subjects and hath accordingly
resolved and determined for the future that such wicked and ill disposed persons who are not to bee reclaimed
by mercy should bee deterred from offending and retained in their duty by a strict and impartial execution of
his Laws yett neverthelesse his Majesty being still desirous to pursue his Princely disposition to forgive and resolving
that his clemency shall precede his justice thereby to leave utterly without excuse all such of his Subjects who
after soe publick a warning and soe full a declaration of his Royal purpose attended with his repeated Act of
grace shall hereafter presume to violate their duty and allegiance and break the Laws and hath accordingly thought
fitt to grant his general and free pardon in a more large and bountiful manner than hath been heretofore done.
And therefore his Majesty is well pleased and contented that it bee enacted by the authority of this present
Parliament and bee it enacted by the authority of the same in manner and forme following that is to say That
all and every his Majesties Subjects as well Spiritual as Temporal of this his Majesties Realme of England
Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed their heires executors and administrators and every of
them and all and singuler Bodies in any manner of wise corporated Cities Burroughs Shires Ridings Hundreds
Lathes Rapes Wapentakes Townes Villages Hamletts and Tythings and every of them and the successor and
successors of every of them shall bee by authority of this present Parliament acquitted pardoned released and
discharged against his Majesty his heires and successors and every of them of and from all manner of treasons
felonies misprisions of treason treasonable and seditious words or libels misprisions of felony seditious and unlawfull
meetings and conventicles, and all offences whereby any person may bee charged with the penalty and danger of
premunire. And alsoe of and from all riots routs offences contempts trespasses entries wrongs deceits misdemeanors
forfeitures penalties and su[m]ms of money pains of death pains corporal and pains pecuniary and generally of and from
all other things causes quarrels suites judgements and executions in this present Act not hereafter excepted or
foreprized which may bee or can bee by his Majesty in any wise or by any means pardoned had done comitted
omitted perpetrated incurred or forfeited before and unto the Twenty ninth day of Aprill in the yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred ninety five.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The Pardon to be as good as if all Things were particularly named;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and the King's Subjects not to be sued, &amp;c. for any Matter done, &amp;c. against the Crown before the said 29th April, except as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And alsoe the Kings most excellent Majesty is contented that it bee enacted by the authority of this present
Parliament and bee it enacted by the authority of the same That this his free pardon shall bee as good and effectual
in law to every of his said Subjects Bodies Corporate and others before rehearsed in for and against all things
which bee not hereafter in this present Act excepted and forprized as the same pardon should have been if all
offences contempts forfeitures causes matters suits quarrels judgements executions penalties and all other things not
hereafter in this present Act excepted and foreprized had been particularly singularly specially and plainely named
rehearsed and specified and alsoe pardoned by proper and expresse words and names in their kinds natures and
qualities by words and termes thereunto requisite to have been putt in and expressed in this present Act of free
pardon And that his said Subjects or any of them the heires executors or administrators of any of them or
the said bodies corporate and other before named and rehearsed or any of them bee not nor shall bee sued
vexed or unquieted in their bodies goods chattels lands or tenements for any matter cause contempt misdemeanor
forfeiture trespasse offence or any other thing suffered done or co[m]mitted or omitted before the said Twenty ninth
day of April against his Majesty his Crowne Dignity Prerogative or the Laws or Statutes of this Realme but onely
for such matters causes and offences as bee rehearsed mentioned or in some ways touched in the exceptions of
this present Act to bee foreprized and excepted and for none other Any statute or statutes laws customes or
usages heretofore had made or used to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Grant of all Forfeitures incurred before said 29th April to the Subject.</head>
			<para id="p5">And his Majesty of his bounteous liberality and by the authority of this present Parliament doth grant and
freely give to every of his Subjects every of the said Bodies Corporate and others before rehearsed and every of
them all Goods Chattells Debts Fines Issues Profitts Amerciaments Forfeitures and Su[m]ms of Money by any of them
forfeited which to his Majesty doe or shall belong or appertaine by reason of any Offence Contempt Trespasse
Entry Misdemeanor Matter Cause or Quarrel suffered done or committed by them or any of them before the said
Twenty-ninth day of April which bee not hereafter in this present Act foreprized and excepted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Grants or Executions upon Forfeitures how far of force.</head>
			<para id="p6">And bee it enacted neverthelesse That all Grants thereof or of any part thereof made by any such as have soe
forfeited the same and are hereby restored as aforesaid and all Executions thereof or of any part thereof had
against any such after such Forfeiture thereof committed or made shall bee of such force and effect as if noe
such Forfeiture had been had or made and of noe other the same Forfeiture or any thing before in this Act to
the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Any Person may plead this Pardon.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Fee</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further enacted That all and every his Majesty's Subjects and all and singuler Bodies Corporate
and others before rehearsed may by him or themselves or by his or their deputy or deputies or by his
or their attorney or attorneys according to the Law of this Realme plead and minister this present
Act of free pardon for his or their discharge of or for any thing that is by virtue of this present Act
pardoned discharged given or granted without any fee or other thing paying to any person or persons for
writeing or entry of the Judgements or other Cause concerning such plea writing or entry but onely Sixteen pence
to bee paid to the Officer or Clerk that shall enter such plea or matter for judgement or the parties discharge
in that behalfe Any Law Custom or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Pardon expounded most beneficially for the Subject.</head>
			<para id="p9">And furthermore his Majesty is contented and pleased that it bee enacted by the authority aforesaid That this
his free pardon by the general words clauses and sentences before rehearsed shall bee reputed deemed adjudged
expounded allowed and taken in all manner of Courts of his Majesty and elsewhere most beneficial and available
to all and singular the said Subjects Bodies Corporate and others before rehearsed and to every of them in all
things not in this present Act excepted and foreprized without any ambiguity question or (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) delay whatsoever to bee
made pleaded objected or alledged by the Kings Majesty his Heires or Successors or by his or any of their
general attorney or attorneys or by any person or persons for his Majesty or any of his Heires or Successors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Officer offending in making out Process, or taking Money for Things pardoned;</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">or Sheriff taking or withholding Things pardoned; Penalty &pound;10. and Treble Damages and Costs; Process void</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any Officer or Clerk of any of his Majesties Courts
commonly called the Chancery Kings Bench Co[m]mon Pleas or Exchequer or any other Officer or Clerk of any (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>)
his Majesties Courts within this Realme att any time after the last day of Trinity Terme One thousand six hundred
ninety five make out or write out any writts processe su[m]mons or other precept whereby any of the said Subjects
or of the Bodies Corporate or others before rehearsed or any of them shall bee in any wise arrested attached
distrained summoned or otherwise vexed inquieted or grieved in his or their Bodies Lands Tenements Goods or
Chattells or any of them for or because of any manner of thing pardoned or discharged by virtue of this Act or
if any Sheriff or Escheator or any their deputy or deputies or any Bayliff or other Officer whatsoever by colour
of his or their Office or otherwise after the said last day of Trinity Terme One thousand six hundred ninety five
doe levy receive take or withhold of or from any person or psons any thing pardoned or discharged by this Act
that then every such person soe offending and thereof lawfully convicted or condemned by any sufficient testimony
witnesse or proof shall yeild and pay for recompence thereof to the party soe grieved or offended thereby his or
their treble damages besides all [the<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] costs of the Suit and shall alsoe forfeit and lose to the Kings Majesty for every
such offence Tenne pounds And neverthelesse all and singuler such writts processe and precepts soe to bee made
for or upon any manner of thing pardoned or discharged by this present Act of free pardon shall bee utterly
void and of none effect.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Exceptions. Persons against whom there has been a Proclamation.</head>
			<para id="p12">Excepted and foreprized out of this Act of general and free pardon all persons against whom any Proclamation
hath been published att any time since the Seven and twentieth day of April in the yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred ninety foure and before the said Nine and twentieth day of April One thousand six hundred
ninety five.</para>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Prisoners of War</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And alsoe excepted out of this general pardon all persons who have been prisoners of Warr att any time since
the First day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty nine and before the Thirtieth
day of April One thousand six hundred ninety five.</para>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Prisoners under Bail for Crimes</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And alsoe excepted all persons who are or shall bee prisoners or under bail for any Crime upon the said Nine
and twentieth day of April One thousand six hundred ninety five.</para>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Persons in Territories of France</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And alsoe excepted and foreprized out of this general and free pardon all persons who are now remaineing
continueing or being in any of the Dominions or Territories belonging to the French King (other than those
who are actual prisoners.</para>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Persons employed by the French King, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">And alsoe excepted all such persons who are any ways employed by or in the service of the said French King
or are employed by or in the service of the late King James.</para>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Persons impeached this Session</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And alsoe excepted all persons who have been or shall bee impeached in Parliament dureing this present Session.</para>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Treasons out of the Realm</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And alsoe excepted all and every manner of treasons committed or done by any person or persons in any
parts or places out of this Realme of England since the Thirteenth day of February One thousand six hundred
eighty eight.</para>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Treasons, &amp;c. 3 &amp; 4 (3) W. &amp; M. c. 13</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">And alsoe excepted all treasons and other offences committed or done contrary to or against an Act of this
present Parliament made att a Session held in the Third and Fourth yeares of the reigne of King William and
Queen Mary intituled An Act against corresponding with their Majesties Enemies.</para>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">Treasons upon the Seas, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p28">And alsoe excepted all treasons done or committed upon the high seas and all suits punishments outlawries
judgments executions paines of death forfeitures and penalties for or by reason or occasion of any the treasons
and offences before excepted.</para>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">Offences against 13 Car. II. Stat. 1. c. 9</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p30">And alsoe excepted all offences comitted or done by any Officers Mariners Soldiers or others contrary to or
against an Act of Parliament made in the Thirteenth yeare of the reigne of King Charles the second intituled An
Act for the establishing articles and orders for the regulateing and better government of his Majesties Navy Ships
of Warr and Forces by Sea.</para>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">Offences against 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 1. c. 34; 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 14; 4 &amp; 5 W. &amp; M. c. 25.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p32">And alsoe all offences comitted or done against an Act made in the first yeare of the reigne of King William
and Queen Mary intituled An Act for prohibiting all trade and commerce with France and another Act made in
the second yeare of the said reigne of King William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for the more effectual
putting in execution the said last menc[i]oed Act and against an Act of this present Parliament made att a Session
held in the Fourth and Fifth yeares of King William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for continuing the Acts
for prohibiting all trade and commerce with France and for the encouragement of Privateers or against any of
them.</para>
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">Forging Great Seal, &amp;c. and Coiners diminishing the Coin</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p34">And alsoe excepted out of this free pardon all offences of forgeing and false counterfeiting the Great or Privy Seal
Signe Manual or Privy Signett or of any of the Moneys currant within this realme and alsoe all offences of
clipping washing fileing scaling lightning impaireing or other unlawfull diminishing any (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) of the said moneys by
any ways or means whatsoever contrary to the laws and statutes of this realme.</para>
			<para id="p35">
				<emph type="i">Bringing in and uttering false Money, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p36">And alsoe except the offences of bringing into this realme any false or counterfeit money made or counterfeited
out of this realme knowing the same to bee counterfeit and uttering any such false or counterfeit money and all
misprisions and concealments of the treasons before excepted and all abetting aiding comforting and procuring of
the same offences or any of the said treasons before excepted</para>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">Escapes of Traitors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p38">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all escapes of traytors or others and the offences of being consenting or
accessary thereto or permitting the same.</para>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">Murders, Petit Treasons, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p40">And alsoe excepted all manner of voluntary murders petit treasons and wilfull poisonings done or committed
by any person or persons and alsoe all wilfull burning of houses or barnes with corne in them att the time of such
burning and all and every the accessaries of the same offences or any of them.</para>
			<para id="p41">
				<emph type="i">Piracies</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p42">And alsoe excepted and foreprized out of this general pardon all piraces and robberies done upon the seas and
all and every procuring or abetting any such offenders and the comforting and receiving of them or any of them
or of any goods taken by way of Piracy or robbery upon the seas as aforesaid.</para>
			<para id="p43">
				<emph type="i">Burglaries, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p44">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all burglaries and all breaking into and stealing out of any dwelling
house or [or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] houses in the day and all accessaries to any the said burglaries and felonies.</para>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">Robberies of Church and on the Highway</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p46">And alsoe excepted all robberies of Churches and stealing any plate utensils or goods of or belonging to the
same And alsoe all robberies committed upon any person or persons in or neare the highway.</para>
			<para id="p47">
				<emph type="i">Buggery</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p48">And alsoe excepted the detestable and abominable vice of buggery committed with mankind or beast.</para>
			<para id="p49">
				<emph type="i">Rape</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p50">And alsoe excepted all rapes and carnal ravishments of women.</para>
			<para id="p51">
				<emph type="i">Taking away Women</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p52">And aisoe excepted all ravishments and wilful takeing away or marrying of any widdow maid or damsel against
her will or without the assent or agreement of her parents or such as then had her in custody and all offences
of aiding and comforting procureing or abetting any such ravishments wilfull takeing or marrying had committed
or done.</para>
			<para id="p53">
				<emph type="i">Perjury, Forgery, Subornation, counterfeiting Fines, &amp;c; Forging Examinations of Witnesses tending to take away Life</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p54">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all offences of perjury and subornation of witnesses and endeavouring
or conspireing to bribe and corrupt any person to give a false testimony and the offences of forgeing and
counterfeiting and solicitation of forgeing and counterfeiting any fines or other records deeds wills escripts or
writeings whatsoever and alsoe the offences of forgeing or counterfeiting Seamens ticketts or authorities for
receiving any su[m]ms of money due to Seamen And all offences of forgeing and counterfeiting any examinations or
testimonies of any witnesse or witnesses tending to bring any person or persons into danger of his life and all
procureing or [concealing<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] of any such forgeries or counterfeitings had made committed or done.</para>
			<para id="p55">
				<emph type="i">Offences against 25 Car. II. c. 2.</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p56">And alsoe excepted out of this Act of general pardon all offences committed or done contrary to or against
an Act of Parliament made in the Five and twentieth yeare of the reigne of King Charles the Second intituled An
Act for preventing dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants.</para>
			<para id="p57">
				<emph type="i">Offences against 30 Car. II. Stat. 2</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p58">And alsoe excepted all offences committed against an Act of Parliament made in the Thirtieth yeare of the
reigne of the said King Charles the Second intituled An Act for the more effectual preserving the Kings Person
and Government by disableing Papists from sitting in either House of Parliament and all forfeitures paines penalties
and disabilities which any person or persons is are or may bee liable to by reason of any of the said offences
committed against either of the said statutes.</para>
			<para id="p59">
				<emph type="i">Destroying Timber in Forests</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p60">And alsoe excepted all offences committed in any Forest since the Thirteenth day of February One thousand
six hundred eighty eight in cutting downe takeing away or destroying any timber or trees or any, fences or
inclosures of or in the said Forests.</para>
			<para id="p61">
				<emph type="i">High Treason and all Offences against any Act (except about Apprentices) already prosecuted; and Forfeitures, &amp;c. for which Action has been brought as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p62">And alsoe excepted all offences of high treason and all other offences misdemeanors contempts or other Act or
deed had suffered committed or done contrary to any Act of Parliament (other then useing or causeing to bee used
any craft mystery or occupation by any persons not brought upp therein seven yeares as an apprentice) or
contrary to the common law of this realme And all forfeitures and other penalties and profitts now due accrued
and growne and which shall or may bee due accrue or grow to the Kings Majesty by reason of any the
crimes or offences aforesaid whereof or for which any action bill plaint information or indictment att any time
within two yeares next before the day of assembling and holding of this Parliament or att any time since hath
been found commenced or sued in any of his Majesties courts att Westminster or before any Commissioners of
Oyer and Terminer Goal Delivery or Justices of Assize and is depending and remaining to bee prosecuted or,
whereupon any verdict judgment or decree is already given or entred or whereof or whereupon his Majesty or
her Majesty the late Queen of blessed memory by his or her bill signed or otherwise have or hath made any
gift or assignment to any person or persons before the said Thirtieth day of April One thousand six hundred
ninety five And all awards of court orders sentences judgements executions and proceedings had or to bee
had upon or concerning or by reason or occasion of any such offence misdemeanor contempt act or deed.</para>
			<para id="p63">
				<emph type="i">Informations concerning Bridges, &amp;c. depending</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p64">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all informations indictments and other proceedings depending concerning
any common high-ways or bridges and all issues returned upon any processe concerning the same since the
Twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred seventy nine.</para>
			<para id="p65">
				<emph type="i">Embezzling the King's Goods, &amp;c; Conveying Stores, &amp;c. to the French King. Breach of Covenant with the King</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p66">And alsoe excepted all offences in taking away imbezling or purloyning any of the Kings Majesties goods monies
chattells jewels armour munition stores naval provisions shipping ordnance and other habiliments of warr and all
offences in conveying to the French King or any of his subjects any naval stores or commodities or contraband
goods or supplying him or them with the same.</para>
			<para id="p67">
				<emph type="i">Breach of convenant with the King</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p68">And alsoe excepted all conditions and covenants and all penalties titles and forfeitures of conditions or covenants
accrued or growne to his Majesty by reason of the breach and not performeing of any covenant and condition
whatsoever.</para>
			<para id="p69">
				<emph type="i">Actions of Quare Impedit</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p70">And alsoe excepted all titles suites and actions of Quare impedit.</para>
			<para id="p71">
				<emph type="i">Incest, Simony, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p72">And alsoe excepted all offences of incest simony or dilapidations.</para>
			<para id="p73">
				<emph type="i">Adultery and other Crimes by Persons in Orders</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p74">And alsoe excepted adultery extortion and all other enormous crimes committed by any person in holy orders
punishable in any ecclesiastical court and all proceedings and sentences thereupon.</para>
			<para id="p75">
				<emph type="i">First Fruits, &amp;c; Bishops not discharged, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p76">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all first fruits and tenths pensions procurations synodals and other
payments out of any ecclesiastical promotion or benefice other then arreares of tenths which att any time before
the said First day of this Session of Parliament did become due for upon or out of any small rectory vicaridge
or benefice which att the true and greatest valuation and improvement is not of the yearely value of Thirty pounds
and which shall bee soe certified [to<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] the respective bishopp or guardians of the spiritualties to his Majesties Courts
of Exchequer before the last day of Michaelmasse terme One thousand six hundred ninety five. Provided that this
shall not bee construed to pardon or discharge any Bishopp or Receiver of or from answering or paying any of
the said arreares by him received.</para>
			<para id="p77">
				<emph type="i">Concealment of Duties</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p78">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all and every the su[m]ms of money and duties following and the
concealment or wrongfull detainment thereof (that is to say) of any custome or subsidy excise arreares of hearth
money imposition upon wine or other liquors or commodities duties upon salt duties upon the tu[r]nage of shipps
duties upon parchment velum and paper arreares of any land tax poll money arreares of rent and all other su[m]ms
of money due or oweing from any licensed hackney or stage coachmen duties ariseing by wine licences or the
post-office or any other tax assessment duty imposition debt or su[m]m of money whatsoever to the Kings Majesty
given or leviable by any Act of Parliament or otherwise due or belonging to the Kings Majesty and all arreares
thereof and all forfeitures penalties and disabilities ariseing thereby or for (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) nonpayment concealment or detayning
thereof and all corruptions and misdemeanors of any officer or minister of in or concerning the same and all
accounts and suits whatsoever to bee had made or prosecuted for the same and all concealments frauds and
offences by which his Majestie hath been deceived and not truely answered of or for the same.</para>
			<para id="p79">
				<emph type="i">Misdemeanors of Officers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p80">And alsoe excepted out of this Act of pardon all misbehaviours misdemeanors or omissions committed suffered
or done by any officer in or concerning the execution of his office and all forfeitures and penalties to which any
officer is or may bee liable by reason of such misbehaviours misdemeanors or omissions and all suits proceedings
&amp; prosecutions had or to bee had for or by reason thereof.</para>
			<para id="p81">
				<emph type="i">&pound;500 Penalty in 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 21. pardoned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p82">Yett neverthelesse the forfeitures of Five hundred pounds and all other penalties and disabilities which have been
incurred by any person before the said Twenty ninth day of April in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred ninety [five<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] or which any person or persons is are or may bee liable to for writing or causing to bee
written before the said Twenty ninth day of April any matter or thing upon parchment velum or paper not
stampt according to the direction of an Act of this present Parliament made in the Fifth and Sixth yeares(<ref idref="n10">10</ref>) of King
William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for granting to their Majesties several duties upon velum parchment
and paper for Foure yeares towards carrying on the warr against France are hereby fully pardoned and
discharged.</para>
			<para id="p83">
				<emph type="i">Taking away Goods, Rents, &amp;c. forfeited to King Charles II. or James II. or His present Majesty and the late Queen; Rents, &amp;c. of Temporalties in the King's Hands</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p84">And alsoe excepted all and every manner of taking from the Kings Majesty or from the Kings and the late
Queens Majesties or the late [King<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Charles the Second and [King<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] James the Second or either of them any goods
or chattells forfeited by reason of any treason petit treason murder or felony heretofore committed or done and
alsoe all and every manner of taking from his Majesty or from his Majesty and the said late Queen or either of the
said late Kings the issues rents revenues or profitts of any mannor lands tenements or hereditaments which
were of any traytor murderer felon clerk or clerks attainted or any of them and alsoe all and all manner of
taking from the Kings Majestie or from the said King and the late Queens. Majesties or either of the said late
Kings the issues rents revenues and profitts of any mannor lands tenements or hereditaments parcell of the
possessions of any bishoprick the temporalties whereof upon the Twentieth day of March in the yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred seventy nine or att any time since were or of right ought to have been in his their
or either of their hands.</para>
			<para id="p85">
				<emph type="i">Arrearages due from Farmers of the Revenue</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p86">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all arrearages of rent due from any farmer of any part of the revenue
ariseing by customs excise or hearth-money or impositions upon proceedings att law or by any other branch or
part of the publick revenue and all arrearages of fee farme rents and other rents.</para>
			<para id="p87">
				<emph type="i">All Accounts, &amp;c. from Collectors, &amp;c. to the King; which have grown due since 25th March 1673, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p88">And alsoe excepted all and singular accounts of all and every Collector and Collectors Commissioners Tresurers
Receivers or other Officers or Accountants whatsoever who have received or collected or are any other way
accountable to his Majestie for any subsidy custome subsidy of tunnage and poundage additional duty prize goods
excise arreares of hearth-money impositions upon wines and other liquors or co[m]modities duties upon salt duties
upon the tunnage of shipps duties upon parchment velum and paper arreares of any land tax poll-money arreares
of rent or other su[m]ms of money for licensing hackney and stage coaches duties ariseing by wine licences or the
post-office or any other tax assessment duty imposition debt su[m]m of money or other things whatsoever given to the
Kings Majesty or leviable by Act of Parliament or otherwise belonging to his Majesty and which have growne due
or happened since the Twenty fifth day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seventy
three and all accounts of every other person whatsoever that ought to bee Accountant to the Kings Majestie for
or in respect of any receipt or other charge which hath growne since the said Twenty fifth day of March and the
heires executors administrators and sureties of any person that ought to account for all things touching onely the
same accounts and all and singuler arrearages of accounts and untrue accounts made or rendred since the said
Twenty fifth day of March and all impetitions charges seizures suites demands and executions which may or can
bee had of or for any such account or accounts or any arrearages of the same.</para>
			<para id="p89">
				<emph type="i">Recognizances of Receivers of Land Tax, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p90">And alsoe excepted all recognizances obligations and other securities given or entred into by any receiver of
any land tax or any other duties impositions or other su[m]ms of money whatsoever due or payable to his Majesty
by Act of Parliament or otherwise or by any reeve bailiffe collector or other accountant in the Court of Exchequer
and their sureties and their accounts [respectively<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] and all other recognizances and obligations whatsoever
conditioned for payment of money.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Recognizances, &amp;c. forfeited and not forfeited as herein mentioned, Specialties to the Crown, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p91">
				<emph type="i">Recognizances, &amp;c. whereupon any Seizure hath been made on which any thing hath been paid since the said 25th March, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p92">Provided always and bee it enacted That this Act shall not extend or bee construed to pardon or discharge
any recognizance or obligation not yet forfeited nor to pardon or discharge any forfeited recognizance or obligation
or any other forfeiture or penalty whereof the Farmers of the Excise or the Farmers of any other part of the
publick Revenue ought to receive any benefitt or advantage Nor to pardon or discharge any debt due by
recognizance obligation or other specialty to any person or persons indebted to his Majesty which hath been duely
seized in aid of his Majesties debt Nor to pardon or discharge any debt due by recognizance obligation
condemnation or otherwise whereupon any estallment or seizure hath been att any time heretofore made upon
which estallment or seizure any thing is or att any time since the said twenty fifth day of March hath been
answered and paid Nor to pardon or discharge any Penalties Forfeitures (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Su[m]ms of money due or accrued to his
Majesty by reason of any Act Statute or Statutes which Forfeitures Penalties and Su[m]ms of money since the
Twenty fifth day of March bee converted into the nature of any debt by any judgment order decree or by the
agreement of the Offender or Offenders or have been estalled or any seizure made for the same And upon such
seizure or estallment any thing answered or paid since the said Twenty fifth day of March.</para>
			<para id="p93">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Recognizances for Appearance forfeited since the said 25th March</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p94">Nevertheless it is hereby declared That all Obligations and Recognizances forfeited since the said Twenty fifth
day of March for Non-appearance in any Court or other Place whatsoever or not keeping the Peace or not being
of the good behaviour shall bee clearely pardoned and discharged except Recognizances granted to or in trust
for the Lord Almoner.</para>
			<para id="p95">
				<emph type="i">Further Exception, Issues, &amp;c. lost, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p96">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all issues fines (<ref idref="n15">15</ref>) amerciaments lost imposed or assessed since the
said Twenty fifth day of March being totted levied or received by any Sheriff Under-Sheriff Bailiff Minister or
other Officer before the last day of Trinity Terme One thousand six hundred ninety five.</para>
			<para id="p97">And alsoe excepted all issues fines and amerciaments lost imposed or assessed since the said Twenty fifth day
of March affeered taxed sett estreated or entred severally or particularly touching or concerning any one or more
persons joyntly or severally above the su[m]m of Six pounds.</para>
			<para id="p98">
				<emph type="i">Issues, &amp;c. returned, &amp;c. within a Year before this Parliament</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p99">And alsoe excepted all issues fines and amerciaments returned affeered taxed sett or entred severally or particularly
in any Court of Record att Westminster att any time within the space of one yeare next before the first day of
holding and assembling this present Parliament or att any time since.</para>
			<para id="p100">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for other Fines and Issues</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p101">And yett neverthelesse all other fines as well fines Pro Licentia Concordandi as others sett taxed estreated or
entred before that time and alsoe all issues and amerciaments as well real as others within any Liberties or without
being sett taxed estreated or entred before the time aforesaid and which severally and particularly extend to or
under the su[m]m of Six pounds and not above whether they bee estreated or not estreated or whether they bee
turned into debt or not turned into debt and not being totted levied or received by any Sheriff Under Sheriff
Minister or other Officer before the first day of this present Session of Parliament shall bee freely clearely
and plainely pardoned and discharged against the Kings Majesty his Heires and Successors by force of this
present Act.</para>
			<para id="p102">
				<emph type="i">Estreats of Fines, &amp;c. hereby pardoned, already estreated, to be delivered into the Pipe Office</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p103">And yett neverthelesse all estreats of such fines issues and amerciaments as bee now pardoned by this Act
and which bee already estreated forth of the Court of Exchequer and bee remaining in the Hands of the
Sheriff Under Sheriff or Bailiffe for collecting of the same fines issues and amerciaments shall upon the returne
of the same estreats bee duely and orderly charged and delivered by Scrowes into the Office of the Pipe in the
Court of Exchequer as heretofore hath been accustomed to the intent that thereupon order may bee taken that
his Majesty may bee truely answered all such fines issues and amerciaments not by this Act pardoned and which
any Sheriff Under Sheriff Bailiffe or other Officer or Minister hath received or ought to answer by force or colour
of any such estreat processe or precept to him or them made for the levying thereof.</para>
			<para id="p104">
				<emph type="i">Sheriffs and other Accountants may petition for Allow-ance of Fines, &amp;c. pardoned without Fee</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p105">And yett that notwithstanding all and every Sheriff and Sheriffs and other Accountants upon his or their
petition or petitions to bee made for the allowance of (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) such fines issues or amerciaments as by this Act are
pardoned shall have all and every such his and their petition allowed in his and their account and accounts without
paying any fee or reward to any Officer Clerk or other Minister for the making entring and allowing of any
such petition or petitions Any usage or custome to the contrary hereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Further Exception King Charles the First's Murderers excepted by 12 C. II. c. 11. and the Two.; Persons appearing upon the Scaffold with Vizors.</head>
			<para id="p106">Provided always That this Act shall not extend to pardon discharge or give any Benefitt whatsoever unto any
person or persons who are by name particularly excepted out of the Act of free and general pardon indempnity
and oblivion made in the Twelfth yeare of the reigne of his late Majestie King Charles the Second for their
execrable treason and horrid murder of his Majesties royal grandfather of gracious memory Nor to those two
persons or either of them who being disguised by frocks and vizors appeared upon the Scaffold att the time
when the said murder was committed.</para>
			<para id="p107">
				<emph type="i">This Act not to heal Disabilities</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p108">Nor shall this present Act give or restore any ability or capacity to take have hold or exercise any office place
authority or employment ecclesiastical civil or military to any person or persons who in and by the said last
mentioned Act or by virtue or reason of any other Act or [Act<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] were or are made or become incapable or disabled
to have take hold or execute the same or of serving as a Member in Parliament but all and every such person
and persons shall remaine and continue under all and every the disabilities and incapacities aforesaid Any thing
in this present Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<para id="p109">
				<emph type="i">Further Exception of Persons who have accepted any Office contrary to 12 Car. II. c. 11</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p110">Nor shall this Act extend to pardon discharge or give any benefitt to any person who if hee after the First
day of September One thousand six hundred and sixty hath accepted or exercised or hereafter shall accept or
exercise any office ecclesiastical civill or military or any other publick employment within England Wales or the
Towne of Berwick upon Tweed is by the said Act made in the Twelfth yeare of King Charles the Second to
stand and bee as if bee had been totally by name excepted out of the said last mentioned Act but all and every
such persons shall if they have or shall accept any office or employment contrary to the tenour of the [of the<ref idref="n18">18</ref>]
said last mentioned Act bee out of this Act wholly excepted and foreprized.</para>
			<para id="p111">
				<emph type="i">Persons attainted of Rebellion</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p112">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all such persons as bee and remaine still attainted or condemned by
Act of Parliament or otherwise of or for any rebellion or levying of warr or of and for any conspiracy of any
rebellion or levying warr within this realme or any other his Majesties Dominions and all such persons who
are attainted or outlawed of or for any treason petit treason murder wilfull poysoning or burglary or robbery upon
the highway and all executions therefore.</para>
			<para id="p113">
				<emph type="i">Persons exiled by express Name, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p114">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all such persons who by virtue of any former Act of Parliament are
by expresse name exiled or upon whom any other paines penalties or disabilities whatsoever are by any Act of
Parliament inflicted.</para>
			<para id="p115">
				<emph type="i">Persons detained in Custody, &amp;c. by Act of this Session</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p116">And alsoe excepted out of this Act of free and general pardon all such persons who by any Act which hath
been or shall bee made dureing this present Session of Parliament are enacted to bee prisoners or detained in
custody or disabled to dispose of their estates.</para>
			<para id="p117">
				<emph type="i">Persons giving or taking Money, &amp;c. for procuring a new Charter, &amp;c. for the East India Company</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p118">And alsoe excepted out of this present Act all offences in giving or promiseing or in receiving or takeing or
in accepting of any promise of any su[m]m of money or other gift reward or gratuity for the procureing or assisting
in procureing (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) a new Charter or Charter of Restitution to the East-India Company or a Charter for the regulating
of the said Company or in order to the obtaining or promoting an Act of Parliament for confirming the EastIndia Company or in order to prevent or obstruct the passing of an Act of Parliament for [settling or erecting.<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] a
new East-India Company or in refusing to give evidence or declare their knowledge touching any of the said
offences haveing been thereunto lawfully required.</para>
			<para id="p119">
				<emph type="i">Persons who have desired Transportation</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p120">And alsoe excepted all such persons who after conviction or attainder of or for any manner of felony have
desired to bee transported into any of his Majesties forreigne plantations.</para>
			<para id="p121">
				<emph type="i">Persons formerly excepted out of 12 Car. II. c. 11</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p122">And alsoe excepted all such persons who being excepted out of the said Act of general pardon have had any
paines or penalties imposed upon them by any subsequent Act of Parliament</para>
			<para id="p123">
				<emph type="i">Crimes against 27 Eliz. c. 2</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p124">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all and every offence and offences committed or done by any Jesuit
Seminary or Romish Priests whatsoever contrary to the tenor or effect of the Statute made in the Seven and
twentieth yeare of the reigne of the late Queen Elizabeth intituled An Act against Jesuits Seminary Priests and
other disobedient persons or of any part thereof And all outlawries proceedings judgements and executions for
the same offences or any of them.</para>
			<para id="p125">
				<emph type="i">Recusants Convictions</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p126">And except all convictions of Popish Recusants for their recusancy</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Outlawry not stayed, &amp;c. unless Defendant appear, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p127">Provided always and bee it enacted by the authority aforesaid That noe processe of outlawry or proceeding
thereon att the suit of any person plaintiffe shall bee by virtue of this pardon stayed or avoyded unlesse the
Defendant appeare and putt in bail where by law bail is necessary and take out a writt of Scire facias against
the party att whose suit hee was outlawed And that this pardon bee not allowed to discharge any outlawry
after judgment till satisfaction or agreement bee made to or with the party att whose suit the outlawry was
obtained.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. This Act of Pardon may be given in Evidence.</head>
			<para id="p128">And it is further enacted by the authority aforesaid That every person or persons hereby pardoned may plead
the general issue without special pleading of this pardon and give this Act of pardon in evidence for his
discharge and that the same shall bee thereupon allowed and the advantage thereof had as fully to all intents
and purposes as if the same had been fully and well pleaded and in such manner as any Justice of Peace Constable
or any other Officer questioned for matters acted by them as Officers may have the advantage of the matter of
their justification upon the general issue by them pleaded by the Laws and Statutes of this Realme.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Good against the King's Grantee and the King.</head>
			<para id="p129">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That this present pardon shall bee of as good force and
effect to pardon and discharge all and singuler the premisses above mentioned and intended to bee pardoned and
discharged as well against such person or persons bodies politick and corporate as doe or shall claime the same by
or under any letters patents or lease or grant by the Kings Majesty or any his predecessors as against the Kings
Majestie himselfe.</para>
			<para id="p130">[Cui quidem bille in se formam actus continentis prelecte et ad plenum intellecte per dictum dominum Regem
ex authoritate Parliamenti predci sic responsum est.</para>
			<para id="p131">Le prelates Seigneurs et communes en ce Parliament assemblez au nom de tous vos autre sujects remercient tres
humblement votre Majestie et prient Dieu vous donner en san&eacute; bonne vie et longue<ref idref="n21">21</ref>].</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">councelling <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">by <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">this word is illegible in the original Act.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">of the Reign <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Kings <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">Law <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">erecting or setting <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">This above is the Form of the Assent to this Act on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

