<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46807" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>Chronological table of the titles of all the acts of parliament passed in the reign of King William III</title>
	<subtitle></subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>CHRONOLOGICAL TABLE OF THE TITLES OF ALL THE ACTS OF PARLIAMENT PASSED IN THE REIGN OF KING WILLIAM III.</head>
		<table id="t1">
			<tr>
				<td cols="7"/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td cols="2">DATE</td>
				<td>TITLE or DESCRIPTION of the ACT.</td>
				<td cols="3">NUMBER</td>
				<td rows="2">Page of this Volume.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>A.D.</td>
				<td>Reign.</td>
				<td>IN CHANCERY.</td>
				<td>of the Chapter as printed.</td>
				<td>On the Roll in Chancery.</td>
				<td>Of the Original Act in Parliament.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1695-6.</td>
				<td>W. III. An. 7, 8.</td>
				<td>An Act for remedying the ill State of the Coin of the Kingdome.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>p. 1. 1</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>1</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enlargeing the Times to come [in<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] and purchase certain Annuities therein mentioned and for continuing the Duties formerly charged on Low Wines or Spirits of the first Extraction for carrying on the Warr against France.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>4</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for regulateing of Tryals in Cases of Treason and Misprision of Treason.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>6</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing Charge and Expence in Elections of Members to serve in P[ar]liament.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>7</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majesty an Aid of Four Shillings in the Pound(<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) for carrying on the War against France.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>p. 2.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>8</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the more easie Recoverie of Small Tythes.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>p. 4. 1</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>62</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent False and Double Returns of Members to serve in Parliament.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>64</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the taking examining and stating the Publick Accounts.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>21</td>
				<td>65</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for repairing the Highways betweene the City of London and the Towne of Harwich in the County of Essex.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>22</td>
				<td>66</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing several Duties granted by former Acts upon Wine and Vinegar and upon Tobacco and East India Goods and other Merchandize imported for carrying on the Warr against France.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>25</td>
				<td>69</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for impowering His Majestie to apprehend and detain such p[er]sons as hee shall find Cause to suspect are conspiring against His Royal Person or Government.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>26</td>
				<td>74</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Relief of poor Prisoners for Debt or Damages.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>28</td>
				<td>75</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for taking off the Obligation and Incouragement for coining Guineas for a certaine Time therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>P. 3. 1</td>
				<td>27</td>
				<td>77</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1695-6.</td>
				<td>An. 7, 8.</td>
				<td>An Act for making navigable the Rivers of Wye and Lugg in the County of Hereford.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>29</td>
				<td>78</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the continueing meeting and sitting of a Parliament in case of the Death or Demise of His Majesty His Heirs and Successors.</td>
				<td>XV.</td>
				<td>p. 5. 1</td>
				<td>40</td>
				<td>84</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for raiseing the Militia of this Kingdom for the Year One thousand six hundred ninety six although the Months Pay formerly advanced bee not repaid.</td>
				<td>XVI.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>42</td>
				<td>85</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to continue Foure former Acts for preventing Theft and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders of England.</td>
				<td>XVII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>41</td>
				<td>86</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majesty severall Rates or Duties upon Houses for making good the Deficiency of the clipped Money.</td>
				<td>XVIII.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>38</td>
				<td>86</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to incourage the bringing Plate into the Mint to be coined and for the further remedying the ill State of the Coine of the Kingdome.</td>
				<td>XIX.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>47</td>
				<td>94</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majesty an additionall Duty upon all French Goods and Merchandize.</td>
				<td>XX.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>39</td>
				<td>97</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Increase and Encouragement of Seamen.</td>
				<td>XXI.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>45</td>
				<td>98</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing Frauds and regulating Abuses in the Plantation Trade.</td>
				<td>XXII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>46</td>
				<td>103</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continueing severall former Acts for punishing Officers and Soldiers who shall mutiny or desert His Majesties Service and for punishing false Musters and for Payment of Quarters for One Yeare longer.</td>
				<td>XXIII.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>44</td>
				<td>107</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act requireing the Practicers of Law to take the Oaths and subscribe the Declaration therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>XXIV.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>48</td>
				<td>109</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the further regulating Elections of Members to serve in Parliament and for the preventing irregular Proceedings of Sheriffs and other Officers in the electing and returning such Members.</td>
				<td>XXV.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>43</td>
				<td>109</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for repaireing the High-wayes betweene Wymondham and Attleborough in the County of Norfolk.</td>
				<td>XXVI.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>49</td>
				<td>111</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Security of His Maj[es]ties. Royal Person and Government.</td>
				<td>XXVII.</td>
				<td>p.6.I</td>
				<td>70</td>
				<td>114</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the more effc[i]ual preventing the Exportac[i]on of Wooll and for [the<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] incouraging the Importation there of from Ireland.</td>
				<td>XXVIII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>71</td>
				<td>118</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better amending &amp; repairing the High-ways and Explanacion of the Laws relateing thereunto.</td>
				<td>XXIX.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>76</td>
				<td>120</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for laying several Duties upon Low Wines or Spirits of the first Extraction and for preventing the Frauds and Abuses of Brewers Distillers and other Persons chargeable with the Duties of Excise</td>
				<td>XXX.</td>
				<td>p.7.I</td>
				<td>67</td>
				<td>122</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing to His Majesty certaine Duties upon Salt Glass Wares Stone and Earthen Wares and for granting several Duties upon Tobacco Pipes and other Earthen Wares for carrying on the Warr against France and for establishing a National Land Bank and for taking off the Duties upon Tunnage of Shipps and upon Coals.</td>
				<td>XXXI.</td>
				<td>p.8.I</td>
				<td>68</td>
				<td>130</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Ease of Jurors and better regulating of Juries.</td>
				<td>XXXII.</td>
				<td>p.9.I</td>
				<td>75</td>
				<td>148</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Incouragement of the Greenland Trade.</td>
				<td>XXXIII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>78</td>
				<td>151</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act that the Solemne Affirmation &amp; Declaration of the People called Quakers shall be accepted instead of an Oath in the usu&acute;l Forme.</td>
				<td>XXXIV.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>79</td>
				<td>152</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the inforcing the Laws which restraine Marriages without Licence or Banns &amp; for the better registring Marriags Births and Burials.</td>
				<td>XXXV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>69</td>
				<td>153</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing several Acts of Parliam[en]t. therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>XXXVI.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>73</td>
				<td>154</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1695&ndash;6.</td>
				<td>An. 7, 8.</td>
				<td>An Act for the Encouragem[en]t of Charitable Gifts and Dispositions.</td>
				<td>XXXVII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>77</td>
				<td>155</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to take away the Custome of Wales which hinders persons from disposeing their Personal Estates by their Wills.</td>
				<td>XXXVIII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>74</td>
				<td>155</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for encourageing the Linen Manufacture of Ireland and bringing Flax and Hemp into and the making of Sail Cloth in this Kingdome.</td>
				<td>XXXIX.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>72</td>
				<td>156</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) An Act for revesting in His Majesty the Hono<emph type="p">r</emph> of Tutbury Forrest of Needwood severall Manno<emph type="p">r</emph>s Parkes Lands and Offices and other Profitts thereunto belonging: and for vacatting certein Letters Patents therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>XL.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>80</td>
				<td>157</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<th cols="7">THE TITLES OF THE PRIVATE ACTS.</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enableing the Lady Katherine Fane to sell the Reversion of certaine Fee-Farme Rents given her by her Grandfather John Bence Esq[uire].</td>
				<td>i.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>159</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enableing Sir Thomas Parkyns Baronett to sell certain Messuages Lands and Hereditaments in Huby and Easing Would in the County of York and the settling other Lands &amp; Hereditaments of greater Value in lieu thereof.</td>
				<td>ii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Sir Thomas Pope Blount Baronett to make a Settlement upon the Marriage of his eldest Son.</td>
				<td>iii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Manor of Madley in the County of Salop in Trustees for certaine Purposes therein mencioed.</td>
				<td>iv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the enableing Thomas Stoner Esq Son and Heire of John Stoner Esquire deceased to make a Jointure and Settlement of his Estate in Marriage not withstanding his Minority.</td>
				<td>v.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting several Messuages and Lands belonging to Samuel Powell Esquire in Trustees for Payment of his Debts.</td>
				<td>vi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Anthony Earle of Kent and Henry Grey his Son and Heire Apparent make a Jointure for to Jemina Wife of the said Henry Grey.</td>
				<td>vii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the Lord Francis Powlett to charge his Estate with Provisions for his younger Children.</td>
				<td>viii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Estate late of Sir Nicholas Stoughton and Sir Lawrence Stoughton Baronetts deceased in Trustees to be sold for the Payment of their Debts and raiseing Portions for the Daughters of the said Sir Nicholas Stoughton.</td>
				<td>ix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>16</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Richard Haynes Esquire to settle a Joynture on his now Wife and to exchange Lands with the Trustees of Thomas Stevens Esquire deceased.</td>
				<td>x.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enableing Trustees to sell Part of the Estate of Edmond Warner deceased for Payment of his Debts and for preserving the rest for the benefitt of his Heire.</td>
				<td>xi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>18</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable John Aunger an Infant and his Mother to make a Lease of his Estate for the Improvement thereof.</td>
				<td>xii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>19</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Trustees to sell Part of the Manor of Barkhampstead and to pay of the Incumbrances charged on the same and to lay out the Overplus in an Estate to be settled as the said Manor is now vested.</td>
				<td>xiii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>20</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Henry de Nassau and other Children of Henry de Nassau Seignior de Auverquerke.</td>
				<td>xiv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>23</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable John Fownes Esquire to sell certaine Lands in the County of Devon which were settled on his Marriage and to settle other Lands of an equal Value to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>xv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>24</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1695-6.</td>
				<td>An. 7, 8.</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Trustees to exchange Lands of Sir James Chamberlaine Baronett an Infant lying in the Common Hill or Feild of Salford in the County of Oxford for like Quantities of Lands there in order to the making an Inclosure.</td>
				<td>xvi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>30</td>
				<td>159</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the Parish of S<emph type="p">t</emph>. James within the Liberty of the City of Westminster to raise upon themselves so much Money as will discharge their Debt for building their Parish Church Rectors House Vestry and other Publick Works there.</td>
				<td>xvii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>31</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to ascertaine and settle the Payment of the Impropriate Tythes of the Parish of St. Lawrence Old Jury in London to the Master and Scholars of Balliol College in Oxford and for confirming an Award made concerning the same.</td>
				<td>xviii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>32</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizeing James Stanhope Esquire and others.</td>
				<td>xix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>33</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Salomon Eyme &amp; others.</td>
				<td>xx.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>34</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to confirme &amp; establish an Exchange made between Thomas Rider Esquire and Christopher Clitherow Esq[uire] of certaine Messuages in London for the Manors of Bilsington and other Lands in Kent of the like Value.</td>
				<td>xxi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>35</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Trustees to fill upp Leases of the respective Estates of Bluet Wallop Esq[uire] and John Wallop Gent? dureing theire Minorities and to purchase other Lands by the Fines thereby to be received to the same Uses as the Estates so to be leased are already settled.</td>
				<td>xxii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>36</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enabling Trustees to sell the Mannor of Pespoole in the County of Durham Part of the Estate of William Midford an Infant for Payment of Debts and Incumbrances charged thereon and for preserving the rest of the said Infants Estate.</td>
				<td>xxiii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>37</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for impowering the most Noble Anne Dutchesse of Buccluch and the Right Honorable James Earle of Dalkeith her Son of the Kingdome of Scotland to grant Leases for improving a Peece of Ground in the Parish of Saint Martins in the Fields in the County of Middlesex.</td>
				<td>xxiv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>50</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Trustees to raise Money for the making a Wett Dock and improving the Estate of the Marquesse and Marchionesse of Tavistock att Rodderith in the County of Surrey.</td>
				<td>xxv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>51</td>
				<td>160</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize William commonly called Viscount Tunbridge and other Children of the Earle of Rochford.</td>
				<td>xxvi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>52</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Improvement of a House and Ground in Great Queen Street.</td>
				<td>xxvii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>53</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Trustees to sell a Messuage Garden and Outhouse in Lincolnes-Inn Fields late Sir Robert Sawyers Knight deceased and for purchasing other Lands and Tenements to be settled to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>xxviii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>54</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for settling divers Lands and Rent-Charge on the Rector of the Church of Maydwell in the County of Northampton and his Successors and in lieu thereof for settling other Lands and dischargeing Tythes belonging to the said Church according to several Agreements between the Patron and the said Rector made upon the incloseing of Lands in Maydwell and afterwards with the Consent of the Ordinary confirmed by several Decrees in the Court of Chancery.</td>
				<td>xxix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>55</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for settling the Personal Estate of Richard Jones Esquire and Mary Gufford Spinster [Minors<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] in Trustees for the Purposes therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>xxx.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>56</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better supplying the City of Bristoll with Fresh-Water.</td>
				<td>xxxi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>57</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting of Hospitals and Work-houses within the City of Bristoll for the better imploying and maintaining the Poor thereof.</td>
				<td>xxxii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>58</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for making good the last Will of Sir. William Barkham Baronett deceased and vesting of Lands in Trustees to be sold for Payment of his Debts and making Provision for his Children.</td>
				<td>xxxiii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>59</td>
				<td>160</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Sir Charles Heron Baronett to sell Lands for Payment of a Portion and Debts.</td>
				<td>xxxiv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>60</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Sir Thomas Wagstaffe Knight to raise &amp; secure a Portion for Frances his onely Daughter and Heire Apparent.</td>
				<td>xxxv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>61</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Moiety of the Manor of Shipton Mallett in the County of Somersett and divided Moiety of the Manor of Wells in the said County in Trustees to be sold for Payment of a Mortgage charged thereon and for making a Provision for the Maintenance of Mary the Wife of William Sandes Esq[uire] and her Children.</td>
				<td>xxxvi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>62</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for makeing the Townes of Stretton and Princethorpe a separate Parish from Wolston in the County of Warwick.</td>
				<td>xxxvii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>63</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting Part of the Estate of Joseph Dawson Esq[uire] in Trustees for Payment of Debts and for a Provision for the Maintenance and Marriage of his Daughters.</td>
				<td>xxxviii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>64</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Sale of Lands in Horsington in the County of Somersett Part of the Estate of William Ridout an Infant for Payment of Incumbrances charged thereon and for preserving the Residue of the said Estate for the Infant.</td>
				<td>xxxix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>65</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting certaine Lands of Thomas Bigg and his Wife in Chislett in the County of Kent in Trustees for Payment of Debts and making Provision for their Children.</td>
				<td>xxxx.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>66</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for revesting in His Majesty the Honor of Tutbury Forrest of Needwood several Manors Parks Lands and Offices and other Profitts thereunto belonging and for Vacating certains Letters Patents therein menc[i]oed.</td>
				<td>xxxxi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>80</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1696&ndash;7</td>
				<td>An. 8, 9.</td>
				<td>An Act for importing and coining Guineas and Halfe-guineas.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>p. I.I</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>161</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the further remedying the ill State of the Coin of the Kingdome.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>162</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to explain that Part of the Act passed last Session of Parliament for laying several Duties on Low Wines &amp; Spirits of the first Extraction and for preventing the Frauds and Abuses of Brewers Distillers and other Persons chargeable with the Duties of Excise which relates to the Payment of Tallies &amp; the Interest thereof.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>164</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to attaint Sir John Fenwick Baronett of High Treason.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>165</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to attaint such of the Persons concerned in the late horrid Conspiracy to assassinate His Majesties Royal Person who are fled from Justice unlesse they render themselves to Justice and for continuing several others of the said Conspirators in Custody.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>165</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting an Aid to His Majesty as well by a Land Tax as by several Subsidies and other Duties payable for One Yeare.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>166</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majesty several Duties upon Paper Vellum and Parchment to encourage the bringing of Plate and hammered Money into the Mints to be coined.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>p.2.1</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>189</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for incouraging the bringing in wrought Plate to be coined.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>196</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to restore the Markett att Blackwell-Hall to the Clothiers &amp; for regulating the Factors there.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>16</td>
				<td>199</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the Returns of Juries as formerly until the First Day of November One thousand six hundred ninety seven.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>201</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better preventing frivolous and vexatious Suits.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>201</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing several additional Impositions upon several Goods and Merchandizes.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>203</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing several former Acts for punishing Officers and Soldiers who shall mutiny or desert His Majesties Service and for punishing false Musters and for Payment of Quarters for One Yeare longer.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>p.3.1</td>
				<td>34</td>
				<td>203</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the compleating the building and adorning the Cathedral Church of Saint Paul London &amp; for repaireing the Collegiate Church of Saint Peter Westm?.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>35</td>
				<td>205</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for (<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) repairing the Highway betweene Ryegate in the County of Surrey &amp; Crawley in the County of Sussex.</td>
				<td>XV.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>39</td>
				<td>207</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enlargeing Co[m]mon High-ways.</td>
				<td>XVI.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>36</td>
				<td>210</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for paving and regulating the Hay-Markett in the pish of Saint Martin in the Fields and Saint James within the Liberty of Westminster.</td>
				<td>XVII.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">p</emph>. 4. <emph type="i">not numbered on the Roll</emph>.</td>
				<td>38</td>
				<td>212</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Relief of Creditors by making Composition with their Debtors in Case Two Thirds in Number &amp; Value doe agree.</td>
				<td>XVIII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>37</td>
				<td>213</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for repealing a Clause in a former Act relateing to Party Guiles and for the better preventing Frauds and Abuses [in<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Brewers and others chargeable with the Duties of Excise.</td>
				<td>XIX.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>33</td>
				<td>215</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for making good the Deficiencies of several Funds therein mentioned and for enlargeing the Capital Stock of the Bank of England and for raising the Publick Creditt.</td>
				<td>XX.</td>
				<td>P.5.1</td>
				<td>32</td>
				<td>218</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for laying a Duty upon Leather for the Terme of Three Yeares and making other Provision for answering the Deficiences as well of the late Duties upon Coals &amp; Culme as for paying the Anumities upon the Lottery and for Lives charged on the T&umacr;nage of Ships and the Duties upon Salt.</td>
				<td>XXI.</td>
				<td>p.6.1</td>
				<td>46</td>
				<td>238</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majesty certain Duties upon Malt Mum Sweets Cyder &amp; Perry as well towards carrying on the Warr against France as for the necessary Occasions of His Maj[es]ties Household &amp; other Occasions.</td>
				<td>XXII.</td>
				<td>p. 7.1</td>
				<td>47</td>
				<td>247</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enforce the Act for the Encrease and Encouragement of Seamen.</td>
				<td>XXIII.</td>
				<td>p.8.1</td>
				<td>52</td>
				<td>257</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majesty a further Subsidy of Tunnage and Poundage upon Merchandizes imported for the Terme of Two Yeares &amp; Three Quarters &amp; an additional Land Tax for One Yeare for carrying on the Warr against France.</td>
				<td>XXIV.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>48</td>
				<td>259</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for licensing Hawkers and Pedlars for a further p[ro]vision for the Payment of the Interest of the Transport Debt for the reducing of Ireland.</td>
				<td>XXV.</td>
				<td>p.9.1.</td>
				<td>49</td>
				<td>266</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better p[re]venting the counterfeiting the current Coine of this Kingdome.</td>
				<td>XXVI.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>61</td>
				<td>269</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the more effectual Relief of Creditors in Cases of Escapes &amp; for preventing Abuses in Prisons and pretended priveledged Places.</td>
				<td>XXVII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>62</td>
				<td>271</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Observation of the Course anciently used in the Receipt of Exchequer.</td>
				<td>XXVIII.</td>
				<td>p.10.1</td>
				<td>57</td>
				<td>275</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Repaire of the Peers of Bridlington alies Burlington in the East-Riding of the County of York.</td>
				<td>XXIX.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>56</td>
				<td>279</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for supplying some Defects in the Laws for the Relief of the Poor of this Kingdom.</td>
				<td>XXX.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>59</td>
				<td>281</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the easier obtaining Partitions of Lands in Coparcenary Joynt Tenancy &amp; Tenancy in Common.</td>
				<td>XXXI.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>58</td>
				<td>283</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to restraine the Number and ill Practice of Brokers and Stock-Jobbers.</td>
				<td>XXXII.</td>
				<td>p. II. 1</td>
				<td>60</td>
				<td>285</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to make p[re]petual and more effectual an Act intituled An Act to prevent Delays att the Quarter Sessions of the Peace.</td>
				<td>XXXIII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>51</td>
				<td>287</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the lessening the Duty upon Tin and Pewter exported and granting an Equivalent for the same by a Duty upon Druggs.</td>
				<td>XXXIV.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>50</td>
				<td>288</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for raiseing the Militia for the Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety seven although the Months Pay formerly advanced be not repaid.</td>
				<td>XXXV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>53</td>
				<td>288</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the further Encouragement of the Manufacture of Lustrings and Alamodes within this Realme and for the better preventing the Importation of the same.</td>
				<td>XXXVI.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>55</td>
				<td>289</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for explaining and enforcing the Act for paving and cleansing the Streets within the Cities of London and Westminster and Borough of Southwark &amp; weekly Bills of Mortality and Streets adjoyning thereunto &amp; for widening the Street at the South end of London-Bridge.</td>
				<td>XXXVII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>54</td>
				<td>291</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<th cols="7">TITLES OF THE PRIVATE ACTS.</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Frederick Christiaen de Rhede commonly called Lord Aghram and others.</td>
				<td>1.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>293</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Settlement of the Mannor of Treyagoe in the County of Hereford and other the Lands late of Crompton Mynors Esquire deceased and for raising and encreasing of the Portion of Theodosia Mynors the Daughter of the said Crompton she being an Infant of the Age of Seventeene Yeares.</td>
				<td>ij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Manor of Holme alias East Holme and Swannage in the County of Dorsett part of the Estate of Sir John Hotham Baronett in Trustees to be sold for discharging a Mortgage thereupon and upon the residue of the said Sir John Hothams Estate &amp; for Payment of his other Debts.</td>
				<td>iij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enabling Oliver Neve of Great Witchingham in the County of Norffolk Esquire to sell Two Houses in London and for vesting other Lands in the said County of greater Value to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>iiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enabling James Duke of Ormond to raise Money by Sale of Woods and making Leases for Lives renewable for ever for Payment of Debts and for encourageing English Plantation in Ireland and for Charles Lord Weston Earle of Arran in the Kingdome of Ireland to make Leases of his Estate in the said Kingdome.</td>
				<td>v.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Exchange of certaine Advowsons betweene the Bishopp of London and the Earle of Nottingham.</td>
				<td>vj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>18</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the speedy satisfying the Debts of Francis late Lord Holles deceased.</td>
				<td>vij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>19</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Sir Ralph Ashton Baronett to supply an omission of Limitation intended in his Marriage Settlement for the Benefitt of his Issue Male.</td>
				<td>viij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>20</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Sale of the Estate of Francis Griffith late of London Scrivener deceased for Payment of his Debts.</td>
				<td>ix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>21</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for settling the Estate of Mary Savile an Infant upon her Marriage.</td>
				<td>x.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>22</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the Sale of Lands late of Jeoffery Stockley in the County of Chester deceased for Payment of his Debts and for making Provision for Mary his Daughter.</td>
				<td>xj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>23</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting certaine Messuages Lands and Tenements late of Charles Milson deceased in Trustees to sell for Payment of Debts and Legacies and lay out the Surplus Money in a Purchase of Lands for the Use of Edward Milson and his Heires according to the Will of the said Charles Milson.</td>
				<td>xij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>24</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Nicholas Goodwin the elder and Nicholas Goodwin the younger to sell the Mannor of Winslow in the County of Bucks and with the Moneys ariseing thereby and other Moneys to be advanced by the said Nicholas Goodwin the elder to purchase Lands of a greater yearely Value to be settled to the same Uses as the said Manor is now settled.</td>
				<td>xiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>25</td>
				<td>293</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the vesting of certaine Lands of William Melward in the County of Hereford Clerk in Trustees for Payment of Debts.</td>
				<td>xiiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>26</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Estate of Edward Kerrey Esquire lying in Binoeston in the County of Salop in Trustees to discharge Incumbrances thereon and to raise Portions for younger Children and for confirming the Marriage Settlement of the said Edward Kerrey.</td>
				<td>xv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>27</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting Part of the Estate of Thomas Panton Esquire in Trustees to be sold for Payment of Debts and securing a Jointure to Mary his now Wife.</td>
				<td>xvj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>28</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing John Keyser &amp; others.</td>
				<td>xvij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>29</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Edward Leigh Esquire and Jane his Wife and their Trustees to sell the Mannors of Waxham and Horsey and certaine Lands and Tenements in the County of Norffolk and to purchase and settle other Lands to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>xviij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>30</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting and settling certaine Estates of William James Gent in and upon Trustees to be sold for the Payment of Debts &amp; making Provision for himselfe his Wife and their Children.</td>
				<td>xix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>31</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for importing several Goods and Merchandizes laden in Turkey on board the Shipps called the Successe and Draggon Galley paying Customes as if imported by English Shipps.</td>
				<td>xx.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>40</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable William Fallows an Infant to sell an Estate in the County of Chester to pay Debts secured by Mortgages.</td>
				<td>xxj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>41</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to supply a Defect in an Act for enabling Oliver Neve Esquire to sell Two Houses in London and for settling Lands in the County of Norffolk of greater Value to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>xxij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>42</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act explaining a former Act of Parliament intituled An Act for enabling Trustees to sell Part of the Estate of Edmund Warner deceased for Payment of his Debts and for preserving the rest for the Benefitt of his Heires.</td>
				<td>xxiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>43</td>
				<td>294</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting Part of the Estate of Roger Crowle Esquire deceased in Trustees for raiseing Portions for his Younger Children in regard hee (being a Lunatick) could not execute a Power in his Marriage Settlement for that Purpose.</td>
				<td>xxiiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>44</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to vest certaine Lands late of Samuel Trotman Esquire deceased lying in Barking Eastham Westham and Woolwich in the Counties of Kent and Essex in Trustees to be sold and to settle other Lands in lieu thereof.</td>
				<td>xxv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>45</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the speedy Payment of the Debts of Sir William Thompson Knight Serjeant att Law deceased.</td>
				<td>xxvj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>63</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for annulling the Marriage of Hannah Knight an Infant and directing the Guardianshipp of the said Infant.</td>
				<td>xxvij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>64</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the enabling the Sale of the Mannor of Rowling in Kent which by Mistake was by General Words comprized in the Marriage Settlement of the said William Hamond Gent contrary to the Meaning of the Parties.</td>
				<td>xxviij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>65</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1697&ndash;8.</td>
				<td>An. 9.</td>
				<td>An Act against corresponding with the late King James and his Adherents.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>p.1. I</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>295</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent the further Currency of any hammered Silver Coine of this Kingdome &amp; for recoining such as is now in being and for the making out new Exchequer Bills where the former Bills are or shall be filled upp by Indorsements.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>297</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to give further Time for the administring of Oaths relating to Talleys &amp; Orders and for the easier Dispatch of the Publick. Businesse in the Exchequer &amp; in the Bank of England.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>298</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing the Imprisonment of Counter and others for the late horrid Conspiracy to assassinate the person of His Sacred Majesty.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>300</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for satisfying and discharging the Arreares of several Annuities which incurred betweene the Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety six and the Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety seven.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>300</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act that all Retailers of Salt shall sell by Weight.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>302</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent the throwing or firing of Squibbs Serpent? &amp; other Fire-works.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>303.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for explaineing an Act made the last Session of Parliament for granting to His Majesty certaine Duties upon Malt Mum Sweets Cyder &amp; Perry.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>304</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for rendring the Laws more effectual for preventing the Importation of Forreign Bone-Lace Loom-lace Needle-work Point &amp; Cutt-work.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>304</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majesty the Sum of One Million foure hundred eighty foure thousand &amp; fifteene Pounds one Shilling eleaven Pence three Farthings for disbanding Forces paying Seamen and other Uses therein mencioed.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>p. 2.</td>
				<td>20</td>
				<td>307</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for explaining an Act made the last Session of Parliament entituled<br/>An Act for supplying some Defects in the Laws for the Relief of the Poorof this Kingdome.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>P. 3. 1</td>
				<td>21</td>
				<td>364</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the inlargeing repaireing and preserving the Bridge &amp; Key of the Borough of Bridgewater in the County of Somersett.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>22</td>
				<td>365</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majestie several Duties upon Coals and Culm.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>35</td>
				<td>367</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing the Duties upon Coffee Tea and Chocolate and Spicestoward? Satisfaction of the Debt due for Transport Service for the Reduction of Ireland.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>36</td>
				<td>369</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for determining Differences by Arbitration.</td>
				<td>XV.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>39</td>
				<td>369</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to execute Judgment? &amp; Decrees saved in a Clause in an Act of the First Yeare of the Reigne of King William and Queen Mary intituled<br/>An Act for taking away the Court holden before the President and Council of the Marches of Wales.</td>
				<td>XVI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>38</td>
				<td>370</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Payment. of Inland Bills of Exchange.</td>
				<td>XVII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>40</td>
				<td>371</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for repairing the Highways from the Town of Birdlipp and the Top of Crickley Hill in the County of Gloucester to the City of Gloucester.</td>
				<td>XVIII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>44</td>
				<td>371</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for cleansing &amp; making Navigable the Channel from the [Hithe<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] att Colchester to Wivenhoe.</td>
				<td>XIX.</td>
				<td>p. 4.1</td>
				<td>43</td>
				<td>375</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize the Children of such Officers and Souldiers &amp; others the natural borne Subjects of this Realme who have been borne abroad during the Warr the Parents of such Children haveing been in the Service of this Government.</td>
				<td>XX</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>41</td>
				<td>380</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better preventing the counterfeiting clipping and other diminishing the Coine of this Kingdome.</td>
				<td>XXI.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>37</td>
				<td>381</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to repeale an Act made in the Nine and thirtieth Yeare of the Reigne of Queen Elizabeth intituled (An Act to restraine the excessive making of Malt) and to discharge &amp; vacate Orders made by Justices of Peace by virtue thereof for restraining Malsters from makeing Malt.</td>
				<td>XXII.</td>
				<td>p.4.4</td>
				<td>42</td>
				<td>382</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majesty a further Subsidy of Tunnage and Poundage towards raiseing the Yearly Summ of Seven hundred thousand Pounds for the Service of His Majesties. Household &amp; other Uses therein mencioned dureing His Majesties Life.</td>
				<td>XXIII.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>63</td>
				<td>382</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for inlarging the Time for purchasing certain Estates or Interests in several Annuities therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>XXIV.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>70</td>
				<td>385</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majesty His Heires &amp; Successors further Duties upon Stampt Vellum Parchment. &amp; Paper.</td>
				<td>XXV.</td>
				<td>p.5.I</td>
				<td>69</td>
				<td>386</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to settle the Trade to Africa.</td>
				<td>XXVI.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>85</td>
				<td>393</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for licensing Hawkers and Pedlars for a further Provision of Interest for the Transport Debt for reduceing of Ireland.</td>
				<td>XXVII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>68</td>
				<td>397</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the exporting Watches Sword-hilts and other Manufactures of Silver.</td>
				<td>XXVIII.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>83</td>
				<td>399</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to repeal the Act made the last Session of Parliament intituled An Act for Relief of Creditors by making Composition with their Debtors in case Two Thirds in Number and Value do agree.</td>
				<td>XXIX.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>84</td>
				<td>400</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for increasing His Ma[jes]ties Duties upon Lustrings and Alamodes.</td>
				<td>XXX.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>65</td>
				<td>401</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for raising the [Milita<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] for the Year One thousand six hundred ninety eight although the Months Pay formerly advanced be not [paid.<ref idref="n10">10</ref>]</td>
				<td>XXXI.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>80</td>
				<td>401</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>
(<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) An Act for preventing Frauds and Abuses in the charging collecting &amp; paying the Duties upon Marriages Births Burials Batchellors and Widowers.</td>
				<td>XXXII.</td>
				<td>p. 6. 1.</td>
				<td>67</td>
				<td>403</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) An Act for the Increase and Preservation of Timber in the New Forest in the County, of Southampton.</td>
				<td>XXXIII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>76</td>
				<td>405</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) An Act for applying to the Use of His Majesties Navy and Ordnance the Overplus of the Money and Stores which were provided for the building Seven and twenty Ships of War.</td>
				<td>XXXIV.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>77</td>
				<td>408</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) An Act for the more effectual suppressing of Blasphemy and Profaneness.</td>
				<td>XXXV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>75</td>
				<td>409</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n15">15</ref>) An Act to stop the coining Farthings and Halfpence for One Year.</td>
				<td>XXXVI.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>74</td>
				<td>409</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) An Act for the better and more orderly Payment of the Lottery Tickets now payable out of certain additional Duties of Excise and of other Annuities lately payable out of (<ref idref="n17">17</ref>) Tunnage Duties.</td>
				<td>XXXVII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>66</td>
				<td>410</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majesty an Aid by a Quarterly Poll for One Year.</td>
				<td>XXXVIII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>64</td>
				<td>411</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for settling and adjusting the Proportion of Fine Silver (<ref idref="n18">18</ref>) Silk for the better making of Silver and Gold Thread and to prevent the Abuses of (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) Wire-Drawers.</td>
				<td>XXXIX.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>82</td>
				<td>420</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Explanation and better Execution of former Acts made against Transportation of Wool Fullers Earth and Scouring Clay.</td>
				<td>XL.</td>
				<td>p.6.9</td>
				<td>81</td>
				<td>421</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better preventing the Imbezlement of His Majesties Stores of War and preventing Cheats Frauds and Abuses in paying Seamens Wages.</td>
				<td>XLI.</td>
				<td>p.7.1</td>
				<td>73</td>
				<td>423</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enlarging the Time for registring of Ships pursuant to the Act for preventing Frauds and regulating Abuses in the Plantation Trade.</td>
				<td>XLII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>78</td>
				<td>425</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Incouragement of the Royal Lustring Company and the more effectual preventing the fraudulent Importation of Lustrings and Alamodes.</td>
				<td>XLIII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>79</td>
				<td>426</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for raising a Sum not exceeding Two Millions upon a Fund for Payment of Annuities after the Rate of Eight Pounds per Centum per Annum and for settling the Trade to the East Indies.</td>
				<td>XLIV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>72</td>
				<td>429</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for taking away Half the Duties imposed on Glass Wares and the whole Duties lately laid on Stone and Earthen Wares and Tobacco Pipes and for granting (in lieu thereof) new Duties upon Whale Fins and Scotch Linen.</td>
				<td>XLV.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>71</td>
				<td>447</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<th cols="7">TITLES OF THE PRIVATE ACTS.</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting in Sydenham Baker Gents an absolute Estate of Inheritance in Fee Simple in a certaine Rent Messuages Lands &amp; Hereditaments in the County of Devon and secureing to John Baker Gents &amp; Henry Baker an Infant his Son Moneys in lieu of their Claims thereunto.</td>
				<td>i.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>449</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enabling Simon Lord Bishop Ely &amp; his Successors to lease the Mannor House &amp; Demesne Lands of Downham in the Isle of Ely &amp; for confirming a Lease lately thereof made by the said Bishopp &amp; for cleareing the said Bishopp and others from Dilapidations there.</td>
				<td>ii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Sir Francis Guybon and Dame Isabella his Wife and their Trustees to sell the Mannor of Avenalls and other Lands in or neare Gunthorpe in the County of Norfolke and for settling other Lands in lieu thereof.</td>
				<td>iii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Naturalization of Gerrard Maesacker and others.</td>
				<td>iv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Rebecca Lassels Widdow to sell Coppyhold Lands and Houses in Ealing in the County of Middlesex.</td>
				<td>v.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting in Trustees to be sold certaine Lands of George Farrington Esquire lying in the Counties of Middlesex and Surrey settled upon the Marriage of William Farrington his Nephew and with the Moneys ariseing thereby for purchasing [of<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] other Lands in Lancashire where the ancient Estate of the Family lies to bee settled to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>vi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the Trustees of William Knott Gents and his Wife to sell a Lease of Houses in Bread Street London for Payment of Debts and to settle another Estate of better Value in lieu thereof.</td>
				<td>vii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>16</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to ennable Thomas Kinnersly Esquire an Infant to make a Joynture and Settlement of his Estate.</td>
				<td>viii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Dudley Vesey an Infant.</td>
				<td>ix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>18</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable John Lewin to sell certaine Messuages in Southwarke for Payment of Debts.</td>
				<td>x.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>19</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for dissolving the Marriage betweene Charles Earle of Macclesfeild and Anne his Wife and to illegitimate the Children of the said Anne.</td>
				<td>xi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>23</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable John Lord Bishopp of Chichester to make Leases of certaine Houses and Grounds belonging to the Bishoprick of Chichester scituate in Chancery-Lane for a competent Number of Yeares.</td>
				<td>xii.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>24</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize Charles May Esq[uire].</td>
				<td>xiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>25</td>
				<td>449</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to rectify a Mistake in the Marriage Settlement of William Gardner Esquires.</td>
				<td>xiiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>26</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable certaine Trustees therein named to make renew and fill upp Leases of the Estate of Sir Coppleston Warwick Bampfylde dureing the Minoritye of the said Sir Copplestone Warwick Bampfylde and John Bampfylde his Brother.</td>
				<td>xv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>27</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for settling the Estate of John Hall a Lunatick subject to a Debt charged thereon.</td>
				<td>xvj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>28</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting Hospitals Work-houses and Houses of Correction within the Towne and Parish of Crediton in the County of Devon and for the better Reliefe of the Poor there.</td>
				<td>xvij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>29</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the Towne and Parish of Tiverton in the County of Devon for the better imploying and maintaining the Poor thereof.</td>
				<td>xviij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>30</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for confirming and establishing the Administration of the Goods and Chattells of Sir Will[ia]m Godolphin Knight dec[eas]ed.</td>
				<td>xix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>31</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the naturalizing of John Francis Fauquire Joseph Ducasse and others.</td>
				<td>xx.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>32</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better enabling Sir Ralph Hare Baronett to make a Joynture and settie his Estate and raise Portions and Maintenances for his younger Children.</td>
				<td>xxj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>33</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting in Trustees to be sold certain Lands of George Hewett Esquires lying in the County of Middlesex settled upon his Marriage and with the Money arising thereby for purchasing other Lands in Leicestershire where his Estate and Seat lies to be settled to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>xxij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>34</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting Lands in Trustees to be sold for Payment of the Debts of Wriothesly Baptist late Earle of Gainesborough deceased.</td>
				<td>xxiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>45</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to annex the Rectory of Whitborne in Herefordshire to the Bishoprick of Hereford.</td>
				<td>xxiiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>46</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better settling the several Estates of the Right Honorable John Lord Viscount Lisburne in the Kingdome of Ireland and the Lady Viscountess Lisburne his Wife.</td>
				<td>xxv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>47</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for supplying a Defect in a Conveyance lately made by Sir Edward Turner and Charles Turner Esquires his Son for the more effectuall securing the Summ of Twelve thousand Pounds &amp; Interest upon their Estate.</td>
				<td>xxvj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>48</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the vesting several Lands late belonging to Robert Smith Esquires deceased in Trustees to be sold for the Payment of his Debts.</td>
				<td>xxvij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>49</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Mannors of Bastwick and Laviles in the County of Norfolk Part of the Estate of John Houghton Esquire in Trustees to be sold for discharging Debts charged thereon and for settling another Estate in lieu thereof.</td>
				<td>xxviij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>50</td>
				<td>450</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Streynsham Master Esquires to sell Lands in Kent which were agreed to be settled by his Marriage Articles and to convey Lands in Derbyshire of a greater Value to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>xxix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>51</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Paris Slaughter William Druce Merchants and Dame Elizabeth Chapman to import several Bails of Fine Italian Thrown Silk into this Kingdome.</td>
				<td>xxx.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>52</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for settling certaine Lands in Essex in Thomas Burgh [Esquires<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] and his Heires in lieu of other Lands of greater Value conveyed by him according to the Decree and the Will of Sir Samuel Jones deceased.</td>
				<td>xxxi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>53</td>
				<td/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting certaine Customary Messu&auml;ges, and Lands within the Mannor of Gillingham in the County of Dorsett (late the Estate of Thomas Davies Gents deceased) in Trustees to be sold for Payment of Debts.</td>
				<td>xxxij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>54</td>
				<td>450</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting Hospitals and Work-houses within the City and County of the City of Exon for the better imploying and maintaining the Poor there.</td>
				<td>xxxiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>55</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the City of Hereford for the better imploying and maintaining the Poor there.</td>
				<td>xxxiiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>56</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to rectifie some Mistakes in an Act intituled An Act to enable John Lewin to sell certaine Messuages in Southwark for Payment of Debts.</td>
				<td>xxxv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>57</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting a Moiety of certaine Messuages and Lands in Hackney in the County of Middlesex in Trustees for the Benefitt of Susanna Cary Widdow and Relict of Nicholas Cary Esquire deceased and others.</td>
				<td>xxxvi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>58</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the Towne of Colchester in the County of Essex for the better imploying and maintaining the Poor thereof.</td>
				<td>xxxvij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>59</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize William Lloyd Esquire and others.</td>
				<td>xxxviij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>60</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to confirme the Sale of Part of the Estate of Sir. John Churchill Knight lately deceased pursuant to his Last Will and Two Decrees of Chancery for performance thereof.</td>
				<td>xxxix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>61</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Mannor of Alveston and other Lands therein mentioned in the County of Gloucester in Trustees to be sold for Payment of Debts and other Purposes therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>xl.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>62</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An AA for confirming a Lease, granted by the Lord Bishopp of Winton of a Parcell of Waste Ground in Alverstock in the County of Southton for the erecting of Waterworks there and for improving the same.</td>
				<td>xli.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>86</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for securing the Portions intended by Sir William Walter Baronett deceased for his Children by the Lady Mary Walter his Second Wife and for preventing all Doubts which might arise upon the Construction of the Articles and Will therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>xlij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>87</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Relief of the Creditors of Edward Backwell Esquire deceased.</td>
				<td>xliij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>88</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting certaine Lands and Hereditaments in Maidstone and elsewhere in the County of Kent in Trustees for the Benefitt of Diana Cecill and others.</td>
				<td>xliiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>89</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to confirme a Conveyance made by George Pitt Esquire and others of the Mannor of Tarrant Preston and other Lands in the County of Dorsett to John Pitt Gents and the Heires Males of his Body.</td>
				<td>xlv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>90</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better supplying the Towne of Newcastle upon Tyne with Fresh Water.</td>
				<td>xlvj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>91</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting Work-houses and Houses of Correction in the Towne of Kingston upon Hull for the Imployment and Maintenance of the Poor there.</td>
				<td>xlvij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>92</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting Work-houses and Houses of Correction in the Towne of Shaftesbury and for the better Imployment and Maintenance of the Poor.</td>
				<td>xlviij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>93</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing of Peter Garon and others.</td>
				<td>xlix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>94</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Hillary Reneu and others.</td>
				<td>l.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>95</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act that the Ships Panther Gloucester Frigott Scarborough and Antelope (formerly taken as Prizes and condemned) may have freedom of trading as English built Shipps.</td>
				<td>li.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>96</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for giving Leave to the Maryland Merchant of Bristoll to arrive and import-her lading into this Kingdome.</td>
				<td>lij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>97</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act that the Ships called the Ruby Prize and Plymouth may have Freedom of trading as English built Shipps.</td>
				<td>liij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>98</td>
				<td>450</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting a Copperas work late Part of the Estate of Robert Mascall Esquire decided in Trustees to be sold for Payment of Debts and other Charges thereupon.</td>
				<td>liiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>99</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Sale of Three Houses in Swan Alley in Coleman Street London late of Joseph Smith deceased for Payment of his Debts with which the same Houses are chargeable.</td>
				<td>lv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>100</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable John Jenkin Merchant to sell part of his Estate for Payment of his Debts.</td>
				<td>lvi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>101</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable John Hawkes Gentleman to sell Lands in the County of Salop for Payment of his Debts.</td>
				<td>lvij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>102</td>
				<td>451</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Humphrey Walrond Gents to sell part of his Estate for the making Provision for his eldest Son and Elizabeth his Daughter (who are Lunaticks) and Payment of his Debts and raising Portions for his other Children.</td>
				<td>lviij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>103</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to give Leave to the Ship Sally Rose (formerly taken as Prize) to arrive and import her lading and to trade as an English built Shipp.</td>
				<td>lix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>104</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting in Thomas Rogers Gents an absolute Estate of Inheritance in Fee Simple in the Mannor of Westcourt Mansion House Messuages Lands and Hereditaments in the County of Kent and securing to John Higgons Gents Alice his Wife and for Portions for Irene Margarett Mary and Alice Cesar Moneys in lieu of their Claims thereunto.</td>
				<td>lx.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>105</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Trustees to make Leases and grant Copies and receive the Rents and Proffitts of the Estates late of Sir Edward Wyndham Baronett deceased and Hopton Wyndham Esquire deceased during the Minority of Sir Will[ia]m Wyndham Baronett for the Intents and Purposes therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>lxi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>106</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enabling Humphrey Trafford Esquire to raise Foure thousand Pounds upon his Estate for Payment of his Debts.</td>
				<td>lxij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>107</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1698.</td>
				<td>An. 10.</td>
				<td>An Act for granting an Aid to His Majesty for disbanding the Army and other necessary Occasions.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>p. I.I</td>
				<td>I</td>
				<td>452</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent the makeing or selling Buttons made of Cloth Serge Drugget or other Stuffs.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>454</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prohibit the Exportation of any Corn Malt Meale Flour Bread Biscuit or Starch for One Yeare from the Tenth Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety eight.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>454</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prohibit the excessive distilling of Spirits and Low Wines from Corne and against the exporting of Beer and Ale and to prevent Frauds in Distillers.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>456</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the clearing repairing preserving and maintaining the Haven and Piers of Great Yarmouth in the County of Norfolke.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>II</td>
				<td>460</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enlarge the Trade to Russia.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>462</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing irregular Proceedings of Sheriffs and other Officers in making the Returns of Members chosen to serve in Parliament.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>464</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for makeing and keeping the River Tone navigable from Bridgwater to Taunton in the County of Somersett.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>464</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n22">22</ref>) An Act for granting to His Majesty the Sum of One Million four hundred eighty four thousand and fifteene one Shilling eleaven Pence three Farthings for disbanding the Army providing for the Navy and for other necessary Occasions.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>p.2.</td>
				<td>32</td>
				<td>469</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n23">23</ref>) An Act for laying further Duties upon Sweets and for lessening the Duties aswell upon Vineger as upon certain Low Wines and Whalefins and the Duties upon Brandy imported and for the more easie raising the Duties upon Leather and for charging Cynders and for permitting the Importation of Pearl Ashes and for preventing. Abuses in the brewing of Beere and Ale and Frauds in. Importation of Tobacco.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>p.3. 1.</td>
				<td>34</td>
				<td>501</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n24">24</ref>) An Act for the more full and effectual charging of the Duties upon Rock-Salt.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>33</td>
				<td>508</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n25">25</ref>) An Act for the better apprehending prosecuting and punishing of Felons that commit Burglary Housebreaking or Robbery in Shops Ware-houses Coach-houses or Stables or that steal Horses.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>48</td>
				<td>511</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n26">26</ref>) An Act for makeing Billingsgate a Free Market for Sale of Fish.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>45</td>
				<td>513</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n27">27</ref>) An Act to incourage the Trade to Newfoundland.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>36</td>
				<td>515</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n28">28</ref>) An Act for opening the ancient and makeing any New Roynes and Water Courses in and neare Sedgmore in the County of Someset for rendring the said Moor more healthfull and profitable to the Inhabitants.</td>
				<td>XV.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>50</td>
				<td>518</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<th cols="7">TITLES OF THE PRIVATE ACTS.</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the more easie and certaine Payment of the Debts of Edward Earl of Darwentwater by Sale of Woods and Timber and for enabling him to raise Money for Discharge of Incumbrances upon Part of his Estate.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>522</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Elizabeth Farewell.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Nicholas Lepell.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Bartholomew Ogilby and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Ships Margaret and Friendship of Bristoll to trade as Free Ships.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalize James St. Pierre John Denty and Remond Hensbergh.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize Charles de Siburg and Francis St. George.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize William Lloyd Cornelius de Witt and Godfrey Lloyd.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>16</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize John Meoles.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>18</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Releife of the Creditors of Sir Robert Vyner Knight and Baronet deceased.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>19</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Naturalization of Theophilus Rabesineres and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>20</td>
				<td>523</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enabling George Penne Esquire to sell Lands for the Payment of his Debts and other Purposes therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>21</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize Philip de Chenevix and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>22</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize William Lower William Darnell and Peter Godby.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>23</td>
				<td>523</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Anthony Columbiere and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>24</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize George Burnett.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>25</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize Mark Anthony Davessins de Moncall and David Loches.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>26</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Naturalization of John Francis de Carcassonet and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>27</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Captain Thomas Browne and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>28</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize John de Philip [0<ref idref="n29">29</ref>]neau Sieur de Montargiere and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>29</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Peter Barailleau and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>30</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Ship Charles Flyboat of Exeter to trade as a Free Ship.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>31</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize Isaac Gouyquette de St Eloy.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act settling Augmentations on certain Vicaridges for ever.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>53</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for confirming of a Grant and Settlement made by William Forster Esquire of divers Mannors and Lands in the County Palatine of Durham and County of Northumberland to Thomas Lord Fairfax and others upon certain Trusts [and Uses<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>62</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Sale of some Part of the Estate of Sir Thomas Darcy deceased for Payment of Debts.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>54</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Edward Price Esquire to transferr a Charge of One thousand Pounds for the Use of his younger Children from an Estate in the County of Montgomery to an Estate in the Countys of Hereford and Radnor of better Value.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>57</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Trustees to sell Part of the Estate of George Scott Esquire to pay Debts and raise Portions for his Brothers and Sister and to settle other Part of his Estate.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>78</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Sale of the Estate of Dudley Vesey in Hintlesham in the County of Suffolke for the Payments of his Debts.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>75</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Robert Aldworth and his Wife to sell their Estate in or near Wantage in the County of Berks for raising Three hundred Pounds for Payment of his Debts and for applying the Residue of the Money for purchasing some other Estate for the sole Use of his Wife and Children.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>80</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Incouragement of a new Invention by Thomas Savery for raising Water and occasioning Motion to all Sorts of Mill Worke by the impellent Force of Fire.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>61</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize Scipio Guy and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>85</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Sale of the Mannors of Halwill and Becket in the County of Devon the Estate of John Moor for Payment of Debts.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>72</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Reall Estate late of Thomas Lascells Esquire deceased in Trustees to be sold for the Payment of Debts.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>69</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable John Young Gentleman to sell Lands for Payment of Debts and Legacies.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>77</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the Towne of Liverpoole in the County Palatine of Lancaster to build a Church and endow the same and for making the said Towne and Liberties thereof a Parish of itselfe distinct from Walton.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>60</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Thomas Okeover Gentleman Son and Heir Apparent of Rowland Okeover [of Okeover<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] in the County of Stafford Esquire together with the said Rowland Okeover to make a Joynture and Settlement upon the Marriage of the said Thomas Okeover.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>58</td>
				<td>523</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Katherine Leeke an Infant under the Age of One and twenty Yeares to settle and dispose of her Estate upon her Marriage.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>59</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting certain Lands of Sir Thomas Seyliard Baronet in the County of Kent in Trustees to be sold for the Payment of his Sisters Portions charged thereon.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>55</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Thomas Byde Esquire an Infant (with the Consent of his Guardians and next Relations) to make a Contract for the buying in his Mothers Joynture and to settle a small Estate in Great Amwell in the County of Hertford and likewise for the securing and raising [a<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] Portion for Barbara-Byde Sister to the said Thomas Byde and for other Purposes in the Act mentioned.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>64</td>
				<td/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Sale of the Mannor of Lordington alias Lurtington and Whitney and divers Lands in the County of Sussex and for laying out Five thousand Pounds in purchasing other Lands to be settled in lieu thereof.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>63</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Samuel Wake alias Jones Esquire to sell Lands to pay Debts and to purchase other Lands adjoyning to and formerly Parcell of the Mannor of Waltham alias Waltham Holy Crosse in the County of Essex to be [settled] to the same Uses<ref idref="n33">33</ref>]</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>65</td>
				<td>524</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the vesting and setling the Estate of Ann Bridges and Infant in Bermudas alias the Summer Islands in America in and upon Trustees to be so sold and laying out the Money ariseing by such Sale in England for the Use of the said Ann Bridges.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>71</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the enabling Cyriac Weslyd Esquire to sell some Part of his Estate which by Articles upon his Marriage was agreed to be settled upon his Wife and Children and for setling of other Part of his Estate of better Value to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>70</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Ships Hawke and Rainbow to trade as English built Ships.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>73</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable John Bull an Infant to sell his Lands in Kent for the Payment of Debts and Annuities charged thereon and for Provision for younger Children.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>66</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enabling the surviving Trustees of Sir William Pulteney Knight deceased to make Leases for the raising of Moneys for Payment of his Son William Pultneys Debts and other Purposes therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>56</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Popham Conway Francis Seymour and Charles Seymour Esquires and their Issue Male severally and successively to make Leases of their Estates.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>51</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Sale of the Estate of Zenobia Hough for the Payment of the Debts of her Husband and other Uses.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>76</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the Ship Hope (of great Length and very serviceable for bringing Masts into this Kingdom) to trade as an English built Ship.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>74</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable William Wrayford Gentleman and Dame Ann Rich Widow to make Leases of Houses and Ground in Covent Garden late the Estate of John Athy Citizen and Haberdasher of London.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>67</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Sale of the Mannor of Downham in the County of Essex (the Estate of Sir Francis Andrews) and for buying and setling other Lands to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>52</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to discharge the Ships King William and Charles the Second from the Penalties of the Act of Navigation.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>81</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>-.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Thomas Methwold Esquire to raise the Sum of Twelve hundred Pounds upon his Estate by him laid out in improving the same.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>79</td>
				<td>52</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for selling divers Freehold and Leasehold Houses the Estate of Thomas Cowslade an Infant and others to discharge a Mortgage and to purchase other Lands to be settled to the like Uses.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>68</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Augustine Cloribus and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>84</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Samuel Bernardeau Peter Chantreau des Gaudree and others Private Gentlemen belonging to His Majesties Three Troops of Guards and Grenadiers.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>86</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize Richard Legg and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>83</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Sir David Collier Isaac la Melionere Peter de Belcastel and William Reiatore.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>82</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n34">34</ref>) An Act to prevent the Exportation of Wool out of the Kingdoms of Ireland and England into Forreigne Parts and for the Incouragement of the Woollen Manufactures in the Kingdom of England.</td>
				<td>XVI.</td>
				<td>p. 4. I</td>
				<td>37</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n35">35</ref>) An Act to enable such Officers and Soldiers as have been in His Majesties Service during the late Warr to exercise Trades and for Officers to account with their Soldiers.</td>
				<td>XVII.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>46</td>
				<td>528
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n36">36</ref>) An Act for raising the Militia for the Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety nine although the Months Pay formerly advanced be not repaid.</td>
				<td>XVIII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>44</td>
				<td>530
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n37">37</ref>) An Act for the continueing the Imprisonment of Counter and others for the late horrid Conspiracy to assassinate the Person of His Sacred Majesty.</td>
				<td>XIX.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>43</td>
				<td>531
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n38">38</ref>) An Act for limiting certaine Times within which Writts of Error shall be brought for the reversing Fines Common Recoveries and ancient Judgments.</td>
				<td>XX.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>38</td>
				<td>531
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n39">39</ref>) An Act for continueing the Act for the more easie Recovery of Small Tythes.</td>
				<td>XXI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>39</td>
				<td>532
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n40">40</ref>) An Act to enable posthumus Children to take Estates as if borne in their Fathers Life time.</td>
				<td>XXII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>49</td>
				<td>532
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n41">41</ref>) An Act for suppressing of Lotteries.</td>
				<td>XXIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>47</td>
				<td>532
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n42">42</ref>) An Act for takeing off the remaining Duties upon Glasse Wares.</td>
				<td>XXIV.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>42</td>
				<td>533
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n43">43</ref>) An Act for the makeing and keeping navigable the Rivers of Aire and Calder in the County of Yorke.</td>
				<td>XXV.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>40</td>
				<td>534
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>(<ref idref="n44">44</ref>) An Act for makeing and keeping the River Trent in the Counties of Leicester Derby and Stafford navigable.</td>
				<td>XXVI.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>41</td>
				<td>538</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1698&ndash;9.</td>
				<td>An. 11.</td>
				<td>An Act for taking away the Bounty Money for exporting Corn from the Ninth Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety nine to the Nine and twentieth Day of September One thousand seaven hundred.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>p.1.1.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>544
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting an Aid to His Majesty by Sale of the forfeited and other Estates and Interests in Ireland and by a Land Tax in England for the severall Purposes therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>545
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for laying further Duties upon wrought Silks Muslins and some other Commodities of the East-Indies and for enlargeing the Time for purchasing certaine reversionary Annuities therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>p.2.1</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>582
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the further preventing the Growth of Popery.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>586
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Repaire of Dover Harbour.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>588
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable His Majesties naturall borne Subjects to inherite the Estate of their Ancestors either lineall or collaterall notwithstanding their Father or Mother were Aliens.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>590
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the more effectuall Suppression of Piracy.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>590
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the appointing Commissioners to take examine and determine the Debts due to the Army Navy and for Transport-Service and alsoe an Account of the Prizes taken during the late Warr.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>25</td>
				<td>594
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing of frivolous and vexatious Suits in the Principality of Wales and the Counties Palatine.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>597
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the more effectuall imploying the Poor by incourageing the Manufactures of this Kingdom.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>p.3. 1</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>598
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to repeale an Act made in the Ninth Yeare of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for rendring the Laws more effectuall for preventing the Importation of Forreigne Bone Lace Loom-Lace Needle-Worke Point and Cut-Worke Three Months after the Prohibition of the Woollen Manufactures in Flanders shall be taken off.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>18</td>
				<td>600
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to punish Governors of Plantations in this Kingdom for Crimes by them committed in the Plantations.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>16</td>
				<td>600
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continueing severall Laws therein mentioned, and for explaining the Act intituled An Act to prevent the Exportation of Wooll out of the Kingdoms of Ireland and England into Forreigne Parts and for the Incouragement of the Woollen Manufactures in the Kingdom of England.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>21</td>
				<td>600
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for raiseing the Militia for the Yeare One thousand seaven hundred although the Months Pay formerly advanced be not repaid.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>24</td>
				<td>603
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the ascertaining the Measures for retailing Ale and Beer.</td>
				<td>XV.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>604
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better ascertaining the Tythes of Hemp and Flax.</td>
				<td>XVI.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>19</td>
				<td>606
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent Disputes that may arise by Officers and Members of Corporations haveing neglected to signe the Association and takeing the Oaths in due Time.</td>
				<td>XVII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>606
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the more effectuall Punishment of Vagrants and sending them whither by Law they ought to be sent.</td>
				<td>XVIII.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>607
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Justices of Peace to build and repair Goales in their respective Counties.</td>
				<td>XIX.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>20</td>
				<td>609
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for takeing away the Duties upon the Woollen Manufactures, Corn Grain Bread Biscuit and Meal exported.</td>
				<td>XX.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>23</td>
				<td>610
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Explanation and better Execution of former Acts made touching Watermen and Wherrymen rowing on the River of Thames and for the better ordering and governing the said Watermen Wherrymen and Lightermen upon the said River between Gravesend and Windsor.</td>
				<td>XXI.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>22</td>
				<td>611</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for makeing the River Larke alias Burn Navigable.</td>
				<td>XXII.</td>
				<td>p.4.1.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>615
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better preserving the Navigation of the Rivers Avon and Froome and for cleansing paving and inlighting the Streets of the City of Bristoll.</td>
				<td>XXIII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>621
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the Mayor and Citizens of the City of Chester to recover and preserve the Navigation upon the River Dee.</td>
				<td>XXIV.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>626</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<th cols="7">TITLES OF THE PRIVATE ACTS.</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Thomas Noble Gentleman to sell the undivided Third Part of the Mannor of Foxton in the County of Leicester when he shall have settled Lands (an entire Estate) of a greater Value to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>632
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to dissolve the Duke of Norfolks Marriage with the Lady Mary Mordant and to enable him to marry again.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>26</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better enabling Ann Baldwin Widow to sell a Capitall Messuage and Lands called Wiltons and other Lands in the County of Bucks devised by her Husbands Will.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>27</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continueing the Governour and Company of Merchants of London trading to the East Indies a Corporation.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>28</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for rectifying a Mistake in the Marriage Settlement of Thomas Hopwood Gentleman on Elizabeth his Wife in order to raise Portions for younger Children and to pay Debts.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>29</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the more speedy Payment of the Debts of John Clobery Esquire deceased and for the raiseing Portions and Maintenance for his Children.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>30</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Thomas May Gentleman to sell Lands in the County of Suffolke which were settled upon his Marriage and to convey other Lands in the same County of a greater Value to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>31</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Reall Estate of Joseph Gardiner and Sarah his Wife late the Estate of William Ridges Esquire deceased in Trustees to be sold for Payment of the Debts and Legacies therein mentioned and for applying the Residue of the Money upon the Trusts therein specified.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>32</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Sale of severall Westerne Mannors and Lands the Estate of Arthur Lacy Esquire for discharging a Mortgage thereupon and for laying out the Surplus Money in the Purchase of Demesne Lands to be settled to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>33</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Mannor of Exton and other Lands in the County of Somersett late the Estate of Thomas Siderfin Esquire deceased in Trustees to be sold for Payment of Debts.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>34</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the speedy and effectuall makeing a convenient Way out of Chancery Lane to Lincolns-Inn Feilds and Places adjacent.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>35</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for settling of the Lands Tenements and Hereditaments late of Robert Merefield and John Merefield Esquires deceased and for ascertaining the Proportions betweene the Widow of the said Robert and his surviving Children.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>36</td>
				<td>633</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the settling all Differences concerning Dame Mary Bonds Will and for performing the same.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>37</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for chargeing the Estate of Sir Thomas Robinson Baronett with Seaven thousand Pounds for the Portion of Ann his Sister and for settling her Estate upon the said Sir Thomas Robinson in lieu thereof.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>38</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for confirmeing a Lease and certain Indentures between the City of Norwich and Richard Barry Esquire George Sorocold Gentleman and Richard Soame Merchant and for enlightening the Streets of the said City.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>39</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for settling the Estate of Catherine Fitzgerald Villiers and raising of Money for Payment of Debts and better secureing the Portions of her Five younger Children by Edward Fitzgerald Villiers Esquire her late Husband.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>40</td>
				<td>633
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Edward Mansell Esquire to mortgage or sell the Impropriate Rectories of Llanriddian and Penrice for Payment of Debts and raiseing Portions for younger Children and for settling the Mannor of Henleys and other Lands of more Value.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>41</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the selling the Reversion and Inheritance of the Farme of Nethercott in the County of Oxon for Payment of the Debts and Legacies of George Harrison Esquire deceased.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>42</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting certaine Lands and Tenements of Sir Josiah Child Baronett deceased in Trustees for the better Performance of certaine Covenants entred into by the said Sir Josiah Child upon the Marriage of his eldest Son with the Daughter of Sir Thomas Cooke Knight.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>43</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to supply the Losse of certain Indentures of Lease and Release here-tofore made by Philip Holman Esquire deceased to George Holman his Son now alsoe deceased.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>44</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Henry Butler Esquire to make Leases of Part of his Estate in Lancashire for Discharge of Incumbrances thereupon.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>45</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting Part of the Estate of Thomas Cowper of the City of Chester Esquire in Trustees for Payment of Debts.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>46</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for confirmeing the Sale of the Mannor of Stansall and certaine Tenements in the County of Yorke made by Thomas Barlow Gentleman and for settling other Lands of greater Value to the same Uses and for vesting other Lands and Hereditaments in Trustees to be sold for purchasing other Lands to be settled to the same Uses.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>47</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for [the<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] selling the Mannor of Fenham in the County of Northum-berland for the Payment of the Debts of Thomas Riddell Esquire and Edward Riddell his Son and raising Portions for the Daughters of the said Thomas Riddell.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>48</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Sale of Part of the Estate of Charles Hore Esquire for Payment of his Debts for settling other Part in Trust for raising a Portion and Maintenance for Elizabeth his only Daughter by his former Wife and for makeing a Joynture for Mary his now Wife and for a Provision for the Children by the said Mary.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>49</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Dalby Thomas Esquire to sell Lands in Islington in Middlesex settled on his Marriage by Dorothy his now Wife as Part of her Joynture he settling another Estate of equall or greater Value in lieu thereof.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>50</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Trustees to make Sale of the Inheritance of the Twelfth Part of severall Mannors Lands and Tenements of Bluet Wallop Esquire during his Minority and to purchase other Lands with the Money to be raised by such Sale to be settled for the same Uses as the said Twelfth Part was settled.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>51</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Leonard Wessell Esquire to sell the Mannor of Acres-Fleet in the County of Essex settled on his Marriage with Sarah his now Wife as Part of her Jointure laying out the Money ariseing by such Sale in Purchase of other Lands.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>52</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for takeing the Estate in Law of severall Messuages and Lands mortgaged to Jeffery and Samuel Howland and their Heires out of Wriothesly Russell commonly called Lord Marquesse of Tavistock and his Lady.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>53</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for confirming a Lease of a Piece of Ground for the Rector and Church-wardens of the Parish of Saint Martins Ogars London for Liberty to build a Church thereon for the Worship and Service of God in the French Tongue according to the Usage of the Church of England.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>54</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Sale of the Estate of Bryan Janson Esquire deceased for Payment of Debts and Provision of his Wife and Children.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>55</td>
				<td>634</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Ship Martha of Margam to trade as a Free Ship</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>56</td>
				<td>634
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Theodore Jacobson and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>57</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Naturalization of Oliver D'Harcourt and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>58</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing John Bourges and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>59</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing John Ricard Jacob Dabbadie and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>60</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Francis Vandertyd, and Agneta Vandermersch Henry Lowman and James Gabriel Le Tresor.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>61</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Isaac Delagard John Batero and others.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>62</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1700&amp;1701.</td>
				<td>An. 12,13.</td>
				<td>An Act for renewing the Bills of Credit commonly called Exchequer Bills.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>p.1.1</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>635
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the further Limitation of the Crown and better securing the Rights and Liberties of the Subject.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>636
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing any Inconveniencies that may happen by Priviledge of Parliament.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>638
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for appointing Wardens and Assay Masters for assaying Wrought Plate in the Cities of York Exeter Bristol Chester and Norwich.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>639
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing a former Act to prevent false and Double Returns of Members to serve in Parliament.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>641
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing the Acts therein mentioned for preventing Theft and Rapine upon the Northern Borders of England.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>641
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better settling and preserving the Library kept in the House at Westminster called Cotton House in the Name and Family of the Cottons for the Benefit of the Publick.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>642
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for raising the Militia for One Year although the Months Pay formerly advanced be not repaid.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>643
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the recovering secureing and keeping in repair the Harbour of Minehead for the Benefitt and Support of the Navigation and Trade of this Kingdom.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>644
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting an Aid to His Majesty for defraying the Expence of His Navy Guards and Garrisons for One Year and for other necessary Occasions. <emph type="i">Stated in the Long Calender to be on the top Press in the Parliament Office</emph>.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>p. 2.</td>
				<td>41</td>
				<td>648
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting to His Majesty several Duties upon Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction and continuing severall additional Duties upon Coffee Tea Chocolate Spices and Pictures and certain, Impositions upon Hawkers Pedlars and Petty Chapmen and the Duty of Fifteen per Cent. upon Muslins and for improving the Duties upon Japanned and Laquered Goods and for continuing the Coinage Duty for the several Terms and Purposes therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>p. 3.1</td>
				<td>42</td>
				<td>716
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for appropriating Three thousand seven hundred Pounds weekly out of certain Branches of Excise for publick Uses and for making a Provision for the Service of His Majesties Household and Family and other His necessary Occasions.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>43</td>
				<td>723
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable His Majesty to make Leases and Copies of Offices Lands and Hereditaments Parcel of His Dutchy of Cornwall or annexed to the same and for Confirmation of Leases already made.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>44</td>
				<td>728</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<th cols="7">TITLES OF THE PRIVATE ACTS.</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the more speedy Payment of the Creditors of James late Duke of Ormond and of the present Duke of Ormond.</td>
				<td>1.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>729
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the Right Honourable Elizabeth Viscountess Bulkeley of Cashells in the Kingdom of Ireland to sell certain Lands in the County of Devon and City and County of the City of Exon for the Payment of Debts.</td>
				<td>ij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Robert Lord Viscount Kilmorey of the Kingdom of Ireland (being an Infant) to settle divers Mannors [Lands<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] and Hereditaments in the Kingdom of England upon a Treaty of Marriage.
1<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>
				</td>
				<td>iij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Sir Charles Barrington Baronet to settle a Joynture and make Provision for his younger Children.</td>
				<td>iiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Sir Robert Marsham Knight and Baronet to dispose of Lands in Hertfordshire and to settle other Lands of better Value in Kent to the same Uses as the Lands in Hertfordshire are settled.</td>
				<td>v.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the Borough of Kings Lynn in the County of Norfolke for the better imploying and maintaining the Poor there.</td>
				<td>vj</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting a Court of Request or Conscience in the City and County of the City of Norwich for the Recovery of small Debts under Forty Shillings.</td>
				<td>vij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>16</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Stephen Jermyn to make Provision for his younger Children and for the Advancement of his eldest Son.</td>
				<td>viij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the vesting and settling divers Mannors and Lands in South Pickenham and other Places in the County of Norfolke in Trustees to be sold and for laying out the Moneys ariseing by Sale thereof in the Purchase of other Lands to be settled to such and the same Uses as the said Mannors and Lands so to be vested are and stand settled.</td>
				<td>ix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>18</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for discharging a Mortgage upon the Estate of Peter Trevisia Esquire deceased and providing a Maintenance for his Widow and Children.</td>
				<td>x.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>19</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the more speedy Payment of the Debts of Christopher Killiow Esquire and for the raising Portions and Maintenance for his Brothers and Sisters in pursuance of his Fathers Will.</td>
				<td>xj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>20</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Estate of Humphrey Hide Esquire deceased in Trustees for raising Portions for his younger Children.</td>
				<td>xij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>21</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for furnishing the Town of New Deal with Fresh Water.</td>
				<td>xiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>22</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting a Messuage and Lands in Stevenage in the County of Hertford the Estate of Richard Nodes in Trustees to be sold for making a Provision for his Wife and Children equal to the Provision secured to them out of the said Estate.</td>
				<td>xiv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>23</td>
				<td>730
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Sale of the Estate of William Davison Esquire deceased for Payment of Debts and raising his Childrens Portions charged thereupon.</td>
				<td>xv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>24</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for separating James Earl of Anglesea from Katharine Countess of Anglesea his Wife for the Cruelty of the said Earl.</td>
				<td>xvj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>25</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for dissolving the Marriage of Sir John Dillon with Mary Boyle and for other Purposes therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>xvij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>26</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to dissolve the Marriage of Ralph Box with Elizabeth Eyre and to enable him to marry again.</td>
				<td>xviij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>27</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the vesting several Messuages Lands and Tenements belonging to John Fawconer Esquire in Trustees to be sold for Payment of Debts.</td>
				<td>xix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>28</td>
				<td>730
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for transferring a Trust in Lands belonging to the City of London unto new Trustees.</td>
				<td>xx.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>29</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for removing the County Goal of Hertford.</td>
				<td>xxi.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>30</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Performance of the last Will of Henry Apsley Esquire deceased.</td>
				<td>xxij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>31</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Estate of Thomas Bennet late of Newton cum Barton in the County of Chester in Trustees for the Use of the Poor of Westkirby pursuant to the Will of the said Thomas Bennet.</td>
				<td>xxiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>32</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable William Vaughan Esq<emph type="p">r</emph> and Frances Vaughan his intended Wife (being both under the Age of One and twenty Years) to perform Articles made for their Marriage.</td>
				<td>xxiv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>33</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to change the Sirname of Ellis Mews and his Heirs to the Sirname Saint John.</td>
				<td>xxv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>34</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for making [good<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] the Deficiency of the Charges of making a Way out of Chancery Lane into Lincolns Inn Fields.</td>
				<td>xxvj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>35</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for declaring the Will of Sir Joseph Herne Knight dated the Twenty fifth Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety eight to be taken and esteemed the last Will of the said Sir Joseph Herne.</td>
				<td>xxvij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>36</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Jane Barkstead Widow and vesting several Mortgages and Securities in her to enable her to convey or assign the same.</td>
				<td>xxviij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>37</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Archibald Arthur and enabling him to dispose of his Estate.</td>
				<td>xxix.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>38</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Jacob Auguste Pyngot and others.</td>
				<td>xxx.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>39</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Adrian Lofland and others.</td>
				<td>xxxj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>40</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Sir Thomas Stanley Bar[one]t to charge certain Mannors and Lands in the County of Lancaster with Three hundred Pounds for Payment of his Sisters Portions and his Debts.</td>
				<td>xxxij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>45</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Sale of the Estate of James Deane and for securing the Moneys raised thereby for the Benefit of himself and Family according to the Settlement thereof.</td>
				<td>xxxiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>46</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Richard Bigg to charge Part of his Estate in the County of Hertford and Bedford with the Payment of his Debts.</td>
				<td>xxxiiij.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>47</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Peter Bagneol Daniel Senault and others.</td>
				<td>xxxv.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>48</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for naturalizing Gasper Cordoso Herman Vant Wedde and others.</td>
				<td>xxxvj.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>49</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1701.</td>
				<td>An.13,14.</td>
				<td>An Act for reviving and continuing an Act intituled an Act for the appointing Commissioners to take examine and determine the Debts due to the Army Navy and for Transport Service and also an Account of Prizes taken during the late War.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>731</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for punishing Officers and Soldiers that shall mutiny or desert in England or Ireland.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>733</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Attainder of the pretended Prince of Wales of High Treason.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>739</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing an Act intituled An Act that the solemn Affirmation and Declaration of the People called Quakers shall be accepted instead of an Oath in the usual Form.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>740</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting an Aid to His Majesty by laying Duties upon Malt Mum Cyder and Perry.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>740</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the further Security of His Majesties Person and the Succession of the Crown in the Protestant Line and for extinguishing the Hopes of the pretended Prince of Wales and all other Pretenders and their open and secret Abettors.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>747</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<th cols="7">TITLES OF THE PRIVATE ACTS.</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to naturalize Charlotte the Wife of Hugh Boscowen Esquire.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>750</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enabling Lionel Earl of Orrery in the Kingdom of Ireland by Sale of certain Lands and Tenements to raise Money for Payment of his Debts and settle other Lands to the Uses and Purposes in this Act mentioned.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td/>
			</tr>
		</table>
		<note id="n1" number="1">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">
			<emph type="i">for one Year O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">
			<emph type="i">O. omits</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">
			<emph type="i">From the Original Act in the Parliament Office</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">
			<emph type="i">the O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n7" number="7">
			<emph type="i">of O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n8" number="8">
			<emph type="i">Heith O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n9" number="9">
			<emph type="i">Militia O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n10" number="10">
			<emph type="i">repaid O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n11" number="11">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XXXV. in the Common Printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n12" number="12">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XXXVI. in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n13" number="13">
			<emph type="i">This is Chapter XXXVII, in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n14" number="14">
			<emph type="i">This is Chapter XXXII. in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n15" number="15">
			<emph type="i">This is Chapter XXXIII. in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n16" number="16">
			<emph type="i">This is Chapter XXXIV. in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n17" number="17">
			<emph type="i">the O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n18" number="18">
			<emph type="i">and O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n19" number="19">
			<emph type="i">the O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n20" number="20">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n21" number="21">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n22" number="22">This Act is not to be found in the Parliament Office, although diligent Search has been made for it. An Entry is made in the long Calendar there, in these Words, 'This Act is not in the Bundle with the Publick Acts of this Year, but on the Top of the Press.</note>
		<note id="n23" number="23">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XXI. in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n24" number="24">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XXII. in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n25" number="25">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XXIII. in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n26" number="26">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XXIV. in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n27" number="27">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XXV. in the common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n28" number="28">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XXVI. in the common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n29" number="29">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n30" number="30">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n31" number="31">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n32" number="32">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n33" number="33">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n34" number="34">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. X. in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n35" number="35">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XI. in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n36" number="36">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XII. in the Common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n37" number="37">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XIII. in the common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n38" number="38">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XIV. in the common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n39" number="39">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XV. in the common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n40" number="40">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XVI. in the common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n41" number="41">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XVII. in the common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n42" number="42">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XVIII. in the common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n43" number="43">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XIX. in the common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n44" number="44">
			<emph type="i">This is Cap. XX. in the common printed Editions</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n45" number="45">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n46" number="46">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>
		</note>
	</section>
</report>

