<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46809" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>An Act. For enlargeing the Times to come [in] and p[u]rchase certain Annuities therein mentioned and for continuing the Duties formerly charged on Low Wines or Spirits of the first extraction for carrying on the Warr against France. [Chapter II. Rot. Parl. 7 &amp; 8 Gul. III. p. 1. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Recital of 6 &amp; 7 W. &amp; M. c.5; And that divers Persons had contributed &pound;235,951. cs. 6d. And that Holders of Annuities on single Lives or other Persons might be desirous to purchase a Term of Years in the said Annuities.; Annuitants for Life may before 24th June 1690, purchase a Term for Years in the said Annuities; to take Effect after the Estate for Life</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in and by an Act lately made and passed in Parliament (to wit) in the Session holden att
Westm in [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Sixth and Seventh Years of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for enableing
such Persons as have Estates for Life in Annuities payable by several former Acts therein mentioned to purchase
and obtain further or more certaine Interest in such Annuities and in Default thereof for admitting other Persons
to purchase and obtain the same for raiseing Moneys for carrying on the Warr against France it was enacted
That it should and might bee lawfull to and for any Person or Persons being intitled to any Estate for One Life
of and in any Annuitie purchased or obtained upon former Acts therein mentioned or any of them att any time
before the Foure and twentieth Day of July which should bee in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
ninety five to advance and pay into the Receipt of His Majesties Exchequer soe much Money as every or any
such Annuity being computed for Four Yeares and an halfe should amount unto And that every such person or
such as hee should nominate upon such payment made should bee intituled to the same Annuity during the terme
of Ninety six Yeares to bee reckoned from the Five and twentieth day of January One thousand six hundred
ninety five in such manner and forme as in the said Act is mentioned. And it was thereby further enacted that if
any person or persons being intituled to any Estate for One Life in any such Annuity or Annuities should not
before the said Foure and twentieth Day of July One thousand six hundred ninety five advance and pay into the
Receipt of Exchequer such Rate or Considerac[i]on Money as is before mentioned That then and in every such case
it should and might bee lawfull to and for any person or persons whatsoever att any time and times after the said Foure
and twentieth day of July and on or before the Twelfth day of November One thousand six hundred ninety five
to contribute advance and pay into the said Receipt of Exchequer soe much Money as any such Annuity being
computed for Five years did or should amount unto And that every such person on such payment made should
have a good Estate and Interest in any such Annuity so to bee purchased dureing the said Terme of Ninety six
yeares subject neverthelesse to the said particular Estate for Life in being And that Tallies should bee levied and
Orders drawne and signed for the same in such manner as by the said Act is prescribed as by the same relation
being thereunto had more plainely and att large it doth and may appeare. And whereas divers persons in prsuance
of the said recited Act did within the said respective times thereby limitted contribute or pay into the said Receipt
of Exchequer severall sunis of Money amounting in the whole to Two hundred thirty five thousand nine hundred
fifty one pounds and Six pence for purchasing further or more certaine Estates in some of the Annuities before
mentioned. And whereas the persons who are or may bee intituled to such of the said Annuities as doe still
depend upon single lives and wherein further Estates are not already purchased by the said former Act are or may
bee willing and desirous or (in case of their or any of their Neglect or Refusal) other persons may yett bee
willing and desirous to purchase and obtain a terme of yeares as aforesaid in the Annuities last mentioned or some
of them att the like Rates or for such Considerations as were prescribed by the said former Act so as further
times bee allowed them for the doeing thereof. Now for the better incouragement of such persons who shall soe
contribute Moneys for the purpose afore?d and for the better supplying of Moneys with as much ease as may bee
for the carrying on the Warr against France Bee it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with
the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled
and by the authority of the same That it shall and may bee lawfull to and for any person or psons Natives or
Foreigners being (as original Contributors or by Mesne Assignements or by other lawfull ways and means) intituled
to any estate for one Life (videlt his owne or the Life of any other person) of or in any Annuity purchased
or obtained upon the several Acts of Parliament mentioned in the Act above recited or any of them or such as
they shall n?ate att the rate of One hundred pounds for every Foureteen pounds per annum att any time
before the Foure and twentieth day of June which shall bee in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
ninety six to advance and pay into the Receipt of His Majesties Excheq[uer] soe much money as every or any such
Annuity being computed for Foure yeares and an halfe doth or shall amount to (that is to say) Every such
person shall or may pay to His Majesties use for every One hundred pounds that was paid for the single Life
in any Annuity of Fourteen pounds per annum the summ of sixty three pounds more for changeing or converting
the same into a certaine terme for the residue which shall bee then to come of the said Ninety six yeares or
for a further Interest for the residue of the said terme of Ninety six yeares to take effect after the estate for
Life as aforesaid and in the same proportion for higher or larger Annuities.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. If such Annuitants do not purchase before 24th June, then any Person having or not having an Interest in such Life Estate may purchase before 29th Sept. 1696.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and such Persons paying the Consideration to be immediately entitled; Directions of 6 &amp; 7 W. &amp; M. c. 5. in force for and in respect of such Annuities.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any person or persons being intituled to any
estate for One Life in being in any such present Annuity or Annuities as aforesaid or such as they shall n?ate
shall not before the said Foure and twentieth day of June advance and pay into the Receipt of Exchequer such
Rate or Consideration Money as is before mentioned for changeing such his her or their Estate for Life into a
terme certaine or for a future interest as aforesaid that then and in every such case it shall and may bee lawfull to
or for any person or persons whatsoever Natives or Forreigners haveing or not haveing any Property or Interest
in such Estate for Life att any time or times after the said Foure and twentieth day of June and on or before
the Nine and twentieth day of September in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety six to
contribute advance and pay into the said Receipt of Exchequer so much Money as any such Annuity being computed
for Five yeares doth or shall amount to (that is to say) For every hundred pounds that was paid for the single.
Life in an annuity of Foureteen pounds a yeare there shall bee paid in all the cases last mentioned the summ of
Seventy pounds for an Interest for the then residue of the said terme of Ninety six yeares to bee reckoned as
aforesaid and to bee charged with and subject to the present estate for life of and in the same or the like annuities
And there shall bee paid a Rate or Consideration in the same proportion for Annuities exceeding Foureteen pounds
a yeare And that all and every the p[er]son and persons soe paying the Considerac[i]on Moneys as aforesaid shall im[m]ediately
upon payment of their Moneys bee intituled by this Act to such Annuity or Annuities soe to bee purchased and
the same shall bee charged upon such respective Fund or Revenue in the said [recited<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Act mentioned as if the
the Consideration Money so to bee contributed or advanced for the same had been actually advanced or contributed
within the respective times limitted by the said former Act and that all and every the Directions Powers and
Clauses in the said recited Act contained for or concerning the levying of Tallies or makeing forth or Orders or
for makeing Transferrences or Assignements or for the appropriating or applying the Moneys ariseing by the said
Funds or Revenues or any of them or for appointing settling or establishing any other Matter or Thing for or in
relation to the respective Annuities thereby purchased or obtained shall bee and are by force and virtue of this
Act revived and shall be duely observed practised and putt in Execution for and in respect of such Annuities as
shall bee purchased or obtained upon this Act as fully and effectually as if the same Powers Directions and Clauses
were here again expressed or particularly repeated.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Stat. 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 9. &sect;1. recited.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">The Duties of the said Act to be levied from 24th Dec. 1695 to 25th March 1696</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And whereas in and by an Act made in the Second Yeare of the Reigne of His Majestie and the late Queene
Mary of blessed Memory intituled An Act for the encourageing the distilling of Brandy and Spirits from Corne and
for laying several Duties on Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction Itt was enacted that from and after the
Foure and twentieth Day of December in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and ninety until the
Five and twentieth Day of December in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety five there should
bee paid by way of Excise unto Their Majesties and their Successors for all Low Wines or Spirits of the First
Extraction drawne by Distillers or other Makers of Spirits and Strong waters for Sale within this Kingdom of
England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed the several Rates and Duties therein mentioned
Bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the several Duties granted by the Act last mentioned shall
bee raised levied collected answered and paid to His Majesties Use for [the<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] carrying on the Warr against the
French King from the foure and twentieth Day of December One thousand six hundred ninety five to the Five and
twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety six and noe longer And that the said last mentioned
Act and all the Powers Provisions and Penalties Articles and Clauses therein contained concerning the said Duties
which were thereby granted shall continue and bee of full Force and Effect until the said Five and twentieth Day
of March and shall bee applied practised and executed for the raiseing levying collecting answering and paying the
said Duties hereby continued according to the Intent and Meaning of this present Act.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

