<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46811" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for preventing Charge and Expence in Elections of Members to serve in P[ar]liament. [Chapter IV. Rot. Parl. 7 &amp; 8 Gul. III. P. 1. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Persons elected to serve in Parliament not to give Money, &amp;c. to Elector</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas grievous Complaints are made and manifestly appeare to bee true in the Kingdome of undue
Elections of Members to Parliament by excessive and exorbitant Expences contrary to the Laws and in
Violation of the Freedom due to the Election of Representatives for the Commons of England in Parliament to the
great Scandal of the Kingdome dishonorable and may bee destructive to the [Constitutions<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of Parliaments wherefore
for Remedy therein and that all Elections of Members to Parliament may bee hereafter freely and indifferently
made without Charge or Expence Bee it enacted and declared by our Sovereigne Lord the Kings most Excellent
Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present
Parliam[en]t assembled and by the Authority of the same That noe Person or Persons hereafter to bee elected to serve
in Parliament for any County City Towne Borough Port or Place within the Kingdome of England Dominion of
Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed after the Teste of the Writt of Summons to Parliament or after the Teste
or the issuing out or ordering of the Writt or Writts of Election upon the calling or summoning of any
Parliament hereafter or after any such Place becomes vacant hereafter in the time of this present or of any other
Parliament shall or doe hereafter by himselfe or themselves or by any other Ways or Means on his or their behalfe
or att his or their Charge before his or their Election to serve in Parliament for any County City Towne Borough
Port or Place within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed directly or
indirectly give present or allow to any Person or Persons having Voice or Vote in such Election any Money Meat
Drink Entertainment or Provision or make any Present Gift Reward or Entertainment or shall at any time hereafter
make any Promise Agreement Obligac[i]on or Engagement to give or allow any Money Meat Drink Provision
Present Reward or Entertainment to or for any such Person or Persons in particular or to any such County City
Towne Borough Port or Place in general or to or for the Use Advantage Benefitt, Employment Profitt or
Preferment of any such Person or Persons Place or Places in order to bee elected or for being elected to serve
in Parliament for such County City Borough Towne Port or Place.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Offenders disabled from serving upon such Election in Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p3">And it is hereby further enacted and declared That every Person and Persons soe giving presenting or allowing
makeing promising or engageing doeing acting or proceeding shall bee and are hereby declared &amp; enacted disabled
and incapacitated upon such Election to serve in Parliament for such County City Towne Borough Port or Place
And that such Person or Persons shall bee deemed and taken and are hereby declared and enacted to bee deemed
and taken noe Members in Parliament and shall not act sitt or have any Vote or Place in Parliament but shall
bee and are hereby declared and enacted to bee to all Intents Constructions &amp; Purposes as if they had been
never returned or elected Members for the Parliament.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Constitution <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

