<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46815" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for the taking examining and stating the Publick Accounts.[Rot.Parl. 7&amp;7 Gul. III.p.4.nu.6]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Commissioners named for taking the Accounts of</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c.11; 4 W.&amp;M. c.11; 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c.23; 6 &amp; 7 W. III. c.9; The said Acts revived and continued; Treasury empowered to issue and pay Allowances to Clerks, &amp;c. as by 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c.11; Commissioners empowered to take Account of Monies granted as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the better Knowledge Examination and Stating the Accounts of the Receipts Issues and Distribution of
the Publick Revenue of the Crowne of England and the Dominions and Territories thereunto belonging and
the due Incouragement of the People of this Realme to pay the Taxes and Payments by Act of Parliament imposed
on them for the Maintenance and Prosecution of the present Warr against France and the Support of His Majesties
Government Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the
Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same
That Robert Harley Esq[uire] Paul Foley Esq[uire] Henry Boyle Esq[uire] John Granville Esq[uire] William Bromley of Warwickshire
Esq[uire] Sir Thomas Dyke Baronett and Francis Gwynne Esq[uire] shall be and are hereby constituted Co[m]missioners for
examining taking and stating of the Accounts of all Money of the said Publick Revenue of the Crowne and all
other Accounts which were by one Act of Parliament made in the Second Yeare of the Reigne of King William
and Queene Mary intituled An Act for appointing and enabling Co[m]missioners to examine take and state the Publick
Accounts of the Kingdome And one other Act made in the Fourth and Fifth Yeares of the Reigne of King
William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for examining taking and stating the Publick Accounts of this Kingdome
And one other Act made in the Fifth and Sixth Yeares of Their said Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for
[appointing &amp;<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] enabling Co[m]missioners to examine take and state the Publick Accounts of the Kingdome And
one other Act made in the Sixth and Seventh Yeares of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for appointing and
enabling Co[m]missioners to examine take and state the Publick Accounts to be taken examined and stated by the respective
Co[m]missioners by the said Acts or any of them constituted or any Five Foure or more of them respectively authorized
by virtue of the same or any of them And that the said Acts and every Clause Matter and Thing therein contained
not hereby altered shall be and are hereby revived and continued in full force and virtue to all Intents Constructions
and Purposes whatsoever from the Foure and twentieth Day of April in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred ninety six to the Five and twentieth Day of April which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred ninety seven And shall be executed with all the Powers and Authorities in them and every
of them respectively contained by the Co[m]missioners herein named or any Foure or more of them And that the
Lords Co[m]missioners of the Treasury or Lord High Treasurer of England for the time being shall and are hereby
authorized and required to issue and pay or cause to be issued and paid the like yearely Allowances for Payment
of Clerks and other Charges as are in the First recited Act directed and the like Quarterly Payments to
every of the said Co[m]missioners hereby constituted as are appointed to be paid to the Co[m]missioners therein named
And the said Co[m]missioners by this Act constituted as aforesaid or any Foure or more of them shall and are
hereby impowered to take Accounts of all Moneys that have been or shall be granted to His Majesty and of all
other His Majesties Treasure or other Publick Money due or payable to His Majesty on the Fifth Day of November
One thousand six hundred eighty eight or att any time betweene the said Fifth Day of November and the said
Five and twentieth Day of April which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety
seven not yett accounted for by virtue or in pursuance of the said recited Acts or either of them or the last
Clause touching Publick Accounts made and enacted in one Act made in the Third Yeare of Their said
Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for raising Money by a Poll payable Quarterly for One Yeare for the carrying
on a vigorous Warr against France.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Two of the first-named Commissioners to be sworn.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That Two of the said Co[m]missioners first named in this
Act before they enter upon the Execution of the same shall take an Oath before the Chancellor of the Exchequer
or Master of the Rolls for the time being which they and either of them are hereby respectively authorized and
required to administer to them the Tenor whereof shall be as followeth that is to say.</para>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Oath</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">I. A. B. doe sweare That according to the best of my Skill and Knowledge I shall faithfully impartially and truly
demeane my selfe in examining &amp; taking the Accounts of all such Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money and other Things
brought or to be brought before me in Execution of one Act intituled An Act for the taking examining and stating
the Publick Accounts according to the Tenor and Purport of the said Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The other Commissioners to take the same Oath before the said Two.</head>
			<para id="p6">And every other of the said Co[m]missioners hereby constituted before hee enters upon the Execution of the said
Act shall likewise take the same Oath before the said Co[m]missioners herein first named who are hereby authorized
and required to administer the same unto them after they shall themselves have taken the said Oath as aforesaid.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


