<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46824" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVII. An Act to continue Foure former Acts for preventing Theft and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders of England.[Rot. Parl. 7&amp;8 Gul.III.p.5.n.3]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Stat. 13 &amp; 14 C. II. c. 22.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">18C. II. c.3; as confirmed by 29 &amp; 30 C.II. C. 2; 1 Jac. II. c. 14; The aforesaid Acts continued for Five Years, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an Act was made in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth Yeares of the Reigne of our late Soveraigne
Lord King Charles the Second entituled An Act for preventing of Thest and Rapine upon the Northerne
Borders of England And whereas also another Act was made in the Eighteenth Yeare of the said King entituled
An Act to continue a former Act to prevent Theft and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders of England both which
Acts were continued by another Act made in the Twenty nineth and Thirtieth Yeares of the Reigne of the said
late King entituled An Act for continuance of Two former Acts for preventing of Thefit and Rapine upon the
Northerne Borders of England for and dureing the space and time of Seaven Yeares and alsoe from thence untill
the End of the First Session of the then next Parliament And whereas the Three afore mentioned Acts were continued
by another Act made in the first Yeare of the Reigne of the late King James the Second entituled An Act for
Continuance of Three former Acts for preventing of Theft and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders of England
for and dureing the Space and Terme of Eleven Yeares and also from thence untill the End of the First Session of
this present Parliament Which Lawes have beene found very necessary for the preservation of those Places from
that great Number of lewd disorderly and lawlesse Persons that usually infested and frequented in those Parts Bee
itt therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That the
said Foure former Acts and all and every of them and every Matter Clause and Clauses therein contained and all
and every the Powers and Authorities thereby given shall be continue and remaine in full force from henceforth for
and dureing the Space and Terme of Five Yeares and also from thence unto the End of the First Session of the
next Parliamen.</para>
	</section>
</report>


