<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46822" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XV. An Act for the continueing meeting and sitting of a Parliament in case of the Death or Demise of His Majesty His Heirs and Successors [Rot. Parl. 7&amp;8 Gul. III. p.s. n.1]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Parliament not dissolved by the Demise of His Majesty or his Successors, but may sit 6 Months after, unless sooner prorogued or dissolved.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 2</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas this Kingdome of England may be exposed to great Dangers by the Invasion of Foreigners or [by
the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] traiterous Conspiracies of wicked and ill disposed Persons whenever itt shall please God to afflict these
Realmes by the Death of our Gracious Sovereigne King William (whome God long preserve) or by the Death of any
of His Heires and Successors before a Parliam[en]t can bee summoned and called by the next Heire and Successor to
the Crowne For Prevention whereof bee itt enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice
and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the
Authority of the same That this present Parliament or any other Parliament which shall hereafter bee summoned
and called by His Majesty King William His Heirs and Successors shall not determine or bee dissolved by the Death or
Demise of His said Majesty His Heirs and Successors but such Parliament shall and is hereby enacted to continue
and is hereby impowered and required immediately to meete convene and sitt and to act notwithstanding such Death or
Demise for and dureing the time of Six Moneths and noe longer unlesse the same shall bee sooner prorogued or dissolved
by such Person who shall be next Heire to the Crowne of this Realme of England in Succession according to an Act
of Parliament made in the first Yeare of the Reigne of King William and Queene Mary intituled An Act declareing
the Rights and Liberties of the Subject and settling the Succession of the Crowne [And if the said Parliament shall
bee soe prorogued then itt shall meete and sitt on and upon the Day unto which itt shall be prorogued and
continue for the Residue of the said time of Six Months unlesse sooner prorogued or dissolved as aforesaid.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>.]</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. If no Parliament sitting at the King's Demise, then last preceding Parliament to sit.</head>
			<para id="p3">And itt is hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in case there shall be noe Parliament in
being att the time of the Death or Demise of His Majesty or any of His Heirs and Successors then the last
preceding Parliament shall immediately convene and sitt and is hereby impowered and required to act as aforesaid to
all Intents and Purposes as if the said Parliam[en]t had never beene dissolved.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Power of the King to prorogue or dissolve Parliament, and also for Stat. 6 &amp; 7 W. &amp; M. c. 2.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided always and itt is hereby declared That nothing in this Act contained shall extend or bee construed to
extend to alter or abridge the Power of the King His Heires and Successors to prorogue or dissolve Parliaments
nor to repeale or make voyd one Act of Parliament made in the Sixth and Seventh Yeares of the Reigne of His
present Majesty King William intituled An Act for the frequent Meeting and calling of Parliaments but that the said
Act shall continue in force in every thing that is not contrary to or inconsistent with the Direction of this Act</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


