<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46829" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXII. An Act for preventing Frauds and regulating Abuses in the Plantation Trade [Rot. Parl. 7 &amp; 8 Gul. III. pt.5.nu.8].</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that notwithstanding</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">12 Car. II. c. 18; 15 Car. II. c. 7; 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 26; 25 Car. II. c. 7; great Abuses are committed; No Plantation Goods to be exported or imported or carried from one Plantation to another, but in Ships built and owned in England, Ireland, or Plantations, and navigated as herein mentioned; Proviso for Prize Ships, and for certain Foreign-built Ships, on Forfeiture of Ship and Goods</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas notwithstanding divers Acts made for the Encouragement of the Navigation of this Kingdome and
for the better secureing and regulating the Plantation Trade more especially one Act of Parliament made
in the Twelfth yeare of the Reigne of the late King Charles the Second intituled An Act for increasing of Shipping
and Navigation another Act made in the Fifteenth yeare of the Reigne of His said late Majesty intituled An Act
for the Incouragement of Trade another Act made in the Two and twentieth and Three and twentieth yeares of His
said late Majesties Reigne intituled An Act to prevent the planting of Tobacco in England and for regulating the
Plantation Trade another Act made in Twenty-fifth yeare of the Reigne of His said late Majesty intituled An Act for
the Incouragement of the Greenland and Eastland Trades and for the better secureing the Plantation Trades great
Abuses are daily committed to the prejudice of the English Navigation and the losse of a great part of the Plantation
Trade to this Kingdome by the Artifice and Cunning of ill disposed Persons. For Remedy thereof for the future
bee itt enacted and itt is hereby enacted and ordained by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the
Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in Parliament assembled and by the
Authority of the same That after the Five and twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety eight
noe Goods or Merchandizes whatsoever shall bee imported into or exported out of any Colony or Plantation to
His Majesty in Asia Africa or America belonging or in his Possession or which may hereafter belong unto or bee
in the Possession of His Majesty His Heires or Successors or shall bee laden in or carried from any One Port or
Place in the said Colonies or Plantations to any other Port or Place in the same, the Kingdome of England
Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed in any Shipp or Bottome but what is or shall bee of the
Built of England or of the Built of Ireland or the said Colonies or Plantations and wholly owned by the People
thereof or any of them and navigated with the Masters and Three Fourths of the Mariners of the said Places onely
(except such Shipps onely as are or shall bee taken Prize and Condemnation thereof made in one of the Courts
of Admiralty in England Ireland or the said Colonies or Plantations [to bee navigated by the Master and Three
Fourths of the Mariners English or of the said Plantations as aforesaid and whereof the Property doth belong to
English Men<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] And alsoe except for the space of Three Yeares such Foreigne built Shipps as shall bee employed by
the Commissioners of His Majesties Navy for the tyme being or upon Contract with them in bringing onely Masts
Timber and other Navall Stores for the Kings Service from His Majesties Colonies or Plantations to this Kingdome
to bee navigated as aforesaid and whereof the Property doth belong to English Men) under paine of Forfeiture of
Shipp and Goods one third part whereof to bee to the use of His Majesty His Heires and Successors one third
part to the Governor of the said Colonies or Plantations and the other third part to the Person who shall informe
and sue for the same by Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster or in
any Court in His Majesties Plantations where such Offence shall bee committed.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Exportation and Importation in certain Prize Ships; and for Masts, &amp;c in certain Foreign-built Ships.</head>
			<para id="p3">[And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That (from and after the said Five and twentieth Day of March)
Goods or Merchandizes may bee exported or imported to and from this Kingdome the Colonies Plantations and Places
aforesaid in any such Shipps as are or shall bee taken as Prize and whereof Condemnation shall bee made in one
of the Courts of Admiralty aforesaid and shall bee navigated as aforesaid by the Master Three fourths of the Mariners
English and whereof the property shall belong to English Men and alsoe Masts Tymber and other Navall Stores for His
Majesties Service for the space of Three Yeares may bee imported from His Majesties Colonies or Plantations to this
Kingdome in such Foreigne built Shipps as shall bee imployed by the Commissioners of the Navy for the tyme being or
by Contract with them Any Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Recital of 12 Car. II. c. 18. &sect; 2.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Governors, &amp;c. of Plantations to take Oaths to observe Acts for securing Plantation Trade; before whom such Oath to be taken; neglecting to take such Oath or neglect in their Duty; Removal and Penalty &pound;1,000</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And whereas by One Clause in the said Act passed in the Twelfth Yeare of the Reigne of the late King Charles the
Second intituled An Act for the encourageing and increaseing of Shipping and Navigation all Governours of His Majesties
Colonies or Plantations in Asia Africa or America are required to take a solemne Oath to doe theire utmost that every the
Clauses therein before mencoined and all the Matters and Things therein contained shall bee punctually and bona fide
observed according to the true intent and meaneing thereof soe that the said Governours are not strictly obliged by that
Oath to putt in Execution the subsequent Clauses of the said Act although some of the Clauses following are of great
Importance and tend greatly to the Security of the Plantation Trade And whereas divers other good Lawes have beene
made for the better regulating and secureing the Plantation Trade since the said last mentioned Act bee itt further
enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all the present Governors or Commanders in Chiefe of any English Colonies or
Plantations shall before the Five and twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety seaven and all who
hereafter shall bee made Governours or Commanders in Chiefe of the said Colonies or Plantations or any of them before
their Entrance into their Government shall take a solemne Oath to doe theire utmost that all the Clauses Matters and
Things contained in the before recited Acts of Parliament heretofore passed and now in force relateing to the said
Colonies and Plantations and that all and every the Clauses contained in this present Act bee punctually and bona
fide observed according to the true intent and meaneing thereof (which Oath shall bee taken before such Person or
Persons as shall bee appointed by His Majesty His Heires and Successors who are hereby authorized to administer
the same) soe farr as appertaines unto the said Governours or Co[m]manders in Chiefe respectively And upon Complaint
and Proofe made before His Majesty His Heires and Successors or such as shall bee by him or them thereunto
authorized and appointed by the Oath of Two or more credible Witnesses That any the said Governours or Commanders
in Chiefe have neglected to take the said Oath att the Tymes aforesaid or have beene wittingly or willingly negligent
in doeing theire Duety accordingly the said Governour soe neglecting or offending shall bee removed from his
Government and forfeite the Summe of One thousand Pounds Sterling.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Recital of 15 Car. II. c. 7.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Officers appointed by Governors to give Security to Commissioners of Customs in England for Performance of Duty; Disability; Governor liable until Security given and Appointment approved by Commissioners of Customs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And whereas by the said Act of the Fifteenth of King Charles the Second intituled An Act for the encouragement
of Trade the Governours of the Plantations are impowered to appoint an Officer for the Performance of certaine
things in the said Act mentioned which said Officer is there commonly knowne by the Name of the Navall Officer
And whereas through the Connivance or Negligence of the Persons soe appointed by the Governours of the said
Plantations divers Frauds and Abuses are or have beene committed Bee itt therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid
That all and every the [s[ai]d<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Officers already appointed shall within Two Moneths after notice of this Act in the
respective Plantations or as soone as conveniently [it may be<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] give Security to the Commissioners of the Customes in
England for the Tyme being or such as shall bee appointed by them for His Majesties Use for the true and
faithfull Performance of their Duty And all and every Person or Persons who shall hereafter bee appointed to the said
Office or Employment shall within Two Moneths or as soone as conveniently itt may bee after his or their Entrance
upon the said Office or Employm[en]t. give sufficient Security to the Commissioners of the Customes as aforesaid for His
Majesties Use for the true and faithfull Performance of his or theire Duty And in Default thereof the Person or
Persons neglecting or refuseing to give such Security shall be disabled to execute the said Office or Employment
And until such Security given and the Person appointed to the said Office or Employment bee approved by the
Commissioners of the Customes as aforesaid the respective Governour or Governours shall bee answerable for any
the Offences Neglects or Misdemeanours of the [Person or<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Persons soe by him or them appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Ships coming into and going out of Plantations, &amp;c. subject to like Regulations as Ships in this Kingdom under 14 (13 &amp; 14) Car. II. c. 11.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Power of Officers of Plantation Trade to visit and search Ships, take Entries, make Seizures, &amp;c. as Powers of Officers of Customs in England under 14 (13 &amp; 14) Car. II. c. 11; Wharfingers, &amp;c. assisting in the rescue of Goods or in resisting Officers; Penalty; Assistance to be given to Officers; Officers subject to Penalties as Officers of Customs in England under 14 (13 &amp; 14) Car. II. c. 11; In Actions against Officers, General Issue may be pleaded</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And for the more effectuall preventing of Frauds and regulating Abuses in the Plantation Trade in America
Bee itt further enacted by the Authority [aforesaid<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] That all Shipps comeing into or goeing out of any of the
said Plantations and ladeing or unladeing any Goods or Commodities whether the same bee His Majesties Shipps
of Warr or Merchants Shipps and the Masters and Commanders thereof and their Ladings shall bee subject and
lyable to the same Rules Visitations Searches Penalties and Forfeitures as to the entring lading or dischargeing
theire respective Shipps and Ladings as Shipps and their Ladings and the Commanders and Masters of Shipps are
subject and lyable unto in this Kingdome by vertue of an Act of Parliament made in the Fourteenth Yeare of the
Reigne of King Charles the Second intituled An Act for preventing Frauds and regulating Abuses in His Majesties
Customes And that the Officers for collecting and manageing His Majesties Revenue and inspecting the Plantation
Trade in any of the said Plantations shall have the same Powers and Authorities for visiting and searching of
Shipps and takeing their Entries and for seizing and secureing or bringing on Shoare any of the Goods prohibited
to bee imported or exported into or out of any the said Plantac[i]ons or for which any Duties are payable or
ought to have beene paid by any of the before menc[i]oned Acts as are provided for the Officers of the Customes
in England by the said last mentioned Act made in the Fourteenth Yeare of the Reigne of King Charles the
Second and alsoe to enter Houses or Warehouses to search for and seize any such Goods And that all the
Wharfingers and Owners of Keys and Wharfes or any Lightermen Bargemen Watermen Porters or other Persons
assisting in the Conveyance Concealement or Rescue of any of the said Goods or in the hindering or resistance
of any of the said Officers in the performance of their Duty and the Boates Barges Lighters or other Vessells
imployed in the Conveyance of such Goods shall bee subject to the like Paines and Penalties as are provided by
the same Act made in the Fourteenth Yeare of the Reigne of King Charles the Second in relation to prohibited
or uncustomed Goods in this Kingdome And that the like Assistance shall bee given to the said Officers in the
Execution of their Office as by the said last mentioned Act is provided for the Officers in England And alsoe
that the said Officers shall bee subject to the same Penalties and Forfeitures for any Corruptions Frauds Connivances
or Concealements in violation of any the before mentioned Lawes as any Officers of the Customes in England
are lyable to by vertue of the said last mentioned Act And also that in case any Officer or Officers in the Plantations
shall bee sued or molested for any thing done in the Execution of their Office the said Officer shall and may
plead the Generall Issue and shall give this or other Custome Acts in Evidence and the Judge to allow thereof,
have and enjoy the like Priviledges and Advantages as are allowed by Law to the Officers of His Majesties
Customes in England.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. How Penalties not particularly mentioned, disposed of; How recovered.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Onus probandi on Owner; Claimer reputed to be the Owner</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And itt is hereby further enacted That all the Penalties and Forfeitures before mentioned not in this Act
particularly disposed of shall bee One third Part to the Use of His Majesty His Heires and Successors and One
third Part to the Governour of the Colony or Plantation where the Offence shall bee committed and the other
Third Part to such Person or Persons as shall sue for the same To bee recovered in any of His Majesties Courts
att Westminster or [in the Kingdome of Ireland or in the Court of Admiralty held in His Majesties Plantations
respectively where such Offence shall bee committed att the Pleasure of the Officer or Informer or in any other
Plantation belonging to any Subject of England<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] wherein noe Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law shall bee
allowed And that where any Question shall arise concerning the Importation or Exportation of any Goods into
or out of the said Plantations in such Case the Proofe shall lye upon the Owner or Claymer, and the Claymer shall
bee reputed the Importer or Owner thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Recital that in some of the American Plantations Doubts had arisen as to the Construction of 25 Car. II.c.7. &sect;2.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">notwithstanding Payment of the Duties therein mentioned, no Goods to be laden till Security given as required by 12 Car. II. c. 18. &sect; 19; 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 26. &sect; 6</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And whereas in some of His Majesties American Plantations a Doubt or Misconstruction has arisen upon the
before mentioned Act made in the Five and twentieth Yeare of the Reigne of King Charles the Second whereby
certaine Duties are laid upon the Commodities therein enumerated (which by Law may bee transported from one
Plantation to another for the Supply of each others Wants) as if the same were by the Payment of those Duties
in one Plantation discharged from giveing the Securities intended by the aforesaid Acts made in the Twelfth Two
and twentieth and Three and twentieth Yeares of the Reigne of King Charles the Second and consequently bee
att liberty to goe to any Foreigne Markett in Europe without comeing to England Wales or Berwick Itt is hereby
further enacted and declared That notwithstanding the Payment of the aforesaid Duties in any of the said Plantations
none of the said Goods shall bee shipt or laden on Board untill such Security shall bee given as is required by
the said Acts made in the Twelfth Two and twentieth and Three and twentieth Yeares of the Reigne of King
Charles the Second to carry the same to England Wales or Berwick or to some other of His Majesties Plantations
and soe toties quoties as any of the said Goods shall bee brought to bee reshipt or laden in any of the said
Plantations under the Penalty and Forfeiture of Shipp and Goods to bee divided and disposed of as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Laws, &amp;c. in force in the Plantations repugnant to the aforesaid Laws or to this Act, or to future Laws, declared void.</head>
			<para id="p14">And itt is further enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid That all Lawes By-lawes Usages or Customes
att this tyme or which hereafter shall bee in practice or endeavoured or pretended to bee in force or practice in
any of the said Plantations which are in any wise repugnant to the before mentioned Lawes or any of them soe far
as they doe relate to the said Plantations or any of them or which are wayes repugnant to this present Act or
to any other Law hereafter to bee made in this Kingdome soe farr as such Law shall relate to and mention the
said Plantations are illegall null and void to all Intents and Purposes whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Recital that Frauds have been committed in the Plantation Trade by false Certificates of Security, and of having discharged Lading, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Where Governor of Plantation has reasonable Suspicion of false Certificates, &amp;c; Proceedings; Counterfeiting Certificate, Cocket, &amp;c. or using the same; Penalty &pound;500, and Certificate, &amp;c. invalid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And whereas great Frauds and Abuses have beene committed by Scotch men and others in the Plantation Trade
by obtruding false and counterfeite Certificates upon the Governour and Officers in the Plantations appointed by
His Majesties Commissioners of the Customes in England of haveing given Security in this Kingdome to bring the
Ladings of Plantation Goods to England Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed as alsoe Certificates of haveing
discharged theire lading of Plantation Goods in this Kingdome pursuant to Securities taken in the Plantation and
also Cocketts or Certificates of haveing taken in their Ladings of European Goods in England Wales or Berwick
by meanes whereof they may carry the Goods of Scotland and other Places of Europe without shipping or lading
the same in England Wales or Berwick to His Majesties Plantations and also carry the Goods of the Plantations
directly to Scotland or to any Markett in Europe without bringing the same into England Wales or Towne of
Berwick upon Tweed Itt is hereby further enacted That in such Cases where the Governour or Officers appointed
by the Commissioners of the Customes in the Plantations shall have reasonable ground of Suspition that such Certificates
are false or couterfeit (that is to say) that the Certificate of having given Security in England is false In such
Case the Governour or Officers appointed by the Commissioners of the Customes shall require and take sufficient
Security there for the Discharge of the Plantation lading in England Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed
And in such Case where there shall bee Cause to suspect that the Certificates of haveing discharged her Lading of
Plantation Goods in this Kingdome is false or counterfeit the Governour or Officers aforesaid shall not cancell or
vacate the Security given in the Plantation untill hee or they shall bee informed from the Commissioners of the
Customes in England that the Matter of the said Certificate is true And if any Person or Persons shall counterfeite
rase or falsify any Cockett Certificate Returne or Permit for any Vessell or Goods or shall knowingly or willingly
make use thereof such Person or Persons shall forfeite the Summe of Five hundred Pounds to bee recovered and
disposed of as aforesaid and the Cockett Certificate Returne or Permit soe counterfeited rased or falsified shall be
invalid and of noe effect.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. The Treasury and Commissioners of the Customs may appoint Officers in Ports, &amp;c. of Islands, &amp;c; In all Actions Jury to be Natives of England or Ireland, or born in the Plantations.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Where Offences to be laid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">[And for the better executing the severall Acts of Parliament relating to the Plantation Trade bee itt enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That the Lord Treasurer Commissioners of the Treasury and the Commissioners of the Customes
in England for the tyme being shall and may constitute and appoint such and soe many Officers of the Customes in any
City Towne River Port Harbour or Creeke of or belonging to any of the Islands Tracts of Land and Proprieties when
and as often as to them shall seeme needfull<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Bee itt further also enacted That upon any Actions Suites and Informations
that shall bee brought commenced or entred in the said Plantations upon any Law or Statute concerning His Majesties
Duties or Shipps or Goods to bee forfeited by reason of any unlawfull Importations or Exportations there shall not
bee any Jury but of such onely as are Natives of England or Ireland or are borne in His Majesties said Plantations
And also that upon all such Actions Suits and Informations the Offences may bee laid or alleadged to bee in any
Colony Province County Precinct or Division of any of the said Plantac[i]ons where such Offences are alleadged to
bee committed att the pleasure of the Officer or Informer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Places of Trust in Courts of Law or Treasury to be held by Natives of England, Ireland, or Plantations.</head>
			<para id="p19">[Provided alwayes, That all Places of Trust in the Courts of Law or what relates to the Treasury of the said Islands
shall from the makeing of this Act bee in the Hands of the Native borne Subjects of England or Ireland or of the
said Islands.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>.]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Recital of 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 26. &sect; 6.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">What Description of Persons only are to be named as Sureties in the said Bonds; Condition of such Bonds</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And whereas by the said Act made in the Two and twentieth and Three and Twentieth Yeares of the Reigne of His
said late Majesty King Charles the Second the Bonds required to bee given in the Plantations by virtue of the said Act for
incouraging and increasing of Shipping and Navigation are altered and the word Ireland to bee left out of the Condition of
all such Bonds And by the said Act itt is enacted and provided That for such Shipps or Vessells comeing from other
Ports or Places to any of the said Plantations which by the said Act for encourageing and increase of Shipping were
permitted to trade there the Governors of such English Plantations should before the said Shipp or Vessell should bee
permitted to load on Board any of the Commodities in the said Act particularly mentioned, take Bond in Manner and to
the Value mentioned and directed in the above mentioned Act for encourageing and encrease of Shipping and Navigation
for each respective Shipp or Vessell That such Shipp or Vessell shall carry all the aforesaid Goods that should bee laden
on Board in the said Shipp to some other of His Majesties English Plantations or to England Wales or Towne
of Berwick upon. Tweed But because noe Provision hath hitherto beene made for the returneing and produceing
Certificates within some reasonable limitted tyme of the landing and dischargeing such Goods according to the
Condition of the said Bonds and also because many tymes itt hath happened that the Sureties taken in the said
Bonds have beene Persons not resident in the said Plantations but of uncertaine and unknowne Abodes, the said
Bonds have proved ineffectuall to the good purposes intended by the said Acts Bee itt therefore enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That in all such Bonds to bee hereafter given or taken in the said Plantations the Sureties
therein named shall bee Persons of knowne Residence and Ability in the said Plantations for the Value mentioned
in the said Bonds and that the Condition of the said Bonds shall bee within Eighteene Moneths after the Date
thereof (the Danger of the Seas excepted) to produce Certificate of haveing landed and discharged the Goods
therein mentioned in one of His Majesties said Plantations or in England Wales or Berwick upon Tweed otherwise
such Bond [or Copies thereof being attested under the Hand and Seale of the Governour or Commander in Chiefe
to whom such Bonds were given shall bee in Force and allowed of in any Court in England Ireland or the
Plantac[i]ons as if the Originall were produced in Court by the Prosecutor.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Recital that several Ships had been unduly discharged in Scotland and Ireland.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Plantation Goods not to be put on Shore in Scotland or Ireland, but on Condition herein mentioned; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And whereas severall Shipps and Vessells laden with Tobacco Sugars and other Goods of the Growth and Product
of His Majesties Plantations in America have beene discharged in severall Ports of the Kingdomes of Scotland and
Ireland contrary to the Lawes and Statutes now in being under pretence that the said Shipps and [Vessells<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] were
driven in thither by Stresse of Weather or for want of Provisions and other Disabilities could not proceed on their
Voyage For Remedy whereof Bee itt enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the First Day of
December One thousand six hundred ninety six itt shall not bee lawfull on any Pretence whatsoever to putt on
Shoare in the said Kingdomes of Scotland or Ireland any Goods or Merchandize of the Growth or Product of any
of His Majesties Plantations aforesaid unlesse the same have beene first landed in the Kingdome of England
Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed and paid the Rates and Duties wherewith they are chargeable
by Law under the Penalty of the Forfeiture of the Shipp and Goods Three fourths without Composition to His
Majesty His Heires and Successors and the other Fourth to him or them that shall sue for the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Proviso for Ships driven by Stress of Weather, &amp;c. into Ireland.</head>
			<para id="p24">Provided neverthelesse That if any Shipp or Vessell [laden<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] as aforesaid shall by Stresse of Weather bee stranded
or by reason of leakynesse or other Disability shall bee driven into any Port or Place within the Kingdome of
Ireland and shall not bee able to proceed on her Voyage then and in such case onely the said Goods and
Merchandizes may bee permitted to bee putt on Shoare but shall bee delivered into the Custody and Possession
of the Collector or Cheife Officer of the Customes of such Port or Place where the said Shipp shall bee soe
stranded or driven into there to remaine untill the said Goods and Merchandize shall att the Charge of the Owner
thereof bee putt on Board some other Shipp or Vessell in order to bee transported and carried to some other
Port or Place within the said Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed the
said Officer first takeing good and sufficient Security for the Delivery of the same according to the true Intent and
Meaneing of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Persons claiming Right in American Islands, &amp;c. not to alien but to natural born Subjects without Licence from the King in Council.</head>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Governors appointed by Proprietors to be approved by the King, and to take, the Oaths; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">[[And<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] bee itt further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Persons and theire Assignees claymeing any
Right or [Property<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] in any Islands or Tracts of Land upon the Continent of America by Charter or Letters Patents
shall not att any tyme hereafter alien sell or dispose of any of the said Islands Tracts of Land or Proprieties other
than to the Naturall Borne Subjects of England Ireland Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed
without the License and Consent of His Majesty His Heires and Successors signifyed by His or Their Order in
Councill first had and obtayned And all Governours nominated and appointed by any such Persons or Proprietors
who shall bee intituled to make such Nominac[i]on shall bee allowed and approved of by His Majesty His Heires
and Successors as aforesaid and shall take the Oaths injoyned by this or any other Act to bee taken by the
Governours or Commanders in Chiefe in other His Majesties Colonies and Plantations before their entring upon
their respective Governments under the like Penalty His Majesties Governours and Commanders in Chiefe are by
the said Acts lyable to.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. No Ship deemed British or Plantation-built until registered as herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p27">[<ref idref="n10">10</ref>And for a more effectuall prevention of Frauds which may bee used to elude the Intention of this Act by
colouring Foreigne Shipps under English Names Bee itt further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and
after the Five and twentieth day of March which shall bee in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
ninety eight noe Shipp or Vessell whatsoever shall bee deemed or passe as a Shipp of the Built of England
Ireland Wales Berwick Guernsey Jersey or of any of His Majesties Plantations in America soe as to bee qualifyed
to trade to from or in any of the said Plantations untill the Person or Persons claymeing Property in such Shipp
or Vessell shall register the same as followeth (that is to say) If the Shipp att the tyme of such Register doth
belong to any Port in England Ireland Wales or to the Towne of Berwick upon Tweed then Proofe shall bee


made upon Oath of One or more of the Owners of such Shipp or Vessell before the Collector and Comptroller
of His Majesties Customes in such Port or if att the tyme of such Register the Shipp belong to any of His
Majesties Plantations in America or to the Islands of Guernsey or Jersey then the like Proofe to bee made before
the Governour together with the Principall Officer of His Majesties Revenue resideing on such Plantation or Island
which Oath the said Governours and Officers of the Customes respectively are hereby authorized to administer in
the Tenour following (vizt)</para>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Oath, of built of Ship, &amp;c. on registering</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">Jurat A&deg;. B. That the Ship Name of Port<ref idref="n11">11</ref> whereof Masters Name
is att present Master being a Kind of Built of Burthen Tuns was built att Place where
in the Yeare. Time when and that owners name of and of &amp;c
are att present Owners thereof and that noe Foreigner directly or indirectly hath any Share or Part or Interest
therein.</para>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Oath attested and registered to be delivered to the Master, and Duplicate of such Register transmitted to the Commissioners of Customs in London; Penalty on Ship not having made Proof of Built. Exception.
Penalty on Ship not having made Proof of Built. Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">Which Oath being attested by the Governour or Custome Officer (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) who administered the same under theire Hands
and Seales shall after haveing beene registred by them bee delivered to the Master of the Shipp for the Security
of her Navigation a Duplicate of which Register shall bee immediately transmitted to the Commissioners of His
Majesties Customes in the Port of London in order to bee entred in a generall Register to bee there kept for this
purpose with Penalty upon any Shipp or Vessell tradeing to from or in any of His Majesties Plantations in America
after the said Five and twentieth Day of March and not haveing made Proofe of her Built and Property as is
here directed that shee shall bee lyable and shee is hereby made lyable to such Prosecution and Forfeiture as any
Foreigne Shipp (except Prizes condemned in the High Court of Admiralty) would for trading with these Plantations
by this Law be lyable to.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Proviso for special Registry of Prize Ships.</head>
			<para id="p32">Provided alwayes That all such Shipps as have beene or shall bee taken att Sea by Letters of Mart or Reprizall
and Condemnation thereof made in the High Court of Admiralty of England as lawfull Prize shall bee specially
registered mentioning the capture and Condemnation instead of the Tyme and Place of Building with Proofe alsoe
upon Oath that the entire Property is English before any such Prize shall bee allowed the Priviledge of an English
Built Shipp according to the Meaneing of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Exemption of Fishing Boats, &amp;c. from Necessity of Registry.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided also That nothing in this Act shall bee construed to require the registring any Fisher-Boates Hoys
Lighters Barges or any open Boates or other Vessells (though of English or Plantation Built) whose Navigation is
confined to the Rivers or Coasts of the same Plantation or Place where they trade respectively but onely of such
of them as crosse the Seas to or from any of the Lands Islands Places or Territories in this Act before recited
or from one Plantation to another.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. On changing the Name of registered Ship, Register de novo.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Sale to be endorsed on Certificate of Registry</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">And bee itt further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That noe Shipps Name registred shall bee afterwards
changed without registring such Shipp de novo which is hereby required to bee done upon any Transferr of
Property to another Port and delivering upp the former Certificate to bee cancelled under the same Penalties and
in the like Method as is herein before directed And that in case any Alteration of Property in the same Port by
the Sale of one or more Shares in any Shipp after registring thereof such Sale shall alwayes bee acknowledged by
Endorsement on the Certificate of the Register before Two Witnesses in order to prove that the entire Property in
such Shipp remaines to some of the Subjects of England if any Dispute arises concerning the same.]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">loaden <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Propriety <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">The following Clauses are annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">respectively <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


