<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46821" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIV. An Act for making navigable the Rivers of Wye and Lugg in the County of Hereford.[Rot.Parl. 7&amp;8 Gul. III.p.3.n.2]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Stat. 14 C.II.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that the said Sir Wm. Sandys, Windsor Sandys, and Henry Sandys had not acted efficiently; and that the Wears upon the said Rivers were mischievous; The said Rivers declared free and common Rivers</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the free and open Navigation upon the Rivers Wye and Lugg and the Streams falling into them
may bee a great increase of Publick Trade and a beneficial easie conveyance of Shipp Timber and a continual
Nursery of Seamen for the Supply and Service of His Majesties Navy. And whereas in and by a certaine Act of
Parliament made in the Foureteenth yeare of the Reigne of our late Sovereigne Lord King Charles the Second
entituled An Act for the making Navigable of the Rivers of Wye and Lugg and the Rivers and Brooks running
into the same in the Counties of Hereford Gloucester and Monmouth Sir William Sandys Knight Windsor Sandys
Esq[uire] and Henry Sandys Esq[uire] their Heires and Assigns were impowered and authorized (upon the Terms and under
the Provisoes in the said Act mentioned) to make the said Rivers navigable portable or paffable for Barges, Boats
or other Vessells and to remove all Impediments that might hinder the said Navigation And in and by the said Act
of Parliament they the said Sir William Sandys Windsor Sandys and Henry Sandys their Heires and Assigns were
invested with the several Powers and Authorities in the said Act mentioned in order to the carrying on improving
and perfecting the said Navigation and to render it effectual from time to time And that they the said Sir William
Sandys Windsor Sandys and Henry Sandys their Heires and Assignes and noe other should have use or imploy Barges
Boats or other Vessells upon the said Rivers and receive take and enjoy all Profitts Benefitts &amp; Advantages that
should arise by or for the Carriage of any Co[m]modities upp or downe the said Rivers In and by which said Act of
Parliament it was provided That from the City of Hereford to the City of Bristoll there should bee Boats fitted
for Passengers as well as Merchandize Weekely to goe to and againe between the said Cities and that the Price
of all Carriage should not exceed Two third parts of the lowest Rate formerly taken for Carriage of Co[m]modities
between the said Cities And in and by the said Act it was further provided That they the said Sir William Sandys
Windsor Sandys and Henry Sandys should finish the said Work before the Nine and twentieth day of September
in the Yeare of oure Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and five And that if the said Work should fail and
not bee compleated before that time that the Co[m]missioners by virtue of that Act to bee appointed or any Seven of
them were thereby impowered to imploy any other Person or Persons to carry on and perfect the said Work
And that the Persons soe by the Commissioners imployed should enjoy all Priveleges and performe all things by the
said Act granted to the said Sir William Sandys Windsor Sandys and Henry Sandys their Heires and Assigns And
in and by the said Act several Su[m]ms of Money that had been formerly raised in the County of Hereford and were
designed to bee imployed for the opening of the said Rivers were appointed to be paid to the said Sir William
Sandys Windsor Sandys and Henry Sandys they giving Security by the said whole Work to pay (for the Publick
Use of the said County) Five Pounds per Annum for ever for every Hundred Pounds that they should so receive
And they the said Sir William Sandys Windsor Sandys and Henry Sandys did accordingly in or about the Yeare of
oure Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and five receive the said several Su[m]ms of Money which amounted in the
whole to One thousand three hundred Pounds. And whereas the said Sir William Sandys Windsor Sandys and
Henry Sandys never did any thing towards the making of the said River of Lugg navigable And what they did
towards the said Work upon the said River of Wye was performed soe slightly that most of the Locks and Passages
by them made did in a very few Yeares fall utterly to decay and ruine. And whereas the several Wears in and upon
the said Rivers of Wye and Lugg are not onely a greate Obstruction to the Passage of Boats upon the said Rivers
but are likewise an occasion of the destroying the Fish in the said Rivers contrary to the Laws of this Realme
Therefore to the end that the Benefitts and Advantages intended to the Inhitants of the County of Hereford by the
said Act may not be totally frustrated by the neglect or failure of the said former Undertakers And that the Trade
of the said Countie may be encouraged and increased by opening the said Rivers and makeing them and either of
them a Co[m]mon Stream for Barges Boats and other Vessells And that the Fish in the said Rivers may be preserved
and increased be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords
Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same
That the said Rivers of Wye and Lugg be and from henceforth be accounted deemed and taken to bee free and
Co[m]mon Rivers and Streams to and for all His Majesties Subjects freely to make use of for the carrying and conveying
of all Passengers Goods Wares and Co[m]modities, by Boats Barges Lighters and other Vessells whatsoever.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Provision for opening and cleansing the said Rivers.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">The Interest and Powers granted by 14 C. II. to the said Sir Wm. Sandys, Windsor Sandys, and Henry Sandys vested in the Bishop of Hereford and in certain other Persons herein named</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the more effectual cleansing and opening of the said Rivers and perfecting what was begun (and not
finished) by the before named Undertakers And for the more orderly management Preservation and carrying on of
the said Navigation. Be it enacted by the Authority of aforesaid That all and every the Estate Interest Powers Liberties
Authorities Priveledges Profitts Commodities Benefitts and Advantages whatsoever which in and by the said Act of
Parliament were given and granted unto the said Sir William Sandys Windsor Sandys Henry Sandys theire Heires
and Assigns shall from henceforth be lodged and vested in the Lord Bishopp of Hereford for the time being. The
Right Honorable James Lord Chandois The Honorable Paul Foley Esq[uire] Speaker of the House of Co[m]mons John Lord
Scudamore Thomas Lord Conningsby Sir Herbert Crofts Sir Edward Harley James Morgan Thomas Foley juns Robert
Price John Dutton Colt Esquires The Mayor of the Citty of Hereford for the time being The Bayliff of Leominster
for the time being William Fiens Robert Dobbins Thomas Geares Serjeant att Law Richard Read jun[er] John Scudamore
of Kent Church Robert Harley Edward Harley Esquires their Heires and Assignes for ever And that all and every
of the said Powers Liberties Authorities Priveleges p[ro]fitts Co[m]modities Beneffitts and Advantages and all the Estate
Right Title and Interest of them the said Sir William Sandys Windsor Sandys and Henry Sandys their Heires and
Assigns of in or about the Navigation of the said Rivers Brooks or Streams in the said Act menc[i]oned or any the Ways
Passages Streams Locks Weares Turnpikes Pens for Water Cranes and Wharfes upon or adjoyning to the said
Rivers and Streams or any of them are and from henceforth for ever hereafter shall bee by the Authority of this
present Act lodged and vested in them the said Lord Bishop of Hereford for the time being The Right Honorable
James Lord Chandois The Honorable Paul Foley Esq[uire] Speaker of the House of Co[m]mons John Lord Scudamore
Thomas Lord Conningsby Sir Herbert Crofts Sir Edward Harley James Morgan Thomas Foley Robert Price John
Dutton Colt Esquires The Mayor of the Citty of Hereford for the time being The Bayliff of Leominster for the
time being William Fiens Robert Dobbins Thomas Geares Serjeant att Law Richard Reed junior John Scudamore of
Kent Church Robert Harley Edward Harley Esquires their Heires and Assignes for ever in Trust onely for the Good
and Benefitt of the Inhabitants of the said County of Hereford.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The said Bishop of Hereford, &amp;c. to act as the said Sir Wm. Sandys, Windsor Sandys, and Henry Sandys might have acted.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to be appointed as by the said Act, and to execute the said Act and this Act upon the request of the said Bishop of Hereford, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That they the said Lord Bishop of Hereford for the time
being The Right Honorable James Lord Chandois The Honorable Paul Foley Esq[uire] Speaker of the House of Co[m]mons
John Lord Scudamore Thomas Lord Conningsby Sir Herbert Crofts Sir Edward Harley James Morgan Thomas Foley
Robert Price John Dutton Colt Esquires The Mayor of the Citty of Hereford for the time being The Bayliffe of
Leominster for the time being Will[ia]m Fiens Robert Dobbins Thomas Geares Serjeant att Law Richard Reed junior
John Scudamore of Kent Church Robert Harley Edward Harley Esquires their Heires and Assignes for ever shall
and may from henceforth for ever hereafter act and do all Matters and Things (in the said before recited Act
mentioned) requisite and necessary to bee done for the benefitt advantage preservation and improvement of the said
Navigation as fully and amply to all Intents and Purposes whatsoever as they the said Sir William Sandys Windsor
Sandys and Henry Sandys their Heires or Assigns might could or ought to have done if they on their parts had
duely observed the Directions of the said recited Act And the Co[m]missioners for the executing the several Powers in
the said recited Act specified shall bee nominated and appointed as in the said recited Act is directed And the said
Co[m]missioners are hereby authorized and required from henceforth from time to time upon the Request of the said
Lord Bishop of Hereford for the time being The Right Honorable James Lord Chandois The Honorable Paul Foley
Esq[uire] Speaker of the House of Commons John Lord Scudamore Thomas Lord Conningsby Sir Herbert Crofts Sir Edward
Harley James Morgan Thomas Foley Robert Price John Dutton Colt Esquires The Mayor of the Citty of Hereford
for the time being The Bayliffe of Leominster for the time being William Fiens Robert Dobbins Thomas Geares
Serjeant att Law Richard Reed junior John Scudamore of Kent-Church Robert Harley Edward Harley Esquires their
Heires and Assignes to putt in Execution the Powers to them given and appointed in and by the said recited Act
of Parliament, and this present Act as fully and largely to all Intents and Purposes as if the said Powers had been
in this present Act particularly menc[i]oed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The said Bishop of Hereford, &amp;c. may pull down Wears, &amp;c. making Satisfaction to Owners, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall &amp; may be lawfull to and for the said Lord
Bishop of Hereford for the time being The Right Honorable James Lord Chandois The Honorable Paul Foley Esq[uire]
Speaker of the House of Co[m]mons John Lord Scudamore Thomas Lord Conningsby Sir Herbert Crofts Sir Edward
Harley James Morgan Thomas Foley Robert Price John Dutton Colt Esquires The Mayor of the Citty of Hereford
for the time being The Bayliffe of Leominster for the time being William Fiens Robert Dobbins Thomas Geares
Serjeant att Law Richard Reed junior John Scudamore of Kent-Church Robert Harley Edward Harley Esquires their
Heires and Assignes to pull downe and demolish all and every the Wears upon the said Rivers or either of them
they first giving satisfaction to the several Owners and Proprietors of the said Wears for the Fee Simple and
Inheritance of the said Wears respectively after the Rate of Sixteene yeares Purchase for the cleare yearly Value
of such Weares above all Taxes Charges and Reprizes and proportionably for any lesser Estate in the said Wears.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Commissioners or any Seven of them empowered to examine upon Oath, and upon such Examination and at the request of the said Bishop and on Notice to settle the yearly Value of Wears, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">In case the said Trustees shall not have agreed with the Proprietors; and apportion Purchase Money</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Co[m]missioners which from time to time shall bee
appointed according to the said recited Act or any Seven of them are hereby authorized by Examination of Witnesses
upon Oath (which Oath they or any Seven of them are hereby impowered to administer) or by any other lawfull
Ways or Means from time to time and att all. times hereafter upon the request of them the said Lord Bishop of
Hereford for the time being The Right Honorable James Lord Chandois The Honorable Paul Foley Esquire Speaker of
the House of Co[m]mons John Lord Scudamore Thomas Lord Coningsby Sir Herbert Crofts Sir Edward Harley James
Morgan Thomas Foley Robert Price John Dutton Colt Esquires The Mayor of the Citty of Hereford for the time
being The Bayliffe of Leominster for the time being William Fiens Robert Dobbins Thomas Geares Serjeant att Law
Richard Reed junior John Scudamore of Kent-Church Robert Harley Edward Harley Esquires their Heires or Assigns
and due Notice given unto the Party or Parties concerned or left for him or them in Writing att his or their
Dwelling House by the space of Six days before hand to determine and settle the just and clear yearely Value or
Values of the said Wears Fishings Corne Mills Fulling Mills and Iron Works or any of them respectively (in
case the said Trustees their Heires or Assigns shall not before hand have agreed with the Proprietors of the said
Wear or Wears Fishings Corne-Mills Fulling Mills and Iron-Works respectively concerning the same) and to settle
or appoint what Share or Proportion of the said Purchase Money any Tennant or other Person having any particular
Estate Terme or Interest in any such Weare or Wears shall have and receive for his and their respective Interest therein.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Decrees of the said Commissioners or any Seven of them to be recorded and subject to Examination or appeal.</head>
			<para id="p10">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Orders Determinations and Decrees of the said
Co[m]missioners or any Seven of them touching the Premisses shall bee binding to all and every Person and Persons
Body or Bodies Politick or Corporate whatsoever therein concerned and their Heires Successors Executors Administrators
and Assigns and all Persons claiming by from or under them and shall bee [preserved and sett downe<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] upon Record
in such sort manner and for me as in and by the said before recited Act is directed and shall bee subject to such
Examination or Appeal as in and by the said is directed and no other.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Charge of opening the said Rivers how defrayed.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p12">And forasmuch as the purchasing of the said Wears and the giving Satisfaction to the several Persons concerned
in and upon the said Rivers is likely to amount to a very great Su[m]m of Money which Charge ought to bee born
by the County of Hereford in regard that the Benefitt and Advantage of opening the said Rivers is likely for the
most part to accrue unto the said County which Charge cannot be reduced to a certaine Su[m]m until the several.
Proprietors therein concerned shall have been first treated and agreed withal or the Values thereof ascertained
according to the Direction of this Act Therefore for the more regular and equal levying of Money in and upon
the said County of Hereford for the defraying the Charge of opening the said Rivers and making them portable and
passable for Boats and doing such things as are necessary and incident thereunto Be it further enacted by the Authority
aforesaid That such Su[m]m and Su[m]ms of Money as shall by the Co[m]missioners for the said Rivers inhabiting in the
County of Hereford (to be named according to this and the before recited Act) or any Seven or more of them
bee deemed &amp; adjudged necessary and sufficient for to answer and satisfie the said Expence and Charge shall bee
assessed taxed levied and paid in the said County of Hereford att such time and times and by such several Payments
and Proportions and in such manner and forme as is herein after by this Act directed and appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. The Amount of Monies to be raised per Month limited.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Proportion of Herefordshire</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">Provided neverthelesse That the Su[m]m and Su[m]ms so to be assessed or levied on the said County shall not
exceed the Su[m]m or Proportion of Three hundred seventy seven Pounds Foure Shillings Five Pence per mensem
being a Third part of the whole One thousand one hundred thirty one Pounds Thirteen Shillings and Foure Pence
Tax usually charged upon the said County of Hereford as its Proportion when the Su[m]m charged upon the whole
Kingdome amounted to Threescore and eight thousand eight hundred and nineteen Pounds and nine Shillings per
mensem.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Commissioners to assess and levy such Monies.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Yearly Amount</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Co[m]missioners for the said Assessment herein
after appointed shall from time to time tax assesse and levy in and upon the said County of Hereford and the
City of Hereford and Borough of Leominster for and towards the carrying on and compleating of the said Work
such Su[m]m and Su[m]ms of Money (not exceeding in any one yeare the Su[m]m of Foure thousand five hundred twenty
six Pounds Thirteen Shillings and a Penny being the Third part of One Years Assessment upon the said County
att the Rate aforesaid) as the Com[m]issioners for the said Rivers inniting in the said County of Hereford (to be
named and made according as in this and the before recited Act is appointed) or any Seven of them shall under
their Hands and Seals direct &amp; appoint.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. The Commissioners under the 7 &amp; 8 W.III. c.5. to be Commissioners under this Act for levying Monies.</head>
			<para id="p17">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all and every the Persons named and appointed
Co[m]missioners for the County of Hereford City of Hereford and Borough of Leominster by an Act made in the
Seventh Yeare of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for granting to His Majesty an Aid of Foure Shillings
in the Pound for One yeare for carrying on the Warr against France shall be Co[m]missioners for the said Assessments
for the said County of Hereford and the Citty of Hereford and the Borough of Leominster within the said County
of Hereford respectively for the assessing levying and raiseing the said Money for the Purposes aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. The said Comissioners in levying the said Monies to have and execute the Powers limited by 7 &amp; 8 W.III.c.5.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">The like Provision as to Collectors, &amp;c; and also as to their Allowances</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Co[m]missioners and every of them shall have
and execute the same Powers and Authorities Rules and Directions touching the better assessing distributing
collecting levying receiving and paying the said Money appointed to bee levied and raised according unto and by
virtue of this present Act and in as large and ample manner as are or were limitted enacted directed given and
appointed to the Co[m]missioners named in the said Act of Parliament made in the Seventh Yeare of His Majesties
Reigne intituled An Act for granting to His Majesty an Aid of Foure Shillings in the Pound for One Yeare for
carrying on the Warr against France And that the Collectors High Collectors Receiver or Receivers General and
other <emph type="i">Officers</emph> and Persons that shall bee nominated appointed and directed by the said Co[m]missioners to putt this
Act in Execution for levying the said Money shall have the same Powers Priveleges and Authorities and the like
Allowances in Proportion as were given to the like Officers for the executing of the said last mentioned Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Times and Places of Meeting and Proceeding of the said Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to act according to 7&amp;8 W. III. c.5.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p21">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Co[m]missioners for the said Assesments shall
meet together att the most usual and co[m]mon Place of Meeting within the said County City and Borough at such
time and times as the Co[m]missioners for the said Rivers inhabiting in the said County of Hereford shall by Order
or Warrant under the Hands and Seals of Seven or more of them direct and appoint And the said Co[m]missioners
for the said Assessments shall from time to time proceed to putt this Act in Execution for the assessing and
levying upon the said County City and Borough such Su[m]m and Su[m]ms of Money as the said Co[m]missioners for the
said Rivers or any Seven of them under their Hands and Seals shall from time to time direct and appoint (not
exceeding the Proportions herein before expressed) and shall act therein according to the Rules and Directions
given in and by the last before mentioned Act unto the Co[m]missioners therein named.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Commissioners at First general Meeting to appoint Receivers General.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Their Duty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Co[m]missioners for the said Assessments or
the major part of them att their First general Meeting shall nominate and make one or more Receiver or Receivers
General for the said County who shall receive from the High Collectors of the several Hundreds the said Money
so collected and shall issue out and pay the same from time to time according as the Co[m]missioners for the said
Rivers inhabiting in the said County of Hereford or any Seven or more of them shall (by Warrant under their
Hands and Seals) direct order and appoint and not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Commissioners to take Security of Receivers General.</head>
			<para id="p24">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Co[m]missioners for the said Assessments before
named shall take of the said Receiver or Receivers Generall good and sufficient Security for the answering and
paying the Money that shall be by him or them respectively received and every Part thereof unto such Person
and Persons and in such Manner and For me as the Co[m]missioners for the said Rivers inhabiting in the County of
Hereford or any Seven of them under their Hands and Seals shall order direct and appoint and not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Receivers to account to Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to deliver yearly to Michaelmas Quarter Sessions, Copy of Orders and Accounts</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Receiver or Receivers General to be appointed
according to this Act shall from time to time when and so often as hee or they shall bee thereunto required
give and make unto the said Co[m]missioners for the said Rivers inhabiting in the County of Hereford or to any
Seven of them a true Account of all the Money by him or them respectively received and of whom and of all
the Money by him disbursed and to whom and by what Order And that the said Co[m]missioners for the said Rivers
shall yearly att Michaelmas Quarter Sessions cause their Register or Clerk to bring and deliver to the said Court
a Copy or Transcript of their Orders and Accounts for the next before going Yeare there to bee preserved
amongst the Records of the said Court.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. How Commissioners or any Seven of them may employ Surplus Money remaining after clearing the said Rivers.</head>
			<para id="p27">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if it shall happen that after the Payment for and
demolishing of the said Wears Mills and Iron-works and clearing the said Rivers from all Obstructions that may
hinder the passage of Barges &amp; Boats upon the said Rivers there shall remaine any part of the Money raised
and undisposed of by virtue of this Act that then it shall and may be lawfull for the said Co[m]missioners for the
said Rivers inhabiting in the County of Hereford or any Seven or more of them by Warrant under their Hands
and Seals to order and direct the imploying of such part as they shall think fitt of the Money soe remaining for
the building of Warehouses or Store-houses and Tenements for the Habitation of Warehouse-keepers or Storekeepers in and upon the Scite of the Castle of Hereford (the same having been heretofore purchased for the said
County in the Names of certaine Persons in Trust for them) and to make one or more Warehouse-keeper or
Warehouse-keepers to take the Charge and Care of the Goods and Merchandizes that shall be brought thither.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. On the Completion of the said Works the Conveyances of the said Wears, &amp;c. and Account of Monies disbursed left with Custos Rotulorum of Herefordshire.</head>
			<para id="p28">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That so soon as the said Work shall be compleated all
Conveyances that shall be taken of or for any of the said Wears and Mills and a perfect Account of all the
Money that shall be disbursed for purchasing or demolishing of the said Wears and Mills and for clearing of the
said Rivers shall be brought unto and left with the Custos Rotulorum of the said County of Hereford to be kept
and preserved amongst the Records of the Sessions of the Peace for the said County.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Power of Survey in Commissioners under this Act the same as in Commissioners of Sewers in respect of any other Rivers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">Charge borne by Herefordshire</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p30">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Co[m]missioners for the said Rivers living in the
County of Hereford to be named from time to time according as in the First before mentioned Act is directed
shall (for the cleansing the said Rivers and removing, all Impediments and Annoyances in the same) have the same
Power and Authority to survey the said Rivers and all Mills Mill-banks Wears and Flood-Gates upon the said
Rivers and all Streams falling into them and all Impediments and Annoyances in the same and to make like
Processe to enquire thereof and to make such Orders and Decrees for altering amending abating or removing the
same and for keeping the said Rivers open and portable for Boats that any Co[m]missioners of Sewers by any Law
Statute or Co[m]mission of Sewers are enabled to doe in any other Rivers and Places Any Law or Statute to the
contrary notwithstanding Provided neverthelesse that the Charge thereof shall be laid upon and born by the County
of Hereford onely.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Commissioners or any Seven may appoint Register, Clerks, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">and allow Salaries, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p32">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Co[m]missioners for the said Rivers inhabiting in
the County of Hereford or any Seven or more of them shall and may by order under their Hands and Seals
constitute and appoint a Register and one or more Clerk or Clerks for the making entring and enrolling of the
Orders Warrants and Decrees of the said Co[m]missioners and to appoint such other Officers and Agents as they shall
think, needfull to be imployed in and for the carrying on and finishing the said Work and to allow them such
Sallaries or Wages (out of the Money that shall bee soe as aforesaid levied) as they or the greater part of them
shall judge fitt and necessary to be given to them for their Pains in and about the Premisses.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Continuance of monthly Levy of &pound;377. 4s. 5d.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided always and be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Su[m]m of Three hundred
seventy seven Pounds foure Shillings and five Pence directed by this Act to bee laid Monthly on the County of
Hereford and the Powers given by this Act to the Co[m]missioners for levying the same shall continue from the Twenty
fourth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety six to the Twenty fourth Day of June One thousand seven
hundred and no longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. In Actions for executing Act.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">General Issue may be pleaded; Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Action Suit or Information shall be co[m]menced
or prosecuted against any Person or Persons for any thing that hee or they shall doe or cause to be done in pursuance
or in Execution of this or the first before recited Act such Person or Persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever
shall and may plead the General Issue and upon any Issue joyned may give this Act &amp; the special Matter in Evidence
And if [in<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] any such Suit the Plaintiff or Prosecutor shall become Nonsuit or forbeare further Prosecution or suffer
a Discontinuance or if a Verdict shall passe against him (then in any of the said Cases) the Defendant or Defendants
shall recover double Costs for which hee and they shall have the like Remedy as in any other Case where Costs by
Law are given to Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. How Money raised to be applied.</head>
			<para id="p36">Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Money to be raised or borrowed by virtue
of this Act as it is received and comes in shall in the first place be applied to purchase the Wears ordered to bee
pulled downe by virtue of this Act upon the several Rivers (that is to say) Three Fourths for the Wears on the River
Wye and One Fourth for the Wears on the River Lugg.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Trustees of the Navigation may borrow &pound;16,000.</head>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">Application thereof, repaid with Interest at &pound;4 per Cent. per Annum</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p38">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for the Trustees of the
Navigation appointed by this Act to borrow and take att Interest for the making the said Rivers of Wye and Lugg
navigable by way of Loan any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money not exceeding in the whole the Su[m]m of Sixteen thousand
Pounds All which Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money soe to be taken upp or borrowed shall be applied to the making the
said Rivers navigable and to no other Purpose whatsoever and shall be repaid by the said Trustees with Interest for the
same not exceeding Foure Pounds per [Centum<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] per Annum to such Person or Persons their Executors Administrators
or Assigns as shall advance or lend the same in Course as the same shall be lent for which this Act shall be their
Security.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. General Saving of Rights to the Duke of Beaufort and other Persons.</head>
			<para id="p39">Saving always and reserving unto his Grace Henry Duke of Beaufort and to the Right Honorable Charles
Marquesse of Worcester Son and Heire Apparent to the said Duke of Beaufort and the Right Honorable Anthony
Earle of Kent and to the Towne of Monmouth and to all other Person or Persons and their respective Heirs Successors
&amp; Assigns all Rights Royalties Tolls Liberties and Priveledges of Fishing or otherwise in or upon the said River
of Wye which they or any of them respectively have had or enjoyed and of right ought to have enjoy or use in
or upon the said River by virtue of any Grant or Grants Prescriptions or Usage or any other lawfull Ways or Means
whatsoever before the making this present Act of Parliament And that they respectively and their respective Heires
Successors and Assigns shall and may have and enjoy the same Rights Royalties Liberties &amp; Priveledges as aforesaid
in and upon the said River as fully freely and beneficially to all Intents and Purposes and by the same lawfull Ways
and Means as they or any of them respectively might or ought to have done before the making this Act of Parliament
(other then by keeping up maintaining or useing their or any of their Wears in the said River appointed to be
purchased of them and to be demolished) Any thing in this present Act to the contrary thereof in any wise
notwithstanding and as if this present Act hadd never been hadd or made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV.</head>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">The Earl of Kent, his Heirs, &amp;c. and any other Person having an Interest in the new Wear to make and maintain; a Lock upon the said River Wye where the said new Wear now stands; and to build a House Rent&mdash;free for and to pay a Person &pound;10 per Annum for opening and shutting the said Lock; and to do certain Works for preserving Salmon and other Fish</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">And whereas the Right Honorable Anthony Earle of Kent is possessed of a Wear called New Weare upon the
said River Wye in the said County of Hereford and a Forge or Iron-work and for the Benefitt of the said Navigation
and Fishery is contented att his owne Charge to make such Lock and doe such things as are herein after mentioned
on his and their parts to bee done and performed and to debarr himselfe and his Heirs for the future from taking
any Fish whatsoever att the said Weare Lock or Forge Be it therefore hereby further enacted by the Authority
aforesaid That the said Earle of Kent His Heires and Assigns and all such Person and Persons as now have or
hereafter shall or may have any Estate Right Title or Interest whatsoever in the said Wear called New Wear the
better to effect the Navigation of the said River shall from time to time for ever hereafter att his and their owne
p[ro]per Costs and Charges make and maintaine a good convenient and sufficient Lock in and upon the said River att
or neare the place where the said Weare now stands such as shall consist with the Navigation of the said River
and the passing of all Boats upp and downe the said River there And shall likewise att all times hereafter att
his and their owne proper Costs and Charges build and keep in good Repaire a fitting and convenient House upon
his the said Earle of Kents Lands next adjoyning to the said New Wear for the perpetual Habitation of a Person
Rent free to keep the said Lock and constantly to attend the opening and shutting thereof Which Person shall
be always named and appointed by the said Trustees for the River named or appointed in this Act or any Seven
or more of them for the time being And further that the said Earle of Kent his Heires and Assigns and all Persons
having any Right Title or Interest in the New Wear as aforesaid shall for ever pay unto such Person attending the
opening and shutting of the said Lock the yearely Su[m]m of Ten Pounds by Foure Quarterly Payments And for
the better Preservation of the Salmon and other Fish from being taken by any Weels Netts Potts Engines or other
Devices att the said New Wear Lock or Forge and for their more convenient Passage up and downe the said River
the said Earle of Kent his Heires and Assigns and all Persons claiming or to claim any Estate Title or Interest in
the said New Wear shall take downe Ten Yards in Length of the said Wear full Twelve Inches lower then the now
lowest part of the said New Weare in such part thereof as is or shall be next adjoining to the said Lock and
shall make and maintaine a plain smooth and slope descent from the said lowered Ten Yards of the said Wear
to the bottom of the said River such as is usual in the like Cases and shall be sufficient for preserving the Fish
from being taken and shall not lay or place any Netts Snares Engines Weels Potts or other Devices whatsoever in
or upon that or any other part of the said Wear Lock or Forge nor take or destroy the said Fish or hinder or
obstruct their free Passage there.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. If the said Earl of Kent, his Heirs, &amp;c. omit to put up such Lock, or do such Works, for Seven Months, from the 25th March 1696.</head>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">then the said Trustees may appoint Persons to do the same; and to repaire, in case the said Earl of Kent, his Heirs, &amp;c. shall neglect, upon Notice; and the Trustees may levy the Charges incurred by Distress; and no Privilege allowed or pleaded in such Proceedings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">And for the better and more certaine effecting the said Navigation Itt is hereby further enacted That in case
the said Earle. of Kent his Heires or Assigns shall omitt or neglect the making and putting up such House and
Lock or taking downe Ten Yards in Length of the Wear aforesaid Twelve Inches lower or making the said smooth
Slope to the bottom of the River so as the Fish may be preserved from being taken which by this Act hee and
they are required to doe and performe relating to the said House Lock Wear and Fishery by the space of Seven
Months after the Five and twentieth Day of March in the Yeare of oure Lord One thousand six hundred ninety
six or if the said Anthony Earle of Kent his Heirs or Assigns shall omitt neglect or refuse the doeing and performing
any other matter or thing on his or their part to be done or performed by virtue of this Act that then it shall
and may be lawfull to and for the said Trustees or any Seven or more of them and they are hereby authorized
and impowered to direct appoint and imploy Agents and Workmen to doe and performe the same and every
other thing on the said Earle of Kent his Heires or Assignes part to be done by virtue of this Act and from
time to time for ever to amend and repaire the said Lock House and Passage for Fish and every part thereof if it
shall want Reparation in case the said Earle of Kent his Heires or Assigns or any other Person or Persons having
any Estate or Interest in the said Wear shall neglect doeing the same by the space of Foure Weeks after Notice in
Writing given att the Mill or Forge there or Farme called Killyards herein after mentioned or to the said Earle of
Kent his Heires or Assignes under the Hands and Seals of any Seven of the said Trustees And further That in case
the said Earle of Kent his Heires or Assigns or such Person or Persons that hereafter may have any Title or Interest
in the said New Weare shall faile in the Performance of all or any of the severall Appointments of this Act that
then and soe often it shall be lawful for the said Trustees or any Seven or more of them to levy by Distresse upon
the said Forge or the said Farme and Lands there called Killyards now in the Possession of George White situate
and being in the Parishes of Whittchurch and Ganarew in the said County of Herefored such Su[m]m and Sum[m]s of Money
as shall be actually expended in making good such Failure and all Arrears of the said Ten Pounds per Annum with
the Costs and Charges thereof and all Money which shall be expended in doeing such other Matters or Things on
the part of the said Anthony Earle of Kent his Heirs or Assignes to be done or performed by virtue of this Act for
the free Navigation of the said River and Preservation of the Fish as aforesaid in which Proceedings noe Priveledge
of Parliament Peerage or any other Protection whatsoever shall be claimed pleaded or allowed of in any Court or
Courts whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Trustees not to pull down the Iron Mill or Wear of the said Earl, further than is herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p44">Provided always That nothing in this Act contained shall extend or be construed to extend to impower the said
Trustees or any Person or Persons whatsoever att any Time or Times hereafter by virtue of this Act to pull downe
or abate the said Iron-Mill or Forge of the said Earle of Kent or to pull downe or abate the said Wear or Lock
of the said Earle of Kent otherwise than for building altering amending or repairing the said Weare &amp; Lock as
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. The said Earl may pull down the said Wear and Lock.</head>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">If the said Wear and Lock decay, &amp;c. so as to leave the said Rivers open, the said Earl, his Heirs, &amp;c. not obliged to maintain the same, or to pay the said &pound;10 per Annum; Occupiers of the said Wear, or other Person hindering Navigation, Penalty &pound;100; Limitation of Prosecution; Full Costs.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p46">Provided alsoe and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it a shall and may be lawfull to and for the
said Earle of Kent his Heires or Assignes to pull downe remove and abate the said Wear and Lock if they shall
think fitt so to doe And that if att any time hereafter the said Wear and Lock shall be pulled downe or suffered to
decay and fall downe soe as the said River shall be left open and free &amp; no Obstruction thereby of the said
Rivers being navigable in that place That then and so long as the same River shall continue open and free no
Obligation shall remaine upon the said Earle his Heires or Assignes to maintaine or keep up the said Lock or
Wear and the said yearly Rent [or Su[m]m<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of Ten Pounds per Annum shall cease and not be paid for that time
Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding And if any Tenant Undertenant or Occupier of the said
Wear or any other Person or Persons whatsoever shall hinder or cause to be hindred any Boats Barges or Vessells
from passing through the said Lock or shall destroy or cause to be destroyed any Fish att the said Wear Lock or
Forge contrary to the Provision herein before for that Purpose made Then every such Tenant Undertenant Occupier
or other Person so offending shall forfeit for every such Offence the Su[m]m of One hundred Pounds of lawfull Money
of England to any Person that shall within Six Months after the Offence co[m]mitted sue for the same by Action of Debt
Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Ma[jes]ties. Courts of Record att Westminster wherein no Essoigne Protection
Privelege of Parliament or other Privelege Wager of Law or more then one Imparlance shall be allowed and in
such Action the Plaintiff shall recover his full Costs</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Recital that the said Earl of Kent or his Ancestors had made Grants of Fishings, and that there might be Suits, &amp;c. concerning the same.</head>
			<para id="p47">
				<emph type="i">All such Grants, &amp;c, declared void</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p48">And whereas the said Anthony Earle of Kent his Heirs and Assigns are by virtue of this present Act debarred
from taking any Fish in the said Wear Lock or Forge and hee the said Earle of Kent or his Ancestors having made
Grants for Lives or Yeares or for Yeares determinable upon Lives to several of his Tenants and others of Fishings
in the said River of Wye att or neare the Place where the said Wear Forge or Lock now stands and in several
other Parts of the said River which has been little or no Advantage to them and least that there may be any Suits
and Controversies for the future between the said Earle his Heires or Assigns and the said Grantees or Lessees of
the said Fishings the said Earle being willing to repay the said Grantees or Lessees or those interested in the said
Fishings what Fines they have respectively paid for such Leasses or Grants Therefore for the better enabling the
said Earle of Kent his Heires and Assignes to execute such Matters and Things as by this Act hee is obliged to
doe Itt is hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Articles Contracts Covenants Leases and
Grants for any Number of Yeares Lives or for Yeares determinable upon Lives made to and with any Person or
Persons by the said Earle or any of his Ancestors of for or concerning any Fishing Royalty of Fishing Liberty of
fishing or taking Salmons or other Fish in any part of the said River shall from and after the Foure and twentieth
Day of June in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety six be absolutely void and of none
Effect.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Proviso for Repayment by the said Earl, his Heirs, &amp;c. of the Money paid for such Grants, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p49">Provided and it is hereby enacted That the said Earle his Heires or Asssigns shall repay unto such Person and
Persons his and their Executors Administrators or Assigns whose Articles Covenants Leases or Grants shall hereby
be made void all such Su[m]m and Su[m]ms of Money as hee the said Earle of Kent or any of his Ancestors have
respectively received for the same as Fines for such Grants or Leases and that none of the said Articles Contracts
Covenants Leases or Grants whereupon Fines have been paid shall be hereby made void until such Fines are repaid
or tendred to be repaid as aforesaid.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">sett down and preserved <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Cent <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


