<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46835" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the more effectual preventing the Exportac[i]on of Wooll and for [the] incouraging the Importation thereof from Ireland. [Chapter XXVIII. Rot. Parl. 7 &amp; 8 Gul. III. p. 6. n. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>1 W. &amp; M. c. 32,; continued by 4 &amp; 5 W. &amp; M. c. 24. &sect; 9,</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">further continued.; Exception</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas several Laws have been made to prevent the Exportac[i]on of Wooll yet neverthelesse the said
Exportac[i]on is still continued whereby dayly Mischiefs and Evils doe happen and a Correspondence with
France is maintained to the great Prejudice of the Government and Discouragement of the Manufacture of this
Kingdom. And whereas in the First yeare of the Reigne of King William and Queene Mary there passed an Act
intituled An Act for the better preventing the Exportac[i]on of Wooll and incouraging the Woollen Manufactures
of this Kingdom which Act was continued by an Act made in the Fourth and Fifth yeares of King William and
Queen Mary intituled An Act for reviving continuing and explaining several Laws therein menc[i]oed which are
expired and neare expiring and will now soon expire And whereas for preventing the said Mischiefs it is necessary
the said Act should be continued Be it therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the
Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual &amp; Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by
the Authority of the same That the said Act and every Clause Matter and Thing therein contained (except what
is hereafter otherwise altered explained or repealed) shall continue and remaine in full Force as if the same were
herein and hereby particularly recited and mentioned.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. 14 Car. II. c. 18. &sect; 1. repealed.</head>
			<para id="p3">And whereas the Statute of the Thirteenth and Fourteenth of King Charles the Second made against the Exportac[i]on
of Wooll among other things in the said Act mentioned doth enact the same to bee deemed Felony by the Severity
of which Penalty the Prosecution of Offenders hath not been soe effectually put in Execuc[i]on Be it therefore
enacted by the Authority aforesaid That soe much of the said Act which relates to the making the said Offence
Felony be repealed and made void.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Importation of Wool from Ireland allowed from and to the Ports as herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That for the better Incouragement of the Importation of
Wooll from Ireland that it shall and may be lawfull for any Person or Persons whatsoever from the Place or
Places in the said Act limited to import into England from Ireland any Quantity or Quantities of Wool to any
the Ports hereafter mentioned (that is to say) Whitehaven in the County of Cumberland Leverpoole Chester Bristoll
Bridgewater Minehead Barnestaple and Biddiford and to noe other Any thing in this Act to the contrary thereof
in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Commissioners, &amp;c. of Customs in Ireland to transmit to Commissioners of Customs in England Accounts of Wool exported; from Ireland, and where and to whom consigned in England, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Co[m]missioners or Farmers of the Customs in the
Kingdom of Ireland for the time being shall from time to time and att all times hereafter once every Six Months
transmitt or cause to bee transmitted unto the Commissioners of His Majesties Customs in England a true Account
of all such Wooll as shall bee from time to time exported from any of the Places within the said Kingdome of
Ireland from whence the same may be exported the Quantity and Weight thereof and by whom and in what
Ships exported and where consigned and the Names of the Persons signing the Certificates of the Landing the
same in England and the Date of the said Certificates and where the same was landed as alsoe the Quantity and
Weight contained in the said Certificates in order that the same may be compared with the Account by the said
Act appointed to be kept by the Co[m]missioners of the Customs of this Kingdome.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. How Certificates for landing Wool from Ireland, &amp;c. are to be written, and what they are to contain.</head>
			<para id="p6">And for preventing the Mischiefs of razing obliterating or interlining such Certificates as aforesaid Be it further
enacted That all Certificates given for the landing of Wooll from Ireland or from one Port to another in England
shall bee written upon Paper and not Parchment and that the Quantities therein expressed shall not be obliterated
or interlined upon any Pretence whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">No Wool, &amp;c. to be carried by Land to Scotland, or to the Sea Coast, but as herein mentioned; Penalty.; Ships exporting Wool; Penalty.; Penalty on Inhabitants of certain exempt Places, according to the Value of the Wool</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And whereas the several Inhabitants of the several Counties and Shires of this Realme next adjoyning to the
Kingdome of Scotland and to the Sea Coasts doe reap great Profitt &amp; Advantage by the carrying out of Wooll
Wooll Fells Mortlings Shortlings Yarn made of Wooll Wooll Flocks Fullers Earth &amp; Scouring Clay into the
said Kingdome of Scotland and exporting of them into France and other Parts beyond the Seas to the great
prejudice and decay of the Woollen Manufacture of this Realme Bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid
That from and after the First day of May in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety six no
Wooll or any other of the Co[m]modities aforesaid shall be laid or loaden on any Horse or other Carriage whatsoever
or shall bee carried or conveyed by Land to or from any Place or Places within the said Counties next adjoyning
to the said Kingdome of Scotland or within Five Miles of the Sea [Cost<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] as aforesaid but between Sun riseing and
Sun setting under the Penalty and Forfeiture of the said Co[m]modities and of the said Horses and other Cattle and
Carriages imployed in carrying the same And that no Shipp or Vessell shall export or carry the same into any
Part beyond the Seas under the Penalty and Forfeiture of the said Co[m]modities Shipp and Vessell and Treble the
Value thereof with Treble Costs of Suit And the Inhabitants of the respective Hundred Port or Place exempt
next adjoyning to the said Kingdom of Scotland or to the Sea Coasts out of or through which any Wooll or any
other of the Co[m]modities aforesaid shall be so carried or exported shall forfeit Twenty Pounds if the said Wooll
so carried out or exported shall bee under the Value of Ten Pounds but if it shall be of greater Value then
Treble the Value thereof so exported or carried out of the said Kingdom as also Treble Costs of Suit all which

















said Forfeitures Penalties and Costs of Suit are to be recovered and received by him or them that shall sue for
the same and to be prosecuted by any Action of Debt Bill Suit Plaint or Information against the Inhabitants of
such Hundred Port or Place exempt out of or through which the said Wooll or other Comodities shall be
exported in any of His Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster where noe Essoign Protection or Wager
of Law shall bee allowed nor any more then one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. How Execution for Informer may be had, and Proceedings thereon by Quarter Sessions.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">27 Eliz. c. 13</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And bee itt further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Execution for the Informer shall and may bee
had against Two or more of the said Inhabitants And that after Execution had by Force of this Act it shall
and may be lawfull (upon Complaint made by the Party or Parties so charged) to and for the Justices of the
Peace of the same County or Place where any such Execution shall be had att their General Quarter Sessions to
be held for the said County or Place to assesse and tax rateably and proportionably according to their Discretions
all and every the Townes Parishes Villages and Hamletts in the said Hundred Port or Place exempt in the same
Manner and Forme as any Hundred ought to bee charged in case of Robbery co[m]mitted for the Persons against
whom Execuc[i]on shall bee had for the Person so robbed pursuant to an Act made in the Seaven and twentieth
Yeare of Queen Elizabeth intituled An Act for the following of the Hue and Cry And that the Justices of the
Peace of the said County or Place where such Fact shall be committed shall and are hereby impowered and
required att their General Quarter Sessions to be held for the said County or Place to levy the Penalties hereby
charged upon the said Inhabitants by an equal Assessment upon the said Inhabitants and reimburse such Person
or Persons Inhabitants within the [said<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Hundred Port or Place exempt adjacent to the Kingdom of Scotland or the
Sea Coast from whence the said Wooll or other the said Co[m]modities shall be transported in the same manner as
if there had been a Judgment att Law against the said Hundred Port or Place exempt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Aiding Exportation of Wool, &amp;c. Punishment and Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">How recovered.; Notwithstanding Death, &amp;c. of Clerk of the Peace, Action may be prosecuted</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Persons who shall be aiding [abetting<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] or
assisting in carrying or exporting any of the said Co[m]modities out of this Realme as aforesaid (being legally
convicted thereof) shall suffer Three Yeares Imprisonment, without Bail or Mainprize and the Owner of the said
Wooll or of any other of the Co[m]modities aforesaid and all and every Person or Persons who shall be aiding
abetting or assisting in carrying or exporting of them or any of them out of this Kingdom shall answer and
satisfie Treble the Value of all such Forfeitures and Penalties which such Inhabitants shall be so charged with
and liable to as alsoe Treble Costs of Suit, which shall and may be recovered by Action of Debt Suit Bill Plaint
or Information in any of His Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Protection or
Wager of Law shall bee allowed nor any more than one Imparlance by and in the Name of the Clerk of the
Peace for the time being of or for every such County or Place without naming the Christian Name or Sirname of
the said Clerk of the Peace which Treble Value and Treble Costs of Suit shall be to the onely use and behoofe
of the said Inhabitants And that notwithstanding the Death or Removal of any such Clerk of the Peace after such
Action of Debt Suit Bill Plaint or Information sued comenced or p[re]ferred the same shall be prosecuted and pursued
to Judgment and Execution in such Manner and Forme to all Intents and Purposes as that Clerk of the Peace
might have done which first co[m]menced or preferred the said Action of Debt Suit Bill Plaint or Information.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. In Actions, &amp;c. Jury of Freeholders to be summoned out of other Counties.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">The first Three Aiders being Informers exempted from Penalties, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And for the better and more impartial Tryals of all such Actions and Informations which shall be co[m]menced
or prosecuted by virtue of this Act be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That such Actions and Informations
shall be tryed in any of His Majesties Courts of Record by a Jury of good and lawfull Freeholders to bee
su[m]moned out of any other County than that wherein the Fact shall bee co[m]mitted And to encourage Persons to
discover the said Crime the first Three Persons who have been aiding abetting or assisting in carrying out or
Exportation of Wooll or any other of the Co[m]modities as aforesaid that shall informe thereof any Justice of the
Peace in either of the said several Counties aforesaid whereby the Punishment and Penalties appointed by this Act
may be inflicted and recovered the Party or Parties so discovering (not being Owner or part Owners of the said
Wooll or other Co[m]modities aforesaid) shall not suffer any of the said Penalties or Punishment.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. In Actions for executing Act,</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">General Issue may be pleaded; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Action [or Suit<emph type="p">2</emph>] shall bee brought
and prosecuted by any Person or Persons against any Justice of Peace or other Person imployed by them or any
of them in the Execuc[i]on of this Act for any Matter Cause or Thing by them or either of them done co[m]mitted
or executed by virtue or reason of this Act or any Clause or Article therein contained That then and in every
such Case the Action shall be [layd<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] in the proper County where the Fact was done and co[m]mitted and not
elsewhere And the Defendant or Defendants may plead the General Issue and give the Special Matter in Evidence
att the Tryal That the same was done in pursuance and by Authority of this Act And if upon Examination it
shall so happen to be done the Jury shall find for the Defendant or Defendants And in such Case or if the
Plaintiff shall be nonsuit or discontinue his Action after the Defendant or Defendants hath or have appeared the
Defendant or Defendants shall have and recover their Treble Costs which hee or they shall sustaine or be put
unto by reason of his or their wrongfull Vexation in Defence of the said Action or Suit And that every Action
Suit Bill Plaint or Information by virtue of this Act shall bee commenced and prosecuted within One yeare after
the Fact co[m]mitted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Persons entitled compounding for Penalties, any other Person may sue for the same.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Punishment on Compounder.; Continuance of Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">Provided always That if any Person who is intituled to the Penalties and Forfeitures by this Act given shall
compound with any Hundred Port or Place exempt hereby liable to pay the same for any lesser Su[m]m then what
is hereby given That it shall att any time hereafter be lawfull for any other Person to sue for and recover the
same in Manner and Forme as aforesaid as if no such Composition had been made and the Person so compounding
shall for such his Offence suffer Five yeares Imprisonment without Bail or Mainprize And this Act to continue in
force for Three yeares and from thence to the end of the next Session of Parliament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Admiralty empowered to appoint Ships to seize Vessels carrying Wool, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p19">(<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) And for the better preventing the Exportation of Wooll and Correspondence with France Be it further enacted
by the Authority aforesaid That the Lord High Admiral of England or Co[m]missioners for executing the Office of
Lord High Admiral for the time being shall from time to time direct and appoint One Shipp of the Fifth Rate &amp;
Two Shipps of the Sixth Rate and Foure Armed Sloops constantly to cruize from off the North-foreland to the
Isle of Wight with Orders for taking and seizeing all Shipps Vessells or Boats which shall export any Wooll or
carry or bring any prohibited Goods or any suspected Persons.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Coast<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">so also in Original Act; but levied, in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

