<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46837" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXX. An Act for laying several Duties upon Low Wines or Spirits of the first Extraction and for preventing the Frauds and Abuses of Brewers Distillers and other Persons chargeable with the Duties of Excise.[Rot. Parl. 7 &amp; 8 Gul. III. p. 7. n. 1].</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">For the supplying Your Majesties extraordinary Occasions and the better Support of Your Government Be it
enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual
and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and
after the Five and twentieth Day of March in the Yeare of oure Lord One thousand six hundred ninety six until
the Five and twentieth Day of March which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and
one there shall be paid by way of Excise unto His Majesty His Heires &amp; Successors for all Low Wines or Spiritts
of the first Extraction drawne by any Distiller or other Person making or drawing Spirits or Strong Waters for
Sale or Exportation within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed the
Rates and Duties following: (that is to say)</para>
		<para id="p2">For every Gallon of Low Wines or Spirits of the first Extraction made or drawne from any Forreigne or imported
Materials or any Mixture with Forreigne Materials Eight Pence.</para>
		<para id="p3">For every Gallon of Low Wines or Spirits of the first Extraction made or drawne from Brewers Wash or Tilts
Twelve-pence.</para>
		<para id="p4">For every Gallon of Low Wines or Spiritts of the first Extraction made or drawne onely from Drink brewed and
made of any sort of Malted Corne One Penny.</para>
		<para id="p5">For every Gallon of Low Wines or Spiritts of the first Extraction made or drawne from any other sort or kind
of English Materials Three Pence.</para>
		<para id="p6">For every Barrel of mixed Liquors co[m]monly called or knowne by the name of Sweets made from Forreigne or
English Materials Twelve Shillings.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Directions for Distillers, &amp;c. drawing Brandy, &amp;c. from Corn.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Gauger to keep Account.; Mixing other Materials.; Duty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And be further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Distillers and others who shall draw or make any
Low Wines Spiritts or Brandy from Corne shall Brew or cause their Corne to be brewed and from such Drink
so made and prepared (without any mixture with any Molosses Wash or Tilts or other Materials whatsoever shall
draw their Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction And that it shall and may be lawfull for the Gauger &amp;
Gaugers of Excise from time to time to gauge and keep an Account of the Liquors Worts and Drink made and
drawne by such Distillers or others for the making such Low Wines Spirits or Brandies and to see that the same
bee drawne and made from Drink made of malted Corne intirely without any mixture as aforesaid And in Case
any Distillers or others shall therewith mix any other Materials either in the Brewing or after the same is made
into Drink and before the same be distilled into Low Wines the said Gauger shall charge the Low Wines drawne
from the Drink soe mixed with the Duty of Twelve pence for every Gallon which said Duty shall be answered
and paid to His Majesty and Successors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Unduly preparing or receiving Wash;</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And be it further enacted That no Distillers or others drawing Low Wines or Spiritts from Corne prepared as
aforesaid shall prepare any Wash from Molosses or other Materials or receive any Wash of Molosses or other
Materials from any other Person whatsoever until he has drawne off and distilled all the Liquors made or prepared
from Corn as aforesaid on paine of Forfeiture for every Barrel of such Liquors made of Corne as aforesaid found
undistilled or drawne into Low Wines the Su[m]m of Five Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Gauger making false Charge;</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid. That if any Gauger or other Officer of Excise shall wittingly
and willingly make a false Charge by returning to the Co[m]missioners any Quantity of Low Wines or Spiritts of the
First Extraction not made from Malted Corne as [drawne and made<ref idref="n1">1</ref> from Malted Corne such Gauger or Officer
shall forfeit his Office or Employment and alsoe shall forfeit for every Gallon of Low Wines so falsly charged or
returned the Su[m]m of Ten Shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Upon Oath and Certificate as herein mentioned, Drawback allowed upon Exportation of Spirits</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And for the further Encouragement of Distillers and others to draw and make Spiritts or Brandies from malted
Corne brewed into Drink as aforesaid and to export the same as Merchandize [into Parts<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] beyond the Seas Be
it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to or for any Distillers or others
upon Oath made before any Two or more of the Co[m]missioners of Excise or Justices of the Peace for the County
or Place from whence any Brandy or Strong Waters is or are intended to be exported That the same were or
was made and drawne from Drink brewed from malted Corne without any mixture with any other Materials and
that the same is not mixed with any Low Wines not drawne a second time nor with any other Spiritts or Brandy
made from any other Materials either Native or Forreigne and that the Duties of the same are duely entred or
paid and that the same are exported for Merchandize to be spent beyond the Seas to export such Spiritts or
Brandies made from Corne prepared as aforesaid And upon a Certificate under the Hands of the Officers of Excise
for the Port or Place where such Spiritts or Brandies were shipt off of the Quantity so shipt and that the same was
shipt in the presence of such Officers that such Distiller or others so exporting shall be allowed or paid back by
the Co[m]missioners or their Collector for the Port or Place where such Spiritts or Brandy shall be shipt off the Su[m]m
of Three Pence for every such Gallon of Brandy or Spiritts so shipt off.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Duties collected, &amp;c. as by 12 Car. II. c. 24. and other former Acts.</head>
			<para id="p15">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the several Rates and Duties hereby imposed on the
Liquors aforesaid shall be raised levied collected recovered and paid unto His Majesty His Heires and Successors
dureing the time before mentioned in the same Manner and Forme and by such Rules Ways and Means and under
such Penalties and Forfeitures as are mentioned expressed &amp; directed in and by one Act of Parliament made in the
Twelfth Yeare of the Reigne of the late King Charles the Second intituled An Act for taking away the Court of
Wards and Liveries and Tenures in Capite by Knights Service and Purveyance and for settling a Revenue upon His
Majesty in lieu thereof or by any other Law now in Force relating to the Revenue of Excise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Gauger finding a certain Quantity of decayed Wines, &amp;c. with Distillers or Stills as herein described, Proceedings; Obstructing Gauger as herein mentioned; Penalty &pound;20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And for preventing the making or drawing of Low Wines or Spiritts of a First or Second Extraction by any
Compound Distiller or rectifying Distiller or any other co[m]mon Distiller whereby to defraud His Majesty of any of
the Duties by this Act imposed Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Gauger or Officer of
Excise shall from and after the said Five and twentieth Day of March find in the Distilling-house or other House
or Warehouse of any compound Distiller or rectifying Distiller or any other co[m]mon Distiller any Quantity of
decayed Wines Cyder or other Materials fitt for or preparing for Distillation whereby hee may be induced to believe
that such compound or rectifying Distiller or other co[m]mon Distiller doth or may draw or extract Low Wines or
Spiritts from such Materials and such Gauger or Officer shall find any Still or Stills of such Distillers charged or
prepared to work. That it shall and may be lawfull to and for such Gauger or Officer to take off the Head of
such Still or Stills and to examine what Materials are therein if not att work and in case such Still or Stills shall
be att work that then it shall and may be lawfull to and for such Gauger or Officer to stay and continue in such
Distillers Distilling-house until such Still or Stills shall be wrought off and then to examine what Materials were
wrought therein And in case any such Distiller shall refuse to permitt such Gauger to continue in his Distilling
House until such Still or Stills shall be wrought off and examined as aforesaid in every such case such Distiller
shall forfeit for every such Offence the Su[m]m of Twenty Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Stills, Utensils, &amp;c. charged with Duties and Penalties.</head>
			<para id="p18">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Five and twentieth Day of
March all and every the Stills. Worms Still-heads and all other Vessells and Utensills for distilling used by any
such Distiller or other Person for making of Low Wines or Spiritts for Sale or Exportation into whose Hands
soever the same shall come and by what Conveyance or Title soever the same be claimed shall be liable and subject
unto and are hereby charged with all and singuler the Debts and Duties of Excise that now are or hereafter shall
be in Arrear and owing by any such Distiller or other Person or Persons for any Strong Waters Spiritts or Low
Wines so made or drawne as aforesaid And that it shall be lawfull in all Cases to levy Debts and Penalties and
use such Proceedings against the Stills Worms Vessells and Utensills therein contained as it may be lawfull to doe
in case the Debtor or Offender using the said Utensills had been truly and really Owner and Proprietor of the
same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Gauger to take Account of Wash, &amp;c. and Low Wines, and missing Wash, &amp;c. and not receiving Satisfaction what is become thereof; Proceedings.</head>
			<para id="p19">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Gauger and Gaugers of Excise shall from time
to time gauge and take Account of all Wash and other Materials prepared or prepairing for the making of Low
Wines and also of all Low Wines Spiritts or Strong Waters found in the Houses Cellars or Ware-houses or in
any Wash Back Cask or other Vessell or Vessells used by any Distiller or Maker of Low Wines or Spiritts
And in case hee shall misse any Quantity or Quantities of Liquor or Drink brewed or made from Corne or any
Wash or other Materials prepared for making of Low Wines which hee found or gauged the last time such Gauger
was att such Distillers not exceeding Twenty foure houres before and shall not on demand receive Satisfaction what
is become of such Drink or Wash or other such like Materials That in every such case it shall be lawfull for such
Gauger to charge such Distiller with so much Low Wines as such Liquor Drink Wash or other Materials so
missing in his Judgment would reasonably have made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Notice to Officer of distilling.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Hours; Penalty &pound;10</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And to the Intent that the Duties payable to His Majesty for all Low Wines Spiritts Aqua Vite and Strong
Waters may be the better ascertained collected and levied Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and
after the said Five and twentieth Day of March no Distiller or Maker of Low Wines Spiritts Aqua Vite or Strong
Waters shall distill or sett their Stills att work for the drawing or making any the Liquors above mentioned or
shall deliver or carry out any Low Wines Spiritts or Aqua Vite to any of their Customers in Cask or by the
Gallon without Notice thereof first given to the Officer of Excise for the Place or Division where such Distiller or
Maker shall live to the Intent that such Officer may be present to see and gauge the same unlesse att such times
as herein after are mentioned (that is to say) from the Nine and twentieth day of September to the Five and
twentieth Day of March yearely between the Houres of Five in the Morning and Eight in the Evening and from
the Five and twentieth day of March to the Nine and twentieth day of September yearely between the houres of
Three in the Morning and Nine in the Evening upon paine that every Distiller and Maker of the Liquors aforesaid
doeing contrary hereunto shall forfeit for every such Offence the Su[m]m of Ten Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Makers of Vinegar, &amp;c. concealing from Gauger.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Maker of Vinegar Cyder Metheglin Mead or
Sweets for Sale shall att any time hereafter hide conceal or convey away any Vinegar or Liquor prepared for
Vinegar or any Cyder Metheglin Mead or Sweets from the sight and view of the Gauger or Gaugers appointed
to take account of the same whereby His Majesty shall or may be defrauded of any of the Duties due for the same
That every such Maker of such Vinegar Cyder Metheglin Mead or Sweets for every Barrel of Vinegar or Liquor 
prepared for Vinegar or Sweets so hid concealed or conveyed away as aforesaid shall forfeit the Su[m]m of Forty
Shillings and so in proportion for any greater or lesser Quantity and for every Hogshead of Cyder so hid concealed
or conveyed away the Su[m]m of Forty Shillings and so in proportion for any greater or lesser Quantity and for every
Gallon of Metheglin or Mead so hid concealed or carried away as aforesaid shall forfeit the Su[m]m of Five Shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Maker, &amp;c. of Vinegar refusing Entrance to Gauger and to take Account, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;15</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from henceforth in case any Maker or Retailer of Vinegar
or of any of the Co[m]modities aforesaid shall upon due Request or Demand made by the Gauger or Officer in the
Day time or if by Night then in the presence of a Constable refuse to permitt such Gauger or Officer to enter and
come into his or their House Store-house or other Place belonging to or used by such Maker or Retailer of
Vinegar or of any other the Liquors or Co[m]modities aforesaid and to take account of any of the Liquors or Co[m]modities
aforesaid in every such Case such Maker of Vinegar or any other of the Liquors or Co[m]modities aforesaid shall
forfeit for every such Offence the Su[m]m of Fifteene Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Notice by Maker of Vinegar to Officer of Delivery, &amp;c. to Customer, unless at Hours herein mentioned;</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from henceforth no Maker of Vinegar or Sweets shall sell
deliver or carry out any Vinegar or Sweets to any of his Customers either in whole Cask or by the Gallon without
Notice thereof first given to the Gauger or Officer of Excise for the Place or Division where such Maker of Vinegar
or Sweets shall live to the intent that such Officer may be present to see gauge and take an Account of the same
unlesse att such times as are herein after mentioned (that is to say) From the Nine and twentieth day of September
to the Five and twentieth day of March yearely between the Houres of Five in the Morning and Eight in the
Evening and from the Five and twentieth Day of March to the Nine and twentieth day of September yearely
between the Houres of Three in the Morning and Nine in the Evening upon Paine that every such Maker of
Vinegar or Sweets doeing contrary hereunto shall for every such Offence forfeit and lose the Su[m]m of Forty Shillings
for every Barrel of Vinegar or Sweets that shall be so carried out contrary to the true meaning of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 9. &sect;11. continued.</head>
			<para id="p28">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That a certaine Clause in an Act made in the Second
Yeare of the Reigne of His Majesty and the late Queen Mary of blessed Memory entituled An Act for the
encouraging the distilling of Brandy and Spirits from Corne and for laying several Duties on Low Wines or Spirits
of the First Extraction relateing to Strong Waters Brandy Aqua Vite and other Excisable Liquors brought from
the Islands of Guernsey Jersey Sark or Alderney and all the Charges Duties and Penalties and every Article and
Thing therein contained shall continue and be of Force and Virtue dureing the continuance of this Act in as full
and ample Manner to all Intents and Purposes as if the said Clause were herein Word for Word repeated and
enacted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Recital that Revenue defrauded by Brewers making and mixing as herein mentioned after Account taken, and unduly carrying off, &amp;c. Works, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">Brewers to declare to Officer how much of Party Guile they intend to make into Strong Beer, &amp;c; and not to permit Strong Beer to be carried until Small Beer be carried; Proceedings.; Brewer increasing Strong Beer, &amp;c. after such Declaration, &amp;c; Penalty.; In what Case Brewer liable, although Strong Beer, &amp;c. increased by adding Strong Beer, &amp;c. that remained of a former Guile</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p30">And forasmuch as it is found by Experience that the Payment of His Majesties Duties on Beer Ale and other
Excisable Liquors is much avoided and defrauded by the Brewers and Makers thereof by their making Drink of
an extraordinary Strength and mixing of small Beer or Worts with the same after an Account hath been taken
by the Gaugers and by their carrying away or laying off part of their Worts after the same hath been gauged
and making them upp by part of another Wort before the Gauger can take an Account of the same by making
use of Private Pipes and other Conveyances under ground And by reason the Gaugers and Officers are not duely
admitted and permitted to enter and come into the Houses Brew-houses Distilling-houses Store houses and other
Places belonging to or used by such Brewers Distillers or Makers of the Liquors aforesaid or being lawfully entred
are not quietly permitted to continue in such Brew-house where the said Liquors are brewing and making to
gauge and take an Account of the Quantity and Quality of the several Worts as they are brewed off and to see
their strong and small drink cleansed and carried out without mixture and to prevent the co[m]mitting any other
Frauds Be it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Co[m]mon Brewers Innkeepers or Victuallers who
after the said Five and twentieth day of March shall brew or make a Party Guile shall declare to the Gauger or
Gaugers appointed to gauge and take an Account of the same how much of such Guile hee or they intend to
make into Strong-Beer or Ale and how much into Small before any Part of such Guile is cleansed and shall
continue all the said Strong-Beer in their Tuns until the said Small Beer shall be carried out and delivered And
in case such Brewers Innkeepers or Victuallers or their respective Servants brewing or making such Guile of Beer
or Ale shall refuse to declare to such Gauger or Officers how much of their Guile or Brewing they intend to
make into Strong Beer or Strong Ale and how much into Small before any part of such Guile is cleansed or
shall permitt the said Strong Beer to be carried out of their Tuns until the said Small Beer shall be carried out
and delivered such Gauger or Gaugers shall charge and returne the whole of such Guile to be Strong and such
Brewer Innkeeper or Victualler shall pay the Duties thereof accordingly And in case such Brewer Innkeeper or
Victualler or their respective Servants after such Declaration made shall made any Increase of their Strong Beer
or Strong Ale so declared as aforesaid by any Wayes or Meanes whatsoever such Increase shall be deemed and
taken to be and proceed from mixing small Beer with such strong Beer or strong Ale And such Brewer Innkeeper
or Victualler shall forfeit and lose for every Barrel so increased the Su[m]m of Forty Shillings and so in Proportion
for a greater or lesser Quantity over and above the Penalties already imposed for mixing Small Beer with Strong
And in case upon any Information brought against such Brewer Innkeeper or Victualler for the Penalties aforesaid
it shall appear by the Evidence given in behalfe of such Brewer Innkeeper or Victualler that the Strong Beer or
Strong Ale so declared as aforesaid was increased by adding to or mixing with the same any Strong Beer or Strong
Ale that remained or was left or returned of a former Guile of his or her brewing such Brewer Innkeeper or

Victualler shall incur all the Penalties aforesaid except it be also proved by the Oath of One or more credible
Witnesses that such Strong-Beer or Strong Ale so added to such Guile was added to such Guile in the sight and
view of the Gauger the said Evidence or any other thing to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Cleansing or removing Guile, &amp;c. before the Whole brewed off and Account taken without Notice to Officer;</head>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p32">And it is hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if from and after the said Five and twentieth
day of March any co[m]mon Brewer Innkeeper or Victualler shall cleanse carry out remove or convey out of his
Brewhouse or Place of brewing any part of his Guile or brewing of Beer Ale or Worts before the whole of such
Guile is brewed off and be in his Tuns Backs or Coolers and until the Gauger or Gaugers shall or might have
taken an Account of the same and of the distinct Quantities thereof in his respective Vessells without first giving
Notice to the Supervisor or Gauger appointed for the Place or Division where such Brewer Innkeeper or Victualler
doth or shall inhabitt att what time and how much of such Guile or Brewing hee intends to cleanse carry out
or remove and where hee intends to lay or dispose of the same such Brewer Innkeeper or Victualler for every
Barrel of Beer Ale or Worts so cleansed carryed out removed or conveyed out of his Brewhouse or Place of
Brewing without giving such Notice as aforesaid shall forfeit and lose the Sum of Forty Shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Brewer refusing Entrance to Officer or to continue whilset Guile brewing and to take Account;</head>
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;20 and Officer not obliged to prove that Brewer carried, &amp;c. Guile before Duties paid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p34">And it is further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Co[m]mon Brewer Innkeeper or Victualler after
the said Five and twentieth day of March shall upon due Request or Demand made by the Gauger or other
Officer in the Day time or in the Night in the presence of a Constable refuse to permitt such Gauger or other
Officer to enter and come into his House Brew-house Storehouses or other Places belonging to or used by such
Brewer Innkeeper or Victualler or being lawfully entred shall refuse such [Officer or Gauger<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] to stay and continue
in his Brewhouse or Place of Brewing whilst his Guile is brewing and quietly gauge and take an Account of the
several Worts as they are brewed off and lett into his Backs and Tuns and to see their Strong and Small Drink
cleansed and carried out without mixture and to gauge and take an Account of the Goods in the Mesh Tun or
of the Quantity of Malt from which such Worts are drawne or made such Brewer Innkeeper or Victualler for
every such Offence shall forfeit and lose the Su[m]m of Twenty Pounds and the Informer or Prosecutor shall not
be obliged to prove that such Brewer Innkeeper or Victualler did carry or deliver out any part of such Guile of
Beer or Ale before hee paid and cleared the Duties due for the same Any thing in the former Acts of Excise
or any other Act or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Brewer, &amp;c. mixing, &amp;c. Beer upon carrying out, or afterwards., &amp;c.;</head>
			<para id="p35">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound; 5.; Gauger may taste Drink upon Drays and in Cellars; Brewer, &amp;c.; refusing Entrance or tasting; Penalty &pound; 5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p36">And for the preventing and discovering of all Frauds made by mixtures or otherwise Be it enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That if any Co[m]mon Brewer or Innkeeper after the said Five and twentieth day of March shall
upon carrying out his Drink or after the same is carried out start or mix any Small Beer or Small Worts with
or amongst any Strong Beer or Strong Ale upon his Dray or in any Victuallers Cellar or other Place such
Brewer or Innkeeper so doing shall forfeit and lose for every such Offence the Su[m]m of Five Pounds And further
That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Gauger or Gaugers of the Excise to taste the Drink upon any
such Brewers Dray or Drays where and whensoever hee or they shall find and meet the same And alsoe upon
Request to enter into the Cellar or Cellars or other Rooms in the Possession of any Innkeeper or Victualler that
doe or shall take or receive any Drink of or from any Co[m]mon Brewer and to taste the Drink in the same And
if any such Innkeeper or Victualler after the said Five and twentieth day of March shall refuse such Gauger or
Gaugers to enter and come into their Cellar or Cellars or other Rooms or being entred shall refuse such Gauger
or Gaugers to taste the Drink in the same such Innkeeper or Victualler for every such Offence shall forfeit and
lose the Su[m]m of Five Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Commissioners of Excise, &amp;c. may summon Parties to give Evidence.</head>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">Refusing to appear or to give Evidence; Penalty &pound;10</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p38">And be it further enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Co[m]missioners of Excise and Justices
of the Peace respectively upon any Information exhibited before them for any Offence co[m]mitted against the Laws
of Excise to su[m]mon any Person or Persons (other than the Party accused) to appeare before them att a certaine
Day Time and Place to be inserted in such Su[m]mons and to give Evidence for the Discovery of the Truth of the
Matter in Controversie before them And in case of Neglect or Refusal to appeare or if upon Appearance such
Person or Persons shall refuse to give Evidence when hee shall be thereunto required every such Person so making
default shall forfeit and lose the Su[m]m of Ten Pounds to be imposed recovered levied and disposed in manner as
herein is directed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Recital of 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 20. &sect;48.</head>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">Gauger within Three Days from the End of every Week to deliver to Brewer a Copy of Charge; Penalty &pound;10.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p40">And whereas in and by one Act of Parliament made in the Fifth and Sixth yeares of the Reigne of His Majesty
and the late Queen Mary of blessed Memory intituled An Act for granting to Their Majesties several Rates and
Duties upon Tunnage of Ships and Vessells &amp; upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for securing certaine Recompences
and Advantages in the said Act mentioned to such Persons as shall voluntarily advance the of Fifteen hundred
thousand Pounds towards the carrying on the Warr against France, Itt is amongst other things enacted in the
Words or to the Effect following (viz<emph type="p">t</emph>.:) That true Notes in Writing of the last Gauges made or taken by the
Gaugers shall be left by them with all Brewers Makers or Retailers of Beer Ale or other Exciseable Liquors
respectively or some of their Servants att the times of their taking their Gauges containing the Quantity and Quality
of the Liquors so gauged upon [certaine<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Penalties in the said Acts mentioned And whereas it is (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) necessary for
the securing His Majesties Duties upon the Liquors aforesaid that several Gauges be taken by one or more Officers
of every Wort of one and the same Guile or Brewing by reason whereof the said Notes left by such Gaugers
doe not sufficiently informe such Brewer or Retailer how much hee is charged in such respective Guile or Brewing 
Be it therefore enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Five and twentieth
day of March every Gauger shall within Three days after the end of every Week deliver to or leave with such
Brewer or Retailer or their respective Servants a true Copy under his Hand of each respective Charge by him
made upon such Brewer or Retailer cotaining the Quantity and Quality of the Liquors by him charged in such
Week respectively And if any such Gauger or Gaugers shall refuse or neglect to leave with such Brewer or
Retailer or their respective Servants such Copy of his or their Charges as aforesaid or shall Charge such Brewer
or Retailer more then such Copy contains such Gauger or Gaugers shall forfeit and lose for every such Offence
or Neglect the Su[m]m of Ten Pounds to be recovered by any Person that shall sue for for the same by Action
of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster in which no Essoigne
Protection Privelege or Wager of Law nor more then one Imparlance shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Gauger delivering Charge not liable to Penalties of former Acts.</head>
			<para id="p41">And it is hereby provided and declared That no Gauger or Gaugers who doe or shall leave such Copy of his
Charges as above directed and required shall from henceforth be liable to any of the Penalties by the former
Acts imposed for not leaving Notes of the last Gauges att the Times of their taking such Gauges The said Act
or any other Act or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII.</head>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">Officer may break open Doors, &amp;c. of Brewhouse, &amp;c. to search for private Backs, &amp;c.; and on finding private Pipe, &amp;c. may follow the same into the House, &amp;c. of any other Person, making Satisfaction to Owner.; Opposing Officer; Penalty &pound;20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">And for the better preventing and discovering of all private Backs Tuns and other private and concealed Vessells or
other Receptacles and of all Drains Pipes or other Conveyancs to or from the same used by any Brewer Distiller
or other Maker or Retayler of Exciseable Liquors to defraud His Majestie of any of the Duties payable by them
or any of them respectively Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Five and
twentieth day of March that it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Officer &amp; Officers of Excise or any of
them in their respective Divisions in the Day time and in the presence of a Constable or other lawfull Officer
for the Peace who are hereby respectively required to be aiding and assisting therein where they shall have a just
Suspicion that any such private Backs Tuns or other Vessells aforesaid are used by any such Brewers Distillers
or Makers aforesaid on Request first made and Cause declared to break open the Door or any part of such
Brew-house Distilling-house Store-house Ware-house or other Roome in their respective Possessions and to enter
into the same and alsoe break upp the Ground in any such Brew-house Distilling-house Store-house Ware-house
or other Roome or the Ground neare adjoyning in their respective Possessions to search after such Back Tun or
other Vessell aforesaid or any Pipe or other Conveyance leading thereto And in case where they shall find any
private Pipe or other Conveyance to search after and follow the same and in case the same shall lead into any
Ground House Out-house or Place in the Possession of any other Person or Persons on like Request and with, a
Constable to enter into the same and break open the Ground or any part of the House or Houses if Occasion
shall be to follow such private Pipe in order to find out and discover such private and concealed Back Tun or
other Vessell into which such Pipe or other Conveyance shall lead making good the Ground or House so broken
upp or giving reasonable Satisfaction for the same to the Owner or Owners thereof And in case any such Brewer
Distiller or any other Person or Persons shall oppose or hinder such Officer or Officers in the due Execution of
the Powers and Authorities hereby given or granted every such Brewer Distiller or other Person so doing shall
forfeit and lose for every such Offence the Su[m]m of Twenty Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Making, &amp;c. Verjuice for Sale Duties as for Cyder.</head>
			<para id="p44">And it is hereby further declared that all Persons who shall buy or make Verjuice for Sale shall be chargeable
with and pay the same Duties as in case of Cyder and Perry</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. How Penalties sued for and disposed of.</head>
			<para id="p45">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Fines Penalties and Forfeitures by this Act imposed
shall be sued for recovered and levied by such Ways Means and Methods as any Fine Penalty and Forfeiture is or
may be recovered by any Law or Laws of Excise or by any Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of
His Majesties Courts of Record att Westminster and that One Moiety of every such Fine Penalty or Forfeiture
shall be to His Majesty or His Heires and Successors and the other Moiety to him or them that shall discover
informe or sue for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV.</head>
			<para id="p46">
				<emph type="i">Inferior Officers to continue notwithstanding Death or Removal of Commissioners by whom they were appointed, or Alteration of Commissioners, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p47">And whereas His Majesties inferiour Officers whether they be Subco[m]missioners Collectors Supervisors Gaugers or
others employed in levying the Rates Impositions and Duties upon Beer Ale and other Exciseable Liquors and
upon Salt are by virtue of His Majesties Co[m]mission appointed authorized and constituted by the Chief Co[m]missioners
and Governors of and for the Receipt of Excise and Rates and Duties upon Salt or any Five of them And whereas
if by the death of any one of the said Chief Co[m]missioners who joyned in the appointing authorizing &amp; constituting
any such inferiour Officer or by the Alteration or other Determination of the Co[m]mission to the said Chief Co[m]missioners
the Authority given to such inferiour Officer or Officers should be determined it would prove very prejudicial to
His Majesty and render it impossible on such Occasions to collect and levy the said Rates and Duties justly and
duely as the same ought to be collected and levied For Prevention whereof and of all Doubts and Questions which
have been or may arise thereupon Be it declared and enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That all such inferior.
Officers who are have been or shall be duely and legally authorized and constituted in pursuance of any Co[m]mission
under the Great Seale of England since His Majesties happy Accession to the Crowne or any such Co[m]mission
which shall hereafter be granted to the Chief Co[m]missioners and Governors of and for the Receipt of Excise and
Rates and Duties upon Salt do and shall remaine and continue in their respective Offices and Employments
notwithstanding the Death or Removal of any Chief Co[m]missioner or Co[m]missioners by whom they were so authorized

and constituted or any Alteration Change or other Determination of the Co[m]mission of such Chief Co[m]missioners and
Governors until the Authority and Constitution of such inferiour Officers respectively be by the Chief Co[m]missioners
and Governors of and for the Receipt of the Excise and Rates and Duties upon Salt for the time being revoked
or annulled.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI.</head>
			<para id="p48">
				<emph type="i">His Majesty or the Exchequer may borrow &pound;70,000 Monies on Credit of Duties.; Interest as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p49">And to the End aswell the whole Rates and Duties upon Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction and
Sweets hereby granted as alsoe the weekly Su[m]m herein after mentioned to be taken and applied out of the hereditary
Branch of His Majesties Revenues of Excise. upon Beer Ale and other Liquors and out of that part of His
Majesties Revenues of Excise upon Beer Ale and other Liquors which is granted to His Majesty dureing His Life
(which God preserve) and likewise another Weekly Su[m]m herein after mentioned to be taken and applied out of
His Majesties Revenue ariseing within the General Letter-Office or Post-Office or the Office of His Majesties
Post-Master-General may be made Funds or Securities for raiseing any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money not exceeding in
the whole Five hundred and fifteen thousand Pounds (that is to say) any Su[m]m or Sums not exceeding Five hundred
thousand Pounds for defraying the Expences of His Majesties Household and Family and other His Majesties
necessary Occasions And any Su[m]m not exceeding Fifteen thousand Pounds for the Relief of the Poor French
Protestants by borrowing Moneys upon the same Rates Duties or Branches respectively in such Proportions Manner
and Forme as are herein after exp[re]sed Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be
lawfull to and for his Majesty or His Majesties Officers in the Receipt of His Exchequer to borrow or take in by
way of Loan to His Majesties Use on Creditt of the said Rates or Duties upon Low Wines or Spiritts of the
First Extraction and Sweets hereby granted any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money not exceeding Seventy thousand Pounds
(to be reckoned part of the said Su[m]m not exceeding Five hundred and fifteen thousand Pounds for the Purposes
aforesaid) from any Person or Persons Natives or Forreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate as shall be willing to
advance or lend the same And that Interest for the Forbearance thereof not exceeding the Rate of Six Pounds
per Centum per Annum for the First Forty thousand Pounds and Seven Pounds per Cents per Annum for remaining
Thirty thousand Pounds which shall be so lent shall be allowed and paid out of the said Rates or Duties upon
Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction and Sweets hereby granted And that the Money so to be lent shall
not be rated or assessed to any Publick Tax or Assessment whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII.</head>
			<para id="p50">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners of Excise to cause Duties to be paid weekly into the Exchequer; the same to be entered apart from other Monies</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p51">And to the end all the Money that shall be so lent to His Majesty on the said Duties upon Low Wines and
Spirits of the First Extraction and Sweets may be well and sufficiently secured and repaid with Interest as aforesaid
out of the same Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Co[m]missioners of the Excise for the
time being shall cause all the Moneys ariseing by the said Duties upon Low Wines Spiritts or Sweetts hereby
granted to be brought and paid from time to time Weekly into the Receipt of the Excheq[uer], (that is to say) upon
Wednesday in every Week if it be not an Holy-day and if it be then the next day after that is not an Holy-day
And that there shall be provided and kept in His Majesties Exchequer (that is to say) in the Office of the Auditor
of the Receipts one Book in which all the said Moneys which shall be paid into the Exchequer as aforesaid shall
be entred apart and distinct from all other Moneys paid or payable to His Majesty His Heires and Successors upon
any Account whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Commissioners refusing, &amp;c. to pay, or diverting Monies;</head>
			<para id="p52">
				<emph type="i">Incapacity and Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p53">And be it further enacted That if the said Co[m]missioners of Excise for the time being shall refuse or neglect to
pay into the Exchequer all or any the said Moneys of the said Duties upon Low Wines Spirits or Sweets hereby
appointed to be paid as aforesaid in such manner as they are before by this Act required to do or shall divert or
misapply any of the same then they for every such Offence shall forfeit their Offices of Co[m]missioners and Governors
for the Management and Receipt of the Excise and be incapable of any Office or place of Trust whatsoever and
shall be liable to pay the full value of any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms so diverted or misapplied to any Person or Persons who
will sue for the same by any Action of Debt or of the Case Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties
Courts of Record att Westminster wherein no Essoign Protection Wager of Law Privelege of Parliament or other
Privelege or more than one Imparlance shall be granted or allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Comptroller of Excise to keep Account of Duties to which Access may be had without Fee.</head>
			<para id="p54">And be it further enacted That the Comptroller of the Excise for the time being shall keep a perfect and
distinct Account of all the Moneys which shall arise by the said Duties on Low Wines Spirits and Sweets hereby
granted as the same shall from time to time arise come or be brought into the said Office of Excise to which
Account all Persons concerned shall have free Accesse att all seasonable times without Fee or Charge.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Tallies of Loan, and Orders for Repayment of Course.</head>
			<para id="p55">
				<emph type="i">Assignable.; Register of Orders of Repayment kept in the Exchequer; without Preference, and paid in Course; No Fee for providing Register, or for Search.; Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p56">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from time to time upon making any such Loans as
aforesaid on creditt of the said Duties on Low Wines Spirits and Sweets Tallies of Loan shall be levied for all and
every Su[m]m and Su[m]ms of Money so to be lent And that Orders according to the course of the Exchequer shall be
drawne and signed for Repayment of the same and for Payment of such Interest as aforesaid for the Forbearance
thereof the said Interest to be paid every Three Months until Satisfaction of the Principal Su[m]m And that all and
every such Order or Orders and the Moneys therein to be contained or any part thereof shall be assignable and
transferrable without Power of Revocation so as the Assignments thereof be endorsed upon the respective Orders
and entred or notified in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt of the Excheq[uer] in a Book to be there kept for
that purpose And that a distinct Register shall be kept in the said Receipt of Exchequer of all the said Orders
of Repayment not exceeding Seventy thousand Pounds in which the said Orders shall be registred in Course
according to the Date of the Tallies respectively without any [other<emph type="p">1</emph>] Preference of one before another And that
every Person shall be paid in Course as his Order shall stand entred in such Register Book out of the said Duties
upon Low Wines Spirits and Sweets by this Act granted which are hereby appropriated thereunto And that no
Fee Reward or Gratuity directly or indirectly shall be demanded or taken for providing or making any such Book
or Register or for any View or Search in the same by any of His Majesties Officers their Clerks or Deputies on
Paine of forfeiting Treble Damages to the Party grieved to be recovered as aforesaid either for demanding or taking
any such Fee or Gratuity or for giving any undue Preference in Point of Registry or Payment.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. What not interpreted undue Preference.</head>
			<para id="p57">Provided always That if it happen that severall of those Tallies and Orders beare Date or be brought the same
day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be registred it shall be interpreted no undue Preference which of those bee
entred first.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. No undue Preference if subsequent Orders paid first, if sufficient reserved for preceding Orders.</head>
			<para id="p58">Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpreted any undue Preference to incur any Penalty in point of Payment
if the Auditor direct or the Clerk of the Pells record and the Tellers do pay subsequent Orders of Persons that
come and demand their Moneys and being their Order before other Persons that did not come to demand their
Money and bring their Order in their Course so as there be so much Money reserved as will satisfie precedent
Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them yett so as that Interest of Loan shall in that case
cease from the time the Money is so reserved and kept in Bank for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII.</head>
			<para id="p59">
				<emph type="i">&pound;6,000 out of Hereditary and Temporary Excise Duties applied weekly in Payment of unsatisfied Tallies with Interest at &pound;6 per Cent. Per Ann.; and then in Payment of &pound;400,000, and Interest as herein mentioned, borrowed upon Credit of this Act.; Interest upon Tallies paid every Three Months; Commissioners of Excise to cause the said weekly Sum to be applied.; Penalty.; If weekly Receipt not sufficient, Deficiency made good out of whole Receipt of Excise</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p60">And whereas severall Tallies of Pro or Assignment and other Tallies have been levied or stricken att the
Receipt of His Majesties Exchequer upon the said Hereditary Branch of His Majesties Revenues of Excise upon
Beer Ale and other Liquors and upon that part of the said Revenues of Excise which is granted to His Majesty
dureing his Life (which God preserve) or upon either of them joyntly or severally and divers Su[m]ms of Money
upon the said Tallies do now remaine unsatisfied which with Interest for the same or for some of them are
appointed or intended to be satisfied or paid out of the Produce of those Branches of Excise in Course according
to the Dates of the said Tallies so remaining unsatisfied Be it therefore further enacted by the Authority aforesaid
That Weekly and every Week from and after the Twentieth Day of April One thousand six hundred ninety-six
the Su[m]m of six thousand Pounds out of the Money from time to time ariseing in the Office of the General
Receipt for the particular Branches or Duties of Excise before mentioned which are co[m]monly called the Hereditary
and Temporary Excise or either of them shall be seperated and kept apart and shall upon Wednesday in every
Week if the same be not an Holyday but if the same be an Holyday then the next day after that is not so
be issued paid and applied and the same is hereby appropriated to and for the Payment and Satisfaction of the
said Tallies already levied and now remaining unsatisfied on the said particular Branches of Excise or either of them
and the Interest thereof not exceeding the Rate of Six Pounds per Centum per annum until the same shall be
fully satisfied and paid off And from and after the full Satisfaction thereof then the like Weekly Su[m]m to arise as
aforesaid shall in like manner be separated and kept apart issued paid and applied and the same is hereby appropriated
to and for the repayment and satisfaction of such further Su[m]m and Su[m]ms of Moneys not exceeding in the whole
[the Su[m]m of<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Four hundred thousand Pounds as by or upon the Creditt of this Act shall be borrowed or
charged thereupon as part of the said Su[m]m not exceeding Five hundred and Fifteen thousand Pounds intended to
be raised for the several purposes aforesaid and the Interest of the Moneys so to be borrowed not exceeding Seven.
Pounds per Centum per annum for the First Two hundred thousand Pounds and Eight Pounds per Centum per
anu[m]m for the remaining Two hundred thousand Pounds so as that the Tallies for the principal Su[m]ms respectively
shall be paid in Course according to their respective Dates until the same shall be fully discharged and paid off
And the Interest upon every such Talley shall be paid every Three Months until the Satisfaction of the Principal
And the Chief Co[m]missioners of His Majesties Revenues of Excise for the time being are hereby authorized and
strictly enjoyned and required to cause the said Weekly Su[m]m ariseing or to arise as aforesaid to be paid and
applied accordingly without diverting or misapplying the same or any part thereof to any other Use Intent or
Purpose whatsoever and without giving any undue Preference in the Payment of the said Tallies last mentioned or
any of them under the Penalty of forfeiting Treble Damages besides Costs of Suit to the Party grieved who shall
or may sue for and recover the same by Action of Debt or on the Case or by Bill Suit or Information as
aforesaid And in case in any Week or Weeks the whole Receipt of the Moneys upon the said particular Branches
called The Hereditary and Temporary Excise shall not be sufficient to answer the weekly Payment or Payments
hereby directed for such particular Week or Weeks That then and so often the Deficiency or Deficiencies thereof
shall be supplied and made good out of the whole Receipts upon the said particular Branches of Excise ariseing
in the next or any subsequent Week or Weeks wherein such Receipt or Receipts shall be sufficient to beare
or make good the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. Monies and Tallies assignable.</head>
			<para id="p61">
				<emph type="i">Assignment entered.; Monies lent Tax free</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p62">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Moneys which shall be lent and secured by such
Tallies as aforesaid and the Tallies for the same and the Interest thereof shall be assignable and transferable from
one Person to another and so over without power of Revocation so as the Assignments or Transferences thereof
be entred or notified in a Book for that purpose to be kept in the head Office of the Excise in London and
that no Money so to be lent on Credit of the said Weekly Su[m]m of Six thousand Pounds shall be charged or
assessed to or for any publick Tax or Imposition whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV.</head>
			<para id="p63">
				<emph type="i">Register of Tallies kept at Head Office of Excise.; Access there to without Fee; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p64">And to the end all the Moneys hereby appropriated or intended to or for the Satisfaction of the said Tallies
last mentioned and the Interest thereof may be duely applied thereunto and not diverted to any other use Be it
further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That there shall be provided and kept by the said Co[m]missioners of
Excise in their Head Office aforesaid one Book in which all the said Tallies levied or to be levied as aforesaid
upon produceing or shewing the same to them or their Clerk to be appointed for keeping the said Book shall
be entred and registed and the particular Dates thereof shall be expressed according to which Dates every Person
is to be paid in course as aforesaid And that all Persons concerned shall have free accesse to the said Book att
all seasonable times And that no Fee Reward or Gratuity directly or indirectly shall be demanded or taken by
the said Co[m]missioners of Excise or any of their Officers Clerks or Substitutes for the Payment of the said Tallies
or any of them or of any View Search or Entry concerning the same under the Penalty that the Person offending
therein shall be forejudged from his Place or Office and be uncapable to serve His Majestie therein.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Payment of Tallies of subsequent Entry or Date brought first, no undue Preference, if sufficient Money reserved for preceding Tallies.</head>
			<para id="p65">Provided always and it is hereby declared That it shall not be interpreted an undue Preference or Misapplication
where any Tallie or Tallies shall not be brought to the said Office to be entred before they come in course of
Payment to satisfie any Tallie of a subsequent Date before the same And if it shall happen that several Tallies shall
bear the same Date the said Co[m]missioners may cause them to be entred and satisfied one after another and it shall
not be interpreted any undue Preference to incurr any Penalty in point of Payment if the said Co[m]missioners of Excise
do pay subsequent Tallies of Persons who come and demand their Money and bring their Tallies before other
Persons that did not come to demand their Money and bring their Tally in course so as there be so much Money
reserved as will satisfie preceeding Tallies which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them neverthelesse in
such Cases the Interest shall cease from the time the Money is so reserved and kept in Bank for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. Proviso for Payment of Salaries and Incidents.</head>
			<para id="p66">Provided always That any thing in this Act contained concerning the said Weekly Payment shall not be construed
to obstruct or hinder the Payment of Salaries or other incident Charges necessary for the Management of His
Majesties Revenues of Excise upon Beer Ale and other Liquors Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII.</head>
			<para id="p67">
				<emph type="i">&pound;600 Weekly out of Post Office Duties applied Weekly in Payment of unsatisfied Tallies, with Interest at &pound;6 per Cent. per Ann.; and then in Payment of &pound;45,000 and Interest at &pound;7 per Cent. per Ann; Interest upon Tallies paid every Three Months; post Master General, &amp;c. to cause the same to be paid; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p68">And whereas several Tallies of Pro of Assignment or other Tallies have been also levied or stricken att the
Receipt of the Exchequer upon His Majesties said Revenue ariseing in the General Letter-Office or Post-Office and
divers Su[m]ms of [Money<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] upon the same Tallies do now remaine unsatisfied Be it further enacted by the Authority
aforesaid That weekly and every Week from and after the Twentieth day of April One thousand six hundred
ninety six the su[m]m of six hundred Pounds out of the Money or Revenue from time to time ariseing in the General
Letter-Office or Post-Office before mentioned shall be separated and kept apart and shall (upon Wednesday in
every Week if the same be not an Holiday and if it be then the next day after that is not an Holiday) be issued
paid and applied and the same is hereby appropriated to and for the Payment and Satisfaction of the said Tallies
already levied and now remaining unsatisfied on the said Revenue ariseing in the said Office and the Interest thereof
not exceeding the Rate of Six Pounds per Centum per Annum until the same [shall<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] be fully satisfied and paid
off And from and after the full Satisfaction thereof then the like Weekly Su[m]m of Six hundred Pounds out of the
Revenue ariseing in the said General Letter-Office or Post-Office shall in like manner be separated and kept apart
issued paid and applied and the same is hereby appropriated to and for the Repayment and Satisfaction of such
further Su[m]m and Su[m]ms of Money not exceeding in the whole the Su[m]m of Forty five thousand Pounds as by or
upon the creditt of this Act shall be borrowed or charged thereupon as part of the said Su[m]m not exceeding Five
hundred and fifteen thousand Pounds intended to be raised for the several Purposes aforesaid and the Interest
thereof not exceeding Seven Pounds per Centum per Annum so as that the Tallies for the Principal Su[m]ms
respectively shall be paid in Course according to their respective Dates until the same shall be fully discharged
and paid off And the Interest upon every such Tally shall be paid every Three Months until Satisfaction of the,
Principal And His Majesties Post-Master and Post-Masters General for the time being and the Receiver General in
the Post-Office for the time being are hereby authorized and strictly enjoyned and required to cause the said
Weekly Su[m]m of Six hundred Pounds to be paid and applied accordingly And all Matters and Things before by
this Act appointed or directed for or concerning the due and regular Payment of the said Tallies att the Excise
Office by the Co[m]missioners or other Officers there shall be observed and executed in relation to the Payment of
the said Tallies hereby appointed or intended to be paid att the General Letter-Office or Post-Office by the said
Post-Masters or other the proper Officers there and under the like Penalties as if the Clauses in that behalfe were
again repeated in this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. Proviso for Annuities to Prince George of Denmark, and the Princess Anne of Denmarke and Monies under Letters Patent herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p69">Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That this Act or any thing herein contained shall
not extend or be construed in any wise to hinder or delay any Payment or Payments whatsoever grown due and
incurred or hereafter to grow due for or upon the several and respective yearely Su[m]ms of Thirty thousand Pounds
and Twenty thousand Pounds by the Yeare granted to several Persons in Trust for His Royal Highnesse Prince
George Hereditary of Denmark and Her Royal Hignesse the Princesse Anne of Denmark and for such further
Uses as are mentioned in several Letters Pattents under the great Seale of England bearing Date on or about the
Twentieth Day of February One thousand six hundred eighty five and the Twenty third day of May One thousand
six hundred and ninety but that the Moneys granted or settled by the said several ires Pattents shall according
to the Tenor thereof be duely paid and satisfied out of the several Branches of His Majesties Revenue yearely
charged therewith as if this Act had never been made Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. And for Annuity to the Duchess of Cleveland.</head>
			<para id="p70">Provided neverthelesse That nothing in this present Act shall be taken or construed to take away or interrupt
the Payment of one Annuity or yearely Su[m]m of Foure thousand seven hundred Pounds due and made payable
out of the Profitts ariseing out of the said Post-Office unto the most Noble Barbara Dutchesse of Cleveland or to
her Trustees named in certaine Letters Patents bearing Date the Nineteenth Day of January in the twentieth Yeare
of the Reigne of His late Majesty King Charles the Second and confirmed afterwards by an Act of Parliament made
in the Two and twentieth and Three and twentieth Yeares of the said King but that the same shall remaine
payable unto her or her said Trustees or to any other Person or Persons lawfully claiming under her them or any
of them according to the Directions and true Intent and Meaning of the said Letters Patents Any thing in this
present Act to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Notes in Writing of Gauge left by Gauger with Brewer.</head>
			<para id="p71">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p72">Provided neverthelesse and be it enacted That true Notes in Writing of every Gauge made or taken signed
by the Gaugers containing the Inches and Tenths of the Backs and Wants of the Tuns and the Quality of the said
Liquors respectively shall be left by them with all Co[m]mon Brewers of Beer or Ale or some one of their Servants
(if demanded) att the time of the taking their said Gauges on paine to forfeit for every Neglect or Refusal
the Su[m]m of Forty Shillings with Costs of Suit to be recovered in any of His Majesties Courts of Record att
Westminster by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information wherein no Priveledge or Wager of Law shall be allowed
nor any more than one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. Recital of c. I. ante, &sect;11.</head>
			<para id="p73">
				<emph type="i">Corporation of Moneyers refusing, &amp;c. to make and mark into Money Silver Plate as herein mentioned; Proceedings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p74">And whereas by an Act of Parliament passed this present Sessions intituled An Act for remedying the ill State
of the Coyne of the Kingdom Itt is (amongst other things) enacted That in regard the small Pieces of the New
Moneys to be coyned will be most useful in Co[m]merce that from and after the Fourth day of February One thousand
six hundred ninety five the Master and Worker of His Majesties Mint for the time being shall upon every [Hundred<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]
Pound Weight Troy of Sterling Silver to be coyned from the Clipt Money pursuant to the direction of that Act
from time to time cause att least Forty Pounds Weight Troy to be coined into Shillings and Ten Pounds
Weight Troy to be coined into Sixpences besides the other Coins which hee is to make out of the same pursuant
to the Indenture of the Mint And that in case the Master and Worker of the Mint shall omitt so to do hee
shall forfeit for every such Offence Twenty Pounds the one Moiety thereof to His Majesty the other Moiety thereof
to the Informer to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information wherein no Wager of Law Protection
Privilege Imparlance or Essoigne shall be allowed And forasmuch as the Penalty for not making the several Species
of Money in Quantity in the said Act directed is wholly and onely laid on the Master and Worker of the Mint
whose part is onely to deliver cleane Silver Plates to the Corporation of Monyers from which the said Corporation
are to make and mark the said Moneys for which they by Indenture of the said Mint are to have Nine Pence
Halfe-penny per Pound Weight Troy for all such Silver made into Moneys and One Penny per Pound Weight
Troy more for [the<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] better and more exact seizing and making the Money Now for the more speedy and effectual
Coining of the said Money into the several Species pursuant to the said Act of Parliament Be it enacted by
the Authority aforesaid That if the said Corporation of Monyers (being from time to time supplyed with sufficient
Clean Silver Plates by the Master and Worker for the making the several Species aforesaid) shall refuse or neglect
to make and mark the same into Moneys of the several Species in the said Act directed att the Prices aforesaid
or shall not imploy so many Men and Horses as shall be sufficient to keep all the Ten Mills (when furnished)
from time to time in full Work for Twenty Hours in each Day That then in both or either of the said Cases it
shall and may be lawfull for the Master and Worker of the Mint for the time being to use and imploy such
and so many other Persons and so many Horses and pay them for the making doeing and performing of the
said Work as shall be necessary and to him shall seem needfull Any Usage Claime or Contract or any other
Matter which shall or may be pretended by the said Corporation of Monyers to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">made and drawn <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Gauger or Officer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">friend <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">their<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


