<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46831" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIV. An Act requireing the Practicers of Law to take the Oaths and subscribe the Declaration therein mentioned. [Rot. Parl. 7 &amp; 8 Gul. III.p.5.n.10].</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Persons acting as herein mentioned, without having taken the Oaths of 1 W. &amp; M. c. 8. and made and subscribed the Declaration of 25 Car. II. c. 2.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Premunire 16 R. II. c. 5</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the better Security of His Majesties Government and the Publick Peace of this Kingdome Bee itt enacted
by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall
and the Commons in this Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That if any Person att any tyme
after the Five and twentieth Day of May which shall bee in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
ninety six shall act as a Serjeant att Law Counsellor att Law Barrister Advocate Attorney Solicitor Proctor Clerke
or Notary by practiseing in any manner as such in any Court or Courts whatsoever not haveing before the tyme
of such acting taken in His Majesties Court of Chancery or Kings Bench or Quarter Sessions of the County wherein hee
lives the Oaths mentioned and appointed to bee taken in and by one Act made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of
King William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for the abrogateing of the Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy and
appointing other Oaths and made and subscribed the Declaration appointed to bee made and subscribed in and by
one Act made in the Five and twentieth Yeare of the Reigne of King Charles the Second intituled An Act for
preventing Dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants such Persons shall incurre all the Paines Penalties and
Forfeitures mentioned in the Statute of Provision and Premunire made in the Sixteenth Yeare of the Reigne of King
Richard the Second.</para>
	</section>
</report>


