<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46841" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXIV. An Act that the Solemne Affirmation &amp; Declaration of the People called Quakers shall be accepted instead of an Oath in the usual Forme. [Rot. Parl. 7 &amp; 8 Gul. III. p.9. n.3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Quakers, instead of Oath, to make Affirmation in the following Form.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">To have the Effect of an Oath</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas divers Dissenters co[m]monly called Quakers refusing to take an Oath in Courts of Justice and other
Places are frequently imprisoned and their Estates sequestred by Processe of Contempt issuing out of such
Courts to the Ruine of themselves and Families For Remedy thereof Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent
Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal &amp; Co[m]mons in this present
Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the Fourth Day of May which shall
be in the Yeare of oure Lord One thousand six hundred ninety six every Quaker within this Kingdome of England
Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed who shall be required upon any lawfull Occasion to take
an Oath in any Case where by Law an Oath is required shall instead of the usual Forme be permitted to make
his or her Solemne Affirmation or Declarac[i]on in these Words following. (viz<emph type="p">t</emph>)</para>
		<para id="p3">I A.B. do declare in the Presence of Almighty God the Witnesse of the Truth of what I say.</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">To have the Effect of an Oath.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p5">Which said Solemne Affirmation or Declaration shall be adjudged and taken and is hereby enacted and declared to
be of the same Force &amp; Effect to all Intents and Purposes in all Courts of Justice and other Places where by
Law an Oath is required within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed
as if such Quaker had taken an Oath in the usual Forme.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. False Affirmation to incur the Penalty of Perjury.</head>
			<para id="p6">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Quaker making such Solemne Affirmation or
Declaration shall be lawfully convicted wilfully falsly and corruptly to have affirmed or declared any Matter or
Thing which if the same had been in the usual Forme would have amounted to wilfull and corrupt Perjury every
such Quaker so offending shall incurr the same Penalties and Forfeitures as by the Laws &amp; Statutes of this Realme
are enacted against Persons convicted of wilfull and corrupt Perjury.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Quaker refusing to pay Tithe, upon Complaint, Two Justices, unless either of them be Patron or interested, may proceed.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Appeal to Quarter Sessions.; In what Case Costs against Appellant.; No Certiorari, &amp;c. except where Title of Tithes in Question</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And whereas by Reason of a pretended scruple of Conscience Quakers do refuse to pay Tythes and Church
Rates Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That where any Quaker shall refuse to pay or Compound for his
great or small Tythes or to pay any Church Rates itt shall and may be lawful to and for the Two next Justices
of Peace of the same County (other then such Justice of the Peace as is Patron of the Church or Chapel whence
the said Tythes do or shall arise or any ways interested in the said Tythes) upon the Complaint of any Parson
Vicar Farmer or Proprietor of Tythes Churchwarden or Churchwardens who ought to have receive or collect the
same by Warrant under their Hands and Seals to convene before them such Quaker or Quakers neglecting or
refuseing to pay or compound for the same and to examine upon Oath which Oath the said Justices are hereby
impowered to administer or in such Manner as by this Act is provided the Truth and Justice of the said Complaint
and to ascertaine &amp; state what is due and payable by such Quaker or Quakers to the Party or Parties complaining
and by Order under their Hands and Seales to direct and appoint the Payment thereof so as the Su[m]m Ordered as
aforesaid do not exceed Ten Pounds And upon refusal by such Quaker or Quakers to pay according to such Order
Itt shall and may be lawfull to and for any one of the said Justices by Warrant under his Hand or Seal to levy
the Money thereby ordered to be paid by Distresse &amp; Sale of the Goods of such Offender his Executors or
Administrators rendring onely the Overplus to him her or them necessary Charges of distraining being thereout
first deducted and allowed by the said Justice And any Person finding him her or themselves agrieved by any
Judgement given by such Two Justices of the Peace shall and may appeal to the next General Quarter Sessions
to be held for the County Riding City Liberty or Towne Corporate And the Justices of the Peace there present
or the major Part of them shall proceed finally to heare and determine the Matter and to reverse the said Judgement
if they shall see cause And if the Justices then present or the major part of them shall find cause to continue the
Judgement given by the first Two Justices of the Peace they shall then decree the same by Order of Sessions
and shall alsoe proceed to give such Costs against the Appellant to be levied by Distresse and Sale of [the Goods
and Chattells of the said Appellant as to them shall seem Just &amp; reasonable And no Proceedings or Judgement
had or to be had by virtue of this Act shall be removed or superseded by any Writt of Certiorari or other
Writt out of His Majesties Courts att Westm[inster] or any other Court whatsoever unlesse the Title of such Tythes
shall be in Question.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. No Distress until Appeal determined.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided always that in case any such Appeal be made as aforesaid no Warrant of Distresse shall be granted
until after such Appeal be determined.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Quaker not to give Evidence in Criminal Causes, or bear Office, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided and be it enacted That no Quaker or reputed Quaker shall by virtue of this Act be qualified or
permitted to give Evidence in any Criminal Causes or serve on any Juries or beare any Office or Place of Profitt
in the Government Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Continuance of Act.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided that this Act shall continue in force for the space of Seven yeares and from thence to the end of
the next Session of Parliament, and no longer.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


