<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46846" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXIX. An Act for encourageing the Linen Manufacture of Ireland and bringing Flax and Hemp into and the making of Sail Cloth in this Kingdome.[Rot. Parl. 7 &amp; 8 Gul.III.p.9.n.8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Natives of England and Ireland may import into England from Ireland, Hemp, Thread, Yarn, &amp;c. free from Duty on Certificate as herein mentioned; and on Oath by Master, &amp;c. of Identity of Goods</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas there are great Su[m]ms of Money and Bullion yearely exported out of this Kingdome for the
purchasing of Hemp Flax and Linen and (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) the Productions thereof which might in great measure be prevented
by being supplied from Ireland if such proper Encouragement were given as might invite Forreigne Protestants into
that Kingdome to settle Be it therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice
and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal &amp; Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the
Authority of the same That from and after the First day of August One thousand six hundred ninety six it shall
and may be lawfull to and for any Native or Natives of England or Ireland to import into England directly from
Ireland any Sorts of Hemp or Flax and all the Production thereof as Thread Yarne and Linen of the Growth
and Manufacture of Ireland free from all manner of Customes Duties and Impositions whatsoever the Master or
other Chief Officer of the Vessell so importing the same bringing with him or them a Certificate or Certificates
from the Chief Officer or Officers of the Port or Ports in Ireland where such Goods shall be putt on Board
expressing the Marks Number Tale or Weight of the Species in each Bale or Parcell mentioned in the Bill or
Bills of Lading with the Name or Names Place or Places of Aboad of the Exporter or Exporters from Ireland and
the Name or Names Place or Places of Aboad of such other Person or Persons that shall have sworne the Goods
therein mentioned to be bona fide of the Growth and Manufacture of the Kingdome without Fraud or Covin and
where and to whom in England consigned and also the Master or Masters Chief Officer or Officers of the said
Shipp or Shipps Vessell or Vessells on Arrival in England making Oath that the said Bales (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Parcells and
Goods therein contained are the said Bales Parcells and Goods taken on Board by virtue of the said Certificate
or Certificates so to be produced Any Act Custome or Usage hertofore to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">English-made Sail Cloth may be exported Duty free, on Oath, as herein mentioned.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And for as much as the making of Sail Cloth in England is of great Use and Benefitt to the Nation &amp; will
employ many thousands of the Poor which Manufacture is already sett upp in several Parts of this Kingdome and
brought to good Perfection Be it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid That for the Encouragement of the
further Improvement of the same all English made Sail Cloth (upon due Proof upon Oath of its being made in
this Kingdome) shall from and after the First day of August One thousand six hundred ninety and six be exported
free from the Payment of all Custome and Duty whatever whether the same be exported in the Piece or Boult
or in Sails ready made Any Law Act or Statute to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">all <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">and <emph type="i">O</emph>
			</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


