<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46844" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXVII. An Act for the Encouragem[en]t of Charitable Gifts and Dispositions. [Rot. Parl. 7 &amp; 8 Gul.III.p.n.6].</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The King may grant Licences to alien, and hold in Mortmain</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas it would be a great hinderance to Learning and other good and charitable Works if p[er]sons well
inclined may not be permitted to found Colleges or Schools for Encouragement of Learning or to augment
the Revenues of Colleges or Schools already founded by granting Lands Tenements Rents or other Hereditaments
to such Colleges or Schools or to grant Lands or other Hereditaments to other Bodies Politick or Incorporated
now in being or hereafter to be incorporated for other good and publick Uses Be it therefore enacted by the
Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal &amp; Co[m]mons
in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That it shall and may be lawfull to and
for the King our most gracious Sovereigne Lord and for His Heires and Successors when and as often and in
such cases as His Majesty His Heires or Successors shall think fitt to grant to any Person or Persons Bodies
Politick or Corporate their Heires and Successors Licence to aliene in Mortmaine and also to purchase acquire take
and hold in Mortmaine in Perpetuity or otherwise any Lands Tenements Rents or Hereditaments whatsoever of
whomsoever the same shall be holden.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.Lands so aliened or acquired not forfeited</head>
			<para id="p3">And it is hereby declared That Lands Tenements Rents or Hereditaments so aliened or acquired and licensed
shall not be subject to any Forfeiture for or by reason of such Alienation or Acquisition.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


