<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46843" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXVI. An Act for continuing several Acts of Parliament. therein mentioned.[Rot. Parl. 7 &amp; 8 Gul.III.p.9.n.5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>19 &amp; 20 Car. II. c.10. continued by 1 Jac. II. c. 13. and revived and continued by I W.&amp; M.c.23.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">further continued for 7 Years, &amp;c. from 25th March 1696</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas diverse temporary Laws which by Experience have been found useful and beneficial are near
expiring therefore for continuing the same Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with
the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal &amp; Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and
by the Authority of the same That an Act made in the Twentieth yeare of the Reigne of King Charles the Second
intituled An Act for giving Liberty to buy and export Leather and Skinns tanned and dressed which Act was
revived by an Act made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of the late King James which Acts were revived &amp;
continued by an Act made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of King William and the late Queen Mary intituled
An Act for reviving Two former Acts for exporting of Leather for the space of Seven Yeares from the end of
that Sessions of Parliament and from thence to the end of the First Session of Parliament then next ensuring shall
be and are hereby continued and shall be in Force dureing the space of Seven Yeares from the Five and twentieth
day of March in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety six and from thence to the end of
the First Session of Parliament then next ensuing and no longer.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. 16 &amp; 17. Car.II. c. 2. revived and continued by 2 W.&amp;M. Sess. 2. c.7.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">made perpetual</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further, enacted by the Authority aforesaid That an Act made in the Sixteenth &amp; Seventeenth Yeares
of the Reigne of King Charles the Second intituled An Act for regulating the Measures and Prices of Coals
which Act was revived &amp; continued by an Act made in the Second Yeare of the Reigne of King William and the
late Queen Mary intituled An Act for reviving a former Acts for regulating the Measures' &amp; Prices of Coals from
the First Day of December One thousand six hundred and ninety for the space of Seven Yeares and from thence
to the end of the First Session of Parliament then next following shall be and are by virtue of this Act continued
and shall be in force and be made perpetual.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III.4 W.&amp; M. c.20. continued by 6 &amp; 7 W.&amp;M.c.14.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">made perpetual</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That an Act made in the Session of Parliament held in
the Fourth &amp; Fifth Yeares of the Reigne of King William and the late Queen Mary entituled An Act for the
better Discovery of Judgements in the Courts of Kings Bench Co[m]mon Pleas and Exchequer att Westm? which Act
was continued by an Act made in the Sixth and Seventh Yeares of the said King and late Queen entituled An
Act for continuing several Laws therein mentioned for one Yeare from the Twenty fifth day of March One thousand
six hundred ninety foure and from thence to the End of the then next Session of Parliament shall be and are by
virtue of this Act continued and shall be in force and [be<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] made perpetual.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. 4 W&amp;.M. c.22.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">made perpetual</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That an Acts made in the Fourth and Fifth Yeares of
the Reigne of King William and the late Queen Mary entituled An Act for regulating Proceedings in the Crowne
Office of the Court of Kings Bench att Westm? which was to continue and be in Force for Three Yeares from
the Twenty fifth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety three and from thence to the end of the then
next Session of Parliament shall be and is hereby continued and shall be in Force and be made perpetual.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


