<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46848" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1695-6</title>
	<subtitle>THE TITLES OF THE PRIVATE ACTS.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>THE TITLES OF THE PRIVATE ACTS.</head>
		<para id="p1">i. An Act for enableing the Lady Katherine Fane to sell the Reversion of certaine Fee-Farme Rents given
her by her Grandfather John Bence Esq[uire].</para>
		<para id="p2">ii. An Act for enableing Sir Thomas Parkyns Baronett to sell certaine Messuages Lands and Hereditaments in
Huby and Easing Would in the County of York and the settling other Lands &amp; Hereditamens of greater Value
in lieu thereof.</para>
		<para id="p3">iii. An Act to enable Sir Thomas Pope Blount Baronett to make a Settlement upon the Marriage of his eldest Son.</para>
		<para id="p4">iiii. An Act for vesting the Manor of Madley in the County of Salop in Trustees for certaine Purposes therein
menc[i]oned.</para>
		<para id="p5">v. An Act for the enableing Thomas Stoner Esq[uire] Son and Heire of John Stoner Esq[uire] deceased to make a
Jointure and Settlement of his Estate in Marriage notwithstanding his Minority.</para>
		<para id="p6">vi. An Act for vesting several Messuages and Lands belonging to Samuel Powell Esquire in Trustees for
Payment of his Debts.</para>
		<para id="p7">vii. An Act to enable Anthony Earle of Kent and Henry Grey his Son and Heire Apparent make a Jointure for
to Jemima Wife of the said Henry Grey.</para>
		<para id="p8">viii. An Act to enable the Lord Francis Powlett to charge his Estate with Provisions for his younger Children.</para>
		<para id="p9">ix. An Act for vesting the Estate late of Sir Nicholas Stoughton and Sir Lawrence Stoughton Baronetts deceased
in Trustees to be sold for the payment of their Debts and raiseing Portions for the Daughters of the said, Sir
Nicholas Stoughton.</para>
		<para id="p10">x. An Act to enable Richard Haynes Esquire to settle a Joynture on his now Wife and to exchange Lands
with the Trustees of Thomas Stevens Esquire deceased.</para>
		<para id="p11">xi. An Act for enableing Trustees to sell part of the Estate of Edmond Warner deceased for payment of his
Debts and for preserving the rest for the benefitt of his Heire.</para>
		<para id="p12">xii. An Act to enable John Aunger an Infant and his Mother to make a Lease of his Estate for the Improvement
thereof.</para>
		<para id="p13">xiii. An Act to enable Trustees to sell part of the Manor of Barkhamstead and to pay of the Incumbrances charged
on the same and to lay out the Overplus in an Estate to be settled as the said Manor is now vested.</para>
		<para id="p14">xiv. An Act for naturalizing Henry de Nassau and other Children of Henry de Nassau Seignior de Auverquerke.</para>
		<para id="p15">xv. An Act to enable John Fownes Esquire to sell certaine Lands in the County of Devon which were settled
on his Marriage and to settle other Lands of an equal Value to the same uses.</para>
		<para id="p16">xvi. An Act to enable Trustees to exchange Lands of Sir James Chamberlaine Baronett and Infant lying in the
Co[m]mon Hill or Feild of Salford in the County of Oxford for like quantities of Lands there in order to the
making an Inclosure.</para>
		<para id="p17">xvii. An Act to enable the Parish of S<emph type="p">t</emph>. James within the Liberty of the City of Westminster to raise upon
themselves so much Money as will discharge their Debt for building their Parish Church Rectors House Vestry and
other Publick Works there.</para>
		<para id="p18">xviii. An Act to ascertaine and settle the Payment of the Impropriate Tythes of the Parish of St. Lawrence Old
Jury in London to the Master and Scholars of Balliol College in Oxford and for confirming an Award made
concerning the same.</para>
		<para id="p19">xix. An Act for naturalizeing James Stanhope Esquire and others.</para>
		<para id="p20">xx. An Act for naturalizing Salomon Eyme &amp; others.</para>
		<para id="p21">xxi. An Act to confirme &amp; establish and Exchange made between Thomas Rider Esquire and Christopher
Clitherow Esq[uire] of certaine Messuages in London for the Manors of Bilsington and other Lands in Kent of the like
Value.</para>
		<para id="p22">xxii. An Act to enable Trustees to fill upp Leases of the respective Estates of Bluet Wallop Esq[uire] and John
Wallop Gent[er] dureing theire Minorities and to Purchase other Lands by the Fines thereby to be received to the
same Uses as the Estates so to be leased are already settled.</para>
		<para id="p23">xxiii. An Act for enabling Trustees to sell the Mannor of Pespoole in the County of Durham part of the
Estate of William Midford and Infant for Payment of Debts and Incumbrances charged thereon and for preserving
the rest of the said Infants Estate.</para>
		<para id="p24">xxiiij An Act for impowering the most Noble Anne Dutchesse of Buccluch and the Right Honorable James
Earle of Dalkeith her Son of the Kingdome of Scotland to grant Leases for improving a Peece of Ground in the
Parish of Saint Martins in the Fields in the County of Middlesex.</para>
		<para id="p25">xxv. An Act to enable Trustees to raise Money for the making a Wett Dock and improving the Estate of the
Marquesse and Marchionesse of Tavistock att Rodderith in the County of Surrey.</para>
		<para id="p26">xxvi. An Act to naturalize William co[m]monly called Viscount Tunbridge and other Children of the Earle of Rochford.</para>
		<para id="p27">xxvii. An Act for the better Improvement of a House and Ground in Great Queen-Street.</para>
		<para id="p28">xxviii. An Act to enable Trustees to sell a Messuage Garden and Outhouse in Lincolnes-Inn Fields late Sir Robert
Sawyers Knight deceased and for purchasing other Lands and Tenements to be settled to the same Uses.</para>
		<para id="p29">xxix. An Act for settling divers Lands and Rent-Charge on the Rector of the Church of Maydwell in the County
of Northampton and his Successors and in lieu thereof for settling other Lands and dischargeing Tythes belonging
to the said Church according to several Agreements between the Patron and the said Rector made upon the
incloseing of Lands in Maydwell and afterwards with the Consent of the Ordinary confirmed by several Decrees
in the Court of Chancery.</para>
		<para id="p30">xxx. An Act for settling the Personal Estate of Richard Jones Esquire and Mary Gufford Spinster [Minors<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
in Trustees for the Purposes therein mentioned.</para>
		<para id="p31">xxxi. An Act for the better supplying the Citty of Bristoll with Fresh-Water.</para>
		<para id="p32">xxxii. An Act for erecting of Hospitals and Work-houses within the Citty of Bristoll for the better imploying and
maintaining the Poor thereof.</para>
		<para id="p33">xxxiii. An Act for making good the last Will of Sir William Barkham Baronett deceased and vesting of Lands
in Trustees to be sold for Payment of his Debts and making Provision for his Children.</para>
		<para id="p34">xxxiiij. An Act to enable Sir Charles Heron Baronett to sell Lands for Payment of a Portion and Debts.</para>
		<para id="p35">xxxv. An Act to enable Sir Thomas Wagstaffe Knight to raise &amp; secure a Portion for Frances his onely Daughter
and Heire Apparent.</para>
		<para id="p36">xxxvi. An Act for vesting the Moiety of the Manor of Shipton Mallett in the County of Somersett and divided
Moiety of the Manor of Wells in the said County in Trustees to be sold for Payment of a Mortgage charged
thereon and for making a Provision for the Maintenance of Mary the Wife of William Sandes Esq[uire] and her Children.</para>
		<para id="p37">xxxvii. An Act for makeing the Townes of Stretton and Princethorpe a separate Parish from Wolston in the
County of Warwick.</para>
		<para id="p38">xxxviii. An Act for vesting Part of the Estate of Joseph Dawson Esq[uire] in Trustees for Payment of Debts and for a
Provision for the Maintenance and Marriage of his Daughters.</para>
		<para id="p39">xxxix. An Act for sale of Lands in Horsington in the County of Somersett part of the Estate of William Ridout
an Infant for Payment of Incumbrances charged thereon and for preserving the Residue of the said Estate for the Infant.</para>
		<para id="p40">xxxx. An Act for vesting certaine Lands of Thomas Bigg and his Wife in Chislett in the County of Kent in
Trustees for Payment of Debts and making Provision for their Children.</para>
		<para id="p41">xxxxi. An Act for revesting in His Majesty the Honor of Tutbury Forrest of Needwood several Manors Parks
Lands and Offices and other Profitts thereunto belonging and for vacating certaine Letters Patents therein menc[i]oned.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>


