<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46851" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act to explain that part of the Act passed last Session of Parliament for laying several Duties on Low Wines &amp; Spirits of the first Extraction and for preventing the Frauds and Abuses of Brewers Distillers and other Persons chargeable with the Duties of Excise which relates to the Payment of Tallies &amp; the Interest thereof. [Rot. Parl. 8 &amp; 9 Gul. III. p. 1. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 7 &amp; 8 W.III. c.30.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">&sect;33. &sect;38; and that Doubts had arisen as to Payment of certain Tallies as herein mentioned; All Tallies of Pro, &amp;c. charged upon Excise, or upon weekly Payments thereout to be satisfied in course without undue Preference; Interest to be paid every Three Months; Tallies charged on the weekly Revenue of the Post Office, to be paid in like Manner; Penalty on Officers offending</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in and by one Act made and passed in the Parliament holden att Westminster in the Seventh and
Eighth Yeares of his Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for laying several Duties upon Low Wines or
Spirits of the first Extraction and for preventing the Frauds and Abuses of Brewers Distillers and other Persons
chargeable with the Duties of Excise itt was (amongst other things) enacted That weekly and every Week from
and after the Twentieth Day of April One thousand six hundred and ninety six the Su[m]m of Six thousand Pounds
out of the particular Branches or Duties of Excise therein mentioned which are co[m]monly called The Hereditary
and Temporary Excise or either of them should be paid and applied and is thereby appropriated to and for the
Payment and Satisfaction of such Tallies of Pro or Assignement or other Tallies as in the said Act were mentioned
to be already levied and to be then remaining unsatisfied on the said particular Branches of Excise or either of
them and the Interest thereof not exceeding the Rate of Six Pounds per Centum per An[n]um until the same should
be paid off and that from and after the full Satisfaction thereof the like weekly Su[m]m should be paid and applied
and is thereby appropriated to and for the Repayment and Satisfaction of such further Su[m]ms not exceeding Foure
hundred thousand pounds as by or upon the Creditt of that Act should be borrowed or charged thereupon and
such Interest for the same as is therein mentioned so as that the Tallies for the principal Su[m]ms respectively should
be paid in course according to their respective Dates until the same should be fully discharged and paid off and
the Interest upon every such Talley should be paid every Three Months until the Satisfaction of the Principal And
it was thereby further enacted That weekly and every Week from and after the said Twentieth Day of April the
Su[m]m of Six hundred pounds out of the Revenue of the General Letter Office or Post-Office should be paid and
applied and is thereby appropriated for payment of such Tallies of Pro or Assignment or other Tallies as in the
said Act were menc[i]oned to be already levied and to be then remaining unsatisfied on that Revenue and the
Interest thereof not exceding the rate of Six pounds per Centum per Annum until the same should be fully paid
off and from and after the Satisfaction thereof then the like weekly Su[m]m out of that Office is to be paid and
applied for Satisfaction of such further Su[m]ms not exceeding Forty five thousand pounds as by or upon the Creditt
of that Act should be borrowed or charged thereupon with Interest as is therein mentioned so as that the Tallies
for the principal Su[m]ms respectively should be paid in course according to their respective Dates until the same
should be fully discharged and paid off and the Interest upon every such Talley should be paid every Three
Months until Satisfaction of the Principal as by the said Act more largely appeares. And whereas some Doubts
have arisen whether several of the Tallies which were levied upon the said respective Branches of Revenues between
the Two and Twentieth Day of November One thousand six hundred ninety five being the First Day of the
Session in which the said Act passed and the Foure and twentieth Day of June One thousaud six hundred ninety
six can or may be paid out of the same Revenues appropriated by the said Act in course according to their
respective Dates in regard they were not levied before the said Two and Twentieth Day of November One thousand
six hundred ninety five or by virtue of the said Act or upon the weekly Su[m]ms thereby appropriated and whether
the Interest of the said Tallies levied between the Two and twentieth Day of November One thousand six hundred
ninety five and the said Foure and twentieth Day of June and the Interest of the Tallies levied or to be levied
for the said Su[m]m not exceeding Foure hundred thousand pounds can or may be paid out of the said Six thousand
pounds a Week first mentioned in and appropriated by the said Act until the Tallies levied before the said Two
and twentieth Day of November One thousand six hundred ninety five and the Interest thereof shall be paid
and discharged. For the obviating and clearing of which Doubts and for the better Explanation of the said Act
of Parliament in relation to the payment of the said several Tallies and the Interest thereof Be it enacted by the
Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice &amp; Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and
Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That all the Tallies of Pro or
other Tallies which have been levied and are charged upon the said Hereditary and Temporary Excise or either
of them or upon the said weekly Su[m]ms of Six thousand pounds payable thereout shall be duely paid and satisfied
in course according to their respective Dates and not otherwise out of all the weekly Su[m]ms of Six thousand
pounds a Week appropriated as aforesaid until they shall be fully satisfied without giving any undue Preference
by paying any Talley or Tallies of subsequent Date or Dates before Tallies of preceding Date or Dates unlesse
in Cases where Money is reserved for payment of the p[re]ceding Tallies according to the true intent and meaning
of the said Act and that the Interest of all the said Tallies in course shall be paid and payable every Three
Months out of all the said weekly Su[m]ms of Six thousand pounds a Week and that all the Tallies of Pro or
other Tallies which have been levied and are charged upon the said Revenue of the Post-Office or upon the said
weekly Su[m]m of Six hundred pounds appropriated thereout shall be in like manner duely paid and satisfied in
course according to their respective Dates and not otherwise out of the said weekely Summs of Six hundred
pounds a Week appropriated as aforesaid until they shall be fully satisfied and without giving auy undue p[re]ference
as aforesaid and that the Interest of the Tallies last mentioned shall be likewise paid and payable every Three
Months out of all the said weekly Su[m]ms of Six hundred pounds a Week and that for any Offence or Neglect in
not duely paying the Principal and Interest or any Part thereof or giving any undue p[re]ference contrary to the true
meaning of this Act the respective Com[m]missioners or other Officers or Persons who shall be guilty thereof shall
incurr the same Penalties or Forfeitures as by the said recited Act are prescribed in the like Case or Cases for
any such Offence Any thing in this or the said recited Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
</report>


