<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46852" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IV. An Act to attaint Sir John Fenwick Baronett of High Treason. [Rot. Parl. 8&amp;9 Gul.III.p.1.nu.4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Sir John Fenwick attainted of High Treason, and to suffer Death, &amp;c</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas Sir John Fenwick Baronett was upon the Oaths of George Porter Esquire and Cardell Goodman
Gentleman att the Sessions of Oyer and Terminer held for the City of London on the Eight and twentieth
Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety six indicted of High Treason in compassing and imagining the
Death and Destruction of his Majesty and adhering to his Majesties Enemies by consulting and agreeing with
several Persons (whereof some have been already attainted and others not yett brought to their Tryal for the said
Treasons) att several Meetings to send Robert Charnock since attainted and executed for High Treason in conspiring
to assassinate his Majesties sacred Person. (whom God long p[re]serve) to the late King James in France to incite and
incourage the French King to invade this Kingdome with an armed Force by promising to joyn with and assist
him with Men and Arms upon such Invasion Of which Treasons the said Sir John Fenwick is guilty And whereas
the said Sir John Fenwick did obtaine his Majesties Favour to have his Tryal delayed from time to time upon
his (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) an ingenious and full Confession of his knowledge of any Designe or Conspiracy against his Majesties Person
or Government and of the Persons therein concerned And whereas hee has so farr abused his Majesties great Mercy
and Indulgence therein that instead of making such Confession hee hath contrived and framed false and scandalous
Papers as his Informations reflecting on the Fidelity of several Noble Peers divers Members of the House of
Co[m]mons and others onely by Hearsay and contriving thereby to undermine the Government and create Jealousies
between the King and his Subjects and to stiffle the real Conspiracy And whereas Cardell Goodman one of the
Witnesses against the said Sir John Fenwick to prove the said Treason lately and since the several times appointed
for the Tryal of the said Sir John Fenwick att one of which times the said Sir John Fenwick had been accordingly
tryed had it not been for the expectation of the said Discoveries so often promised by him is withdrawn so that
the said Cardell Goodman cannot bee hadd to give Evidence upon any Tryal Be it enacted by the Kings most
Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Com[m]ons in
this Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That the said Sir John Fenwick be and is hereby
convicted and attainted of High Treason and shall suffer the pains of Death and incurr all Forfeitures as a Person
attainted of High Treason.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">An Erasure on the Roll, leaving a Space sufficient for the Words "repeated Promises of making," which are in the Original Act.</note>
	</section>
</report>


