<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46855" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act for granting to His Majesty several Duties upon Paper Vellum and Parchment to encourage the bringing of Plate and ha[m]mered Money into the Mints to be coined [Rot. Parl. 8 &amp; 9 Gul.III.p.2.nu.1].</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Stat. 8 &amp; 9 W.III. c. 2. &sect; 1.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">&sect; 2; Duties upon Paper, &amp;c. made within the Kingdom for Two Years, from 1st March 1696, to be paid by Makers, and an ad valorem Duty upon Paper, &amp;c. imported, to be paid by Importers</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in and by one Act made and passed in this present Session of Parliament entituled An Act for
the further remedying the ill State of the Coine of the Kingdome Itt is amongst other things enacted
That all such ha[m]mered Silver Money clipped or unclipped as should be brought by any Person att any time
[before<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the Fourth Day of November One thousand six hundred ninety six and before the First Day of July
One thousand six hundred ninety seven unto any of His Majesties Mints shall be there received by the Officers
of His Majesties Mints att the Rate of Five Shillings and Foure Pence for every Ounce Troy of all such ha[m]mered
Silver And His Majesties Officers who are or may be concerned are thereby required (amongst other things) to
receive all such ha[m]mered Silver Coine as should be tendred to them for or upon any Loans att any time betweene
the Fourteenth day of November One thousand six hundred ninety six &amp; the First Day of February then next
ensuing att the Rate of Five Shillings and Eight Pence for every Ounce as is therein mentioned Now to the end
a Supply may be granted to Your Majesty as well for and towards the paying of the said Rate or Allowance
of Five Shillings and Foure Pence an Ounce for ha[m]mered Moneys as for making good the Deficiences of the
said Loans made or to be made in hamered Moneys occasioned by the recoining thereof as also for and towards
the paying such Rate or Allowance as is or shall be settled in Parliament for the Encouragement of those that
shall bring in Wrought Plate to be coined and for bearing the Wast and Charges [for<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] coining the said hammered
Money and Plate Wee Your Majesties most dutiful and loyal Subjects the Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled do
humbly present to Your Majesty the Impositions Rates and Duties herein after menc[i]oned and do beseech Your
Majesty that it may be enacted and be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice
and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and of the Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and
by Authority of the same That for and dureing the Terme of Two Yeares co[m]mencing from the First Day of
March One thousand six hundred ninety six there shall be raised levied collected and paid unto and for the
Use of His Majesty for and upon all Paper Pastboard Parchment &amp; Vellum which att any time or times within
or dureing the said Terme of Two Yeares shall be made or manufactured within this Kingdome of England Dominion
of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed or imported or brought into the same the several and respective
Impositions Rates and Duties herein after mentioned that is to say For all Paper White or Browne or of any other
Colour or Kind whatsoever and for all Vellum and Parchment of what Nature or Kind soever which att any time
or times within or dureing the said Terme of Two Yeares shall be made or manufactured within the Kingdome
Dominion or Towne aforesaid there shall be paid &amp; answered to His Majesty a Duty to be computed after the
Rate of Twenty Pounds for every One hundreds Pounds of the true and real Value of the same to be paid by
the respective Maker or Makers thereof And for all Paper White or Browne or of any other Colour or Kind
whatsoever and for all Pastboard Vellum and Parchment of what Nature or Kind soever and whether the same
be contained in Rolls Reams Quires Books printed or not printed or otherwise howsoever which att any time or
times within or dureing the said Terme of Two Yeares shall be imported or brought into the said Kingdome of
England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed there shall be paid by the respective Importer or
Importers thereof a Duty to be computed after the Rate of Five &amp; twenty Pounds for every Hundred Pounds of
the true and real Value of the same over and above all such Customs and Duties as are already payable for or
upon the Importation thereof.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Duties paid by Importer in ready Money or at Three Months.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Discount &pound;10 per Cent, for ready Money; Goods landed before Entry made and Duty paid, or Warrant had, forfeited</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Duties hereby sett on all the said Forreigne and
imported Co[m]modities before mentioned shall be from time to time satisfied and paid by the Importer or Importers
of the same in Ready Money upon his or their Entry or Entries made and before the Landing thereof or else
the said Importer shall give Security for Payment of the said Duty within Three Months time after the said
Entry [thereof<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] as aforesaid And in Case of Payment in Ready Money that there be allowed a Discount after
the Rate of Ten Pounds per Centum per Annum for the said Three Months And that in Case any such
Foreigne &amp; imported Co[m]modities of the kinds before mentioned shall be landed or putt on Shore out of any
Shipp or Vessell from beyond the Seas before due Entry be made thereof in the Custome House in the Port or
Place where the same shall be imported and the Duties hereby imposed shall be fully satisfied and paid or
without any Warrant for the landing and delivering of such imported Co[m]modities of the kinds aforesaid first
signed by the Co[m]missioners Collectors or other proper Officer or Officers of His Majesties Customs respectively
that all such imported Co[m]modities of the kinds aforesaid as shall be so landed or putt on Shore or taken out of
any Shipp or Vessell contrary to the true Intent and Meaning hereof or (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) Value of the same shall be forfeited and
lost and shall and may be recovered of the Importer or Proprietor thereof (to witt) one Moiety of the same to
the Use of His Majesty His Heires or Successors the other Moiety to the Use of him or them that will seize
the said Co[m]modities or sue for the same or the Value thereof by Action of Debt or of the Case Bill Suit or
Information wherein no Essoigne Protection Wager of Law or more than one Imparlance shall be granted or
allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Duties on imported Goods under Management of the Customs.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Value of Goods imported ascertained upon Oath of Merchant or Importer; Oath administered in the usual Form</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And it is hereby further enacted That the said Duties on such of the said Co[m]modities as shall be imported as
aforesaid shall be from time to time under the Management &amp; Government of the Co[m]missioners of His Majesties
Customs for the time being who shall cause the same from time to time to be raised levied collected and paid
by His Majesties Officers of the Customs to the Hands of the Receiver or Receivers General of the Revenue of
the Customes for the time being and such Receiver &amp; Receivers General for the time being shall answer and pay
the Moneys ariseing thereby (the necessary Charges of raiseing collecting and answering the same onely excepted)
into His Majesties [Receipt of<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Exchequer distinct and apart from all other Branches within his or their Receipt for
the purposes in this Act mentioned and that the respective Customer or Collector or other Person or Persons
Officer or Officers of the Customs for the time being shall receive &amp; levy the Duties of Five &amp; twenty Pounds
for every One hundred Pounds hereby imposed according to the true Value and Price of such Goods to be
esteemed upon the Oath of the Merchant or Importer And such Oath shall be administred and all other Matters
done for ascertaining recovering and levying the said Duties hereby granted upon the Values of the said imported
Co[m]modities in the same manner and forme as are now lawfully used and practised in Cases where Goods pay the
Subsidy of Poundage or other Duties ad valorem upon the Importation thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Treasury to appoint Commissioners or Surveyours for the said Duties on Paper, &amp;c. made in England, &amp;c. who may substitute Deputies, &amp;c; Commissioners may settle Orders, &amp;c. for Guidance of Officers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And for the better ascertaining the Duties by this Act charged and imposed upon such of the said Co[m]modities
of Paper Vellum and Parchment as shall be made [or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] manufactured in England Wales or Towne of Berwick as
aforesaid and for the better raiseing levying and collecting of the same according to the true Meaning of this
Act Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for His Majesty
His Heires or Successors or to and for the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury or any Three or more of them now
being or the High Treasurer of England of any Three or more of the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time
being in Writing to [constitute<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] and appoint such Co[m]missioners or Persons as they shall think fitt from time to time
to be the Co[m]missioners or Surveyors for the said Duties who shall hereby have Power to substitute Deputies or
inferiour Officers under them for the Purposes aforesaid and shall cause all the Moneys arising by the said Duties
(except the necessary Charge in managing or collecting of the same) to be brought and paid into the Receipt of
the Exchequer from time to time to the Uses in this Act mentioned And the said Co[m]missioners of the Treasury
or any Three or more of them now being or the High Treasurer of England or any Three or more of the
Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time being are hereby impowered from time to time to sett downe settle and
prescribe such Orders Rules and Instructions for the better Guidance of the said Officers or any of them in and
for the ascertaining charging &amp; collecting of the Duties hereby imposed or intended to be imposed upon the said
Co[m]modities manufactured in England Wales or Towne of Berwick aforesaid as shall be most conducing or agreeable
to the Ends and Intent of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. How Value of Goods made in England, &amp;c. estimated; in Case of Dispute as to Value, the same to be estimated by Affidavit of Maker.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">How Officer to proceed in case of apparent Fraud in such Affidavit</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And it is hereby declared &amp; enacted That the Values of all the said Co[m]modities made in England Wales or
the said Towne of Berwick or imported into the same shall in all Cases be taken to be so much as such Co[m]modity
shall be worth to be sold as soon as they are perfectly made or imported And in Case any Dispute or Controversie
shall att any time or times arise touching the Valuation of any such Co[m]modities between the Maker or Makers
thereof and His Majesties Officer or Officers (which said Officer and Officers are to be under such Orders and
Instructions as are before mentioned) in all and every such Case and Cases the Value of such Goods made in
England Wales or Towne of Berwick aforesaid shall be esteemed by the Affidavitt of such Maker or Makers
to be made in Writing before any of His Majesties Justices of the Peace who are hereby impowered and required
to take the same and to be delivered to the said Officer or Officers who shall thereupon have Power by this Act
if hee thinks His Majesty to be apparently defrauded by the Values sworne to by the Maker to take such Goods
att the Value specified in such Affidavitt paying downe Ready Money to the Maker for the same which Ready
Money so paid downe shall be allowed upon the Accompts to be made to His Majesty for the Duties aforesaid
and the Goods in such Cases shall be sold and disposed of for His Majesties best Advantage and Profitt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Before 25th March 1697 Makers to give Notice to Commissioner or Officer, of Manufactory, and Name and Place of Abode.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">The like on Change of Manufactory; Penalty &pound;20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And it is hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all and every the Maker or Makers of the
said Manufactures of Paper Parchment and other the said Co[m]modities or any of them shall before the Five and
twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety seven give Notice in Writing to some one or more
of the Co[m]missioners or Officers to be appoynted to manage or collect the said Duties or cause such Notice to be
left where such Co[m]missioners or Officers shall usually reside or execute his or their Trust of the Place or Places
where every such Person or Persons do usually make the Manufactures aforesaid with their Names and Places of
Abode respectively And that all and every such Maker or Makers as often as hee she or they shall change
their Places of working or making of Vellum Parchment or Paper and all and every Person &amp; Persons who
shall att any time or times hereafter be the Maker or Makers of any such Co[m]modities as aforesaid or any
of them shall give or leave the like Notice of their respective Names and Places of Abode and the Places
where they shall make or intend to make any such Parchment Paper or other the Co[m]modities, aforesaid before
they or any of them do presume to make the same in any such New Place or Places to the End the said
Co[m]missioners or other Officers(<ref idref="n7">7</ref>) from time to time have due Knowledge of all the Places where the said Goods
shall be made and be the better enabled to secure the Duties hereby granted thereupon And if any such Maker
or Makers shall neglect to give or leave such Notice as is required by this Act hee she or they shall for every
such Offence forfeit the Su[m]m of Twenty Pounds the one Moiety to His Majesty His Heires and Successors and the
other Moiety to him or them that shall sue for the same as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Places for drying, &amp;c. not to be used before Notice.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Makers to permit Officers to take Notice of Stock of Rags,; &amp;c; Entry to be made of Paper, &amp;c. within Five Days after drying, &amp;c. and before Removal, and Duty paid within Six Months; Penalty; Permit for Removal gratis; Allowance of &pound;10 per Cent. on prompt Payment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And the better to prevent any Frauds or Concealments whereby His Majesty His Heires or Successors may be
injured or deprived of His or their Dues according to the true Meanyng of this Act Be it further enacted That
the several Makers of Paper which shall be made dureing the Terme aforesaid shall use no Place for drying
the same or making it fitt for Use other than such Co[m]mon Place or Places whereof hee she or they first shall
have given Notice to the proper Officer of the said Duties to be the Place or Places for his her or their drying
or finishing the same And that the several Makers of Parchment or Vellum which shall be made dureing the
Terme aforesaid shall use no Pitts or Places for the preparing making drying or finishing the same other then
such Pitts or Places whereof hee shee or they shall first have given the like Notice to the proper Officer of the
said Duties to be the Pitts or Places for his her or their preparing making drying or finishing the same And
that the respective Makers of the said Paper Parchment or Vellum shall from time to time permitt &amp; suffer the
respective Officers of the said Duties who shall be thereunto appointed to take Notice of the Stock or Quantities
of their Skins Rags Stuffs or other Mat[er]ials for making of the said Vellum Parchment or Paper and of such
Vellum Parchment or Paper as they shall so make and of their Proceedings in making [and<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] converting the same
into Paper Parchment or Vellum and shall from time to time within Five Days after such Parchment Paper or
Vellum shall be dryed so as to be fitt for Use and before the Removal thereof make true Entry with His
Majesties Officer or Officers as shall be appointed to attend such Mills or Works respectively or give them true
Accounts in Writing of the several Quantities and Kinds of Parchment Paper or Vellum as shall be so by them
respectively made and att the time of making such Entries or within Six Months after shall pay His Majesties
Duties by this Act payable for the same and shall likewise have a Permission signed by some one of the said
Officers to carry away every or any Parcel of such Co[m]modities before such time as the same shall be removed or
carryed away from the Worke-house or other Place where such Goods shall be first putt after their being dryed
and fitt for Use under the several Penalties and Forfeitures herein after mentioned which Permitts the said Officers
are hereby required to give gratis unto the said Makers of such Paper Parchment or Vellum upon paying the
said Duty, hereby granted or securing the same to be paid within the said Six Months. And if any such Maker
or Makers att the time of such Entry shall pay down the Duty hereby, imposed hee she or they shall be allowed
for such Prompt Payment after the Rate of Ten Pounds per Cents per Annum upon every Su[m]m so to be paid
for the said time of Six Months.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Officers may search drying Goods.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Owner refusing Entrance; Penalty &pound;10; Maker using private Drying Rooms, &amp;c. or not making due Entries, or unduly removing, &amp;c; Penalty, &pound;50; and Goods forfeited</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawful for the said Officer or
Officers so to be appointed att all seasonable times in the day-time to search and see what Quantities of the said
Co[m]modities are making drying or finishing and to enter into any Mill Yard Drying-house Warehouse or other
House or Place where the same shall be making or be lodged And if any Owner or Occupier of any such Mill
Yard House Warehouse or Places aforesaid shall att any time or times refuse Entrance to the Officers as aforesaid
they shall for every such Refusal forfeit the Su[m]m of Ten Pounds the one Moiety thereof to the Use of His Majesty
His Heires and Successors &amp; the other Moiety thereof to the Use of him or them who shall sue for the same to
be recovered as aforesaid And if any Maker or Makers Owner or Owners of any of the said Co[m]modities of Paper
Parchment or Vellum shall endeavour to defraud His Majesty of any Duty by this Act payable by using any Private
Mill Pitt Drying-Roome or other Place for the making or finishing the same contrary to this Act or by not making
due Entries and giving an Account thereof as aforesaid or by removing or carrying away any such Co[m]modities
before the Duty be paid or secured and a Permission be given for carrying away such Goods as aforesaid or shall
fraudulently hide or conceal any of the said Co[m]modities to the intent to deceive His Majesty of His just Dues for
the same That then and in every such Case hee she or they so offending shall forfeit the Su[m]m of Fifty Pounds
(to witt) one Moiety thereof to the King and the other Moiety thereof to him or them that shall (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) for the same
to be recovered as aforesaid And moreover in all such Cases the said Co[m]modities which shall be found in any such
Private Mill Pitt Warehouse Drying Roome or other Place or for which no such Entry shall be made or that
shall be unlawfully removed or carried away without a Permission given or be fraudulently hidd or concealed shall
be forfeited &amp; shall and may be seized by any of the Officer or Officers aforesaid to His Majesties Use.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Duty to be paid for Stock in Hand on 1st March 1696.</head>
			<para id="p17">And whereas several Merchants Stationers Wholesale Sellers Retailers Paper-Makers and other Persons Bodies
Politick or Corporate have or may have on the First Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety six several
Stocks or Quantities of Paper Pastboards Vellum &amp; Parchment to be sold Be it further enacted by the Authority
aforesaid That all and every such Merchaunts Stationers Wholesale Sellers Retailers Paper-Makers &amp; other Persons.
Bodies Politick or Corporate on the said First Day of March having in his her or their Custody or Possession or
in the Custody or Possession of any other Person or Persons for his her or their Use Benefitt or Account any
Stock or Quantity of Paper Parchment Vellum or Pastboard within the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales
or Towne of Berwick upon Tween being for Sale shall yeild &amp; pay unto His Majesty for the same a Duty after
the Rate of Seventeen Pounds Ten Shillings to be computed upon every One hundred Pounds of the true and
real Value of all such Paper Pastboard Vellum and Parchment as the same shall be worth to be sold by them
respectively on the said First Day of March which said Duty of Seventeen Pounds Ten Shillings per Cents upon
the Value as aforesaid shall be answered and paid to His Majesty by the respective Merchants Stationers Wholesale
Sellers Retailers Paper Makers and other the Persons or Bodies Politicks or Corporate aforesaid within Ten Days
after the said First Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety six.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Paper Maker, &amp;c. to deliver to Officer a Particular in in Writing, signed, of Stock in Hand liable to Duty.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Officers may enter Shops, &amp;c. for the Purpose of receiving and comparing Valuation with the Goods; Refusing Entrance, Penalty &pound;20; If Officer is satisfied of Valuation, he is to collect the Duty; If such Duty not paid by 11th March 1696, or not secured; Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And to the end the said Stocks of Paper Parchments Vellum and Pastboards and the true Value thereof may
be knowne and discovered and the said Duty of Seventeen Pounds Ten Shillings [thereupon<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] thereupon may be
ascertained &amp; answered Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all and every the said Merchants
Stationers Wholesale Sellers Retailers Paper-Makers and others before mentioned shall deliver or cause to be delivered
to the proper Officer to be appointed as aforesaid a Particular in Writing signed by themselves or by their
Appointment of the whole Quantities Kinds and Values of the several Stocks of Paper Parchment Pastboard or
Vellum for which such Person or Persons respectively ought to be charged according to the true Intent and
Meaning of this Act And the said Officers to be appointed for that purpose where any such Stock of Goods shall
be or remain shall have Power and Authority and are hereby authorized and impowred to enter into any Shopps
Warehouses or other Places whatsoever where any such Goods shall be or remaine there to take an Account
thereof and to view the same &amp; if such Valuations be given in as aforesaid then to compare the said Goods
therewith And all and every the said Person or Persons chargeable as aforesaid for their Stock of Paper Parchment
Vellum and Pastboard shall be obliged by Force and Virtue of this Act (if thereunto required) to permitt and
suffer the said proper Officers of the District or Place to make such Entrance and View as aforesaid And if any
such Person or Persons shall refuse to permitt or suffer such Officer to enter in their Shops Warehouses or other
Places (if thereunto required as aforesaid there to view the said Stock as aforesaid or any part thereof) then every
such Person for such refusal shall forfeit the Su[m]m of Twenty Pounds One Moiety thereof to His Majesty and
the other Moiety to him or them that will sue for the same in the manner before mentioned And in case the
Officer or Officers so to be imployed shall be satisfied both as to the Quantities and Values of such Stock of
Paper Parchment Vellum and Pastboard for which any Person or Persons Bodies Politick or Corporate ought to
pay by this Act then the same Officer or Officers as shall be appointed in that behalfe shall p[ro]ceed to collect and
receive the said Duties after the Rate of Seventeene Pounds Ten Shillings per Cents upon the Value of such
Goods for which such Person or Persons Bodies Politick or Corporate shall be chargeable as aforesaid and uppon
receipt of any such Duties shall give Acquittances for the same gratis And in case such Duties be not paid by
the Eleaventh Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety six or if by that time the same be not secured
to be paid within Three Months then next ensuing (which Security the said Officers are hereby impowered to
take by Bonds in His Majesties Name and to His Majesties Use) then such Officer or Officers shall and may
by virtue of this Act levy such Duties that shall not be so paid or secured by Distresse of the Goods and
Chattells of the Person or Persons Bodies Politick or Corporate liable thereunto and for Nonpayment may sell such
Distresse within Five Days rendring the Overplus if any be to the Owner after Satisfaction of the Duty and Charges
of the said Distresse.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Allowance &pound;10 per Cent. on prompt Payment of Duty for Stock in Hand.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Valuation of Stock, in case of Dispute, estimated by Oath of Owners; In case of apparent Fraud; Proceedings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">Provided always That if any such Person or Persons Bodies Politick or Corporate Chargeable for such Stock
shall pay or cause to be paid his or their Duties the said Eleaventh Day of March One thousand six hundred
ninety six hee she or they shall be allowed for such prompt Payment after the Rate of Ten Pounds per Centum
per Annum for every Su[m]m so to be paid for the same time of Three Months But in case any Dispute or
Controversie shall arise touching the Valuation of any such Stock of Paper Parchment Vellum or Pastboard in all
such Cases the same shall be esteemed by the Oath of the Owner or Owners to be made and taken in Writing
before any of His Majesties Justices of Peace as aforesaid and to be delivered to the said Officer or Officers who
shall hereby have Power (if hee thinks the King to bee apparently defrauded thereby) to take such Goods att the
Value specified in such Affidavitt paying downe Ready Money to the Owner for the same which Ready Money
so paid downe shall be allowed upon the Accounts to be made to His Majesty for the Duties aforesaid And the
Goods in such Cases shall be sold and disposed of for His Majesties best Advantage and Profitt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Paper Makers, &amp;c. not giving particulars, &amp;c. of Stock in Hand, or omitting or concealing Stock,</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;50. and Goods omitted or concealed, &amp;c. forfeited</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in case any of the said Merchants Stationers Wholesale
Sellers Retaylers Paper-Makers or other Person or Persons Bodies Politick or Corporate having on the said First
Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety six in his or their Custody or Possession or in the Custody or
Possession of any other Person or Persons for his her or their Use Benefitt or Account any Stock or Quantity
of Paper Parchm[en]t Vellum or Pastboard shall neglect to give a Particular and Valuation of the same to the proper
Officer or Officers on or before the Fifth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety six or shall wittingly
or willingly omitt or leave out of the same any part of his said Stock to the intent to defraud His Majesty or shall
remove or carry away or conceal any part of his said Stock before His Majesties Duties thereupon shall be paid
or secured as aforesaid that then and in every such Case hee she or they so offending for every such Offence
shall forfeit the Su[m]m of Fifty Pounds to witt one Moiety thereof to the King and the other Moiety thereof to
him or them that will sue for the same as aforesaid And in all &amp; every such Case and Cases the Paper Parchm[en]t.
Vellum or Pastboard for which no such Particular or Valuation shall have been given or which shall be fraudulently
o[m]mitted out of the same or which shall be so concealed or carried away before His Maj[es]ties. Duties shall be paid
or secured shall be forfeited and shall and may be seized by any of the Officer or Officers aforesaid to His
Majesties Use.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Information of Seizure to be laid within Eight Days before Two Justices.</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">Appeal to Quarter Sessions; Final</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And it is hereby enacted That in all Cases where any Paper Parchment Vellum or Pastboard shall be seized for
any Offence against this Act and an Information thereof shall be layed by the Officer or a Complaint made by the
Owner within Eight Days after the Seizure before any Two or more of His Majesties Justices of the Peace of the
same County Riding or Place where such Seizure shall be made the Cause of every such Seizure shall and may
be heard and determined by such Justices of the Peace who have hereby Power to su[m]mon and examine Witnesses
upon Oath concerning the same And if either Party shall think himselfe or herselfe agrieved or remaine unsatisfied
in the Judgment of the said Justices Then hee she or they shall and may by virtue of this Act complaine or
Appeal to His Majesties Justices of the Peace in the next General Quarter Sessions for that County Riding or Place
who are hereby impowered to su[m]mon and examine Witnesses upon Oath for that Purpose and finally to heare
and determine the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. No Fee for Entries, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p26">Provided always and it is hereby enacted That no Fee or Reward shall be had or taken by any of the said
Officers from any of the said Makers or others for the Entries Accompts or Permissions aforesaid or any of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Repayment of Duties on Exportation, on Oath that Duties have been paid, and Security not to reland.</head>
			<para id="p27">Provided also That if any person or persons shall export beyond the Seas for Sale any of the said Co[m]modities
by this Act charged as aforesaid that then upon Oath made that the Duties first due [and<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] payable to His Majesty
for the same by this Act were duely paid or secured expressing the Su[m]m paid or secured and by whom and upon
Security to be first given that the Goods shall not be relanded in England Wales or Towne of Berwick aforesaid
(which Oath shall and may be administred and the (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Security taken by the Customer or Comptroller of the Port
where such Exportation shall be had) the Duties which by this Act shall have been payd or secured for such
of the said Co[m]modities so exported shall be repaid (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) so much shall be discharged upon the Security before given
for the same Any thing in this Act before mentioned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Loan of &pound;125,000 at &pound;8 per Cent. per Ann.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Tallies of Loan; Orders registered in course; No Fee for any Master relating to Loan; Officer offending; Deputies offending</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">And to the intent that Moneys may the more speedily be raised for the Ends and Purposes in this Act mentioned
Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That itt shall and may be lawfull to and for any Person or
Persons Bodies Politick or Corporate Natives or Foreigners to advance and lend to His Majesty upon the Security
of this Act any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money not exceeding the Su[m]m of One hundred twenty five thousand Pounds
and to have and receive Interest for the Forbearance thereof not exceeding Eight Pounds per Centum per Annum
and that no Money so to be lent shall be rated or assessed to any Tax or Assessment whatsoever And that the
Auditor of the Receipt of Exchequer shall keep one Book in which all Moneys coming into the said Receipt for
the said Duties upon Paper Parchment or other Duties by this Act granted shall be distinctly entred and registred
and the Lenders shall according to the Course of Exchequer have Tallies of Loan and Orders of Repayment
bearing such Interest as aforesaid which Interest shall be paid every Three Months until Satisfaction of the Principal
And the said Orders shall be registred in Course according to the Dates of the Tallies without any undue Preference
And all and every Person and Persons shall be paid the Principal in Course according to the Dates of their
Tallies And all the Money coming in by this Act shall in the same Order be liable to the Satisfaction of the
Parties their Executors Administrators or Assigns without any undue Preference and shall not be diverted to any
other Use Intent or Purpose whatsoever And that no Fee Reward or Gratuity directly or indirectly shall be
demanded or taken for any Matter or Thing relating to the said Loans And if any Officer shall offend by
diverting or misapplying the Moneys or giving any undue Preference in point of registry or Payment or by taking
any Fee Reward or Gratuity hee shall forfeit his Place and any Deputy or Clerk offending therein without Direction
[or Privity<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] of his Master shall forfeit double the Value of the Money so diverted or misapplied demanded or
taken to the Party grieved.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p30">Provided always That if several Tallies of Loan or Orders for Payment beare Date or be brought the same
Day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be registred then it shall be interpreted no undue Preference which of
those [he enters<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] first so hee enters them all the same Day.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded, no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Orders.</head>
			<para id="p31">Provided also That it shall not be interpreted any undue Preferrence to incurr any Penalty in point of Payment
if the Auditor direct and the Clerk of the Pells Record and the Tellers do pay subsequent Orders of Persons
that come and demand their Moneys and bring their Order in their Course so as there may be so much Money
reserved as will satisfie precedent Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon
Loan being to cease from the time the Money is so reserved and kept in Bank for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Orders for Payment of Money lent may be assigned by Indorsement.</head>
			<para id="p32">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee; Assignee may in like Manner assign</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p33">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Person or Persons to whom any Money shall
be due by virtue of this Act after Order entred in the Book of Register as aforesaid for Payment thereof his
Executors Administrators or Assigns by Indorsment of his Order may Assigne and transfer his Right Title Interest
and Benefitt of such Order or any part thereof to any other Which being notified in the Office of the Auditor
of Receipt aforesaid and an Entry or Memorial thereof also made in the Book of Register aforesaid for Orders
which the Officers shall upon request without Fee or Charge accordingly make shall intitle such Assignee his
Executors Administrators [or<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Assignes to the Benefitt thereof and Payment thereon And such Assignee may in like
manner assigne againe and so toties quoties and afterwards it shall not be in the power of such Person or Persons
who have or hath made such Assignements to make void release and Discharge the same or any the Monies
thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. 8 &amp; 9 W. III. c. 2. &sect; 1.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Master and Worker of the Mint to receive hammered Silver Money at the Rate of 58. 4d. per Ounce, and to weigh and compute the same; Duty of Officers at the Mint; Receipt to Persons bringing Silver; Charges of Recoining, &amp;c. how defrayed; New Money delivered at the aforesaid Rate</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">And to the end all the hammered Silver Money clipped or unclipped as pursuant to the said Act of Parliament
for further remedying the ill state of the Coin of the Kingdome may or might be brought by any Person att any
time after the Fourth Day of November One thousand six hundred ninety six and before the First Day of July
One thousand six hundred ninety seven unto any of His Majesties Mints to be there received att the Rate of
Five Shillings and Foure Pence per Ounce may be regularly received and entred and be recoined and that the
Partie or Parties bringing the same may duly receive and be satisfied after the Rate of Five Shillings and Foure
Pence in lawfull English Moneys for every Ounce so brought in Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That
the Master and Worker of His Majesties Mints now being or that hereafter shall be or his sufficient Deputy or
Deputies in this behalfe appointed or to be appointed (for whom hee will be answerable) shall duely receive the
said hammered Silver Moneys so brought att the said Rate of Five Shillings and Foure Pence an Ounce taking
Care in receiving the same to separate and cutt in Pieces all Base or Counterfeit Moneys and to returne such
Pieces to the Bringers thereof and shall weigh such Silver hammered Moneys and exactly compute the same att
the Rate last mentioned And the p[ro]per Officers or Clerks in the said several Mints to whom it appertains shall
cause Entries thereof to be made in their Day-Books according to the Ordinary Course which of late Yeares hath
been used in His Majesties Mint in the Tower of London for entring Silver in Course taking Care in such Entries
to specifie the Names of the Person or Persons bringing such hammered Money the Day or Time of bringing the
same the Weight or Quantity brought and the Amount thereof att the Rate aforesaid And the said Master and
Worker his Deputy or Deputies shall give to the Party or Parties bringing such Silver a Receipt in Writing
specifying all the Particulars last mentioned And that the proper Officers of the respective Mints shall new coin
such hammered Moneys into the the lawfull Coins of this Realme And the said Master and Worker his Deputy
or Deputies by or with the new Moneys proceeding therefrom with the helpe of such [new<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Moneys as shall be
raised and imprested to him by virtue of this Act shall not onely defray the necessary Charges of Receiving melting
downe refining and recoining the said hammered Monies so brought att Five Shillings and Foure Pence an Ounce
and the Wast incident thereunto but shall also pay back to all and every Person and persons bringing in such
hammered Money so much in new or milled Money as the said Rate or Allowance of Five Shillings and Foure
Pence an Ounce for his her or their hammered Money shall amount to in such due Course and Order as are
herein after mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. 8 &amp; 9 W. III. c. 2. &sect;. 6.</head>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">Master and Worker of the Mint to receive hammered Money of Collectors of Taxes, &amp;c; Entries thereof in Day Books; To give Collector a Receipt; Officers of the Mint to new coin hammered Monies and pay back new Monies; Collectors to pay the same into the Exchequer; Allowance to Collectors of Deficiency by recoining</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">And whereas by the aforesaid Act it is amongst other things enacted That all Money that should be brought in
upon the Account of Taxes or Revenues att Five Shillings and Eight Pence per Ounce according to that Act shall
be by the respective Receivers General or Collector carried to the next adjacent Mint in order to be recoined
And that the said Taxes and Revenues shall not be brought into His Majesties Exchequer till recoined Now to
the end that all the hammered Silver Monies which are or shall be received for Taxes or Revenues within the
respective times by the said Act limitted att the said Rate of Five Shillings and Eight Pence an Ounce and are
or shall be carried by the said Receivers General or Collectors to the next adjacent Mint may be regularly
received recoined delivered back applied answered &amp; accounted for Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid
That the said Master and Worker of His Majesties Mints his Deputy or Deputies shall duely receive the said
hammered Silver Moneys of the said Taxes or Revenues taking care in receiving the same to separate and cutt
in peeces all Base or Counterfeit Moneys and to returne such Pieces to the Bringers thereof and shall weigh such
Silver hammered Moneys and exactly compute the same att the said Rate of Five Shillings and Eight Pence an
Ounce And that the proper Officers or Clerks in the said several Mints to whom it appertains shall cause Entries
thereof to be made in their Day Books according to the ordinary Course of the Mint specifying the Names of the
respective Receivers General or Collectors bringing such hammered Money the Day or Time of bringing the same
the Weight &amp; Quantity brought and the Amount thereof att the said Rate of Five Shillings and Eight Pence per
Ounce and the Revenue or Tax to which it belongs And the said Master and Worker his Deputy or Deputyes
shall give to such Receiver or Collector bringing such Silver a Receipt in Writing specifying all the Particulars
last mentioned and shall cause the said Silver to be melted essayed and reduced to Standard and the Standard
Weight thereof to be fairely entred in the Books of the Mint And that the proper Officers of the respective
Mints shall new coin such hammered Moneys into the lawfull Coins of this Realme And the said Master &amp;
Worker his Deputy or Deputies shall pay back all the new Moneys proceeding from the Silver of the said Revenues
or Taxes except the necessary Charge of receiving melting downe refining and coining the same and the Waste
thereunto incident unto the respective Receivers or Collectors who brought such Revenues or Taxes to the Mint
And the said Receivers or Collectors are hereby strictly enjoyned and required upon the Receipt of such new
Money to answer or pay the same into the Receipt of His Majesties Exchequer upon the several Heads of Revenues
or Taxes whereunto it doth belong or otherwise as the Law directs and carefully to observe all Appropriations which
have been made by any Act or Acts of Parliam[en]t concerning the same or any Part thereof And that all and every
such Receivors General and Collectors in their respective Accompts to His Majesty shall be allowed the Deficiency
occasioned by the recoining the said ha[m]mered Money of the said Revenues or Taxes that is to say the difference
betweene the Su[m]m of the hammered Money brought into the Mint computed att Five Shillings and Eight Pence
an Ounce and the Su[m]m in Tail of the new Money which hee or they doe receive back from the Mint for
the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Master and Worker of the Mint in paying back Monies to observe the late established Course.</head>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">Officer, &amp;c. offending; Forfeiture of Officer; Incapacity; Deputy offending; Treble Damages and Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">And it is hereby further enacted That the said Master and Worker of the Mints his Deputy or Deputies in
paying back the said hammered Moneys as well those which shall be brought att Five Shillings and Foure Pence
an Ounce as those which shall be brought for Taxes or Revenues as aforesaid shall carefully observe the due
Course establisht or of late Yeares practised within His Majesties Mint in the Tower of London and shall not give
any undue Preference in Point of Entry or Payment but that all and every Person and Persons first bringing
their hammered Money shall have the same first entred and be first satisfied in the Course of Repayment And
in case any Officer of the Mint Receiver or Collector shall offend against this Act in any Matter or Thing
concerning the receiving entring or coining the said hammered Moneys or paying back new Money for the same
or in the answering or applying the said new Money in the Excheq[uer] or otherwise as the Law directs or by
diverting or misapplying any of the said Moneys then every such Officer Receiver or Collector shall forfeit his
Office and be forever incapable to serve His Majesty And moreover every such Officer of the Mint Receiver
or Collector his or their Deputies or Clerks offending in any the Matters aforesaid shall for every such Offence
forfeit Treble Damages to the Party grieved to be recovered by Action of Debt or of the Case besides Costes
of Suit.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Master and Worker may use the new Melting House at Westminster.</head>
			<para id="p40">Provided always and it is hereby enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Master and
Worker of His Majesties Mints by himselfe his Deputies or Servants for whom hee will be answerable to make
use of the Melting House newly erected neare the Receipt of the Exchequer att Westminister and the Utensils
thereof for the receiving melting and casting into Ingotts such hammered Monies as shall be brought to be recoined
att His Majesties Mint in the Tower of London Any things in this or the said other Act contained to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. In what Case Collector to pay hammered Money to Receiver General.</head>
			<para id="p41">Provided always and it is hereby enacted That in all Cases where any particular Collector is not required by
Law to pay his Receipt directly into the Exchequer but to the Hands of some Receiver or Receivers General
who are answerable for the same att the Receipt of the Exchequer such particular Collectors shall pay the hammered
Monies by them received to their respective Receivers General to carry the same to the next adjacent Mint as by
the said other Act is directed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Appropriation of Monies borrowed, and which shall arise by the said Duties, except so</head>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">much of the said Duties as are directed to repay the said Loan and Interest, Charges, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all the Monies which shall be borrowed as aforesaid
and which shall arise by the Duties hereby granted excepted so much of the said Duties as are hereby directed to
repay the said Loans and the Interest thereof and the necessary Charges of Collection and Management shall be
disposed and applied and the same are hereby appropriated for or towards the paying of the said Rate or
Allowance of Five Shillings and Foure Pence an Ounce for hammered Monies brought or to be brought in
pursuant to the said Act and for or towards the making Good of the said Deficiencies of the said Loans made or
to be made in hammered Monies pursuant to the said Act and for or towards the paying such Rate or Allowance
as is or shall be settled in Parliament for the Encouragement of those that bring in Wrought Plate to be coined
and for bearing the Waste and Charges of receiving in melting and coining the said hammered Money and Plate
and other necessary Expences of the Mints and shall not be diverted or misapplied to any other Use Intent or
Purpose whatsoever under the Paine of Double the Su[m]m so diverted or misapplied to be forfeited by any Officer
or Person who shall be Guilty thereof to any other Person or Persons who will sue for the same to be recovered
by Action of Debt or of the Case as is before menc[i]oned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Overplus of Duties after Payment of Charges and of the said Loan brought into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p44">Provided always That if more Money arise by the several Duties by this Act granted then shall be sufficient;
to pay the Su[m]m of One hundred twenty five thousand Pounds (over and above the necessary Charges of Collection)
for the Purposes in this Act mentioned and the Interest of the same or of so much thereof as shall be borrowed
by this Act That then the Overplus shall be brought into the Receipt of Exchequer and remained there without
being issued or disposed of but by Authority of Parliament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Recital of Advantages of making the best Writing Paper in this Kingdom; and that White Rags were used in making Brown Paper.</head>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">Using White Linen Rags for making Brown Paper, &amp;c; Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p46">And whereas the making the best and finest sorts of Writing Paper in England hath kept great Su[m]ms of Money
in this Kingdom which formerly were sent to France and other Forreigne Parts to buy the same and for as much as
there are made in this Kingdome White Linen Rags sufficient to make all sorts of Writing Paper not onely for
the Use of the Subjects of this Kingdome but likewise to export to Forreigne Parts beyond the Seas did not
many Persons beat upp and mingle such White Rags with Ropes Netts and Sail cloth for the making of Browne
Paper (<ref idref="n18">18</ref>) which may be made as well without the [Rags<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] to the great hindrance and discouragement of making
White Writing Paper in this Kingdome Be it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after
the Five and Twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety seven no Person or Persons whatsoever
within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed shall use or cause to
be used any White Linen Rags for making of Browne or Course Papers for making of any other sort of
Paper but such sorts of Paper onely as are generally deemed esteemed or taken to be and are co[m]monly called
or knowne by the Name of White Writing or Printing Paper And if any Person or Persons whatsoever shall
beat upp or cause to be beat up and used any White Linen Rags for making any sort or sorts of Paper
whatsoever except White Writing or Printing Paper as aforesaid such person or persons so offending shall for every
such Offence forfeit and pay the Su[m]m of Five Pounds One Moiety thereof to His Majesty His Heires and Successors
and the other Moiety thereof to such person or persons who shall prosecute, and sue for the same to be recovered
by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties Courts of Record wherein no Essoign
Protection Priveledge or Wager of Law shall be allowed or more than one Imparlance.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">after, <emph type="i">O</emph>. and King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">the O.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">commissionate <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">may <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">sue <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits, per Cent. in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">be entred, <emph type="i">O</emph>. and in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">"and other sorts of course Paper," <emph type="i">O</emph>. and in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">"White Rags," <emph type="i">O</emph>. and in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


