<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46853" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act to attaint such of the Persons concerned in the late horrid Conspiracy to assassinate His Majesties Royal Person who are fled from Justice unlesse they render themselves to Justice and for continuing several others of the said Conspirators in Custody. [Rot. Parl. 8 &amp; 9 Gul.III.p.1.nu.5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Conspirators Names</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Not rendering themselves by 25th March 1697; to be attainted of High Treason</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in the Months of January and February last there was a horrid and detestable Conspiracy
formed and carried on by Papists and other wicked and traiterous Persons to assassinate and destroy the
Royal Person of our most Gracious Sovereigne King William (whom God long preserve) which Conspiracy had
not God Almighty in his great Mercy prevented the Execution thereof had deprived these Kingdomes of the
enjoyment of their Liberties and Religion involved them in Blood and Ruine and subjected the People thereof to
the Bondage and Oppression of Popery and Tyranny for which execrable and bloody Treason several of the
Conspirators have been apprehended justly condemned &amp; executed and have upon their Deaths fully owned the
Truth of the Accusations against them and their being ingaged in the said wicked Conspiracy and several others
herein after named being charged upon Oath before one or more of his Majesties Justices of the Peace of having
been privy to and ingaged as principal Contrivers of and Actors in the said intended Assasination notwithstanding
several Proclamations issued against them have not rendred themselves nor have been yett apprehended but are fledd
from Justice Therefore to manifest the just Indignation Wee your Majesties most loyall Subjects the Lords Spiritual
&amp; Temporal and Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled have against so barbarous &amp; villanous a Designe and the great.
Tendernesse and Regard wee beare for the Preservation of your Majesties Royal Person and Government to whom
next under God wee owe the Recovery of our Religion and Liberties when they were so neare expiring under
the prevailing Influence of Popery and arbitrary Power and the continuance and enjoyment thereof att p[re]sent and
that none of the said Conspirators by flying from the ordinary course of Justice may escape Punishment which
would be to great an Incouragement to other wicked and rebellious Persons to enter into the like Conspiraces
hereafter do humbly beseech your Majesty that it may be enacted and be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent
Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Com[m]ons in Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same That if Sir George Barclay Knight Johnson ats Harrison
Durant ats Durance [Michael Hare<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Major George Holmes Phillipp Hanford ats Browne Richard
Richardson John Maxwell Bryerly Plowden Hungate shall not on or before the Five and
twentieth Day of March in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety seven render themselves to
the Lord Chief Justice of his Majesties Court of Kings Bench or to one of his Majesties Principal Secretaries of
State in order to their Tryals for the Treason aforesaid that then such of them the said Sir George Barclay Knight
Johnson ats Harrison Durant ats Durance Michael Hare Major George Holmes Philipp Hanford
alias Browne Richard Richardson John Maxwell Bryerly Plowden Hungate as shall not so
render him or themselves as aforesaid shall stand and be convicted and attainted and are hereby convicted and
attainted of High Treason and shall suffer the Pains of Death and incurr all Forfeitures Penalties and Disabilities
as Traytors convicted and attainted of High Treason.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Persons in Custody to be kept until 1st Jan. 1697, unless discharged by Privy Council.</head>
			<para id="p3">And whereas the Persons hereafter named videl[ie]t Counter John Bernardi Robert Cassells Robert Meldrum
James Chambers and Robert Blackbourne have been co[m]mitted and are still in Custody in Newgate for the said
Conspiracy and Treason Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Counter John Bernardi
Robert Cassells Robert Meldrum James Chambers and Robert Blackbourne and such other Persons who shall
hereafter render themselves or shall be apprehended and against whom there shall be Evidence upon Oath of their
being concerned in the said barbarous and bloody Conspiracy of assassinating the Person of his Sacred Majesty shall
be detained and kept in Custody without Bail or Mainprize until the First Day of January which shall be in the
Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety seven unlesse they shall be sooner bailed by Order of
Council signed by six of his Majesties most Honorable Privy Council.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


