<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46868" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XX. An Act for making good the Deficiences of several Funds therein mentioned and for enlargeing the Capital Stock of the Bank of England and for raising the Publick Creditt. [Rot. Parl. 8 &amp; 9 Gul. III. p. 5. nu.1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 4 W. &amp; M. c. 1. &sect; 54.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">6 &amp; 7 W. III. c. 3; 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 5. &sect; 69; 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 14.; 2 W. &amp; M. c. 4; and that the greatest Part of the Monies lent upon the said Aids had been paid off, but that there was a Deficiency to pay the Whole with Interest; Recital of 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 31.; &sect; 67.; &sect; 27; 
and that Persons who have advanced Monies therein mentioned may have Tallies that cannot in due Time be satisfied out of the said Duties; and that Persons have lent Money upon the Credit of 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 10.; 4 W. &amp; M. c. 5. &sect; 15.; 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 21. &sect; 15; 6 &amp; 7 W. &amp; M. c. 1; 6 &amp; 7 W. III. c. 3. &sect; 76; 6 &amp; 7 W. III. c. 6. &sect; 51; 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 10. &sect; 7; and that great Part of the Monies lent upon the Credit of the said Duties had been repaid with Interest, but that it was feared there would be a Deficiency to repay the Whole; and that Persons had lent Money upon the Credit 4 W. &amp; M. c. 15. &sect; 3.; 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 30.; 
&sect; 26.; 8 &amp; 9 W. III. c. 3.; and that by reason of the Deficiencies of the said Aids and the Remoteness of the Course of Payment of the Tallies, &amp;c. the Owners are frequently obliged to sell the same at Loss, and that the said Deficiencies amounted to the several Sum[m]s of Money herein mentioned.; 12 Car. II. c. 4; 6 &amp; 7 W. III. c. 7; Tunnage and Poundage continued till 1st Aug. 1706
</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas several Persons as well Natives as Forreigners Bodies Politick and Corporate did advance and
lend att the Receipt of His Majesty's Excheq[uer] very considerable Su[m]ms of Money upon the Security of the
several and respective Aids Revenues or Funds herein after mentioned that is to say upon the first Aid of Foure
shillings in the Pound payable out of Lands and other Things for One Yeare by virtue of an Act of Parliament
made and passed in the Fourth Yeare of the Reigne of His Majesty and the late Queen (of Blessed Memory)
whereby Interest not exceeding the Rate of Seven pounds per Cent[um] per Annum was allowed for the Su[m]ms
borrowed in pursuance thereof and upon the Third Aid of Foure shillings in the Pound payable out of Lands
and other Things for One Yeare by virtue of an Act of Parliament made and passed in the Sixth Yeare of His
Majesties Reigne whereby Interest not exceeding the Rate of Five pounds per Cent[um] per Annum was allowed for the
Sum[m]s thereby borrowed and upon the Fourth Aid of Foure shillings in the Pound payable out of Lands and other
Things for One Yeare by virtue of an Act of Parliament made and passed in the Seventh Year of His Majesties
Reigne whereby Interest not exceeding the Rate of Six pounds per Cent[um] per Annum is allowed for the Su[m]ms
borrowed in pursuance thereof and upon the Moneys which were to arise by an Act passed in the Parliament holden
att Westminster in the Fifth and Sixth Yeares of their said Majesties Reigne whereby a Poll was granted to their Majesties
payable quarterly for One Yeare which Moneys were directed to be applied to satisfie the Principal of such Loans
and upon the Moneys which were to arise by the Three fourth Parts of the Customs after Satisfaction of the Principal
and Interest of Five hundred thousand pounds charged thereupon by an Act of Parliament in the Second Yeare of
their said Majesties Reigne for which Loans so made and which were intended to be paid out of the Three fourths
of the Customes the Lenders were intituled to receive Interest after the Rate of Six pounds per Cent[um] per Annum And
whereas the greatest Part of the Moneys so lent upon the Aids Revenues or Funds before mentioned hath been
actually satisfied and paid off but the several Terms for which the said respective Aids of Foure shillings in the
Pound and the said Poll Money were granted being determined and expired and Three hundred thousand
pounds per Annum out of the Revenue of Customes being appropriated by Act of Parliament to the Satisfaction of
other Loans it doth plainly appeare that the several Aids and Funds herein before mentioned are deficient and
could not fully satisfie all the Moneys which were charged thereupon and the Interest thereof and for so much as
remaines unsatisfied the respective Lenders their Executors Administrators &amp; Assignes have or are intituled to have
in their Hands Tallies and Orders of Repayment levied and drawne according to the Forms used in His Majesties
Receipt of Excheq[uer] And whereas by an Act made and passed in the Parliament holden att Westminster in the
Seventh and Eighth Yeares of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for continuing to His Majesty certaine Duties
upon Salt glasse Wares stone &amp; earthen Wares and for granting several Duties upon Tobacco Pipes and other earthen
Wares for carrying on the Warr against France and for establishing a National Land Bank and for taking off the
Duties upon Tunnage of Ships and upon Coals His Majesty was impowered to borrow or take into the Receipt of
Excheq[uer] any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money either upon the Creditt of Repayment by Orders to be registred and paid in
course with Interest after the Rate of Seven pounds per Centum per Annum or upon Creditt of Bills to be made
payable upon Demand with Interest not exceeding the Rate of Three pence per Diem for every One hundred pounds
so as that the principal Su[m]ms which att any one Time should be due and owing either upon the said Orders or
upon the said Bills or both should not exceed the Su[m]m of Two millions five hundred sixty foure thousand pounds
and out of the Moneys to be raised by the Act last mentioned it was directed and intended that the Su[m]ms following
should be paid and applied that is to say the Su[m]m of Five hundred and sixty thousand Pounds to discharge Moneys
which were lent att the Receipt of Exchequer upon the Security of certain Duties upon glasse Wares stone and
earthen Bottles Coals and Culme (which Duties upon Coals and Culme were taken away by the Act last mentioned)
and the Interest thereof One hundred and fourty thousand pounds to answer and make good the Rates and Duties
of Tunnage upon Ships from the Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety [six until the Seventeenth
Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] seven (which Duties of Tunnage upon Ships was also taken away
by the said Act) and the further Su[m]m of One hundred and fourty thousand pounds to answer and make good the
Rates and Duties upon Salt from the said Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety six until the
said Seventeenth day of May One thousand six hundred ninety seven in the manner therein mentioned which said
several Su[m]ms of Five hundred and sixty thousand pounds One hundred and fourty thousand pounds &amp; One hundred
and fourty thousand pounds amounting in the whole to Eight hundred and fourty thousand pounds being taken or
subducted from the said Su[m]m of Two millions five hundred sixty foure thousand pounds the Remainder thereof
will amount to One million seven hundred twenty foure thousand pounds which is borrowed or may be borrowed
by His Majesty for the Service of the Warr against France and the Person or Persons who have advanced or shall
advance the same his her or their Executors Administrators or Assignes have or may have in their Hands Talleys
and Orders of Repaym[en]t or Bills for the Su[m]ms so advanced or to be advanced which cannot in any reasonable Time
be satisfied out of the said Duties chargeable therewith by the Act last mentioned And whereas several Persons
did advance and lend att the said Receipt of the Excheq[uer] several other Su[m]ms of Money att the Rate of Seven
pounds per Centum per Annum for Interest upon the Creditt of Two third Parts of the Excise of Eighteen pence
per Barrel and other additional Duties of Excise upon Beer Ale and other Liquors which were granted to their said
Majesties for Foure Yeares by an Act of Parliament in the Second Yeare of theire Reigne and afterwards continued
by a subsequent Act of Parliament in that behalfe until the Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred
ninety seven from which time the same or the like Duties of Excise are continued or granted by Act of Parliament
for other Uses And whereas several Persons as well Natives as Forreigners Bodies Politick and Corporate have also
advanced and lent att the said Receipt of the Exchequer very considerable Su[m]ms of Money upon the Security of
other Aids Supplies Impositions Revenues or Funds herein after mentioned that is to say upon certaine additional
Impostions upon several Goods and Merchandizes which were granted to their said Majesties by an Act passed in the
Parliament holden att Westminster in the Fourth &amp; Fifth Yeares of their Reigne to continue until the First Day
of March One thousand six hundred ninety six which Act allows Interest after the Rate of Eight pounds per
Centum per Annum for the Moneys thereby borrowed and upon certaine Duties payable for Vellum Parchment and
Paper for Foure Yeares which co[m]menced from the Twenty eighth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety
foure by virtue of an Act which passed in the Parliament holden att Westminster in the Fifth and Sixth Years of
the Reigne of their said Majesties whereby there was allowed Interest not exceeding the Rate of Eight pounds per
Centum per Annum for the Moneys lent in pursuance thereof and upon Creditt of a certaine yearely Su[m]m of Three
hundred thousand pounds payable for Five Yeares from the Five &amp; twentieth Day of December One thousand
six hundred ninety foure out of Moneys ariseing by the Subsidy of Tunnage and Poundage and other Duties upon
Merchandizes exported and imported by virtue of several Acts of Parliament passed in the Sixth Yeare of the
Reigne of their said Majesties wherein a Creditt was given for any Su[m]ms not exceeding One million two hundred and
fifty thousand pounds to be repaid with Interest not exceeding the Rate of Five pounds per Centum per Annum
for the First Three hundred thousand pounds Six pounds per Cent[um] per Annum for the Second Three hundred
thousand pounds Seven pounds per Cent[um] per Annum for the Third Three hundred thousand pounds and Eight
pounds per Cent[um] per Annum for the remaining Three hundred and fifty thousand pounds and upon Creditt of
an Act made in the Parliament holden att Westminster in the Sixth &amp; Seventh Yeares of His Majesties Reigne for
granting certaine Rates and Duties upon Marriages Births Burials Batchelors and Widdowers for the Terme of
Five Yeares from the First Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety five whereby Interest not exceeding
the Rate of Eight pounds per Cent[um] per Annum is allowed for the Su[m]ms lent in pursuance thereof and upon
the Creditt of several Impositions payable for Wines Vinegar Tobacco East-India Goods and other Merchandizes
imported continued until the Twenty ninth Day of September One thousand seven hundred and one by virtue
of an Act passed in the Parliament which was holden att Westminster in the Seventh and Eighth Yeares of his
Majesties Reigne whereby a Creditt was given for borrowing any Su[m]ms not exceeding One million five hundred
thousand pounds to be repaid with Interest not exceeding the Rate of Five pounds per Cent[um] per Annum for the
First Foure hundred thousand pounds Six pounds per Cent[um] per Annum for the Second Foure hundred thousand
pounds Seven pounds per Cent[um] per Annum for the Third Foure hundred thousand pounds and Eight pounds
per Cent[um] per Annum for the remaining Three hundred thousand pounds And whereas a great part of the
Moneys so lent upon the Two third Parts of the said additional Duties of Excise and upon the said additional
Impositions payable for Goods and Merchandizes and upon the said Duties payable for Vellum Parchment &amp; Paper
and upon the said Three hundred thousand pounds per Annum charged upon the Subsidy of Tunnage and
Poundage &amp; upon the said Duties charged upon Marriages Births Burials Batchelors and Widdowers and upon
the said continued Impositions payable for Wines Vinegar Tobacco East-India Goods and other Merchandizes
imported hath been actually repaid and satisfied with Interest but by computing the Product of these Duties for
the Time past and considering the Terms yett to come and unexpired in them respectively itt is supposed and
feared that the same Duties respectively att the end of the severall Terms for which they are granted as aforesaid
will be more or lesse deficient to answer pay off and cleare all the Principal &amp; Interest of the Moneys which
were authorized to be borrowed thereupon and the Persons intituled to the Moneys not paid off upon the Duties
last mentioned have or may have in their Hands Talleys and Orders of Repayment for the same And whereas
several Persons or Corporations did advance and lend att the said Receipt of Exchequer other considerable Su[m]ms
of Money upon the Creditt of an Act made in the Parliament holden att Westminster in the Fourth and Fifth
Yeares of their said Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for continuing certaine Acts therein mentioned and chargeing
several Joynt Stocks wherein a Creditt was given for the borrowing any Su[m]m not exceeding Five hundred thousand
pounds att Interest not exceeding Eight pounds per Centum per Annu? part of which Moneys doth still remaine
unsatisfied and the Persons intituled thereunto have likewise Tallies and Orders of Repayment for the same &amp;
pursuant to another Act made and passed in the Parliament holden att Westminster in the Seventh and Eighth
Yeares of His Majesties Reign intituled An Act for laying several Duties upon Low Wines or Spiritts of the first
Extraction and for preventing the Frauds and Abuses of Brewers Distillers &amp; other Persons chargeable with the Duties
of Excise several other Su[m]ms of Money have been lent to His Majesty not exceeding Seventy thousand pounds on
Credit of the Rates or Duties upon Low Wines or Spiritts of the first Extraction and Sweets thereby granted to
be repaid with Interest not exceeding the Rate of Six pounds per Centum per Annum for the first Forty thousand
pounds and Seven pounds per Centum per Annum for the Remainder thereof and by virtue of the same Act
and of another Act made and passed in this present Session of Parliam[en]t to explaine the same the weekely Su[m]m
of Six thousand pounds ariseing by or out of the Hereditary Branch of His Majesties Revenues of Excise upon
Beer Ale and other Liquors and by or out of that part of the said Revenues of Excise which is granted to his
Majesty during his Life (which God preserve) co[m]monly called The Hereditary and Temporary Excise and the
weekly Su[m]m of Six hundred pounds out of the Money or Revenue from time to time ariseing in the General
Letter Office or Post-Office do severally stand charged to pay off and satisfie in course several Tallies of Pro or
Assignement or other Tallies in those Acts mentioned for the Payment whereof Provision is thereby made together
with such several and respective Rates of Interest for the same as are thereby allowed And whereas by reason
of the Deficiences of several of the Aids Supplies Impositions and Duties above mentioned which have not or
will not be sufficient to answer the Principal and Interest charged thereupon and by reason of the Remoteness of
the Course of Payment of the Tallies and Orders charged upon some of them and upon other the Duties in this
Act before mentioned the Owners of the said Talleys or Orders are frequently necessitated to sell and dispose
thereof att great Losse or att an excessive Discount whereby the publick Creditt is very much prejudiced &amp;
impaired and the Trade and other publick and private Affaires within this Realme do exceedingly suffer And
whereas it is computed or estimated that the Deficiences or Su[m]ms which are or will be wanting to satisfie and
pay off all Principal and Interest due or to be due on the deficient Aids Duties or Funds before mentioned (over
and above all Arrears standing out upon any of them which are determined &amp; over and above all Monies to be
raised by such of them as are yett unexpired) do or may amount to the Su[m]ms following that is to say upon
the said First Aid of Foure Shillings in the Pound Fifty five thousand six hundred twenty two pounds ten shillings
and five pence upon the said Third Aid of Foure shillings in the Pound Foure hundred and seven thousand
three hundred seventy and two pounds and three pence upon the said Fourth Aid of Foure shillings in the Pound
Nine hundred and seventeen thousand one hundred and one pounds thirteen shillings and two pence halfe penny
upon the said quarterly Poll Eighty nine thousand two hundred seventy five pounds thirteen shillings and foure
pence upon the said Three fourth Parts of the Customes Two hundred and thirteen thousand foure hundred
forty seven pounds fifteene shillings &amp; nine pence upon the said Act chargeing Salt and other Things therein
mentioned One million seven hundred and eleven thousand and five hundred pounds upon the said Two third
Parts of the additional Excise One hundred and sixty thousand pounds upon the said additional Impositions payable
for Goods &amp; Merchandizes Foure hundred forty five thousand one hundred seventy seven pounds seven shillings
and foure pence upon the said Duties payable upon Vellum Parchment &amp; Paper Two hundred twenty-foure thousand
one hundred and fourteen pounds seven shillings eight pence halfe penny upon the said Duties charged upon
Marriages Births Burials Batchelors and Widdowers Six hundred forty and eight thousand pounds and upon the
said continued Impositions payable for Wine Vinegar Tobacco East-India Goods and other Merchandizes imported
One hundred forty six thousand one hundred eighty one pounds nineteene shillings and five pence halfe penny
and on the said yearely Su[m]m of Three hundred thousand pounds out of the Subsidy of Tunnage and Poundage
One hundred fourty two thousand six hundred sixty six pounds seven shillings three pence and three farthings
amounting in the whole to the Su[m]m of Five millions one hundred and sixty thousand foure hundred fifty and
nine pounds fourteen shillings nine pence one farthing Wee your Majesties most dutiful and loyal Subjects the
Co[m]mons of England in Parliament assembled having duely weighed and considered the Premisses and being desirous
to raise such Aids &amp; Supplies and to use such proper Methods as may make good the said Deficiences and
raise the publick Creditt have cheerfully and unanimously given and granted unto your Majesty the Supplies Impositions
and other Duties herein after mentioned for and dureing the respective Terms hereafter expressed and do beseech
your Majesty to accept thereof and that it may be enacted and be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty
by &amp; with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same That the Subsidy of Tunnage and Poundage and other Su[m]ms of
Money payable upon Merchandizes exported and imported which were given and granted unto his late Majesty
King Charles the Second for his Life by an Act of Parliament made in the Twelfth Yeare of his Reigne
intituled A Subsidy granted to the King of Tunnage and Poundage and other Su[m]ms of Money payable upon
Merchandizes exported &amp; imported and which by an Act of Parliament made in the Sixth Yeare of his Majesties
Reigne were granted and continued for the Terme of Five Years to co[m]mence on the Six and twentieth Day of
December One thousand six hundred ninety foure shall be continued to his Majesty from the Expiration of the
said Terme of Five Yeares until the First Day of August which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord one thousand
seven hundred and six and no longer and that the said Act made in the Twelfth Yeare of the Reigne of King
Charles the Second and every Article Rule and Clause therein mentioned and also an Order of the Co[m]mons in
Parliament assembled made in pursuance of the Rules and Orders annexed to the aforesaid Act for settling of
Officers Fees dated the Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred sixty two and signed by Sir Edward
Turner then Speaker shall be of full force and effect to all intents and purposes until the said First Day of August
One thousand seven hundred &amp; six as fully and in like manner as if the same were particularly and att large
recited and sett downe in the Body of this Act.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. 12 Car. II. c. 19.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">14 Car. II. c. II.; 22 Car. II. c. 13.; 25 Car. II. c. 6.; 25 Car. II. c. 7.; 1 Jac. II. c. 19.; 6 W. &amp; M. C. r</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That an Act of Parliament made in the Twelfth Yeare of
the Reigne of the said King Charles the Second (entituled An Act to prevent Frauds and Concealments of His
Majesties Customs and Subsidies) as also an Act made in the Foureteenth Yeare of the Reigne of the said late
King (entituled An Act for preventing Frauds and regulateing Abuses in his Majesties Customs) and also an Act
made in the Two and twentieth Yeare of the Reigne of the said late King Charles the Second (entituled An Act
for the Improvement of Tillage and the Breed of Cattle) and also one other Act made in the Five and twentieth
Yeare of the Reigne of the said late King Charles the Second (entituled An Act for taking off Aliens Duties upon
Co[m]modities of the Growth Product and Manufacture of the Nation) and also one other Act made in the said Five
and twentieth Yeare of the said late King Charles the Second (entituled An Act for the Encouragement of the
Greenland and Eastland Trades &amp; for the better securing the Plantation Trades) and also one other Act made in
the First Yeare of the late King James the Second (entituled An additional Act for the improvement of Tillage)
and all the Clauses and Directions whatsoever contained therein or in the said Act passed in the Sixth Yeare of
the Reigne of his Majesty and the said late Queen for granting to them the said Subsidy of Tunnage and Poundage
and other Su[m]ms of Money upon Merchandizes exported and imported be of full Force and Effect until the said
First Day of August which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and six.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Clauses in any of the said Acts intended to be perpetual.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Such as would otherwise determine, continued until 1st Aug. 1706</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">Provided neverthelesse and be it declared and enacted That nothing herein contained shall be construed or
taken to determine any Articles or Clauses in any of the last mentioned Acts hereby enacted to be in force until
the said First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six which were appointed and intended to be perpetual
or which are continued by any Act of Parliam[en]t. for any Time which will not expire by or before the said First
Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six but that the same and every of them shall continue and
remaine in force as if this present Act had not been made But such of the said Acts and such Clauses in any
of them as would otherwise determine before the said First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six
shall hereby be revived and stand continue and be in force until the said First Day of August One thousand
seven hundred and six and no longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Duties on Wines and Vinegar, by 1 Jac. II. c. 3. continued until 1st Aug. 1706;
and the said Act continued until 1st Aug. 1706.</head>
			<para id="p7">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the several Impositions and Duties upon Wines and
Vinegar granted by an Act made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of the late King James the Second entituled An
Act for granting to His Majesty and Imposition upon all Wines and Vinegar imported between the Twenty fourth
Day of June One thousand six hundred eighty five and the Twenty fourth Day of June One thousand six hundred
ninety three which said Act by several Acts of Parliament afterwards passed hath been continued and is to continue
until the Nine and twentieth Day of September One thousand seven hundred and one shall be continued from the
Eight and twentieth Day of September One thousand seven hundred and one until the First Day of August which
shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and six and no longer and that the said Act so
made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of the late King James the Second and all Powers Provisions Penalties Articles
and Clauses therein contained for or concerning the said Imposition on Wines and Vinegar shall continue and be of
full Force and Effect until the said First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six and shall be applied
practised and executed for the raising levying collecting answering and paying the said Duties upon Wine and
Vinegar hereby continued according to the Tenour and Intent of this present Acts as fully to all Intents &amp; Purposes
as if all and every the Clauses Matters and Things in the said Act of the First Yeare of King James the Second
contained had been again repeated in this Act and particularly enacted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. 1 Jac. II. c. 4. which was continued as to Tobacco only, continued until 1st Aug. 1706.</head>
			<para id="p8">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Rates Duties and Impositions upon all sorts of
Tobacco granted by an Act made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of the said late King James intituled An Act
for granting to His Majesty an Imposition upon all Tobacco and Sugar imported between the Foure &amp; twentieth
Day of June One thousand six hundred eighty five and the Foure &amp; twentieth Day of June One thousand six
hundred ninety three Which said Act as for and concerning the said Duties and Impositions upon Tobacco onely
was by several Acts of Parliament afterwards made continued and is to continue to the Nine and twentieth Day
of September One thousand seven hundred and one shall be continued from the Twenty eighth Day of September
One thousand seven hundred and one until the said First Day of August which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord
One thousand seven hundred and six and no longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Duty on Tobacco to be paid according to 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 10.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided always and be it enacted &amp; declared by the Authority aforesaid That the said Duty upon Tobacco
which shall be imported during the Terme hereby granted shall be secured collected raised levied answered and
paid to His Majesty in such Method and with such Discount and Allowancs and according to such Rules and
Directions as are mentioned referred to or prescribed as to the Duties or Impositions upon Tobacco in and by
the said Act made in the Parliament holden in the Seventh and Eighth Yeares of His Majesties Reigne (intituled
An Act for continuing several Duties granted by former Acts upon Wine and Vinegar and upon Tobacco and East
India Goods and other Merchandizes imported for carrying on the Warr against France) and not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Additional Duties on Goods and Merchandizes, by 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 4. continued until 1st Aug. 1706.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 4; (Exception) continued until 1st Aug. 1706; 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 10. continued until 1st Aug. 1706</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the several additional and other Rates Impositions
Duties and Charges upon the several sorts of Goods and Merchandizes granted by and Act made in the Second
Yeare of their said Majesties Reigne (intituled An Act for granting to their Majesties certaine Impositions upon all
East India Goods and Manufactures and upon all wrought Silks and several other Goods and Merchandizes to be
imported after the Five and twentieth Day of December One thousand six hundred and ninety) and which thereby
and by several other Acts afterwards passed were to have Continuance and are to continue until the Nine and
twentieth Day of September One thousand seven hundred and one shall be further continued from the Eight
and twentieth Day of September One thousand seven hundred and one until the said First Day of August which
shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seven hundred &amp; six and no longer And that the said Act
made in the Second Yeare of their said Majesties Reigne concerning East India Goods and other Things therein
charged and all Powers Provisions Penalties Articles &amp; Clauses therein contained shall continue and be of full
Force and Effect until the said First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six and shall be applied
practised and executed for the raising levying collecting answering &amp; paying the said respective Duties hereby
continued according to the Tenour and Intent of this present Act as fully to all Intents and Purposes as if the
said last mentioned Act and all and every the Clauses Matters and Things therein contained had been again
repeated and enacted particularly except onely as to such Part of the said Acts concerning the said Impositions on
Wines Vinegar Tobacco East-India Goods and other Merchandizes imported touching which other Provisions or
Alterations are made by any Act or Acts of Parliament now in being which other Provisions or Alterations are
to be observed and to continue dureing the Continuance of this Act and the said Act intituled An Act for continuing
several Duties granted by former Acts upon Wine and Vinegar and upon Tobacco and East India Goods and other
Merchandizes imported for carrying on the Warr against France and every Article Clause Matter and Thing therein
contained for the raising levying securing answering and paying the Impositions &amp; Duties on the Merchandizes and
Co[m]modities thereby charged and which are by this Act continued shall be of full Force and Effect until the said
First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Additional Impositions on Goods and Merchandizes, by 4 W. &amp; M. c. 5. and the said Act, continued until 1st Aug. 1706.</head>
			<para id="p12">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the additional and other Rates Duties Impositions
and Charges upon the several sorts of Goods and Merchandizes granted by an Act of Parliament made in the
Fourth and Fifth Yeares of their said Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for granting to their Majesties certaine
additional Imposic[i]ons upon several Goods and Merchandizes for prosecuting the present Warr against France and
which were thereby to have Continuance from the First Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety two to
the First Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety six shall be continued from the last Day of February.
One thousand six hundred ninety six to the said First Day of August which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord
One thousand seven hundred and six and no longer and that the said Act last mentioned &amp; all Powers Provisions
Penalties Articles and Clauses therein contained as herein after is excepted and provided as for and concerning the
said Rates Duties and Impositions shall continue and be of full Force and Effect until the said First Day of August
One thousand seven hundred and six and shall be applied practised and executed for the raising levying collecting
answering and paying the said Duties hereby continued according to the Tenour and Intent of this present Act
[as fully to all Intents and p<emph type="p">r</emph>poses<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] as if the said last mentioned Act and all and every the Clauses Matters and
Things therein contained had been again repeated and enacted in this Act particularly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. 4 W. &amp; M. c. 5. &sect; 1. Lapis Calaminaris exported, to pay only 2s. per Tun over and above the Rate in the Book of Rates.</head>
			<para id="p13">And whereas by the said Act passed in the Fourth Yeare of their Majesties Reigne for granting the said
additional Impositions on Goods and Merchandizes the Su[m]m of Twenty shillings is imposed on every Tun of
Lapis Calaminaris exported which was found by experience to hinder the Exportation thereof and utterly to ruine
the Manufacture itt is therefore hereby provided and enacted by the Authority aforesaid That for and dureing the
Continuance of the said additional Impositions the Su[m]m of Two shillings onely shall be paid for every Tun of
Lapis Calaminaris exported over and above the Rates thereon charged by the Book of Rates to be collected as in
and by the said Act is directed and appointed Any thing in this or the last mentioned Act contained to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Bar or hammered Iron (Exception) imported from Ireland discharged of the additional Duties.</head>
			<para id="p14">And whereas the Scarcity and Dearness of Iron in this Kingdome have of late much discouraged the Manufactures
thereof in which great Numbers of the Poor are imployed Be it therefore further provided and enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to import into this Kingdome from Ireland any Barr Iron
unwrought and Iron slitt or hamered into Rods (other than Swedish or other Forreigne Iron) discharged of the
Impositions and Duties laid upon the same by this or the said Act for granting the said additional Impositions
Any thing in this or the said Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Proviso for other Acts concerning the said Duties.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided also That in all Cases where any other Provision or Alteration is made by any Act or Acts of
Parliament now in being in or about any other Matter or Thing contained in the said Act of Parliament for the
Impositions last mentioned such other Provisions or Alterations shall be observed dureing the continuance of the
Terme hereby granted in the same Impositions Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 21.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Duties on Vellum, Parchment, and Paper, and the said Act continued until 1st Aug. 1706</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the several Rates and Duties granted to their said
Majesties by an Act made in the Fifth and Sixth Yeares of their Reigne intituled An Act for granting to their
Majesties several Duties upon Vellum Parchment and Paper for Foure Yeares towards carrying on the Warr against
France and which were thereby to commence from and after the Eight &amp; twentieth Day of June One thousand
six hundred ninety foure shall be and are hereby continued after the Expiration of the said Terme of Foure Yeares
until the First Day of August which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and six and
that the said Act and all Powers Provisions Articles and Clauses therein contained shall continue and be of full
force &amp; effect until the said First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six and shall be applied practised
and executed for the raiseing levying collecting answering and paying the said Duties hereby continued according
to the Tenour and Intent of this present Act as fully to all Intents and Purposes as if the said last mentioned Act
and all and every the Clauses Matters and Things therein contained had been again repeated and enacted in this
Act particularly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for other Acts concerning the said Duties.</head>
			<para id="p18">Provided always and it is hereby further enacted That in all Cases where any further or other Provision or
any Alteration is made by any other Act or Acts of Parliament now in being in relation to the said Duties upon
Vellum Parchment and Paper such other Provisions or Alterations shall be observed and complyed with dureing
the continuance of the Terme hereby granted in the same Duties Any thing herein contained to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Duties on Marriages, Births, and Burials, by 6 &amp; 7 W. 3. c. 6. continued until 1st Aug. 1706.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">How levied; and the said Act continued until 1st Aug. 1706</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Rates Duties Impositions and Su[m]ms of Money
granted to His Majesty by an Act passed in the Sixth and Seventh Yeares of His Reigne intituled An Act for
granting to His Majesty certaine Rates and Duties upon Marriages Births and Burials and upon Batchelors and
Widdowers for the Terme of Five Yeares for carrying on the Warr against France with Vigour and which were
thereby to co[m]mence from the First Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety five shall be and are hereby
continued from and after the Expiration of the said Terme of Five Yeares until the said First Day of August which
shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and six and no longer and shall be raised levied
collected answered and paid unto His Majesty in the same manner and forme and by such Rules Ways and
Meanes and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are mentioned in the same Act for raising levying collecting
answering and paying the same and which were thereby prescribed for the Foure last Yeares of the Terme thereby
granted and that the said recited Act last mentioned and every Article Rule and Clause therein mentioned as for
and concerning the said Rates Duties and Impositions shall continue and be in full Force to the said First Day of
August One thousand seven hundred and six as fully and amply as if the same were particularly recited expressed
and enacted in the Body of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Duties on Houses, by 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 18. continued until 1st Aug. 1706.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">How levied; and the said Act continued</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Rates Duties Impositions and Su[m]ms of Money
granted by an Act passed in the Seventh and Eighth Yeares of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for granting
to His Majesty several Rates or Duties on Houses for making good the Deficiency of the clipped Money and which
were thereby to continue for and dureing the Terme of Seven Yeares from the Five and twentieth Day of March
One thousand six hundred ninety six shall be and are hereby continued from and after the Expiration of the said
Terme of Seven Yeares until the said First Day of August which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand
seven hundred and six and no longer and shall be raised levied collected answered and paid unto His Majesty in
the same manner and forme and by such Rules Ways and Means and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are
mentioned in the same Act for raising collecting levying answering and paying the same and which were thereby
prescribed for the Six last Yeares of the Terme thereby granted and that the same Act and all Powers Provisions
Penalties Articles and Clauses therein contained shall continue and be of full force and effect until the said First
Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six and shall be applied practised and executed for the raising
levying collecting answering &amp; paying the said Duties tthereby continued according to the Tenour and Intent of
this present Act as fully to all intents and purposes as if all and every the Clauses Matters and Things in the
said Act contained had been again repeated in this Act &amp; p[ar]ticularly enacted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. The King may appoint Officers for surveying the Duties on Marriages, &amp;c. and for numbering Windows in Houses not assessed at 10s.; Officers to supervise the Registers of Marriages, &amp;c.; and with the Assistance of Constables, &amp;c. to view Houses not rated 10s; and to certify Under-ratings to the Commissioners, who are to cause the Rate to be set.
</head>
			<para id="p23">And for the better ascertaining and collecting the said several Rates and Duties upon Marriages Births and
Burials and upon Batchelors and Widdowers and the said several Rates and Duties upon Houses Be it enacted
That it shall and may be lawfull to and for his Majesty his Heires and Successors from and after the Five and
twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety and seven from time to time to give Directions for
constituting and appointing such Person or Persons as His Majesty His Heires &amp; Successors shall think meet to be
the Officer or Officers for the Survey and Inspection of the Rates and Duties ariseing upon Marriages Births and
Burials and upon Batchelors and Widdowers and of the Register or Registers of all such Marriages Births and
Burials within the several Counties of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed and also
of the Duties arising upon Houses within the same and for viewing and numbring the several Windows in each
House (not already assessed at the Rate of Ten shillings) and for the inspecting &amp; examining the Assessments or
Certificates thereof made and to be made from time to time in pursuance of the said Acts for granting the said
Rates or Duties or any other thing belonging to the same which Officers or any of them shall have full power
to examine and supervise the Register &amp; Registers of all Marriages Births &amp; Burials and of the Assessments of
the same and the Assessments of the Windows rated in every Parish and Place as aforesaid and to take Copy or
Copies or Extracts of such Register and Assessments and att seasonable times with a Constable Headborough
Tythingman or other Officers of the respective Parishes or Places within the several Counties of England Dominion
of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed who are hereby required to assist accordingly to view &amp; examine
whether there be any more Windows (in Houses not rated Ten shillings) than is certified and rated in such Assessment
and shall have liberty to make like View Examination and Inspection twice in the Yeare att the least dureing the
continuance of the said several Duties by this or the said former Acts for granting the same and if upon or
after such View or Examination and Inspection of the Registers and Assessments as aforesaid such Officer or Officers
shall find that any Person or Premisses are under-rated or not rated &amp; charged as by the said Acts or either of
them are directed and appointed such Officer or Officers shall certifie the same to the Co[m]missioners or any Two
or more of them within the Division Hundred Parish or Place wherein such Neglect or Failure shall happen to
be which said Co[m]missioners or any Two or more of them shall &amp; are hereby required to cause such Rate or
Rates to be sett upon every such Person and Premisses as shall be according to the true intent and meaning of
the said Acts and either of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Duty for Servants in Husbandry to be paid by the Master, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p24">And whereas Batchelors and Widdowers that are Servants in Husbandry by their frequent Removals are returned
as Fugitives and escape the Payment of the Duties to which they are liable by the said Act Be it further enacted
That the Duty or Duties wherewith such Servant or Servants shall be charged shall from time to time be paid
by the Master or Mistresse of such Servant and be deducted out of his her or their Wages Any thing in the said
Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. House inhabited by Two or more Families, to pay as one.</head>
			<para id="p25">And be it also enacted and declared That where any House shall be inhabited by Two or more Families such
House shall neverthesse be subject to and shall in like manner pay the Rates and Duties charged on Houses by
the said Act as if such House were inhabited by one Family only.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Edifices in Inns of Court, &amp;c. to pay for Windows as if an entire House.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">House committed to a Servant, to pay as if inhabited.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p27">And be it also enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid That every Edifice in any of the Inns of Court
or Chancery being severally in the Tenure or Occupation of any Person or Persons shall be subject to the same
Rates and Duties for the Number of Windows therein as if it were an intire House and every House whereof the
keeping onely is co[m]mitted or left to the Care or Charge of any Person or Servant who doth not pay to the
Church and Poor shall be subject to the like Rates &amp; Duties for the Windows therein as if it were inhabited
by the Occupier or by a Tenant and to be paid by the respective Occupiers or Tenants of the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Stock of the Bank of England to be enlarged by new Subscriptions.</head>
			<para id="p28">And for the better restoring of the Creditt of the Nation and advancing the Creditt of the Corporation of the
Governor and Company of the Bank of England Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the present Co[m]mon
Capital and Principal Stock of the said Governour and Company shall be augmented and enlarged by the voluntary
new Subscriptions of all such Person and Persons Natives and Foreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate who shall
be willing to subscribe any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money into the said present Co[m]mon Capital and Principal Stock and
to answer and make good the same in manner as herein after is appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI.</head>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">Stock of the Bank to be computed.; Old and new Members to settle the Capital Stock,; or else Lord Chancellor, &amp;c. to adjust the same before 24th Aug. 1697.; Capital Stock to be made up to &pound;1,200,000, and the Overplus divided amongst the old Members</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p30">And for the better settling and adjusting the Right and Property of each Member of the present Corporation of
the Governor and Company of the Bank of England before any such Enlargement as aforesaid be made thereunto
Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That before the Foure and twentieth Day of July One thousand
six hundred ninety seven the Co[m]mon Capital &amp; Principal Stock of the said Governour and Company shall be
computed and estimated by the Principal and Interest owing to them from the King or any others and by Cash or
by any other Effects whereof the said Capital Stock shall then really consist over and above the value of the
Debts which they shall owe att the same time for Principal or Interest to any other Person or Persons whatsoever
which Computation shall be made &amp; settled by Seven of the present Members of the said Corporation to be
elected for that purpose att the General Court of the old Members and by Seven of the new Subscribers to be
nominated and elected by the major part of such new Subscribers who are hereby authorized to meet att any time
within Ten Days after the Foure and twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety and seven to make
such Elecc[i]on And in case the said Members and Subscribers shall not settle the same before the said Foure and
twentieth Day of July One thousand six hundred ninety seven then the value of the said Capital Stock shall be
finally settled and adjusted by the Lord Keeper of the Great Seale of England or by the Lord Chancellor or
Co[m]missioners for the Custody of the Greate Seale of England for the time being who have hereby power to settle
and adjust the same att any time before the Foure and twentieth Day of August One thousand six hundred ninety
and seven and in case by such Settlement or Adjustment of the value of the said Stock it shall appeare that the
same doth not amount to Twelve hundred thousand pounds then the Members of the said Corporation being
Owners thereof shall and are hereby obliged at their owne proper Cost and Charge to contribute so much as will
compleatly make the said Capital Stock Twelve hundred thousand pounds which Contribution shall or may be
made either in their owne particular Tallies and Orders or in Bank Bills or Notes whereunto they shall be
respectively intituled and in case the Value of the said Capital Stock upon such Adjustment to be made shall
exceed Twelve hundred thousand pounds that then the Su[m]m so exceeding Twelve hundred thousand pounds be
divided amongst those who shall be the old Members of the said Corporation of the Governor &amp; Company of the
Bank of England according and in Proportion to their respective Interests att that time.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII.</head>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">The King may appoint Commissioners to take Subscriptions made on or before the 24th June 1697; Who, on or before 2d April 1697, are to prepare an Office for Subscriptions in London or Westminster, and to give Notice thereof.; Commissioners to provide Books for Subscriptions
</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p32">And for the better pursuing the End and Intent of this Act in taking the said Subscriptions and for the greater
Ease and Convenience of all his Majesties Subjects and others who shall be willing to make such Subscriptions Be
it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That such Persons as his Majesty shall appoint by Co[m]mission under the
Greate Seale of England or any Seven or more of them shall be and are hereby authorized and appointed to be
Co[m]missioners to take all such voluntary Subscriptions as shall be made on or before the Foure and twentieth Day
of June which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and seven by or for any Person
or Persons Natives or Forreigners or by or for any Body Politick or Corporate in the said Capital and Principal
Stock of the present Governor and Company of the Bank of England in manner as hereafter in this Act is appointed
Which Co[m]missioners are hereby ordered and directed on or before the Second Day of April One thousand six hundred
ninety &amp; seven to provide and prepare One or more convenient House or Houses within the Cities of London
and Westminster or One of them to be the publick Office or Place Officers or Places to which all or any Persons
shall or may resort for the making of the said Subscriptions and to give such publick Notice thereof as they the
said Co[m]missioners or any Seven or more of them shall think will most conduce to the promoting the said Subscriptions
and the said Co[m]missioners are hereby directed on or before the said Second Day of April to provide or cause to be
provided One or more Book or Books made of Vellum or Parchment for the said Subscriptions to be made therein
which Book or Books shall lie open every Day in the Week (Sundays only excepted) att the said publick Office
or Offices from the said Second Day of April to the said Foure and twentieth Day of June daily and from the
Houre of Eight to the Houre of Twelve in the Morning and from the Houre of Three to the Houre of Seven in
the Afternoon of each Day.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII.</head>
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">Any Persons may subscribe Money for inlarging the Capital Stock.; Subscriptions how to be answered and made good</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p34">And for the better encouraging the said Subscriptions to be made Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid
That from and after the[s?d<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Second Day of April it shall and may be lawfull to and for all and every Person
or Persons Natives or Forreigners Bodies Politick and Corporate by and for themselves or any of them or by themselves
or any of them in Trust for any other Person or Persons Bodies Politick or Corporate or any of them freely to
subscribe any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of money into the Capital and Principal Stock of the said present Governor and Company
in order to the augmenting and enlargeing thereof as aforesaid which said Subscriptions att the respective times of
making the same shall be answered and made good by the respective Subscribers thereof to the said Capital and
Principal Stock of the said present Governor &amp; Company in the Manner and Proportion following (that is to say)
Foure fifth Parts of each respective &amp; particular Subscription (the Value of the said whole Subscriptions into Five
equal Parts being divided) shall be answered and made good to the said Capital and Principal Stock of the said
present Governor and Company by assigning to them the Principal and Interest whereunto such Subscribers respectively
shall be then really intituled by Talleys of Loan and Orders of Repayment or by Talleys of Pro or Assignement
for Moneys which were lent or advanced or are or shall be charged as aforesaid upon some of the Aids Supplies
Revenues Impositions or other Funds herein after mentioned &amp; by delivering upp att the same time to the said
Governor and Company the Talleys and Orders so assigned that is to say Upon the said First Aid of Four shillings
in the Pound the said Third Aid of Foure shillings in the Pound the said Fourth Aid of Foure shillings in the Pound
the said quarterly Poll the said Three fourth Parts of the Customes the said Act for continuing the Duties upon
Salt and other Things or upon the said Two third Parts of the additional Excise or upon the said additional
Impositions upon several Goods &amp; Merchandizes or upon the said Duties payable for Vellum Parchment and Paper
or upon the said yearely Su[m]m of Three hundred thousand Pounds payable out of the Subsidy of Tunnage &amp; Poundage
or upon the said Duties charged upon Marriages Births Burials Batchelors and Widdowers or upon the said continued
Impositions payable for Wines Vinegar Tobacco East India Goods or other Merchandize imported or upon the
said Act for continuing certaine Acts therein mentioned and chargeing Joynt Stocks or upon the said Duties payable
for Low Wines Spirits and Sweets or which are or shall be charged upon the said weekly Su[m]m of Six thousand
pounds issuing out of the Hereditary &amp; Temporary Excise or upon the said Weekly Su[m]m of Six hundred pounds
issueing out of the Revenue of the Post-Office and the other Fifth Part of each of the said Subscriptions shall be
answered and made good to the said Capital Stock of the said Governor and Company in Bank Bills or Bank
Notes which have so much Money bona fide resting due thereupon as the said One fifth Part of the said respective
Subscriptions shall fully amount to.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Bank to allow &pound;8 per Cent. on Tallies brought in until the Principal be paid off.</head>
			<para id="p35">And be it further enacted That from and after the said Foure &amp; twentieth Day of June and until such Tallies
and Orders so subscribed assigned &amp; brought into the Bank shall be actually paid off and discharged an Interest
of Eight pounds per Cent[um] per Annum shall be allowed and paid for all the Principal which shall be due upon
or secured by the said Tallies or Orders so subscribed assigned and brought in and where an Interest of Eight
pounds per Cent[um] per Annum is not already granted by Parliament for the same or any of them there shall be
allowed so much as will compleat and make upp the said Interest of Eight pounds per Cent[um]s per Annum out of
the respective Funds and Provisions by this Act granted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. And receive &pound;8 per Cent. Interest for One Fifth Part of the Subscriptions until paid off.</head>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">After Subscriptions compleated, Governor to deliver a Schedule of the Tallies, &amp;c. to the Auditor of Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">And in regard the said Governor and Company are to accept One fifth Part of the said Subscriptions in Bank
Bills or Bank Notes and are already possessed of several Tallies or Orders charged upon the Aids or Funds before
mentioned to a much greater Value than the said Fifth Part in Bank Bills or Bank Notes will amount to Itt is
hereby further enacted That the Interest payable to the said Governor and Company of the Bank of England upon
so many of the said Tallies or Orders whereof the Principal shall be equal to the amount of the said Fifth Part
to be subscribed in Bank Bills or Bank Notes shall be augmented and raised to the Rate of Eight pounds per
Centum per Annum from the said Foure and twentieth Day of June until the same shall be actually paid off &amp;
discharged the said Governour and Company after the said Subscriptions shall be compleated delivering to the
Auditor of the Receipt of Exchequer a Schedule fairely written in Parchment and signed by the Governour or
Deputy Governour containing the Tallies and Orders not to exceed as aforesaid whereupon they shall desire their
Interest to be so augmented to the said Rate of Eight pounds per Centum per Annum and the said Rate of Eight
pounds per Centum per Annum shall be payable to the said Governour &amp; Company and their Successors out of
the respective Funds or Provisions by this Act made or granted for that Purpose the several Acts of Parliament by
which the said Funds are settled or any of them or any Clause Proviso Matter or Thing in them or any of them
contained or any other Act Law Statute Usage or Custome whatsoever to the contrary thereof in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Subscribers to the Capital Stock incorporated with the present Governor and Company, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">Stile of the Corporation to have perpetual Succession, a Common Seal, and may purchase Lands, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all and every the Person and Persons Natives and
Forreigners Bodies Politick and Corporate who shall so subscribe or for whom such Subscriptions shall be made
to the said Capital Stock of the present Governor and Company of the Bank of England by virtue of this Act
and who shall answer and make good their said Subscriptions in the proportion of Tallies Orders Bank Bills and
Bank Notes as aforesaid and the Executors Administrators Successors or Assigns of such Person or Persons Bodies
Politick or Corporate as aforesaid having any Title or Interest under any of the Subscribers by virtue of this Act
att the time of closing or shutting upp of the said intended Book or Books of Subscriptions on the said Foure
and twentieth Day of June shall i[m]mediately from and after the said Foure and twentieth Day of June be and shall
be deemed and reputed to be Members of united to and incorporated with the present Governor and Company of
the Bank of England and their Successors and shall att all times from and after the said Foure and twentieth Day
of June together with the present Governour and Company of the Bank of England and their Successors be and
be construed reputed accepted &amp; taken to be one Body Politick &amp; Corporate by the Name of The Governour
and Company of the Bank of England and by the same Name of the Governour and Company of the Bank of
England shall have a perpetual Succession and a co[m]mon Seale and that they and their Successors by the Name
aforesaid shall be able and capable in Law to have purchase receive possesse enjoy and retaine to them and their
Successors Lands Rents Tenements and Hereditaments of what Kind Nature or Quality soever and also to sell
grant demise alien or dispose of the same and by the same Name to sue and implead be sued and impleaded answer
and be answered in Courts of Record or any other Place whatsoever and to do and execute all and singular other
Matters and Things by the Name aforesaid that to them shall or may appertaine to doe subject neverthelesse to the
Proviso or Condition of Redemption herein after mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. After 1st Aug. 1710, Bank to cease, upon Repayment of several Sums mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">Provided always and it is hereby further enacted That att any time upon Twelve Months Notice after the First
Day of August which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ten and not before and
upon Repayment by Parliament of the Su[m]m of Twelve hundred thousand pounds mentioned in the said Act intituled
An Act for granting to their Majesties several Rates and Duties upon Tu[n]nage of Shipps and Vessells and upon
Beer Ale and other Liquors for securing c[er]tain Recompences &amp; Advantages in the said Act mentioned to such
Persons as shall voluntarily advance the Su[m]m of Fifteene hundred thousand pounds towards carrying on the Warr
against France unto the said Governor and Company of the Bank of England hereby constituted &amp; made and of
all Arrears of the One hundred thousand Pounds per Annum payable to the Governour &amp; Company of the Bank
of England and their Successors by virtue of the said recited Act and also upon payment of all the Principal and
Interest Moneys which shall be owing to the said Governour and Company of the Bank of England hereby
established upon all such Talleys Exchequer Orders or Parliamentary Funds which the said Governour and Company
shall have remaining in their Hands or be intituled to att the time of such Notice to be given as aforesaid then
and in such Case and not till then the said yearely Payment of One hundred thousand pounds per Annum and
also the said Corporation by this and the said former Act established shall cease &amp; determine Any thing herein
contained in any wise to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. During the Continuance of the Bank of England, no other to be established.</head>
			<para id="p42">And be it further enacted That dureing the Continuance of the Corporation of the Governor and Company of
the Bank of England no other Bank or any other Corporation Society Fellowshipp Company or Constitution in the
nature of a Bank shall be erected or established permitted suffered countenanced or allowed by Act of Parliament
within this Kingdome.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Interest on Tallies or Orders brought in as herein mentioned to be taken as so much Principal Money.</head>
			<para id="p43">
				<emph type="i">Assignments of Orders to be registered before Subscription, or not to be accepted</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p44">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all the Interest due on such Talleys or Orders which
shall be so as aforesaid brought into the Bank upon the said intended Subscriptions by virtue of this Act being
computed from the time to which Interest hath been actually satisfied thereupon to the end of the last preceding
Quarter of a Yeare next before the Day appointed for begining of such Subscriptions shall be accepted taken or
allowed by the said Co[m]missioners upon the taking the said Subscriptions as so much Principal Money subscribed
and paid into the Capital Stock of the said Governor and Company and that all Assignements of Orders on all
such Talleys as shall be so brought in upon the said Subscriptions shall before the making of such Subscriptions
be registred in the Exchequer by the proper Owner or Owners thereof and in Default or Neglect of such
registring as aforesaid the said Talleys or Orders so unregistred shall not be accepted or taken nor any Subscription
be allowed or permitted in respect of the same until such Orders shall be first duly registred as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Recital of 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 28. &sect; 25.</head>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">Bank may borrow any Sum above the &pound;1,200,000, not exceeding the Sum hereby subscribed; In Default of Payment, Bills to be paid at the Exchequer; out of the Money due to the Bank; Bills made for above &pound;1,200,000 to be expressed and distinguished</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p46">And whereas in and by the said recited Act of Parliament intituled An Act for granting to their Majesties
several Rates and Duties upon Tunnage of Ships and Vessells and upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for securing
certain Recompences and Advantages in the said Act mentioned to such Persons as shall voluntarily advance the
Su[m]m of Fifteen hundred thousand pounds towards carrying on the Warr against France itt is enacted amongst
other things That the said Corporation to be made in pursuance of the said Direcc[i]ons of [the said<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] recited Act
should not borrow or give Security by Bill Bond Covenant or Agreement under their co[m]mon Seale for any more
further or other Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money exceeding in the whole the Sum[m] of Twelve hundred thousand pounds
so that they should not owe att any one time more than the said Su[m]m under their co[m]mon Seale unlesse it be by
Act of Parliament upon Funds agreed in Parliament and in such Case onely such further Su[m]ms as should be so
directed &amp; allowed to be borrowed by Parliament and for such time onely until they should be repayd such further
Su[m]ms as they should borrow by such Authority and if any more or further or other Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money
should be borrowed taken upp lent or advanced under their Co[m]mon Seale or for Paym[en]t of which any Bill Bond
Covenant or Agreement or other Writing should be made sealed or given under the co[m]mon Seale of the said
Corporac[i]on then and in such Case all and every Person and Persons who should be a Member or Members of
the said Corporation his and their respective Heirs Executors and Administrators should in his and their respective
private and personal Capacities be chargeable with and liable in proportion for their several Shares or Subscriptions
to the Repayment of such Moneys which should be so borrowed taken upp or lent with Interest for the same
as in and by the said recited Act among other things may appeare Be it therefore enacted by the Authority
aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Governour and Company of the Bank of England
&amp; their Successors to borrow or give Security by Bills or Agreement under their co[m]mon Seale for any Su[m]m or
Su[m]ms of Money (over and above the said Su[m]m of Twelve hundred thousand pounds mentioned in the said recited
Act) so as the same exceed not the Value of the Su[m]m which shall be subscribed by virtue of this Act Provided
the said Governour and Company do oblige themselves in [their<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] said Bills by them to be given out to answer
and pay the Money therein mentioned upon Demand And in default of such Payment demanded att the Bank
between the Hours of Nine and Twelve in the Forenoon and the Default thereof being proved by an Affidavitt
made in Writing before the Baronons of the Exchequer or any One of them be it enacted That all such Bills
over and above the said Twelve hundred thousand pounds be answered and paid att the Exchequer out of the
first Money which shall be due or payable att that Receipt to the said Governour and Company (other then
their said yearely Fund of One hundred thousand pounds per Annum and the said Governour and Company are
hereby required in the making forth of the said Bills for any Su[m]m being over and above the said Twelve hundred
thousand-pounds to expresse the same to be made by virtue of this Act and otherwise to distinguish the same
from all their said Debts contained within the said Su[m]m of Twelve hundred thousand pounds Any thing contained
in the said recited Clause or in the said recited Act or any other Act Law Statute Usage or Custom to the
contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Bank Stock and Profit thereof exempted from Taxes.</head>
			<para id="p47">And be it further [enacted<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] That the Co[m]mon Capital &amp; Principal Stock and also the real Fund of the
Governour and Company of the Bank of England or any Profitt or Produce to be made thereof or arising thereby
or the particular Share Part and Interest of any Member of the said Corporation in the said Stock or Fund or
the Profitt or Produce to be made thereof or ariseing thereby shall be and is hereby exempted from any Taxes
Rates Assessments or Impositions whatsoever dureing the Continuance of the said Bank.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Growing Interest on Tallies until Principal paid, and the Principal and the yearly Fund of &pound;1,000,000 applied to the Uses of all Members of the Corporation in proportion to their Shares.</head>
			<para id="p48">And be it further enacted That from and after the compleating of the said Subscriptions to be taken by virtue
of this Act the growing Interest of all the Talleys and Orders brought in by virtue of the said Subscriptions till
the Principal thereon shall be paid off and the said Principal it self so fast as the same shall be received together
with the said yearely Paym[en]t. of One hundred thousand pounds per Annum payable to the present Governor and
Company by virtue of the said recited Act and all the Profitt Benefitt and Advantage from time to time ariseing
out of the Management of all the said Corporation from and after the compleating the said Subscripc[i]ons shall be
applied to the Uses of all the Members of the said Corporation of the Governour and Company of the Bank
of England rateably and in proportion to each Members Part Share and Interest in the Co[m]mon Capital and
Principal Stock of the said Governor and Company hereby establisht.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Bank Stock to be Personal and not Real Estate; and shall go to Executors and not to the Heir.</head>
			<para id="p49">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the Five and twentieth Day of March
One thousand six hundred ninety seven the Estate Interest &amp; Stock of the Money of the said Corporation of the
Governour and Company of the Bank of England and of each and every particular Member thereof shall be and
be adjudged taken and accepted in Construction of Law by all Judges in all Courts of Law &amp; Justice and in all
Courts and Places whatsoever within this Realme to be a personal and not a real Estate and shall go to the
Executors or Administrators of the Person or Persons dyeing possessed thereof or intituled thereunto and not to the
Heires of such Person or Persons Any thing contained in the said Act of Parliament for erecting the Bank or in
any other Act or any other Law Statute Usage or Custome to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. No Contract for buying or selling Bank Stock to be good, till registered in the Bank Books.</head>
			<para id="p50">And for the preventing of clandestine or fraudulent Bargains or Dealings in Bank Stock for the future Be it
further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Five and twentieth Day of March which
shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety seven no Promise Contract Bargaine Covenant
or Agreement made either by word of mouth or in writing for the buying or selling of any Bank Stock or for
the transferring changeing or altering the Property thereof either in Trust or otherwise however it be shall be
good or valid in Law or Equity or adjudged to be legal obligatory or binding to either or any of the Parties
making the same or concerned therein or for whose Use or Account the same is or shall be made unlesse such
Promise Contract Bargaine Covenant or Agreement shall be actually registred in Words att length in the Book
or Books of the Bank by the Officer there thereunto appointed within Seven Days &amp; actually transferred within
Foureteen Days next after the making of such Promise Contract Bargaine Covenant or Agreement.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. No Act of the Corporation to subject the particular Share of any Member to Forfeiture; but such Share to remain entire.
</head>
			<para id="p51">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no Act Matter or Thing Acts Matters or Things
already done or hereafter to be done by the said Corporation of the Governor and Company of the Bank of
England or by their Successors or by the Court of Directors of the said Corporation or by any Sub Co[m]mittee
appointed or to be appointed by the said Corporation shall forfeit or subject or make liable to forfeiture the particular
private and personal Estate Interest Stock and Property of any Member of the said Corporation but that notwithstanding
any Act or Acts Matter or Matters Thing or Things done or to be done by the said Governour and Company
of the Bank of England or by the said Court of Directors or Sub-Co[m]mittees as aforesaid the Estate Stock Interest
and Property with the whole Proceed Benefitt Profitt &amp; Advantage thereof belonging to each and every Member
of the said whole Corporation and his particular Right Claime and Title thereunto and to every part thereof shall
be and remaine unforfeited untouched whole safe and entire to the proper Use &amp; Behoofe of each and every of
the said Members subject neverthelesse to the Payment of all just Debts contracted by the said Corporation Any
Law Statute Usage or Custome to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI.</head>
			<para id="p52">
				<emph type="i">Forging or counterfeiting the Common Seal, or any Bank Note, &amp;c.; Death</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p53">And whereas of late diverse Frauds &amp; Cheats have been putt upon the Governour and Company of the Bank
of England by the altering forging &amp; counterfeiting of the Bank Bills and Bank Notes of the said Governor and
Company and by the rasing and altering Endorsements thereupon to the great decay of Creditt For redressing
the same for the future be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the forging or counterfeiting the co[m]mon
Seale of the said Corporation of the Governor and Company or of any sealed Bank Bill made or given out in
the Name of the said Governor &amp; Company for the Payment of any Su[m]m of Money or of any Bank Note of
any sort whatsoever signed for the said Governour and Company of the Bank of England or the altering or rasing
any Endorsement on any Bank Bill or Note of any sort shall be and is hereby declared and adjudged to be Felony
without Benefitt of Clergy.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. Officers of Exchequer to keep true Accounts of all Monies due to the Bank, on Account of the yearly or other Funds.</head>
			<para id="p54">
				<emph type="i">Company to have free Access to Accounts without Fee.; Payments to be made in course.; Officers of the Exchequer neglecting, &amp;c. to keep Accounts, or to pay in course, &amp;c; Loss of Office, Incapacity, and Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p55">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Auditor of the Receipt of his Majesties Exchequer
for the time being and all Tellers Receivers and Officers whatever in the said Receipt of Excheq[uier] shall from time
to time for ever hereafter keep just and true Accounts in a Book or Books fairely written of all Moneys coming
to their and every of their Hands which are or shall be appropriated belonging due or owing to the said Governor
and Company of the Bank of England as the same shall from time to time come into the Receipt of Exchequer
or shall come to their several Hands either on account of the yearely Fund of One hundred thousand pounds
per Annum payable to the said Governour and Company by virtue of the said Act of Parliament for erecting
the Bank or on account of any Parliamentary Funds on the Creditt of which the said Governour and Company
already have or shall hereafter have lent or advanced any Su[m]m of Money or on account of the Principal Moneys
or Interest due or to be due to the said Governor and Company on any Tallies to them belonging to which
Books the said Governour and Company their Assigns Agents and Servants shall have free Accesse from time
to time and att all seasonable Times without any Fee or Reward to be paid for the same to inspect search
examine and copy out of the said Books as they shall think fitt which said Auditor of the Receipt shall from
time to time duely direct the said Orders and the Clerk of the Pells shall record the same and the Tellers in
the Receipt of the Exchequer shall duely make payment thereupon in their due course without delay to the said
Governour &amp; Company their Agents Servants &amp; Assignes and if any such Auditor Teller Receiver or Officer of
the Exchequer for the time being shall either neglect or refuse to keep such Accounts or to direct record or
make such Payments in due Course and Order as are herein before required or shall delay or putt off the
Payment thereof or divert or misapply any of the Moneys so as aforesaid or any otherwise due or belonging to
the said Governour and Company in such case hee or they so offending respectively for any such Offence shall
forfeit his or their Places and be ever afterwards uncapable of enjoying any Office or Place of Trust whatsoever
and also shall be liable to pay double the Value of any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms so delayed to be paid or so diverted or
misapplied as aforesaid to the said Governour and Company or to any Person or Persons grieved thereby and who
will sue for the same to be recovered in any of his Majesties Courts of Record in Westminster by any Action
of Debt or on the Case to be framed and founded on this Act or by Bill Plaint or Information wherein no
Protection Wager of Law Essoigne Priveledge of Parliament or any other Priveledge shall be allowed nor any more
than one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. Monies arising from the Duties, continued by this Act.</head>
			<para id="p56">
				<emph type="i">Tunnage and Poundage, Wines, Vinegar, Tobacco, &amp;c; Additional Impositions on Merchandize; Duties on Vellum, Parchment, and Paper; on Marriages, Births, Burials, &amp;c on Houses; Monies borrowed upon the Credit of 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 10.; and brought into the Exchequer; Monies borrowed upon the Credit of 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 18; and upon 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 31. as herein mentioned,; Declared the General Fund for making good the Fund herein mentioned to be deficient; The said Monies not divertible</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p57">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all the Moneys which shall arise and be brought into
the Receipt of His Majesties Exchequer of or for the Subsidy of Tunnage and Poundage and other Duties upon
Merchandizes therewith continued by this Act from the Five and twentieth Day of December One thousand six
hundred ninety nine until the said First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six and of or for the said
Impositions or Duties upon Wines Vinegar Tobacco East-India Goods wrought Silks and other Duties therewith
continued by this Act from the Eight and twentieth Day of September One thousand seven hundred &amp; one until
the said First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six and of or for the said additional and other
Rates Duties Impositions and Charges upon several sorts of Goods and Merchandizes by this Act continued from the
last Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety six to the said First Day of August One thousand seven
hundred and six and of or for the said Duties upon Vellum Parchment and Paper by this Act continued from the
Eight &amp; twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight until the said First Day of August One
thousand seven hundred and six and of or for the said Rates and Duties upon Marriages Births Burials Batchelors &amp;
Widdowers hereby continued from the First Day of May One thousand seven hundred [until the s[ai]d First Day of
August One thousand seven hundred<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] and six and of or for the said several Rates or Duties upon Houses by this
Act continued from the Five and twentieth Day of March One thousand seven hundred and three until the said First
Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six and all the Moneys (if any such be) which from and after
the full Payment and Satisfaction of the Su[m]ms of Money not exceeding Fifteen hundred thousand pounds borrowed
upon the Creditt of the said Act passed in the Parliament holden in the Seventh and Eighth Yeares of His Majesties
Reigne intituled An Act for continuing several Duties granted by former Acts upon Wine &amp; Vinegar and upon Tobacco
&amp; East India Goods and other Merchandizes imported for carrying on the Warr against France and the Interest
thereof shall arise &amp; be brought into the Exchequer of or for the said Impositions or Duties upon Wines Vinegar
Tobacco East India Goods wrought Silks and other Goods thereby granted or continued until the said Nine and
twentieth Day of September One thousand seven hundred and one and all the Moneys which from and after the
Satisfaction of the Principal Su[m]ms not exceeding Seven thousand three hundred eighty two pounds eleven shillings
and foure pence borrowed upon the said Act made in the Parliament holden in the Seventh and Eighth Yeares of
His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for granting to His Majestie several Rates or Duties upon Houses for making
good the Deficiency of the clipt Money &amp; the Interest thereof and after that all the Bills signed by the Master
and Worker of His Majesties Mints for the Reward after the Rate of Six pence per Ounce for every Ounce of Sterling
Silver proceeding from wrought Plate Vessells or [any<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] other manufactured Silver brought into any of His Majesties
Mints between the Fourth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety six and the Fourth Day of November One
thousand six hundred ninety six shall be fully paid off and satisfied shall arise and be brought into the Exchequer
of or for the said Rates or Duties upon Houses granted by the said Act for Seven Yeares from the Five &amp; twentieth
Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety six and all the Moneys which from and after the full Payment
and Satisfaction of the Su[m]ms of Money not exceeding One million seven hundred twenty foure thousand pounds
borrowed or to be borrowed as aforesaid for the Service of the Warr upon Creditt of the said Act passed in the
Parliament holden in the Seventh and Eighth Yeares of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for continuing to His
Majestie certaine Duties upon Salt glasse Wares stone and earthen Wares and for granting several Duties upon
Tobacco Pipes and other earthen Wares for carrying on the Warr against France and for establishing a National Land
Bank &amp; for taking off the Duties upon Tunnage of Shipps and Vessells and upon Coals and after the Interest thereof
shall also be satisfied shall arise and be brought into the said Receipt of Exchequer of and for the said Duties
upon Salt glasse Wares stone and earthen Wares and upon Tobacco Pipes and other the Duties thereby granted or
continued to His Majesty His Heires and Successors shall be and are hereby declared to be the General Fund for
making good the particular Funds before in this Act expressed or computed to be deficient and are and shall be
appropriated issued and applied for &amp; towards the making good of the said deficient Funds by the Payment and
Satisfaction of the Principal and Interest due and to grow due thereupon in such Manner &amp; Forme and according
to such Rules and Methods as are hereafter in this Act prescribed and directed and shall not be diverted or divertible
to any other Use Intent or Purpose whatsoever until all the said Principal and Interest shall be fully satisfied and
paid off.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX.</head>
			<para id="p58">
				<emph type="i">Monies of the said General Fund hereby appropriated, arising before 28th June 1698, for the Duties on Houses, after Payment of &pound;7, 382 11s. 4d. and Interest, &amp;c. also for additional Rates on Merchandizes, &amp;c. continued by this Act, to satisfy the Interest due on Loans directed to be repaid out of the 1st, 3d, and 4th 4s. Aids, Quarterly Poll, &amp;c.; With Interest after the Rate of &pound;8 per Cent. per Ann</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p59">And to the end all the Monies which shall arise and be brought into the Receipt of the Excheq[uier] of or for the
several Duties Impositions and Revenues which are hereby appropriated for making good of the deficient Funds and
are before in this Act particularly enumerated and declared to be the general Fund for that purpose may be duely
issued and applied for and towards the Payment &amp; Satisfaction of the Principal and Interest due and to grow due
upon the said Funds hereby declared or computed to be deficient according to the true Intent &amp; Meaning of this
Act and that the Moneys by this Act appropriated for that Purpose may not be diverted or applied to any other
Use then is hereby intended Be it further enacted and provided That so much of the Moneys of the said general
Fund hereby appropriated as aforesaid as shall arise and be brought into the said Receipt of the Exchequer att any
Time or Times before the Eight and twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight as well for the
said Duties upon Houses (after the said Principal Moneys not exceeding Seven thousand three hundred eighty two
pounds eleven shillings and foure pence and the Interest thereof and the said Reward of Six pence an Ounce for
Silver shall be satisfied) as also for, the said additional and other Rates Duties Impositions &amp; Charges upon several
sorts of Goods and Merchandizes by this Act continued from the last Day of February One thousand six hundred
ninety six shall be [issued &amp;<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] applied for and towards the Payment and Satisfaction of the Int[r]est due or to grow
due (as well to the Bank of England as to any other Person or Persons that are or shall be intituled to Interest)
of or for the Loans that are or shall be remaining unsatisfied which were made upon or directed to be repaid out
of the said First Aid of Foure shillings in the Pound and the said Third Aid of Foure shillings in the Pound and
the said Fourth Aid of Foure shillings in the Pound and the said quarterly Poll and the said Three Fourth Parts
of the Customes and the said Two third Parts of the additional Excise and such additional Impositions and Duties
on Goods and Merchandizes as were granted by the said Act ending on the First Day of March One thousand six
hundred ninety six and that out of the same Moneys so ariseing and brought into the Exchequer att any Time or
Times before the said Eight and twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight the said Governour
&amp; Company of the Bank of England and their Successors shall receive so much as will make upp their Part
of the Interest out of the Funds last mentioned to be after the Rate of Eight pounds per Centum per Annum as
well for such Talleys and Orders charged on those Funds as shall be subscribed and brought into the Bank as
aforesaid as for other their Talleys and Orders on those particular Funds whereof the Interest is to be augmented
to the said Rate of Eight pounds per Centum per Annum by virtue and in pursuance of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. Interest out of the last mentioned Fund, how to be satisfied.</head>
			<para id="p60">Provided always and be it enacted That if the Moneys soe ariseing and being brought into the said Receipt of
Exchequer att any Time or Times before the said Eight and twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety
eight as is before mentioned shall not be sufficient to satisfie all the Interest which in the meane Time shall grow
due to the said Governour and Company of the Bank of England and to all other Persons intituled to Interest out
of the Funds last mentioned that then the Co[m]missioners of his Majesties Treasury or any Three or more of them
now being or the Treasurer or any Three or more of the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time being shall
cause the Moneys that shall so arise and be brought in att any Time or Times before the said Eight and twentieth
Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight to be distributed and applied so farr as it will extend to
and for the Payment of the said Interest upon the Funds last mentioned so that a proportionable Part thereof
shall be issued for Interest upon each of those Funds according and in Proportion to the Su[m]m of all the Principal
Money that shall then remaine due thereupon.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Overplus, after Payment of the said Interest, to be applied to pay the Principal.</head>
			<para id="p61">Provided also and be it enacted That if the Moneys so ariseing and being brought into the said Receipt of
Exchequer att any Time or Times before the said Eight and twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred
ninety eight as is before mentioned shall be sufficient to satisfie all the Interest which in the meane Time shall
grow due to the said Governor and Company and all others intituled to Interest out of the Funds last mentioned
with an Overplus that then the said Co[m]missioners of the Treasury or any Three or more of them now being or
the Treasurer or any Three or more of the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time being shall cause the said
Overplus Moneys so ariseing &amp; being brought in att any Time or Times before the said Eight and twentieth
Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight to be distributed and applied so farr as it will extend to
and for the Payment of the Principal Moneys owing upon the Funds last mentioned and enumerated so that a
proportionable Part there of shall be issued for Principal upon each of those Funds according and in Proportion to
the Su[m]m (whether it be greater or lesser) of all the Principal Moneys that shall then remaine due thereupon &amp;
the Moneys so distributed to pay of Principal upon each of those Funds shall be issued in Satisfaction of Principal
Moneys which shall in course be payable to the said Governour and Company or to any other Persons out of
the same Funds respectively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII.</head>
			<para id="p62">
				<emph type="i">Application of the General Fund; Treasury, on or before 26th July 1698, and thenceforth, once in 28 Days, to cause an Account to be taken of all Monies brought into the Exchequer, &amp;c.; and cause the same to be applied to Account of deficient Taxes</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p63">And as to for and concerning so much of the Moneys of the said General Fund hereby appropriated as aforesaid
as shall arise and be brought into the said Receipt of Exchequer att any time or times after the said Eight &amp;
twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight as well for the said Duties upon Houses as for
the said additional and other Rates Duties Impositions and Charges upon several sorts of Goods and Merchandizes
dureing the Continuance of this Act and as to for and concerning so much of the Moneys of the said General
Fund hereby appropriated as aforesaid as shall arise and be brought into the said Receipt of Exchequer att any
time or times of or for the Several Duties Impositions or Revenues herein after mentioned (that is to say) of or
for the said Duties upon Vellum Parchment and Paper by this Act granted and continued from the Eight and
twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight until the said First Day of August One thousand
seven hundred &amp; six and of and for the said Subsidy of Tunnage and Poundage &amp; other Duties upon Merchandizes
therewith granted and continued by this Act from the said Five and twentieth Day of December One thousand
six hundred ninety nine until the said First Day of August One thousand seven hundred &amp; six and of [and<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] for
the said Rates &amp; Duties upon Marriages Births Burials Batchelors &amp; Widdowers hereby granted and continued
from the First Day of May One thousand seven hundred until the said First Day of August One thousand seven
hundred and six and of or for the said Impositions or Duties upon Wines Vinegar Tobacco East India Goods
wrought Silks and other Duties therewith granted and continued by this Act from the Eight &amp; twentieth Day
of September One thousand seven hundred and one until the said First Day of August One thousand seven
hundred and six and all the Moneys (if any such be) which from &amp; after the full Payment and Satisfaction of
the said Su[m]ms not exceeding Fifteen hundred thousand pounds borrowed upon the Creditt of the said Act passed
in the Parliament holden in the Seventh and Eight Yeares of his Majesties Reigne for the said continued Duties
upon Wines Vinegar Tobacco East India Goods and other Merchandizes shall arise thereby until the said Nine
and twentieth Day of September One thousand seven hundred and one and be brought into the said Receipt of
Exchequer and as to all the Moneys which from and after the full Payment and Satisfaction of the Su[m]ms of
Money not exceeding One million seven hundred twenty foure thousand pounds borrowed or to be borrowed as
aforesaid for the Service of the Warr upon Creditt of the said Act for continuing and making perpetual the said
Duties upon Salt Glasse Wares Stone and Earthen Wares and upon Tobacco Pipes and other the Duties thereby
granted or continued itt is hereby further enacted and provided That all the Moneys so ariseing and brought
from time to time into the said Receipt [of Exchequer <ref idref="n9">9</ref>] of or for the said general Fund consisting of the said
several Duties Impositions and Revenues before enumerated and mentioned as the same shall from time to time
co[m]mence or take effect shall be distributed issued &amp; applied to and for the Payment of Principal and Interest
charged upon or directed to be paid as aforesaid out of the said deficient Funds that is to say the said First
Aid of Foure shillings in the pound the said Third Aid of Foure shillings in the pound the said Fourth Aid of
Foure shillings in the pound the said quarterly Poll the said Three fourth parts of the Customes the said Duties
upon Salt glasse Wares and other earthen Wares and Tobacco Pipes the said Two third parts of the additional
Excise the said additional Impositions payable for Goods and Merchandizes the said Duties payable upon Vellum
Parchment and Paper the said Rates and Duties payable upon Marriages Births and Burials Batchelors and Widdowers
the said continued Impositions payable for Wines Vinegar Tobacco East India Goods and other Merchandizes
imported and upon the said yearely Su[m]m of Three hundred thousand pounds payable out of the Subsidy of
Tunnage and Poundage so as that a proportionable part of the Moneys so coming in to be distributed as aforesaid
shall be distributed issued &amp; applied to pay principal and Interest upon every one of the Funds last mentioned
according and in proportion to the Su[m]m of the Deficiency thereof before in and by this Act computed and expressed
and that the Co[m]missioners of his Majesties Treasury or any Three or more of them now being or the High Treasurer
or under Treasurer of the Exchequer or any Three or more of the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time
being shall on or before the Six and twentieth Day of July One thousand six hundred ninety eight and from
thenceforth once in every Eight and twenty Days or oftner cause and exact Account to be made or taken of all
the Moneys that shall be brought into the Excheq[uer] applicable to pay Principal &amp; Interest on the said deficient
Funds as aforesaid and shall thereupon i[m]mediately from time to time by their Warrants and Orders cause such
Money to be distributed applied and placed to the Account of each Tax Revenue or Fund so deficient as aforesaid
in the just Proportions before mentioned and according to the true intent and meaning of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>XLIII. The said Monies to be paid out to the Bank and others entitled to the same, and not divertible.</head>
			<para id="p64">
				<emph type="i">Penalty; Bank to receive &pound;8 per Cent. out of General Fund, for Tallies subscribed, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p65">And it is hereby enacted That all the Money which shall be so distributed or placed to the Account of each
and every of the said deficient Taxes Duties and Funds before enumerated &amp; expressed for or towards the
Payment of Principal &amp; Interest thereupon shall be issued paid out and disposed so farr as the same will from
time to time extend as well to the said Governor and Company of the Bank of England and their Successors as
to all &amp; every other Person and Persons Bodies Politick and Corporate who are or shall be intituled to receive
the said Principal and Interest in such and the like Course Order Manner and Forme as if the same were Moneys
really ariseing by the said respective Taxes Duties or Funds hereby computed and expressed to be deficient as
aforesaid and that without being diverted or divertible to any other Use or misapplied &amp; without giving any undue
Preference under the Penalty of incurring the same Forfeitures and Disabilities by the Officers and other Persons
concerned therein as they would have incurred for diverting or misapplying any the Money of such Tax Duty or
Fund in case the same were not deficient and that out of the said Moneys so from time to time ariseing and
being brought into the Exchequer of or for the said General Fund hereby provided &amp; established for making
good the said deficient Funds the said Governor and Company of the Bank of England shall from time to time
receive so much as will make upp and compleate for them an Interest after the Rate of Eight pounds per Centum
per Annum as well for all and every the Talleys and Orders which shall be subscribed and brought into the
Bank as aforesaid and be charged upon any of the Funds pursuant to this Act as for any other their Talleys
and Orders whereupon the Interest (in regard of the Subscripc[i]on of One Fifth in Bank Bills or Notes is to be
augmented to the Rate of Eight pounds per Centum per Annum by virtue and in pursuance of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>XLIV. Duties of former Acts applied as by such Acts is required.</head>
			<para id="p66">
				<emph type="i">The new Duties by this Act to be applied in Aid thereof</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p67">Provided also and it is hereby declared and enacted That in all Cases where any Duty Revenue Imposition
or Branch whatsoever is by any Act or Acts of Parliament before this time made &amp; passed appropriated to or
for the Repayment of Principal in course or the Satisfaction of Interest att any Rate or Rates whatsoever of or
for any Loans which have been made upon the Creditt of such former Act or Acts the respective Duties Revenues
Impositions or Branches ariseing by virtue of such former Acts shall be applied and such Principal and Interest
out of the Moneys ariseing thereby shall be satisfied to those which are or shall be intituled thereunto (whether
it be the Bank of England or any others) in the same Course Manner and Forme as by the said former Act
are prescribed and required and that the new Duties or Funds by this Act provided &amp; established shall go and
be applied in Aid thereof in such Manner and Forme and under such Limitations and Directions as are hereby
prescribed until the said Principal and Interest shall be all entirely paid off and discharged Any thing in this
Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>XLV.</head>
			<para id="p68">
				<emph type="i">If Judgment be given against the Bank, yearly Payments, &amp;c. belonging to them to be vested in 24 Trustees, elected by the Bank, for 3 Years; who may receive and sue for the Debts of the Corporation, and discharge such Judgment, &amp;c; Surplus to be divided amongst the Members; In such Case yearly Payments payable to the Bank to be payable Quarterly to Members, and transferable without Fee.; Monies due upon the said Funds to be paid to the Trustees; and not misapplied</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p69">And to the Intent that all Persons concerned with the Governor &amp; Company of the Bank of England may be
secured in their respective Debts and Effects in case any Forfeiture should be co[m]mitted or any Judgement or
Forfeiture or Seizure of the said Corporation should be given for or by reason of or under any pretence of any
Forfeiture whatsoever Be it enacted That i[m]mediately upon such Judgement given all and every the [the<ref idref="n10">10</ref>]. Funds
yearely Payments and Moneys payable out of the Exchequer to the Governor and Company of the Bank of
England or which should have become due &amp; payable to them in case no such Judgement had been given and
also all and every the Estate Goods Debts and Chattells due belonging or owing to the said Governor and Company
att the time of such Judgement shall be and are hereby (in such case) actually vested and settled in Foure &amp;
twenty such Persons as shall be for that purpose elected and chosen by the Governor and Company of the Bank
of England in a General Court assembled before such Judgement given dureing the space of Three Yeares which
said Persons so elected and the Survivors of them dureing the said Three Yeares shall be Trustees for the purposes
aforesaid and shall and may receive sue for and recover the Money Debts and Estate of the said Corporation
or which would have belonged to the said Governor and Company in case no such Judgement had been given
and with the Moneys and Estate so received and recovered shall pay and discharge all the Debts due and owing
by the said Corporation att the time of such Judgement given and performe and fulfil such Covenants and Contracts
as the said Corporation att the time of such Judgement given had entred into and were bound and obliged to
performe and after the said Three Yeares or after the Debts and Estate so gott in paid and applied then that the
Surplus if any there shall be shall be paid and divided amongst such Persons as were Members of the said
Corporation att the time of such Judgement given according to their several Shares and Proportions and also that
the yearely Su[m]ms afterwards payable att the Receipt of Excheq[uer] to the said Corporation shall be vested in and
payable quarterly to such Person and Persons their Executors Administrators &amp; Assigns as were Members of the
said Corporation att the time of such Judgement respectively according to their several Shares and Proportions in
the said Stock and Company to be ascertained and specified in a List to be returned or given in by the said
Trustees or the Survivors of them under their Hands and Seales into the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt
and which said several yearely Paym[en]ts. so specified shall be from time to time assignable and transferrable by an
Entry in a Book to be kept in the Office of Auditor of the Receipt for that purpose without any Fee or Reward
whatsoever and that all the Moneys due upon the said Funds or payable in the said Receipt as aforesaid shall
be from time to time paid and applied to the said Trustees to be elected as aforesaid dureing the said Three
Yeares and afterwards to the said several and respective p[er]sons their Executors Administrators and Assigns and
not any ways diverted or misapplied under the like Penalties Forfeitures and Disabilities as are given or imposed
by any Act or Acts of Parliament now in force against any Person or Persons for diverting or misapplying any
Moneys payable to any Person by the said Acts of Parliament or any of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>XLVI. Company may transcribe Dockets of Extents, &amp;c. paying the usual Fees.</head>
			<para id="p70">Provided That for the Encouragement of the said Corporation to lend Moneys upon Lands or Tenements and
for Discovery of Incumbrances thereon Be it enacted That it shall &amp; may be lawfull for the said Governour and
Company or any Officer or Clerk to be imployed by them from time to time to copy and transcribe the Docketts
and Notes of any Extents Judgements Statutes or Recognizances kept in any of the Offices of the several Courts
of Record att Westminster paying to the Masters or Clerks of the several Offices the usual Rates and Fees for
Search onely of such Extents Judgements Statutes or Recognizances.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>XLVII. No Member to be adjudged a Bankrupt.</head>
			<para id="p71">
				<emph type="i">Stock not liable to Foreign Attachment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p72">And be it enacted That no Member of the said Corporation shall be or be adjudged liable to be a Bankrupt
within the intent and meaning of all or any the Statutes made against or concerning Bankrupts for or by reason
of their Stock or Interest in the said Corporation and that no Stock in the said Corporation shall be subject or
liable to any forreigne Attachment by the Custome of London or otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>XLVIII. Money due on Tallies subscribed into the Capital Stock of the Bank, to be divided so soon as received, or within 4 Months after.</head>
			<para id="p73">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Moneys which from time to time shall become
due and payable by virtue of any Talley or Order subscribed as aforesaid into the Capital Stock of the said
Governor and Company by virtue of this Act as soon as conveniently may be after the same shall be received
out of the Exchequer or any publick Office by the said Governour and Company their Officers Servants and
Agents and att farthest once in every Foure Months shall be divided by the said Governor and Company amongst
the Members of the whole Corporation ratably and in proportion to their several and respective Parts Shares and
Interests in the said Capital Stock for the particular proper and onely use and behoofe of the said Members
separately and in their private and personal Capacities Any thing in this Act or in the aforesaid Act for granting
the said Rates and Duties upon Tunnage of Shipps and for erecting of the said Bank or in the Charter of
Incorporation granted to the said Governour and Company beareing Date att Westminster the Seven and twentieth
Day of July One thousand six hundred ninety foure or any Rule Order Usage Custome Act Statute or Law
whatsoever to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>XLIX. Debts of the Bank not to exceed the Value of the Capital undivided Stock.</head>
			<para id="p74">
				<emph type="i">If Governor and Company lessen their Joint or Capital Stock, so as the Value thereof be not sufficient to answer their Debts, Members liable, to the Extent of their Shares, to satisfy the Debts unpaid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p75">Provided always and be it enacted That the said Governor &amp; Company and their Successors shall always take
care that the Su[m]m total of all their Debts which they shall owe att any one time to any other Person or Persons
Bodies Politick or Corporate do not exceed the Value of the Capital Stock which att any such time shall be and
remaine to the said Governour and Company undivided and that in case the said Governor and Company or
their Successors by virtue or colour of the Power hereby given to them of dividing the Moneys coming in by
their Talleys and Orders as aforesaid or by any other Dividend whatsoever to be made amongst themselves or in
their private or personal Capacities shall reduce or lessen their Joint Stock or Capital without limitting paying off
or proportionably reducing the Total Su[m]m of the said Debts which they shall owe to others as aforesaid so that
the value of their Joint Stock or Capital undivided shall not be sufficient to answer their just Debts then remaining
unpaid in every such Case the particular Members and every of them respectively who in their private or personal
Capacities shall receive any Share of such Dividend shall be severally liable and they are hereby made liable so
farr as the respective Shares so by them respectively received upon such Dividend will extend to pay and satisfie
the Debts which shall remaine due and unpaid by the said Governor and Company to any other Persons or
Bodies Politick or Corporate as aforesaid who by virtue of this Act shall and may sue for and recover the same
(besides treble Costs of Suit) by Action of Debt or of the Case as is before mentioned Any thing in this Act
or in any former Act Charter or otherwise howsoever to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s50">
			<head>L.</head>
			<para id="p76">
				<emph type="i">If at the End of One Year the Duties hereby appropriated be not sufficient to pay off the Interest due for that Year; the Deficiency to be supplied out of the next Aids.; In case, upon 1st Aug. 1706, or Three Months afterwards, the Funds hereby granted be not sufficient to pay off the Principal and Interest due on the foresaid Tallies and Orders,; the Deficiency to be supplied out of such Aids as shall be granted after the said 1st Aug. 1706</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p77">And to obviate all Doubts for the future concerning the Securities by this Act intended for the payment of the
Principal and Interest Moneys to be paid as aforesaid Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in case
att the end of One Yeare to be reckoned from the utmost Day or time by this Act limited for taking of the said
Subscriptions for augmenting the said Capital Stock of the Bank of England it shall appeare that the Funds or
Duties by this Act appropriated to and for the payment of Interest Moneys (as well to the said Governour and
Company of the Bank of England as to any other Persons or Corporations) shall not be sufficient to satisfie and
discharge all the Interest Moneys which before the end of the said One Yeare shall be incurred growne due or
ought to be paid of for or upon the respective Talleys and Orders before mentioned and every of them that then
the Deficiency thereof (to witt) so much as will suffice to make upp &amp; compleat the Interest Moneys which shall
be growne due before the end of the said One Yeare as aforesaid shall be supplied and paid out of such Aids
or Revenues as shall be granted to His Majesty His Heires or Successors in the Session of Parliament then next
ensuing and so in like manner in case of Deficiency of Interest in any succeeding Yeare and in case upon the
First Day of August which shall be in the Yeare of oure Lord One thousand seven hundred and six or within
Three Months then next ensuing it shall appeare that the whole produce of the several Aids Revenues and Funds
by this Act granted or appropriated together with the Moneys which shall have arisen by the Grants now in
being and before this time made for the payment of the Principal Moneys of the said Tallies and Orders and the
Interest thereof shall not be sufficient to discharge and pay off as well all the Principal Moneys upon all the
said Talleys and Orders for the payment whereof Provision is intended to be made by this Act and all the Interest
Moneys that are or shall be due or payable for the same that then the Deficiency thereof to witt so much as
will be needfull compleatly to make upp satisfie and discharge all the said Principal and Interest Moneys which
shall appeare on the said First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six or within Three Months then
next ensueing to remaine due and unpaid shall be supplied and paid out of such Aids or Revenue as shall be
granted to His Majesty his Heires or Successors in the Session of Parliament which shall be next after the said
First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s51">
			<head>LI. Present Governor and Directors to continue till 24th June 1697.</head>
			<para id="p78">
				<emph type="i">Afterwards a General Court to be held for electing a new Governor and 24 Directors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p79">Provided also and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the p[er]sons who are att present Governor Deputy
Governour and Directors of the Bank of England shall continue in their respective Offices until the said Foure and
twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven and until others shall be duely chosen and sworne
in their Places and that betweene the said Foure and twentieth Day of June and the Foure and twentieth Day of
July next ensuing a general Court of the Persons [then<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] interested in the said Corporation shall be su[m]moned and
held and then and there by [the<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Majority of the said Members present a new Governour Deputy Governour and
Foure &amp; twenty Directors (of which Number there shall not be above Two thirds of such Persons who were Directors
the preceeding Yeare) shall be chosen who shall continue in their respective Offices until the Five and twentieth Day
of March One thousand six hundred ninety eight and until others shall be duely chosen and sworne in their Places
according to the Times prescribed by their present Charter and under such Regulations as are directed by this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s52">
			<head>LII. Not above Two Thirds of the old Directors to be chosen.</head>
			<para id="p80">And be it further enacted That in all future Elections of Directors there shall not be chosen above Two thirds
of those who were Directors the preceeding Yeare Any thing in the said Charter or any Law Statute or Ordinance
to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s53">
			<head>LIII.</head>
			<para id="p81">
				<emph type="i">Additional Duties on Salt.; For Salt imported, 2d per Gallon.; For Salt and Rock Salt made at the Salt Works, &amp;c. 1d. per Gallon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p82">And to the end there may be no Defect in the payment of the Interest by this Act intended and directed to be
paid out of the Moneys hereby granted or appropriated and that the General Fund by this Act provided for the
Purposes in this Act mentioned may be inlarged for the full Satisfaction of all Persons that are or may be concerned
therein Wee your Majesties said dutifull and loyal Subjects the Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled do further give
and grant unto your Majestie the several additional Rates or Duties upon Salt herein after mentioned for and dureing
the Terme herein after expressed and do beseech your Majesty that it may be enacted and be it further enacted
by the Authority aforesaid That from &amp; after the Five and twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred
ninety seven there shall be throughout the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon
Tweed raised levied collected and paid unto His Majesty His Heires and Successors until the Five and twentieth
Day of December which shall be in the Yeare of oure Lord One thousand six hundred ninety nine and no longer
for Salt the Rates and Duties following over and above all other Duties already payable for the same that is to say
For every Gallon of Salt that shall be imported into the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of
Berwick upon Tweed within the time aforesaid the Su[m]m of Two pence of lawfull Money of England to be paid
by the Importer thereof and after that Rate for a greater or lesser Quantity and for every Gallon of Salt and Rock
Salt made att the Salt Works or taken out of any Salt Pitts within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales
or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed within the Days or Times aforesaid the Su[m]m of One penny and after that Rate
for a greater or lesser Quantity.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s54">
			<head>LIV.</head>
			<para id="p83">
				<emph type="i">The said Duties to be levied as by 5 W. &amp; M. c. 7. and 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 31; Proviso for Allowances herein mentioned for Fish and Salt exported.; over and above Allowances by former Acts; to be paid by Debentures</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p84">And for the better ascertaining charging levying collecting and answering all &amp; every the Duties hereby sett or
imposed as well upon forreigne &amp; imported Salt as upon Salt and Rock-Salt made att the Salt Works or taken out
of any Salt Pitts within the said Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed
dureing the terme hereby granted Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all and every the Powers
Authorities Directions Rules Ways Methods Penalties Forfeitures Clauses Matters and Things which in and by one
Act made in the Parliament holden att Westminster in the Fifth and Sixth Yeares of the Reigne of His Majestie
and the late Queen of Blessed Memory intituled An Act for granting to their Majesties certaine Rates and Duties
upon Salt and upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for securing certaine Recompences and Advantages in the said Act
mentioned to such Persons as shall voluntarily advance the Su[m]m of Ten hundred thousand pounds towards carrying
on the Warr against France and in and by one other Act made in the Parliament holden att Westminster in the
Seventh and Eighth Yeares of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for continuing to His Majesty certaine Duties
upon Salt glasse Wares stone and earthen Wares and for granting several Duties upon Tobacco Pipes and other
earthen Wares for carrying on the Warr against France and for establishing a National Land Bank and for taking
off the Duties upon Tunnage of Shipps &amp; upon Coals are provided settled or established for or concerning the raising
levying ascertaining securing collecting or recovering the several Duties upon Salt and Rock-Salt thereby granted
or continued and for determining and ascertaining the Measure of English Salt by Weight shall be exercised
practised applied levied recovered and putt in Execution for the raising levying chargeing ascertaining securing
collecting recovering and paying the said several Duties upon Salt and Rock-Salt by this Act granted dureing the
Continuance of the Duties thereupon by this Act as fully and effectually to all intents and purposes as if all and
every the said Powers Authorities Rules and Directions Methods Penalties Forfeitures Clauses Matters and Things
were particularly repeated and again enacted in the Body of this Act neverthelesse with such Allowances for Fish
and Salt to be exported as are herein mentioned (that is to say) For all such Fish hereafter mentioned as shall be
exported dureing the Continuance of the Duties hereby granted upon Salt from any Port or Place in the said
Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed into Parts beyond the Seas by any
Person or Persons whatsoever the Rates and Su[m]ms of Money hereafter expressed that is to say For every Cask or
Vessell of Pilchards or Scads containing Fifty Gallons Eight shillings and so proportionably for a greater or lesser
Quantity for every Barrel of White Herrings One shilling and eight pence for every Barrel of Red Herrings One
shilling and foure pence for every Barrel of Salmon Three shillings and foure pence for every Hundred of Cod
Fish Ling or Hake Ten shillings and so proportionably for a greater or smaller Number or Quantity shall (over and
above the Allowances for the said Fish by the said former Acts for the Duties upon Salt or either of them) be
paid by Debentures in such Manner and Forme and under the same Rules and Penalties as are prescribed in the said
former Acts concerning the said Duties upon Salt or either of them for or concerning the Allowances upon the
Exportation of the like kinds of Fish.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s55">
			<head>LV. On Exportation of Salt, Security for Duties discharged upon Certificate and Oath.</head>
			<para id="p85">And be it further enacted That if any Person or Persons att any Time or Times dureing the Continuance of the
additional-Duties hereby granted upon Salt shall export beyond the Seas any Salt as well Forreigne as English or
any Rock Salt the Security for the Duty by this Act payable for such exported Salt shall be discharged upon such
Certificate and Oath made? and according to such Rules as are prescribed for drawing back the Duties upon exported
Salt by the said former Acts or either of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s56">
			<head>LVI. Application of the Duties of this Act. upon Salt.</head>
			<para id="p86">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all the Duties by this Act granted upon Salt which
shall from time to time be levied and raised shall be appropriated and applied together with the other Duties by
this Act provided for that purpose to and for the Payment and Satisfaction of the Interest Moneys due or to grow
due att any Time before the said Five &amp; twentieth Day of December One thousand six hundred ninety nine to the
Bank of England or any other Person or Persons Bodies Politick or Corporate upon the Tallies or Orders charged
upon the deficient Funds before mentioned and in case there be any Overplus of these Duties more than shall be
sufficient to discharge such Interest then the said Overplus shall be applied to the Paym[en]t. of the Principal upon the
said deficient-Funds in the like Proportions as are above mentioned according to the true meaning of this Act under
the like Penalties to be incurred for diverting or misapplying any the Monies ariseing by the said Duties upon Salt
hereby granted as are to be incurred for diverting or misapplying any the Moneys of the said General Fund hereby
appropriated for Satisfaction of the said Principal and Interest.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s57">
			<head>LVII. Recital that many Persons entitled to Tallies may be induced to sell or dispose of them at an unreasonable; Allowance.</head>
			<para id="p87">
				<emph type="i">No Talley to be taken at more than the Interest allowed thereupon, with a further Allowance of &pound;6 per Cent; Penalty. and the Buyer deemed a common Extortioner</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p88">And whereas for Moneys lent or advanced or to be lent or advanced att the Receipt of his Majesties Exchequer
by several Persons as well Natives as Foreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate they or some other claiming by from
or under them respectively have or hereafter may have or are or may be intituled to Tallies of Loan levied att the
said Receipt and have or may have Orders signed by the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury or some of them for the
time being or by the Lord Treasurer for the time being for Repayment of the Money so lent (with Interest att
certaine Rates or without Interest) out of diverse Taxes Aids Impositions Revenues or other Branches chargeable
therewith and also have or may have in their Hands or Possession divers Tallies of Pro or Assignment levied or
charged or to [be<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] levied or charged upon certaine of His Majesties Revenues Duties or Impositions And whereas
it is found by Experience that many avaricious or ill disposed Persons taking an Advantage of the Necessities of
those who have occasion to sell or dispose of such Tallies and Orders as aforesaid do in the buying or purchasing
of such Orders or Tallies extort and gaine to themselves an exorbitant and unreasonable Allowance Premium or
Consideration out of the principal Moneys besides the Interest accruing for the same to the unspeakable Damage
and Prejudice of his Majesty and many of his good Subjects in Trade and otherwise and in a great measure to
the ruine of the publick Creditt which cannott be repaired as long as such Practises are continued or suffered
For prevention whereof be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no Person or Persons whatsoever
Natives or Foreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate from and after the Tenth Day of June One thousand six
hundred ninety seven att any time or times dureing the Terme of Five Yeares from thence next ensuing or before
the end of the then next Session of Parliament shall upon any Contract Agreement or Bargaine whatsoever for or
concerning any of the said Talleys or Orders or for or concerning the Moneys or any Part thereof due or payable
or to be due or payable [by<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] or upon any of the said Talleys or Orders take accept or receive or agree to take
accept or receive or shall give or allow or promise or agree to give or allow directly or indirectly by way of
Premium Reward Discount Gratuity Guift or otherwise or by means of any Exchange Wager Shift Chevisance
Covin Device or Way whatsoever more than the lawfull Interest allowed upon such Talley or Order and due or
payable att the time of such Assignement together with a further Allowance not exceeding the Rate of Six pounds
per Cents for every Hundred pounds principal Money and so proportionably for a greater or lesser Su[m]m upon paine
of forfeiting and losing for every such Offence treble the value of the principal Moneys contained or specified
in such Talley or Order for which such Bargaine Agreement or Contract shall be made that is to say One third
part thereof to the King his Heires and Successors and the other Two thirds thereof to such Person or Persons
as will informe and sue for the same to be recovered by Action of Debt or of the Case Bill Suit or Information
wherein no Essoigne Protection Wager of Law or more than one Imparlance shall be granted or allowed and that
every Person who shall be guilty of such Offence in the buying of any such Order or Talley and be thereof
convicted shall be deemed and is hereby adjudged to be a co[m]mon Extortioner and shall suffer such further Paines
and Penalties as by the Laws and Statutes of this Realme may be inflicted for co[m]mon Extortion.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s58">
			<head>LVIII. No Assignment of Order or Talley to be good, unless made in Writing, and signed by the Party making the same; or under the common Seal of a Corporation, &amp;c.; and if of Money payable at the Exchequer, then to be entered in the Exchequer in 10 Days after signing, and Oath made thereon; and an Affidavit that no further Allowance taken.</head>
			<para id="p89">
				<emph type="i">If Assignment of Money payable by Talley of Pro at the Excise or General Post Office, &amp;c. then to be entered in the Excise or Post Office, &amp;c; and on the like Affidavit.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p90">And for the more effectual obviating and preventing of the aforesaid evil Practice and the mischievious Consequences
thereof Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no Assignement or Transference which from and
after the said Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven shall be made of any of the said Orders
or Talleys or of any of the Moneys contained or specified therein upon the selling buying or bargaining of the
same shall be good and available either in Law or Equity or be in any wise effectual for the assigning or transferring
the Right or Property of any such Order or Talley or any the Moneys thereby due or payable unlesse such
Assignement or Transferrence be made in Writing and be signed by the Party or Parties making the same or be
under the co[m]mon Seale of a Corporation or Body Politick or be signed by some Person or Persons by the Authority
or Direction of such Party or Parties Corporation or Body Politick and be within Ten Days after the signing
thereof entred or registred and that Oath be thereupon made in the Manner and Forme following that is to say in
case such Assignment or Transferrence be of Money payable by any Order att the Receipt of the Exchequer then
the said Assignment shall be registred by an Entry or Notification thereof in the Books kept or to be kept by the
Auditor of the Receipt of his Majesties Excheq[uer] or the Clerk of the Pells there for that purpose and the Person
or Persons to whom such Assignement of or upon any such Order shall be made or the Treasurer for any Corporation
or Body Politick who are to have the Benefitt of such Assignment or some other credible Person or Persons
imployed to make the Bargaine or Contract for which such Assignement shall be made and being privy thereunto
shall within the said Ten Days make Affidavits before the said Auditor or [the<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Clerk of the Pells in the said
Receipt of Excheq[uer] (who have hereby power to administer the same) that no Allowance Premium Gratuity or
Consideration whatsoever exceeding the lawfull Interest and the said Allowance not exceeding the Rate of Six
pounds per Cents as aforesaid directly or indirectly or by any Way Device Shift Exchange Wager Chevisance or
otherwise howsoever was taken accepted gained gotten or agreed to be taken accepted gained or gotten for or in
respect of such Assignement and in case such Assignement or Transferrence be of Money payable by any Talley
of Pro or Assignement att the Excise Office or att the General Post Office or in any other publick Office then
such Assignment or Transferrence shall be registred by an Entry or Notification thereof in the Books to be kept
for that purpose by the Co[m]missioners of Excise the Post-Master or Post-Masters General or other Chief Officers in
any of the said publick Offices for the time being respectively and the Person or Persons to whom such Assignement
of or upon any such Talley of Pro or Assignement shall be made or the Treasurer for any Corporation or Bodie
Politick or some other credible [p[er]son or<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Persons imployed to make the Bargaine or Contract for which such
Assignment shall be made and being privy thereunto as aforesaid shall within the said Ten Days make the like
Affidavitt as aforesaid before one or more of the said Co[m]missioners of Excise and Post Masters General or other
Chief Officers in such publick Office for the time being or such Persons as shall be deputed by them respectively
for this purpose who have hereby power to administer the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s59">
			<head>LIX. Officers in the Exchequer, Excise, and Post Office to attend daily for registering Assignments, and administering the Oaths; without Fee;</head>
			<para id="p91">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p92">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Auditor of the Receipt and the Clerk of the
Pells or one of them and some one or more of the said Co[m]missioners of Excise Post-Masters General or other Chief
Officers in the said publick Offices respectively or their respective Deputies shall from and after the said Tenth Day
of June One thousand six hundred ninety seaven attend dayly and every Day from the Houre of Nine to the Houre
of Twelve in the Forenoon (Sundays and such Holydays as are usually observed onely excepted) for registring or
causing to be registred the said Assignments and for administring the said Oaths and shall duely register &amp;
administer the same and shall upon the registring of every such Assignment and administring the said Affidavitt
relating thereunto make a Memorandum as well in their respective Books as upon the respective Writings of
Assignment [as<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] aforesaid importing that such Affidavit was duely administred according to this Act all which they
shall do and performe or cause to be done and performed without Fee or Charge under the paine of forfeiting
treble Damages besides Costs of Suit to the Party grieved and to be recovered by Action of Debt or of the Case
as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s60">
			<head>LX. Brokers, &amp;c. taking above 28. 6d. per Cent. for Brokerage, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p93">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;20.; or making Bargain in which greater Allowance made than herein mentioned; Penalty &pound;500.; and deemed a common Extortioner</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p94">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons who shall be imployed as
a Broker or Brokers Sollicitor or Sollicitors or otherwise in the behalfe of any other Person or Persons to make or
drive any Bargaine or Contract for the buying or selling of any of the said Orders or Tallies who shall after the
said Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven take or receive directly or indirectly any Su[m]m or
Su[m]ms of Money or other Reward or Thing for Broakidge solliciting driving procuring or making such Contract or
Bargaine over and above the Su[m]m of Two shillings and Six pence for the Broakidge solliciting driving or procuring
such Contract or Bargaine for One hundred pounds and so ratably for a greater or lesser Su[m]m shall forfeit for
every such Offence Twenty pounds to such Person or Persons as will sue for the same by Action of Debt or of
the Case as aforesaid and if any Broaker Sollicitor or Driver of any Bargaine or Contract for any such Tallies or
Orders as aforesaid shall after the said Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven drive or make
any such Bargaine or Contract for any Talley or Order or any Money due thereupon in which Contract or Bargaine
there shall be any Premium or Allowance made or agreed to be made contrary to this Act then hee or they so
offending shall for every such Offence forfeit the Su[m]m of Five hundred pounds to witt One third part thereof to
the King and the other Two thirds thereof to such Person or Persons who will sue for the same to be recovered
as aforesaid and that every such Broaker Sollicitor or Driver of such Bargaine who shall be guilty of such Offence
and be thereof convicted shall be deemed and is hereby adjudged to be a co[m]mon Extortioner and shall suffer
such further Paines and Penalties as by the Laws and Statutes of this Realme may be inflicted for co[m]mon Extortion.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s61">
			<head>LXI.</head>
			<para id="p95">
				<emph type="i">Claimers of Orders purchased before 10th June 1697 not obliged to take the Oath concerning the Premium</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p96">And whereas diverse Persons have or before the said Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven
may have purchased and bought several Orders of Loan or Parts thereof or such Talleys as aforesaid neglecting
to have their Assignements thereof to be duely registred as the Law directs &amp; many of them instead of taking
formal Assignments which might be registred have accepted from the Person or Persons who should make the
same the indorsing of his or their Names onely upon such Orders be it further enacted and provided by the
Authority aforesaid That where any such Orders of Loan or Parts thereof or such Tallyes have been actually and
bona fide purchased and bought before the said Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven and
Oath thereof shall be made att any Time or Times within Three Months from thence next ensuing before any of
the Officers or Persons hereby authorized to administer the other Oaths concerning the Premium or Allowance as
aforesaid in all such Cases the Person or Persons claiming such Orders or Parts of Orders or Talleys by such
Assignments not registred or by such Indorsements shall not in respect there of be obliged by virtue of this Act
to take the said other Oath concerning the Premium Reward or Allowance Any thing herein contained to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s62">
			<head>LXII. Affidavit to be in Writing, and filed.</head>
			<para id="p97">And be it further enacted That the Affidavitt herein before directed shall be in Writing and remaine filed with
the respective Officers before whome the same shall be made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s63">
			<head>LXIII. Recital of c. 6. ante.</head>
			<para id="p98">
				<emph type="i">&sect;94; Exchequer Bills to be taken for Taxes, &amp;c. granted this Parliament, and in all Payments at the Exchequer due to the King.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p99">And whereas by an Act of this present Session of Parliament intituled An Act for granting an Aid to His
Majesty as well by a Land Tax as by several Subsidies and other Duties payable for One Yeare itt is amongst
other things enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Co[m]missioners of his Majesties Treasury or
any Three of them now being or the High Treasurer or any Three or more of the Co[m]missioners of his Majesties
Treasury for the time being to cause Bills to be made forth att the Receipt of Excheq[uer] in such manner and forme
as they shall appoint for any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money not exceeding One million five hundred thousand pounds
by virtue of that Act and to issue the same to the Uses of the Warr in such Proportions as they shall think fitt
and that the said Bills shall be current to the Receivers or Collectors of any Aids Taxes or Supplies thereby
granted or that should be granted for the Service of the Warr for the Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety
seven (except for the Aid of Three shillings in the Pound) and such other Directions are thereby given concerning
the making issuing receiving back and cancelling the said Bills as in and by the said Act relation being thereunto
had more att large appears Now to the end the said Bills so authorized to be issued may be of more general
Use as well for the Occasions of the Warr as for the publick Co[m]merce and Trade be it further enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That the said Bills so authorized to be issued shall be received and taken not onely by Receivors
or Collectors of the Taxes or Supplies granted or to be granted for the Warr for the Yeare One thousand six
hundred ninety seven but shall also passe and be current to all and every the Co[m]missioners Receivers or Collectors
of any Revenue Aid Tax or Supply whatsoever already granted or that shall or may be granted dureing this
present Session of Parliament either for the Warr or any other Use and also att the Receipt of the Excheq[uer] from
the said Co[m]missioners Receivers or Collectors or from any other Person or Persons whatsoever making any Payments
there to his Majesty upon any Account whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s64">
			<head>LXIV. Bills to bear 5d. a Day per Cent. Interest till paid into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p100">And to the end that all Persons may be the more willing and ready to accept and receive the said Bills in all
Manner of Paym[en]ts. be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That there shall be annexed unto attend and go along
with the said Bills an Interest after the Rate of Five pence a Day for every One hundred Pounds contained therein
and so proportionably for a greater or lesser Su[m]m which said Interest shall be payed or allowed to the Person who
is last possest thereof to the Day hee pays the same into the Excheq[uer] or to any Receivers or Collectors for any
Aids Taxes Revenues or Supplies whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s65">
			<head>LXV. Bills paid into the Exchequer to be signed by Person paying, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p101">And that no Interest may be allowed on the said [former<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] Bills for any longer time than the same shall be
unanswered to His Majesty Itt is hereby enacted That the Person who pays the same into the Exchequer or to
any Receivers or Collectors for any Aids Taxes or Revenues shall at the Time of making such Paym[en]t. putt his
Name to the said Bill and write the Day of the Month to which Day the Collector or other Person who receives
the same to His Majesties Use shall be allowed again the Interest that hee shall have allowed thereupon and when
any of the said Bills which in pursuance of this Act shall be received att the Exchequer Custom-House Excise
Office or General Letter Office or by any of his Majesties Receivers or Collectors or for any Revenues Taxes or
Supplies shall be applicable to the Satisfaction of Tallies &amp; Orders of Loan or to any other Uses or Payments
whatsoever and by reason thereof are not to be i[m]mediately cancelled att the said Exchequer or in any other publick
Office then the respective Tellers in the Receipt of the Excheq[uer] and the Receivers General or Cashiers of the
Customes Excise and Post Office or any other Receivers upon their issuing or paying out the said Bills shall sign
the same and add the Day of the Month and so toties quoties until the said Bills shall or may come or be paid
into the Excheq[uer] on account of the proper Funds or Supplies (upon which they are or shall be first issued out)
to be cancelled.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s66">
			<head>LXVI.</head>
			<para id="p102">
				<emph type="i">Treasury may contract for lending Money to exchange Exchequer Bills not accepted in Payment; Persons so lending Monies to have the said Bills for Security, or other Security agreed upon, and Interest at &pound;10 per Cent. per Ann</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p103">And to the intent that such Person or Persons who have or may have or be intituled to any Talleys or Orders
on any Branch of the Revenues or on any Aid Tax or Supply that is or shall be appropriated for repayment and
Satisfaction thereof and shall refuse or be unwilling to accept the said Bills in payment may not be obliged to
receive the same Be it further enacted That for the Ease Accomodation and Satisfaction of all and every Person
and Persons so refusing or being unwilling to receive the said Bills in repayment of such Talleys and Orders Itt
shall and may be lawfull to and for the Co[m]missioners of his Majesties Treasury or any Three of them now
being or the High Treasurer or any Three or more of the Co[m]missioners of his Majesties Treasury for the time
being to covenant and agree in such manner as they shall think fitt with any Persons Natives or Foreigners
Bodies Politic or Corporate (with whose Abilities they shall be well satisfied) for the i[m]mediate advancing or lending
of Money from Time to Time as there shall be occasion for exchanging such Bills as shall be so refused or not
accepted or taken in repayment of Tallies and Orders as aforesaid And that such Person and Persons as shall so
contract and agree with the said Co[m]missioners of the Treasury or High Treasurer to advance and furnish Money
for the exchangeing and circulating the said Bills in such Manner as the said Co[m]missioners of the Treasury or High
Treasurer shall appoint shall i[m]mediately upon their paying or advancing any Moneys pursuant to their Contracts or
Agreements have for their Security &amp; Satisfaction the said Bills or such Security as shall be agreed upon between
the said Co[m]missioners of the Treasury and the said Contractors and shall also have and receive as a further
Encouragement an Interest or Reward not exceeding the Rate of Ten pounds per Cents per Annum for the Su[m]ms
so by them respectively contracted or agreed to be furnished or advanced from the Day they become severally
obliged for and dureing so long time as their said Obligations shall be in force.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s67">
			<head>LXVII. Contractors Names, &amp;c. to be registered in the Auditor's Office, and Interest to be paid quarterly.</head>
			<para id="p104">And for the better ascertaining such Interest to the said Lenders or Contractors be it further enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That the Names of such Lenders or Contractors and the Dates of their respective Contracts
and Su[m]ms contracted for shall be registred in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt of the Excheq[uer] and that
the said Interest shall be paid out of the Supplies granted for carrying on the Warr against France for the Service
of the Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety and seven quarterly for so long time as the said Contractors shall
stand obliged as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s68">
			<head>LXVIII. Until the King by Proclamation make known when Exchequer Bills may be exchanged for ready Money, the said Bills to be current only for Aids, &amp;c. of 1697, afterwards for all Revenues, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p105">[Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That until such Time as his Majesty by his
Royal Proclamation to be issued by the Advice of his Privy Council shall be pleased to publish and make knowne
that the said Comissioners of his Majesties Treasury or Three or more of them or the High Treasurer for the
Time being shall (by such Covenants or Agreements made with Persons of Ability as aforesaid) have sufficiently
secured and made Provision that all Persons who att the said Receipt of Excheq[uer] or att any the said publick
Offices shall have any of the said Bills for satisfaction of their Tallies or Orders of Loan or for any other Payments
whatsoever may have such Bills exchanged for ready Money the said Bills so to be made forth for the said Fifteen
hundred thousand pounds or any part thereof shall be current onely for the Aids Taxes or Supplies granted or to
be granted for the Service of the Warr for the Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety seven exclusive of the
said Aid of Three shillings in the Pound according to the tenour and true meaning of the said former Act in
that behalfe and that after the said Proclamation shall be issued and not sooner the said Bills so authorized to be
issued as aforesaid shall passe and be current for all Revenues Aids Taxes Supplies or other Payments to his Majestie
according to the true meaning of this present Act Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.<ref idref="n16">16</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s69">
			<head>LXIX. 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 22. &sect; 3.</head>
			<para id="p106">
				<emph type="i">12 Car. II. c. 18; 15 Car. II. c. 7; 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 22; Further Time allowed for administering and taking the Oath in the said Acts mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p107">And whereas by an Act of Parliament made in the Seventh and Eighth Yeares of the Reigne of his p[re]sent
Majestie entituled An Act for preventing Frauds and regulating Abuses in the Plantation Trade it is amongst other
things therein enacted That all the present Governors and Co[m]manders in Chief of any English Colonies or Plantations
shall before the Five and Twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety seven and all who shall be
made Governors or Co[m]manders in Chief of the said Colonies or Plantations or any of them before the entring into
their Governments shall take a solemne Oath to do their utmost that the Clauses Matters and Things contained
in one Act of Parliament made in the Twelfth Yeare of the Reigne of the late King Charles the Second intituled
An Act for encourageing &amp; increasing of Shipping and Navigation and One other Act made in the Fifteenth Yeare
of his said late Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for Encouragement of Trade and also the said Act made in the
Seventh and Eighth Yeares of the Reigne of his present Maj[es]ty. intituled An Act for preventing Frauds and regulating
Abuses in the Plantation Trade be punctually and bona fide observed according to the true intent and meaning
thereof so farr as appertains unto the said Governors or Co[m]manders in Chief respectively And whereas the Persons
appointed to administer the said Oaths are by some Accidents prevented from performing the same within the
time limitted by the said Act to the end therefore that the good intent of the said Act may not be disappointed
for want of time to putt the same in Execution Be it therefore enacted That further time shall be allowed for
administring the said Oath and that all present Governors &amp; Comanders in Chief of any English Colonies or
Plantations shall before the Five and Twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety eight and who
shall hereafter be made Governors or Co[m]manders in Chief of the said Colonies or Plantations or any of them shall
att their Entrance upon their respective Governments or within the space of Six Months after the same take a
solemne Oath to do their utmost that all the Clauses Matters and Things contained in the before recited Acts of
Parliament or any of them heretofore passed and now in force relateing to the said Colonies and Plantations be
punctually and bona fide observed according to the true intent &amp; meaning thereof which Oath shall be taken before
such Person or Persons as shall be appointed by his Majesty his Heires and Successors who are hereby authorized
to administer the same so farr as appertaines to the Governors or Co-manders in Chief respectively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s70">
			<head>LXX.</head>
			<para id="p108">
				<emph type="i">Tellers in the Exchequer to receive the said Monies, and discharge the Receiver</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p109">And whereas the Su[m]m of Three thousand two hundred and eighty pounds eight shillings and nine pence was
actually and bona fide received by Ralph Williamson Receiver General of the Fourth Aid of Foure shillings in
the Pound in the Counties of York Durham and Northumb[er]land for the said Aid within the Counties aforesaid
which Su[m]m consisting of hammered Monies is deposited in the Receipt of his Majesties Excheq[uer] but the same or the
greatest Part thereof is not charged as Money actually paid into the said Receipt be it further enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That the Tellers in the said Receipt of Excheq[uer] or some of them shall forthwith receive
the said Money amounting to Three thousand two hundred &amp; eighty pounds eight shillings &amp; nine pence upon
the said Receivers Account of the said Aid &amp; shall throw downe a Bill or Bills for the same according to the
Course of the Excheq[uer] to the end the said Receiver may have a Talley or Talleys for his Discharge and the
said Collectors and other his Majesties Subjects in the said Counties may have no further trouble concerning
the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s71">
			<head>LXXI. 7 &amp; 8 W. 3. c. 31.</head>
			<para id="p110">
				<emph type="i">&sect; 61; Tobacco Pipes found unfit for Sale, may on Notice be reburnt, and then the Duty to be paid; and free from Penalties</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p111">And whereas in and by one Act of Parliament made and passed in the Seventh &amp; Eighth Yeares of his
Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for continuing to his Majesty certaine Duties upon Salt glasse Wares stone &amp;
earthen Wares &amp; for granting several Duties upon Tobacco Pipes &amp; other earthen Wares for carrying on the Warr
against France &amp; for establishing a National Land Bank &amp; [for<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] taking off the Duties upon Tunnage of Ships &amp;
upon Coals Itt is amongst other things provided That if any of those Wares upon drawing are broken or otherwise
made unfitt for Sale there shall no Duty grow due for the same by virtue of that Act but the Officers shall see
the same destroyed And whereas it often happens that [where<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Tobacco Pipe Makers do make &amp; burn Tobacco
Pipes that att the opening or drawing of the Potts Kilns Furnaces or Ovens wherein the same are burnt or nealed
the Tobacco Pipes or a [great<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Part of them are unfitt for Sale by reason of some default in the Burning &amp;.
nealing thereof &amp; the destroying the same by the Officer is of great Losse to the Maker when as such Tobacco
Pipes may be rendred fitt for Sale in case they were new burnt or nealed For the remedying of which Mischief
be it hereby enacted &amp; declared by the Authority aforesaid That from &amp; after the First Day of May One thousand
six hundred ninety seven if any Tobacco Pipe Makers upon drawing their Tobacco Pipes out of their Potts Kilns
Furnaces or Ovens shall find the same or any Part thereof unfitt for sale that it shall &amp; may be lawfull for such
Tobacco Pipe Maker or Makers (on Notice given to the said Officer of his Intention to reburne the same) to
putt such Tobacco Pipes into any Pott Kiln Furnace or Oven to be reburnt or nealed &amp; on the drawing of the
same shall then pay the Duty by the said Act charged or otherwise be destroyed &amp; that the said Tobacco Pipe
Maker or Makers so reburning or nealing such Tobacco Pipes as aforesaid shall not be liable to any of the
Penalties in the said Act mentioned.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">On a separate Schedule annexed to the Original Act.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


