<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46863" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for repairing the High-way betweene Ryegate in the County of Surrey &amp; Crawley in the County of Sussex. [Chapter XV. Rot. Parl. 8 &amp; 9 Gul. III.p.3. nu.3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that the Lanes herein mentioned are in a ruinous and dangerous State; and that the several Parishes were unable of themselves to repair the same.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Justices on Special Sessions held pursuant to 3 W. &amp; M. c. 12. to appoint Surveyors of the Highways yearly; Surveyors to meet in 10 Days after Election,; within their Divisions, to view the Lanes,; and certify; Orders of Sessions to be observed</emph>.
<emph type="i">Carts and Persons liable to work, and to be paid the Rate of the Country.; Differences settled by Two Justices</emph>.
</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the High-way betweene Ryegate in the County of Surrey &amp; Crawley in the County of Sussex
(that is to say) the Lanes leading from Woodhatch Borough to Sidlow Mill and Salmons Crosse in the
said Parish of Ryegate and the Lanes called Horsehill and Bonehurst ats Borners and Petteridge in the Parish of
Horley in the said County of Surrey being the Road from Stenning Horsham &amp; other Parts of great Trade and
Co[m]merce in the County of Sussex to London are very ruinous and almost impassable for above three Miles in
length insomuch that it is become dangerous to all Persons that passe those ways and for that the ordinary course
appointed by the Laws and Statutes of this Realme now in force is not sufficient for the effectual repairing and
amending the same neither are the Inhabitants of the several and respective Parishes in which the said ruinous
Lanes do lye of ability to repaire the same without some other Provision be made for repairing thereof there
being also no Materials for the amending thereof to be had but att great distance from the said respective Places
For remedy whereof and to the intent the same may be forthwith effectually repaired and amended and kept in
good repaire may it please Your Majesty that it may be enacted and be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent
Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Co[m]mons in this
present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That for the surveying ordering repairing &amp; keeping
in repaire of the said ruinous Places in the said Roads or Lanes the Justices of the Peace att their next special
Sessions to be holden for the said County pursuant to an Act made in the Third and Fourth Yeares of the
Reigne of His present Majesty and the late Queen intituled An Act for the better repaireing or amending the
High-ways shall and may then and there and so from time to time in every yeare no[m]i[n]ate and appoint a convenient
number of sufficient and able Persons Inhabitants of the Parish or Place aforesaid to be the several and respective
Surveyors of the respective Places aforesaid for the yeare from thence next ensuing and in default of such
Surveyors that the said Justices att their special Sessions may appoint such other Person or Persons to be Surveyors
who shall be willing to accept of the said Office and that the said Justices shall cause notice to be given to the
several Surveyors so chosen in Writing of the said Choice which said Surveyors and every of them (having no
lawfull Impediment to be allowed by the said Justices by whom they shall be chosen in manner aforesaid or any
Two of them within ten Days next after such Notice to him or them given of their Election) shall and are hereby
required to meet in some convenient Place within their respective Divisions for the which they are appointed
Surveyors to the intent to view and survey the said respective Lanes and consider the Defects thereof and the
best method and means that can be used for the repairing and also the several Su[m]ms of Money that will be
necessary for making good the same and make their respective Certificates thereof to the Justices of Peace att the
next special Sessions to be held as aforesaid who thereupon shall and may make such Order and Orders in and
about the same as to them shall seem good which said Order or Orders so to be made shall be by the said
				respective Surveyors and all other p[er]sons concerned in putting this Act in Execuc[i]on duely observed and performed
and the said respective Surveyors are hereby impowered to appoint and require such Carts and Persons (who are
liable to work in the High-ways by the Statutes already in force) from time to time to come and work in the
said respective Places as they shall think needfull and appoint for which the said respective Surveyors shall pay
unto such Labourers and to the Owners of such Teams Carts and Wains according to the usual Rate of the
Countrey wherein if any difference happen the same to be settled by Two or more Justices of the Peace next
thereunto which is to be conclusive to all Parties.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. If not sufficient Gravel, Chalk, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Surveyors may dig out of neighbouring Common, paying for the same; Damage to be assessed by Sessions, and Pits filled up again if desired, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That where there is not sufficient Gravel Chalk Sand or
Stones within any Parish Towne Hamlett or Village wherein the said ruinous Places do severally lie to repaire the
same it shall and may be lawfull for the said Surveyors in their several and respective Places and such Person
or Persons as they shall appoint to digg take and carry away Gravel Chalk Sand or Stones if the said Justices of
the Peace shall direct the same out of the Waste or Co[m]mon of any neighbouring Parish Towne Village or Hamlett
paying a reasonable Satisfaction for the same Materials to the Person or Persons that have right to the Soyl where
the same shall be so digged and carried away and for such Damage hee or they shall thereby sustaine to be
assessed and adjudged by the said Justices att the next special Sessions for the said County in case of difference
concerning the same and that the Pitts &amp; Places where and from whence such Materials shall be digged and carried
away for the Reparations aforesaid shall with all convenient speed if adjudged by the said Justices of Peace as
aforesaid or desired by the Party owning such Ground be filled upp and levelled with Earth or other Materials.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Sessions to appoint a Receiver of the Toll.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">The Rates to be paid for Horses, Carts, &amp;c; All Persons to pay Rates to Collector; Place for collecting Toll to be on the Highway, and a Turnpike set up; Collector to give in a monthly Account on Oath; Sessions to examine same; Refusing to pay the Toll, Collector to distrain; Distress paid to Surveyors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And for defraying of the Charge in and about the Reparations to be done in the Places aforesaid Be it further
enacted That the said Justices att their special Sessions aforesaid shall and may choose and appoint one or more
fitt Person or Persons to be Receiver or Receivers Collector or Collectors of such Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money in
the name of Toll or Custome to be paid for all such Horses Coaches Carts Waggons Droves and Gangs of
Cattle as in to come shall passe be led or droven in or through the said Way as are hereafter in this Act
limitted (that is to say) For every Horse one Penny for every Stage-Coach or Hackney-Coach six Pence for
every other Coach Calash or Chariot six Pence for every Waggon six Pence for every Cart six Pence for every
score of Sheep or Lambs one Penny and so proportionable for every greater or lesser Number for every score of
Calves two Pence for every score of Hoggs two Pence and so for every greater or lesser Number of Calves
or Hoggs proportionably not being under five for every score of Oxen or Neat Cattell six Pence and so for every
greater or lesser Number proportionably And that from and after the passing this Act all &amp; (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Person and Persons
who shall travel or passe with Horse Coach Cart or Waggon or that shall passe lead or drive any Oxen Sheep
or other Cattel before mentioned in and through the Highway aforesaid shall and are hereby required to pay unto
the said Collector or Collectors Receiver or Receivers of Toll in that behalfe from time to time to be appointed
as aforesaid after the Rates aforesaid the Place or Places for collecting the said Toll to be in some convenient
Place upon the High-way in or neare the said Lanes by setting upp a Turnpike or Gate Turnpikes or Gates there
as the Justices of the Peace att the next special Sessions to be held for the said County next after the passing
this Act shall direct and appoint and the Person or p[er]sons Receiver or Receivers Collector or Collectors appointed
as aforesaid for the receiving of the said Toll shall give in a true monthly Account upon Oath unto one or more
Justices of the Peace that lives neare to the Lanes aforesaid (which Oath they are hereby impowered to administer)
which said Account shall be duely returned to the Justices of the Peace att the next Special Sessions to be
holden for the Hundred aforesaid who shall thereupon examine the same and make such Orders therein as to them
shall seem meet according to the true meaning of this Act and in case any Person or Persons upon demand made
of Toll aforesaid by the Collector or Receiver (in that behalfe to be appointed) shall neglect or refuse to pay
the same That then it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Collector or Receiver appointed for Receipt
of the said Toll upon such Refusal to distraine and detaine such Horse Cart Coach Calash Chariott Waggon
Oxen or other Cattle before mentioned or any of them until the said Toll shall be satisfied and paid according to
the Tenour of this present Act together with such Damags as the Party or Parties so distraining shall sustaine in
and about the making the said Distresse or by the keeping thereof Which said Moneys so to be received shall
be paid proportionably to the said Surveyors for and towards the Amendment of the said Lanes according to the
true meaning hereof and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Surveyors to account to Sessions for Monies received from Collectors, and of Disbursements.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Overplus paid to Surveyors for Year ensuing.; Allowance to Surveyors</emph>.
								<emph type="i">Collectors or Surveyors not making Payment; Sessions to enquire of Default; and on Conviction, commit to Gaol</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And be it furthere enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Surveyors and every of them att the first
special Sessions to be holden for the said Division by force of the said recited Act shall make and yeild up unto
the said Justices of the Peace there to be assembled a perfect Account in Writing under their Hands of all
Moneys which hee they or any of them have received from the said Collector or Receivor of Toll and likewise
of all their Disbursements in and about the said Highway or otherwise by reason of their Offices and in case of
any Overplus of Money so received remaine in their Hands shall pay the same to the Surveyors to be chosen
for the yeare ensuing to be disbursed and laid out in mending the said Lanes according to the true meaning of
this Act and not elsewhere which said Justices to whom such Account shall be given att the said Special Sessions
shall out of the Benefitt of the said Toll make such Allowance unto the said Surveyors or Surveyor for and in
considerac[i]on of their Care and Pains taken in Execution of their Offices and to such other Person and Persons
who have been or shall be assisting in and about procuring the said High-ways to be amended as aforesaid by
advancing or laying out any Moneys or otherwise relating thereto as to them shall seem good and in case the
				Collector or Receiver of the aforesaid Toll so to be paid as aforesaid shall not upon request duely pay the same
unto the said Surveyors for the time being so to be appointed as aforesaid or in case the said Surveyors or any
of them shall not make such Account &amp; Payment unto the several Person &amp; Persons according to the Order
Direcc[i]on and Appointment of the said Justices as aforesaid that then the said Justices att any such Special Sessions
to be holden for the said Division shall make Inquiry concerning such Default as well by Confession of the said
p[er]ties themselves as by Testimony of Two or more credible Witnesses upon Oath which Oath they are hereby
impowered to administer and if any Person, or Persons shall be thereof convicted the said Justices upon such
Conviction shall co[m]mitt the Party or Parties so convict to the Co[m]mon[Goal<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] of the said County there to remaine
without Bail or Mainprize until hee or they shall have made a true and perfect Account and Payment as aforesaid:</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Surveyors, on Order of Sessions, may engage Toll for Loans at &pound;6 per Cent. per Ann.: and grant same for 15 Years; Money lent to be distributed by Sessions</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And forasmuch as the Moneys so to be collected by such Receipt of the said Toll will not att present raise
such a Stock or Su[m]m of Money as may be sufficient for the speedy repairing of the Premisses Itt is hereby further
enacted That the said Surveyors or the more part of them are hereby enabled by Order of the said Justices to be
be made att such Special Sessions and not otherwise to engage the Profitts arising by the said Toll for such Su[m]m
or Su[m]ms by them to be borrowed for that purpose and by Indenture under the Hands and Seals of the said
Surveyors for the time being or the more part of them to transferr the said Profitts of the said Toll and to grant
and convey the same for any time not exceeding Fifteen Yeares unto any person or persons that shall or will
upon that Security advance any present Su[m]m or Sum[m]s of Money so lent with Interest for the same after the Rate
of Six pounds per Cent[um] per Annum for every Hundred pounds which said Money so to be advanced shall be distributed
by the Justices att such Special Sessions in the proportions and for the purposes aforesaid and not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Persons refusing to be Surveyors, or to do their Duty,</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Penalty; Distress; On Death of Surveyor, Two Justices may appoint another</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any person or persons not having any lawfull
Excuse to be allowed as aforesaid shall neglect or refuse to take upon him or them the said Office of Surveyor
being thereunto nominated and chosen as by this Act is appointed or to do and performe his or their Duty in
the due and speedy Execution of this Act the said Justices att such Special Sessions shall and may hereby have
power to impose on such person or persons so refusing or neglecting such Fine or Fines not exceeding Five
pounds upon such person or persons so refusing as to them shall seem meet and to cause the same to be levied
by Distresse and Sale of his or their Goods rendring to the Party the Overplus if any shall be and then and in
any such case or in case of the death of any of the said Surveyors some other person or persons shall be appointed
as aforesaid by Two or more Justices of Peace that live nearest to the Party or Parties so dying refusing or
neglecting and such other person or persons so to be appointed by the said Justices are hereby required to execute
their said Offices in such Manner and under such Penalties as if they had been chosen by the Justices att their
special Sessions as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Fines paid to the Surveyors.</head>
			<para id="p13">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Fines and Forfeitures to be imposed or incurred
by virtue of this Act shall be paid to the Surveyors for the time being for and towards the repairing of the said
Lanes according to the true meaning of this Act and not to any other p[er]son or persons or to or for for any other
use or uses intent or purpose whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Actions for executing Act to be laid in Surrey.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">General Issue; If brought in any other County, Jury to find for Defendant Double Costs, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Suit shall be co[m]menced against any Person for
any thing done in pursuance of this present Act that in every such Case the Action shall be laid in the said
County of Surrey not elsewhere and the Defend<emph type="p">t</emph>. in such Action to be brought may plead the general Issue and
give this Act and the special Matter in Evidence att any Tryal to be had thereupon &amp; that the same was done in
pursuance and by the Authority of the said Act And if it shall so appeare to be done or that such Action shall
be brought in any other County that then the Jury shall find for the Defendant and upon such Verdict or if the
Plaintiffe shall be nonsuited or discontinue his Action after the Defendant shall have appeared or if upon Demurrer
Judgement shall be given against the Plaintiffe the said Defendant shall have &amp; recover his double Costs and have
the like Remedy for the same as any Defendant hath in other Cases by Law.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. No Second Toll for the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">In what Case Persons in neighbouring Parishes may carry Stones, &amp;c. and Hay Carts, &amp;c. in Hay Time, &amp;c. Toll-free; Soldiers on March with Waggons, and Persons riding Post, Toll-free</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">Provided always that no person or persons having occasion to passe the place where the Toll is taken and
return the same day before Eight of the Clock att Night between the Months of September and February and
before Ten of the Clock att Night dureing the other Months of the Yeare with the same Horse Coach Waggon
Cart or other Carriage or with other Cattel shall be compelled the same day to pay the said Toll a second time
And further also that all and every person and persons passing through the place appointed for the receiving the
Toll aforesaid and coming from any Parish next adjoyning to the said Lanes respectively shall have liberty to carry
any quantities of Stones Sand Lime or Gravel Dung Mould or Compost of any nature or kind whatsoever Brick
or Chalk or any Wood not goeing to any Markett and that all Carts with Hay not goeing to any Markett or
Corne in the Straw att Hay-time or Harvest Ploughs Harrows and other Implements of Husbandry and all other
Things whatsoever imployed in the husbandring stocking and manuring of their several and respective Lands in
the said several and respective Parishes shall passe through the said Place where such Toll is to be received as
aforesaid without paying any thing for their respective passing through the same And that it shall and may be
lawfull also for all and every Soldier &amp; Soldiers upon their March and all Carts and Waggons attending them
and all p[er]sons riding Post to passe through the said Places where the said Toll is to be collected without paying
any thing for their passing Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Persons chargeable for repairing Highways to remain so.</head>
			<para id="p18">Provided also That all and every person and persons who by Law are chargeable towards the repairing the
said Highways shall still remaine so chargeable and do their respective Works in the said High-ways as before they
used to do therein Any thing aforesaid to the contrary thereof notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Act to be in force for 20 Years.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Toll to cease after sufficient Reparation, and Monies repaid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">Provided also That neither this Act nor any thing herein contained shall extend to any further time or be of
force any longer than the terme of Twenty Yeares to be accounted from the passing of this Act And also that
if any time before the expiration of the Twenty Yeares aforesaid the said Lanes shall be sufficiently amended and
repaired and so adjudged by the Justices of the Peace of the said County att the Quarter Sessions to be holden
for the said County that then from and after such Adjudication made and Repayment of such Monies as shall
have been borrowed the aforesaid Toll shall cease and determine Any thing herein contained to the contrary
thereof notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Quarter Sessions for Surrey and Sussex may appoint yearly Three Persons of each County to survey ruinous Lanes, and examine Surveyors' Accounts.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">If Misapplication of Monies, &amp;c. Judges of Assise to determine the same</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Justices
of the Peace att their General Quarter Sessions to be holden for the County of Surrey and also the Justices of
the Peace att the General Quarter Sessions to be holden for the County of Sussex yearely and every yeare after
the Feast of the Epiphany if they think fitt to appoint Three Persons of each County respectively to survey and
view the said ruinous Lanes and Ways and to examine the Accounts of the Surveyors of the same Lanes and
Ways by this Act from time to time appointed and the Duties and Tolls received in pursuance of this Act and
to enquire how the Monies so received have been from time to time employed and laid out in pursuance of this
Act and in case they find any Misapplication of the Moneys levied by this Act or any Abuses of the Powers and
Authorities to them limitted as aforesaid thereupon to certifie the same to the Judges of Assize att the next Assizes
to be held for the said County of Surrey who are hereby authorized and impowered to heare examine and finally
determine the same without any further or other Appeal.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">every <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Gaole <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

