<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46860" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII. An Act for continuing several additional Impositions upon several Goods and Merchandizes. [Rot. parl. 8&amp;9 Gul. III.p.2.nu.6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Additional Impositions on Goods imported by 4 W. &amp; M.c.5. &amp;c. continued from 1st March 1696 to 17th May 1697.</head>
		<para id="p1">Wee your Majesties most dutiful and loyal Subjects the Co[m]mons assembled in Parliament for a further Supply of Your Majesties extraordinary Occasions and the effectual Prosecution of the Warr against France and for Satisfaction of such Persons who have advanced and lent Moneys into Your Majesties Exchequer for the purposes aforesaid have chearfully &amp; unanimously given and granted unto Your Majesty the Impositions and Duties herein after mentioned for and dureing the Terme hereafter expressed and do most humbly beseech Your Majesty that it may be enacted and be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That the several additional &amp; other Rates Impositions Duties and Charges upon Goods and Merchandize imported into this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed and from thence exported mentioned expressed and granted in and by an Act made in the Fourth and Fifth Yeares of the Reigne of his present Majesty and the late Queen Mary intituled An Act for granting to their Majesties certaine additional
Impositions upon several Goods and Merchandizes for the prosecuting the present Warr against France shall be continued from the First Day of March in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety six and be raised levied collected answered &amp; paid unto His Majesty His Heires and Successors until the Seventeenth Day of May in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety seven and that the said Act and all Powers Provisions Penalties Articles and Clauses therein contained shall continue and be of full Force and Effect until the said Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety seven and shall be applyed practised &amp; executed for raiseing levying collecting answering and paying the said additional Duties and other Rates and Impositions hereby continued according to the Tenor and Intent of this present Act.</para>
	</section>
</report>


