<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46872" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIV. An Act for granting to His Majesty a further Subsidy of Tunnage and Poundage upon Merchandizes imported for the Terme of Two Yeares &amp; Three Quarters &amp; an additional Land Tax for One Yeare for carrying on the Warr against France. [Rot. Parl. 8 &amp; 9 Gul. III. p. 8. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Additional Subsidy of Tunnage on Wines imported from 1st May 1697 and before 1st Feb. 1699.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The same as expressed in Book of Rates.; 12 Car. II. c. 4; Additional Subsidy of Poundage on Goods imported during the same Time; How Value of Goods ascertained.; Exceptions out of Subsidy of Poundage</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee your Majesties most dutiful and loyal Subjects the Co[m]mons of England in Parliament assembled being
desirous to raise so much Money as may be sufficient for the Defence of your Majesties Realmes and for
carrying on the Warr against France do for that end and purpose give and grant unto your Majesty the further
Aids and Supplies herein after mentioned and do humbly beseech your Majesty that it may be enacted and be it
enacted by [the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice &amp; Consent of the Lords Spiritual and
Temporal and of the Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by Authority of the same That over and
above all Subsidies of Tunnage &amp; Poundage and over and over all additional Duties Impositions and other Duties
whatsoever by any other Act or Acts of Parliament or otherwise howsoever already due or payable or which
ought to be paid to his Majesty for or upon any Wines Goods or Merchandizes whatsoever imported or to be
imported there shall be raised levied collected paid and satisfied unto his Majesty his Heires and Successors one other
Subsidy called Tunnage for and upon all Wines which (from and after the First Day of May One thousand six
hundred ninety seven and before the First Day of February which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred ninety nine) shall be imported or brought into the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or the
Towne of Berwick upon Tweed (that is to say) of every Tun of Wine of the Growth of France or of any the
Dominions of the French King or Crowne of France that shall come into the Port of London and the Members
thereof by way of Merchandize by his Majesties natural borne Subjects the Su[m]m of Foure pounds &amp; ten shillings
of current English Money and so after that Rate and by Strangers and Aliens Six pounds of like Money and of
every Tun of the like Wine which shall be brought into all and every the other Ports and Places of this Kingdome
and the Dominions thereof by way of Merchandize by his Majesties natural borne Subjects the Su[m]m of Three
pounds and by Aliens Foure pounds ten shillings and of every Butt or Pipe of Muscadels Malmeseys Cutes Tents
Alicants Bastards Sacks Canaries Malagaes Maderaes &amp; other Wines whatsoever co[m]monly called Sweet Wines of
the Growth of the Levant Spain Portugal or any of them or any of the Islands or Dominions to them or any
of them belonging or elsewhere that shall come or be brought into the Port of London by his Majesties natural
borne Subjects the Su[m]m of Forty five shillings of current English Money and so after that Rate and by Strangers
&amp; Aliens Three pounds of like Money and of every Butt and Pipe of the like Wine which shall come or be
brought into all and every or any the other Ports and Places of this Kingdome and Dominions thereof by way
of Merchandize by his Majesties natural borne Subjects the Su[m]m of Thirty shillings and by Strangers Forty five
shillings and of every Awm of Rhenish Wine or Wine of the Growth of Germany that shall be brought into
this Realme and the Dominions thereof by his Majesties natural borne Subjects the Su[m]m of Twenty shillings of
current English Money and by Strangers and Aliens Twenty five shillings and that such Wines as shall be landed 
in any of the out Ports and afterwards brought to the Port of London by Certificate shall pay so much more
Subsidy by this Act as they paid short of the Duty due in the Port of London which several Rates for Wines
are the same which are expressed in a certaine Book of Rates which were signed by Sir Harbottle Grimston
Baronett formerly Speaker of the House of Co[m]mons and which is referred to by an Act of Parliament made in
the Twelfth Yeare of the Reigne of King Charles the Second intituled A Subsidy granted to the King of Tunnage
and Poundage &amp; other Su[m]ms of Money payable upon Merchandizes exported &amp; imported and one further Subsidy
called Poundage (that is to say) of all manner of Goods and Merchandizes of every Merchant natural borne
Subject Denizen &amp; Alien to be imported or brought into this Realme or any his Majesties Dominions to the same
belonging att any time or times after the said First Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety seven and
before the said First Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety nine by way of Merchandize of the Value
of every Twenty shillings of the same Goods &amp; Merchandizes according to the several and particular Rates and
Values of the same Goods and Merchandizes as the same are particularly and respectively rated and valued in the
aforesaid Book of Rates Twelve pence and so after that Rate and if there shall happen to be brought into this
Realme any Goods liable to the Payment of Subsidy by this Act granted which are not particularly rated in the
said Book of Rates that in every such Case every Customer or Collector for the time being shall levy the Subsidy
by this Act granted according to the Value and Price of such Goods to be affirmed upon the Oath of the
Merchant in the presence of the Customer Collector Comptroller and Surveyor or any Two of them except and
foreprized out of this Grant of Subsidy of Poundage all Wines before limitted to pay Subsidy of Tunnage and all
manner of Fish English taken and brought by English Bottoms into this Realme and all manner of fresh Fish and
Bestial that shall come into this Realme and all other Goods and Merchandizes which in the said Book of Rates
are mentioned to be Custome free and except and foreprized out of this Grant of Subsidy of Poundage all Goods
and Merchandizes which are co[m]monly used in dying.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Duties on Drugs imported, Spicery</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Linen,; and for Foreign wrought Silks exported within One Year from mportation; and for wrought Silks imported; and for Tobacco of the English Plantations; and for Wines of the Growth of France,&amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided always and it is hereby enacted That all Drugs chargeable by this Act which shall be imported
directly from the Place of their Growth in English built Shipping shall be rated to pay by this Act One third Part
of what is charged thereupon in the said Book of Rates and no more and that all Spicery except Pepper which
shall be imported directly from the Place of its Growth in English built Shipping shall be rated to pay by this
Act One third Part of what is charged in the said Book of Rates and no more and that this Act shall not
extend to charge Linnen imported with the additional Duty of one Moiety of the Rate mentioned in the said
Book of Rates and that all Forreigne wrought Silk exported within One Yeare from the Importation shall have
Two thirds of the Rate hereby charged repaid att the Custome House and this Act shall not extend charge
wrought Silks imported with the additional Duty of one Moiety mentioned in the said Book of Rates or to charge
Tobacco of the English Plantation with the additional Duty of One penny per Pound over and above the Subsidy
mentioned in the said Book of Rates or to charge Wines of the Growth of France Germany Portugal or Madera
with the additional Duty of Three pounds per Tun or any other Wines with the additional Duty of Foure pounds
per [<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] mentioned in the said former Acts or Book of Rates and that for all Tobacco of the English Plantations
which shall be imported and exported againe within One Yeare after such Importation the further Subsidy of One
penny per Pound hereby granted shall be repaid att the Custome House.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Allowances and Abatements as in the Book of Rates.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That out of the several Subsidies of Tunnage and Poundage
by this Act granted there shall be such and the like Allowances and Abatements in all Cases as are prescribed
in the like cases by the said former Act or by the said Book of Rates or the Rules thereunto annexed and
to be made &amp; allowed under the same Restrictions and in the same Manner and Forme as are therein expressed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Duties to be levied by Officers of the Customs, and paid into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Powers, Penalties, &amp;c. in 12 Car. II. c. 4. and in the Book of Rates and other former Acts in force</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said several Subsidies of Tunnage and Poundage
hereby granted shall be raised levied &amp; collected by the respective Officers of his Majesties Customes for the time
being under the Management &amp; Direction of the Co[m]missioners of the Customs for the time being and shall be
brought and paid or answered into the Receipt of his Majesties Exchequer for the Purposes in this Act mentioned
(such additional Charge as shall be necessary for the Management of this Revenue onely excepted) and that all
and every the Clauses Powers Directions Penalties Forfeitures Matters &amp; Things whatsoever contained in the said
former Act of Tunnage &amp; Poundage or in the said Book of Rates or the Rules thereunto annexed or in any
other Laws or Statutes whatsoever now in force for raiseing levying securing collecting answering or paying the
Subsidy of Tunnage &amp; Poundage thereby granted shall be applied practised and putt in Execution for the raiseing
levying securing collecting answering and paying the Subsidy of Tunnage and Poundage by this Act granted
as fully and effectually to all intents and purposes as if all and every the said Clauses Powers Directions
Penalties Forfeitures Matters and Things were particularly repeated and again enacted in the Body of this
present Act.</para>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 20. &sect;1.; The said Act not to extend to charge French Goods condemned as Prize with any other Duties than before that Act.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">And whereas by an Act made in the last Session of Parliament intituled An Act for granting to his Majesty
an additional Duty upon all French Goods &amp; Merchandize a Duty of Twenty five pounds is laid upon every Tu[n]n
of French Wine imported from and after the Twenty eighth Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety
six upon every Tun[n] of French Brandy of single Proof Thirty pounds upon every Tun of French Brandy of double
Proof Sixty pounds upon every Tun of French Vinegar Fifteen pounds and upon all other Goods of the Growth
Product or Manufacture of France Twenty five pounds per Centum ad valorem over &amp; above the Duties already
charged thereupon which proves a very great Discouragem<emph type="p">t</emph>. to the Co[m]manders Officers and Seamen of his Majesties Shipps of Warr and to Privateers in annoying the Enemy Be it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid That
nothing in the said [Act<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] contained shall extend or be construed to extend to the chargeing of any Goods Wares
or Merchandizes of the Growth Product or Manufacture of France which shall be bona fide seized or taken and
condemned as Prize with any further or other Duties than what they were or ought to have been charged with all
before the making of the said Act Any thing therein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>VI. Ship, &amp;c. taken by Connivance subject to the Duties of that Act.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided neverthelesse That if it shall appeare that such Shipp or Vessell with the loading thereof shall be
seized or taken by Connivance or Collusion that then and in every such Case such French Goods so imported
shall still be subject to pay the Duties imposed by the said recited Act Any thing in this Act to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VII. Drawback of Duties on Sugars from America on Exportation.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided always and be it enacted That the whole further Subsidy laid by this Act upon all Sugars that shall
be imported from the English Plantations in America shall and may be drawne and paid back att the Exportation
thereof Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VIII.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Drawback on English refined Sugar exported during this Act, on Oath, and on Searcher's Certificate of Shipping. &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And whereas great Quantities of Browne and Muscovado Sugars have formerly been refined here in England
and afterwards exported to Forreigne Marketts whereby a great Number of People have been imployed and a
Manufactury carried on very profitable to this Kingdome which Trade of refining Sugars for Exportation will be
lost unlesse a Draw back be allowed when such Sugars are exported after they are refined here suitable to the
Draw back allowed on the Exportation of Browne &amp; Muscovado Sugar by reason forreigne Nations will be thereby
enabled to refine them cheaper abroad than [they<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] can be done here att home Be it therefore enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That for every Hundred weight of Sugar refined in England (and so in proportion for a greater
or lesser Quantity) exported out of this Kingdome during the continuance of this Act there shall be repaid att
the Custome House to the Exporter within One Month after Demand thereof the Su[m]m of Three shillings Oath
being first made that the said Sugar so exported was produced from Browne and Muscovado Sugar charged by
this Act imported from his Majesties Plantations in America and that the Duty of the said Browne and Muscovado
Sugar was duely paid att the time of the Importation thereof and that the same was duely exported his Majesties
Searcher also certifying the shipping thereof and all other Requisities duely performed according to the Book
of Rates.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>IX. Three Months allowed to the Subsidy on Tobacco, and &pound;10 per Cent. for prompt Payment.</head>
			<para id="p14">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That for the further Subsidy hereby granted upon Tobacco of
the English Plantations in America the Merchant Importer shall have Three Months time from the Importation to
pay the same giving Security for the Payment thereof accordingly and in case of paying the same sooner than
the said Three Months the said Merchant Importer shall be allowed a Discount after the Rate of Ten pounds
per Centum per Annum for prompt payment Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>X. Ginger to pay 2s. per Cwt.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided always That Ginger of the English Plantations in the West Indies which by the said Book of Rates
is valued att Sixteene pence a pound shall pay for the said former Subsidy One shilling for every hundred weight
and for the Subsidy by this Act One shilling for every Hundred weight and after that proportion for a greater
or lesser Quantity and no more Any thing in this or the said former Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>XI.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">After 1st May 1697. cut Whalebone imported, except in Fins, forfeited, and double the Value</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And whereas great Quantities of cutt whalebone fitt for Use are frequently imported in short Lengths and
small Parcells by meanes whereof not onely his Majesty is defrauded of the Duties laid thereon but the Merchants
importing and the Manufacturers imployed in cutting of Fin-Whalebone are greatly prejudiced and discouraged
Be it therefore declared and enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Person or Persons Natives or
Forreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate shall after the First Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety
seven import or bring into this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed
any cutt Whalebone (other then in Fins onely) hee she or they shall forfeit the Goods and double the Value
of the said cutt Whalebone so imported One Moiety thereof to His Majesty His Heires and Successors and the
other Moiety to him or them that shall seize or sue for the same in any of His Majesties Courts of Record
wherein no Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed nor any more then one Imparlance Any thing
in this Act or any former Law to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XII. Goods imported and exported again in Twelve Months (Exception) whole Duties to be repaid without Fee, on Oath of Merchant and Certificate by Officer that Entry has been made and Duty paid; No Drawback to be allowed on exporting Foreign wrought Silks, &amp;c. unless exported in Time, &amp;c. and then the whole Duties to be repaid.</head>
			<para id="p18">[<ref idref="n3">3</ref> Provided always and it is hereby declared and enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in all cases where
any the Forreigne Goods [Wines<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] or Merchandizes by this Act charged with the Subsidy of Tunnage or Poundage
hereby granted (other than and except forreigne wrought Silk Tobacco Sugars and refined Sugars touching which
other Provisions are hereby made) shall att any time or times be againe exported by any Merchant English
within Twelve Kalendary Months or Stranger within Nine Kalendary Months after the Importation thereof and
that due Proof be first made by Certificate from the proper Officers of the due Entry and Payment of the
Subsidy hereby granted of any such forreigne Goods Wines or Merchandizes inward together with the Oath of
the Merchant importing and exporting the same affirming the Truth thereof and that all other Requisites shall
be performed which are by Law required to be performed in Cases where the Halfe Subsidy is repaid by the
said former Act the whole Subsidy by this Act granted and which shall have been actually paid for such 
Goods Wines or Merchandizes shall without any Delay or Reward be repaid unto such Merchant or Merchants
who do export the same within One Month after Demand thereof or the Security for the said Subsidy by this Act
charged shall be vacated as to so much as shall be [so<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] exported and that as to the said forreigne wrought Silks
Tobacco Sugars and refined Sugars no Repayment or Draw back of or for the Subsidy by this Act shall be
made or allowed for the same unlesse they respectively be again exported within the times hereby limitted for
other Goods and that the like due Proof be made and other Requisites performed for the said Silks Tobacco
Sugar and refined Sugar as are hereby directed in the like Case for other Goods or Merchandizes exported and
that upon such Exportac[i]on of forreigne wrought Silks and such due Proof made and other Requisites performed
for the same not onely the Two thirds of the Subsidy by this Act directed to be repaid for such Silks as
aforesaid but also the remaining One third of the same Subsidy shall be intirely repaid att the Custome House
Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for Naval Stores bought for the King's Use.</head>
			<para id="p19">[<ref idref="n5">5</ref> Provided always That nothing in this Act contained shall extend or be construed to extend to charge with
the Duty hereby granted such Naval Stores as shall appeare by Certificate from the Co[m]missioners of the Navy
to have been by them contracted for or bought for the Service of his Majesties Navy before the Five and twentieth
Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety seven Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary
notwithstanding.]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIV.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Recital of c. 6. ante, &sect; 10.; &sect; 57.; &sect; 58.; &sect; 59.; 1 W. &amp;M. c.8; 3 W. &amp; M. c. 6.; 1 W. &amp; M. c. 8.; 1 W. &amp; M. c. 18. &sect; 10.; Manors, &amp;c. as charged by c. 6. ante, charged with a further Sum of 1s. in the Pound for One Year from 25th Jan. 1696</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And whereas wee Your Majesties said dutiful and loyal Subjects the Co[m]mons [in Parliament assembled<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] for
carrying on the Warr against France and the Defence of Your Majesties Realmes did humbly present Your
Majesty with a certaine Aid or Supply upon all Lands Tenements and Hereditaments to be raised by a Pound
Rate of Three Shillings for every Twenty Shillings of the true Yearely Value thereof (amongst other things)
by an Act of this present Parliament (entituled An Act for granting an Aid to His Majesty as well by a Land
Tax as by several Subsidies and other Duties payable for One Yeare) by which it was enacted That all and every
Manors Messuages Lands and Tenements as also all Quarries Mines of Coal Tin or Lead Copper Mundick Iron
or other Mines Iron-Works Salt Springs and Salt-Works all Allum Mines or Worke all Parkes Chaces Warrenns
Woods Underwoods Coppices and all Fishings Tythes and Tolls whatsoever and also all An[n]uities Rents Charge
and other Rents and Yearely Profitts issuing or payable of or for any Estate Terme or Interest whatsoever out
of any Lands Tenements and Hereditaments and all Hereditaments of what Nature or Kind soever scituate
lyeing and being happening renewing or ariseing within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne
of Berwick upon Tweed should be and are thereby charged for One Yeare onely and no longer with the Su[m]m
of Three Shillings for every Twenty Shillings of the true and full Yearely Value and so in Proportion for any
greater or lesser Value and all and every Person and Persons Bodies Politick and Corporate Guilds Mysteries
Fraternities and Brotherhoods whether Corporate or not Corporate having or holding any Manors Messuages
Lands Tenements Hereditaments or other the Premisses should yield any pay to His Majesty the Su[m]m of Three
Shillings for every Twenty Shillings by the Yeare which the said Manors Messuages Lands Tenements and
Hereditaments and other the Premisses should be worth to be leased if the same were truely and bona fide leased
or demised att a Rack Rent and according to the full true and Yearely Value thereof without any respect had
to the present Rents reserved for the same if such Rents have been reserved upon such Leases or Estates made
for which any Fine or Income hath been paid or secured or have been lessened or abated upon Consideration
of Money laid out or to be laid out in Improvements and without respect had to any other Rates or Taxes
thereupon imposed or making any Abatement in respect of Reparations Taxes Scots Parish Duties or any other
Charges whatsoever which said Su[m]m of Three Shillings for every Twenty Shillings by the Yeare of the said
true Yearely Value of all the Premisses aforesaid was by the said Act appointed to be assessed levied and collected
in manner therein mentioned and to be paid &amp; payable by all and every the (<ref idref="n7">7</ref>) said Person or Persons Bodies Politick
or Corporate Guilds Mysteries Fraternities or Brotherhoods having or holding any such Manors Messuages Lands
Tenements Hereditaments &amp; other the Premisses by Twelve equal Monthly Payments the First Payment whereof
was to be made on the Five and twentieth Day of February in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
ninety six and every other Monthly Payment to be made on the Five and twentieth Day of every (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) Kalendary
Month successively until the whole should be satisfied And whereas it was thereby further enacted That every
Papist or reputed Papist being of the Age of Sixteene Yeares and upwards who had not taken the Oaths
mentioned and required to be taken by an Act of Parliament made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of King
William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for the abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy &amp; Allegiance &amp; appointing
other Oaths should yeild and pay unto His Majesty double the Su[m]ms and Rates as is therein mentioned Provided
neverthelesse That if any such Papist or reputed Papist within Ten Days after the First Meeting of the Co[m]missioners
thereby authorized to be appointed in the respective Counties or Places where hee or she ought to be taxed or
assessed according to the Intent of the said Act should take the said Oaths before Two or more of the said
Co[m]missioners in that case hee or she should not be liable to be double assessed as aforesaid and it was thereby
also enacted That every Person being of the Age of Sixteen Yeares and upwards and being within this Realme
att the time of the Execution of the said Act who should not before that time have taken the Oaths mentioned
and required to be taken by the said Act intituled An Act for the abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy and
Allegiance and appointing other Oaths and upon Su[m]mons by Warrant under the Hand and Seale of any Two or
more of the said Co[m]missioners should refuse to take the said Oaths att the time appointed in the said Warrant or 
should neglect to appeare att such time before the Co[m]missioners in order to take the said Oaths should also pay
double as in the said Act is expressed and that every Gentleman or so reputed or owning or writing himselfe as
such or being above that Quality who by virtue of an Act made in the Third Yeare of the Reigne of King
William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for raiseing Money by a Poll Payable Quarterly for One Yeare for
carrying on a vigorous Warr against France did pay or ought to have paid double the Su[m]ms charged by the said
Act or were or ought to have been returned into the Exchequer for Non-payment thereof who should not
voluntarily appeare before the said Co[m]missioners or any Two or more of them within Ten days after the First
Meeting, of the said Co[m]missioners in the respective Place or Places where hee ought to be taxed or assessed and
take the said Oaths appointed by the said Act made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of King William and
Queen Mary such Person should likewise pay double as in the said Act is specified and moreover itt was thereby
enacted That any One or more of the said Co[m]missioners upon Information given or upon any Cause of Suspicion
in that behalfe should and are thereby required and enjoyned to cause every suspected Person or against whome
such Informac[i]on should be given to be su[m]moned to appeare to take the said Oaths as aforesaid and it is thereby
provided that whereas certaine persons Dissenters from the Church of England Co[m]monly called Quakers and knowne
to be such do scruple the taking of any Oath itt should be sufficient for any such Person to make and subscribe
the Declaration of Fidelity contained in an Act made in the Parliament held in the First Yeare of the Reigne
of King William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for exempting His Majesties Protestant Subjects dissenting
from the Church of England from the Penalties of certaine Laws and every such Person so doeing should not
be liable to or charged with any the double Rates aforesaid As by the said Act amongst others things therein
contained doth more fully appeare And whereas wee Your Majesties said Subjects the Co[m]mons in Parliament
assembled are sensible that a further Aid and Supply is requisite &amp; necessary for the Ends and Purposes aforesaid
Wee doe humbly present Your Majesty with the free Guift of the further Rates and Assessments herein after
menc[i]oned and doe humbly beseech Your Majesty that it may be enacted and be it enacted by the Authority
aforesaid That all and every Manors Messuages Lands and Tenements as also all Quarries Mines of Coal Tin or
Lead Copper Mundick Iron or other Mines Iron-works Salt-springs and Salt-works all Allum Mines or Workes all
Parks Chaces Warrens Woods Underwoods Coppices &amp; all Fishings Tythes and Tolls whatsoever and also all
Annuities Rents charge &amp; other Rents and Yearely Proffitts issuing or payable of or for any Estate Terme or
Interest whatsoever out of any Lands Tenements and Hereditaments and all Hereditaments of what Nature or Kind
soever charged by the said other Act for One Yeare with the said Su[m]m of Three Shillings for every Twenty
Shillings of the full Yearely Value and so in proportion for any greater or lesser Values shall by virtue of this
Act for One Yeare to be reckoned from the Five and Twentieth Day of January One thousand six hundred
ninety six be charged with and they who have or hold the same shall yeild &amp; pay unto His Majesty the further
Su[m]m of One Shilling for every Twenty Shillings that is to say in the whole Foure Shillings for every Twenty
Shillings of the full Yearely Value and so in proportion for any greater or lesser Value.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XV. Papists and others charged by the said Act with Double Rates to pay 2s. in the Pound additional.</head>
			<para id="p22">And be it further enacted That every Papist or reputed Papist and every other Person which by the said other
Act was or ought to be charged with and made liable to pay unto His Majesty double the Rates and Su[m]ms
therein mentioned shall be charged with and shall pay unto His Majesty (over and besides the same) double the
Su[m]m or Rate of One Shilling in the Pound given and granted by this Act that is to say the Su[m]m of Two Shillings
over and above every Su[m]m of Six Shillings which such Papists reputed Papists or other Persons were charged
with or liable to pay by virtue of the said other Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XVI. Commissioners under c. 6. ante (see &sect; 12.) to be Commissioners for executing this Act.</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Assessors and Collectors appointed by the said Commissioners to be Assessors and Collectors under this Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And be it further enacted That all and every the Persons nominated constituted or appointed or to be
nominated constituted or appointed by His Majesty under the Greate Seale of England His Majesties Co[m]missioners
for putting the said Act for Three Shillings in the Pound and for other Things therein menc[i]oned in Execution
shall be His Majesties Co[m]missioners for putting in Execution this present Act as to the said Rate of One Shilling
in the Pound Charged on Mannors Lands Tenements and other the Premisses and as to the said Double Rates
to be paid by Papists or Reputed Papists and such other Persons as are liable to Double Rates as aforesaid and
shall respectively in this behalfe have and execute all Powers Authorities &amp; Priveleges as they had and ought
to have by or in Relation to the said other Act And that all and every Person and Persons who are or shall
be lawfully appointed by the said Co[m]missioners or any of them pursuant to the Powers to them in that behalfe
given to be Assessors &amp; Collectors of the said Rate of Three Shillings in the Pound and other the Duties in the
said other Act mentioned shall be and are hereby appointed to be the Assessors and Collectors of the said Rate
of One Shilling in the Pound hereby charged upon all Mannors Lands Tenements and other the p[re]misses as
aforesaid and of the Double Rate amounting to Two Shillings in the Pound hereby charged upon Persons liable
thereunto as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVII. The Times and Manner in which the said Rate of 1s. and Double Rate of 2s. in the Pound is to be collected.</head>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Collectors to answer for Monies collected to the Head Collectors, and by the said Head Collectors to the Receivers General.; Receivers General to give Security to be approved by Treasury; and to pay Monies received by them into the Exchequer, as by c.6. ante, &sect; 19.; Persons liable to pay or concerned in the collecting the said 1s. and 2s. in the Pound to be liable to the like Penalties and have the like Advantages as by c.6.ante.; All Manors, &amp;c. liable to Distress, &amp;c. inrespect of the said Rate of 3s. in the Pound to be in like Manner liable to the said Rate of 1s. and 2s. in the Pound</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">And for the avoiding as much as may be the unnecessary trouble of repeated Assessments Itt is hereby
enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in all Cases where any Manors Messuages Lands Tenements Rents
Hereditaments &amp; other the Premisses or those which have or hold the same are or shall be by the said other
Act assessed or charged with the said Rate of Three Shillings for every Twenty Shillings of the full yearely
Value thereof or with the said Double Rate of Six Shillings in the Pound as aforesaid the said Assessors and
Collectors shall charge collect &amp; levy by virtue of this Act for and in Satisfaction of the said Rate of One
Shilling in the Pound and for and in Satisfaction of the said Double Rate of Two Shillings in the Pound hereby
granted respectively One Third Part of the Su[m]ms so assessed or to be assessed by or in pursuance of the said 
other Act for such Mannors Messuages Lands Tenements and Hereditaments [Rents<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] and other the Premisses
respectively and that so much as shall be due to His Majesty of and for the said Rate of One Shilling in the
Pound and the said Double Rate of Two Shillings in the Pound hereby granted reckoning by Kalendary Months
for Three Months from the said Five and twentieth Day of January One thousand six hundred ninety six until
the Five and twentieth Day of April One thousand six hundred ninety seven for all and every the said Mannors
Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditam<emph type="p">t</emph>.s Rents and other the Permisses or from those which have or hold the
same shall be demanded collected and levied by the said Collectors respectively on or before the said Five and
twentieth Day of April One rhousand six hundred ninety seven or within Fourteen Days then next ensuing
And that the residue of the Moneys which shall be due to His Majesty of or for the said Rate of One Shilling
in the Pound and the said Double Rate of Two Shillings in the Pound respectively for the said Mannors
Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments Rents &amp; other the Premisses or from those having or holding the
same shall be demanded collected &amp; levied by the said Collectors respectively by Monthly Payments att such
times and in such manner and forme as they are required by the said other Act to demand levy and receive
the Rates or Duties of Three Shillings in the Pound or the Double Rates of Six Shillings in the Pound thereby
granted from the said Five and twentieth [day<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] of April One thousand six hundred ninety seven until the end of the
said One Yeare And that all the said Rates and Su[m]ms of Money by this Act granted &amp; charged upon Mannors
Lands Tenements Hereditam<emph type="p">t</emph>.s and other the Premisses hereby charged with the additional Pound Rates as
aforesaid shall be demanded collected &amp; levied by the said Collectors in such manner and att such times as
aforesaid and shall be paid &amp; answered by them to the respective Head Collectors and by such Head Collectors
to the respective Receivers General to be appointed for these Rates or Duties (which Receivers General shall
give such Security for performing their Trusts in respect to the said Rates hereby granted as the Commissioners
of His Majesties Treasury or the High Treasurer for the time being shall approve of) and shall be paid [and<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]
answered by the said Receivers General into the Receipt of His Majesties Exchequer by such Methods Ways
and Means and in such manner and forme and according to such Rules and Direcc[i]ons and under such Penalties
&amp; Forfeitures and with such Abatements Deductions &amp; Allowances as in the said other Act are respectively
appointed of for &amp; concerning the several Rates and Su[m]ms of Three Shillings in the Pound and Six Shillings
in the Pound thereby given and granted to His Majesty And all and every Person and Persons who are or
shall be liable to pay or be any way concerned or imployed in the assessing collecting levying receiving or paying
any the Moneys of the said Rates or Duties of One Shilling in the Pound or the said Double Duties by
this Act appointed to be charged taxed and levied shall be respectively subject and liable to the like Penalties
and Forfeitures for any Non-payment Neglect Refusal or Default and shall have the like Deductions Benefitts by
Appeal or otherwise Advantages Respits Priveleges and Discharges as in the like cases any Person or Persons by
virtue of the said other Act for the said Pound Rate of Three Shillings in the Pound or the Double thereof
ought to have or be subject unto And all Mannors Lands Tenements and Hereditaments and other Things
respectively subject by Distresse or otherwise to the Payment of the said other Rates of Three Shillings in the
Pound or the the said double Rates of Six Shillings in the Pound shall by this Act be subject in like manner to
the said Rate of One Shilling in the Pound or the said double Rate respectively by this Act charged thereupon
as fully and amply as if all and every the Clauses in the said other Act contained for such Purposes were againe
in this Act particularly repeated &amp; enacted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVIII. Recital of c. 6. ante, &sect; 94.; and of c. 20. ante,</head>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">&sect; 63.; &sect; 64.; Treasury may make forth Bills for &pound;1,200,000 over and above the Sum of &pound;1,500,000, to beissued under c. 6. ante, &sect; 94. so as there be not Bills at one Time outstanding to more than &pound;2,000,000; Such Bills to have the like Currency and bear the same Interest as the Bills for &pound;1,500,000</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p28">And whereas by an Act of this present Session of Parliament intituled An Act for granting an Aid to His
Majesty as well by a Land Tax as by several Subsidies and other Duties payable for One Yeare Itt is amongst
other Things enacted That for the better and more speedy answering of the Supplies hereby granted or that
should be granted for this present Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety seven Itt should and might be lawfull
to and for the Co[m]missioners of His Majesties Treasury or any Three of them now being or for the High Treasurer
or any Three or more of the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury for the time being to cause Bills to be made forth
att the Receipt of Exchequer in such Manner as they should appoint for any Sum[m] or Su[m]ms of Money not
exceeding Fifteen hundred thousand Pounds and to issue the same to the Uses of the Warr in such proportions
as they should think fitt And by another Act of this present Session of Parliament intituled An Act for making
good the Deficiency of several Funds therein mentioned and for enlargeing the Capital Stock of the Bank of
England and for raiseing the Publick Creditt Itt is enacted That the Bills by the aforementioned Act authorized
to be issued should passe and be current to all and every the Co[m]missioners Receivers or Collectors of any Revenue
Aid Tax or Supply whatsoever granted or that should be granted dureing this present Session of Parliament
either for the Warr or any other Use and also att the Receipt of Exchequer and that there should be annexed
unto attend and go along with the said Bills an Interest after the Rate of Five Pence a Day for every One
hundred Pounds contained therein and proportionably for a greater or lesser Su[m]m with such Directions concerning
the said Bills as in and by the said several Acts relation being thereunto respectively had may more fully appeare
Now to the end His Majesty may likewise have the better and more speedy effect of the Supplies by this
Act intended be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall &amp; may be lawfull to and for the
Co[m]missioners of His Majesties Treasury or any Three of them now being or for the High Treasurer or any
Three or more of the Co[m]missioners of His Majesties Treasury for the time being to cause Bills to be made forth
att the Receipt of Exchequer for any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms not exceeding Twelve hundred thousand Pounds over and
above the said Fifteene hundred thousand Pounds by the First mentioned Act authorized to be issued in such
Proportions neverthelesse as that there shall not att any one time be more Bills standing out than to the Value 
or Amount of Two Millions in Principal Money And that the said Bills shall have like Currency and beare the
same Interest after the Rate of Five Pence per Centum per diem as the Bills for the said One Million Five
hundred thousand Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XIX. Recital that the Treasury may have contracted with Persons for circulating Bills for the said &pound;1,500,000 as may have been refused.</head>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">In what Cases Persons so contracting released from their Contracts</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p30">And whereas the Co[m]missioners of His Majesties Treasury or High Treasurer for the time being have or may
contract or agree with divers Persons for the advancing or lending Money for the circulating or exchanging such
of the Bills of the said One million five hundred thousand Pounds as shall be refused or not accepted or taken
att the Excheq[uer] or in any other publick Office for the Satisfaction of Tallies and Orders of Loan in course of
Payment from time to time Itt is hereby enacted That the Persons so contracting shall be freed and discharged
from their respective Contracts as soon as the whole Su[m]ms by them agreed to be advanced shall be called for and
paid by them respectively or so soon as Bills for One million five hundred thousand Pounds principal Money
issuable as well by the First recited Act as in pursuance hereof shall be cancelled or that the Funds granted or
that may be granted for the Service of the Warr for this present Yeare shall have produced sufficient to take upp
and cancell the same Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary thereof notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XX. Treasury enabled to make such Contracts for exchanging Bills for the said &pound;1,200,000 as may be refused.; Terms of such Contracts.</head>
			<para id="p31">And it is hereby further enacted and declared That the said Co[m]missioners of His Majesties Treasury or the
High Treasurer for the time being shall or may contract and agree in such manner as they shall think fitt with
the same or any other Person or Persons (with whose Abilities they shall be well satisfied) for the advancing or
lending, such further Su[m]ms as they shall think necessary for the exchanging of such Bills of the said Twelve
hundred thousand Pounds hereby authorized to be issued as shall or may be refused or not accepted in satisfaction
of Tallies and Orders of Loan in course of Repayment as aforesaid which Persons so contracting shall have and
receive the like Interest or Reward after the Rate of Ten Pounds per Centum per Annum for the Money they
shall advance for the Purposes aforesaid as in and by the last recited Act is allowed to such as shall contract
for the One million five hundred thousand Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XXI. Proviso as to cancelling Bills as well for the said &pound;1,500,000 as for the said &pound;1,200,000 which shall not be cancelled by the Produce of the Supplies granted for the War in 1697 by the 25 March 1698, and for the Discharge of Persons from their said Contracts in respect of the Bills for the said &pound;1,200,000.</head>
			<para id="p32">And it is hereby also enacted That all the Bills which shall or may be issued as well for the said Fifteen
hundred thousand Pounds as for the said Twelve hundred thousand Pounds which shall not be cancelled by the
Produce of the said Funds or Supplies granted or to be granted for the Service of the Warr in this present Yeare
One thousand six hundred ninety seven by the Five &amp; twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety
eight shall be satisfied taken upp and cancelled as well by the Arrears of the said Funds which shall be then
standing out as by and out of the Moneys which shall arise by any Aid which shall be granted in the next
Session of Parliament And that the Person or Persons which shall so contract and agree for advancing or lending
Money for the exchanging such Bills of the said Twelve hundred thousand Pounds as shall be refused or not taken
in Repayment &amp; Satisfaction of Tallies and Orders of Loan in course as aforesaid shall be discharged from their
respective Contracts as soon as the whole Su[m]ms by them agreed to be advanced shall be answered and paid by
them according to their respective Agreements. And if the same be not called for or required from them by the said
Five and twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety eight they shall thenceforth be im[m]ediately and
absolutely discharged and acquitted from any further Compliance with their said Contracts.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXII. Until Proclamation of such Contracts the said Bills for &pound;1,200,000 shall be current in the Supplies for the War of 1697 only.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided neverthelesse and be it hereby enacted That until such time as His Majesty or the Lords Justices of
England by Proclamation to be issued by Advice of the Privy Council shall make knowne that the said Co[m]missioners
of His Majesties Treasury or the High Treasurer for the time being shall (by such Contracts or Agreements made
with Persons of Ability as aforesaid) have sufficiently secured and made Provision That all Persons who att the
Receipt of His Majesties Excheq[uer] or att any of the said public Offices shall have any of the Bills for the said
Twelve hundred thousand Pounds for satisfaction of their Talleys or Orders of Loan or for any other Payments
whatsoever may have such Bills exchanged for ready Money the said Bills to be made forth for the said Twelve
hundred thousand Pounds or any part thereof shall be current onely in the Funds or Supplies granted for the
Service of the Warr for this present Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety seven (except the Aid of Three
Shillings in the Pound) Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXIII. Forging Bills or knowingly tendering or demanding Money on such Bills.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Death</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Person shall forge or counterfeit any of the
Bills hereby authorized to be issued or tender in Payment any such forged or counterfeited Bill or demand Money
thereupon of any Receiver or att the Exchequer (knowing the Bill so tendred or whereupon the Money shall be
so demanded to be actually forged or counterfeited and with an intention to defraud His Majesty or any other
Person or Persons) that then every such Person or Persons so offending (being thereof convicted in due Forme
of Law) shall be adjudged guilty of Felony and suffer the Paines and Penalties of Felony without Benefitt
of Clergy.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIV. Appropriation of &pound; 672,197. out of the Monies arising under this Act.</head>
			<para id="p36">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That out of the Moneys arising by virtue of this present
Act either by Bills of Creditt or otherwise the Su[m]m of Six hundred seventy two thousand one hundred ninety
seven Pounds shall be &amp; is hereby appropriated for the Service of the Navy and for the Sea Service in the
Office of the Ordnance performed &amp; to be performed and for the Ordnary of the said Navy Payment of Marine
Officers and Charge of registring Seamen to compleat the Su[m]m of Two Millions three hundred seventy two

thousand one hundred ninety seven Pounds for those Services And that all other Moneys which shall be raised
by this Act as well by Bills of Creditt as otherwise shall be applied and appropriated to and for the Payment
of His Majesties Land Forces &amp; Ordnance Am[u]nition &amp; other Charges incident to the Warr &amp; not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXV.</head>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">Rules of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 1. applied to the Sums of Money appropriated by this Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p38">And that the Su[m]ms by this Act appropriated may not be diverted or applied to any other Purpose than is
hereby directed &amp; intended Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Rules &amp; Directions appointed and
enacted in one Act made in the First Yeare of His Majesties Reigne (intituled An Act for a Grant to Their
Majesties of an Aid of Two Shillings in the Pound for one Yeare) for the speedy Payments of Moneys thereby
granted into the Receipt of the Excheq[uer] by the Receivers &amp; Collectors thereof &amp; for the Distribution &amp; Application
thereof &amp; keeping distinct Accounts of the same &amp; all other Provisoes Pains Penalties &amp; Forfeitures thereby
enacted in case of Diversion of any Money thereby appropriated are hereby revived &amp; enacted to be in Force &amp;
shall be practised applied executed &amp; putt in Ure for &amp; concerning the Distribution &amp; Application of the said
Su[m]ms hereby appropriated as fully amply &amp; effectually as if the same were here particularly repeated &amp; reenacted.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Tonn <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule;</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">assembled in Parliament <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">subsequent, <emph type="i">O</emph>. and King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


