<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46875" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXVII. An Act for the more effectual Relief of Creditors in Cases of Escapes &amp; for Preventing Abuses in Prisons and pretended priveledged Places. [Rot. Parl. 8&amp;9 Gul. III. p.9.nu.3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Prisoners in the King's Bench or Fleet to be detained there or in the Rules.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Keeper suffering them to go at large without Hab. Corp. &amp; c. deemed an Escape</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by reason of the many grievous Extortions and ill Practices of such Persons who have for
several Yeares last past respectively executed the Offices of Marshal of the Kings Bench Warden of the
Fleet &amp; Keeper of the Marshalsea Newgate &amp; other Prisons and by several pretended priviledged Places within this
Realme both Creditors and Debtors have been notoriously abused and the good Intents of the Law wholly eluded
For Reformation thereof be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent
of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of
the same That from and after the First Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety seven all Prisoners either
upon Contempt or Mesne Processe or in Execution who are or shall be co[m]mitted to the Custody of the Marshall
of the Kings Bench Prison or Warden of the Fleet shall be actually detained [within the said Prisons of the
Kings Bench and Fleet or the respective Rules of the same<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] until they shall be from thence discharged by due
course of Law and if att any time from and after the said First Day of May the said Marshall or Warden or
any other Keeper or Keepers of any Prison shall permitt and suffer any Prisoner co[m]mitted to their Custody either
in Mesne Processe or in Execution to goe or be att large out of the Rules of their respective Prisons (except by
virtue of some Writt of Habeas Corpus or Rule of Court (which Rule of Court shall not be granted but by
Motion made or Petition read in open Court) every such going or being out of the said Rules shall be adjudged
and deemed and is hereby declared to be an Escape.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Upon Judgment in Action of Escape, Marshal or Warden's Fees to be sequestered for Satisfaction.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said First Day of May every
Person or Persons obtaining Judgment in any Action of Escape against the said Marshall or Warden or their
respective lawfull Deputie or Deputies shall and may have not onely the several Remedies already by Law allowed
for obtaining Satisfaction thereon but the Judges of the respective Courts where such Judgement shall be obtained
(upon Oath before them made by the Person or Persons obtaining such Judgement that the same was obtained
without Fraud or Coven and that the Debt of the Prisoner making such Escape was a true and real Debt and
unsatisfied) shall upon Motion made to them in open Court for that purpose sequester the Fees and Proffitts
of the Office of Marshall and Warden [or so much or such Part or Proportion thereof as the said Court wherein
such Motion shall be made shall think fitt and reasonable with respect to the Debt or Debts due from such
Prisoner or Prisoners so escaping<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] and in the first Place apply the same towards Satisfaction of the Debt or Debts
due from the Prisoner or Prisoners who escaped together with all Costs and Damages recovered in such Action
of Escape.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Marshal, &amp;c. suing a Writ of Error to reverse Judgment, to put in special Bail.</head>
			<para id="p4">And to the end that such Satisfaction may not be deferred by any Writt of Error brought for delay onely be
it enacted That if the said Marshall or Warden or their respective Deputie or Deputies shall att any Time after
the said First Day of May sue forth any Writt or Writts of [Error<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to reverse any Judgement given in any Action
of Escape such Marshall or Warden or their respective Deputy or Deputies shall be obliged to putt in special
Bail or in default thereof no Execution shall be stayed nor any Sequestration of the Proffitts delayed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Marshal, &amp;c. taking Reward to connive at Prisoner's Escape;</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;500. Loss of Office and Incapacity</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And whereas it is notorious that diverse great Su[m]ms of Money and other Rewards have been given to and
actually received by the severall Persons executing the respective Offices of Marshall and Warden and other Keepers
of the several Prisons within this Kingdome to assist or permitt Prisoners in their Custody to escape in open
defiance and contempt of the Laws of this Realme For preventing the like evil Practise for the time to come be
it further enacted That if any Marshall or Warden or their respective Deputie or Deputies or any Keeper of any
other Prison within this Kingdome shall take any Su[m]m of Money Reward or Gratuity whatsoever or Security for
the same to procure assist connive att or permitt any such Escape and shall be thereof lawfully convicted the
said Marshall or Warden or their respective Deputy or Deputies or such other Keeper of any Prisons as aforesaid
shall for every such Offence forfeit the Su[m]m of Five hundred pounds and his said Office and be for ever after
incapable of executing any such Office.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Securities given for Lodging within the Rules of the said Prisons.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided always That this Act nor any thing herein contained shall extend or be construed to extend to
make void such Securities or any of them as shall att any Time or Times hereafter be given by any Prisoner
or Prisoners for his or their Lodging or Lodgings without the aforesaid Prisons or either of them within the
Rules of the said Prisons of Kings Bench and Fleet or either of them so as such Security or Securities be not
taken for the Enlargement of any Prisoner or Prisoners out of or beyond the Rules of the said Prisons of Kings
Bench and Fleet or either of them respectively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. No retaking on fresh Pursuit to be given in Evidence on Action of Escape, unless specially pleaded; nor any special Plea, unless upon Oath that Escape was without Consent of the Marshal, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p8">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said First Day of May no retaking
on fresh pursuit shall be given in Evidence on the Tryal of any Issue in any Action of Escape against the said
Marshall or Warden or their respective Deputie or Deputies or against any other Keeper or Keepers of any other
Prison or Prisons as aforesaid unlesse the same be specially pleaded nor shall any special Plea be taken received
or allowed unlesse Oath be first made in writing by the Marshal or Warden or their respective Deputie or
Deputies or by such other Keeper or Keepers of any other Prison or Prisons as aforesaid against whom such
Action shall be brought and filed in the proper Office of the respective Courts that the Prisoner for whose
Escape such Action is brought did without his consent privity or knowledge make such Escape and if such
Affidavitt shall att any Time afterwards appeare to be false and the Marshall or Warden or other Keeper or
Keepers of any other Prison or Prisons shall be convicted thereof by due course of Law such Marshall or Warden
or other Keeper or Keepers of any other Prison or Prisons shall forfeit the Su[m]m of Five hundred pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Prisoner in Execution escaping may be retaken by any new Capias, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p9">And be it further enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid That if att any Time after the said First
Day of May any Prisoner who is or shall be co[m]mitted in Execution to either or any of the said respective
Prisons shall escape from thence by any Ways or Means howsoever the Creditor or Creditors att whose Suit
such Prisoner was charged in Execution att the Time of his Escape shall or may retake such Prisoner by any
new Capias or Capias ad satisfaciendum or sue forth any other kind of Execution on the Judgement as if the
Body of such Prisoner had never been taken in Execution.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Keeper, upon Notice, refusing to shew Prisoner, adjudged an Escape.</head>
			<para id="p10">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if the said Marshall or Warden for the time being
or their respective Deputy or Deputies or other Keeper or Keepers of any other Prison or Prisons shall after One
Days notice in Writing given for that purpose refuse to shew any Prisoner co[m]mitted in Execution to the Creditor
att whose Suit such Prisoner was co[m]mitted or charged or to his Attorney every such Refusal shall be adjudged
to be an Escape in Law.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Marshal, &amp;c. refusing to give a Note whether a Person be Prisoner or not, Penalty &pound;50.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Such Note sufficient Evidence of Person being a Prisoner</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Person or Persons whatsoever desireing to
charge any Person with any Action or Execution shall desire to be informed by the said Marshal or Warden
or their respective Deputy or Deputies or by any other Keeper or Keepers of any other Prison or Prisons whether
such Person be a Prisoner in his Custody or not the said Marshal or Warden or such other Keeper or Keepers
of any other Prison or Prisons shall give a true Note in writing thereof to the Person so requesting the same
or to his lawfull Attorney upon demand att his Office for that purpose or in default thereof shall forfeit the Su[m]m
of Fifty pounds and if such Marshal or Warden or their respective Deputy or Deputies exercising the said Office
or other Keeper or Keepers of any other Prison or Prisons shall give a Note in Writing that such Person is an
actual Prisoner in his or their Custody every such Note shall be accepted and taken as a sufficient Evidence that
such Person was att that time a Prisoner in actual Custody.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. On or before 24th June 1697, all Conveyances of the Inheritance and Leases of King's Bench and Fleet Prisons, &amp;c. to be inrolled; and all present and future Conveyances, &amp;c. to be inrolled in Six Months after Execution thereof, or else to be void.</head>
			<para id="p13">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That on or before the Foure and twentieth Day of June
One thousand six hundred ninety seven all &amp; every the Conveyances Grants and Mortgages of the Inheritance
of the aforesaid Prisons of Kings Bench and Fleet or either of them and of the Prison houses Lands Tenements
Buildings &amp; other Hereditaments to the said Prisons of Kings Bench and Flee or either of them (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) belonging or in
any wise apptaining and all Leases thereof and the respective Titles of the Marshall of the Kings Bench and
Warden of the Fleet Prisons thereunto or of him or them in whom the Inheritance or Inheritances of in &amp; to
the said Prisons and Prison-houses and Premisses or either of them now are and all Trusts and Declarations of
Trust thereunto or unto either of them relating shall be inrolled (viz<emph type="p">t</emph>:) that of of the Marshall of the Kings Bench
in the Kings Bench Court and that of the Warden [of the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Fleet in the Court of Co[m]mon Pleas att Westminster
and that all future Conveyances Grants &amp; Mortgages of the Inheritance of the said Prisons of Kings Bench and
Fleet or of either of them or of any Part of either of them and all Leases thereof and all Trusts and Declarations
of Trust thereunto or unto either of them relating shall be so enrolled in the respective Courts as aforesaid
within Six Months next after the executing of every or any such Conveyances Grants Mortgages or Leases or
such Trusts or Declarations of Trusts thereunto or unto either of them relating or of any of them and if any
such Conveyances Grants or Mortgages of the Inheritance of the said Prisons of Kings Bench or Fleet or either
of them [or of any Part of either of them<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] or any such Trusts or Declarations of Trust thereunto or unto either
of them relating or any Leases of the said Premisses be not so enrolled within the Times limitted as aforesaid
in the said Courts respectively as aforesaid that then and in such Case as well the present as all future Conveyances
Grants and Mortgages of every of them &amp; the Inheritance of the said Prisons of King's Bench and Fleet or either
of them or of any Part of either of them and all Leases thereof and all Trusts and Declarations of Trust thereunto
or unto any of them relating shall be and are hereby declared to be utterly void and of none effect as if the
same had never been executed Any Law Statute or Custome to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Office of Marshal of the King's Bench and Warden of the Fleet to be executed by those who have the Inheritance of the said Prisons, or their Deputies, &amp;c.; and the Marshal and Warden answerable for their Deputies.</head>
			<para id="p14">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said First Day of May the said
Offices of Marshal of the Kings Bench Prison and Warden of the Fleet and each of them shall be executed by
the several Persons to whom the Inheritance of the Prisons Prison-houses Lands Tenements &amp; other Hereditaments
of the said Prisons of Kings Bench and Fleet or either of them shall then belong or appertaine respectively in
his or their respective proper Person or Persons or by his or their sufficient Deputy or Deputies (for which
Deputy or Deputies and for all Forfeitures Escapes and other Misdemeanors in their respective Offices by such
Deputy or Deputies permitted suffered or co[m]mitted the said Person or Persons in whom the aforesaid Inheritances
respectively are or shall then be shall be answerable) and the Profitts and aforesaid Inheritances of the said several
Offices shall be sequestred seized or extended to make satisfaction for such Forfeitures Escapes and Misdemeanours
respectively as if premitted suffered or co[m]mitted by the Person or Persons themselves or either of them in whom the
respective Inheritances of the said Prisons shall then be.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. On Bill filed against Warden, and Rule given out, Judgement to be signed unless Plea in Three Days after Rule is out.</head>
			<para id="p15">And whereas the way of proceeding against the Warden of the Fleet Prison by Bill in the Courts of Co[m]mon
Pleas &amp; Excheq[uer] att Westminster is found to be very dilatory Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid
That from and after the said First Day of May itt shall and may be lawfull to and for any Person or Persons
having cause of Action against the Warden of the Fleet Prison upon Bill filed in the said Courts of Co[m]mon Pleas
or Exchequer against the said Warden and a Rule being given to plead thereto to be out Eight Days att most
after filing such Bill to signe Judgement against the said Warden of the Fleet unlesse hee plead to the said Bill
within Three Days after such Rule is out.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Copy of Declaration may be delivered to Prisoner, &amp;c. and after Rule to plead be out and Affidavit made thereof, Plaintiff may sign Judgement.</head>
			<para id="p16">And for the more easie and quick obtaining of Judgement against any Person or Persons who now is or
hereafter shall be a Prisoner or Prisoners in the aforesaid Prison of the Fleet Be it further enacted by the Authority
aforesaid That from and after the First Day of May it shall and may be lawfull to &amp; for any Person or Persons
who hath or shall have any cause of Action against any Prisoner or Prisoners who now is or are or hereafter shall
be co[m]mitted to the said Prison of the Fleet after filing or entring of a Declaration in such Action with the proper
Officer to deliver a Coppy of such Declaration or Declarations to any such Defendant or Defendants in any
personal Action or Actions, or to the Turn-key or Porter of the said Fleet Prison and after Rule given thereupon
to plead to be out att Eight Days att most after delivery of such Copy of Declaration or Declarac[i]ons and Affidavitt
made of such delivery before the Lord Chief Justice or one other of the Justices of the Co[m]mon Pleas or before the
Lord Chief Baron or some other of the Barons of the Coif of the Exchequer att Westminster of the delivery of
such Declaration or Declarations to the Defendant or Defend<emph type="p">t</emph>s in such Action or Actions or to the Turn-key or Porter
of the said Fleet Prison as aforesaid to sign Judgement in such Action or Actions against such Defendant or Defendants
as if such Defendant or Defendants had been actually charged att the Barr of the Co[m]mon Pleas or Exchequer
with such Action or Actions Any Law Statute Usage or Custome to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">No Prisoner to pay Chamber Rent longer than while in actual Possession, nor above 2s. 6d. per Week.; Taking or demanding more,; Penalty &pound;20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And whereas great Summs of Money have been and are still taken of the Prisoners of the aforesaid Prisons of
Kings Bench and Fleet and other Prisons under pretence of Chamber Rent although the said Prisoners have not
had the actual Possession of any Chamber within the said Prisons or any of them For the avoiding of that Inconvenience
for the future be it enacted That from and after the said First Day of May no Prisoner or Prisoners shall pay
or be compellable to pay any Chamber Rent for any Chamber within either or any of the said Prisons for any
longer Time than hee or they is or are actually in Possession of the said Chamber or Chambers and that dureing
such Time as hee or they is or are actually in Possession of any such Chamber or Chambers within either or any
of the said Prisons as aforesaid such Prisoner or Prisoners shall not pay above the Su[m]m of Two Shillings and six
pence per Week for any such Chamber and if the Marshal of the Kings Bench Prison Warden of the Fleet or
Keeper or Keepers of any other Prison or Prisons as aforesaid shall take or demand any greater Su[m]m or Su[m]ms
of Money for the Use of such Chamber than the Su[m]m of Two shillings and six pence per Week hee or they so
taking or demanding shall in such Case for every such Offence forfeit the Su[m]m of Twenty Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Debtor being in pretended Privileged Places, Sheriffs, &amp;c. may take Posse Comitatus, and arrest in the said Privileged Places, on Mesne or other Process, Extent, or Execution; may break open Doors to execute Process; Sheriff, &amp;c. neglecting or refusing to execute such Process,; Penalty &pound;100; Opposing Officers in executing the same,; Penalty &pound;50 and Punishment; Rescuing Prisoner so taken,; Penalty &pound;500; and on Nonpayment thereof and Costs within One Month after Judgment signed,; Transportation for Seven Years.; Returning,; Death; Harbouring or concealing Rescner, Transportation for Seven Years, unless Debt and Costs paid; Returning,; Death</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">And for the preventing for the future the many notorious &amp; scandalous Practices used in many pretended
priveledged Places in and about the Cities of London and Westminster and Borough of Southwark in the County
of Surrey by obstructing the Execution of legal Processe there and thereby defrauding &amp; cheating great Numbers
of People of their honest and just Debts Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the
said First Day of May it shall and may be lawfull for any Person or Persons who have or hath any Debt or
Debts Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money due or oweing to him from any person or p[er]sons who now is or hereafter shall be
and reside within the White Fryars Savoy Salisbury Court Ram-Alley Mitre Court Fullers Rents Baldwyns Gardens
Mountague Close or the Minories Mint Clink or Deadmans Place upon legal Processe taken out against such Person
or Persons to demand and require the Sheriffs of London and Middlesex Head Bayliffe of the Liberty of the
Dutchy of Lancaster or High Sheriff of the County of Surrey of Bayliffe of the Liberty of the Borough of
Southwarke for the time being (as the Case shall require if the Plaintiffe think itt requisite) or their respective
Deputy or Deputies Officer or Officers to take and they are hereby enabled respectively to take the Posse Comitatus
or such other Power as to him or them or any of them shall seem requisite &amp; enter the said pretended
priveledged Places and any or either of them (as the Case shall require) and to arrest and in case of resistance or
refusal to open the Doors to break open any Door or Doors to arrest such Person or Persons upon any Mesne
or other Processe Extent or Execution or to seize the Goods of any such person or p[er]sons upon any Execution 
or Extent and if the said Sheriff or Sheriffs Head Bayliff or their Deputy or Deputies Officer or Officers or either
or any of them shall neglect or refuse (upon such request) with such forcer to [doe<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] their best endeavours for the
executing of such Processe Execution or Extent hee or they so neglecting or refuseing to execute such Processe
Execution or Extent shall forfeit to the Plaintiff or Plaintiffs in such Action the Su[m]m of One hundred pounds
to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in which no Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law
or more than one Imparlance shall be allowed and if in the executing of such Processe Execution or Extent any
Person or Persons shall oppose or resist any such Officer or Officers or any of them or any who shall be aiding
or assisting to him them or any of them in the executing of such Processe Execution or Extent hee or they so
offending shall for every time hee or they shall so offend forfeit the Su[m]m of Fifty pounds [and moreover shall
be by some Justice of Peace co[m]mitted to the co[m]mon Goal of such County City or Place where such Offence
shall be co[m]mitted there to remain without Bail or Mainprize until the next Assizes Sessions of Oyer &amp; Terminer
and general Goal Delivery to be held for such County City or Place and such Offender or Offenders being of
such Offence or Offences duely convicted every such Offender shall suffer and undergo such Imprisonment and
be sett in the Pillory as the Court where such Conviction shall be shall think fitt<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] and if any Rescous shall be
made of any Prisoner taken by any such Officer or Officers as aforesaid upon any such Processe Execution or
Extent within the Limitts of any the before mentioned p[re]tended priveledged Places by any Person or Persons
whatsoever such person or p[er]sons so making such Rescous or aiding assisting or abetting the same &amp; being thereof
lawfully convicted shall respectively forfeit to the Plaintiff in any such Action the Su[m]m of Five hundred pounds
to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of his Majesties Courts att Westminster
in which Action Bill Plaint or Information no Essoigne Priveledge Protection Wager of Law or more than one
Imparlance shall be allowed and if after such Recovery had against any Person or Persons for such Rescous
or for aiding assisting or abetting the same the Person or Persons against whom such Recovery shall be had
shall refuse or neglect to pay to the Plaintiff in such Action or to his her or their Executors Administrators or
Assigns the Su[m]m or Su[m]ms recovered with full Costs of Suit within One Month after Judgement signed upon
such Recovery &amp; Demand made that then the Person or Persons so refusing or neglecting as aforesaid [upon
producing a Copy of the Judgement upon which such Recovery shall be had and Oath made that the Money
recovered is not paid shall by order of such Court wherein the said Person or Persons was or were so convicted
of or for any such Rescous or for aiding assisting or abetting the same be transported by the Sheriff or Sheriffs
of the County City or Place where such Conviction shall happen to be<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] to one of his Majesties Plantations
beyond [the Seas<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] there to remaine for the space of Seven Yeares and if the Person or Persons so transported
shall returne againe to this Kingdome within the space of Seven Yeares hee she or they so returning shall be
and is hereby adjudged guilty of Felony and shall not be allowed the Benefitt of Clergy but shall suffer &amp;
forfeit as in Cases of Felony where Clergy is not allowed and if any Person or Persons inhabiting within either
or any of the aforesaid p[re]tended priveledged Places shall receive conceal or harbour any Person or Persons who
shall have made any Rescous as aforesaid hee she or they so receiving concealing or harbouring any such Person
or Persons knowing or having had Notice that such Person or Persons had been guilty of such Offence being
thereof convicted by due Course of Law shall be [by order of that Court where such Conviction shall happen to
be by the Sheriff or Sheriffs of the County City or Place where the Offence was co[m]mitted <ref idref="n6">6</ref>] transported to some
or one of his Majesties Plantations beyond the Seas there to remaine for the space of Seven Yeares [unlesse such
Person or Persons shall within the space of One Month next after such Conviction pay to the Plaintiff or Plaintiffs
in such Action or Suit the full Debt or Duty for which such Action or Suit was brought with full Costs<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] and if
hee she or they shall returne into this Kingdome within the said space of Seven Yeares hee she or they so
returning shall be and is hereby adjudged guilty of Felony and shall not be allowed the Benefitt of Clergy but
shall suffer and forfeit as in Cases of Felony where Clergy is not allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Penalties how disposed of.</head>
			<para id="p21">And be it further enacted That the several Penalties before in and by this Act inflicted and not particularly
disposed of shall goe one halfe to his Majesty his Heires and Successors and the other halfe to him or them that
will sue for the same to be recovered as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. This Act to be a general Law.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">In Action for executing the same, General Issue may be pleaded; Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And for the prevention of Disputes touching this Act be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid, That the same
and every Clause and Thing therein contained shall be deemed adjudged and taken to be a general Law and that
it shall not be needful to shew or sett forth the same or any Clause thereof in pleading and that the same and
all Clauses therein shall be construed most largely and beneficially for the p[re]venting of all the Mischiefs Abuses
Escapes &amp; other Inconveniences herein provided against And further that if any Person or Persons shall att any
time be sued for putting in Execution any Power or Authority given by this Act such p[er]son and Persons shall
and may plead the general Issue and give in evidence this Act and the special Matter and if the Plaintiff or
Plaintiffs in such Action shall be nonsuit or a Verdict given for the Defendant or Defendants or if the Plaintiff
or Plaintiffs discontinue their Action or if upon Demurrer Judgement shall be given for the Defendant or Defendants
every such Defendant or Defendants shall have his or their double Costs.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Proviso for Right of Martha Johnson and others.</head>
			<para id="p24">Saving unto Martha Johnson Widow Thomas Johnson &amp; John Johnsons Sons of the said Martha and Frances
her Daughter their Heires Executors Administrators and Assigns all such Right Title Estate Equity Interest &amp;
Demand as she or they now have [or shall<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] or may have challenge or claime of in or unto all or any the
Houses and Shops belonging to the Office of the Warden of the Fleet or to the Prison of the Fleet herein before
contained as fully and effectually to all Intents and Purposes as she or they had before the making of this Act
as if this Act had never been had or made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Proviso for Securities made by William Lenthall Esq[uer] to Sir John Cutler and Edmund Boulter.</head>
			<para id="p25">(<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) Provided neverthelesse That nothing in this Act contained shall extend to prejudice impeach or lessen any
Security or Securities for any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms of Money made or given by or out of the said Officer of Marshal of
the Marshalsea of the Court of Kings Bench or the Profitts thereof by William Lenthall Esq[uer] to Sir John Cutler
Baronett deceased or to Edmund Boulter Esq[uer] Executor of the said Sir John Cutler or to any other Person or
Persons in trust for them or either of them or to subject the said Office or the Proffitts thereof or the Person or
Person or Persons in whom the same are or shall be vested to any of the Forfeitures or Penalties in this Act
contained other than such as they are or may be liable unto before the making of this Act until such Su[m]m or
Su[m]ms of Money secured thereby shall be fully satisfied and paid Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary
thereof notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Proviso for Right of Anthony Smith.</head>
			<para id="p26">Saving unto Anthony Smith Mariner his Heires Executors Administrators &amp; Assigns all such Right Title Estate
Equity Interest and Demand as hee or they now have or shall or may have challenge or claime of in or unto
the Office of Warden of the Fleet or the Prison of the Fleet or all or any of the Houses and Shopps belonging
to the Office of Warden of the Fleet or to the Prison of the Fleet or herein before contained (by virtue of Two
Decrees in Chancery the one of them made the Two and twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred
eighty three and the other of them the Six &amp; twentieth Day of January One thousand six hundred eighty five
whereby Foure hundred twenty five pounds &amp; the Int[er]est thereof was &amp; is decreed to be paid to the said Anthony
Smith out of the said Office Houses Shops &amp; App[en]tenances after a Mortgage made thereof by Thomas Bromhall
unto Henry Norwood Esq[uer] was satisfied) as fully &amp; effectually to all intents &amp; purposes as hee or they had before
the making of this Act and as if this Act had never been had or made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Proviso for Right of Thomas Norwood; and of John Clements.</head>
			<para id="p27">Provided neverthelesse That nothing in this Act contained shall be deemed construed or adjudged to take
away lessen charge or prejudice the Right Title or Interest of Thomas Norwood surviving Executor of Henry
Norwood as for touching or concerning a Debt of Two thousand one hundred fifty and three Pounds &amp; Interest
secured to the said Henry Norwood by virtue of a Mortgage of the Office of Warden of the Fleet Prison bearing
Date the Twenty third Day of November in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seventy &amp; six
or so much thereof as is justly due thereupon nor to take away lessen or prejudice the Right Title or Interest of
John Clements of the Middle Temple London Gentleman as for touching or concerning a Debt of Two thousand
two hundred ninety nine pounds &amp; Interest secured to the said John Clements in trust for himselfe &amp; others
by virtue of a Mortgage of the said Office of Warden bearing Date the Third Day of May One thousand six
hundred seventy &amp; eight or so much thereof as is justly due thereupon.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Deputations granted by William Lenthall made void, and succeeding Marshals to be constituted by him with Consent of Edmund Boulter for the time herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p28">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all &amp; every Deputation or Deputations Grant or
Grants att any Time heretofore made or executed by William Lenthall Esq[uer] of the said Office of Marshall of the
Marshalsea of the said Court of Kings Bench is and are hereby declared void and of none effect and that all &amp;
every succeeding Marshall shall from time to time &amp; att all times hereafter be constituted &amp; appointed by the said
William Lenthall his Heires &amp; Assigns by &amp; with the consent in writing under the Hand &amp; Seale of Edmund
Boulter Esq[uer] his Executors Administrators &amp; Assigns until the Debt oweing by the said William Lenthall to the
said Edmund Boulter Executor of Sir John Cutler Baronett deceased be satisfied.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Errors <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">respectively <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">use <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">The following Clauses are annexed to the Original Act in four separate Schedules.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


