<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46873" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXV. An Act for licensing Hawkers and Pedlars for a further provision for the Payment of the Int[er]est of the Transport Debt for the reducing of Ireland. [Rot. Parl. 8&amp;9 Gul. III. p.9. nu.1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>6 &amp; 7 W. III. c.7. &sect; 8.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">From 24 June 1697 till 25 June 1698, every Hawker, &amp;c. to pay a Duty of &pound;4.; and an additional &pound;4 for every Horse, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an Act of Parliament was made in the Sixth and Seventh Yeares of His Majesties Reigne intituled
An Act for granting to his Majesty several additional Duties upon Coffee Tea Chocolate and Spice towards
Satisfaction of the Debts due for Transport Service for the Reduction of Ireland in which Provision was made for
the Payment of Interest att Five pounds per Centum for Three Yeares for the Principal Sum[m]s of Three hundred
and thirty thousand seven hundred and sixty nine pounds ten shillings seven pence then allowed to be due for
the said Transport Service for the reducing of Ireland which Duties have proved very deficient to answer such
Interest Wee your Majesties most dutiful and loyal Subjects the Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled being willing that
a further Provision may be made and Fund raised for making good to your Majesties said Subjects the Deficiency
of that Provision do hereby give &amp; grant unto your Majesty the Duties herein after mentioned and do humbly
beseech your Majesty that it may be enacted and be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with
the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal &amp; Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and
by the Authority of the same That from &amp; after the Foure and twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred
ninety seven until the Five and twentieth Day of June which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred ninety eight there shall be answered and paid to his Majesty his Heires &amp; Successors by every Hawker
Pedler Petty Chapman or any other trading Person or Persons going from Towne to Towne or to other Means
Houses &amp; travelling either on Foot or with Horse Horses or otherwise within the Kingdome of England Dominion
of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed (except as herein after is excepted) carrying to sell or exposing to
sale any Goods Wares or Merchandizes a Duty of Foure pounds and that every Person so travelling with a Horse
Ass or Mule or other Beast bearing or drawing Burthen shall pay the Su[m]m of Foure pounds from the said Fource
&amp; twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven to the Five &amp; twentieth Day of June One
thousand six hundred ninety eight for each Horse Ass or Mule or other Beast bearing or drawing Burthen hee or
she shall so travel with over and above the said first mentioned Duty of Foure pounds.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Hawkers to certify Commissioners for Transportation how they travel and trade; and pay down One Moiety of the Duty, and give Bond for the other at Six Months End.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Allowance for prompt Payment.; Licence</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Pedlar Hawker Petty Chapman and other trading
Person or Persons so travelling as aforesaid shall before the Foure and twentieth Day of June One thousand six
hundred ninety seven deliver or cause to be delivered unto the Co[m]missioners for Transportation or any Person or
persons authorized or deputed by them or the major part of them in writing under their Hands &amp; Seals a Note
in writing under his or her Hand or under the Hand of some Person by her or them authorized in that behalfe
how and in what manner hee or she will travel and trade whether on Foot or with One or more Horse or
Horses Ass or Asses Mule or Mules or other Beast or Beasts of Burthen for her or his so travelling and trading
for which hee or she shall thereupon pay or cause to be paid unto the said Co[m]missioners for Transportation or
any Person or Persons authorized or deputed by them or the major part of them in writing under their Hands
&amp; Seales one Moiety of the Duty by this Act payable for the same and give Security by Bond with One or
more sufficient Sureries to be taken in his Majesties Name for the true Payment of the other Moiety of the said
Duties att the end of Six Kalendar Months unlesse the Party shall chuse to pay downe the other Moiety of the
said Duty in which case hee or she shall be allowed after the Rate of Two shillings in the Pound for prompt
Payment of the same and thereupon a Licence shall be granted unto him or her so to travel or trade by the
said Co[m]missioners for Transportation or any Two or more of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Hawker, &amp;c. trading without or contrary to Licence; Penalty &pound;12</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Refusing to produce Licence to Mayor, &amp;c.; Penalty &pound;5.; and on Non-payment; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further enacted That if any such Hawker Pedlar or Petty Chapman from &amp; after the said Fource
and twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven be found trading as aforesaid without or
contrary to such Licence such Person shall for each and every such Offence forfeit the Su[m]m of Twelve pounds
the one Moiety thereof to the Informer &amp; the other Moiety to the Poor of the pish wherein such Offender shall 
be discovered and that every Person so trading who upon demand made by any Justice of the Peace Mayor
Constable or other Officer of the Peace of any Towne Corporate or Borough where hee or she shall so trade
shall refuse to produce and shew unto such Justice of Peace Mayor Constable or other Officer of the Peace his
or her Licence for so trading to be granted as aforesaid that then the person so refusing shall forfeit Five pounds
to be paid to the Churchwardens of the Parish where such demand shall be made to the Use of the Poor of the
same and for Nonpayment thereof shall suffer as a co[m]mon Vagrant and be co[m]mitted to the House of Correction.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Commissioners for Transportation to grant Licences to Hawkers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Fee.; A distinct Account to be kept, and Duties paid into the Exchequer Weekly.; Penalty.; Money to be applied as by 6 &amp; 7 W. III. c. 7</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for the said Co[m]missioners for
Transportation or any Two or more of them and they are hereby directed appointed and required upon the
Terms aforesaid and upon the Receipt and Security given as aforesaid to grant a Licence to be by them subscribed
to every Hawker Pedlar Petty Chapman or any other trading Person for him or herselfe or for him or herselfe
with One or more Horses Asses Mules or other Beasts which hee or she shall travel with as the Case shall
require for which Licence there shall be taken onely One shilling unlesse such Hawker Pedlar or Petty Chapman
shall travel with Horse Asse or Mule or other Beast of Burthen and in that Case there shall be paid for such
Licence Two shillings onely over &amp; above the Duties aforesaid and no more and that the said Co[m]missioners shall
keep a separate and distinct Account of the Duties granted by this Act and pay the Money ariseing thereby
into his Majesties Exchequer upon Wednesday in every Week (unlesse a Holyday) and if it be a Holyday then
on the next Day after that is not a Holyday and upon Neglect or Refusal of the same shall incurr the
Penalties Forfeitures Damages and Costs as other the Officers of the Exchequer herein after mentioned shall be
liable unto which Money so paid in shall be applied to the Uses herein after menc[i]oned by this Act that is to
say for the paying the Interest of the said Three hundred and thirty thousand seven hundred sixty nine pounds
ten shillings seven pence in such Sort &amp; Manner and in such Proportions as the Duties ariseing by virtue of the
said recited Act made in the Sixth and Seventh Yeare of his Majesties Reigne are appointed to be paid and
applied and not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Forging Licence; Penalty &pound;50 and Punishment.</head>
			<para id="p9">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Person and Persons whatsoever shall forge
or counterfeit any Licence or Licences or travel with such forged or counterfeited Licences for the Purposes aforesaid
such Person shall forfeit the Su[m]m of Fifty pounds one Moiety thereof to the King the other to him that shall
prosecute or sue for the same to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of his Majesties
Courts of Record att Westminster in which no Essoigne Protection Wager of Law or more then one Imparlance
shall be allowed and shall be subject to such other Pains and Penalties as may be inflicted on Persons for Forgery.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. In Actions for executing Act, General Issue. Treble Costs.</head>
			<para id="p10">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Person or Persons shall be sued molested or
troubled for putting in Execution any the Powers contained in this Act or for doeing any Matter or Thing pursuant
thereunto such Person or Persons shall and may plead the General Issue Not Guilty and give the special matter
in Evidence and if the Plaintiff or Plaintiffs shall be nonsuited or Judgment be given against him or them upon
Demurrer or a Verdict passe for the Defendant such Defendant shall have his her or their Treble Costs to be
recovered in such Manner as where by Law Costs are given to Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Constable, &amp;c. refusing to assist in the Execution of the Act;</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Constable Headborough or other Officer or
Officers aforesaid shall refuse or neglect upon due Notice or on their owne View to be aiding and assisting in
the Execution of this Act being thereunto required and each and every such Officer or Officers being thereof
convicted by the Oath of One or more credible Witnesse or Witnesses before any Justice of the Peace for the
County or Place where such Offence shall be co[m]mitted shall forfeit for each and every such Offence contrary to
this Act the Su[m]m of Forty shillings to be levied by Distresse and Sale of the Offenders Goods by Warrant under
the Hand and Seale of such Justice of the Peace the one Moiety to the Poor of the Parish where such Offence
shall be co[m]mitted the other Moiety to the Informer who shall prosecute for the same rendring the Overplus thereof
to the Owner if any be.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Hawker, &amp;c. may be detained till be produce his Licence.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Hawker trading without Licence may be carried before Justice of Peace.; Penalty &pound;12,; Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And it is further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for any Person and
Persons whatsoever to seize and detaine any such Hawker Pedlar Petty Chapman or other trading Person or Persons
as aforesaid till such Time as hee she or they shall produce a Licence in that behalfe if hee she or they have any
and if hee she or they shall be found trading without a Licence contrary to this Act for such reasonable Time as
hee she or they may give Notice to the Constable Headborough Tythingman Churchwarden Overseer of the Poor
or some other Parish Officer or Officers who are hereby required to carry such Person so seized before some one
of his Majesties Justices of the Peace of the County or Place where such Offence or Offences shall be co[m]mitted
which said Justice of the Peace is hereby authorized and strictly required either upon the Confession of the Party
offending or due Proof by Witnesse upon Oath (which hee is hereby impowered to administer) that the person so
brought before him had so traded as aforesaid and that no such Licence shall be produced by such Offender before
the said Justice by Warrant under his Hand and Seale to cause the said Su[m]m of Twelve pounds to be forthwith
levied by Distresse and Sale of the Offender or Offenders Goods Wares or Merchandizes rendring the Overplus
if any be to the Owner or Owners thereof after true deducc[i]on of the reasonable Charge for taking the said Distresse
and out of the said Sale to pay the said respective Penalties and Forfeitures aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Proviso for selling of Newspapers, &amp;c. Fish, &amp;c. and Goods or Wares by the Makers thereof, and for Tinkers, Coopers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided always and be it enacted That this Act or any thing herein contained shall not extend to prohibit
any Person from selling of any Acts of Parliament Forms of Prayer Proclamations Gazettes licensed Almanacks
or other printed Papers licensed by Authority or any Fish Fruits or Victuals nor to hinder any Person or Persons
who are the real Workers or Makers of any Goods or Wares within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales
or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed or his her or their Children Apprentices Servants or Agents from carrying
abroad exposing to sale and selling any of the said Goods and Wares of his her or their owne making in any
publick Mart Faires Marketts or elsewhere nor any Tinker Cooper Glazier Plummers Harnesse-menders or other
Persons usually trading in mending Kettles Tubs Houshold Goods or Harnesse whatsoever from going about and
carrying with him or them proper Materials for mending the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. A Register to be kept of Monies paid into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p16">Provided also and it is further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That there shall be provided and kept in his
Majesties Exchequer that is to say in the Office of the Auditor of Receipts one Book or Register in which all
Moneys that shall be paid into the Exchequer by virtue of this Act shall be entred registred and kept apart and
distinct from all other Moneys paid or payable to his Majesty or upon any other Branch of his Majesties Revenue
or upon any other Account whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Officers of Exchequer misapplying Monies, Forfeiture of Office, Incapacity, and Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Orders for paying Money contrary to this Act void</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">Provided and it is further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Officer in the Exchequer shall divert
or misapply any of the Moneys that shall be paid into the Exchequer by virtue of this Act to any other Uses or
Purposes than are hereby directed then such Officer so offending shall forfeit his Office in the Exchequer and be
incapable of any Office or Place of Trust and shall be liable to pay the treble Value of any Su[m]m or Su[m]ms so
diverted or misapplied to any of the Persons thereby grieved their respective Executors Administrators or Assigns
who will sue for the same by any Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Informac[i]on in any of his Majesties Courts of
Record att Westminster wherein no Essoigne Protection Wager of Law Priveledge of Parliament or other Priveledge
or more than one Imparlance shall be granted or allowed and all Orders and Warrants for issuing paying or
disposing any of the Moneys to be raised by virtue of this Act contrary to the true Intent and Meaning thereof
shall be utterly void to all intents &amp; purposes whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Proviso for Sale of Goods in public Markets, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p19">Provided always and it is hereby further enacted That nothing herein contained shall extend or be construed
to extend to hinder any Person or Persons from selling or exposing to sale any sorts of Goods or Merchandizes
in any publick Mart Markett or Faire within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick
upon Tweed but that such person and Persons may do therein as they lawfully might have done before the making
of this Act Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Recital of 6&amp;7 W.&amp;M. c. 7. &sect; 7.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Owners of Ships, &amp;c. to deliver to Commissioners an Account of their Shares, &amp;c.; and if transferred or assigned, and how entitled, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And whereas by the said before in part recited Act itt is provided that the Co[m]missioners for Transportation
should within Three Months after the passing of the said Act make out authentick Debentures for each Su[m]m of
Money due to or for every respective Shipp as the same was adjusted by the Co[m]missioners for taking and stating
the publick Accounts of the Kingdome and that such Debenture when made out be delivered either to the Owner
of or to the Agent appearing for every such respective Shipp and shall be made payable to such Person or his
Assigns as such respective Owner or his Agent shall nominate for the Use of the Owners of the respective Shipps
Now for the better adjusting and setting forth of what Share Part and Proportion of the Money by this and the
said in part recited Act any Person is or may be intituled unto &amp; that the respective Agents may be the better
informed for making their Payments and for preventing of Frauds in that behalfe Be it enacted by the Authority
aforesaid That on or before the First Day of August One thousand six hundred ninety seven the several Owners
of the said Shipps or such person or Persons to whom their several Shares Parts or Interests in the same shall
before that time come or be transferred shall deliver in to the Co[m]missioners for Transportation an Account of
what Share Part or Interest in each Shipp hee or they under whom they claime are att the Time of such Account
possessed of and if such Share Part or Interest shall att that time be transferred assigned or vested in any other
Person than the first Proprietor then the Person or Persons claiming the same shall give an Account to the said
Co[m]missioners how and by what Ways and Means hee or they become intituled to the same and so from time
to time upon the Death of any Person intituled to any Part Share or Interest of the Money intended to be raised
by this or the said in part recited Act or upon assignement or transferring of such Part Share or Interest the
Person who shall be intituled to such Part, Share or Interest upon such Death Assignment or Transferrence shall
give an Account of the same to the said Co[m]missioners as above directed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. A Register of Claims to be kept.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Fee.; No Person to receive any Share till his Claim be delivered to the Commissioners</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That a Register of every persons Claime and Interest shall
be made and from time to time be continued and kept in a Book or Books to be provided by the said Co[m]missioners
for that purpose in their Office and for [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] registring of each Persons Claime or Title there shall be paid to
the Clerk One shilling and no more and no Person shall be intituled to receive from the Agent of any Shipp
any of the Money raised or intended to be raised by this or the said in part recited Act till hee hath delivered
in to the said Co[m]missioners an Account of his Share Part and Interest by him demanded or claimed together with
his Title to the same (if hee be not the first Proprietor) as aforesaid which Register shall be att(<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) seasonable times
viewed without Fee or Reward.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. 6&amp;7 W. III. c. 7. &sect; 1.</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">Surplus after Payment of Interest at 5 per Cent. to be kept in the Exchequer, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in case it shall so happen that the several additional
Duties so granted to his Majesty upon Coffee Tea Chocolate and Spice by the said herein recited Act together
with the Duties to be raised by virtue of this Act shall amount to more than what may prove sufficient for
Payment of Interest att Five Pounds per Centum for the said principal Sum[m] of Three hundred thirty thousand
seven hundred sixty nine pounds ten shillings seven pence that then and in such Case such Surplus ariseing
by the said Duties more than sufficient for payment of the said Interest shall remaine in the Excheq[uer] and not be
disposed of otherwise than by Act of Parliament expresly made in that behalfe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Commissioners, &amp;c. to be paid out of Duties.</head>
			<para id="p26">Provided always That it shall and may be lawfull for the Co[m]missioners of his Majesties Treasury or the Lord
High Tresurer for the time being out of the Monies raised by this or the said recited Act to pay to the said
Co[m]missioners their Clerks or any other Persons such Su[m]ms of Money as they or any of them shall or may
reasonablie deserve for their Service or shall or may have expended in the Execution of or in relation to this or the
said recited Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. This Act not to give any new Powers for licensing Hawkers, &amp;c. to sell Goods in Cities, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p27">Provided always and be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That this Act or any thing therein
contained shall not extend or be construed to give any Power for the licensing of any Hawker Pedlar or Petty
Chapman to sell or expose to sale any Wares or Merchandizes in any City Borough Towne Corporate or Markett
Towne within this Realme any otherwise than might have [been<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] done before the making of this Act Any thing
therein contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">all <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


