<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46878" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXX. An Act for supplying some Defects in the Laws for the Relief of the Poor of this Kingdome.[Rot. Parl.8 &amp; 9 Gul.III.p.10.nu.3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Persons coming to inhabit, and bringing with them a Certificate, under the Churchwardens Hands, &amp;c. of any other Parish, &amp;c. of being inhabitants of such other Parish, &amp;c. and such Certificate being allowed, the said other Parish to provide for them whenever they become chargeable.</head>
<para id="p1">
<emph type="i">In what Case removed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Forasmuch as many poor Persons chargeable to the Parish Towneshipp or Place where they live meerly
for want of Work would in any other Place where sufficient Imployment is to be had maintaine themselves
and Families without being burthensome to any Parish Townshipp or Place but not being able to give such Security
as will or may be expected and required upon their coming to settle themselves in any other Place and the Certificates
that have been usually given in such Cases having been oftentimes construed into a notice in Hand-writing they
are for the most parte confined to live in their owne Parishes Townshipps or Places and not permitted to inhabitt
elsewhere though their Labour is wanted in many other Places where the Increase of Manufactures would imploy
more Hands Be it therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent
of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled That if any Person or
Persons whatsoever that from and after the First Day of May which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred ninety seven shall come into any Parish or other Place there to inhabitt and reside shall att the same
time procure bring and deliver to the Churchwardens or Overseers of the Poor of the Parish or Place where any
such Person shall come to inhabitt or to any or either of them a Certificate under the Hands and Seales of the
Churchwardens and Overseers of the Poor of any other Parish Townshipp or Place or the major part of them or
under the Hands and Seales of the Overseers of the Poor of any other Place where there are no Churchwardens
to be attested respectively by Two or more credible Witnesses thereby owning and acknowledging the Person or
Persons mentioned in the said Certificate to be an Inhabitant or Inhitants legally settled in that Parish Townshipp
or Place every such Certificate having been allowed of and subscribed by Two or more of the Justices of the Peace
of the County City Liberty Borough or Towne-Corporate wherein the Parish or Place from whence any such
Certificate shall come doth lie shall oblige the said Parish or Place to receive and provide for the Person mentioned
in the said Certificate together with his or her Family as Inhabitants of that Parish whenever hee she or they
shall happen to become chargeable to or be forced to ask Relief of the Parish Townshipp or Place to which such
Certificate was given and then and not before it shall and may be lawfull for any such Person and his or her
Children though borne in that Parish not having otherwise acquired a legal Settlement there to be removed conveyed
and settled in the Parish or Place from whence such Certificate was brought.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Persons receiving Alms, their Wives, Children, &amp;c. to wear a Badge on the Shoulder of the Right Sleeve.; Refusing to wear the Badge,; Punishment; Churchwardens, &amp;c. relieving poor Persons not wearing such Badge; Penalty 20s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And to the end that the Money raised onely for the Relief of such as are as well impotent as poor may not
be misapplied &amp; consumed by the idle sturdy and disorderly Beggars Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid
That every such Person as from and after the First Day of September One thousand six hundred ninety seven
shall be upon the Collection and receive Relief of any Parish or Place and the Wife and Children of any such
Person cohabiting in the same House (such Child onely excepted as shall be by the Churchwardens and Overseers
of the Poor permitted to live att home in order to have the care of and attend an impotent and helplesse Parent)
shall upon the Shoulder of the right Sleeve of the uppermost Garment of every such Person in an open and
visible manner weare such Badge or Mark as is herein after mentioned and expressed that is to say a large Roman
P, together with the first Letter of the Name of the Parish or Place whereof such poor Person is an Inhabitant
cutt either in red or blew Cloth as by the Churchwardens and Overseers of the Poor it shall be directed and
appointed And if any such poor Person shall att any time neglect or refuse to weare such Badge or Mark as
aforesaid and in manner as aforesaid itt shall and may be lawfull for any Justice of the Peace of the County City
Liberty or Towne Corporate where any such Offence shall be co[m]mitted upon complaint to him for that purpose
to be made to punish every such Offender for every such Offence either by ordering of his or her Relief or usuall
Allowance on the Collection to be abridged suspended or withdrawne or otherwise by co[m]mitting of any such
Offender to the House of Correction there to be whipt and kept to hard Labour for any Number of Days not
exceeding One and twenty as to the said Justice in his discretion it shall seem most meet and if any such
Churchwarden or Overseer of the Poor from and after the said First Day of September shall relieve any such
poor Person not haveing and wearing such Badge or Mark as aforesaid being thereof convicted upon the Oath of
One or more credible Witnesse or Witnesses before any Justice of the Peace of the County City Liberty or Towne
Corporate where any such Offence shall be co[m]mitted shall forfeit for every such Offence the Su[m]m of Twenty
shillings to be levied by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of every such Offender by Warrant under the Hand
and Seale of any such Justice one Moiety thereof to be to the use of the Informer and the other to the Poor of
the Parish where the Offence shall be co[m]mitted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Justices in Sessions, on Appeal to them concerning the Settlement of any poor Person, to award Costs.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Person ordered to pay Costs, living out of Jurisdiction, Justice of the County, &amp;c. where such Person inhabits, may cause the Money to be levied; If no Distress, Imprisonment in County Gaol</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And for the more effectual preventing of vexatious Removals and frivolous Appeals Be it further enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That the Justices of the Peace of any County or Riding in their General or Quarter Sessions
of the Peace upon any Appeal before them there to be had for and concerning the Settlement of any poor
Person or upon any proof before them there to be made of notice of any such Appeal to have been given by
the proper Officer to the Churchwardens or Overseers of the Poor of any Parish or Place (though they did not
afterwards prosecute such Appeal) shall att the same Quarter Sessions award and order to the Party for whom
and in whose behalfe such Appeal shall be determined or to whome such Notice did appeare to have been given
as aforesaid such Costs and Charges in the Law as by the said Justices in their discretion shall be thought most
reasonable and just to be paid by the Churchwardens Overseers of the Poor or any other Person against whome
such Appeal shall be determined or by the p[er]son that did give such Notice as aforesaid and if the Person ordered
to pay such Costs shall happen to live in any County Riding City or Towne Corporate or elsewhere out of the
Jurisdiction of the said Court Itt shall and may be lawfull for any Justice of the Peace of the County Riding City
Liberty or Towne Corporate wherein such Person shall inhabitt and every such Justice is hereby required upon
request to him for that purpose to be made and a true Copy of the Order for the Payment of such Costs produced
and proved by some credible Witnesse upon Oath by Warrant under his Hand and Seale to cause the Money
mentioned in that Order to be levied by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of the Person that is ordered and ought
to pay the same and if no such Distresse can or may be had to co[m]mitt such Person to the co[m]mon Gaol of that
County or Liberty there to remaine by the space of Twenty Days.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Single Persons not deemed to have a good Settlement under One Year's Service.</head>
			<para id="p7">And whereas some Doubts have arisen touching the Settlement of unmarried p[er]sons not having Child or Children
lawfully hired into any Parish or Towne for One Yeare Be it therefore enacted &amp; declared by the Authority
aforesaid That no such Person so hired as aforesaid shall be adjudged or deemed to have a good Settlement in
any such Parish or Townshipp unlesse such Person shall continue and abide in the same Service dureing the space
of One whole Yeare.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V.</head>
			<para id="p8"><emph type="i">43 Eliz. c. 2. &sect; 5.; Poor Children appointed Apprentices pursuant to 43 Eliz. c. 2. those to whom they are appointed, bound; to execute Indenture and to provide for them according to the Indenture signed by the Justices, &amp;c. Penalty &pound;10. Persons to whom poor Children appointed, may appeal</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And whereas by an Act made in the Three and fortieth Yeare of the Reigne of Queen Elizabeth intituled
An Act for the Relief of the Poor Itt is amongst other Things enacted That it shall be lawfull for the Churchwardens
&amp; Overseers of the Poor of any Parish or the greater part of them by the Assent of Two Justices of the Peace
whereof One to be of the Quorum to bind poor Children Apprentices where they shall see convenient but there
being Doubts whether the Person's to whom such Children are to bound are compellable to receive such Children
as Apprentices that Law hath failed of its due Execution Be it therefore enacted and declared by the Authority
aforesaid That where any poor Children shall be appointed to be bound Apprentices pursuant to the said Act
the Person or Persons to whome they are so appointed to be bound shall receive and provide for them according
to the Indenture signed and confirmed by the Two Justices of the Peace and also execute the other part of the
said Indentures and if hee or she shall refuse so to doe Oath being thereof made by one of the Churchwardensss
or Overseers of the Poor before any Two of the Justices of the Peace for that County Liberty or Riding hee or
she for every such Offence shall forfeit the Su[m]m of Ten pounds to be levied by Distresse and Sale of the Goods
of any such Offender by Warrant under the Hands and Seales of the said Justices the same to be applied to the use
of the Poor of that Parish or Place where such Offence was co[m]mitted saving always to the Person to whome
any poor Child shall be appointed to be bound an Apprentice as aforesaid if hee or she shall think themselves
agrieved thereby his or her Appeal to the next General or Quarter Sessions of the Peace for that County or Riding
whose Order therein shall be final and conclude all Parties.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Appeal against Order for Removal determined at Sessions.</head>
			<para id="p10">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the First Day of May One thousand
six hundred ninety seven the Appeal against any Order for the removal of any poor Person from out of any
Parish Townshipp or Place shall be had prosecuted and determined att the General or Quarter Sessions of the
Peace for the County Division or Riding wherein the Parish Townshipp or Place from whence such poor Person
shall be removed doth lie and not elsewhere Any former Law or Statute to the contrary thereof in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Promise, &amp;c. to take Poor back.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided always That nothing in this Act contained shall extend or be construed to extend to make void any
Promise or Engagement already made by the Churchwardens or Overseers of the Poor of any Parish Townshipp
or Place to receive and take back any Persons in case they should become poor or want Releif.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. And for Justices of Peace at St. Alban's hearing Appeals.</head>
			<para id="p12">(<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Provided That this Act nor any thing therein contained shall be construed to hinder the Justices of the Peace
within the Liberty of Saint Albans from hearing and determining any Appeals for the Settlement of the Poor in
their Quarter Sessions as they might have done before the making of this Act Any thing therein contained
to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


