<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46886" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>THE TITLES OF THE PRIVATE ACTS.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">i. An Act for naturalizing Frederick Christiaen de Rhede co[m]monly called Lord Aghram and others.</para>
		<para id="p2">ij. An Act for the Settlement of the Mannor of Treyagoe in the County of Hereford and other the Lands
late of Crompton Mynors Esq[uire] deceased and for raising and encreasing of the Portion of Theodosia Mynors the
Daughter of the said Crompton she being an Infant of the Age of Seventeene Yeares.</para>
		<para id="p3">iij. An Act for vesting the Mannor of Holme al[ia]s East Holme and Swannage in the County of Dorsett part of
the Estate of Sir John Hotham Baronett in Trustees to be sold for dischargeing a Mortgage thereupon and upon
the residue of the said Sir John Hothams Estate &amp; for payment of his other Debts.</para>
		<para id="p4">iiij. An Act for enabling Oliver Neve of Great Witchingham in the County of Norffolk Esquire to sell two
Houses in London and for vesting other Lands in the said County of greater value to the same Uses.</para>
		<para id="p5">v. An Act for enabling James Duke of Ormond to raise Money by Sale of Woods and making Leases for
Lives renewable for ever for payment of Debts and for encourageing English Plantation in Ireland and for Charles
Lord Weston Earle of Arran in the Kingdome of Ireland to make Leases of his Estate in the said Kingdome.</para>
		<para id="p6">vj. An Act for the Exchange of certaine Advowsons betweene the Bishopp of London and the Earle of
Nottingham.</para>
		<para id="p7">vij. An Act for the speedy satisfying the Debts of Francis late Lord Holles deceased.</para>
		<para id="p8">viij. An Act to enable Sir Ralph Ashton Baronett to supply an omission of Limitation intended in his Marriage
Settlement for the Benefitt of his Issue Male.</para>
		<para id="p9">ix. An Act for the Sale of the Estate of Francis Griffith late of London Scrivener deceased for payment of
his Debts.</para>
		<para id="p10">x. An Act for settling the Estate of Mary Savile an Infant upon her Marriage.</para>
		<para id="p11">xj. An Act to enable the Sale of Lands late of Jeoffery Stockley in the County of Chester deceased for
payment of his Debts and for making provision for Mary his Daughter.</para>
		<para id="p12">xij. An Act for vesting certaine Messuages Lands and Tenements late of Charles Milson deceased in Trustees
to sell for Payment of Debts and Legacies and lay out the Surplus Money in a Purchase of Lands for the use
of Edward Milson and his Heires according to the Will of the said Charles Milson.</para>
		<para id="p13">xiij. An Act to enable Nicholas Goodwin the Elder and Nicholas Goodwin the Younger to sell the Mannor of
Winslow in the County of Bucks and with the Moneys ariseing thereby and other Moneys to be advanced by
the said Nicholas Goodwin the Elder to purchase Lands of a greater yearely Value to be settled to the same
uses as the said Mannor is now settled.</para>
		<para id="p14">xiiij. An Act for the vesting of certaine Lands of William Melward in the County of Hereford Clerk in
Trustees for payments of Debts.</para>
		<para id="p15">xv. An Act for vesting the Estate of Edward Kerrey Esq[uire] lying in Binoeston in the Country of Salop in
Trustees to discharge Incumbrances thereon and to raise Portions for Younger Children and for confirming the
Marriage Settlement of the said Edward Kerrey.</para>
		<para id="p16">xvj. An Act for vesting part of the Estate of Thomas Panton Esq[uire] in Trustees to be sold for payment of
Debts and securing a Jointure to Mary his now Wife.</para>
		<para id="p17">xvij. An Act for naturalizing John Keyser &amp; others.</para>
		<para id="p18">xviij. An Act to enable Edward Leigh Esq[uire] and Jane his Wife and their Trustees to sell the Mannors of
Waxham and Horsey and certaine Lands and Tenements in the County of Norffolk and to purchase and settle
other Lands to the same uses.</para>
		<para id="p19">xix. An Act for vesting and settling certaine Estates of William James Gent. in and upon Trustees to be sold
for the payment of Debts &amp; making Provision for himselfe his Wife and their Children.</para>
		<para id="p20">xx. An Act for importing several Goods and Merchandizes laden in Turkey on board the Shipps called the
Successe and Draggon Galley paying Customes as if imported by English Shipps.</para>
		<para id="p21">xxj. An Act to enable William Fallows an Infant to sell an Estate in the County of Chester to pay Debts
secured by Mortgages.</para>
		<para id="p22">xxij. An Act to supply a Defect in an Act for enabling Oliver Neve Esquire to sell Two Houses in London
and for settling Lands in the County of Norffolk of greater Value to the same Uses.</para>
		<para id="p23">xxiij. An Act explaining a former Act of Parliament intituled An Act for enabling Trustees to sell part of the
Estate of Edmund Warner deceased for Payment of his Debts and for preserving the rest for the Benefitt of
his Heires.</para>
		<para id="p24">xxiiij. An Act for vesting part of the Estate of Roger Crowle Esquire deceased in Trustees for raiseing Portions
for his Younger Children in regard hee (being a Lunatick) could not execute a Power in his Marriage Settlement
for that purpose.</para>
		<para id="p25">xxv. An Act to vest certaine Lands late of Samuel Trotman Esquire deceased lying in Barking Eastham Westham
and Woolwich in the Counties of Kent and Essex in Trustees to be sold and to settle other Lands in lieu thereof.</para>
		<para id="p26">xxvj. An Act for the speedy Payment of the Debts of Sir William Thompson Knight, Serjeant att Law deceased.</para>
		<para id="p27">xxvij. An Act for annulling the Marriage of Hannah Knight an Infant and directing the Guardianshipp of the
said Infant.</para>
		<para id="p28">xxviij. An Act for the enabling the Sale of the Mannor of Rowling in Kent which by mistake was by General
Words comprized in the Marriage Settlement of the said William Hamond Gent. contrary to the Meaning of
the Parties.</para>
	</section>
</report>


