<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46883" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXV. An Act for raiseing the Militia for the Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety seven although the Months Pay formerly advanced be not repaid.[Rot. Parl.8&amp;9 Gul.III.p.11.nu.4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 14 Car.II. c. 3. &sect; 6;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">And that upon Invasion it was found necessary to draw out the
Soldiers into actual Service, and to provide Pay in Hand; and that the like Occasion may happen during the present War. If before 25th April 1698, it shall be found necessary to draw out Soldiers, the same shall be signified to Lieutenants, &amp;c. the said Lieutenants, &amp;c. in pursuance of Orders from His Majesty, and although Pay advanced be not reimbursed, may raise and draw out Soldiers into actual Service, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act of Parliament made in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth Yeares of the Reigne of
the late King Charles the Second intituled An Act for ordering the Forces in the several Counties of
this Kingdome itt was (amongst other things) enacted That in case of Invasions Insurrections or Rebellions
whereby Occasion should be to draw out the Soldiers mentioned and appointed in and by the said Act into actually
Service the Persons charged by the said Act with Horses Horsemen and Arms should provide each their Soldier
respectively with pay in Hand not exceeding One Months Pay as should be in that behalfe directed by the
respective Lieutenants of the several Counties and in their Absence or otherwise by their Direction by their Deputies
or any Two or more of them for Repayment of which said Moneys and for Satisfaction of the Officers for their
Pay dureing such time not exceeding One Month as aforesaid as they should be with their Soldiers in such actual
Service it was thereby declared That Provision should be made for the same by His said Majesty His Heires and
Successors out of his or their publick Treasury or Revenue Neverthelesse it was thereby further provided and
enacted That in case a Months Pay should be provided and advanced as aforesaid That no Person who should
have advanced his Proportion thereof should be charged with any other like Months Payment until hee or they
should have been reimbursed the said Months Pay and so from time to time the said Months Pay by him or
them last before provided and advanced as aforesaid And whereas upon the Invasion of the Coasts of this Kingdome
by the French it was found necessary for the Publick Defence and Safety to draw out the said Soldiers into actual
Service and to charge the said Persons to provide each their Soldier respectively with Pay in Hand although the
Months Pay by several of them before that time provided and advanced was not nor could be reimbursed And
whereas the like Occasions may possibly happen dureing the present Warr Be it therefore enacted by the Kings
most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Co[m]mons
in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That if att any time before the Five and
twentieth Day of April which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety &amp; eight it shall
be found by His Majesty to be necessary for the Defence and Safety of this Kingdome to draw out the said Soldiers
into actual Service and the same shall be declared and signified to the respective Lieutenants or Deputy Lieutenants
and the Lord Warden of the Cinque Ports Two Ancient Towns and their Members or in his Absence his Lieutenant
or Lieutenants by His Majestie itt shall be lawfull for the said Lieutenants or their Deputies] or any Three or
more of them as aforesaid and the Lord Warden of the Cinque Ports Two Ancient Townes and their Members or
in his Absence his Lieutenant or Lieutenants in pursuance of such Orders from His Majesty notwithstanding that
One or more Months Pay before that time advanced be not reimbursed to raise and draw out the said Soldiers
into actual Service and to cause the Persons charged as aforesaid to provide each their Soldiers with Pay in Hand
not exceeding One Months Pay in such manner as if all the Pay before that time advanced and provided had been
fully reimbursed and paid.</para>
	</section>
</report>


