<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46882" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXIV. An Act for the lessening the Duty upon Tin and Pewter exported and granting an Equivalent for the same by a Duty upon Druggs. [Rot.Parl.8&amp;9 Gul.III.p.11.nu.3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Tin exported to pay 3s. per Cwt. Wrought Tin, called Pewter, 28. per Cwt.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas upon due Consideration of the greate Abatement in the Price of Tin since the Book of Rates
was settled itt has been found just to reduce the Duty payable on the Exportation thereof to a more
reasonable Par with other Goods of the Product of England Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty
by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred
ninety seven there shall be paid on [an<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Entry of Tin to be exported for every Hundred weight containing One
hundred &amp; twelve pounds of such Tin unwrought the Su[m]m of Three shillings and for every Hundred weight of
Tin wrought co[m]monly called Pewter containing One hundred &amp; twelve pounds the Sum of Two shillings and so in
proportion for any greater or lesser Quantity of either and no more Any thing in the Book of Rates to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Recital of 12 Car. II. c.4. and Book of Rates (D.)</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">Drugs imported in English Shipping to pay the full Value, otherwise imported Treble the Value</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p3">And whereas by an Act made in the Twelfth Yeare of the late King Charles the Second intituled A Subsidy
granted to the King of Tunnage and Poundage and other Su[m]ms of Money payable upon Merchandizes exported &amp;
imported which Act is to have Continuance until the First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six
it is provided That all Drugs imported directly from the Place of their Growth in English built Shipping be rated
One third Part of what is charged in the said Book of Rates and no more Now for a full Recompence to such
Persons who may have any Loan upon the said Duty on Tin so taken off as aforesaid Be it further enacted by
the Authority aforesaid That from the said Tenth Day of May the Subsidy to be received for all Drugs imported
directly from the Place of their Growth in English built Shipping shall be according to the full Value on the
respective Species enumerated in the Book of Rates and not according to the said Abatement and for all Drugs
otherwise imported Treble such [full<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Value Any thing in the said recited Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Dyers Drugs excepted.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided always That nothing in this Act contained shall extend to the laying a further Duty on any sort of
Drugs used in Dying.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


