<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46881" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1696-7</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXIII. An Act to make perpetual and more effectual an Act intituled An Act to prevent Delays att the Quarter Sessions of the Peace. [Rot. Parl.8&amp;9 Gul.III.p. II.nu.2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>5W. &amp;M.c.II. made perpetual.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas an Act made in the Fifth (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Sixth Yeares of the Reigne of King William and the late Queen
Mary intituled An Act to prevent Delays of Proceedings att the Quarter Sessions of the Peace which
was to continue and be in force for Three Yeares and from thence to the end of the next Session of Parliament
by Experience hath been found useful and beneficial therefore for continuing the same be it enacted by the Kings
most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in
this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That the said Act shall be and is hereby
continued and shall be in force and made perpetual.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Party prosecuting any Certiorari to remove an Indictment may find Two Manucaptors to enter into a Recognizance, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">Party to appear daily in the King's Bench Court until discharged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">And for the making the Purpose and Designe of the said Act more effectual be it enacted by the Authority
aforesaid That from &amp; after the One and twentieth Day of April which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred ninety seven the Party or Parties prosecuting any Certiorari to remove any Indictment or
Presentment from the Quarter or General Sessions of the Peace may find two sufficient Manucaptors who shall
enter into a Recognizance before any One of His Majesties Justices of the Court of Kings Bench in the same Su[m]m 
and under the same Condition as is required by the said Act whereof mention shall be made on the Back of such
Writt under the Hand of the Justice taking the same which shall be as effectual and available to all Intents &amp;
Purposes to stay or supersede any further Proceedings upon any Indictment or p[re]sentment for the removal of which
the said Writt of Certiorari shall be granted as if the Recognizance had been taken before any one of the
Justices of the Peace of the County or Place where such Indictment was found or p[re]sentment made and also it
shall be added to the Condition of every Recognizance taken by virtue of this and the said Act that the Party or
Parties p[ro]secuting such Writt of Certiorari shall appeare from Day to Day in the said Court of Kings Bench and
not depart until hee or they shall be discharged by the said Court.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


