<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46889" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act to give further time for the administring of Oaths relating to Talleys &amp; Orders and for the easier dispatch of the Publick Businesse in the Exchequer &amp; in the Bank of England.[Rot. Parl. 9 Gul. III.p.1.n.3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 8&amp;9 W. III.c.20. &sect; 58;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that many Persons through Ignorance, &amp;c. had neglected to take Assignments, &amp;c. in Writing, as prescribed by the said Act, &amp;c.; and that the like Omissions may happen before the 10th June 1698; Persons having purchased since 10th June 1697, or who may before the 10th June 1698, purchase Tallies, &amp;c., and neglect to take Assignments, &amp;c. as by the said Act, may do so on or before the 10th June 1698</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act made in the Parliament holden att Westminster in the Eighth and Ninth Yeares of
His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for making Good the Deficiencies of several Funds therein mentioned
and for enlargeing the Capital Stock of the Bank of England and for raiseing the Publick Creditt (amongst other
Provisions Matters and Things therein contained) itt was enacted That no Assignement or Transference which
from and after the Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven should be made of any of the
Orders or Talleys therein mentioned or of any of the Moneys contained or specified therein upon the selling
buying or bargaining of the same should be good and available either in Law or Equity or be in any wise effectual
for the assigning or transferring the Right or Property of any such Order or Talley or any the Moneys thereby
due or payable unlesse such Assignement or Transference be made in Writing and be signed or sealed in the
manner therein mentioned and be within Ten Days after the Signing thereof entred or registred in the manner
therein expressed and that Oath be made within the said Ten Days before such Officers or Persons as are therein
appointed that no Allowance Premium Gratuity or Consideration whatsoever exceeding the lawfull Int[er]est and an
Allowance exceeding the Rate of Six Pounds per Centum directly or indirectly or by any Way Device Shift
Exchange Chevisance [Wager<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] or otherwise howsoever was taken accepted gained gotten or agreed to be taken
accepted gained or gotten for or in respect of such Assignement and it is thereby further enacted and provided
That where any such Orders of Loan or Parts thereof or such Talleys were actually &amp; bona fide purchased. and
bought before the said Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven and Oath thereof should be
made att any time or times within Three Months from thence next ensuing before the Officers or Persons therein
mentioned in all such cases the Person or Persons claiming such Orders or Parts of Orders or Talleys should not
in respect thereof be obliged by that Act to take the said other Oath concerning the Premium Reward or Allowance
as by the said Act relation being thereunto had may more fully appeare And whereas many Persons through
ignorance or inadvertency or by some other Impediment have neglected to take such Assignements or Transferences
as aforesaid in Writing signed or sealed in the manner prescribed by the said former Act or to enter or register
the same or to make such respective Oath concerning such Talleys or Orders as is required by the said Act as
aforesaid within the respective times thereby limitted and the like Neglects or Omissions may possibly happen
before the Tenth Day of June which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety eight
whereby the Assignements so made or intended and the Right or Property of the Assignees thereupon are or may
in strictnesse of Law be invalidated by virture of the said Act Now to the end that Relief may be given to such
p[er]sons who may suffer by reason of such Neglects or Omissions and yett that the Remedy provided by the said
former Act against Extortion and unreasonable Bargains concerning the said Talleys and Orders may still be
preserved Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords
Spiritual and Temporal and of the Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by Authority of the same
That all and every Person and Persons Bodies Politick or Corporate who since the said Tenth Day of June One
thousand six hundred ninety seven or before the said Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight
have bought or purchased [or shall have bought or purchased<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] any Orders or Part of Orders or Talleys and
have neglected or shall neglect to take such Assignements and register the same and to make an Oath there upon
concerning the premium or Allowance within the Ten Days time limited by the said former Act in the manner
thereby required and the Executors Administrators Successors and Assignes of all and every such Person and persons
Bodies Politick or Corporate shall have Liberty for the doing thereof att any time or times upon or before the
said Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight and the respective Officers Co[m]missioners or other
Persons who were impowered by the said Act to administer the said Oaths within the respective times thereby
limitted are hereby authorized to administer the like Oaths within the respective times by this Act appointed.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Persons having, before 10th June 1697, purchased;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Orders of Loan, &amp;c. and neglected to have their Assignments registered, &amp;c. and making Oath thereof upon or before 10th June 1698, not obliged, on claiming such Orders, &amp;c. to take the Oath concerning the Premium, &amp;c.; and in such Case the Assignment, &amp;c. to be good in Law</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And whereas diverse Persons did before the said Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven
purchase and buy several Orders of Loan or Parts thereof or such Talleys as aforesaid neglecting to have their
Assignements thereof duely registred as the Law directs and many of them instead of taking formal Assignements
 which might be registred have accepted from the Person or Persons who should make the same the indorsing of
his or their names onely upon such Orders Be it further enacted and provided by the Authority aforesaid That
where any such Orders of Loan or Parts thereof or such Talleys were actually and bona fide purchased and
bought before the said Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety seven and Oath thereof shall be made
att any time or times upon or before the said Tenth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight before
any of the Officers or Persons appointed by the said former Act for administring the other Oaths concerning the
Premium or Allowance who have hereby Power given to them in that behalfe in all such cases the Person or
Persons claiming such Orders or Parts of Orders or Talleys by such Assignements not registred or by such
Indorsements shall not in respect thereof be obliged by virtue of this or the said former Act to take the said
other Oath concerning the Premium Reward or Allowance and that in all and every case and cases where the
respective Oath shall be duely made pursuant to this Act and within the respective time hereby limitted for or
concerning such Orders or Parts of Orders or Talleys as aforesaid the Assignement or Transferrence thereof shall
be as good and available in Law and Equity and shall be as effectual for the assigning &amp; transferring the Right or
Property of any such Order or Talley or any the Moneys thereby due or payable as if the respective Oath concerning
the same had been made within the respective times limitted by the said former Act Any thing therein contained
to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Recital that under the Circumstances herein mentioned the Exchequer Tallies had been so much multiplied so as to render Dispatch in Payment of the Interest difficult, and that many of the Holders were desirous of fewer Orders.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Officers of the Exchequer empowered to take in and cancel certain Orders and Tallies, and to give fewer Orders and Tallies of the same Value, &amp;c., as herein mentioned.; No new Order to contain more than &pound;5,000; Indorsement thereon; New Orders to be valid; Principal and Interest thereon paid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And whereas it hath been found necessary to accomodate&mdash;all such Persons as lent any Moneys upon the Creditt
of the Aids Taxes and Impositions given by Parliament with as many Orders and Talleys as they desired by which
Means and the long Continuance of the late Warr the Orders and Talleys of Loan given out of the Exchequer
are multiplied to so great a Number that the Officers of the Exchequer cannot without great difficulty dispatch the
Payment of the Interest (which is payable every Three Months) to the satisfaction of the Lenders And whereas
great Numbers of the said Orders of Loan are now come into the Hands of particular Persons or Bodies Politick
who had rather have fewer Orders &amp; Talleys as well for the case of themselves as the said Officers and to promote
the dispatch of the Publick businesse in the Receipt of Exchequer Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That
from and after the Tenth day of January One thousand six hundred ninety seven itt shall and may be lawfull to
and for the Officers of the Receipt of Excheq[uier] att the Request of any Person or p[er]sons Bodies Politick or Corporate
who are or shall be lawfully entituled to such Orders and Talleys or any of them to take in and cancel so many
Orders as follow successively in Number and Course and are of one and the same Date &amp; are payable to one and
the same Person or Corporation and whereof the Interest shall appeare to have been paid to [one<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and the same
time together with the Tallies belonging to such Orders and to give them as few Orders and Talleys in lieu thereof
of the same Value and in the same Course of Payment as shall be desired by such Persons or Bodies Politick
respectively so as any one such new Order doe not containe in the whole more than Five thousand Pounds upon
which new Orders the Auditor of the Receipt of Exchequer shall cause Indorsements to be made how farr the
Interest of the principal Su[m]ms payable by such new Orders hath been satisfied and to whome last assigned which
said Orders and Talleys so to be given out as aforesaid shall be good valid and effectual in the Law to all Intents
and Purposes to the several Owners &amp; Proprietors thereof And that the principal Moneys upon such new Orders &amp;
Talleys [or any part thereof<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] shall be paid and payable in Course and the Interest thereupon every Three Months
as fully and effectually as if the former Orders or Talleys respectively were not cancelled Any thing in this or
any former Act or Acts of Parliament to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Recital of 8&amp;9W.III.c.20. &sect;48.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">and that the making Dividends at the End of every Four Months was inconvenient; Bank to make Dividends every Six Calendar Months</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And whereas by the Act before recited or mentioned itt was also enacted That the Moneys which from time to
time should become due and payable by virtue of any Talley or Order subscribed into the Capitall Stock of the
Governor and Company of the Bank of England by virtue of the said Act as soon as conveniently might be after
the same should be received out of the Excheq[uer] or any Publick Office by the said Governor and Company their
Officers Servants and Agents and att farthest (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) every Foure Months should be divided by the said Governour and
Company among the Members of the whole Corporation ratably and in Proportion to their several and respective
Parts Shares and Interests in the said Capital Stock for the particular proper and onely Use and behoofe of the
said Members seperately and in their private and personal Capacities as by the said Act relation being thereunto
had may appeare And whereas since the enlarging the Capital Stock of the said Governor and Company of the
Bank of England by Subscription of Talleys and Orders pursuant to the said Act the making Dividends of such
Moneys att the end of every Foure Months is found to be very inconvenient and a great Interrupc[i]on to the
businesse of Transferrs Payments and other Occasions of Persons dealing with the said Bank Be it therefore enacted
and declared by the Authority aforesaid That the [said <ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Governour &amp; Company of the Bank of England or their
Successors shall not be obliged to make Dividends of the Moneys which from time to time shall become due or
payable to and be received by the said Governour and Company by virtue of the Talleys and Orders which have
been so subscribed into the Capital Stock of the said Governour and Company of the Bank of England pursuant
to the said Act of Parliament once. in every Foure Months But the said Governour and Company and their Successors
are hereby required and enjoyned from and after, the Five and twentieth Day of March which shall be in the Yeare
of our Lord One thousand sixe hundred ninety eight to make such Dividends of the said Moneys once in every
Six Kalendary Months att the least unto the Members of the said Corporation according to their respective Shares
and Interests in the said Capital Stock of the said Governour and Company Any thing in the aforesaid Act to
the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">once in <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll; omitted in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


