<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46894" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for explaining an Act made the last Session of Parliament for granting to His Majesty certain Duties upon Malt Mum Sweets Cyder &amp; Perry.[Rot. Parl. 9 Gul. III. p.1.n.8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 8 &amp; 9 W. III. c. 22. &sect; 28. 44</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Duties of the said Act appropriated</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in one Act made in the last Sessions of Parliament intituled An Act for granting to His Majesty
certaine Duties upon Malt Mum Sweets Cyder and Perry as well towards carrying on the Warr against
France as for the necessary Expences of His Majesties Household Liberty was given for making and issuing of
Bills or Ticketts to a certain Value and for borrowing of Two hundred thousand Pounds by Loan in Manner
therein mentioned And whereas some Misconstructions have been made touching the Payment and Satisfaction of
the Loan mentioned in the said Act and of the Bills or Ticketts which have been made and issued pursuant
thereunto Be it hereby declared and enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and
Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority
of the same That all the Duties which have been or hereafter shall be paid into the Receipt of His Majesties
Excheq[uire]by virtue of the said recited Act shall be and are hereby appropriated to be issued and applied to the
Payment and Satisfaction of the said Loan of Two hundred thousand Pounds with Interest for the same or so
much as remains due and unpaid thereof and to the Discharge and Satisfaction of the said Bills or Ticketts with
Interest in the first place in such Course and Order as the said Act directs and appoints and to no other Use
or Purpose whatsoever until the said Loan and the said Bills or Ticketts with Interest shall be fully paid and satisfied
Any thing in the said Act or in any other Act or Acts to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Rules of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c.1. applied to this Act.</head>
			<para id="p3">And [whereas<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the first Moneys ariseing by the said Duties may not be diverted or applied otherwise than is
hereby directed Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Rules &amp; Directions appointed and
enacted in one Act made in the First Yeare of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for a Grant to Their
Majesties of an Aid of Two Shillings in the Pound for One Yeare for the speedy Payment of Moneys thereby
granted into the Receipt of the Exchequer by the Collectors and Receivers thereof and for the Distribution and
Application thereof and keeping distinct Accounts of the same and all other Provisoes Pains Penalties and Forfeitures
thereby enacted in case of Diversion of any Money thereby appropriated are hereby revived and enacted to be in
Force and shall be practised executed and putt in Ure for and concerning the Distribution &amp; Application of the
said Duties hereby appropriated as fully amply and effectually as if the same were particularly repeated and
reenacted.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">that <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


