<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46891" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act for satisfying and discharging the Arreares of several Annuities which incurred betweene the Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety six and the Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety seven. [Rot. Parl. 9 Gul. III. p.1.n.5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Persons having one Life in Annuity, purchased under the several Acts mentioned in 6 &amp; 7 W.III.c.5. may before 25th March 1698, advance the Value of such Annuity, as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For raiseing and dischargeing the Su[m]m of Two hundred fifty five thousand six hundred sixty three Pounds
Five Shillings and Eight pence which remaines due and unpaid to satisfie cleare and pay off the several
Annuities or Su[m]ms of Money which betweene the Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety
six and the Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety seven incurred and became due and ought
to have been paid as well out of Five Seventh Parts of the late Duties of Tunnage of Shipps and other Vessells
and out of Two Seventh Parts of the same Duties as also out of certaine Duties charged upon Salt Be it enacted
by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal
and the Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That it shall and may
be lawfull to and for any Person or Persons Natives or Forreigners having any Estate for One Life of and in
any Annuity purchased or obtained att the Rate of One hundred Pounds for every Foureteene Pounds per Annum
upon the several Acts of Parliament mentioned in an Act made and passed in the Parliament which was holden
att Westminster in the Sixth and Seventh Yeares of His Majesties Reigne (intituled An Act for enabling such
Persons as have Estates for Life in Annuities payable by several former Acts therein mentioned to purchase and
obtaine further and more certaine Interests in such Annuities and in default thereof for admitting other Persons
to purchase and obtaine the same for raising Money for carrying on the Warr against France) or any of them
att any time before the Five and twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety eight to advance
and pay into the Receipt of His Majesties Excheq[uer] so much Money as every or any such Annuity being computed
for Foure Yeares doth or shall amount unto (that is to say) Every such Person shall and may pay to His Majesties
Use for every One hundred Pounds that was paid for the single Life in any Annuity of Fourteen Pounds per
Annum the Su[m]m of Six and fifty Pounds more for changing or converting the same into a certaine terme for
the Residue which shall be then to come of Ninety six Yeares to be reckoned from the Five and twentieth Day
of January One thousand six hundred ninety five or for a further Interest for the residue of the said Terme of
Ninety six Yeares to take Effect after the said Estate for Life and in the same proportion for higher or larger
Annuities.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. If the Persons above mentioned do not make such Advance, any other Person having or not having an Interest in such Life Estate may make such Advance as herein mentioned;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and upon Payment become entitled to such Annuity, and the same shall be charged upon the Funds of the said Act.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Person or Persons being intituled to any
Estate for one Life in being in any such present Annuity or Annuities as aforesaid or such as they shall nominate
shall not before the said Five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety eight advance and
pay into the Recept of Exchequer such Rate or Consideration Money as is before mentioned for changeing such
his her or their Estate for Life into a Terme certaine or for a future Interest as aforesaid that then and in every
such Case it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Person or Persons whatsoever Natives or Forreigners having
or not having any Property or Interest in such Estate for Life att any time or times after the said Five and
twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety eight and on or before the Tenth day of April One
thousand six hundred ninety eight to contribute advance and pay into the said Receipt of Exchequer so much
Money as any such Annuity being computed for Foure Yeares doth and shall amount to that is to say For every
One hundred Pounds that was paid for the single Life in an Anuity of Foureteene Pounds a yeare there shall
be paid in all the Cases last mentioned the like Su[m]m of Six and fifty Pounds for an Interest for the then Residue
of the said Terme of Ninety six Yeares to be reckoned as aforesaid and to be charged with subject to the
present Estate for Life of and in the same Annuities respectively and there shall be paid a Rate or Consideration

in the same proportion for Annuities exceeding Foureteene Pounds a Yeare and that all and every the Person
and Persons so paying the Consideration Money as aforesaid shall im[m]ediately upon Payment of their Moneys be
intituled by this Act to such Annuity or Annuities so to be purchased and the same shall be charged upon such
respective Fund or Revenue in the said former Act mentioned as if the Consideration Money so to be contributed
or advanced for the same had been actually advanced or contributed within the respective Times limitted by the
said former Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Persons entitled to Arrears between 17th May 1696 and 17th May 1697, of Annuities charged upon the Tunnage and Salt Duties, discharging His Majesty to the Amount of Purchase of further Term, entitled to Annuity as herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided always and it is hereby enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Person or Persons who are
or shall be intituled to any Arrears incurred between the Seventeenth day of May One thousand six hundred
ninety six and the Seventeenth day of May One thousand six hundred ninety seven upon the said several Annuities
which were charged upon the said Tunnage Duties or upon the said Duties on Salt and are hereby intended to
be provided for shall upon their Orders Talleys or Lottery Ticketts for such Arrears discharge His Majesty in
the Exchequer of so much as the Consideration Money to be paid by him or them respectively for purchasing a
further Terme or Interest as aforesaid shall amount unto that then and in every such Case all and every
the Person and Persons so dischargeing His Majesty of the Value of the Consideration Money as aforesaid shall
im[m]ediately upon such Discharge given and entred in the Receipt of His Majesties Exchequer (which the proper
Officers there are hereby required to enter and register accordingly without Fee or Charge) be intituled by this
Act to such Annuity or Annuities so to be purchased and the same shall be charged upon such respective Fund
or Revenue in the said former Act mentioned as if the said Consideration Money was actually paid in the lawfull
Coins of this Realme.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Power of former Act revived and extended to this Act.</head>
			<para id="p6">And it is hereby enacted That all and every the Directions Powers and Clauses in the said former Act contained
for or concerning the levying of Tallies the making forth of Orders or for making Transferrences or Assignements
or for apportioning or applying the Moneys ariseing by the said Funds or Revenues or any of them or for
appointing settling or establishing any other Matter or Thing for or in relation to the respective Annuities
thereby purchased or obtained shall be and are by force and virtue of this Act revived and shall be duely observed
practised and putt in Execution for and in respect of such Annuities as shall be purchased or obtained upon this
Act as fully and effectually as if the same Powers Directions and, Clauses were here again expressed and particularly
repeated.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Monies for the said Contributions paid into the Exchequer applied in Payment of Arrears of Annuities charged upon the Tunnage and Salt Duties, during the times and in manner herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p7">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all the Moneys which shall come into the Receipt
of His Majesties Excheq[uire] of or for the said Contributions for further or more certaine Estates in the said Annuities
to be purchased as aforesaid shall be issued and applied and the same are hereby appropriated to &amp; for the
Payment and Satisfaction of the Arrears of the several Annuities which are charged upon the Five Seventh Parts
of the said Tunnage Duties and upon the Two Seventh Parts of the said Tunnage Duties and upon the said
Duties upon Salt and which are or shall be incurred or become payable out of those Funds respectively from
the said Seventeenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety six to the said Seventeenth Day of May One
thousand six hundred ninety seven so that a proportionable Part of the Co[n]ntributions so ariseing in Money shall
be applied to make good each of those Funds according to the Su[m]m of the Arreares incurred within the time
aforesaid which shall from time to time be remaining unpaid thereupon and shall not be diverted to any other
Use Intent or Purpose whatsoever upon paine that any Officer offending therein shall for such Offence forfeit his
Office and Double the Value of every Su[m]m of Money so diverted or misapplied.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Recital that by virtue of 4 W. &amp; M. c. 3. and of subsequent Acts, divers Persons are intitled to Annuities out of Duties of Excise under 4 W. &amp; M. c.3.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">No Quarter's Payment of such Annuities to be made till preceding Quarter paid, of which Public Notice to be given; Officer offending; Loss of Office and Penalty &pound;50; Full Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And whereas by virtue of an Act of Parliament made in the Fourth Yeare of the Reigne of His present Majesty
and of the late Queen of Blessed Memory intituled An Act for granting to Their Majesties certaine Rates and
Duties of Excise upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for securing certaine Recompences &amp; Advantages in the said
Act mentioned to such Persons as shall voluntarily advance the Su[m]m of Ten hundred thousand Ponnds towards
carrying on the Warr against France and of diverse other subsequent Acts of Parliament several Persons are
intituled to have and receive certaine yearely Annuities Rents or Payments out of the said Duties of Excise
granted by the said Act first mentioned payable Quarterly wherein no Benefitt of Survivorshipp is to be had
Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the First Day of March One thousand six
hundred ninety seven next ensuing no Officer or Officers appointed to pay the said Annuities shall pay off any
Quarterly Payment of the said A[n]nuities upon any Order or Orders whatsoever until all and every Person and
Persons intituled to such Annuities [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Payments shall or may have had and received his her or their Annuities
and Payments for the precedent Quarter for which public Notice shall be given by hanging the same upp in
the most convenient publick Place in the said Office that the last precedent Quarter is either fully paid or that
the Money is ready in the Office for the Payment of such as have not timely brought their respective Orders to
be directed or have not thought fitt to call for their Money and in case any Officer shall offend herein by making
any Payment contrary to the Tenor hereof or in any other manner (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) as aforesaid every such Officer shall forfeit
his Office and shall for every such Offence forfeit the Su[m]m of Fifty Pounds to such Person or Persons who shall
sue for the same to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties Courts
of Record att Westminster wherein no Essoigne Protection Priveledge of Parliament or other Priveledge Wager of
Law Injunction or Order of Restraint or more than one Imparlance shall be granted or allowed and in the said
Action the Plaintiffe upon Recovery shall have his full Costs.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">then <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


