<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46897" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XI. An Act for explaining an Act made the last Session of Parliament. entituled An Act for supplying some Defects in the Laws for the Relief of the Poor of this Kingdome. [Rot. Parl. 9. Gul. III. P. 3. n. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 8 &amp; 9 W.III. c. 30. &sect; I.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that Doubts had arisen thereupon.; No Certificate Person adjudged settled, unless he rent a Tenement of &pound;10 per Ann. or execute a Parish Office</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in and by a certaine Act made in the last Session of this present Parliament entituled An Act
for supplying some Defects in the Laws for the Releife of the Poor of this Kingdome Itt was amongst
other things therein contained enacted That if any Person or Persons whatsoever that from and after the First Day
of May in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety seven shall come into any Parish or (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Place
there to inhabitt &amp; reside should att the same time procure bring and deliver to the Churchwardens or Overseers
of the Poor of the Parish or Place where any such Person should come to inhabitt or to any or either of them a
Certificate under the Hands and Seales of the Churchwardens and Overseers of the Poor of any other Parish
Townshipp or Place or the major part of them or under the Hands and Seales of the Overseers of the Poor of
any other Place where there are no Churchwardens to be attested respectively by two or or more credible Witnesses
thereby owning &amp; acknowledging the Person or Persons mentioned in the said Certificate to be an Inhabitant or
Inh[ab]itants legally settled in that Parish Towneshipp or Place every such Certificate having been allowed of and
subscribed by two or more of the Justices of the Peace of the County City Lib[er]ty Borough or Towne-Corporate
wherein the Parish or Place from whence any such Certificate shall come doth lye shall oblidge the said Parish or
Place to receive and provide for the Person mentioned in the Certificate with his or her Familie as Inhabitants of
that Parish whenever he she or they shall happen to become chargeable to or be forced to ask Releife of the
Parish Townshipp or Place to which such Certificate was given and that then and not before it should and might
be lawfull for any such Person and his or her Children though borne in that Parish not having otherwise acquired
a legal Settlement there to be removed conveyed and settled in the Parish or Place from whence such Certificate
was brought And whereas some Doubts have arisen upon Construction of the said Act by what Acts any Person
coming to inhabitt or reside within any Parish by virtue of any such Certificate as aforesaid may procure a legal
Settlement in such Parish and whether such Certificate did not amount to a Notice in writing in order to gaine a
Settlement For explaining thereof and of the said Act Be it therefore enacted &amp; declared by the Kings most
Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this
present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That no Person or Persons whatsoever who shall
come into any Parish by any such Certificate as aforesaid shall be adjudged by any Act whatsoever to have procured
a legal Settlement in such Parish unlesse he or they shall really and bona fide take a Lease of a Tenement of the
yearly Value of Ten Pounds or shall execute some Annual Office in such Parish being legally placed in such
Office.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


