<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46900" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIV. An Act for continuing the Duties upon Coffee Tea and Chocolate and Spices towards Satisfaction of the Debt due for Transport Service for the Reduction of Ireland. [Rot. Parl. 9 Gul. III. p.3.n.4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>The additional Duties on the Exportation of imported Goods by 6 &amp; 7 W. III. c. 7. continued until 1st May 1701, and the said Act in like manner continued.</head>
		<para id="p1">Wee Your Majesties most dutifull and loyal Subjects the Co[m]mons assembled in Parliament for a further
provision of Interest for the Debt due for Transport Service in the Reduction of Ireland att the Rate of
Five Pounds for every Hundred Pounds for One whole Yeare and so proportionably for any greater or lesser
Su[m]m do hereby give and grant unto Your Majesty the additional and other Duties and Impositions herein after
expressed and do most humbly beseech Your Majesty that it may be enacted and be it enacted by the Kings
most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual &amp; Temporal and Co[m]mons in
Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That the additional and other Duties &amp; Impositions upon
the several sorts of Goods &amp; Merchandizes imported into this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and
Towne of Berwick upon Tweed and from thence exported mentioned expressed and granted in and by an Act
made in the Session held in the Sixth and Seventh Yeares of the Reigne of His present Majesty intituled An Act
for granting to His Majesty several additional Duties upon Coffee Tea Chocolate and Spices towards Satisfac[i]on
of the Debts due for Transport Service for the Reduction of Ireland shall be continued from the First Day of
May One thousand six hundred ninety &amp; eight and be raised levied collected answered and paid unto His Majesty
His Heires and Successors until the First Day of May One thousand seven hundred and one And that the said
Act &amp; all Powers Provisions Penalties Articles and Clauses therein contained which by the said Act were or were
intended to have Contin[n]ance until the First Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety and eight shall continue
and be in full Force and Effect until the said First Day of May One thousand seven hundred and one and shall
be practised &amp; executed for raiseing levying collecting answering and paying the said additional and other Duties
and Impositions hereby continued for paying Interest for the Debt due. for the said Transport Service according
to the Tenor and Intent of this present Act.</para>
	</section>
</report>


