<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46901" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XV. An Act for determining Differences by Arbitration. [Rot.Parl. 9 Gul. III.p.3. n.5]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that References made by Rule of Court have contributed to the Ease of the Subject</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Merchants, &amp;c., where Remedy only by Personal Action or Suit in Equity, may agree that Award may be made a Rule of Court, and may insert the same in their Submission</emph>.
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas it hath been found by Experience That References made by Rule of Court have contributed
much to the Ease of the Subject in the determining of Controversies because the Parties become thereby
obliged to submitt to the Award of the Arbitrators under the Penalty of Imprisonment for their Contempt in case
they refuse Submission Now for promoting Trade and rendring the Awards of Arbitrators the more effectual in all
Cases for the final Determination of Controversies referred to them [by<ref idref="n1">1</ref>
] Merchants and Traders or others
concerning Matters of Account or Trade or other Matters Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by
and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled and
by Authority of the same That from &amp; after the Eleventh Day of May which shall be in the yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred ninety eight Itt shall and may be lawfull for all Merchants and Traders &amp; others desiring
to end any Controversie Suit or Quarrel Controversies Suits or Quarrels (for which there is no [other<ref idref="n1">1</ref>
] Remedy
but by Personal Action or Suit in Equity) by Arbitration to agree that their Submission of their Suit to the Award
or Umpirage of any person or persons should be made a Rule of any of His Majesties Courts of Record which
the Parties shall choose and to insert such their Agreement in their Submission or the Condition of the Bond or
Promise whereby they oblidge themselves respectively to submitt to the Award or Umpirage of any Person or
Persons which Agreement being so made and inserted in their Submission or Promise or Condition of their respective
Bonds shall or may upon producing an Affidavit thereof made by the Witnesses thereunto or any one of them
in the Court of which the same is agreed to be made a Rule &amp; reading and filing the said Affidavitt in Court
be entred of Record in such Court and a Rule shall thereupon be made by the said Court that the Parties shall
submitt to &amp; finally be concluded by the Arbitration or Umpirage which shall be made concerning them by the
Arbitrators or Umpire pursuant to such Submission And in case of Disobedience to such Arbitration or Umpirage
the Party neglecting or refusing to performe and execute the same or any part thereof shall be subject to all the
Penalties of contemning a Rule of Court when hee is a Suitor or Defendant in such Court and the Court on
Motion shall issue Processe accordingly which Processe shall not be stopt or delayed in its Execution by any Order
Rule Co[m]mand or Processe of any other Court either of Law or Equity unlesse it shall be made appeare on Oath
to such Court that the Arbitrators or Umpire misbehaved themselves and that such Award Arbitration or Umpirage
was procured by Corruption or other undue Means.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Arbitration unduly procured, void.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That any Arbitration or Umpirage procured by Corruption
or undue Means shall be judged and esteemed void and of none Effect and accordingly be sett aside by any Court
of Law or Equity so as Complaint of such Corruption or undue Practise be made in the Court where the Rule
is made for Submission to such Arbitration or Umpirage before the last Day of the next Terme after such
Arbitration or Umpirage made and published to the Parties Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


