<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46908" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXII. An Act to repeale an Act made in the Nine and thirtieth Yeare of the Reigne of Queen Elizabeth intituled (An Act to restraine the excessive makeing of Malt) and to discharge &amp; vacate Orders made by Justices of Peace by virtue thereof for restraining Malsters from makeing Malt. [Rot. Parl. 9 Gul. III. p. 4. n. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 8 &amp; 9 W. III. c. 22; and of 39 Eliz. c. 16. and that it was doubted whether the same was in force; 39 Eliz. c. 16. repealed, and Orders of Justices, herein mentioned to have been made, therein discharged.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas by an Act made the last Sessions of this present Parliament intituled An Act for granting to His Majesty certaine Duties upon Malt Mum Sweets Cyder and Perry as well towards carrying on the Warr against France as for the necessary Expence of His Majesties Household and other Occasions a Duty of Six Pence per Bushell was laid upon Malt for a certaine time therein limitted And whereas an Act was made in the Nine and thirtieth Yeare of the Reigne of Queene Elizabeth intituled An Act to restraine the excessive makeing of Malt and there hath been some Doubt whether the same Act be now in force by Reason the Title of the said Act was mistaken in the Act of Parliament whereby it was designed to have [been <ref idref="n1">1</ref>] continued yett neverthelesse several Justices of Peace att their Quarter Sessions have taken upon them to make Orders to suppresse and restraine Malsters from buying of Barley to convert into Malt and from using and exerciseing the Imploy of Malting by the Space of One Yeare which is a great Damage to His Majesty by lessening the Revenue and a Discouragement to Malsters For Remedy whereof be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That the said Act made in the Nine and thirtieth Yeare of the Reigne of Queen Elizabeth be repealed
and all Orders made by Justices of Peace for restraining Malsters from making of Malt since the said Duty of Six Pence a Bushell was laid upon Malt are hereby vacated and discharged.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>


