<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46902" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVI. An Act to execute Judgements &amp; Decrees saved in a Clause in an Act of the First Yeare of the Reigne of King William and Queen Mary intituled An Act for taking away the Court holden before the President and Council of the Marches of Wales. [Rot. Parl. 9 Gul. III. p. n. 6]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 1 W.&amp; M. c. 27. &sect; 4; and that the said Clause had become ineffectual.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Court of Chancery, Exchequer, and Great Sessions, where the Cause originally arose, may issue Process upon Decree made in the Court before the President and Council of the Marches of Wales, before 1st June 1689</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in a Statute made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of His Majesty and the late Queen Mary
intituled An Act for taking away the Court holden before the President and Council of the Marches of
Wales Itt is provided That no Judgements nor Decrees passed in the said Court before the First Day of June One
thousand six hundred eighty nine shall be by that Act repealed or annulled but all and every of them shall remaine
in the same force and all Executions upon them in the same state in which they were before the making of that
Act Any thing in that Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding But forasmuch as no Provision is made in
the said Act to authorize His Majesties Courts of Westm[inster] and Great Sessions of Wales or any other Court to order
or issue out any Executions upon the said Judgments and Decrees the said Clause is become fruitlesse &amp; ineffectual
to the great and manifest Damage &amp; Injuries of the Parties on whose behalfes such Judgements and Decrees passed
For Remedy whereof Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice &amp; Consent of
the Lords Spiritual &amp; Temporal and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by Authority of the same
That it shall and may be lawfull to and for His Majesties High Court of Chancery Court of Exchequer att Westminster
or His Majesties Court of Great Sessions in the respective Counties within the Principality of Wales where the
Cause or Causes originally arose to issue forth Execution or Executions and other Processes upon every Judgement
or Decree given or made in the said Court held before the President and Council of the Marches of Wales before
the First Day of June in the Yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred eighty nine in the same Manner
and to the same intent and purpose as if such Judgement or Decree had been given or made in either of the said
Courts of the Exchequer or Grand Sessions.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The said Courts to have Power to review, &amp;c. the said Judgements, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided also and it is hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Courts before mentioned
respectively shall have Power and Authority and are hereby impowered to review reheare reverse or affirme the
said Judgements and Decrees.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


