<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46916" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXX. An Act for increasing His Majesties Duties upon Lustrings and Alamodes. [Rot. Parl. 9 Gul. III. p.5.n.6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Valuation of Lustrings and Alamodes under the Book of Rates, 12 Car. II., and that Duty had been paid thereon accordingly; and that the said Silks were under-valued.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Ad valorem Duties increased; Such Silks valued at &pound;4 for every Pound weight, and Duties paid thereon.; under the like Penalties as by former Acts</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Wrought Silks commonly called Lustrings and Alamodes under the name of Wrought Silks
in and by the Book of Rates referred to in the Act of Tunnage and Poundage which was made and
passed in the Twelfth Yeare of the Reign of His late Majesty King Charles the Second were valued at Fourty
Shillings the Pound Weight containing Sixteen Ounces and according to that Valuation are and will be lyable to
pay several Subsidies additional and other Duties or Impositions to Your Majesty by virtue of several Acts of
Parliam[en]t. since that time made and past referring to the said Book of Rates for the Value of the said Silks We
Your Majesties most dutiful and loyal Subjects the Commons of England in Parliament assembled being sensible
that the said Silks called Lustrings and Alamodes were much undervalued in the said Book and that the same
are ordinarily of a much higher Value than Fourty Shillings for such a Pound Weight as aforesaid Do therefore
in all humility Grant that Your Majesties Duties for and upon all Lustrings and Alamodes imported now payable
by or according to the said Valuation of Fourty Shillings the Pound Weight shal be increased answered and paid
according to the Valuation herein after mentioned And be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and
with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by Authority of the same That all Lustrings and Alamodes which from and after the Four and
twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight shal be imported or brought into the Kingdom of
England Dominion of Wales or Town of Berwick upon Tweed shal be valued at Four Pounds for every Pound
Weight containing Sixteen Ounces as aforesaid And His Majesties several Susbsidies additional and other Duties
and Impositions as aforesaid dureing the continuance of the same respectively shal be collected paid and answered for
and upon the said Lustrings and Alamodes according to the said Valuations of Four Pounds for every Pound
Weight as if the same had been originally inserted in the said Book of Rates and had been pticularly referred to
(instead of the said Rate of Forty Shillings) in the several Acts before mentioned and that according to the
same Rules and Methods and with such and the like Allowances and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are
by the said Acts or every or any of them prescribed for the respective Duties on the said Commodities Any
thing therein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
</report>


