<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46911" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXV. An Act for granting to His Majesty His Heires &amp; Successors further Duties upon Stampt Vellum Parchm[en]t. &amp; Paper. [Rot. Parl. 9 Gul. III. p. 5. n. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Grant of Stamp Duties to the King, his Heirs, &amp;c</head>
		<para id="p1">Wee Your Majesties most dutiful &amp; loyal Subjects the Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled being desirous to raise
such Aids and Supplies as may be proportionable to Your Majesties great and extraordinary Occasions do
humbly present Your Majesty with the free Gift of the further Rates &amp; Duties herein after mentioned and do beseech
Your Majesty that it may be enacted and be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice
and Consent of the Lords Spiritual &amp; Temporal and Co[m]mons in Parliament assembled &amp; by Authority of the same
That from and after the First Day of August in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety eight
there shall be throughout the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Town of Berwick upon Tweed raised
collected &amp; paid unto His Majesty His Heires and Successors for ever the several and respective Things herein after
mentioned which shall be written or ingrossed at any Time or Times after the said First Day of August One
thousand six hundred ninety eight (over and above the Rates [and<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Dutyes and Sums of Money now due and payable
to His Majesty or to any Person or Persons Bodies Politick or Corporate whatsoever for the same) the several and
respective Rates Impositions Duties Charges and Sums of Money herein after expressed in Manner and Forme
following (that is to say).</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Duties on Grants or Letters Patents, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">For every Skin or Peice of Vellum or Parchment on which any Grants or Letters Patents under the Great Seale
of England or the Seal of the Dutchy or the County Palatine of Lancaster of any Honour Dignity Promotion
Franchise Liberty or Priviledge to any Person or Persons Bodies Politick or Corporate or Exemplifications of the same
shall be ingrossed or written (Co[m]missions of Rebellion in Process always excepted) the Sum of Forty Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Pardons, &amp;c. (except Newgate Pardons, &amp;c.)</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p5">For every Skin or Peice of Velum Parchment or Sheet of Paper on which any Pardon (except the General Circuits
and Newgate Pardon) of or for any Crime or Offence [or of <ref idref="n2">2</ref>] any Sum [of Money<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] or Forfeiture whatsoever or on
which any Warrant of Repreive or Relaxation from any Fines Corporal Punishments or other Forfeiture shall be
ingrossed or written the Sum of Fourty Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">Grant of Money, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p7">For every Skin of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Grant from His Majesty His Heires or
Successors of any Sum of Money exceeding One hundred Pounds which shall pass the Great Seal (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) (not directed to
the Great Seal) shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Fourty Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">Grant of Office above &pound;50 per Ann</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p9">For every Skin of Velum or Parchment or for every Sheet of Paper upon which any Grant of any Office or
Imployment which [shall<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] be above the Value of Fifty Pounds per Annum shall be written or ingrossed the Sum of
Fourty Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">
and of Lands in Fee, &amp;c. under the Great Seal, &amp;c</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p11">For every Skin of Velum or Parchment on which any Grant of Lands in Fee Lease for Years or other Grant of
Profit not herein particularly charged that shall passe the Great Seal of England the Seal of the Exchequer the Seal
of the Dutchy or County Palatine of Lancaster or the Privy Seal (not directed to the Great Seal) shall be ingrossed
or written the Sum of Fourty Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p12">
			<emph type="i">Presentation or Donation, &amp;c.
Proviso</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p13">For every Skin or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Poper upon which any Presentation or Donation which
shall pass the Great Seal of England or upon which any Collation to be made by any Arch-Bishop or other Bishop
or any Presentation or Donation to be [made<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] by any Patron whatsoever of or to any Benefice Dignity or Spiritual
or Ecclesiastical Promotion whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Fourty Shillings (Provided such
Benefice Dignity or Promotion be of the yearly Value of Ten Pounds or above in the Kings Books).</para>
		<para id="p14">
			<emph type="i">Dispensation to hold Two Benefices</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p15">For every Skin or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheet or Peice of Paper on which any Dispensation to hold
Two Ecclesiastical Dignities or Benefices or both a Dignitie and a Benefice or any other Dispensation or Faculty from
the Lord Arch-Bishop of Canterbury or the Master of the Facultys for the time being shall be ingrossed or
written the Sum of Fourty Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p16">
			<emph type="i">Admittance to Fellowship, or Attorney, &amp;c</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p17">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment Sheet or Piece of Paper upon which Admittance of any Fellow
of the College of Physicians or of any Attorney Clerk Advocate Procter Notary or other Officer or Officers in any
Court whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Fourty Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p18">
			<emph type="i">Annual Officers in Corporations, &amp;c. exempted</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p19">Provided That this Act shall not be extended to charge with the Duty last mentioned any annual Officer in any
Corporation or inferior Court whose Office is under the Value of Ten Pounds per Annum in Sallaries Fees or other
Perquisites but the said annual Officer is hereby exempted and discharged from the said Duty.</para>
		<para id="p20">
			<emph type="i">Appeal from the Admiralty, Arches, &amp;c</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p21">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Appeal from the Court of
Admiralty Arches or the Prerogative Courts of Canterbury or York shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Fourty
Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p22">
			<emph type="i">Exemplifications</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p23">For every Skin of Velum or Parchment upon which any Exemplification of what Nature soever that shall pass the
Seal of any Court whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Five Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p24">
			<emph type="i">Decree in Chancery, Exchequer, &amp;c</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p25">For every Skin of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Decree or Dismission made by or in
the Court of Chancery Exchequer Court of the County Palatine or Dutchy of Lancaster Courts of the Counties
Palatine of Chester Durham or other Court of Equity whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Six Pence.</para>
		<para id="p26">
			<emph type="i">Institution or Licence under Bishop's Seal, &amp;c</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p27">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Institution or Licence that
shall pass the Seal of any Archbishop or Bishop Chancellor or other Ordinary or any Ecclesiastical Court whatsoever
shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Five Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p28">
			<emph type="i">Writ of Error, Certiorari, &amp;c</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p29">For every Skin or Peice of Vellum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Writt of Error Certiorari
or Appeal (except to the Deligates) shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Five Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p30">
			<emph type="i">Significavit, &amp;c</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p31">For every Skin Piece of Velum Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Significavit pro Corporis deliberatione
shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Five Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p32">
			<emph type="i">Sentence in the Admiralty, &amp;c</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p33">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet or Piece of Paper upon which any Sentence that
shall be given in the Court of the Lord High Amiral of England or the Cinque-Ports exerciseing Admiralty
Jurisdiction or upon any Attachment that shall be made out of any of the said Courts of Admiralty [or any
Relaxation of any such Attachment<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Five Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p34">
			<emph type="i">Letters of Mart</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p35">For every Skin or Pieice of Velum or Parchment or Sheet or Piece of Paper upon which any Letters of Mart
shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Five Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p36">
			<emph type="i">Probates of Wills, Administrations, &amp;c</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p37">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Piece of Paper upon which any Probate of a Will or Letters
of Administration for any Estate above the Value Twenty Pounds shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Five
Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p38">
			<emph type="i">Recognizance, Statute Staple, &amp;c</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p39">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment Sheet or Piece of Paper upon which any Recognizance Statute
Staple or Statute Merchant shall be ingrossed or written or entred of Record in any Court or Office the Sum
of Five Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p40">
			<emph type="i">Nisi Prius or Postea</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p41">For any Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment upon which any Record of Nisi prius or Postea shall be ingrossed
or written the Sum of Two Shillings and Six Pence.</para>
		<para id="p42">
			<emph type="i">Judgments</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p43">For every Skin [or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Piece of Velum or Parchment or Paper upon which shall be ingrossed or written any
Judgment whatsoever which shall be signed by the Master of any Office or his Deputy or Secondary or by any
Prothonotary or his Secondary Deputy or Clerk or any other Officer belonging to any of the Courts at Westminster
who have Power or usually doth or shall sign Judgments the Sum of Two Shillings and Six Pence.</para>
		<para id="p44">
			<emph type="i">Ecclesiastical Commission, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p45">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Commission issuing out
of any Ecclesiastical Court not herein otherwise particularly charged shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Two
Shillings and Six Pence.</para>
		<para id="p46">
			<emph type="i">Admiralty or Cinque Ports Warrant or Decree, or beneficial Warrant, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p47">For every Skin or Peice of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Warrant Monition or
personal Decree in any Court of Admiralty or the Cinque Ports shall be ingrossed or written or upon which any
beneficial Warrant or Order under the Sign Manual of His Majesty His Heires or Successors (except Warrants or
Orders for the Service of the Navy Army and Ordnance) shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Two Shillings
and Six Pence.</para>
		<para id="p48">
			<emph type="i">Special Bail or Appearance</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p49">For every Piece of Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any Special Bail to be taken in any of the Courts
at Westminster or before any of the Judges of the said Courts or in any other Court whatsoever shall be ingrossed
or written and for every Peice of Velum Parchment or Paper upon which shall be ingrossed or written any
Appearance upon such Special Bail the Sum of One Shilling.</para>
		<para id="p50">
			<emph type="i">Bill, Answer, Replication, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p51">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment upon which shall be ingrossed or written any Bill Answer
Replication Rejoyder Interrogatories Depositions taken by Commission or any other Pleadings whatsoever in the
Courts of Chancery Exchequer Dutchy Court and County Palatine Courts or other Courts of Equity the Sum of
One Shilling.</para>
		<para id="p52">
			<emph type="i">Admission, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p53">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment and for every Sheet or Piece of Paper upon which any
Admission into any Corporation or Company or any Matriculation in either of the Two Universities or any Admission
into any of the Inns of Court or Inns of Chancery shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of One Shilling.</para>
		<para id="p54">
			<emph type="i">Affidavit. Exception</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p55">For every Piece of Parchment or Paper upon which any Affidavit shall be ingrossed or written (except Affidavits
taken pursuant to several Acts made in the Thirtieth and Two and thirtieth Years of the Reign of King Charles
the Second for burying in Woollen and except such Affidavits as shall be taken before the Officers of the Customs
or any Justice or Justices of the Peace or before any Co[m]missioners appointed or to be appointed by any Act of
Parliament for the assessing &amp; levying any Aids or Duties granted or to be granted to His Majesty His Heires or
Successors and which Affidavits shall be taken by the said Officers of the Customs Justices or Commissioners by
vertue of their Authority as Justices of the Peace or Co[m]missioners respectively and not otherwise) the Sum of
Six Pence.</para>
		<para id="p56">
			<emph type="i">Copy of Affidavit filed, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p57">(<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) For every Piece of Parchment or Paper upon which any Copy of such Affidvit as is herein before charged that
shall be filed or read in any Court whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Six Pence.</para>
		<para id="p58">
			<emph type="i">Indenture, Lease, &amp;c.; Exception</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p59">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which shall be written or ingrossed
any Indenture Lease or Deed Poll not hereby otherwise charged the Sum of Six Pence (except Indentures for
binding poor Parish Children Apprentices).</para>
		<para id="p60">
			<emph type="i">Original Writ, Subp&oelig;na, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p61">For every Piece of Velum or Parchment or Peice of Paper upon which any original Writt (except such Originall
on which a Writt of Capias issues) Subpena Bill of Middlesex Latitat Writt of Capias Quo Minus Writt of
Dedimus Potestatem to take Answers examine Witnesses or appoint Guardians or any other Writt whatsoever or
any other Process or Mandate that shall issue out of or pass the Seals of any the Courts at Westminster Courts
of the Great Sessions in Wales Courts in Countys Palatine or any other Court whatsoever holding Plea) where
the Debt or Damage doth amount to Forty Shillings or above or the Thing in Demand is of that Value shall be
ingrossed or written (Writts of Covenant for levying Fines Writts of Entry for suffering Co[m]mon Recoveries and
Writts of Habeas Corpus always excepted) the Sum of Six Pence.</para>
		<para id="p62">
			<emph type="i">Entry of Action in Mayor's Court, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p63">For every Pieice of Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any Entry of any Action in the Mayors and Sheriffs
[Cours<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] of London and in Courts in all Corporations and other Courts whatsoever out of which no Writts Process
or Mandates issue holding Plea where the Debt or Damage doth amount to Forty Shillings or above shall be
ingrossed or written the Sum of Six Pence.</para>
		<para id="p64">
			<emph type="i">Common Bail or Appearance</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p65">For every Piece of Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any Co[m]mon Bail to be filed in any Court whatsoever
and upon which any Appearance that shall be made upon such Bail shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Six
Pence which Appearance or Co[m]mon Bail the Defendant shall cause to be entred or filed within Eight [Days
<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]
after the Day upon which the Process on which the Defend[en]t. is arrested shall be returnable upon Penalty of Five
Pounds to be paid to the Plaintiffe for which the Court shall imediately award Judgment whereupon the Plaintiff
may take out Execution.</para>
		<para id="p66">
			<emph type="i">Rule of Court</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p67">For every Piece of Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any Rule or Order made or given in any the Courts
at Westminster either Courts at Law or Equity shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Sixpence.</para>
		<para id="p68">
			<emph type="i">Copy</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p69">For every Piece of Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any Copy of such Rules or Orders entred or the
Copys of any other Records or Proceedings in any of the said Courts at Westminster not hereby otherwise charged
shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Six Pence.</para>
		<para id="p70">
			<emph type="i">Ecclesiastical Monition, Libel, &amp;c.; Copy. &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p71">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which shall be ingrossed or written
any Citation or Monition made in any Ecclesiastical Court or any Libell or Allegation Deposition Answer Sentence
or final Decree or any Inventory exhibited in any Ecclesiastical Court the Courts of Admiralty or Cinque-Ports
or whereupon any Copys of them respectively shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Sixpence.</para>
		<para id="p72">
			<emph type="i">Charter Party, Policy of Assurance, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p73">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Charter Party Policy of
Assurance Pasport Bond Release Contract or other Obligatory Instrument or any Protest Procuration Letter of
Attorney or any other Notaryal Act whatsoever shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of Six Pence.</para>
		<para id="p74">
			<emph type="i">Declaration, Plea, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p75">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Declaration Plea Replication
Rejoynder Demurrer or other Pleadings whatsoever in any Court of Law shall be ingrossed or written the Sum
One Penny.</para>
		<para id="p76">
			<emph type="i">Copy</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p77">And for every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment upon which any Copy thereof shall be written or ingrossed
the Sum of One Penny.</para>
		<para id="p78">
			<emph type="i">Depositions in Chancery, &amp;c. Exception</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p79">For every Skin of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Depositions taken in [the Court
of Chancery<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] or other Court of Equity (except the Paper Draughts of Depositions taken by vertue of any
Co[m]mission before they [are<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] ingrossed) which are not herein before charged or upon which any Copy of any
Bill Answer Plea Demurrer Replication Rejoynder Interrogatories Depositions or other Proceedings whatsoever in any
Court of Equity shall be ingrossed or written the Sum of One Peny.</para>
		<para id="p80">
			<emph type="i">Copy of Will</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p81">For every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which a Copy of any Will shall be
ingrossed or written the Sum of One Peny.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.</head>
			<para id="p82">
				<emph type="i">Officer to date Writ of Arrest; and enter the same,; Officer neglecting, Penalty &pound;10</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p83">And for preventing Abuses co[m]mitted by arresting Persons without any Writt or legall Process to justifie the same
by Means whereof the Duty hereby given for ever to the Crown upon such Process will be lost. be it enacted by
the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said First Day of August One thousand six hundred ninety eight
every Officer or Clerk belonging or which shall hereafter belong to the Court of Kings Bench Co[m]mon Pleas or
Exchequer who shall sign any Writt or Process before Judgment to arrest any Person or Persons thereupon shall
at the signing thereof set down upon such Writt or Process the Day and Year of [his
<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] signing the same which
shall be entred upon the Remembrance or in the Book where the Abstract of such Writt or Process shall be entred:
upon Pain to forfeit the Sum of Ten Pounds for every Offence or Neglect of such Officer or Clerk aforesaid to
be recovered by any Person who shall sue for the same in any Court of Record of His Majesty His Heires or Succes srs
by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information wherein no Wager of Law Protection or Essoign or more than One
Imparlance shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for certain Bills of Exchange, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p84">Provided always That this Act or any thing therein contained shall not extend to charge with the said Duties
or any of them any Bills of Exchange Accounts Bills of Parcell Bills of Fees or any Bills of Notes (not sealed)
for Payment of any Money at Sight or upon Demand or at the End at certain Days of Payment.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. And for Seamen and Soldier's Wills,; on Certificate and Oath of being in the Service at the Time of Death.</head>
			<para id="p85">Provided That nothing in this Act contained shall extend to charge with the said Dutyes or any of them the
Probate of any Will or Letters of Administration of any co[m]mon Seaman or Soldier who shall be slain or dye
in the Service of His Majesty His Heires or Successors a Certificate being produced from the Captain of the Ship
or Vessel or Captain of the Troop or Company under whom such Seaman or Soldier served at the Time of his
Death and Oath made of the Truth thereof before the proper Judge or Officer by whom such Probate or Administration
ought to be granted which Oath such Judge or Officer is hereby authorized and required to administer and for
which no Fee or Reward shall be taken.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V.</head>
			<para id="p86">
				<emph type="i">And for Recognizances before Justices, Surrenders of Copyholds, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p87">Provided also, That this Act or any Clause therein contained shall not be construed to charge with any Duty
any Warrant made by or Recognizance taken before any Justice or Justices of the Peace or any Surrender of any
Copyhold Estate or Copies of such Estate or any Proceedings of any Court Marshal which relate to any Tryal of
any co[m]mon Soldier or any Orders Decrees or Proceedings before any Co[m]missioners of Sewers or in the Court
of Stannerys but such Warrants Recognizances Surrenders Copys Orders Decrees and Proceedings shall and are
hereby declared to be exempted from the Payment of any the Duties before mentioned in this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Sea Officers to pay the same Duty as Land Officers.</head>
			<para id="p88">Provided also and it is hereby enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid That the Officers at Sea shall
by this Act pay the same Duty for their Stamps that the Officers of the Army at Land pay by this Act and no
more upon the same Act only Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Duties redeemable by Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p89">And it is hereby declared That all the Duties by this Act granted to His Majesty His Heires and Successors
shall nevertheless be subject and lyable to such Condition and Power of Redemption by Parliament as by any Act
of this Session is or shall be declared and provided.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII.</head>
			<para id="p90">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners of Stamps to be appointed, &amp;c; Head Office to be kept in London or Westminster; Commissioners to appoint inferior Officers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p91">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That for the better and more effectual levying collecting
and paying unto His Majesty His Heires and Successors the several and respective Duties hereby granted for or
upon stampt Velum Parchment and Paper it shall and may be lawful for His Majesty His Heires and Successors
and to and for the Co[m]missioners of the Treasury or any Three or more of them or the High Treasurer of England
for the time being from time to time to nominate and appoint such Persons as they shalt think fit to be Co[m]missioners
or Officers for the stamping and marking of Parchment Velum and Paper and manageing the Duties thereupon
pursuant to this Act. And that the Co[m]missioners soe to be appointed shall keep their Head Office in some
convenient Place within the Cities of London or Westminster and such Co[m]missioners or the major Part of them
are hereby impowered under their Hands and Seals to appoint such other inferior Officers for the marking or
stamping of Velum Parchment and Paper or for the better collecting or levying the Duties hereby granted to His
Majesty His Heires and Successors as they in their Discretion shall think fit. And the same Co[m]missioners shall
provide from time to time Marks or Stamps proper for the marking and stamping of Velum Parchment and Paper
according to which Marks or Stamps the Kings Dutys ought to be paid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. 5 &amp; 6 W.&amp;M.c.21. 8 &amp; 9 W. III. c.20. &sect; 12.</head>
			<para id="p92">And whereas such or the like Duties as are by this Act charged for ever upon the several Skins Sheets or
Pieces of Velum Parchment and Paper herein before enumerated or mentioned are also charged upon and payable
for the same respectively until the First Day of August One thousand seven hundred and six by several former
Acts of Parliament in that Behalfe. so that in Effect the Duties (as to (<ref idref="n10">10</ref>) Skins Sheets or Peices of Velum Parchment
and Paper in this Act before particularly expressed) are doubled until the said First Day of August One thousand
seven hundred and [six<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] but the said Duties by the said former Acts and those by this thereupon are appropriated
or applicable to different Purposes soe that it is necessary to have distinct Accounts kept of the same. Now for
the better secureing His Majestys Dues and for distinguishing of such Skins Sheets or Pieces of Velum Parchment
and Paper as are doubly charged as aforesaid from those which remain lyable only to the single Duties on the
said former Acts: and to the Intent that the said Duties upon this and the said former Acts upon Velum Parchment
and Paper may be issued and applied to the respective Uses to which they are severally appropriated or intended.</para>
			<para id="p93">
				<emph type="i">Every Skin of Vellum, Parchment, &amp;c. liable to Double Duty, and being once stamped, to be stamped with a Second Mark before being wrote upon; except such as are liable only to single Duty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p94">Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Velum Parchment and Paper herein before charged and
whereof the Duties are hereby intended to be doubled for a Time as aforesaid shall before any of the Matters
or Things herein before mentioned to be thereupon ingrossed or written (such Writeing or ingrossing being after
the said First Day of August One thousand six hundred ninety eight and before the said First Day of August
One thousand seven hundred and six) be first brought to the Head Office for the said Duties to be stamped and
marked with Two Marks or Impressions (that is to say) every [such<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Skin Sheet or Piece of Velum Parchment
and Paper having One Mark or Stamp set thereupon pursuant to the said former Acts or any of them before
the Writeing or ingrossing any of the Matters or Things as aforesaid thereupon shall be brought to the said Office
to be stamped with a Second Mark or Impression of the same Kind. And every Skin Sheet or Piece of Velum
Parchment or Paper having not been stamped or marked with a single Stamp or Mark pursuant to the said former
Acts or any of them shall before the Writeing or ingrossing any of the [Matters<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] or Things as aforesaid thereupon
tither the said First Day of August One thousand seven hundred &amp; six be brought to the said Office to receive
Two several Marks or Impressions [of the same Kind of all which double Marks or Impressions<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] the One shall
denote the Duty by the said former Acts or some of them and the other the Dutie by this present Act thereupon.
Except such Skins Sheets or Pieces of Velum Parchment and Paper which do still remain liable onely to the single
Dutyes on the said former Acts during the Terms thereby granted and are to have only a single Mark or Stamp
according to the Directions of the said former Acts namely.</para>
			<para id="p95">
				<emph type="i">Circuit or Newgate Pardon.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p96">Every Skin or Piece of Velum Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any general Circuit or Newgate Pardon
shall be ingrossed or written liable [only<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] to the single Duty of Fourty Shillings by the said former Acts.</para>
			<para id="p97">
				<emph type="i">Certificate of Degree in the Universities; except Bachelor of Arts</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p98">Every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet or Piece of Paper upon which any Register Entry
Testimonial or Certificate of any Degree taken in either of the Two Universities or Four Inns of Court shall be
ingrossed or written (the Register or Entry of the Degree of any Batchelor of Arts being always excepted) for
which Skins Pieces or Sheets respectively a Duty of Fourty Shillings is payable by the said former Acts only
during the Continuance thereof.</para>
			<para id="p99">
				<emph type="i">Conveyance or Surrender of Grants or Offices, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p100">Every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Conveyance Surrender of
Grants or Offices Release or other Deed whatsoever shall be enrolled of Record in any of the Courts at Westminster
or in any other Court of Record whatsoever or by any Custos Rotulorum or Clerk of the Peace shall be ingrossed
or written whereof the Duty payable as aforesaid by the said former Acts is Five Shillings.</para>
			<para id="p101">
				<emph type="i">Marriage Licence.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p102">Every Skin or Peice of Velum Parchment or Sheet or Peice of Paper upon which any Lycence for or Certificate
of Marriage shall be ingrossed or written which are to be liable only to a Duty of Five Shillings by the said
former Acts.</para>
			<para id="p103">
				<emph type="i">Writ of Covenant</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p104">Every Piece of Velum or Parchment upon which any Writt of Covenant for levying of Fines shall be ingrossed
or written whereof the Duty remaining upon the said former Acts is Five Shillings.</para>
			<para id="p105">
				<emph type="i">Writ of Entry</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p106">Every Piece of Velum or Parchment upon which any Writt of Entry for suffering a common Recovery shall be
engrossed or written which is subject to the like single Duty of Five Shillings.</para>
			<para id="p107">
				<emph type="i">Habeas Corpus</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p108">Every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet of Paper upon which any Writt of Habeas Corpus shall
be ingrossed or written which is also liable to the single Duty of Five Shillings.</para>
			<para id="p109">All [which<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Matters and Things so liable only to the said single Duties until the said First Day of August One
thousand seven hundred and six shall be marked and stamped only with a single Mark or Stamp according to the
said former Acts. Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Vellum, &amp;c. before written, to be stamped, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p110">And it is [hereby <ref idref="n11">11</ref>] further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Velum Parchment and Paper herein
before charged shall before any of the Matters or Things herein before mentioned be thereupon ingrossed or written
(such Writeing or ingrossing being after the last Day of July One thousand seven hundred and six) be first brought
to the Head Office for the said Duties to be stamped and marked with One Mark or Impression for the respective
Duties by this Act payable to His Majesty His Heires and Successors for ever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Commissioners required upon Demand to stamp Vellum, &amp;c. paying the Duties.</head>
			<para id="p111">
				<emph type="i">The Stamp to be a Discharge for Payment; Ingrossing Vellum, &amp;c. before stamped; or marked with a lower Duty; Penalty &pound; 10</emph>.
<emph type="i">Officer in any Public Office guilty of Fraud in the above Matters; Forfeiture of Office and Penalty; Attorney offending disabled; Other Persons offending; Penalty &pound;10; No such Record Deed, &amp;c. good in Law, until Duty and Penalty paid; and Deed stamped, &amp;c; Counterfeiting Stamp, &amp;c; Death</emph>.
</para>
			<para id="p112">And it is hereby further enacted That the Chiefe Co[m]missioners for the said Dutyes upon Velum Parchment and
Paper by themselves or by their Officers imployed under them shall and they are hereby impowred and required
forthwith upon Demand to them made by any Person or Persons from time to to time to stamp or mark as this
Act directs any Quantities or Parcells of Velum Parchment or Paper he or they paying to such Officer or Officers as
shall be appointed in that Behalf the respective Duties payable to His Majesty His Heires or Successors for the same
without any other Fee or Reward and without Delay which Stamp or Mark shall be a sufficient Discharge for the
several and respective Duties by this Act payable for the said Velum Parchment or Paper which shall be so stamped
or marked. And if any Person or Persons shall ingrosse or write or cause to be ingrossed or written upon any
Velum Parchment or Paper any of the Matters or Things for which the said Velum Parchment or Paper ought to
have a double or single Stamp or Mark as aforesaid before such Time as the said Velum Parchment or Paper shall
be marked or stamped with such double or single Mark or Stamp (as the Case requires) or upon which there shall
not be some double or single Marks or Stamps (as the Case shall require) resembling the same or shall ingross or
write or cause to be ingrossed or written any Matter or Thing upon any Velum Parchment or Paper that shall be
marked or stamped for any lower Duty or Duties than the Duty or Duties by this and the said former Acts or
either of them payable for what shall be so ingrossed or written such Person so offending shall for every such
Offence forfeit the Sum of Ten Pounds (besides Costs of Suit) One Moiety of which Penalty of Ten Pounds shall be
to the King and the other Moiety thereof to him or them that will inform or sue for the same in any Court of
Record by Action of Debt or of the Case Bill Plaint or Information wherein no Essoign Protection Wager of Law or
more than One Imparlance shall be allowed And in case any Clerk Officer or Person who in respect of any publick
Office or Imployment is or shall be intituled or intrusted to make ingross or write any Records Deeds Instruments
or Writeings charged to pay a Duty or Duties as aforesaid shall be guilty of any Fraud or Practice to deceive His
Majesty His Heires or Successors of any Duty by this or any of the said former Acts payable by makeing ingrossing
or writeing any such Record Deed Instrument or Writeing or causeing the same to be made ingrossed or written upon
Velum Parchment or Paper not marked or stamped according to this Act or upon which there shall not be some
Stamp or Stamps resembling the same or upon Velum Parchment or Paper marked or stamped with any Mark or
Stamp which he shall know to be counterfeited or by ingrossing or writeing any such Deed Instrument or other
Writeing upon Velum Parchment or Paper that shall be marked or stamped for a lower Duty as aforesaid that then
every such Clerk Officer or Person so guilty of any such Fraud or Practice and being thereof lawfully convicted shall
(over and above the Penalty aforesaid) forfeit his Office Place or Imployment respectively and be disabled to hold or
injoy the same for the future and if any Attorney belonging to any Court whatsoever shall be guilty [of any such
<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]
Fraud or Practice as aforesaid and be convicted thereof he shall be disabled for the future to practice as an Attorney
And if any Deed Instrument or Writing whatsoever by this Act intended to be stamped as aforesaid shall contrary
to the true Intent and Meaning thereof be written or ingrossed by any Person or Persons whatsoever not being a
known Clerk or Officer who in respect of any publick Office or Imployment is or shall be intituled to the makeing
writeing or ingrossing the same) upon Velum Parchment or Paper not marked or stamped or not doubly stamped (as
the Case may require) according to this Act or upon Velum Parchment or Paper marked or stamped for a lower
Duty as aforesaid that then and in every such Case there shall be due answered &amp; paid to His Majesty His Heires
or Successors (over and above the Duty aforesaid) for every such Deed Instrument or Writing the Sum of Ten
Pounds and that no such Record Deed Instrument or Writing shall be pleaded or given in Evidence in any Court
or admitted in any Court to be good useful or available in Law or Equity until aswell the said Duty as the said
Sum of Ten Pounds shall be first paid to the Use of His Majesty His Heires or Successors and a Receipt produced
for the same under the Hand or Hands of some of the Officers which shall be appointed to receive the Duties
above mentioned and until the Velum Parchment or Paper on which such Deed Instrument or Writing shall be
written or made shall be marked or stamped with a lawfull Mark or Stamp or with double Marks or Stamps
according to this Act and the proper Officer and Officers are hereby injoyned and required upon Payment or Tender
of the said Duty and the Sum of Ten Pounds unto him or them to give a Receipt for the same and to mark or
stamp or double mark or stamp the said Velum Parchment or Paper with the Mark or Stamp that shall be proper
for such Deed Instrument or Writing respectively And if any Person or Persons whatsoever shall at any Time or
Times hereafter counterfeit or forge any Stamp or Mark to resemble any Stamp or Mark which shall be provided
made or used in pursuance of this Act or shall counterfeit or resemble the Impression of the same upon any Velum
Parchment or Paper thereby to defraud His Majesty His Heires or Successors of any the said Duties upon Velum
[Parchment<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] or Paper or shall utter vend or sell any Velum Parchment or Paper with such counterfeit Mark or
Marks thereupon knowing such Mark or Marks to be counterfeit then every such Person so offending being thereof
convicted in due Form of Law shall be adjudged a Felon and shall suffer Death as in Cases of Felony without the
Benefit of Clergy.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Commissioners may appoint a fit Person to attend in any Court or Office to take Notice of the Stamps, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p113">
				<emph type="i">Judges to make Orders, &amp;c. herein; Commissioners and Officers to take the following Oath</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p114">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Commissioners for the said Dutys on Velum
Parchment and Paper from time to time shall and may appoint a fit Person to attend in any Court or Office to
take Notice of the Velum Parchment or Paper upon which any the Matters or Things aforesaid shall be ingrossed
written or put and of the Marks or Stamps thereupon and of all other Matters and Things tending to secure the
said Duties and that the Judges in the several Courts and such others to whom it may appertain at the Request or
Requests of such Commissioners or of any Two or more of them shall make such Orders in the respective Courts
and do such other Matters and Things for the better secureing of the said Duties under their Charge as shall be
lawfully and reasonably desired in that Behalf and that every Person who shall be commissionated as aforesaid and
every Person to be imployed by or under them for the marking or stamping of Velum Parchment or Paper as
aforesaid before his acting in the marking or stamping of the said Velum Parchment or Paper shall take the Oath
following (that is to say).</para>
			<para id="p115">I A. B. do swear That I will faithfully execute the Trust reposed [in<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] me pursuant to the Act of Parliament for
the further or additional Duties upon [stampt<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Velum Parchment and Paper without Fraud or Concealment and shall
from Time to Time true Account make of my Doings and deliver the same to such Person or Persons as His Majesty
His Heires or Successors shall appoint to receive such Account and shall take no Fee Reward or Profit for the
Execution or Performance of the said Trust or the Business relateing thereunto from any (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) other than such as shall
be paid or allowed by His Majesty His Heirs or Successors or by the Commissioners of His Majestys Treasury or any
Three or more of them now being or by the Treasurer of the Exchequer or Three or more of the Commissioners
of the Treasury for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p116">
				<emph type="i">Oath, how to be administered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p117">Which Oath shall and may be administred to such Commissioner or Commissioners [by any Three or more of the
same Commissioners<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] which shall be appointed as aforesaid. And any of the said Commissioners shall and may
administer the like Oath (mutatis mutandis) to such Sub-Commissioners or other Persons which shall be imployed
under them in the said Business of marking or stamping.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Commissioners, &amp;c. to observe the Directions of the Treasury; and furnish the several Parts of the Kingdom with stamped Vellum, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p118">And be it enacted That the Chief Commissioners or Officers [so<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] to be appointed and all Sub-Commissioners
and Officers to be imployed [or intrusted<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] by or under them as aforesaid in relation to the said Duties on
Parchment Velum and Paper shall from time to time in and for the better Execution of their several Places and
Trusts observe and performe such Rules Methods and Orders as they respectively shall from time to time receive
from the said Commissioners of the Treasury now being or from the Treasurer of the Exchequer or the Commissioners
of the Treasury for the time being or any Three or more of them and that the Chief Commissioners so to be
appointed shall take especial Care that the several Parts of this Kingdom and the Dominion of Wales and the
Town of Berwick upon Tweed shall from time to time be sufficiently furnished with Velum Parchment and Paper
stamped and marked as aforesaid so as the Subjects of His Majesty His Heirs and Successors may have it in their
Election to buy the same of the Officers or Persons to be imployed by the said Commissioners at the usual or
most common Rates above the said Duty or to bring their own Velum Parchment or Paper to be stamped as
aforesaid or to furnish themselves or others that shall have done the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Persons suing in forma pauperis, not to pay Duty.</head>
			<para id="p119">Provided always and it is hereby further enacted That none of the Rates Impositions or Sums of Money upon
Velum Parchment or Paper before in this Act expressed shall be raised levyed collected or paid or payable to
His Majesty His Heirs or Successors by vertue of this Act by any Person or Persons that shall be admitted to sue
or defend in forma pauperis.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. All Records, Writs, &amp;c. to be ingrossed as usual.</head>
			<para id="p120">And to the end His Majesty His Heirs or Successors may not be defrauded of any of the said Duties upon
Velum Parchment and Paper be it enacted That all Records Writts Pleadings or other Proceedings in Courts of
Law and Equity and all Deeds Instruments and Writings whatsoever hereby charged shall be ingrossed and written
in such Manner as they have been usually accustomed to be written and are now written.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. In case Stamps altered, Persons having stamped Vellum, &amp;c. by them not ingrossed, in 60 Days after Proclamation, may bring the same to the Head Office in London, and Commissioners to deliver them the like Quantity new stamped, &amp;c. without Fee.</head>
			<para id="p121">
				<emph type="i">Penalty; Stamped Vellum, &amp;c. not brought within the Time, declared useless. Matters ingrossed thereon to be of no Effect, and to incur Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p122">Provided always and be it further enacted That as often as His Majesty His Heirs or Successors shall think
fit to alter [or renew<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] the said Marks or Stamps or any of them it shall be lawful for all Persons who shall at
that Time have in their Custody or Possession any Velum Parchment or Paper marked with the Stamp or Stamps
which shall be so altered or renewed and upon which none of the Matters or Things hereby charged shall be
ingrossed or written at any Time within the Space of Sixty Days after such Intention of renewing or altering
shall be published by Proclamation to bring or send such Velum Parchment or Paper unto the said Commissioners
to the Head Office in London or Westminster or to such other Officers as shall be appointed in that Behalf and
the said Commissioners and Officers respectively are hereby required to deliver or cause to be delivered unto the
several Persons who shall so bring and deliver any Quantity of Velum Parchment or Paper the like Quantity of
Velum Parchment or Paper and as good in Quality stamped with such new Stamp or Stamps without demanding
or taking directly or indirectly for the same any Sum of Money or other Consideration whatsoever under the
Penalty or Forfeiture for every Offence One hundred Pounds to be sued for recovered and divided in such
Manner as the other Penalties in this Act relating to the Duties of Velum Parchment and Paper are directed to
be sued for recovered and divided and in case any Person shall neglect or refuse within the Time aforesaid to
bring or cause to be brought unto the said Commissioners or Officers as aforesaid any such Velum Parchment or
Paper the same is hereby declared to be of noe other Effect or Use than if it had never been stamped and that all
Matters or Things [which<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] shall after, that Time be ingrossed or written thereon shall be of noe other Effect
than if they had been ingrossed or written on Velum Parchment or Paper not marked or stamped at all and all
Persons who ingross or write any the Matters or Things hereby charged on such Vellum Parchment or Paper
after the said Time shall forfit and suffer as herein before is enacted for Persons writing or ingrossing on Velum
Parchment or Paper not marked or stamped.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Commissioners Salaries, &amp;c. and incident Charges, to be paid out of the Duties.</head>
			<para id="p123">Provided always and be it enacted That it shall and may be lawful to and for His Majesty His Heires and
Successors or to or for the Commissioners of the Treasury or any Three or more of them or the Treasurer of
the Exchequer for the time being out of the Duties ariseing by this Act for or upon stamped Velum Parchment
or Paper to cause such Sum &amp; Sums of Money to be expended and paid from time to time for Salaries and other
incident Charges as shall be necessary in and [for<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] the receiving collecting levying or managing the same Duties
by this Act granted Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Proclamation for altering the Stamps to be sent to the Mayor, &amp;c. of every Corporation, &amp;c; who shall cause the same to be published, &amp;c. Penalty &pound;200.</head>
			<para id="p124">Provided always and be it further enacted That as often as His Majesty His Heires or Successors shall think
fit to alter the said Stamps or any of them that the Proclamation which is hereby intended to be made for giving
[to<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] all Persons due Notice thereof shall within Twenty Days after the Date thereof be sent to the Mayor
Chief Magistrate or other Head Officer of every City Corporation Burough and Market Town throughout the
Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales and Town of Berwick upon Tweed which Officers respectively shall
cause the same to be be published to the Inhabitants of such City Corporation or Town either on the next
Market Day or next Sunday in the Church immediately after the [Time
<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] of Divine Service upon pain of
forfeiting the Sum of Two hundred Pounds to be sued for by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any
Court of Record at Westminster wherein no Essoign Protection Wager of Law Priviledg nor more than One
Imparlance shall be granted or allowed the One Moiety of which Forfeiture to be to His Majesty the other
Moiety to such Person who shall sue for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Treasury once a Year to set the Prices on stamped Vellum, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p125">
				<emph type="i">The Price to be stamped thereon; Allowance on prompt Payment, where Stamps amount to &pound;10 and upwards.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p126">And for the better Distribution of the said Velum Parchment and Paper and that the Subjects may have the
same with more Conveniency and [att<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] an easie Rate Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Lord
High Treasurer of England or Commissioners of His Majestys for the time being shall once in every
Year at least set the Prices of all Sorts of stamped Velum Parchment and Paper that it shall be sold at and that
the said Commissioners for the said Duties upon Velum Parchment and Paper shall stamp the said Price soe set
upon every Skin or Piece of Velum or Parchment or Sheet or Piece of Paper so by them to be sold and that
the said Commissioners shall likewise allow and pay to every Person that shall bring Velum Parchment or Paper
to be stamped (the Duty whereof shall amount to the Sum of Ten Pounds or upwards) after the Rate of Six
Pounds in the Hundred [Pounds<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] per Annum for Three Months upon present Payment of the said Duty upon
the said Velum Parchment and Paper so by them bought over and above the like Allowance upon the same
Quantitie by the said former Acts and that any Persons that shall by of the said Commissioners or their Agents 
Velum Parchment or Paper the Duty whereof amounts to the like Su[m]me of Ten Pounds or upwards shall have the
same Allowance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Briefs not charged.</head>
			<para id="p127">Provided always That nothing in this Act contained shall extend to charge any Letters Patents for collecting
charitable Benevolence commonly called Briefs with the Dutie therein mentioned or to make it necessary that such
Briefs should be doubly stamped Any thing [herein<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">or Privy Seale <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Courts <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">stamp <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">Persons <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n16" number="16">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n17" number="17">therein; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


