<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46915" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIX. An Act to repeal the Act made the last Session of Parliament intituled An Act for Relief of Creditors by making Composition with their Debtors in case Two thirds in Number and Value do agree. [Rot.Parl. 9 Gul.III.p.5.n.5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that 8 &amp; 9 W. III. c.18. hath not answered the End for which it was intended.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Repealed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an Act [made<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] in the Second Session of this present Parliament held in the Eighth and Ninth
Years of His Majesties Reign intituled An Act for Relief of Creditors by making Compositions with their
Debtors in case Two thirds in Number and Value do agree. hath not answered the end for which the same was
intended in regard that notwithstanding the Provisions in the said Act for preventing Frauds in the making such
Compositions many fraudulent Practices have been committed by making pretended Agreements with Persons who
were not real Creditors and for greater Advantages than what were expressed in such Compositions which Practices
have (as there is just Cause to fear) occasioned much Perjury For Remedy whereof be it enacted by the Kings most
Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Commons in this
present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the Four and twentieth Day of
June in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and eight the said Act and every Clause Matter
&amp; Thing therein contained shal be repealed determined and of no Force.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Agreements and Compositions bona fide entered into before 24th June 1698; and for Orders for discharge of Debtors, made in pursuance thereof; and also in respects of Pardons of Penalties and Forfeitures against 8 &amp; 9 W. III.c.18.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided nevertheless and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That this Act shal not extend or be construed
to extend in any wise to prejudice make void or impeach any Agreement or Composition made or which before
the [said<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Twenty fourth Day of June shal be made bona fide and without Fraud and which shal be performed
from time to time according to the true Intent and Meaning thereof nor any Order for the Discharge of any Debtor
out of Custody made or which shal be made in pursuance of such Agreement and Composition and by virtue of
the abovesaid Act or which [is<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] or shal be within the Saving or Benefit thereof before the said Twenty fourth
Day of June but that every such Agreement or Composition whereupon any such Order of Discharge is or shal be
made as aforesaid shal be good and effectual to all Intents and Purposes and every such Order and Discharge is
hereby ratifyed and confirmed And every such Agreement and Composition whereupon no such Order of Discharge
is or shal be made as aforesaid shal be and remain of the same Force and Effect (and no other) as if this present
Act had not been made nor to pardon indempnifie or discharge any Person who hath incurred or before the said
Twenty fourth Day of June shal incurr any Penalty or Forfeiture by committing any Offence against the said Act but
that every such Offender shal be liable to the same Forfeitures and Penalties as if the said Act had continued in full
Force.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Agreements, Releases, and Discharges made; or procured upon false Oath, &amp;c. void</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no Person or Persons [that<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] heretofore have
been or shal before the said Twenty fourth Day of June be discharged by vertue of this Act shal be deemed or
adjudged to be discharged thereby who to procure any Agreement Compositions Releases or Discharges whatsoever
from any of [his<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] or their Creditor or Creditors have before any one of the Judges of either Bench Barons of the
Exchequer or Master in Chancery Ordinary or Extraordinary willingly and corruptly made or before the said Twenty
fourth Day of June shal make any false Oath to the defrauding of his or their Creditor or Creditors but that all
and every such Agreement Releases and Discharges upon any false Oath obtained and being thereof convicted upon
any Indictment or Information shal be void and of none Effect Any Thing in this or the said former Act contained
to the contrary hereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">who <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlines of the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


