<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46914" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXVIII. An Act for the exporting Watches Sword-hilts and other Manufactures of Silver. [Rot. Parl. 9 Gul.III.p.5.n.4]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>7 &amp; 8 W. III.c.19. &sect; 6.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">8 &amp; 9 W.III. c. 8. &sect; 8; Watches, Swordhilts, wrought Plate, &amp;c. may be; exported, as shall be yearly allowed by the Commissioners of the Customs</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act of Parliament made in the Seventh and Eighth Years of His present Majesty [King<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
William the Third intituled An Act to incourage the bringing Plate into the Mint to be coined and for
the further remedying the ill State of the Coine of this Kingdom it is amongst other things so enacted That after
the last. Day of March then next ensuing no wrought Plate of this Kingdom can be shipped off under the great
Penalties in the said Act contained whereby no Home wrought manufactured Plate though never so beneficial to
the Artificers and Trade of this Kingdom is permitted to be exported which was at that time a good and wholesom
Law and tended to the Benefit of the Kingdom by keeping Bullion at home to be coined Now forasmuch as by a
subsequent Act made in the Eighth and Ninth Year of the Reign of his said Majesty intituled An Act for the
encouraging the bringing in of wrought Plate to be coined it is therein enacted That from and after the Five and
twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety seven no Goldsmith Silversmith or other Person whatsoever
shal work make or cause to be wrought or made any Silver Vessell Plate or Manufacture of Silver less in Fineness
than that of Eleven Ounces and Ten Peny Weight of fine Silver in every pound Troy nor putt to sale the same
until it be marked as in the said Act is directed whereby no Profit can arise to any Person who shal export
such Plate as hath been or shal be made pursuant to that Act by loseing the Charge of the Fashion in melting
down the same and selling the Silver abroard the principal Thing aimed at to be prevented by the first recited
Act But on the contrary a great Benefit may accrew to many Artificers and to the Kingdom in general by giving
liberty to export Watches Sword-hilts wrought Plate and several other Silver Manufactures made within this Kingdom
being of the Fineness prescribed in the said last recited Act Be it therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent
Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Commons in this
present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the Four and twentieth Day
of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight it shal and may be lawful to export such Watches Sword-hilts 
wrought Plate and other Silver Manufactures made within this Kingdom being of the Finess : of Eleven Ounces
and Ten Peny Weight to every Pound Troy and so proportionable for a greater or lesser Weight according to
the Rules prescribed in the last recited Act as shal be yearly allowed by the Commissioners of his Majesties Customs
for the time being or any Three of them Any Law or Statute to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">No Case or Dial Plate, &amp;c. for Clock or Watch to be exported without the Movement, &amp;c. nor made up without engraving Maker's Name.; Penalty &pound;20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And whereas great Quantities of empty Boxes Cases and Dyal Plates for Clocks and Watches have been exported
without their Mov[e<emph type="p">1</emph>]ments and in Foreign Parts made upp with badd Movements and thereon some London Watchmakers
Names engraven and so are sold abroad for English Work and alsoe there hath been the like ill Practices in
England by divers Persons as well by some professing the Art of Clock and Watch making as others ignorant
therein in putting counterfeit Names as alsoe the Names of the most known London Watch-makers on their bad
Clocks and Watches to the great prejudice of the Buyers and the Disreputation of the said Art at home and abroad
For the preventing therefore of all such ill Practices for the future be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That
no Person or Persons whatsoever shal after the said Four and twentieth Day of June export or send or endeavor
to export or send out of this Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or Town of Berwick upon Tweed any
outward or inward Box Case or Dyal plate of Gold Silver Brass or other Metal for Clock or Watch without the
Movement in or with every such Box Case or Dyal plate made upp fit for Use with the Clock or Watch-Makers
Name ingraven thereon nor any Person whatsoever after the said Four and twentieth Day of June shal make up
or cause to be made up any Clock or Watch without ingraving or putting or causing to be ingraven or put his
or her own Name and Place of Aboad or Freedom and no other Name or Place on every Clock or Watch he
or she shal so make up or cause to be made up under the Penalty of forfeiting every such empty Box Case and
Dyal plate Clock and Watch not made up and ingraven as aforesaid and also for each and every of such Offence
the Sum of Twenty pounds one Moiety whereof to be to his Majesty his Heirs and Successors and the other
Moiety shal be to him her or them that shal sue for the same in any of his Majesties Courts of Record by Action
of Debt Bill Plaint or Information wherein no Essoign Protection or Wager of Law shal be allowed or more than
than one Imparlance Any thing herein contained or any Law or Statute to the contrary thereof in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


