<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46923" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXVII. An Act for the better and more orderly Payment of the Lottery Tickets now payable out of certain additional Duties of Excise and of other Annuities lately payable out of Tunnage Duties. [Rot. Parl. 9 Gul. III.p.6.n.6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head><ref idref="n1">1</ref> <ref idref="n2">2</ref>5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c.7. &sect; 34.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 14. &sect; 35; From the 15th May 1698, the Duties of Excise of 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M.c.7. applied as herein mentioned; How the subsequent or growing Produce of the said Duties to be applied; Course of Payment of the said Annuities; Officer making Payment contrary to the Tenor hereof: Penalty &pound;100, and Loss of Office</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in and by one Act made in the Parliament holden at Westminster in the Fifth and Sixth Years
of the Reign of His Majestie and the late Queen Mary of blessed Memory intituled An Act for granting
to Their Majesties certain Rates and Duties upon Salt and upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for securing certain
Recompences and Advantages in the said Act mentioned to such Persons as shal voluntarily advance the Sum of
Ten hundred thousand Pounds towards carrying on the War against France it was amongst other things enacted
That yearly and every Year reckoning the First Year to begin from the Five and twentieth day of March One
thousand six hundred ninety four the full Sum of One hundred and forty thousand Pounds by or out of the
Moneys to arise or to be made good as in that Act is mentioned should be a yearly Fond for answering or paying
the Annuities therein mentioned and other the Purposes in that Act expressed and that the Persons who should be
intituled to extraordinary Benefits as in the said Act is mentioned their Executors Administrators or Assigns should
have and enjoy during the Term of Sixteen Years such Annuities as are therein mentioned out of the said yearly
Fond by equal half yearly Payments at the Feasts of the Annunciation of the blessed Virgin Mary and S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Michael
the Arch Angel or within Twenty Days after every or any such Feast Day the First Payment whereof was to be
made at the Feast of the Annunciation of the blessed Virgin Mary One thousand six hundred ninety five or within
Twenty Days then next ensuing and such Contributors or Adventurers as are mentioned in the said Act and in
another Act of the said Parliament holden in the Fifth and Sixth Years of Their Majesties Reigns intituled An
Act for raising Money by a Poll payable Quarterly for One Yeare for carrying on the War against France wherein
there was an Explanation of the said former Act were to have and receive during the said Term for every Ten
Pounds contributed or adventured One Pound by the Year out of the said Fond to be paid at the Feast of
S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Michael the Arch-Angel in every Year or within Twenty Days after and the First Payment thereof was to be
made at the Feast of S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Michael the Arch-Angel One thousand six hundred ninety five or within Twenty Days
then next ensuing as by the said Act relation being thereunto had doth more fully appear Now to the intent that
the Proprietors of the Annuities or other Benefits or Advantages granted or appointed by the said Acts or either
of them and their Assigns may with better Order and more certainty receive the Money due to or to grow due
upon their Tickets for the same Be it hereby declared and enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and
with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the Fifteenth Day of May One thousand six
hundred ninety eight the Money arising and coming into the Exchequer of or for the Duties of Excise granted by
the said first mentioned Act shal in the first Place be applicable and is hereby directed to be applied to pay and
satisfy such of the said Annuities and the Tickets for the same which became due or payable at the Feast of the
Annunciation of the blessed Virgin Mary One thousand six hundred ninety six or within Twenty Days after the
same and are yet remaining unsatisfyed And in the Second Place the Produce of the said Duties shal be applicable
and is hereby directed to be applied to pay and satisfie such of the said Annuities as became due or payable at
the Feast of S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Michael the Arch-angel One thousand six hundred ninety seven or within Twenty Days after
the same and are yet remaining unsatisfied And in the Third Place the Produce of the said Duties shal be applicable
and is hereby directed to be applied for the paying and satisfying such of the said Annuities as became due and payable
on the Five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety eight or within Twenty days after the
same and not otherwise Any thing in the said Act or any other Act or Acts contained to the contrary notwithstanding
And that in respect to the subsequent or growing Produce of the said Duties of Excise the foregoing Arreares
being first fully satisfyed and discharged or Money sufficient being reserved for the Payment thereof the said growing
Produce shal be applicable and is hereby directed to be applied to satisfy and pay the said Half-yearly and yearly
Annuities in course that is to say no Officer or Officers appointed to pay the said Annuities shall pay any
Half-yearly or yearly Payment of the said Annuities until al and every Person and Persons intituled to such Annuities
and Payments shal or may have had and received his her or their Annuities and Payments for the preceding
Half year or Year for which publick Notice shal be given by hanging the same up in the most convenient publick
Place in the said Office that the last preceding Half Year or Year is either fully paid or that the Money is ready
in the Office for the Payment of such as have not timely brought in their respective Tickets or have not thought
fit to call for their Money and in case any Officer shal offend herein by making any Payment contrary to the
Tenour hereof or in any other manner than as aforesaid every such Officer shal forfeit his Office and shal for
every such Offence forfeit the Sum of One hundred Pounds to such Person or Persons who shal sue for the same
to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties Courts of Record at
Westminster wherein no Essoign Protection Priviledge Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint or more
than one Imparlance shall be granted or allowed And in the said Action the Plaintiff upon Recovery shall have
Treble Costs.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. How Benefit Tickets to be paid.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That for the more orderly Payment of the Lottery
Tickets for the said Annuities the Tickets commonly called Benefit Tickets which became due at Lady Day One
thousand six hundred ninety eight or within Twenty Days after the same shal be paid in Arithmetical Progression
as they are numbred beginning at Number One and ending with the Number Two thousand five hundred and
the Tickets for Twenty Shillings apiece commonly called Blank Tickets being due at Michaelmas One thousand
six hundred ninety eight or within Twenty Days after the same shal also be paid in Arithmetical Progression as
they are numbred beginning with Number One and so proceeding to and ending with the Number Ninety seven
thousand five hundred and in the Year next following the Benefit Ticket shal be paid in an Arithmetical
Progression descending (to wit) beginning with Number Two thousand five hundred and ending with the Number
One and the said Tickets called Blank Tickets from [the<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Number Ninety seven thousand five hundred inclusive to
Number One Inclusive and so onwards in every subsequent Year during the said Term the said Tickets shal be
paid in such alternate Course as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Not undue Preference if Officer pay subsequent Tickets first brought if Money reserved for preceding Ticket.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided That it shal not be interpreted any undue Preference to incur any Penalty in point of Payment if
such Officer or Officers as are or shal be appointed to pay such Tickets as aforesaid to pay subsequent Tickets
of Persons that come and demand their Moneys and bring their Tickets before other Persons that did not come
and take their Moneys and bring their Tickets-in course so as there be so much Money reserved as will satisfy
such preceding Ticket which Money shal not be otherwise disposed of but kept for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. How additional Excise Duties of 5 &amp; 6 W.&amp; M.c.7. appropriated.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the additional Duties of Excise granted by the said
recited Act and which do or ought to come from time to time Weekly into the Exchequer as is thereby directed
(the Salaries of the Officers and other incident Charges not exceeding Two thousand five hundred Pounds per
Annum allowable by the said former Act only excepted) shal be and are hereby appropriated during the whole
Term of Sixteen Years therein granted to the Payment of the said Annuities and the Tickets for the same until
they be fully satisfyed Any thing in this or any other Act of Parliament contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 20. &sect;53.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Officers not to pay Annuities when preceding quarterly Payments unpaid; Notice fixed up in the Office; Officer offending; Loss of Office and Penalty &pound;100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And whereas [by<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] one Act made and passed in the Parliament holden the Fifth and Sixth Years of the Reign
of His Majesty and the late Queen (of blessed Memory) intituled An Act for granting to Their Majesties several
Rates and Duties upon Tunnage of Ships and Vessels and upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for securing certain
Recompences and- Advantages in the said Act mentioned to such Persons as shal voluntarily advance the Sum of
Fifteen hundred thousand Pounds towards carrying on the War against France certain Annuities for One Two
or Three Lives have been purchased or obtained for the respective Considerations therein mentioned and are
payable Quarterly out of Two Seventh Parts of the several Duties thereby granted and the Reversions of the
said Annuities or some of them or further Interests therein have been or may be purchased by several subsequent
Acts of Parliament in that behalf Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the
Fifteenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety eight no Officer or Officers appointed to pay the said
Annuities shal pay off any Quarterly Payment of the said Annuities upon any Order or Orders whatsoever until
all and every Person and Persons intituled to the said Annuities and Payments shal or may have had and received
his her or their Annuities and Payments for the precedent Quarter or Quarters and that Publick Notice shall be
given from time to time by fixing openly a Paper in the Office for Payment of the said Annuities when the last
precedent Quarter is fully paid (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) or the Money is ready in the Office for Payment of such as have not timely
brought their respective Orders to be directed or have not thought fit to call for their Money and in case any
Officer shal offend herein by making any Payment contrary to the Tenor hereof or in any other manner than as
aforesaid every such Officer shal forfeit his Place and shal for every such Offence forfeit the Sum of One
hundred Pounds to such Person or Persons who shal sue for the same to be recovered (besides Costs of Suit) in
such manner as aforesaid.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This is Chapter XXXIV. in the Common printed Editions.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">upon <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">that <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


