<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46924" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXVIII. An Act for granting to His Majesty an Aid by a Quarterly Poll for One Year. [Rot. Parl. 9 Gul.III.p.6.n.7].</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for granting the Subsidy by this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">We Your Majesties most dutiful and loyal Subjects the Commons in Parliament assembled having seriously
considered Your Majesties extraordinary Occations Do towards supplying thereof most humbly present to
Your Majesty a free Gift of the several Sums of Money herein after specified beseeching Your Majesty that it may
be enacted And be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the
Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by Authority of the same
That all and every Person and Persons of what Age Sex or Condition soever within this Kingdom of England
Dominion of Wales and Town of Berwick upon Tweed shal and do pay unto His Majesty the Sums hereafter
mentioned (that is to say) The Sum of One Shilling on the Four and twentieth Day of August One thousand six
hundred ninety eight The Sum of One Shilling on the Four and twentieth Day of November One thousand six
hundred ninety eight The Sum of One Shilling on the Four and twentieth Day of February One thousand six
hundred ninety eight The Sum of One Shilling on the Four and twentieth Day of May One thousand six
hundred ninety nine except such Persons as shal receive Alms of the Parish where the dwel and their Children
being under the Age of Sixteen Years at the Time of the Execution of this Act And except all poor House-keepers
or Housholders who by Reason of the Poverty only are exempted from contributing to the Church or Poor and
their Children being under the Age of Sixteen Years And also except all Children being under the Age of Sixteen
of all Day Lalourers and of all Servants in Husbandry And also except all Children under the Age of Sixteen
Year Years of such have Four or more Children and and not worth in Lands Goods and Chattels or any of them
the Sum of Fifty Pounds.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Gentlemen having an Estate of &pound;300 or more.</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">Widows having Dower or Jointure of &pound; 100, &amp;c; Unmarried Women having an Estate of &pound;1,000</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">And be it further enacted That over and above the Sums aforesaid every Gentleman or Person so reputed or
owning or writing himself such having an Estate in the whole either Real or Personal or in both of the clear
[Yearly<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Value of Three hundred Pounds or more And every Person above that Quality (and not a Peer of this
Realm) and Widows having a Dower or Joynture of the clear Yearly Value of One hundred Pounds or more or
being worth in the whole the clear Sum of One thousand Pounds And all unmarryed Women being worth in
the whole in any Estate Real or Personal the clear Sum of One thousand Pounds shal severally pay unto His
Majesty the Sum of Twenty Shillings Quarterly at the several Days before mentioned during One Year as aforesaid
And no Gentleman Widow or unmarryed Woman not having such Estates respectively and thereof making Oath
before Two or more of the respective Commissioners hereafter appointed shal be charged with the said Quarterly
Su[m]m of Twenty Shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Cursitors, Philizers, Attornies, Proctors, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Certain Preachers not of the Church of England to pay Double; Also certain Clergymen of the Church of England</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And be it further enacted That every Cursitor Philizer Attorney Sollicitor Clerk in Chancery or Exchequer or
other Courts of Law or Equity or Scrivener or practising as such and every Chancellor Commissary Official and
Register and every Advocate Proctor Apparitor and Public Notary or practising as such and all other Officers in any
Court and all Merchant Brokers to Merchants and Pawn-Brokers shal be charged and pay Twenty Shillings Quarterly
at the several Days before mentioned and none of the said Persons so charged to be further liable or to be charged
or pay as a Gentleman or reputed Gentleman And alsoe that every Clergyman not being a Lord Spiritual having
or receiving in or by any Benefice Benefices Contribution or otherwise to the Value of Sixty Pounds by the Year
or upwards and every Preacher or Teacher in any Congregation whatsoever not having taken Orders according to
the Discipline of the Church of England having or receiving in Gratuities Contributions Rewards and Bounties or any
of them to the Value of Sixty Pounds a Year or upwards shal be charged and pay Twenty Shillings Quarterly at
the several Days before mentioned and none of the last mentioned Persons so charged to be further charged or pay as a
Gentleman or reputed Gentleman And also that every Preacher or Teacher in any Congregation whatsoever not
having taken Orders according to the Discipline of the Church of England having and receiving by any Contribution
or otherwise to the Value of One hundred and fifty Pounds per Annum or upwards shal pay double the said Sum
of Twenty Shillings Quarterly at the several Days before mentioned And also every Clergyman having in several
Benefices or in several Ecclesiastical Promotions or in a Benefice &amp; Promotion or in several Benefices and Promotions
in the whole the Yearly Value of One hundred and fifty Pounds or upwards shal pay double the Sum charged
upon other Clergy-men And every Tradesman Shopkeeper and Vintner having an Estate in the whole of the
clear Value of Three (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Pounds and upwards shal over and above the aforesaid Quarterly Sums of One Shilling
pay unto His Majesty the Sum of Ten Shillings Quarterly on the several Days before mentioned during the said
Year.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Certain Persons charged in respect of their Horses.</head>
			<para id="p6">And be it further enacted That every Person who by reason of his or her Estate is charged (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) by any Law now
in being or to be made during this Session of Parliament is or shal be in any Manner chargable or by reason of
his Estate would be chargable if he was no Officer in the Militia to find a Horse and Horsman with Arms to serve
in the Militia of this Kingdom (over and above all other Sums wherewith he or she is chargable by this Act) shal
for each and every Horse he or she is so charged or chargable or if he was no Officer might be chargable with
pay the Sum of Twenty Shillings Quarterly on every of the Four several Quarter Days of Payment before mentioned
and so proportionably every Person contributing towards finding a Horse or Horses and Horsemen with Arms as
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. And also certain Persons in respect of their Carriages.</head>
			<para id="p7">And be it further enacted That every Person not finding or contributing to the finding of a Horse or Horseman
with Arms as a foresaid who does keep a Coach Chariot or Calash (over and above all other Sums with which he
or she is chargable by this Act) shal pay the Sum of Twenty Shillings Quarterly on every of the Four Quarterly
Days of Payment before mentioned except such Persons as keep Stage-Coaches or Hackney Coaches.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Lords Spiritual and Temporal charged.</head>
			<para id="p8">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Lord Spiritual or Temporal of this Realm
shal (over and above any Sum with which he is charable by this Act) pay to His Majesty the Sum hereafter
mentioned (that is to say) The Sum of Ten Pounds on the said Four and twentieth Day of August One thousand
six hundred ninety eight The Sum of Ten Pounds on the said Four and twentieth Day of November One thousand
six hundred ninety eight The Sum of Ten Pounds on the said Four and twentieth Day of February One thousand
six hundred ninety eight and the Sum of Ten Pounds on the said Four and twentieth Day of May One thousand
six hundred ninety nine.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Gentlemen who by 3 W.&amp; M. c.6. &sect;7. paid double, or have been returned into Exchequer for Non-payment, not
appearing before the Commissioners to take the Oaths, to pay double.</head>
			<para id="p9">And be it further enacted That every Gentleman or Person so reputed or owning or writing himself such or
being above that Quality and under the Degree of a Peer of this Realm and having an Estate of the Value of Three
hundred Pounds and being of the Age of Sixteen Years or upwards and within this Realm at the Time of the
Execution of this Act who have not already taken the Oaths to His Majesty hereafter mentioned and who shal not
voluntarily appear before the said Commissioners or Two or more of them within the Time lymitted by this Act
for hearing Appeals and take the Oaths mentioned and required to be taken by an Act made in the First Year of
the Reign of His Majesty and the late Queen of Blessed Memory intituled An Act for abrogating the Oaths of
Supremacy and Allegiance and appointing other Oaths (which Oaths the Commissioners or any Two or more of
them are hereby impowred and required to administer) and make an Entry or Memorandum thereof in some Book
to be kept for that Purpose shal be charged with and pay to His Majesty double the Sums which by force or virtue
of any Clause in this Act he should or ought to pay or be charged with to be levyed collected answered recovered
and paid in such Manner and by such Ways and Means as are in this Act expressed and appointed for and
concerning the Rates and Sums hereby intended to be doubled as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for Quakers to subscribe the Declaration of Fidelity, 1 W. &amp; M. c. 18. &sect; 10.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided nevertheless That whereas certain Persons Dissenters from the Church of England commonly called
Quakers and now known to be such do scruple the taking any Oath it shal be sufficient for every such Person
to make and subscribe the Declaration of Fidelity contained in an Act intituled An Act for exempting Their
Majesties Protestant Subjects dissenting from the Church of England from the Penalties of certain Laws which
Declaration any Two or more of the Commissioners appointed for the Execution of this Act are hereby impowred
and required to administer and every such Person so doing shal not be liable to or chargable with any the
double Rates aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Commissioners appointed by c. 10. ante, to be Commissioners under this Act.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">The said Commissioners to meet on the 20th July 1698 to put this Act in Execution; and divide themselves. Commissioners to order Constables, &amp;c. to attend, and then to read to them their Charge; and prefix other Days for bringing in Certificates of Names, &amp;c. of Persons residing within certain Limits, together with the Assessment; Penalty; Parish answerable for Payment by Collectors to Receiver General; Certificates, &amp;c. returned to Commissioners, 12th Aug. 1698; Commissioners to issue Warrants, &amp;c. for collecting; Collectors to demand Payment within Four Days after Receipt of Warrant: Times of Quarterly Payments by Collectors; Receivers to hasten Collectors; and if they make Default, Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That for the better assessing ordering and levying of the
several Sums of Money so as aforesaid limitted and appointed to be paid and for the more effectual putting of
this present Act in Execution all and every the Persons named and appointed to be Commissioners by an Act of
this present Session of Parliament intituled An Act for granting to His Majesty the Sum of One Million four
hundred eighty four thousand and fifteen Pounds one Shilling and Eleven Pence Three Farthings for disbanding
Forces paying Seamen and other Uses therein mentioned shal be Commissioners for putting in Execution this
present Act and the Powers therein contained within all and every the several and respective Counties Ridings
Cities Cinque-Ports Boroughs Towns and Places for which they are appointed Commissioners respectively by the
said Act and the said Commissioners in order to a speedy Execution of this Act shal and are hereby required in
their respective Counties Ridings Cities Boroughs Towns and Places to meet together at the most usual or
[accustomed <ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Place of Meeting within such of the said Counties Ridings Cities Boroughs Towns and Places
respectively on the Twentieth Day of July One thousand six hundred ninety eight and the said Commissioners
or so many of them as shal be present at the First General Meeting or the major part of them may by their
Consents and Agreements divide as well themselves as other the Commissioners not then present for the Execution
of this Act in Hundreds Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Wards Towns and other Places within their Limitts priviledged
or not priviledged in such Manner and Form as to them shal seem expedient and shal direct their several or
joynt Precept or Precepts to such Inhabitants High Constables Petty Constables Bayliffs and other such like Officers
and Ministers and such number of them as they in their discretions shal [seem<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] most convenient to be Presenters
and Assessors requiring them to appear before the said Commissioners at such Time and Place as they shal appoint
not exceeding Eight Days and at such their appearing the said Commissioners or so many of them as shal be
thereunto appointed shal openly read or cause to be read unto them the Rates in this Act mentioned and openly
declare the Effects of their Charge unto them and how and in what manner they ought and should make their
Certificates according to the Rates aforesaid and shal then and there prefix another Day to the said Persons to
appear before the said Commissioners and bring in their Certificates of the Names and Sirnames Qualities Degrees
Titles Estates Professions Imployments and Trades of all every the Persons dwelling or resideing within the
Limitts of those Places with which they shal be charged and of all other things in respect whereof any Person
is or may be chargable by this Act together with the Assessment of the respective Rates hereby imposed upon each
particular Person according to the Rules and Directions hereof without Concealment Love Favour Dread or Malice
upon [Pain of<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Forfeiture of any Sum not exceeding Ten Pounds to be levied as by Act is appointed and
shal then returne the Names of Two or more able and sufficient Persons within the Bounds and Limits of those
Parishes or Places where they shal be charged respectively as aforesaid to be Collectors of the Money due to His
Majesty by this Act for whose paying unto the Receivers General to be appointed by His Majestie their Deputy
or Deputies in manner following such Moneys as they shal be charged withal the Parish or Place by whom they
shal be imployed shal be answerable which Certificates and Assessments shal be ascertained and returned unto
the Commissioners at or before the Twelfth Day of August One thousand six hundred ninety eight and upon the
Delivery or Returning in of such Certificates or Assessments unto the said Commissioners they or any Two or
more of them shall forthwith issue out and deliver their Warrants of Estreats to such Collectors as aforesaid for
the speedy collecting and levying of the said Assessments and all Moneys and Rates due thereupon according to
the Intent and Directions of this Act of all which the said Collectors are hereby required to make Demand of
the Parties themselves or at the Places of their last abode within Four Days after the Receipt of such Warrants
or Estreats and to levy and pay in at such Place as the Commissioners shal appoint unto the respective Receiver
General his Deputy or Deputies the Sums payable for the First of the said Quarterly Payments on or before the
First Day of September One thousand six hundred ninety eight and the Sums payable for the Second of the said
[Quarters<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] on or before the First Day of December One thousand six hundred ninety eight and the Sums
payable for the Third of the said Quarterly Payments on or before the First Day of March One thousand six
hundred ninety eight and the Sums payable for the Fourth of the said Quarterly Payments on or before the First
Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety nine and the respective Receivers are hereby impowred and required
to call upon and hasten the Collectors to the said Payments and in Default thereof to levy by Warrant under the
Hands (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) and Seals of any Two or more of the Commissioners upon the respective Collectors by Distress such Sum
and Sums of Money as they have received and as ought by them to have been paid and are not paid by reason
of their Failure in doing their Duty respectively according to the Direction of this Act</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Commissioners to cause Duplicate of Sums assessed to be returned into Exchequer, under Hand and Seal, without naming the Persons assessed, before 10th Sept. 1698; others to Receiver General.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Time for the First Quarterly Payment; Second; Third; Fourth; Commissioners may examine Presenters, and if they have cause to suspect that any Person is not fully charged, they may summon such Persons; Persons neglecting, &amp;c. to appear; Penalty; Commissioners may examine, &amp;c; Allowance to Receiver General; Allowance to Collector</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And be it enacted That a [true<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Duplicate of the whole Sum charged within every Hundred Lathe Wapentake
Parish Ward or Place rated and assessed in pursuance of this Act without naming the Persons shall under the
Hands and Seals of Two or more of the Commissioners thereunto appointed be returned into His Majesties Exchequer
before the Tenth Day of September One thousand six hundred ninety eight (all Appeals being first determined)
and in like manner within Thirty Days after every other Quarterly Payment And that like Duplicates be also in
convenient time made out and delivered unto the Receivers General so [that<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] every of them may be duely charged
to answer their respective Collections and Receipts And that the said several Quarterly Sums to be paid into His
Majesties Exchequer at the several times following (that is to say) The First of the said Quarterly Payments on or
before the Twentieth Day of September One thousand six hundred ninety eight The Second of the said Quarterly
Payments on or before the Twentieth Day of December One thousand six hundred ninety eight The Third of the
said Quarterly Payments on or before the Twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety eight And
the Fourth and last of the said Quarterly Payments on or before the Twentieth Day of June One thousand six
hundred ninety nine And upon Returne of any such Certificate the said Commissioners or any Two or more of
them shal and may (if they see cause) examine the Presenters thereof And if the said Commissioners or any Two
or more of them within their several Limitts shall at the time of the Delivery of the said Certificates or within
Twelve Days after have Knowledge or reasonable Cause of Suspicion that any Person or Persons who ought to
be mentioned in the said Certificate is or are omitted or that any Person or Persons in the said Certificate mentioned
is not or are not fully and duly charged according to the true Intent of this Act the said Commissioners or
any Two or more of them shal have Power to warn such Person or Persons to appear before them at a Day and
Place prefixed to be examined touching the Premisses or any Matter which may any way concern the same And
if the Person or Persons warned to be examined shal neglect to appear not having a reasonable Excuse for
his Default every. Person so making Default shall pay unto His Majesty Double the Sum or Rate he should or
ought to have been set at And moreover the said Commissioners or Two or more of them shal have Power by
any lawful Ways and Means to examine and enquire into all Matters and Things for or by reason of which any
Persons are chargable by this Act and to set such Rate or Rates upon such Persons as shal be according to the
true intent and meaning of this Act And the said Receiver General shall have an Allowance of Two Pence in
the Pound for all Moneys which shal be by him paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer And every Collector
shal have Three Pence in the Pound for what Money he shal pay to the Receiver General his Deputy or Deputies.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Allowance to Clerks of Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Persons refusing to pay Rates upon Demand; Distress; And if Rate not paid within Four Days, Distress sold, &amp;c; Persons assessed not paying in 10 Days, and where no sufficient Distress, imprisoned in Common Gaol, without Bail; Complaint of Over Rate within Six Days after Demand to Commissioners; who may examine upon Oath, and may increase or abate Rate, and to issue Warrant accordingly</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And for the careful Writing and Transcribing the said Warrants Estreats and Duplicates in due time and for
making Certificates upon. Appeals or otherwise Be it further enacted That the Commissioners Clerks who shal
respectively perform the same shal by Warrant under Three or more of the Commissioners Hands have and receive
from the respective Receivers General their Deputy or Deputies Three Halfpence in the Pound of all such Moneys
as they shal have received by vertue of such Warrants and Estreats who are hereby appointed to pay the same
accordingly And if any Person or Persons shal refuse or neglect to pay the several Sum and Sums and Proportions
appointed by this Act for such Persons to pay upon Demand made by the Officer or Collector of the Place
according to the Precepts or Estreats to him delivered by the said Commissioners It shal and may be lawful to
and for such Officer and Collector (who is hereby thereunto authorized and required) for Non payment thereof
to distrain the Goods and Chattels of such Person or Persons and the Distress so taken to keep by the Space
of Four Days at the Costs and Charges of the Owners thereof And if the said Owners do not pay the Sum of
Money due by this Act within the said Four Days then the said Distress to be appraised by Two or more of the
Inhabitants where the said Distress is taken and there to be sold by the said Officer for Payment of the said
Money and the Overplus coming by the said Sale (if any be) over and above the Charges of taking and keeping
the said Distresse to be immediately restored to the Owners thereof And if any Person or Persons assessed by
this Act shal refuse or neglect to pay the Sum or Sums so assessed by the Space of Ten Days after demand as
aforesaid where no such sufficient Distress can or may be found whereby the same may be levied in every such
Case Three of the Commissioners by this Act appointed for any such City County or Place are hereby authorized
by Warrants under their Hands and Seals to commit such Person or Persons to the Common Goal there to be
kept without Bail or Mainprize until Payment shal be made And if any Person certified assessed or rated find
him or her self agrieved with such assessing or rateing and do within Six Days after Demand thereof made complain
to the said Commissioners (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) or any Three or more of them (whereof Two shal be of the Commissioners who
signed or allowed his or her Rate) shal and may within Eight Days next after such Complaints particularly examine
the Parties so complaining upon his or her Oath touching the same and upon due Examination or Knowledge
thereof abate defaulk increase or inlarge the said Assessment and the same so abated [defaulked<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] increased or enlarged
shal be estreated by them into the Exchequer in manner aforesaid And to that end the said Commissioners are
hereby required to meet together for the determining of such Complaints and Appeals accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Persons to be rated where resident at Execution of Act.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Persons not being Householders, Servants</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And be it further enacted [That every Person<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] to be rated by this Act shal be rated at such Places where
he or she and with his or her Family shal be resident at the time of the Execution of this Act And that every
Person not being a House-holder nor having a certain Place of Abode and all Servants shal be taxed at the Place
where they are resident at the time of the Execution of this Act the Tax upon such Servants to be paid by their
respective Master or Mistress and to be deducted out of their Wages which Deduction the said Master or Mistress
is hereby impowred to make.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. If Persons having several Mansion Houses be doubly charged, on Certificate of Commissioners to be granted without Fee, and on Oath before Justices of Peace.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Absentees rated at last Place of Abode; Persons escaping from Taxation charged at Double Value</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">Provided always That if any Person having several Mansion Houses or Places of Residence shal be doubly
charged by virtue of this Act that upon Certificate made by Two or more of the Commissioners for the County
City or Place (which Certificate the said Commissioners are hereby required to give without Delay Fee or Reward)
of his or their personal Residence under their Hands and Seals of the Sum or Sums there charged [up<ref idref="n13">13</ref>]on
him or them or in what Capacity or Respect he or they were so charged and upon Oath made of such Certificate
before any Justice of the Peace of the County or Place where such Certificate shal be made (which Oath the
said Justice of the Peace is hereby authorized to administer) then the Person or Persons so doubly charged shal
for so much as shal be certified be discharged in every other County City or Place And if any Person at the
time of the assessing shal be out of the Realm such Person shal be rated where such Person was last abiding
in the Realm And if any Person that ought be taxed by virtue of this Act by changing his Place of Residence
or by Fraud or Covin shal escape from the Taxation and not be taxed and the same be proved before the
Commissioners or Two of them or Two Justices of the Peace of the County where such Person dwelleth or resideth
at any time within Twelve Months next ensuing after such Taxation made every Person that shal so escape from
the said Taxation and Payment shal be charged upon Proof thereof at the Double Value of so much as he should
or ought to have been taxed by this Act the said Double Value upon Certificate thereof made into the Exchequer
by the Commissioners or Justices before whom such Proof shal be made to be levied of the Goods Chattels and
Tenements of such Person towards the Supply aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Commissioners may assess Commissioners;</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">and also Assessors.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p22">Provided always and be it further enacted That the Commissioners within any County or Place within their
respective Limits or the major Part of them shal tax and assesse every other Commissioner joyned with them And
the Commissioners within their Division shal assess every Assessor within their Division And as wel al Sums upon
every of the said Commissioners and Assessors as the Assessments made and presented by the Presenters as
aforesaid shal be written estreated levied and gathered as the same should and ought to have been if the said
Commissioners had not been named Commissioners.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Assessor, Collector, &amp;c. neglecting, &amp;c. to perform their Duty.</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may fine; Commissioners to require Accounts from Receivers General; and in case of Failure to levy; If Controversy concerning assessing Commissioners, Commissioners concerned to withdraw; Penalty; Questions concerning Rates determined by Commissioners; Receivers General, &amp;c. to give Acquittances gratis to Collectors; Collectors to deliver a Schedule to Receivers General of Defaulters; to be returned by him into Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And be it further enacted That if any Assessor Collector Receiver or any other Person appointed by the
Commissioners shal wilfully neglect or refuse to perform his Duty in the due and speedy Execution of this present
Act the said respective Commissioners or any Two or more of them may and shal by virtue of this Act impose
on such Person or Persons so refuseing or neglecting their Duties any Fine not exceeding Twenty Pounds for any
Offence the same to be levied and certified as aforesaid into His Majesties Court of Exchequer and charged upon
the respective Receivers General amongst the rest of the Rates aforesaid And the said Commissioners or any Two
or more of them may and shal from time to time call for and require an Account from the respective Receivers
General of all the Moneys received by them of the said Collectors and of the Payments thereof into His Majesties
Receipt of Exchequer according to the Direction of this Act And in case of any Failure in the Premisses the
said Commissioners or any Two or more of them are hereby required to cause the same to be forthwith levied
and paid according to the true Intent and Meaning of this [Act<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] And in case of any Controversie arising
between the said Commissioners concerning the said Rates or Assessments the Commissioners that shal be concerned
therein shal have no Voice but shal withdraw during the Debate of such Controversie until it be determined by
the rest of the Commissioners and in Default thereof that the Commissioners then present shall have Power and
are hereby required to impose such Fine or Fines as to them shal be thought fit upon such Commissioners so
refusing to withdraw not exceeding the Sum of Twenty Pounds and to cause the same to be levied and paid as
other Fines to be imposed by this Act are to be levied and paid And all Questions and Differences that shal
arise touch[ing<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] any of the said Rates Taxes Assessments or Levies and the collecting thereof shal be heard and
finally determined by Three or more of the Commissioners upon Complaint thereof to them made by any Person
[or Persons<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] thereby grieved without further Trouble or Suit in Law And the said Receiver General his Deputy
or Deputies shall give Acquittances gratis to the said Collectors for all Moneys of them received in pursuance of
this Act which Acquittances shall be a ful Discharge of the said Collectors respectively And the said Collectors
shal make and deliver to the said Receivers General their Deputy or Deputies a perfect Schedule fairly written in
Parchment under their Hands and Seals signed and allowed by any Two or more of the respective Commissioners
containing the Names and Sirnames and Places of Abode of every Person within their respective Collection that
shal make Default of Payment of any the Sums that shal be rated or assessed on such Person by virtue of this
Act and the Sum and Sums charged on every such Person the same to be by him returned into His Majesties
Exchequer wherupon every Person so making Default of Payment may be charged by Process of the said Court
And the Officers of the said Court are hereby strictly enjoyned and required to issue such Process against all
Persons whatsoever so making Default And the said Process shal be duely executed for Recovery of the [Money<ref idref="n14">14</ref>]
whereof Default in Payment shal be made as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Letters Patent, &amp;c. no Exemption.</head>
			<para id="p25">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no Letters Patents granted by the Kings Majesty
or any of His Royal Predecessors or to be granted by His Majesty to any Person or Persons Cities Boroughs or
Towns Corporate within this Realm of any manner of Liberties Priviledges or Exemptions from Subsidies Tolls
Taxes Assessments or Aids shall be construed or taken to exempt any Person or Persons City Borough or Town
Corporate or any the Inhabitants of the same from the Burthen or Charge of any Sum or Sums of Money granted
by this Act and all Non obstante's in snch Letters Patents for any such Purpose or Intent are hereby declared
to be void and of none Effect.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Constables, &amp;c. to aid and execute Commissioners Precepts.</head>
			<para id="p26">And be it enacted That all Constables Headboroughs, Tythingmen and other His Majesties Officers shal and are
hereby required and enjoyned to be respectively aiding and assisting in the Execution of this Act and to obey and
execute such Precepts and Warrants as shall be to them directed in that behalf by the respective Commissioners
hereby appointed or any Two or more of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. In Actions for executing Act,</head>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">General Issue may be pleaded; Treble Costs.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p28">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Action Plaint Suit or Information shall be
commenced or prosecuted against any Person for what he or they shall do in pursuance or in Execution of this
Act such Person or Persons so sued in any Court whatsoever shall and may plead the General Issue not guilty
any upon any issue joyned may give this Act and the special Matter in Evidence and if the Plaintiff or Prosecutor
shall become Nonsuit or forbear further Prosecution or suffer Discontinuance or if a Verdict pass against him the
Defendant and Defendants shall recover their Treble Costs for which they shall have the like Remedy as in Cases
where Costs by Law are given to Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Parents and Guardians to pay Rates imposed on Infants.</head>
			<para id="p29">And be it further enacted and ordained That the respective Parents Guardians and Tutors of every Person under
the Age of One and twenty Years shall upon Default of Payment by such Person and upon Demand pay what is
due and payable by this Act for every [such<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] Person residing in their Family or under their Tuition as before
herein is mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Monies due paid by particular Collectors to Receivers General or Deputy, who is to give Notice thereof to the Commissioners or Two of them as herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p30">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Moneys due and payable by this Act shall be paid by
the particular Collectors of respective Counties Cities Boroughs Towns Parishes and Places who shall collect
the same unto such Receiver General as shall by His Majesty be appointed to receive the same or to the Deputy
or Deputies of such Receiver General to be appointed under his Hand and Seal whereof Notice shall be given by
the Receiver General to the Commissioners or any Two of them within the respective Divisions within Ten Days after
their General Meeting and so from time to time within Ten Days after every Death or Removal of any Deputy
(if any such shal happen) and the Receipt of such Receiver General his Deputy or Deputies or any one [of<ref idref="n15">15</ref>]
them shall be a sufficient Discharge unto every such Collector.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. How far particular Collectors obliged to travel.</head>
			<para id="p31">And be it further enacted That the particular Collectors for Payment of any Sums by them received unto such
Receiver General or his Deputy shall not be obliged to travel above Ten Miles from the Place of their Habitations.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Receiver General to give to Commissioners a Receipt;</head>
			<para id="p32">
				<emph type="i">such Receipt to be a Discharge against His Majesty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p33">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Receiver General from time to time within the
Space of One Month next after he shal have received the full Sum that shall be charged upon any Hundred or
Division for each particular Quarterly Payment that is to be made to such Receiver General by virtue of this Act
shall give the Commissioners that shall act in such Hundred or Division a Receipt under his Hand and Seal
acknowledging his Receipt of the full Sum charged upon such Hundred or Division for such particular Payment
which Receipt shal be a full Discharge to such Hundred or Division for such particular Payment against His Majesty
His Heirs or Succesors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Receivers General certifying Arrears due where Monies have been received.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Penalty to Party; Penalty to His Majesty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p35">And for preventing such unjust Vexations as might be occasioned by such Persons as shall be appointed Receivers
General of any the Sums of Money granted by this Act and to the Intent the said Receivers General may return
a true Account into His Majesties Court of Exchequer of such Sums of Money as shall [be<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] received by them
and every of them their and every of their Deputy and Deputies Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid
That if any such Receiver General shall return or certifie into the said Court any Sum or Sums of Money to be
in Arrear and unpaid after the same hath been received either by such Receiver General or by his Deputy or
Deputies or any of them or shall cause any Person or Persons to be [set <ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Insuper in the said Court for any Sum or
Sums of Money that hath been so received that then every such Receiver General shall forfeit to every Person
[or<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Persons that shall be molested vexed or damaged by reason of such unjust Certificate Return or Setting Insuper.
Treble Damages that shall be thereby occasioned the said Damages to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint
or Information in which no Essoign Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed or any more then One Imparlance
and shall also forfeit to His Majesty His Heirs and Successors Double the Sum that shall be so unjustly certified
or returned or caused to be set Insuper.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Commissioners not liable to Penalties in Act 25 Car. II. c. 2.</head>
			<para id="p36">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no Commissioner or Commissioners who shall be
imployed in the Execution of this Act shall [be<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] liable for or by reason of such Execution to any the Penalties
mentioned in an Act made in the Five and twentieth Year of the Reign of King Charles the Second for the
preventing of Dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Penalties how levied.</head>
			<para id="p37">Provided always and be it enacted That all Penalties and Forfeitures to be incurred for any Offences against
this Act (for which there is no way of levying herein before prescribed [and<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] appointed) shall be levied by Warrant
of any Two or more of the respective Commissioners of the Division or Place where such Offence was or shall
be committed by Distress and Sale of the Goods of the Offender rendring the Overplus to the Owner thereof
after Deduction of seasonable Charges for distraining the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. After Appeals determined Commissioners to cause Duplicates of Sums charged to be transmitted to Sheriff, to be by him transmitted to Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p38">And be it further enacted That the Commissioners in every County at a General Meeting to be by them
appointed after all Appeals shall be first determined shall cause Duplicates of the whole Sum charged within every
Hundred Lathe Wapentake Parish Ward or Place rated and assessed in such County in pursuance of this Act
without naming the Persons to be fairly written in Parchment and assertained under Three or more of their Hands
respectively to each Duplicate and the same so by them subscribed and ascertained shall be joyntly and together
delivered to the Sheriff of such County and be by him transmitted to the Exchequer at or before the Twentieth
Day of September One thousand six hundred ninety eight.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Commissioners to take the Oaths of 1 W. &amp; M. c. 8.</head>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">which Commissioners may administer; Commissioner acting without taking the Oaths, Penalty &pound;200</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p40">Provided always that no Person shall be capable of acting as a Commissioner in the Execution of this Act
before he shall take the Oaths appointed by an Act made in the First Year of the Reign of His Majesty and the
late Queen of blessed Memory intituled An Act for abrogateing the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance and
appointing other Oaths which Oaths it shall be lawful for [any<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Two or more of the Commissioners to administer
and they [are<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] hereby authorized and required to administer the same to any other Commissioner And in case
any Person named a Commissioner for putting in Execution this Act shall presume to act as a Commissioner before
he shall have taken the said Oaths he shall forfeit to His Majesty the Sum of Two hundred Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Where Persons charged to Horse or Horsemen to be assessed.</head>
			<para id="p41">
				<emph type="i">Assessment not paid, and no Goods; Tenant of Land may pay and deduct out of Rent</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p42">Provided always that all Persons charged or chargeable by this Act in respect of their finding or contributeing
or being liable to find or contribute to the finding any Horse or Horseman with Armes as aforesaid shall be assessed
for the same in such Counties and Places respectively where they do or ought so to find or contribute as aforesaid
And if the Sums assessed or charged in such Counties or Places respectively shall not be paid within the
respective times in this Act before limitted for Payment thereof and no Goods or Chattels of the Person so assessed
sufficient to pay the said Sums shal be found in the Place where such Assessment shall be made it shall be lawful
in case the Tenant or Tenants of the Lands in respect of which such Assessment shall be made shall not within
Ten Days after demand thereof pay the said Sums to levy the same by Distress and Sale of the Goods of such
Tenant or Tenants in manner aforesaid And every Tenant paying the Sum so assessed or upon whome the same
shall be levyed as aforesaid shall and may deduct so much out of the Rent payable for the Premisses which said
Sum so deducted and detained shall be allowed on Payment of the residue of the Rent as fully as if the whole
Rent had been actually paid to such Person to whom the same was due.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Serjeants' Inns, Inns of Court, and Inns of Chancery to be assessed.</head>
			<para id="p43">And it is hereby further enacted That the several and respective Persons inhabiting or lodging in Serjeants Inn
in Fleet-street and Serjeants Inn in Chancery Lane the Four Inns of Court and the Inns of Chancery belonging
thereto shall be rated and assessed by this Act according to such Proportions as are imposed by this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Commissioners may summon Persons coming to reside in District in London, &amp;c. where not rated.</head>
			<para id="p44">And it is hereby further enacted That if any Person shall come to inhabit or reside in any Division or Place
within London or Westminster or Five Miles thereof where such Person was not rated or taxed the Commissioners
acting within such Division or Place are hereby required and impowred to summon such Person before them and
unless he or she shal produce a Certificate (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) according to the direction of this Act whereby it shall appear that he
or she were assessed and had actually paid all the preceeding Quarterly Payments in some other Place the said
Commissioners shall and are hereby required to cause such Persons to be assessed according to this Act and cause
the same or such Quarterly Payments thereof as shall be unassessed and unpaid to be assessed levyed and paid
according to the true intent and meaning of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Housekeepers to give an Account of Lodgers to Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p45">And it is further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Householder shall upon the demand of the
Assessors of the respective Parishes or Places give an Account of the Names and Qualities of such Persons as shal
sojourn or lodg in their respective Houses under the Penalty of forfeiting to His Majesty the Sum of Five Pounds
to be levied recovered and distributed in such manner as other Penalties in this Act mentioned are to be levied
and recovered.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Proviso for Persons paying Assessment before hand.</head>
			<para id="p46">And whereas several Persons who are to be assessed by this Act may be willing and desireous to pay or satisfy
all or several of the Quarterly Payments by this Act intended to be satisfied and paid by them Be it further
enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawful to and for any Person or Persons to satisfie
and pay to the respective Collector or Collectors all or any of the said Quarterly Payments assessed upon him
her or them for the said whole Year or any Quarters thereof before hand which said Collectors are hereby
enjoyned and required on every such Payment made before hand to give the Party or Parties paying the same an
Acquittance expressing the Sum received for such Quarterly Payments for which such Payment shall be so
made and every such Acquittance shall be a good Discharge against (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) His Heirs and Successors as if the Sums
chargeable by this Act on such Person or Persons were assessed or answered at such several and respective
Quarterly. Times and Payments as are above mentioned Any [thing<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] in this Act to the contrary thereof in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Members of Parliament to be rated at Place where they reside when Parliament not sitting.</head>
			<para id="p47">Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all and every the Members of this present
Parliament shall be assessed and taxed at the Place where their usual Residence is in the Intervals of Parliament
and not elsewhere Any thing in this Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. C. 13. ante.; Out of Monies levied &pound;250,000 towards Payment of Seamens Wages;</head>
			<para id="p48">
				<emph type="i">and &pound;250,000 for Land Forces</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p49">And it is further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That out of the Money that shall be levied or paid into the
Receipt of the Exchequer aswel upon Loans as otherwise by vertue of an Act made in this present Session of
Parliament intituled An Act for granting to His Majesty several Duties upon Coal and Culm the Sum of Two
hundred and fifty thousand Pounds shall be and is hereby applied and appropriated for and towards the Payment
of Wages to Seamen that have or shall serve in His Majesties Navy Royal And also that out of the first Money
that shall be raised aswel upon Loans as otherwise by virtue of this present Act the Sum of Two hundred and
fifty thousand Pounds shall be and is hereby appropriated to and for the satisfying and paying the Debts due for
Quarters from His Majesties Land Forces within the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales and Town of Berwick
upon Tweed since the First Day of January One thousand six hundred ninety six.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. Rules, Penalties, &amp;c. of 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 1. in Force and applied in Execution of Act.</head>
			<para id="p50">And for the more effectual doing thereof and that the Sums [by this<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Act appropriated may not be diverted
or applied to any other purpose than is hereby declared and intended Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That
the Rules and Directions appointed and enacted by one Act made in the First Year of the Reign of King William
and Queen Mary intituled An Act for a Grant to Their Majesties of an Aid of Two Shillings in the Pound for
one Year for the speedy Payment of Money thereby granted into the Receipt of the Exchequer by the Collectors
and Receivers and for Distribution and Application thereof and keeping distinct Accounts of the same and all other
Provisions Pains Penalties and Forfeitures thereby enacted in case (<ref idref="n24">24</ref>) of any Money thereby appropriated are hereby
revived and enacted to be in Force and shal be practised applied executed and put in ure for and concerning the
Distribution and Application of the said Sums hereby appropriated as fully amply and effectually as if the same
were here particularly repeated and reenacted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Persons may lend Money to His Majesty on this Act, not exceeding &pound;500,000, at Rates herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p51">Provided also and it is hereby enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawful to and for
any Person or Persons Natives or Foreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate to advance and lend unto His Majesty
at the Receipt of His Majesties Exchequer upon the Security of this Act any Sum or Sums of Money not exceeding
the Sum of Five hundred thousand Pounds and to have and receive for the Forbearance thereof Interest after the
Rate of Seven Pounds per Centum per Anumm [for the First Two hundred and fifty thousand Pounds and Eight
Pounds per Centum per Annum] for the remaining Two hundred and fifty thousand Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. C. 13. ante. Persons may lend Money to His Majesty not exceeding &pound;500,000, at Rates of Interest herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p52">And whereas by an Act of this present Session of Parliament several Duties upon Coals and Culm are granted
to His Majesty Be it further enacted That it shal and may be lawful to and for any Person or Persons Natives
or Foreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate to advance and lend unto His Majestie at the said Receipt of His Majesties
Exchequer upon the Securities of the Moneys which from and after the Twenty fourth Day of June One thousand
six hundred ninety eight shall arise of or for the said Duties upon Coals and Culm any Sum or Sums of Money
not exceeding the Sum of Five hundred thousand Pounds and to have and receive for the Forbearance thereof
Interest after the Rate of Seven Pounds per Centum per Annum for the First Hundred thousand Pounds and
Eight Pounds per Centum per Ann for the remaining Four hundred thousand Pounds And moreover that no Money
which shall be so lent or advanced as aforesaid shal be rated or assessed by virtue of any Act of Parliament
whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. Repayment of Monies, how secured.</head>
			<para id="p53">
				<emph type="i">Books provided; Tally of Loan to Lender, and Warrant for Interest; Orders for Repayment registered according to Date of Tally, and paid in course; Monies to come in by this Act, &amp;c. liable to satisfy such Loans; No Fee for providing or making Books, &amp;c; or for Payment of Money lent; Penalty; Punishment; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty; Punishment; By Deputy; Penalty; Punishment; Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller not making Payment in due Order, Penalty; How all such Penalties to be recovered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p54">And to the end that all Money that shall be lent to His Majesty as well upon Credit of this Act as also upon
Credit of the Act of the said Duties upon Coals and Culm may be well and sufficiently secured out of the
Moneys arising by the same Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That there shall be provided and
kept in His Majesties Exchequer (that is to say) in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt Two several Books
or Registers in which all the Moneys that shall be paid into the Exchequer for the Quarterly Poll hereby granted
and for the said Duties on Coals and Culm shall be entred and registred apart and distinct from all other Money
paid and payable to His Majesty upon any Account whatsoever And that all and every Person and Persons who
shall lend any Money to His Majesty upon the Creditts aforesaid and pay the same into the Receipt of Exchequer
shall immediately have a Tally of Loan struck for the same and an Order for his or their Payment bearing the
same Date with his or their Tally in which Order shall be also contained a Warrant for Payment of Interest
for the Forbearance thereof not exceeding the Rates aforesaid for his and their Consideration to be paid every
Three Months until Repayment of the Principal And that all Orders for Repayment of Money shal be registred
in course upon the said respective Registers according to the Date of the Tallys respectively without Preference
of one before another and that all and every Person and Persons shall be paid in course according as their Orders
shall stand entred in the said Registers so as the Person Native or Foreigner his Executors Administrators or
Assigns who shall have his Order [or<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Orders first entred in the said respective Registers shall be accounted
the first Person to be paid out of the Money coming into the Exchequer for dischargeing thereof (that is to say)
by the Quarterly Poll hereby granted for one of the said Registers and by the Dutyes on Coals and Culm for
the other Register hereby appointed to be kept as aforesaid And that he or they who shall have his or their
Order or Orders next entred on the said respective Registers shall be taken and accounted to be the Second
Person to be paid thereupon and so successively and in course And that the Money coming in by this Act and
the Duties which from and after the said Four and twentieth [Day<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] of June One thousand six hundred ninety
eight shall arise by the said Act on Coals and Culm shall be in the same Order liable to the Satisfaction of the
[said<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] respective Parties their Executors Administrators or Assigns successively without Preference (<ref idref="n26">26</ref>) one before
another and not otherwise and not to be divertible to any other Use Intent or Purpose whatsoever And that no
Fee Reward or Gratuity directly or indirectly be demanded or taken of any His Majesties Subjects for providing
or making of any such Books Registers Entries Views or Search in or for Payment of Money lent or the Interest
thereof as aforesaid by any of His Majesties Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputies on pain of Payment of
double Damages to the Party agrieved by the Party offending with Costs of Suit or if the Officer himself take
or demand any such Fee or Reward then to lose his Place also And if any undue Preference of one before
another shall be made either in point of Registry or Payment contrary to the true meaning of this Act by any
such Officer or Officers then the Party offending shall be liable by Action of Debt or on the Case to pay the
Value of the Debt Damages and Costs to the Party grieved and shall be forejudged from his Place or Office
And if such Preference be unduly made by his (<ref idref="n27">27</ref>) Deputy or Clerk without Direction or Privity of his Master then
such Deputy or Clerk only shall be liable to such Action Debt Damages and Costs and shall be for ever after
uncapable of his Place or Office And in case the Auditor shall not direct the [Order<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] or the Clerk of the Pells
Record and the Teller make Payment according to each Persons due Place and Order as afore directed then
he or they shall be judged to forfeit and their respective Deputies and Clerks herein offending to be liable to
such Action Debt Damages and Costs in such manner as aforesaid all which said Penalties Forfeitures Damages
and Costs to be incurred by any of the Officers of the Exchequer or any their Deputies or Clerks shall and
may be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties Courts of Record at
Westminster wherein no Essoign Protection Priviledge Wager of Law Injunction or Order of Restraint shall be in
any wise granted or allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date or brought same Day.</head>
			<para id="p55">Provided always and be it hereby declared That if it happen that several Tallys of Loan or Orders of Payment
as aforesaid bear Date or be brought the same Day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be registred then it shal
be interpreted no undue Preference which of those be entred first so he enters them all the same Day</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. Paying subsequent Orders if first demanded no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy the preceding Orders.</head>
			<para id="p56">Provided also That it shall not be interpreted any undue Preference to incurr any Penalty in point of Payment
if the Auditor direct and the Clerk of the Pells record and the Tellers to pay subsequent Orders of the Persons that
come and demand their Money and bring their Orders before other Persons that did not come to demand their
Money and bring their Orders in their Course so as there be so much Money reserved as will satisfy Precedent
Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon Loan being to cease from the
time the Money is to be reserved and kept in Bank for them</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Orders for Payment of Money lent may be assigned by Indorsement.</head>
			<para id="p57">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee; Assignee may in like manner assign</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p58">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Person or Persons to whom any Money shall
be due by vertue of this Act after Order entred in either of the Books of Register aforesaid for Payment thereof
his Executors Administrators or Assigns by Indorsment of his Order may assign &amp; transfer his Right Title Interest
and Benefit of such Order or any part thereof to any other which being notified in the Office of the Auditor
of the Receipt aforesaid &amp; an Entry or Memorial thereof also made in the Books of Register aforesaid for
Orders which the Officers shall upon Request without Fee or Charge accordingly make shall intitle such
Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assigns to [the<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] Benefit thereof and Payment thereon and such Assignee
may in like manner assign again and so toties quoties and afterwards it shal not be in the Power of such Person
or Persons who have or hath made such Assignments to make void release or discharge the same or any the
Moneys thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. His Majesty may apply the Supplies of this Session, not exceeding &pound;600,000, as herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p59">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawful to and for His Majesty
to make use of any Sum or Sums of Money (not exceeding Six hundred thousand Pounds in the whole) arising
by any the Aids or Supplies granted or that shall be granted during this present Session of Parliament and not
particularly appropriated for and towards dischargeing the Talleys of Pro or Assignment or other Talleys remaining
unsatisfied on the Hereditary Branch of His Majesties Revenues of Excise upon Beer Ale and other Liquors and
on that part of His Majesties Revenues of Excise of Beer Ale and other Liquors which is granted to His Majesty
during His Life (which God preserve) or upon the Weekly Sum of Six thousand Pounds issuing out of the same
and likewise on His Majesties Revenue arising within the General Letter Office or Post-Office or Office of Post-master
General or upon the Weekly Sum of Six hundred Pounds issuing out of the same and for other His Majesties
necessary Occasions or for satisfying such Moneys as have been or shall be borrowed to supply the same Any
thing in this or any other Act of Parliament contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>XLIII. Recital of c. 10. &sect;24. ante.</head>
			<para id="p60">
				<emph type="i">Allowance by Auditors, &amp;c. of 3s. in the Pound in respect of Rents; Auditor, &amp;c. unduly setting insuper; Penalty &pound;100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p61">And whereas in an Act of this present Session of Parliament intituled An Act for granting to His Majesty
One million four hundred eighty four thousand and fifteen Pounds One Shilling Eleven Pence Three Farthings for
disbanding Forces paying Seamen and other Uses therein mentioned It is (amongst other things) provided and
enacted That all and every Auditor Reeve or Receiver and their Deputy or Deputies who receive any Fee-Farm-Rent
or other Chief Rents due to His Majesty or the Queen Dowager or to any Person or Persons claiming by any
Grant or Purchase from or under the Crown shall abate and deduct (<ref idref="n29">29</ref>) out of such Rents in proportion to the Rate
to be taxed or assessed on the Lands or Hereditaments out of which such Rents shall be issuing or payable and
many Doubts and Controversies are likely to arise between the said Auditors Reeves and Receivers and the respective
Tenants and Owners of the said Lands or Hereditaments by reason of the uncertainty of the said recited Clause
therefore for the further explaining and ascertaining the same It is hereby provided enacted and declared That
all and every the said Auditors Reeves or Receivers and their Deputy or Deputies shall allow Three Shillings for
every Pound of the said Rents and proportionably for any greater or lesser Sum to the Party and Parties so paying
the same without any Fee for such Allowance upon the Penalty of Twenty Pounds to the Party grieved to be
recovered as aforesaid And if any Auditor of the Revenues or any of them belonging to His Majesty or to Her
Majesty Katherine the Queen Dowager or any Deputy or other Person acting for or on the behalf of any such
Auditor shall in the Account of any Reeve Receiver or otherwise set insuper any Tenant or other Person or make
any such Tenant or other Person or his or their Estate lyable to any Distress Forfeiture or Vexation whatsoever
for any Sum or Sums of Money which by the true meaning of this Act ought to be allowed after the said Rate
of Three Shillings in the Pound or shall refuse neglect or delay to allow and finally to discharge the same in
the proper Accounts wherein the same ought to be allowed or discharged that then and for every or any such
Offence every such Auditor or Deputy or Person acting for any such Auditor shall forfeit the Sum of One hundred
Pounds to the Party grieved to be recovered as aforesaid And shall be also incapable to enjoy his Office or Place
or any other Office or Place of Trust or Profit by from or under His Majesty or the said Queen Dowager.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">O. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Hundred <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">common <emph type="i">O</emph>. &amp; King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">thinke <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Quarterly Payments <emph type="i">O</emph>. &amp; King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">as <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">the said Commissioners, in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Moneys <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">let <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">made O.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">His Majesty, O. and King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">this O.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">of Diversion, <emph type="i">O</emph>. and King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">be <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">only <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


