<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46922" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXVI. An Act to stop the coining Farthings and Halfpence for One Year. [Rot. Parl. 9 Gul. III.p.6.n.5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head><ref idref="n1">1</ref> Coining Farthings or Halfpence.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by Reason of the great Quantities of Copper Farthings and Halfpence which have lately been
coined and uttered the same are at present become a Burthen and Inconveniency to many of His
Majesties Subjects in several Parts of this Kingdom Be it therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by
and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by Authority of the same That no Person or Persons whatsoever shal (at any Time or Times from
and after the Four and twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety eight and before the Four and
twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred ninety nine) coin or make or cause or procure to be coined or
made any Farthings or Halfpence [or Tokens to go for Farthings or Halfpence<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of Copper or any other Metal
whatsoever upon Pain of forfeiting the Sum of Five Pounds for every Avoirdupoize Pound Weight of such Farthings
and Halfpence or either of them as shal be so coined or made contrary to this Act (that is to say) One Moiety
thereof to the King and the other Moiety thereof to such Person or Persons as wil inform or sue for the same by
Action of Debt or of the Case Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties Courts of Record wherein no
Essoign Protection Wager of Law or more than One Imparlance shal be granted or allowed.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso respecting Agreement by Contractors for making Copper Farthings, &amp;c. for exchanging weekly Copper Farthings, &amp;c. for those made of Tin.</head>
			<para id="p3">And it is hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Contractors for making or coining of
Copper Farthings &amp; Halfpence shal not by virtue of any Covenant or Agreement made with His Majesty &amp; the
late Queen of blessed Memory for giving in Exchange to His Majesties Subjects weekly Farthings and Halfpence
made of Copper for Farthings and Halfpence made of Tin be obliged to perform such Exchange for so many
Weeks only as are to be reckoned between the said Four and twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred
ninety eight and the said Four and twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred ninety nine.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This is Chapter XXXIII. in the Common printed Editions.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


