<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46925" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXIX. An Act for settling and adjusting the Proportion of Fine Silver Silk for the better making of Silver and Gold Thread and to prevent the Abuses of Wire-Drawers. [Rot. Parl. 9 Gul.III.p.6.n.8].</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head><ref idref="n1">1</ref> <ref idref="n2">2</ref>Recital that Abuses had been committed in the refining of Silver, and making Silver and Gold Thread</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Regulation of Silver Wire to be drawn for making Gold and Silver Thread; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas of late by several Refiners Wire-Drawers and others concerned in the refining of Silver and
guilding thereof and in making of Silver and Gold Thread and Wire either through Unskilfulness or
coveting to make an unjust Advantage to themselves there have been committed several Abuses in the refining
of Silver and making of Silver and Gold Thread and Wire especially in not allowing a due Proportion of Fine
Silver to Silk whereby the Silver breaking and crumbling off from the Silk there not only is a great Loss to the
respective Buyers but an irreparable Loss to the Nation in general in the wasting and consuming the Bullion
thereof and the said Silver and Gold Thread and the Manufactures in which the "same are made use of consequently
have not that Credit Use and Service that Silver Thread and the Manufactures thereof made Abroad have to the
great Discouragement of the Exportation of the said Silver Thread and Manufactures and the Use and Wear of
the same at Home For Remedy whereof for the future Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and
with the Advice and Consent of the Lord Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled
and by Authority of the same That from and after the Four and twentieth Day of July One thousand six hundred
ninety eight all Silver Wire to be drawn for the making of Gold and Silver Thread shall hold at the least Eleven
Ounces Sixteen Peny Weight [of Fine Silver upon every Pound Weight<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Troy And that all Silver to be guilt and
made Use of in the Wire-Drawers Trade shall hold at the least Eleven Ounces Sixteen Peny Weight of Fine Silver
upon the Pound Weight Troy and shall not have less than Four Peny Weight of Fine Gold laid upon each Pound
Weight of the said Silver upon Pain to forfeit Five Shillings an Ounce for every Ounce to be paid by the Refiner
or Maker thereof.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Colouring gilt Wire with Verdigrease, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Penalty; Allowance for Gold and Silver reduced into Plate, and for Gold and Silver Thread of the Fineness herein mentioned; How Gold and Silver Plate is to be spun; Penalty.; Undue laying of Plate upon Silk, Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Four and twentieth Day of
July no guilt Wire shall be couloured with Verdigrease or Dead Head or any other forced Colour upon Pain to
forfeit Two Shillings and Six Pence an Ounce for every Ounce so coloured And for all Gold and Silver prepared
as aforesaid and reduced into Plate there shall be allowed at the least Six Ounces of the said Plate to cover Four
Ounces of Silk the Finest of which Silk shall not run above Sixteen Yards to the Peny Weight Troy And that
for all Gold and Silver Threads made Finer than the aforesaid Sizes there shal be allowed at the least Six Ounces
of Plate to cover Three Ounces and an Half of Silk the Finest of which said Silk shal not run above Thirty six
Yards to the Peny Weight Troy And that for all Gold and Silver Threads made Finer then the aforesaid Sizes
there shall be allowed at the least Six Ounces of Plate to cover Three Ounces of Silk the Finest of which Silk
shall not run above Ninety Yards to One Peny Weight Troy And for all Gold and Silver Thread made Finer. Six
Ounces of Plate to cover Two Ounces and an Half of Silk And that for the future all Gold and Silver Plate shall
be spun close upon well boiled and light dyed Silk only (except Frost being run thin and spun upon differing
coloured Silk) upon Pain of forfeiting Two Shillings and Six Pence an Ounce for [every Ounce<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] otherwise made
And that any Spinner of Gold and Silver Thread that shall lay Gold or Silver Plate upon Silk in other Proportion
than as aforesaid shall forfeit and pay for each and every Ounce so spun the Sum of Two Shillings.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. How Metal inferior to Silver shall be spun.</head>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p6">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Four and twentieth Day of
July Copper Brass and every other inferiour Metal than Silver shall be spun upon Thread Yarn or Incle only and
not upon Silk upon Pain that each and every Person offending therein shall forfeit Five Shillings for every Ounce
so spun.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Importing Gold or Silver or inferior Thread.;</head>
		<para id="p7">
			<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p8">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Four and twentieth Day of
July no Gold or Silver Thread Lace Fringe or other Work made thereof nor any Thread made of Copper Brass or
any inferiour Metal or Wire or Plate ready wrought for the covering of Silk or Thread shall be imported or brought
into this Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or Town of Berwick upon Tweed upon Pain of being forfeited
and burnt.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. How Penalties divided and recovered.</head>
		<para id="p9">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That [after<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the several Penalties and Forfeitures made and
inflicted by this Act One Moiety thereof shall be the King and the other Moiety to him or them that shall inform
sue or prosecute for the same And that the said Penalties and Forfeitures may be prosecuted sued for and recovered
by Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties Court of Record at Westminster wherein no Essoign Protection
Priviledge or Wager of Law shall be allowed or more than One Imparlance.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. In Actions for executing Act, General Issue may be pleaded.;</head>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p11">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Person shall be sued for what he or they shal
do in Execution of this Act he or they may plead the General Issue and give the Special Matter in Evidence And
if the Plaintiff shall become nonsuit or discontinue his or their Action or if a Verdict pass against him or them
the Defendant shall recover Treble Costs for which Execution shall issue in such Manner as in other Cases where
Costs are allowed to Defendants.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. Proviso in respect of Penalties for selling, &amp;c. Wire and Thread, &amp;c. before 29th Sept. 1699.</head>
		<para id="p12">Provided always That nothing in this Act contained shall be construed to inflict any Penalty upon any Person
for selling or exposing to Sale any Silver Wire or Silver or Gold Thread or any Lace or Fringe on or before the
Nine and twentieth Day of September One thousand six hundred ninety nine though the same be not made
according to the Rules and Directions of this Act provided the same be proved by Oath to be made by One or
more credible Witnesses before some Justice of Peace of the County City or Place where the same shall be sold or
exposed to Sale who is and are hereby impowred to administer the same That such Goods were made on or before
the said Four and twentieth Day of July One thousand six hundred ninety eight.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. Limitation of Action.</head>
		<para id="p13">Provided always That every Suit Action or Prosecution to be brought by virtue of this Act shall be commenced
within Six Months after the Offence committed.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>IX. Continuance of Act.</head>
		<para id="p14">Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That this Act shall continue for the Space of
Three Years and from thence to the (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) next Session of Parliament and no longer Any Thing in this Act to the
contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">Of <emph type="i">O</emph>. and King's Printer's Copy.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">end of the <emph type="i">O</emph>. and King's Printer's Copy.</note>
	</section>
</report>


