<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46932" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1697-8</title>
	<subtitle>The Private Acts</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Item quedam Peticiones privatas Personas concernentes in se form[er] Acts continents exhibite fuerunt predicto Do[mi]no Regi in Parliamento predicto quorum Tituli subscribuntur (viz<emph type="p">t</emph>)</head>
		<para id="p1">i An Act for vesting in Sydenham Baker Gents an absolute Estate of Inherita.nce in Fee Simple in a certaine
Rent Messuages Lands &amp;Hereditaments in the County of Devon and secureing to John Baker Gents &amp;Henry
Baker an Infant his Son Moneys in lieu of their Claims thereunto</para>
		<para id="p2">ij An Act for enabling Simon Lord Bishop of Ely &amp;his Successors to lease the Mannor House &amp;Demesne
Lands of Downham in the Ise of Ely &amp;for confirming a Lease lately thereof made by the said Bishopp &amp;for
cleareing the said Bishopp and others from Dilapidations there.</para>
		<para id="p3">iij An Act to enable Sir Francis Guybon and Dame Isabella his Wife and their Trustees to sell the Mannor of
Avenalls and other Lands in or neare Gunthorpe in the County of Norfolke and for settling other Lands in lieu
thereof.</para>
		<para id="p4">iiij An Act for the Naturalization of Gerrard Maesacker and others.</para>
		<para id="p5">v An Act to enable Rebecca Lassels Widdow to sell Coppyhold Lands and Houses in Ealing in the County
of Middlesex.</para>
		<para id="p6">vi An Act for vesting in Trustees to be sold certaine Lands of George Farrington Esquire lying in the Counties
of Middlesex and Surrey settled upon the Marriage of William Farrington his Nephew and with the Moneys ariseing
thereby for purchasing [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] other Lands in Lancashire where the ancient Estate of the Family lies to bee settled
to the same Uses.</para>
		<para id="p7">vij An Act to enable the Trustees of William Knott Gents and his Wife to sell a Lease of Houses in Bread
Street London for Payment of Debts and to settle another Estate of better Value in lieu thereof.</para>
		<para id="p8">viij An Act to ennable Thomas Kinnersly Esquire an Infant to make a Joynture and Settlement of his Estate.</para>
		<para id="p9">ix An Act for naturalizing Dudley Vesey an Infant.</para>
		<para id="p10">x An Act to enable John Lewin to sell certaine Messuages in Southwarke for Payment of Debts.</para>
		<para id="p11">xi An Act for dissolving the Marriage betweene Charles Earle of Macclesfeild and Anne his Wife and to
illegitimate the Children of the said Anne.</para>
		<para id="p12">xij An Act to enable John Lord Bishopp of Chichester to make Leases of certaine Houses and Grounds
belonging to the Bishoprick of Chichester scituate in Chancery-Lane for a competent Number of Yeares.</para>
		<para id="p13">xiij An Act to naturalize Charles May Esquire.</para>
		<para id="p14">xiiij An Act to rectify a Mistake in the Marriage Settlement of William Gardner Esq[uire].</para>
		<para id="p15">xv An Act to enable certaine Trustees therein named to make renew and fill upp Leases of the Estate of Sir
Coppleston Warwick Bampfylde dureing the minoritye of the said Sir Copplestone Warwicke Bampfylde and John
Bampfylde his Brother.</para>
		<para id="p16">xvi An Act for settling the Estate of John Hall a Lunatick subject to a Debt charged thereon.</para>
		<para id="p17">xvij An Act for erecting Hospitals Work-houses and Houses of Correction within the Towne and Parish of
Crediton in the County of Devon and for the better reliefe of the Poor there.</para>
		<para id="p18">xviij An Act for erecting Hospitals and Work houses within the Towne and Parish of Tiverton in the County
of Devon for the better imploying and maintaining the Poor thereof.</para>
		<para id="p19">xviiij An Act for confirming and establishing the Administration of the Goods and Chattells of Sir Willm Godolphin
Knight dec[eas]ed</para>
		<para id="p20">xx An Act for the naturalizing of John Francis Fauquire Joseph Ducasse and others</para>
		<para id="p21">xxi An Act for the better enabling Sir Ralph Hare Baronett to make a Joynture and settie his Estate and raise
Portions and Maintenances for his younger Children.</para>
		<para id="p22">xxij An Act for vesting in Trustees to be sold certaine Lands of George Hewett Esq[uire] lying in the County of
Middlesex settled upon his Marriage and with the Money ariseing thereby for purchasing other Lands in Leicestershire
where his Estate and Seat lies to be settled to the same Uses.</para>
		<para id="p23">xxiij An Act for vesting Lands in Trustees to be sold for Payment of the Debts of Wriothesly Baptist late
Earle of Gainesborough deceased.</para>
		<para id="p24">xxiiij An Act to annex the Rectory of Whitborne in Herefordshire to the Bishoprick of Hereford.</para>
		<para id="p25">xxv An Act for the better settling the several Estates of the Right Honorable John Lord Viscount Lisburne in
the Kingdome of Ireland and the Lady Viscountess Lisburne his Wife.</para>
		<para id="p26">xxvi An Act for supplying a Defect in a Conveyance lately made by Sir Edward Turner and Charles Turner Esq[uire]
his Son for the more effectuall securing the Su[m]m of Twelve thousand Pounds &amp;Interest upon their Estate.</para>
		<para id="p27">xxvij An Act for the vesting several Lands late belonging to Robert Smith Esq[uire] deceased in Trustees to be sold
for the Payment of his Debts.</para>
		<para id="p28">xxviij An Act for vesting the Mannors of Bastwick and Laviles in the County of Norfolk part of the Estate of
John Houghton Esquire in Trustees to be sold for discharging Debts charged thereon and for settling another Estate
in lieu thereof.</para>
		<para id="p29">xxix An Act to enable Streynsham Master Esq[uire] to sell Lands in Kent, which were agreed to be settled by his
Marriage Articles and to convey Lands in Derbyshire of a greater Value to the same Uses.</para>
		<para id="p30">xxx An Act to enable Paris Slaughter William Druce Merchants and Dame Elizabeth Chapman to import several
Bails of fine Italian Thrown Silk into this Kingdome.</para>
		<para id="p31">xxxi An Act for settling certaine Lands in Essex in Thomas Burgh [Esquire <ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and his Heires in lieu of other
Lands of greater Value conveyed by him according to the Decree and the Will of Sir Samuel Jones deceased.</para>
		<para id="p32">xxxij An Act for vesting certaine Customary Messuages and Lands within the Mannor of Gillingham in the County
of Dorsett (late the Estate of Thomas Davies Gents deceased) in Trustees to be sold for Payment of Debts.</para>
		<para id="p33">xxxiij An Act for erecting Hospitals and Work-houses within the City and County of the City of Exon for the
better imploying and maintaining the Poor there.</para>
		<para id="p34">xxxiiij An Act for erecting Hospitals and Work-houses within the City of Hereford for the better imploying and
maintaining the Poor there.</para>
		<para id="p35">xxxv An Act to rectifie some mistakes in an Act intituled An Act to enable John Lewin to sell certaine Messuages
in Southwark for Payment of Debts.</para>
		<para id="p36">xxxvi An Act for vesting a Moiety of certaine Messuages and Lands in Hackney in the County of Middlesex in
Trustees for the Benefitt of Susanna Cary Widdow and Relict of Nicholas Cary Esquire deceased and others.</para>
		<para id="p37">xxxvij An Act for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the Towne of Colchester in the County of Essex for
the better imploying and maintaining the Poor thereof.</para>
		<para id="p38">xxxviij An Act to naturalize William Lloyd Esquire and others.</para>
		<para id="p39">xxxix An Act to confirme the Sale of Part of the Estate of Sir John Churchill Knight lately deceased pursuant
to his Last Will and Two Decrees of Chancery for performance thereof.</para>
		<para id="p40">xl An Act for vesting the Mannor of Alveston and other Lands therein mentioned in the County of Gloucester
in Trustees to be sold for Payment of Debts and other Purposes therein mentioned.</para>
		<para id="p41">xli An Act for confirming a Lease granted by the Lord Bishopp of Winton of a Parcell of Waste Ground
in Alverstock in the County of Southton for the erecting of Waterworks there and for improving the same.</para>
		<para id="p42">xlij An Act for securing the Portions intended by Sir William Walter Baronett deceased for his Children by
the Lady Mary Walter his Second Wife and for preventing all Doubts which might arise upon the Construction
of the Articles and Will therein mentioned.</para>
		<para id="p43">xliij An Act for Relief of the Creditors of Edward Backwell Esquire deceased.</para>
		<para id="p44">xliiij An Act for vesting certaine Lands and Hereditaments in Maidstone and elsewhere in the County of Kent
in Trustees for the Benefitt of Diana Cecill and others.</para>
		<para id="p45">xlv An Act to confirme a Conveyance made by George Pitt Esquire and others of the Mannor of Tarrant Preston
and other Lands in the County of Dorsett to John Pitt Gents and the Heires Males of his Body.</para>
		<para id="p46">xlvj An Act for the better supplying the Towne of Newcastle upon Tyne with Fresh Water.</para>
		<para id="p47">xlvij An Act for erecting Work-houses and Houses of Correction in the Towne of Kingston upon Hull for the
Imployment and Maintenance of the Poor there.</para>
		<para id="p48">xlviij An Act for erecting Work-houses and Houses of Correction in the Towne of Shaftesbury and for the
better Imployment and Maintenance of the Poor.</para>
		<para id="p49">xlix An Act for naturalizing of Peter Garon and others</para>
		<para id="p50">I An Act for naturalizing Hillary Reneu and others</para>
		<para id="p51">li An Act that the Ships Panther Gloucester Frigott Scarborough and Antelope (formerly taken as Prizes and
condemned) may have freedom of trading as English built Shipps.</para>
		<para id="p52">lij An Act for giving Leave to the Maryland Merchant of Bristoll to arrive and import her lading into this
Kingdome.</para>
		<para id="p53">liij An Act that the Ships called the Ruby Prize and Plymouth may have Freedom of trading as English Built
Shipps.</para>
		<para id="p54">liiij An Act for vesting a Copperas work late Part of the Estate of Robert Mascall Esquire dec[eas]ed in Trustees to be
sold for Payment of Debts and other Charges thereupon.</para>
		<para id="p55">lv An Act for Sale of Three Houses in Swan Alley in Coleman Street London late of Joseph Smith deceased
for payment of his Debts with which the same Houses are chargeable.</para>
		<para id="p56">lvi An Act to enable John Jenkin Merchant to sell part of his Estate for Payment of his Debts.</para>
		<para id="p57">lvij An Act to enable John Hawkes Gentleman to sell Lands in the County of Salop for Payment of his
Debts.</para>
		<para id="p58">lviij An Act to enable Humphrey Walrond Gents to sell part of his Estate for the making Provision for his
eldest Son and Elizabeth his Daughter (who are Lunaticks) and Payment of his Debts and raising Portions for
his other Children.</para>
		<para id="p59">lix An Act to give Leave to the Ship Sally Rose (formerly taken as Prize) to arrive and import her Lading
and to trade as an English built Shipp.</para>
		<para id="p60">lx An Act for vesting in Thomas Rogers Gents an absolute Estate of Inheritance in Fee Simple in the Mannor
of Westcourt Mansion House Messuages Lands and Hereditaments in the County of Kent and securing to John
Higgons Gents Alice his Wife and for Portions for Irene Margarett Mary and Alice Cesar Moneys in lieu of their
Claims thereunto.</para>
		<para id="p61">lxi An Act to enable Trustees to make Leases and grant Copies and receive the Rents and Proffitts of the
Estates late of Sir Edward Wyndham Baronett deceased and Hopton Wyndham Esq[uire] deceased during the Minority
of Sir Will[ia]m Wyndham Baronett for the Intents and Purposes therein mentioned.</para>
		<para id="p62">lxij An Act for enabling Humphrey Trafford Esq[uire] to raise Foure thousand Pounds upon his Estate for Payment
of his Debts.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>

