<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46939" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act for preventing irregular Proceedings of Sheriffs and other Officers in making the Returns of Members chosen to serve in Parliament.[Rot. Parl. 10 Gul. III. p. I. n.7]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Returning Officer to make Return of Election within 14 Days to Clerk of the Crown; Fees to be paid by such Returning Officer; Such Fees to be charged to the Crown</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For preventing Abuses in the Returns of Writts of Summons for the calling and assembling of any Parliament
for the future or Writts for the Choice of any new Member to serve in Parliament and to the end such
Writts may by the proper Officer or his Deputy be duely returned and delivered to the Clerke of the Crowne to
be by him filed according to the ancient and legall Course Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty
by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in Parliament assembled
and by Authority of the same That the Sheriffe or other Officer having the Execution and returne of any such
Writt which shall be issued for the future shall on or before the Day that any future Parliament shall be called
to meet and with all convenient Expedition not exceeding Fourteene Daies after any Election made by virtue of
any New Writt either in Person or by his Deputy make returne of the same to the Clerke of the Crowne in
the High Court of Chancery to be by him filed and the Sheriffe or other Person makeing such Return shall pay
to the said Clerke of the Crowne the ancient and lawfull Fees of Four Shillings and no more for every Knight
of a Shire and Two Shillings and no more for every Citizen Burgesse or Baron of the Cinque Ports returned
into the same Court to be by him filed and the said Sheriffe or Officer shall by virtue of this Act charge the
same to His Majesty His Heires or Successors and have Allowance thereof in his Account in the Exchequer or
elsewhere</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Recital of 7 &amp; 8 W.III.c.25. &sect; 1</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Officer of the Cinque Ports allowed Six Days for Delivery of Precept</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And whereas by an Act made in the Seaventh and Eighth Yeares of the Reigne of His present Majesty intituled
An Act for the further regulating Elections of Members to serve in Parliament and for the preventing irregular
Proceedings of Sheriffs and other Officers in the electing and returning such Members It is provided and enacted
That the Officer on the Receipt of any such Writt shall within Three Daies after such his. Receipt by himselfe
or proper Agent deliver or cause to be delivered a Precept or Precepts to the proper Officer of every Borough
Towne Corporate Port or Place within his Jurisdiction to whom the Execution of such Precept doth belong or
appertaine which by Experience hath been found too short a time for the performance of the same in the Cinque
Ports Be it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from henceforth the proper Officer of the Cinque
Ports shall be allowed Six Daies from the Receipt of such Writt for the Delivery of the Precept according to the
Purport of the said Act Any thing in the said Act or any other Law Statute or Usage to the contrary in any
wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Returning Officer not making Returns,; Penalty &pound; 500.</head>
			<para id="p5">And it is further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Sheriffe or other Officer or Officers aforesaid
who shall not make the Returns according to the true Intent and Meaning of this Act shall forfeite for every
such Offence the Sum of Five hundred Pounds One Moiety whereof shall be to His Majesty and the other Moiety
to him or them that shall sue for the same to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any
of His Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster wherein no Essoigne Protection Priviledge or Wager of Law
shall be allowed nor any more than one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


