<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46938" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act to enlarge the Trade to Russia. [Rot. Parl. 10 Gul. III. p. I. n. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Letters Patent, 6th Feb.; 1 
&amp; 2 Phil. &amp;Mar.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that the same were confirmed by Act of Parliament, 8 El. c. I. Private Act; Reasons for passing this Act; Subjects of this Country may, on Request, as herein mentioned, be admitted Members of the Russia Company</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas King Philip and Queene Mary by their Letters Patents dated at Westminster the Sixth Day of
February in the First and Second Yeares of their Reigne being willing to animate advance and further the
Persons in the said Letters Patents named in their good Purpose and profitable Adventure for the discovering
discrying and finding out Isles Lands and Territories unknowne lying to the Northward and by English Subjects
before then not commonly frequented by Sea as well for the Glory of God as for illustrating the Royall Dignity in
the Increase of the Revenues of the Crowne and the generall Wealth of this Realme and of the Subjects of the
same (as in the said Letters Patents is particularly expressed) did incorporate the said Persons by the Name of
Merchants Adventurers for the Discovery of Lands Territories Isles and Seigniories unknowne and not by the Seas
and Navigations before their said late Adventure or Enterprize by Sea or Navigation commonly frequented with
Power to make Statutes Acts and Ordinances for the good Government of the said Fellowship and alsoe to admitt
unto the said Fellowship Persons to be free of the same and that every Person or Persons soe to be admitted should
from the time of his or their Admittances be free of the said Fellowship and that the said Fellowship should have
and enjoy the sole Trade to all the main Lands Isles Ports Havens Creeks and Rivers of the Emperor of Russia and
to all and singular other Lands Dominions Territories Ports Creekes and Armes of the Sea whatsoever in the said
Letters Patents particularly mentioned and described as by the said Letters Patents (among other Things therein
contained) more at large may and doth appeare And whereas the Liberties Powers and Priviledges granted by the
said Letters Patents were afterwards by an Act of Parliament made in the Eighth Yeare of the Reigne of Queen
Elizabeth ratified and confirmed to the said Fellowship and their Successors by the Name of the Fellowship of
English Merchants for Discovery of new Trades with Power to have and enjoy all and singular the Liberties Priviledges
Jurisdictions Powers and Authorities as well in the said Letters Patents as Act of Parliament mentioned or contained
with a Prohibition that no Subject or Denizon of this Realme should traffick to visitt or frequent any of the Places
granted by the said Act to the said Fellowship to trade in but by Order Agreement or Consent of the Governour
Consulls and Assistants of the said Fellowship for the time being or the major Part of them upon Paine that every
Person and Persons offending in that behalfe should forfeite and loose (ipso facto) every such Ship and Ships with
the Appurtenances and all such Goods and Things whatsoever as by any such Persons should be by any Meanes
directly or indirectly carried conducted brought or exchanged in at or to through or from any of the Places
prohibited contrary to the true Intent of the said Act One Moiety thereof to the Queens Majesty Her Heires and
Successors and the other Moiety thereof to the said Fellowship and their Successors as by the said Act of Parliament
(amongst other Things therein contained) more at large may and doth appeare And whereas the easie Admission
of Persons into the said Company or Fellowship will in all probability tend very much to the enlargeing the said
Trade for the publick Good and for that there is no mention made either in the said Letters Patents or Act of
Parliament upon what Termes Persons shall be admitted or what certaine Fine shall be taken by the said Fellowship
for the admitting Persons to be free thereof the ascertaining whereof would very much tend to the encreasing the
Number of Traders to the said Places therefore for the ascertaining hereafter what Fine shall be taken by the said
Fellowship for the said Admissions and for enlargeing and encourageing the Trade to Russia and other the Places
in the said Charter and Act of Parliament mentioned and described Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent
Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Commons in this
present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the Five and twentieth Day of
March which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety nine every Subject of this
Realme desireing Admission into the said Fellowship of English Merchants for Discovery of new Trades commonly
called or knowne by the Name of the Russia Company on Request in that Behalfe to be made to the Governour
Consuls and Assistants for the time being of the said Fellowship or any Three or more of them shall be admitted
into the said Fellowship and shall have use and enjoy all the Liberties Priviledges Jurisdictions Franchises Powers
and Authorities granted to the said Fellowship either by the said Letters Patents or Act of Parliament as largely
fully and amply to all Intents Constructions and Purposes as any other Member of the said Fellowship could can or
may have use or enjoy the same by virtue of the said Letters Patents and Act of Parliament or either of them
such Subject paying for such his Admission for the use of the said Fellowship only the Sum of Five Pounds and
no more</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. &pound;5 and no more to be taken for Admission.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Five and twentieth Day of
March the Sum of Five Pounds only and no more shall be demanded taken or accepted by the said Fellowship
for any Admission to the Freedom thereof Any By-Law Statute or Ordinance of the said Fellowship made or to
be made to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Within Ten Days after Request and Tender of &pound;5 Company to admit;</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">and to administer the Oath taken by Members</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That where any Person or Persons residing in any Out-port
or any other Place within this Realme the Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed shall make Request
to be admitted into the said Fellowship as aforesaid by his Agent or Deputy making Tender of Five Pounds for his
Admission the said Governour Consuls and Assistants shall under the Common Seale of the said Fellowship within
Ten Daies after such Request appoint one or more Person or Persons to admitt such Person or Persons into the
Freedome of the said Fellowship and to administer to him and them the Oath to be taken by the Freemen of the
said Fellowship which Oath they are hereby impowered to administer which Admission and Administration of the said
Oath shall be as good and effectuall as if the same were actually done by the said Governour Consulls and
Assistants</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV.</head>
			<para id="p6">(<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Commissioners of His Majesties Customs shall at
every Session of Parliament lay before both Houses a true Account in Writing under their Hands of what Navall
Stores shall have been imported into this Kingdome by any Persons trading [to <ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Russia.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">into <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


