<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46936" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IV. An Act to prohibit the excessive distilling of Spirits and Low Wines from Corne and against the Exporting of Beer and Ale and to prevent Frauds in Distillers. [Rot. Parl. 10 Gul. III. p.1. n.4]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Unduly making Aqua Vit&aelig;, &amp;c; Penalty;; and Stills, &amp;c. forfeited; How Penalties divided and recovered</emph>.
<emph type="i">Servants, &amp;c. aiding,; Imprisonment</emph>.
</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas it is found by Experience that the drawing distilling and makeing of Brandies or Spiritts from
Malt is one Cause of the present dearnesse of Corne especially of Barley in this Realme and by reason of
the great Scarcity of Corne in Forreigne Parts and the Restraints which are or may be made there of distilling
Spiritts from Corne great Demands are and may be made of Spiritts drawne from malted Corne in this Kingdom
to supply the occasions of those Forreigne Parts which must needs tend to a further enhanceing of the Price of
Corne here and prove a great Grievance to many His Majesties good Subjects if a speedy Remedy be not provided
be it therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same
That no Person or Persons whatsoever from and after the last Day of January in the Yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred ninety eight and before the First Day of February which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred ninety nine shall directly or indirectly draw distill or make or cause or procure to be
drawne distilled or made within the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed
any Brandy Aqua Vit&aelig; Spiritts or Low Wines whatsoever other than such Quantities as are allowed by this Act
and under such Restrictions and in such Manner and Forme as are herein prescribed from any Malt Corne or
Graine or from any Wash or Liquors produced or to be produced from any Malt Corne or Graine whatsoever
under the Penalties and Forfeitures herein after mentioned (that is to say) That all the Brandy Aqua Vit&aelig; Spiritts
and Low Wines soe made or drawne shall be forfeited and that every Offender and Offenders therein shall forfeite
and pay the Sum of Ten Shillings for every Gallon of Brandy Aqua Vit&aelig; Spiritts or Low Wines which shall be
drawne distilled or made contrary to this Act and moreover that all the Stills Backs Casks and other Utensills and
Vessells imployed in the distilling drawing makeing or keeping the same or any part thereof shall be forfeited the
moiety of all which Penalties and Forfeitures shall be to the Kings Majesty His Heires and Successors and the
other moiety to him or them that shall discover informe or sue for the same and the said Penalties and Forfeitures
shall and may be recovered in the same Manner and by the same Meanes as any Penalties and Forfeitures by any
of the Laws and Statutes for the Excise now in force for any Offence or Offences against the same are or may
be recovered and that all Servants and others who shall be wittingly or willingly aiding or assisting in the makeing
of the said Spiritts or Low Wines contrary to this Act and being thereof duely convicted in any of His Majesties
Courts of Record at Westminster or at the Generall Quarter Sessions of the County City Rideing or Place where
such Offence shall be committed or where such Person or Persons shall be apprehended or arrested for such
Offence shall suffer Imprisonment by the space of Six Months without Bail or Mainprize.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for using Yeast in certain Distillations.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwaies That it shall and may be lawful for any Person or Persons drawing Spiritts Brandy or Low
Wines from any Forreigne Materialls or any English Materialls other than such as are prohibited by this Act to
make use of a reasonable Quantity of Yeast for the Fermentation of their Wash in order to the distilling of the
same Any thing in this or any other Act to the contrary (
<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Recital of Inconveniences arising from the Use of Private Stills, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Distillers keeping private Conveyances, before 28th Feb. 1698, to take up and demolish the same, &amp;c; Distiller, after 28th Feb. 1698, keeping private Conveyance,; Penalty &pound; 100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And whereas it is found by experience That His Majesty hath been very much defrauded of His Duties upon
Low Wines and Spiritts by many Distillers and other Persons who keepe or sett up private and concealed Warehouses
Storehouses Cellars or other Places or private or concealed Stills Backs or other Vessells for the makeing preparing
or keeping Wash Low Wines Spiritts or other Materialls fitt for Distillation and by Private Pipes and Stopcocks
and other Private Conveyances have Communication betweene their Private and Publick Backs and other Vessells
by which they doe privately convey their Wash or other Liquors fitt for Distillation from one Back or other Vessell
to another by meanes whereof the Officers cannot take and keepe a true and distinct Account of such Wash and
other Liquors fitt for Distillation nor of the Low Wines and Spiritts made or drawne from the same And whereas
the Gaugers and Officers of Excise are not sufficiently impowered by Law upon Suspicion or Knowledge of such
Frauds to enter the Houses or Places where the same are practised without Consent of the Possessors thereof or
upon Entry and Discovery of such Frauds cannot find out or discover the Person or Persons concerned therein
by reason that the true Owner or Owners of such Warehouses Storehouses Cellars or other Places Stills Backs
or other Vessells Spiritts Low Wines Wash or other Materialls fitt for Distillation will not appeare or Claime
any Interest therein but frequently disowne the same Be it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid That
every Distiller having and keeping any Private Pipe or Stopcock or other Private Conveyance by which any Wash
or other Liquors fitt for Distillation may be conveyed from one Back or Vessell to another or from any such
Back or other Vessell to their Still or Stills or into any other Place shall before the Eight and twentieth day of
February One thousand six hundred ninety eight take up or demolish every such Pipe Stopcock or other Private
Conveyance and shall alsoe stop up every Hole in every such Back or Washbatch by which any Wash or other
Liquors fitt for Distillation may be conveyed into or out of such Back or Washbatch or any of them and that
no Distiller from and after the said Eight and twentieth Day of February shall have or keepe any Private Pipe
Stopcock or other Private Conveyance by which any Wash or other Liquors fitt for Distillation may be conveyed
from one Back or other Vessell to another or from any such Back or other Vessell to his or her Still or Stills or
into any other Place nor shall have or keepe any Hole in any such Back or Washbatch by which any Wash or
any other Liquors fitt for Distillation may be conveyed into or out of such Back or Washbatch or any of them
on Paine to forfeite for every such Pipe Stopcock Conveyance and Hole the Sum of One hundred [Pounds<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Officer, in the Day-time, and with Constable, may search for private Pipes, &amp;c. and may break up Ground, &amp;c. of any House, &amp;c. into which the same may lead, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p6">And for the better discovering of all such Pipes Stopcocks and other Private Conveyances aforesaid Be it further
enacted That from and after the said Eight and twentieth Day of February it shall and may be lawfull to and
for the Gaugers and Officers of Excise or any of them in the Day time and in the Presence of a Constable or
other lawfull Officer for the Peace (who are hereby required to be aiding and assisting therein) on Request first
made and Cause declared to breake up the Ground in any Distilling House or the Ground near adjoyning or any
Wall Partition or other Place to search for any such Pipe Stopcock or any other private Conveyance and upon
finding such Pipe or other Conveyance to breake up the Ground House Wall or other Partition or Place through
or into which any such Pipe or other Conveyance shall lead and to breake up or cutt any such Pipe or other
Conveyance and to turne any Cock or Cocks to try and examine whether such Pipe or other Conveyance may or
can convey any Wash or other Liquors fitt for Distillation out of one Back or Vessell into another or from any
such Back or Vessell into any Still or Stills or into any other Place.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. If no Pipe, &amp;c. found, Officer to make good the Ground, or make Satisfaction to Owner, to be adjudged by Two Justices, or Party may bring his Action; Damages paid out of Excise Revenue Opposing Officer, Penalty &pound; 100</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwaies That in case upon such Search no such Pipe or other Private Conveyance shall be found
such Gaugers and Officers of Excise shall make good the Ground Wall House or other Place soe broken up as
aforesaid or make reasonable Satisfaction to the Owner or Owners thereof to be adjudged by Two of the next
Justices of the Peace whereof one to be of the Quorum or the Party injured shall be at liberty to bring his
Action for the Damages by him sustained and what shall be adjudged by the said Justices or recovered upon such
Action shall be paid out of His Majesties Revenue of Excise by the Commissioners thereof for the time being
and if any Distiller or any other Person or Persons whatsoever shall oppose obstruct or hinder any such Gauger
or Officer in the due Execution of the Powers hereby given and granted every such Distiller and other Person
shall forfeite and loose for every such Offence the Sum of One hundred Pounds</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Distiller may use Pipe, &amp;c. above Ground.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided neverthelesse and it is hereby declared That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Distiller to
keepe and make use of any Pipe Stopcock or other Conveyance above Ground which are Publick and in open
View from one End thereof to the other for the letting his Wash out of his Publick Coolers into his Publick
Backs or Washbatches and for conveying his Wash or Worts out of such Publick Back or Washbatch into his
Publick Stills Any thing in this Act or any other Law or Statute to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Officer suspecting concealed Stills, &amp;c. on Affidavit thereof,</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">may in the Day-time, and with Constable, &amp;c. break open Doors and search;; and seize such Stills, &amp;c; And if the same not claimed within 20 Days, then forfeited, and may be sold; How Proceeds of Sale disposed of; If such Stills, &amp;c. claimed, then Claimant to pay Penalty of &pound;200</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in case the Gaugers or Officers of Excise or any
of them shall know or have cause to suspect any such Private or concealed Still Back or other Vessell Spiritts
Low Wines Wash or other Materialls preparing for Distillation to be sett up or kept in any House or Place and
shall make Affidavit before one or more Justice or Justices of the Peace for the County or Place where he shall
soe know or suspect such Private or concealed Still Back or other Vessell Spiritts Low Wines or Materialls preparing
for Distillation are or shall be soe sett up or kept and shall in such Affidavit declare the Grounds of such his
Knowledge or Suspition then and in such case it shall and may be lawfull for such Officer or Officers in the
Day time and in the Presence of a Constable or other lawfull Officer of the Peace (who are hereby required to
be aiding and assisting therein) by Warrant from such Justice or Justices of the Peace before whom such Affidavit
shall be made to be directed to such Officer or Officers of Excise (which Warrant the said Justice or Justices of
the Peace are hereby authorized and required to grant) to breake open the Door or any Part of such House or
Place where he or they shall soe know or suspect such Private or concealed Still Back or Vessell Spiritts Low
Wines or Materialls for Distillation are soe sett up or kept and to enter into such House or Place and to seize
all such Stills Backs or other Vessells and also all such Spiritts Low Wines Wash or other Materialls for
Distillation that shall be found therein and to detaine and keepe the same in such House or other Place where
he or they shall find the same soe kept private or concealed and in case the same shall not within Twenty Daies
next after such Seizure be claimed by the true and lawfull Owner thereof then the said Stills Backs and other
Vessells Spiritts Low Wines and Materialls for Distillation shall be absolutely forfeited and shall and may be sold
at the next generall Day of Sale to be appointed by the Commissioners of Excise or their Officer or Officers
respectively after the said Twenty Daies are expired one Moiety of the Proceed thereof (all necessary Charges being
first deducted out of the whole) to be paid to the Use of His Majesty His Heires and Successors and the other
Moiety to the Party or Parties who shall soe discover and seize the same and in case such Stills Backs and other
Vessells Spiritts Low Wines and Materialls for Distillations shall within the said Twenty Daies be claimed by any
Person or Persons whatsoever the Person or Persons soe claiming the same shall forfeite and loose for every such
Warehouse Storehouse or other Place in which any such Still Back or other Vessell shall be found and alsoe for
every such Still Back and other Vessell found therein the Sum of Two hundred Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. If no Still, &amp;c. found, then Officer to make good Place broken up, or make Satisfaction to Owner, to be adjudged by Two Justices, or Party may bring his Action;
Damages paid out of Revenue of Excise; Opposing Officer; Penalty &pound; 200.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwaies That in case upon such breaking open any such Door or House no such Private or concealed
Back Still or other Vessell Spiritts Low Wines Wash or other Materialls for Distillation shall be found such
Gauger and Officers of Excize shall make good the House or Place soe broken up as aforesaid or make reasonable
Satisfaction to the Owner or Owners thereof to be adjudged by Two of the next Justices of the Peace whereof
one to be of the Quorum or the Party injured shall be at liberty to bring his Action for the Damages by him
sustained and what shall be adjudged by the said Justices or recovered upon such Action shall be paid out of
His Majesties Revenue of Excise by the Commissioners thereof for the time being and if any Distiller or any
other Person or Persons whatsoever shall oppose obstruct or hinder any such Gauger or Officer soe authorized as
aforesaid in the due execution of the Powers hereby given and granted every such Distiller or other Person shall
forfeite and loose the Sum of Two hundred Pounds all which said Penalties shall be recovered and levied by
the same Meanes and Methods as any Fine or Penalty imposed by any Law of Excise now in force is recoverable
One Moiety of which said Forfeitures shall be to His Majesty His Heires and Successors and the other Moiety
to him or them that will discover informe or sue for the same as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. How Spirits made from Mixture of Spirits with Wash, &amp;c. except with Water, chargeable.</head>
			<para id="p12">And whereas many Distillers on pretence of rectifying of Spiritts doe mix Spiritts with Wash and other Liquors
and afterwards distill the same whereby His Majesties Duties on Low Wines are avoided and not duely answered
and paid as by the former Acts is directed and appointed for Prevention whereof be it enacted and declared by
the Authority aforesaid That all Spiritts made or drawne by any Distiller from any Mixture of Spiritts with any
kind of Wash or other Liquor (except common Water) shall be deemed and taken to be Low Wines and shall
be chargeable with the Duties already sett and imposed on Low Wines drawne from Forreigne Materialls.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. The Owners of Houses, &amp;c. used as open Distilleries, as herein described, may, between 31 Jan. 1698 and 1st Feb. 1699, distil Spirits or Low Wines, as herein mentioned,;
so as the Whole does not exceed the Quantity herein mentioned
</head>
<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Controversy respecting the Quantity to be determined by Accounts and Vouchers returned into the Head-Office of Excise of the Year already ended; Access gratis to such Accounts</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in such House and Houses and other
Edifices which were used as publick or open Distilleries for the drawing or distilling of Spiritts or Low Wines
from Wort or Drink brewed from malted Corne during the Yeare ended on the Thirtieth Day of September One
thousand six hundred ninety and eight or during any part thereof (and in no other House or Place whatsoever)
it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Owners and Occupiers of the said Houses and Distilleries respectively
at any time or times betweene the last Day of January One thousand six hundred ninety and eight and the First
Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety and nine to draw distill and make or cause to be drawne
distilled and made any Spiritts or Low Wines from Drink or Wort brewed from malted Corne soe as the whole
Quantity of Low Wines or Spiritts of the first Extraction which betweene the said last Day of January One thousand
six hundred ninety and eight and the said First Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety and nine shall
be drawne distilled or made in every such Distillery respectively from any Malt Corne or Graine or from the
Produce thereof doe not in the whole exceede halfe the Quantity of Low Wines or Spiritts of the first Extraction
which in the Yeare already ended as aforesaid were drawne distilled or made within the same House or Distillery
respectively from Drink or Wort brewed with malted Corne and soe as the Quantity of Low Wines or Spiritts of
the first Extraction which in the First Second Third and every other Kalendary Month of the Yeare reckoned from
the said last Day of January One thousand six hundred ninety and eight shall be drawne distilled or made in
every such Distillery respectively from Malt Corne or Graine or from the Produce thereof doe not exceed halfe the
Quantity of Low Wines or Spiritts of the first Extractions which in the like First Second Third and every other
Calendary Month of the Yeare ended as aforesaid were drawne distilled or made within the same House or Distillery
respectively from Drink or Wort brewed with Malted Corne And in Case any Doubt or Controversy shall arise
concerning the Quantity of Spiritts or Low Wines which were drawne or distilled in any House or Distillery within
or during the said Yeare ended on the said Thirtieth Day of September One thousand six hundred ninety and eight
or any Month of the same from Drink or Worts brewed from malted Corne or concerning the exceeding of halfe
that Quantity or Proportion in the Yeare to be reckoned from the said last Day of January One thousand six
hundred ninety and eight or in any Month thereof then the same shall be determined by the Accounts or Vouchers
returned into the Head Office of the Excise containing the Quantities of such Low Wines or Spiritts of the first
Extraction made in every such House or Distillery within or during the Yeare already ended as aforesaid whereby
His Majesties Duties were charged or chargeable or by the Entries of the same to which all Persons concerned
(upon reasonable Request) shall have free accesse without Fee or Charge Any thing herein contained to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Commissioners of Excise to give to Owners a true Account in Writing of Quantities charged in such Vouchers, ending 30th Sept. 1698.</head>
			<para id="p15">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Commissioners of the Excise or any Three or more of
them upon Request to them made shall make forth and deliver in Writing under their Hands gratis to the Owners
or Occupiers aforesaid or such as they shall appoint a true Account of the Quantities of Low Wines or Spiritts
of the first Extraction charged in the said Vouchers as were made in every respective Distillery in each respective
Month of the Yeare ended at the Thirtieth Day of September One thousand six hundred ninety and eight as
aforesaid from Drink or Worts brewed with malted Corne.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Exporting or Lading for Exportation Beer, Ale, Wash, &amp;c.;</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p17">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no Person or Persons whatsoever from and after the
last Day of February in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety [and <ref idref="n3">3</ref>] eight and before the
First Day of February which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and nine shall
directly or indirectly export transport carry out convey or cause or procure to be exported or transported carried or
conveyed out of or from the said Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed
or any of them or load or lay on board or cause or procure to be loaden or laid on board in any Ship Vessell
or Boat in order to be exported or carried out of the Kingdom Dominion or Towne aforesaid for any Forreigne
Parts any Beere Ale or any Wash or Worts drawne from Corne or any Ale or Beere from which Spiritts may
be extracted under the Pains and Forfeitures herein after mentioned that is to say For every Barrell of Beere
Ale Wash or Worts soe exported the Sum of Five Pounds and soe in proportion for any greater or lesser Quantity
One Moiety thereof to His Majesty and the other Moiety to the Informer to be recovered as other Penalties by this
Act are directed to be recovered</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for Exportation of Beer and Ale for Ships' Crews and Passengers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p18">Provided alwaies That this Act or any thing therein contained shall not extend to prohibite the Exportation
or carrying out of such Beere or Ale as shall be necessary to be carried in any Ship or other Vessell or Vessells
from this Kingdom or the Dominion aforesaid or in their Returne to the same only for the Sustenance or Drink
of the Commanders Masters Marriners Passengers or others in the same Ships and not to be sold in Forreigne
Parts or for the Supply of any of His Majesties Ships in Forreigne Parts Any thing in this Act to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. And to Colonies, Forts, &amp;c. in America, Persia, and East Indies, for their Sustentation, &amp;c.;
on Security by Exporter for the due Landing thereof.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Such Security to be taken without Fee.</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">Provided alsoe That nothing in this Act contained shall extend to any Beere or Ale which shall be exported
or shipt to be exported out or from any of the Ports of this Kingdom or Dominion of Wales unto such of His
Majesties Colonies in America Persia or the East-Indies that have been usually supplyed with such Liquors from
this Kingdom or from the Dominion of Wales aforesaid or for the Sustentation of the said Islands and Colonies
Forts Castles or Factories therein only soe as the Exporters before the shipping or laying on board the same for
the Islands or Colonies for which the said Liquor is designed doe give sufficient Security in Treble the Value to
the Commissioners or Officers of His Majesties Customs respectively who have hereby Power to take such Security
in His Majesties Name and to His Majesties Use that such Liquors shall not be landed in any Parts whatsoever
other than the Islands and Colonies for which the same shall be soe declared for takeing which Security no
Fee or Reward shall be demanded or received And the said Bond or Bonds or other Securities if not prosecuted
within Three Years shall be void</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Proviso in favour of Charles Bennett.</head>
			<para id="p21">(<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) Provided alwaies That nothing in this Act contained shall extend to prevent or hinder Charles Bennett Distiller
from drawing or distilling Spiritts or Low Wines from Worts or Drink brewed from malted Corne from the last
Day of January One thousand six hundred ninety eight to the First Day of February One thousand six hundred
ninety nine alwaies soe as the whole Quantity of Low Wines or Spiritts of the first Extraction which betweene the
said last Day of January One thousand six hundred ninety eight and the said First Day of February One thousand
six hundred ninety nine shall be drawne distilled or made in his now Distillary from any Malt Corne or Graine
or from the Produce thereof doe not in the whole exceed halfe the Quantity of Low Wines or Spiritts of the
first Extraction by him drawne and extracted in the Yeare already ended on the Thirtieth of September One thousand
six hundred ninety eight and soe as the said Charles Bennett doth observe and performe in all things else as all
other Distillers are by this Act obliged to observe and performe.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


