<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46933" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for granting an Aid to His Majesty for disbanding the Army and other necessary Occasions. [Rot. Parl. 10 Gul. III. p. 1. n.1].</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">On or before the 26th March 1699 the Army to be disbanded as herein mentioned; Exception</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That
the Army and all the respective Regiments Troops Companies Officers and Souldiers of the said Army within the
Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed shall on or before the Six and
twentieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety nine be disbanded except such Regiments Troops and
Companies consisting only of His Majesties naturall born Subjects not exceeding Seaven thousand Persons Commission
and Non commission Officers included as before the First Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety eight
shall be particularly expressed in and by His Majesties Royall Proclamation under the Great Seale of England in
which Proclamation the particular Number only of each Regiment Troope and Company shall be expressed.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The said Army disbanded.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further enacted and declared That immediately from and after the said Six and twentieth Day of
March One thousand six hundred ninety nine the said Army Regiments Troops and Companies (except as before
is excepted) is and are hereby actually disbanded.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Regiments, &amp;c. in Ireland, not being natural born Subjects, disbanded.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That immediately from and after the said Six and twentieth
Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety nine all the Regiments Troops and Companies Officers and
Souldiers within the Kingdom of Ireland not being His Majesties naturall born Subjects be and are hereby enacted
and declared to be actually disbanded.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The like as to other Regiments, except as to 12,000 Soldiers natural born Subjects expressed in Proclamation.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further enacted That all other the Army Regiments Troops Companies Officers and Souldiers within
the said Kingdom of Ireland shall on or before the First Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine be
disbanded except such Regiments Troops and Companies consisting only of His Majesties naturall born Subjects
not exceeding Twelve thousand Persons Commission and Non commission Officers included as before the Tenth
Day of Aprill One thousand six hundred ninety nine shall be particularly expressed in and by His Majesties
Royall Proclamation under the Great Seale of Ireland in which Proclamation the particular Number only of each
Regiment Troop and Company shall be expressed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. The said Army disbanded.</head>
			<para id="p6">And be it further enacted and declared That immediately from and after the said First Day of May One
thousand six hundred ninety nine the said Army Regiments Troops and Companies in Ireland (except as before
is excepted) is and are hereby actually disbanded.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Forces in Ireland not disbanded, maintained at the Charge of Ireland.</head>
			<para id="p7">And be it further enacted and declared That all such Forces within the said Kingdom of Ireland not hereby
directed to be disbanded which shall be maintained within that Kingdom shall be maintained at the sole Charge
of the said Kingdom of Ireland</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Disbanded Officers exercising Authority, and Persons aiding the keeping together of disbanded Regiments,; Premunire, and disabled to sue.</head>
			<para id="p8">And be it further enacted That all and every Commission Officer and Officers who shall exercize any Power
or Authority over the Souldiers in their respective Regiments Troops or Companies after such Officer or Officers
shall be disbanded and every Person or Persons that shall wittingly and willingly advise frame contrive countersigne
or putt in Execution any Proclamation Commission Act Order or Command whatsoever for continueing together
any of the said Regiments Troops or Companies or parts of Regiments Troops or Companies after they shall be
disbanded as aforesaid he or they soe offending shall incurr and sustaine the Pains Penalties and Forfeitures limitted
ordained and provided in and by the Statute of Provision and Premunire made in the Sixteenth Yeare of King
Richard the Second and being thereof lawfully convicted shall from thenceforth be disabled during his Life to
sue or implead any Person in any Action reall or personall in his owne Right or to make any Guift Grant
Conveyance or other Disposition of any his Lands Tenements Goods or Chattells which he hath to his owne Use
either by Act executed in his life time or by his last Will or otherwise or to take any Guift Conveyance or
Legacy to his own use And none of the said Souldiers or Non commissioned Officers disbanded as aforesaid shall
after the space of Two Daies after such disbanding continue together above Ten in a Company.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Loan for &pound;800,000; Interest at &pound;7 per Cent. per Ann; Repayment out of First Supplies of the present Session</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p10">And for the Payment of the severall Regiments Troops and Companies in England hereby declared and appointed
to be disbanded and for supplying other necessary Occasions of the Kingdom and alsoe for the Payment of the
Arreares due to the Forces in Ireland hereby appointed to be disbanded during their Continuance upon the English
Establishment Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any
Person or Persons Natives or Forreigners Bodies Politick or Corporate to advance and lend to His Majesty at the
Receipt of His Majesties Exchequer any Sum or Sums of Money not exceeding the Sum of Eight hundred thousand
Pounds which Sum and Sums soe to be advanced and lent shall and may be charged upon the Creditt of His
Majesties Exchequer in Generall and Tallies of Loane and Orders for Repayment of the same shall be levied
accordingly of which said Sum of Eight hundred thousand Pounds soe much shall in the first place be applyed
for the paying off and disbanding the Regiments Troops and Companies within this Kingdom hereby enacted to
be disbanded as shall be sufficient for that Service and the Overplus shall be afterwards applyed for other necessary
Occasions of the Kingdom And all and every Sum and Sums of Money soe to be advanced and lent not exceeding
the said Sum of Eight hundred thousand Pounds together with Interest for the same not exceeding the Rate of
Seaven Pounds per Centum per Annum to be paid every Three Months untill Satisfaction of the Principall shall
be payable and be paid or satisfied in course according to the Daies or Times of lending the same unto the
respective Lender or Lenders of the same his her or their Executors Administrators Successors or Assignes out of
the first Aids or Supplies granted or to be granted to His Majesty in this present Session of Parliament and shall
immediately be transferred unto such Aid or Supply Any thing in this present Act or any other Acts or Acts of
Parliament contained to the contrary notwishstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Naturalized Persons not considered as natural-born Subjects, for the Purposes of this Act.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no Alien who hath been or at any time
shall be naturalized within the Kingdom of Ireland by virtue of any Act of Parliament made or to be made within
that Kingdom or by reason of any Act or Thing done or to be done in pursuance thereof shall be adjudged or
reputed to be His Majesties naturall born Subject within the meaning of this Act nor shall any such Person soe
naturalized or to be naturalized be capable of being continued within any Regiment Troop or Company which
shall be excepted by either of His Majesties said Proclamations.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Proviso for disbanded Troops. already embarked.</head>
			<para id="p12">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in case any Regiments Troops or Companies
or parts of Regiments Troops or Companies which are to be disbanded or discharged from His Majesties Service
by virtue of this Act shall be embarked or ready to be embarked to be transported beyond the Seas and shall be
hindred by contrary winds or weather beyond the said Six and twentieth Day of March no Person or Persons shall
incurr the said Pains and Penalties by this Act ordained for such their Continuance together during such hindrance
as aforesaid Any thing herein to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


