<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46942" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for laying further Duties upon Sweets and for lessening the Duties aswell upon Vineger as upon certaine Low Wines and Whalefins and the Duties upon Brandy imported and for the more easie raising the Duties upon Leather and for charging Cynders and for permitting the Importation of Pearl Ashes and for preventing Abuses in the brewing of Beere and Ale and Frauds in Importation of Tobacco. [Chapter X. 	Rot. Parl. 10 Gul. III. p.3. n.I.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Additional Duties upon Sweets. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>)</head>
		<para id="p1">We Your Majesties most dutifull and loyall Subjects the Commons of England in Parliament assembled as a
further Supply for Your Majesties necessary Occasions have given and granted unto Your Majesty the Rates
and Duties herein after mentioned and do humbly beseech Your Majesty that it may be enacted and be it enacted
by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall
and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That there shall be raised
levied collected and paid to and for the use of Your Majesty Your Heires and Successors for and upon all
Sweets made or to be made within the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon
Tweed for Sale (over and above all former Duties already granted upon Sweets and which are to continue during
the respective Termes granted in the same) the Rates and Duties following (that is to say)</para>
		<para id="p2">For every Barrell of Sweets made for Sale after the Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine
and before the Twentieth Day of July One thousand six hundred ninety nine the Sum of Twelve Shillings</para>
		<para id="p3">For every Barrell of Sweets made for Sale after the Nineteenth Day of July One thousand six hundred ninety
nine and before the Twenty fifth Day of March One thousand seaven hundred and one the Sum of Twenty four
Shillings</para>
		<para id="p4">And for every Barrell of Sweets made for the Sale from and after the Twenty fourth Day of March One thousand
seaven hundred and before the Five and twentieth Day of March which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One
thousand seaven hundred and six the Sum of Six and thirty Shillings the said Duties to be paid by the Maker
and Makers of the said Sweets and so in Proportion for greater or lesser Quantities</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. What Liquors deemed Sweets.</head>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">How Duties upon Sweets by former Acts chargeable; What Persons deemed Makers of Sweets</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">And it is hereby declared That all Liquors made by Infusion Fermentation or otherwise from Forreigne Fruit
or Sugar or from Fruit or Sugar mixt with other Materialls and commonly made use of for recovering increasing
or makeing of any kinds of Wine or Cyder or of any Liquor called Wine shall be deemed to be Sweets within
the meaning of this and all former Acts for laying Duties on Sweets And that the respective Duties imposed on
Sweets by every of the said former Acts are chargeable by the Barrell and so in proportion for any greater or
lesser Quantity And that any Person who is a Retailer of or shall at any time sell or make use of any the
Liquors aforesaid for any the Purposes before mentioned and in whose Custody any Quantity of such Sweets
exceeding Two Gallons shall be found shall be deemed and taken to be a Maker of Sweets for Sale within the
meaning of this and the said former Acts</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Refiners of Sugar, before 1st June 1699, entering into Bond, not chargeable with the Duties of this Act upon Sweets made from Sugar and Syrups, until they shall have sold the same.</head>
		<para id="p7">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Refiners of Sugar who shall before
the First day of June One thousand six hundred ninety nine enter into a Bond or Bonds to His Majesty of the
penall Sum of Five hundred Pounds upon Condition that he or they shall not sell deliver out or dispose of any
Sweets or Liquors commonly called Syrrups made from Sugar (except Mellassuses) or make use of the same in
makeing or increasing or improving any Wine Cyder or Perry or any Liquor called Wine shall not be chargeable
with the Duties of Sweets or Syrrups hereby imposed which he or they shall make from Sugar untill he or they
shall so sell dispose or make use of such Sweets or Liquors made from Sugar</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. How the said Duties on Sweets appropriated.</head>
		<para id="p8">And it is enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Duties on Sweets hereby granted shall be applyed and
are hereby appropriated for the same Uses and Purposes to which part of the present Duties on Sweets with all
the Duties on Malt, are appropriated by an Act of Parliament made in the Eighth Yeare of His Majesties
Reigne</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. Recital of the Inconveniences arising from the high Duties of former Acts upon Rape Vinegar.</head>
		<para id="p9">
			<emph type="i">
 From the 10th May 1699
the Duties herein mentioned to cease</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p10">And whereas by virtue of severall Acts of Parliament now in force there are severall different Rates and
Duties imposed on Vinegar [Vineger<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Beer or Liquors prepared for Vinegar made within this Kingdom for Sale
by which meanes the same Liquor is twice charged in different Operations and it is found by Experience that
Vinegar made by passing through Rape is much better for any use at home and fitter for Exportation than any
other sort of English Vinegar and that the high Duties chargeable on Rape Vineger by the former Acts are so
great a Discouragement to the Makers thereof that little or none is made whereby His Majesty is defeated of
the said High Duties and the Nation deprived of a good and sound Commodity Be it therefore enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That from and after the Tenth day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine all the
Duties on Vineger Vineger Beer and Liquors preparing for Vineger which might be chargeable after the said
Tenth day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine by virtue of the said former Acts or any of them shall
cease and determine</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. Duty upon Vinegar, &amp;c. paid by the Maker.</head>
		<para id="p11">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Tenth Day of May One
thousand six hundred ninety nine there shall be raised levied collected and paid for and upon every Barrell of
Vineger Vineger Beer or Liquors preparing for Vineger which shall be brewed or made of any English or Forreigne
Materialls by any Person or Persons whatsoever for Sale and so in Proportion for a greater or lesser Quantity the
Sum of Eight Shillings to be paid by the Maker thereof in the Manner hereafter in this Act expressed</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. For what Terms the Duties on Vinegar, &amp;c. to be paid.</head>
		<para id="p12">
			<emph type="i">How the same applied; 6d. per Barrel,Part thereof, to His Majesty for Life, in lieu of the like Duty of 2 W. &amp; M. c.3; 6d. per Barrel, other Part thereof, to His Majesty and His Successors, in lieu of the like Duty of 12 Car, II, c. 24, 2s, 4d other Part thereof, to His Majesty and His Successors, for the Remainder of a Term of 99 Years, commencing 28th Jan, 1692, in lieu of certain Duties of 4 W. &amp; M. c. 3; 2s. 4d other Part thereof, to His Majesty and His Successors, for the Remainder of a Term of 16 Years, commencing 17th May 1697, in lieu of certain Duties of 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 7; 2s. 4d. Residue thereof, to His Majesty and His Successors, in lieu of certain Duties of 5&amp;6 W. &amp; M. c. 20</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p13">And it is hereby enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid That the Duties on Vineger Vineger Beer and
Liquors preparing for Vineger hereby granted shall be raised and paid during the respective Terms hereafter
mentioned and no longer And the Moneys thereby ariseing shall be paid applied and disposed to and for the
respective Uses and Purposes following that is to say Six Pence part of the said Duty of Eight Shillings for every
Barrell of Vineger Vineger Beere or Liquor preparing for Vineger shall be raised collected and paid to His Majesty
during his Life in lieu of the like Duty of Six Pence charged on every Barrell of Vineger Beer by an Act made in
the Second Yeare of the Reigne of His present Majesty and the late Queene intituled An Act for granting to Their
Majesties for their Lives and the Life of the Survivor of them certain Impositions upon Beer Ale and other Liquors
and shall be paid applyed and disposed of to and for the same Uses and Purposes as the Duties granted by the same
Act are directed to be applied and disposed of Six Pence more part of the said Eight Shillings to His Majesty His
Heires and Successors in lieu of the like Duty of Six Pence charged on every Barrell of Vineger Beer by an Act
made in the Twelfth Yeare of the Reigne of the late King Charles the Second intituled An Act for takeing away (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) the
Court of Wards and Liveries and Tenures in Capite and by Knights Service and Purveyance and for settling [of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] a
Revenue upon His Majesty in lieu thereof and shall be applied and disposed of to and for the same Uses and
Purposes as the Duties granted by the same Act are directed to be applied and disposed of Two Shillings and Four
Pence part of the said Eight Shillings to His Majesty His Heires and Successors during the Remainder of a Terme
of Ninety nine Yeares commencing from the Twenty eighth Day of January One thousand six hundred ninety two
in lieu of certaine Duties imposed on Vineger and Vineger Beere and Liquors prepared for Vineger by an Act made
in the Fourth Yeare of His present Majesty and the said late Queen intituled An Act for granting to Their Majesties
certaine Rates and Duties of Excise upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for securing certaine Recompences and
Advantages in the said Act mentioned to such Persons as shall voluntarily advance the Sum of Ten hundred
thousand Pounds towards carrying on the War against France and shall be applied and disposed of to and for the
same Uses and Purposes as the Duties granted by the same Act are directed to be applied and disposed of Two
Shillings and Four Pence part of the said Eight Shillings to His Majesty His Heires and Successors during the
Remainder of a Terme of Sixteene Yeares commenceing from the Seaventeenth Day of May One thousand six
hundred ninety seaven in lieu of certaine Duties imposed on Vineger Vineger Beer and Liquors prepared for Vineger
by an Act made in the Fifth and Sixth Yeares of the Reigne of His present Majesty and the said late Queen
intituled An Act for granting to Their Majesties certaine Rates and Duties upon Salt and upon Beer Ale and other
Liquors for securing certaine Recompences and Advantages in the said Act mentioned to such Persons as shall
voluntarily advance the Sum of Ten hundred thousand Pounds towards carrying on the War against France and
shall be applied and disposed of to and for the same Uses and Purposes as the Duties granted by the same Act
are directed to be applied and disposed of Two Shillings and Four Pence Residue of the said Eight Shillings to
His Majesty His Heires and Successors in lieu of certaine Duties imposed on Vineger Vineger Beere and Liquors
prepared for Vineger by another Act made in the same Yeares intituled An Act for granting to Their Majesties
certaine Rates and Duties upon Tunnage of Ships and Vessells and upon Beer Ale and other Liquors for securing
certaine Recompences and Advantages in the said Act mentioned to such Persons as shall voluntaryly advance the
Sum of Fifteene hundred thousand Pounds towards carrying on the War against France and shall be applied and
disposed of to and for the same Uses and Purposes as the Duties granted by the same Act are directed to be
applied and disposed of</para></section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. What Liquors deemed Vinegar, or Liquors preparing for Vinegar</head>
			<para id="p14">And for avoyding Disputes and Controversies which may arise touching Liquors preparing for Vinegar Be it
enacted and declared That all Stale Beer Returns of Beer or Ale Cyder Verjuice or any other Liquors proper to
be made into Vineger which at any time after the said Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine
shall be found in the Custody or Possession of any common Vinegar Maker (except such Beer Ale and other Liquors
as are to be drank in his Family and which shall be kept separate and apart for that Purpose) shall be deemed
and taken to be Vineger or Liquors preparing for Vineger within the Meaning of this Act</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. After 10th May 1699, Vinegar Maker receiving Stale Beer, &amp;c. or sending out Vinegar without Notice to Officer, as herein mentioned,</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;50</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Tenth Day of May One
thousand six hundred ninety nine no Vineger Maker shall receive into his Custody any Stale Beere Returns of
Beere of Ale Cyder Verjuice or other Liquors proper to be made into Vineger nor carry or deliver out any Vineger
in Casks or by the Gallon without Notice thereof first given to the Officer of Excise for the Place or Division
where such Maker shall inhabit to the Intent that such Officer may be present to see and take an Account of the
same unless at such times as hereinafter are mentioned That is to say From the Nine and twentieth Day of September
to the Five and twentieth Day of March yearly betweene the Houres of Seaven in the Morning and Five in the
Evening and from the said Five and twentieth Day of March to the Nine and twentieth Day of September yearly
betweene the Houres of Five in the Morning and Seaven in the Evening upon Paine that every Maker doing
contrary thereunto shall forfeite for every such Offence the Sum of Fifty Pounds</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Vinegar Maker receiving the said Liquors, to shew. same to Gauger before mixing with other Liquors. Penalty &pound;20.</head>
			<para id="p17">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Tenth Day of May One
thousand six hundred ninety nine every Vineger Maker receiving into his Custody any of the Liquors aforesaid shall
shew the same to the Gager of the Division where such Maker shall live before he mix the said Liquors soe
received or any Part thereof with any other Liquors Rape or other Materialls on Paine to forfeite for every such
Omission or Neglect the Sum of Twenty Pounds</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI.Vinegar Maker using Storehouse, &amp;c. without Notice to Officer of Excise,</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound; 50</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And be it. further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Vineger Maker shall at any time after the said
Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety and nine without first giveing Notice thereof at the next
Office of Excise make use of any Storehouse Warehouse Celler or other Place for [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] makeing laying or keeping
any Vineger Vineger Beere or Liquors preparing for Vineger every such Vineger Maker shall forfeite and loose for
every such private Storehouse Warehouse Celler and other Place so made use of without such Notice as aforesaid
the Sum of Fifty Pounds</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. How a Barrel of Vinegar to be accounted and returned.</head>
			<para id="p20">And whereas the Duties on Vinegers and Vineger Beer charged by the former Acts were computed by different
Measures whereby Disputes and Controversies have arisen touching the charging of the same For preventing whereof
for the future be it enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid That every Thirty and four Gallons taken by
the Gage according to the Standard of the Ale Quart (Four whereof shall be deemed a Gallon) remaining in the
Custody of the Chaimberlaines of His Majesties Exchequer from and after the said Tenth Day of May One thousand
six hundred ninety nine shall be reckoned accounted and returned by the Gager for a Barrell of Vineger Vineger
Beere or Liquor preparing for Vineger Any thing in the said former Acts or any of them or any other Law
Statute or Provision to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. How far Vinegar Makers having in Custody Vinegar, &amp;c. on the 10th May 1699, charged with former Duties are to be charged for the same.</head>
			<para id="p21">And whereas severall Makers of Vineger may have in their Custody severall Quantities of Vineger Beere or
Liquors preparing for Vineger on the said Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine for which
they may then stand charged with or have answered to His Majesty some of the Duties imposed by the former
Acts Be it enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid That every such Vineger Maker shall by virtue of
this Act be chargeable for such Vineger Beere or Liquors preparing for Vineger with so much only as shall
make the Duties charged thereon by virtue of the former Acts Eight Shillings for every Barrell thereof and no
more Any thing therein contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Recital of Improvement in distilling of Brandy; and 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 30. and of the Inconvenience 
and of the Inconvenience of the said Duties. 4d., Part of the said Duty of 8s. per Gallon of Low Wines, and a Moiety of the said Duty of 3d. per Gallon (Exception) to cease.</head>
			<para id="p22">And whereas it is found by Experience that the Art of distilling Spirits or Brandy in this Kingdom is of late
Yeares very much improved and that Spirits or Brandy made here from Mellasses and Sugar which are the Produce
of the English Plantations is near as good as Brandy imported from Forreigne Parts And whereas by an Act
made in the Seaventh Yeare of the Reigne of His present Majesty (intituled An Act for laying severall Duties
upon Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction and for preventing the Frauds and Abuses of Brewers Distillers
and other Persons chargeable with the Duties of Excise) there is a Duty of Eight Pence imposed upon every
Gallon of Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction made or drawne from any Forreigne or imported Materialls
or any mixture with Forreigne Materialls and a Duty of Three Pence upon every Gallon of Low Wines or
Spirits of the First Extraction made or drawne from any English Materialls other than Drink made or brewed
from malted Corn or from Brewers Wash or Tilts which said high Duties are a great Discouragement to the
makeing of the said Commodities and do occasion undue Practices in the same Be it therefore enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That from and after the Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine Four
Pence per Gallon part of the said Duty of Eight Pence imposed upon every Gallon of Low Wines and Spirits
of the First Extraction made or drawne from any Forreigne or imported Materialls or any Mixture with Forreigne
Materialls and one Moiety or halfe part of the said Duty of Three Pence upon every Gallon of Low Wines or
Spirits of the First Extraction made or drawne from any English Materialls (other than Drink made or brewed
from malted Corne or from Brewers Wash or Tilts) granted by the said former Act shall cease and determine
and be no longer payable to His Majesty His Heires or Successors in any manner of wise Any thing in the
said Act to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Proviso for Duties due before 10th May 1699, 
and for Clauses in the said Act, 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 30. respecting the Payment and Appropriation of the said Duties; and of the Duties not hereby determined.</head>
			<para id="p23">Provided alwaies and it is hereby enacted That this Act or any thing herein contained shall not extend to
take away lessen or make void the Payment of any Sum or Sums of Money accrewing or becomeing due to His
Majesty for any Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction actually made or drawne from any the Materialls
before mentioned before the said Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine and which shall be
then due and owing to His Majesty And that all and every the Clauses Matters and Things in the last mentioned
Act contained for chargeing securing raising levying or paying the whole Duties on the said Low Wines and
Spirits of the First Extraction which were thereby granted and for disposing applying and appropriating the same
to the Uses and Purposes therein mentioned shall be applyed practised and put in Execution for the charging
securing levying raising and paying the said remaining parts of the said Duties upon Low Wines or Spirits (not
hereby taken away) and for disposing applying and appropriating thereof to the same Uses and Purposes as fully
and effectually as if the said Clauses Matters and Things were for that purpose againe repeated and particulerly
re-enacted by this present Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Stat. 12 Car. II. c. 24. and other Acts to remain in force for levying the said Duties.</head>
			<para id="p24">And be further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all and every the Powers Authorities Directions Rules
Methods Penalties Forfeitures Clauses Matters and Things which in and by an Act of Parliament made in the
Twelfth Yeare of the Reigne of the late King Charles the Second intituled An Act for takeing away the Court
of Wards and Liveries and Tenures in Capite and by Knights Services and Purveyance and for settling a Revenue
upon His Majesty in lieu thereof or by any other Law now in force relating to His Majesties Revenue of Excise
upon Beere Ale and other Liquors are provided settled or established for raising levying collecting recovering
adjudging or ascertaining the Duties thereby granted or any of them (other than in such Cases for which other
Penalties or Provisions are made and prescribed by this Act) shall be exercised practiced applied used levied
recovered and put in Execution for the raising levying collecting recovering and paying as well the said Duties
upon Sweets as the said Duties upon Vineger Vineger Beer or Liquors preparing for Vineger and the severall
Duties upon Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction during the continuance of the same or any of them
as fully and effectually to all intents and purposes as if all and every the said Powers Authorities Rules Directions
Methods Penalties Forfeitures Clauses Matters and Things were particularly repeated and againe enacted in the
Body of this present Act</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. How Penalties of this Act recovered.</head>
			<para id="p25">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Fines Penalties and Forfeitures by this Act
imposed shall be sued for levied and recovered by such Waies Meanes and Methods as any Fine Forfeiture and
Penalty is or may be recovered by any Law or Laws of Excise or by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information
in any of His Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster And that one Moiety of every such Fine Penalty or
Forfeiture shall be to His Majesty His Heires and Successors and the other Moiety to him or them that shall
discover informe or sue for the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. In Actions for executing this Act, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">General Issue may be pleaded; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">Provided alwaies and be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Person or Persons shall
at any time be used or prosecuted for any thing by him or them done or executed in pursuance of this Act
or any other Act relating to His Majesties Revenue of Excise he or they shall and may plead the Generall Issue
and give this Act and the said respective Acts in Evidence for his or their Defence and if upon the Tryall a
Verdict shall pass for the Defendant or Defendants or the Plaintiff or Plaintiffs be nonsuited then such Defendant
or Defendants shall have Treble Costs to him or them awarded against such Plaintiff or Plaintiffs</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Officers of Excise to keep Accounts of Wash found with Distillers; and to make Charges upon Decrease thereof, as herein mentioned; Distillers to pay Duty according to such Charge</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">And whereas it is found by Experience that any Quantity of Wash made of Mellasses will upon Distillation
produce One Fourth Part of the same Quantity into Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction And that such
Low Wines or Spirits upon the Second Distillation will produce Two Third Parts of the Quantity of the same
Low Wines or Spirits into Proof-Spirits or Spirits of the Second Extraction And whereas many Distillers doe
hide and conceale great Quantities of such Low Wines and Spirits from the Sight and View of the Gager before
he can come to charge the same by meanes whereof His Majesty is very much defrauded in His Duties on such
Low Wines and Proof-Spirits Be it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said
Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Gagers
and Officers of Excise to keep an Account of all such Wash which shall from time to time be found by him
or them in the Hands of any Distiller and upon any Decrease thereof to charge such Distiller with so much
Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction as One Fourth Part of the Wash soe decreased shall amount unto
and alsoe with so much Proof-Spirits or Spirits of the Second Extraction as Two Third Parts of the Low
Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction soe charged as aforesaid shall amount unto And such Distiller shall
pay the respective Duties of the Low Wines and Spirits soe charged as by the former Act is directed and appointed
Any thing in the said Act or any other Statute to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Recital of c, 4. ante, &sect; 7.</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Penalty of &pound;200 upon Proprietors of Private Stills, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">And whereas by an Act next herein After recited it is enacted That upon the Discovery of any Private Still
Back or other Vessell according to the Directions of the said Act every such Still Back and other Vessell shall
be seized and that the Owner or Owners of every such Still Back and other Vessell who shall claime the same
within Twenty Daies after such Seizure shall forfeite and loose for every such Still Back and other Vessell the
Sum of Two hundred Pounds And whereas upon the Discovery of severall private Stills and Backs since the
Commencement of the said Act some Doubt hath been made whether the Owners of such Stills and Backs by
refuseing to claime the same within the time limitted by the said Act may not avoid the Penalties thereby imposed
Be it enacted That from and after the Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine the Proprietor of
any such private Still Back or other Vessell which shall be discovered according to the Directions of the said
Act or the Person in whose Custody the same shall be found shall forfeite and loose for every such Still Back
and other Vessell the said Penalty of Two hundred Pounds Any thing in the said Act or any other Law or Statute
to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Recital of c.4. ante, &sect;1.</head>
			<para id="p32">
				<emph type="i">Distiller abating Quantities of Low Wines which he might draw, equal to those he exceeded, as herein mentioned, not liable to Prosecution</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p33">And whereas by an Act made this present Session of Parliament intituled An Act to prohibit the excessive
distilling of Spirits and Low Wines from Corne and against the exporting of Beere and Ale and to prevent Frauds
in Distillers it is enacted That no Person whatsoever from and after the last Day of January in the Yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred ninety eight and before the first Day of February which shall be in the Yeare
of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety nine shall draw distill or make any Brandy Aqua Vit&aelig; Spirits or
Low Wines whatsoever other than such Quantities as are allowed by the said Act from any Malt Corne or Graine
whatsoever under the Penalties and Forfeitures therein mentioned And whereas severall Distillers of this Kingdom
their Servants and Agents had incurred the Penalties of the said Law without any knowledge thereof by distilling
in the Two Months betwixt the last of January. One thousand six hundred ninety eight and the first of Aprill One
thousand six hundred ninety nine greater Quantities of Spirits or Low Wines from Corne than the said Act doth
allow Be it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every such Distiller his Servant or Agent who in
the next succeeding Month or Months after the One and thirtieth Day of March One thousand six hundred ninety
nine shall abate of the Quantities of such Low Wines and Spirits which he might lawfully draw in the same so
much as he exceeded the Quantities allowed in the said Two Months shall not be prosecuted or have any Penalty
inflicted upon him for or on Account of such breach of the said Act in the said Two Months Any thing in the
said Act to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Recital of Stat. 8 W. III. c. 21;</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Two Justices may dertermine the Penalties of the said Act; who may issue their Warrant for levying the same, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">And whereas the pecuniary Penalties inflicted by an Act made in the Eighth Yeare of His Majesties Reigne for
laying severall Duties upon Leather for the terme of Three Yeares are directed to be sued for by Action of Debt
or on the Case or by Bill Suit or Information in some Court of Record whereby the Recovery of those Penalties
are not only tedious and chargeable but troublesome and vexatious by multitudes of popular Actions and Informations
brought by common Informers For the preventing whereof and more easie and speedy recovering the pecuniary
Penalties inflicted by the said Act be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the Tenth
Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Two or more of
the Justices of the Peace resideing neare to the Place where any such Forfeiture shall be made or Offence committed
to heare and determine the same who are hereby authorized and required upon any Information exhibited or
brought for any of the pecuniary Penalties by the said Act inflicted to summon the Party accused and alsoe the
Witnesses on either Side and upon the Appearance or Contempt of the Party accused in not appearing (upon Proofe
of Notice given) to proceed to the Examination of the Witnesses upon Oath (which Oath they are hereby impowered
to administer) and to give Judgement or Sentence accordingly and where the Party accused shall be convicted of the
Offence alledged against him to award and issue Warrants under their Hands for the levying of such Penalty or
Penalties on the Goods of the Offender and to cause Sale to be made thereof in case they shall not be redeemed
within Six Daies rendring to the Party the Overplus (if any be) And if either Party shall find himselfe agrieved
by the Judgment of the said Justices then he or they may appeale to His Majesties Justices of the Peace at the next
Quarter Sessions in like manner as by the said recited Act is mentioned in case of Appeale</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Power to such Justices to mitigate Penalties, allowing Costs over and above such Mitigation</head>
			<para id="p36">Provided nevertheless That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said respective Justices where they shall
see Cause to mitigate or lessen such Penalty in such manner as they in their Discretion shall think fitt the reasonable
Cost and Charges of the Officers as well in makeing the Discovery as in the Prosecution of the same being alwaies
allowed over and above such Mitigation and so as such Mitigation doe not reduce the Fine to less than One Fourth
Part thereof over and besides the said Costs and Charges Any thing in the said recited Act to the contrary
notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Recital of Stat. 12 Car. II. c. 24. &sect;14.</head>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">2 W. &amp; M. c. 3; 4 W. &amp; M. c.3. &sect; 1; 5 W. &amp; M. c. 7. &sect; 26; 5 W. &amp; M. c. 20. &sect; 9; and that it is doubted that by the general Words of 8 W. III. c. 20. the Duties herein mentioned are chargeable from the last Day of Feb. 1696 until 1st Aug. 1706; Stat. 8 W. III. c. 20. declared to charge the Duties herein mentioned, From the Commencement and during the Continuance of the said Act</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p38">And whereas by on	e Act made in the Twelfth Yeare of the Reigne of King Charles the Second a Duty of
Four Pence was imposed upon every Gallon of Strong Waters perfectly made imported from beyond the Seas to
be paid for ever And by one other Act made in the Second Yeare of the Reigne of His present Majesty and the
late Queen of Blessed Memory the like Duty of Four Pence per Gallon thereupon is payable during His Majesties
Life and by another Act made in the Fourth Yeare of Their said Majesties Reigne there is a Duty of Six Pence
imposed upon every Gallon of Single Brandy imported and a Duty of Twelve Pence on every Gallon of Double
Brandy imported for the Terme of Ninety nine Yeares commenceing on the Twenty fifth Day of July One thousand
six hundred ninety two And by one other Act made in the Fifth Yeare of Their said Majesties Reigne there is
a Duty of Two Shillings imposed upon every Gallon of Single Brandy and Four Shillings upon every Gallon of
Double Brandy imported for the Terme of Sixteene Yeares commenceing the Seaventeenth Day of May One thousand
six hundred ninety seaven And by one other Act made in the same Yeare there is a Duty of Six Pence upon all
Single Brandy and One Shilling on all Double Brandy imported granted in Perpetuity all which Duties upon Single
Brandy do Amount to Three Shillings and Eight Pence for every Gallon and upon Double Brandy to Six Shillings
and Eight Pence for every Gallon for the Excize thereof over and above other Duties which are payable for the
Customes of the same And it is nevertheless doubted that by the generall Words of an Act of Parliament made
in the Eighth Yeare of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for making good the Deficiencies of severall Funds
therein mentioned and for inlarging the Capital Stock of the Bank of England and for raising the Publick Credit
a further Duty of Two Shillings for every Gallon of Single Brandy and of Four Shillings for every Gallon of
Double Brandy imported (which had been granted in the Fourth Yeare of the Reigne of His Majesty and the said
late Queen) were and are (in strictness) imposed or chargeable from the last Day of February One thousand six
hundred ninety six untill the First Day of August which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seaven
hundred and six which (if required or insisted upon) would amount to a Prohibition of (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) the said Commodities Be
it therefore enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid That the said Act for making good the Deficiencies
of severall Funds therein mentioned and for inlarging the Capitall Stock of the Bank of England and for raiseing
the Publick Credit or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be construed to extend to charge Single
Brandies imported with the last mentioned Duty of Two Shillings for every. Gallon or Double Brandy imported
with the last mentioned Duty of Four Shillings for every Gallon or any part thereof from the Commencement or
during the Continuance of the Act last mentioned Any thing therein contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Duty on Cinders of Pit Coal, shipped, &amp;c. for Four Years, of 5s. per Chalder.</head>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">Contents of Chalder; to be paid by Owner, &amp;c. of Ship at Place of Landing or Importation; Duties to be under Management of Commissioners of Customs, and under Penalties, &amp;c. of 9 W. III. c. 13</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p40">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That there shall be raised levied collected and paid unto and for
the Use of His Majesty His Heires and Successors for all Cynders made of Pit Coale which at any time or times
dureing the Terme of Four Yeares commencing from the Fifteenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety
nine shall be shipped or waterborn in order to be shipped within the Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or
Towne of Berwick upon Tweed or brought into the same the Sum of Five Shillings of lawfull English Money for
every Chalder reckoning the Chalder to consist of Thirty six Bushells Winchester Measure and after that Rate for
a greater or lesser Quantity to be paid at the respective Ports and Places of Importation or landing of such
Cynders and to be charged upon the respective Owner and Owners Master and Masters or other Persons haveing
the Charge of the Ship or Vessell in which the said Cynders shall be carried imported or brought And that the
said Duties upon Cynders shall be under the Management and Government of the Commissioners of the Customes
for the time being and shall be raised levied and collected by such Waies and Meanes and under the like Penalties
and Forfeitures and with such Allowances and according to such Rules and Methods as in and by an Act of
Parliament made in the Ninth Yeare of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for granting to His Majesty severall
Duties upon Coals and Culm are prescribed authorized or mentioned for raising levying and collecting the Duties
thereby granted</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI.</head>
			<para id="p41">
				<emph type="i">Regulations for Importation of Tobacco; Contents of Cask, &amp;c; Importing Tobacco contrary to Act; Penalty; Proviso respecting Tobacco necessary for Ships Voyages, &amp;c; How Penalties recovered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p42">And whereas the Importation of Tobacco in Bulk hath given abundant Opportunity to ill-disposed Persons to run
the same on Shore without paying His Majesties Customes due thereon to the great impairing of the Revenue and
the no less Prejudice of the fair Trader For Remedy whereof be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from
and after the Twenty ninth Day of September which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seaven
hundred no Tobacco be brought or imported into this Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of
Berwick upon Tweed in any Ship or Vessell from any of His Majesties Plantations on the Continent of America
nor shipped in any of the said Plantations in order to be so imported otherwise than in Cask Chest or Case only
each Cask Chest or Case whereof shall containe Two Hundred Weight of neat Tobacco at the least and each
Hundred thereof shall containe One hundred and twelve Pounds under the Penalties and Forfeitures following
that is to say That all the Tobacco so imported or shipped to be imported contrary to this Act shall be forfeited
and every Person or Persons offending contrary to the true Intent and Meaning hereof shall forfeite Six Pence for
every Pound Weight thereof Two third Parts thereof to His Majesty His Heires and Successors and the other Third
Part thereof to such Person as shall seize and sue for the same Provided nevertheless That such small Quantities
as shall be necessary for the Shipps Companies smokeing in the said Voyage shall not be deemed or construed any
Breach of this Act the said Forfeitures and Penalties to be recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information
in any of His Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster in which no Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law shall be
allowed nor more than one Imparlance</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Proviso for Importation of German Pearl Ashes.</head>
			<para id="p43">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Person or
Persons whatsoever from and after the said Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine to import
into England Wales or Berwick upon Tweed from Germany Pearl-Ashes being the Product of Germany paying His
Majesty His Customs and Duties as Pott-Ashes Any Law Custome or Usage to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Whale Fins, American taken and imported, charged under 9 W. III. c. 45. as herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p44">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Whale Fin taken and caught by the People and
Inhabitants of New England New York and Pensilvania or any other His Majesties Plantations and Colonies in America
and imported from thence shall be chargeable with and pay to His Majesty (by virtue of an Act of the last Session
of Parliament intituled An Act for takeing away Half the Duties imposed on Glass Wares and the whole Duties
lately laid on Stone and Earthen Wares and Tobacco Pipes for granting in lieu thereof new Duties upon Whale Fins

and Scotch Linnen) the like Duties as Whale Fin caught and imported in and by any Ships or Vessells whatsoever
of or belonging to the Company established for the Greenland Trade are chargeable withall and no further or other
Duty by meanes or virtue of the said Act only Any thing in the said last mentioned Act to the contrary
notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Recital that the Duties of 8 &amp; 9 W. III. c. 22. are likely to expire before they have proved effectual.</head>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">Additional Interest of One Farthing a Day on Tickets</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p46">And whereas the Duties granted to His Majesty by one Act of Parliament intituled An Act for granting to His
Majesty certaine Duties upon Malt Mum Sweets Cyder and Perry as well towards carrying on the War against France
as for the necessary Expences of His Majesties Household are likely to expire befere they have fully answered and
satisfied the Ends and Purposes for which they were granted And whereas the Commons in Parliament assembled
have declared they will make good all such Deficiencies as shall happen upon the falling short of the said Duties
And whereas there is a small Interest of One Farthing a Day allowed by the last recited Act upon severall Bills or
Ticketts commonly called Malt Lottery Ticketts Now for the advanceing the Credit and Value of the said Bills or
Ticketts be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the Twenty fifth Day of March in the Yeare
of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety nine upon every such Bill or Tickett carrying the said Interest of
One Farthing a Day (other than such Bills or Tickets as shall be paid off and discharged by the Duty now
chargeable with the same) an additionall Interest of One Farthing a Day shall be allowed and paid respectively upon
every such Bill or Ticket untill such Bill or Ticket shall be fully paid off and discharged</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. 8 &amp; 9 W.III. c. 22.</head>
			<para id="p47">
				<emph type="i">When it appears, by Affidavit before a Baron of the Exchequer, that any Tickets, being in course of Payment, as herein mentioned, are burnt, &amp;c. the Officers for Payment of Annuities, on Certificate of Affidavit and Indemnity, to pay Amount of such Ticket; and be allowed such Payments</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p48">And whereas by an Act passed in the Eighth Yeare of His Majesties Reigne (wherein certaine Duties were
granted upon Malt and other things) severall Tickets were made forth for severall Sums of Money payable with
Interest severall of which Tickets are since burnt lost or otherwise destroyed Be it further enacted by the Authority
aforesaid That in all Cases where it shall appeare by Affidavit to be made before any of the Barons of the Exchequer
that any Ticket or Tickets being in Course of Payment out of the Moneys arisen or to arise on or before the
Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine into the Receipt of the Exchequer for the Duties aforesaid
is or are burnt destroyed or otherwise lost it shall and may be lawfull for the Officer or Officers appointed to pay
or discharge the said Annuities on producing a Certificate from the said Baron of such Affidavit made before him
which Affidavit the said Barons or any of them is and are hereby authorized to take and which Certificate he or
they are hereby required to grant without Fee or Reward And on Security given to the said Officer to his good
likeing to indempnifie him against all other Persons whatsoever for or concerning the Moneys contained or specified
in such Ticket or Tickets or which was due thereon he the said Officer shall and is hereby required to pay and
discharge the said Tickets being such as came in Course within the time aforesaid as if the said Tickets had been
produced and shall be allowed such Payment in his Accompts Any thing in this or any other Act contained to
the contrary hereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI.</head>
			<para id="p49">
				<emph type="i">Common Brewers using Melasses, &amp;c. in brewing, or receiving Melasses, &amp;c. exceeding Iolbs; Penalty &pound;100; Persons aiding, &amp;c; Penalty &pound;20, and in Default, Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p50">And whereas it is found by Experience that notwithsanding any Law now in force many common Brewers do
use great Quantities of Mellasses in the brewing Ale and Beere whereby the Consumption of Malt is very much
hindred and His Majesty defrauded of a great Part of the Duties of such Ale and Beere so brewed as aforesaid Be
it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any common Brewer or Retailer of Beer or Ale shall after
the said Tenth Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine make use of any Mellasses course Sugar Honey
or Composition or Extract of Sugar in the brewing makeing or working of any Ale or Beer or if any common
Brewer shall receive or take into his Custody or Possession any Quantity of Mellasses course Sugar Honey or
Composition or Extract of Sugar exceeding Ten Pounds every such Brewer and Retailer shall forfeit and loose for
every such Offence respectively the Sum of One hundred Pounds And every Servant of such Brewer and every
other Person who shall be aiding and assisting in the useing any Mellasses course Sugar Honey or Extract of
Sugar in the brewing or working of such Ale or Beer or in carrying or conveying the same into the House
Brewhouse or other Place belonging to such Brewer shall alsoe forfeite and loose for every such Offence the Sum of
Twenty Pounds and in Default of Payment thereof shall suffer Three Months Imprisonment</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Recital of c. 9. ante, &sect; 87.</head>
			<para id="p51">
				<emph type="i">The Money so appropriated, and applicable for 1699, to be also appropriated as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p52">And whereas by an Act of this present Session of Parliament intituled An Act for granting to His Majesty the
Sum of One million four hundred eighty four thousand and fifteen Pounds One Shilling Eleaven Pence Three
Farthings for disbanding the Army providing for the Navy and for other necessary Occasions It is amongst other
things enacted That a Sum not exceeding the Sum of Six hundred thousand Pounds of the Moneys to be paid
into the Exchequer by virtue of the said Act should be and is thereby appropriated in the first Place to the
paying and disbanding the Forces enacted to be disbanded and the Residue of the said Sum of Six hundred
thousand Pounds for and towards the Subsistance and Clearings of His Majesties Guards and Garrisons within the
Kingdom of England and the Dominions thereunto belonging (Ireland excepted) for the Yeare One thousand six
hundred ninety nine and to other the Purposes in the said Act mentioned And whereas it is or may be doubted
whether any part of the said Money so appropriated to the Subsistance and Clearings of His Majesties Guards and
Garrisons may or ought to be applyed towards the paying the Arreare of Subsistance due to the said Garrisons
before the Twenty fifth day of March One thousand six hundred ninety nine according to the course of Payment
and true intention of the said last mentioned Act Be it therefore enacted and declared by the Authority
aforesaid That the Money so appropriated and applicable to the Subsistance and Clearings of the Guards and
Garrisons for the Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety nine shall and may be applyed as well to the Payment
of the said Arreare of Subsistance due to the said Garrisons at any time before the said Twenty fifth Day of
March One thousand six hundred ninety nine [as<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] for and towards the Subsistance and Clearings of the said
Guards and Garrisons for the yeare One thousand six hundred ninety nine Any thing in the said last mentioned
Act to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Recital of Appropriation of Part of &pound;600,000, mentioned in c. 9. ante; Out of the said Money &pound;20,000 applied to disbanded Officers of Scotch and English Regiments herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p53">And whereas so much of the said Sum of Six hundred thousand Pounds mentioned in an Act of this Session
of Parliament (wherein a Land Tax is granted to His Majesty) as is or shall be sufficient for paying off and
disbanding the Regiments Troops and Companies appointed and enacted to be disbanded as is therein mentioned
is appropriated for that Purpose It is hereby declared and enacted by the Authority aforesaid That out of the
Money so appropriated or appointed for paying off and disbanding of Regiments Troops and Companies as aforesaid
any Sum not exceeding Twenty thousand Pounds shall and may be issued applied and distributed towards clearing
the disbanded Officers of the Scotch Regiments which were on the English Establishment and the disbanded Officers
of the Three English Regiments lately of Colonel Henry Holt Colonel Luke Lillingston and Colonel Russell
which were in the West Indies and for whom no Half Pay is allowed Any thing in the said Act contained
to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This is Cap. XXI. in the common printed Editions.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	
</report>

