<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46953" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XX. An Act for limiting certaine times within which Writts of Error shall be brought for the reversing Fines Common Recoveries and ancient Judgments. [Rot. Parl. 10 Gul. III. p. 4. n. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head><ref idref="n1">1</ref>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Fines, Recoveries, or Judgements not reversed for Error, &amp;c. unless upon Suit brought within 20 Years</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas Fines and Common Recoveries are the Principall Assurances of Mens Estates and Titles and
Possessions depend thereon and are protected and secured thereby and by ancient Judgments which
neverthelesse are reversible at any time without Restraint or Limitation for any Error or Defect which
happens therein by the Ignorance or Carelessnesse of Clerks and sometimes by unavoydable Accidents For the
Remedy thereof and for the quieting Mens Titles and Possessions under ancient Fines and Recoveries and ancient
Judgments Be it enacted and ordained by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by Authority of
the same That no Fine or Common Recovery nor any Judgment in any Reall or Personall Action shall from and
after the First Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety nine be reversed or avoyded for any Error or Defect
therein unlesse the Writt of Error or Suite for the reversing such Fine Recovery or Judgment be commenced
or brought and prosecuted with effect within Twenty Yeares after such Fine levied or such Recovery suffered or
Judgment signed or entred of Record.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Infancy, Coverture, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwaies That if any Person who is or shall be intituled to any such Writt of Error as aforesaid
shall at the time of such Title accrewed be within the Age of Twenty one Yeares or Covert non compos mentis
imprisoned or beyond the Seas that then such Person his or her Heires Executors or Administrators (notwithstanding
the said Twenty Yeares expired) shall and may bring his her or their Writt of Error for the reversing any such
Fine Recovery or Judgment as he she or they might have done in case this Act had not been made soe as the
same be done within Five Yeares after his or her full Age Discoverture comeing of sound Mind Enlargement out
of Prison or returning from beyond the Seas or Death but not afterwards or otherwise.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This is Cap. XIV. in the common Printed Editions.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


