<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46951" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVIII. An Act for raising the Militia for the Yeare One thousand six hundred ninety nine although the Months Pay formerly advanced be not repaid.[Rot. Parl. 10 Gul. III. p. 4. n. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head><ref idref="n1">1</ref>Recital of Stat. 14 Car. II. c. 3. &sect;6.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Before 24th June 1700, Lieutenants, Deputy Lieutentants, and Lord Wardens of Cinque Ports, &amp;c. may draw out Soldiers, though Pay before advanced be not repaid</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act of Parliament made in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth Yeares of the Reigne of the late
King Charles the Second intituled An Act for ordering the Forces in the several Counties of this Kingdom
it was (amongst other things) enacted that in case of Invasions Insurrections or Rebellions whereby Occasions should
be to draw out the Soldiers mentioned and appointed in and by the said Act into actuall Service the Persons
charged by the said Act with Horses Horsemen and Armes should provide each their Soldier respectively with Pay
in Hand not exceeding One Months Pay as should be in that Behalfe directed by the respective Lieutenants of the
severall Counties and in their Absence or otherwise by their Directions by their Deputies or any Two or more of
them For Repayment of which said Moneys and for Satisfaction of the Officers for their Pay during such time not
exceeding One Month as aforesaid as they should be with their Soldiers in such actuall Service it was thereby
declared that Provision should be made for the same by His said Majesty His Heires and Successors out of his or
their publick Treasury or Revenue Neverthelesse it was thereby further provided and enacted that in case a Months
Pay should be provided and advanced as aforesaid that no Person who should have advanced his Proportion
thereof should be charged with any other like Months Payment until he or they should be reimbursed the said
Months Pay and soe from time to time the said Months Pay by him or them last before provided and advanced
as aforesaid And whereas upon the Invasion of the Coasts of this Kingdom by the French it was found necessary
for the publick Defence and Safety to draw out the said Soldiers into actual Service and to charge the said
[Persons to<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] provide each their Soldier respectively with Pay in Hand although the Months Pay by several of
them before that time provided and advanced was not nor could be reimbursed And whereas it may be necessary
for the publick Safety and Defence of this Realme to draw the said Forces into actual Service Be it therefore
enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and
Temporall and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That if at
any time before the Four and twentieth Day of June which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand
seaven hundred it shall be found by His Majesty to be necessary for the Defence and Safety of this Kingdom to
draw out the said Soldiers into actuall Service and the same shall be declared and signified to the respective
Lieutenants or Deputy Lieutenants and the Lord Warden of the Cinque-Ports Two ancient Towns and their Members
or in his Absence his Lieutenant or Lieutenants by His Majesty it shall be lawfull for the said Lieutenants or their
Deputies or any Three or more of them as aforesaid and the Lord Warden of the Cinque-Ports Two ancient Townes
and their Members or in his Absence his Lieutenant or Lieutenants in pursuance of such Orders from His Majesty
notwithstanding that One or more Months Pay before that time advanced be not reimbursed to raise and draw
out the said Soldiers into actual Service and to cause the Persons charged as aforesaid to provide each their Soldier
with Pay in Hand not exceeding One Months Pay in such Manner as if all the Pay before that time advanced and
provided had been fully reimbursed and paid</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Papists chargeable to the finding of Soldiers, refusing to take the Oaths of Stat. 1 W. &amp; M. c.8. &sect; 12., Lieutenants or Deputy Lieutenants may set forth Soldiers, and charge the Estates of such Persons, and may levy the same by Distress; Amount may be adjudged by their Deputy Lieutentants.; Tenants paying may deduct</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And whereas Papists reputed Papists and such Persons as doe or shall refuse to take the Oaths mentioned in an
Act of Parliament made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of King William and Queene Mary intituled An Act for
abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance and appointing other Oaths when lawfully tendred to them are
not thought fitt to be intrusted with setting out Horses and Armes in the Militia of this Kingdom Be it enacted
by the Authority aforesaid That where any Papist or reputed Papist or other Person refusing to take the Oaths as
aforesaid are in respect of their Estates charged or chargeable to the finding any Horse Horseman and Armes or
any Foot Soldier and Armes the Lieutenant or Lieutenants or in their Absence the Deputy Lieutenants of and for
the County Rideing Division or Place where such Estates do lye or Three or more of them are hereby authorized
and impowered to nominate and appoint such Person or Persons as they shall think most meet and proper to
furnish and sett forth One or more Horse Horsemen and Armes or Foot Soldiers and Armes for the said Estates and
shall and may charge the same Estates with the Payment of the yearly Sums hereafter mentioned that is to say
For a Horse Horseman and Armes the Sum of Eight Pounds and for every Foot Soldier and Armes the Sum of
Thirty Shillings to be paid to the Persons that shall furnish and set forth the same And in case such Papist or
reputed Papist or Person refuseing to take the Oaths as aforesaid shall neglect or refuse to pay the same upon
Demand it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Lieutenants or Three or more of the said Deputy
Lieutenants by Warrant under their Hands and Seales to levy the same by Distress and Sale of the Goods of such
Papist or reputed Papist or Person refuseing to take the Oaths as aforesaid or upon his and their severall and
respective Tenant or Tenants and the remaining Arreares from the said Persons refuseing the Discharge thereof for
the like Services already performed to be adjudged and determined by Three Deputy Lieutenants or more of them
rendring the Overplus to the Party so distrained all necessary Charge in levying thereof being first deducted And
the Tenant or Tenants soe paying or distrained on as aforesaid shall and are hereby impowered to deduct the
same out of their Rents payable for the said Estates</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Where Two or more Persons charged, Three; Deputy Lieutenants may settle Contributions</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Contributor refusing to pay,; Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That where Two or more Persons are charged to find any
Horse or Foot Soldier and Arms it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Three or more Deputy Lieutenants
of the same County Riding Division Limitts of the Cinque-Ports or other Places to direct and appoint who shall
find the Horse and Arms or Foot Soldier and Arms and who shall be the Contributors and to settle the Sums of
Money to be paid by every Contributor in case the same Contribution be not ascertained by Agreement of the
Parties And if any Person so charged as a Contributor being Inhabitant of the said County Riding Division
Limitts of the Cinque Ports or other Place shall refuse to pay his Proportion upon Demand or in case he be not
an Inhabitant in that County Riding Division Limitts of the Cinque-Ports or other Place his Tenant or Tenants whose
Estate is charged with the same Proportion shall neglect or refuse to pay his said Proportion upon Demand that
then it shall and may be lawfull to and for Three or more Deputy Lieutenants of the said County Riding Division
Limitts of the Cinque-Ports or other Place by Warrant under their Hands and Seales to levy such Sum and Sums
of Money by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of the Person soe neglecting or refuseing to pay if he be an
Inhabitant of the same County Riding Division Limitts of the Cinque-Ports or other Place and in case he dwell out
of the County Riding Division Limitts of the Cinque-Ports or other Place then by Distresse and Sale of the Goods
of his Tenant or Tenants or the Estate charged with the same Proportion rendring the Overplus to the Party all
necessary Charge in levying thereof being first deducted And the Tenant and Tenants is and are hereby authorized
and impowered to deduct and defaulk the Sum soe charged out of the Rent by him or them payable to his or
their Landlord And the Sum soe levyed shall be paid according to the Direction of the Warrant of such Three or
more Deputy Lieutenants.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This is Cap. XII. in the common Printed Editions.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


