<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46957" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIV. An Act for takeing off the remaining Duties upon Glasse Wares. [Rot. Parl. 10 Gul. III. p. 4. n. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head><ref idref="n1">1</ref>Recital of Stat. 6 &amp; 7 W. &amp; M. c. 18. &sect; 1.; and of Stat. 7 W. III. c. 31. &sect; 1.; and of Stat. 9 W. III. c. 45. &sect; 1.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this Act; The remaining Moiety of the said Duties upon Glass and Glass Wares to cease</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in and by an Act made and passed in the Parliament holden at Westminster in the Sixth Yeare
of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for granting to His Majesty certaine Duties upon Glass Wares
Stone and Earthen Bottles Coals and Culme for carrying on the Warr against France severall Rates and Duties
therein mentioned were laid upon all Glass and Glass Wares Stone and Earthen Bottles which at any time or
times during the terme of Five Yeares from the Nine and twentieth Day of September which was in the Yeare
of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety five should be made within the Kingdom of England Dominion
of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed or imported or brought into the same and in and by another Act
made and passed in the Parliament holden at Westminster in the Seaventh Yeare of His Majesties Reigne intituled
An Act for continueing to His Majesty certaine Duties upon Salt Glass Wares Stone and Earthen Wares and for
granting severall Duties upon Tobacco Pipes and other Earthen Wares for carrying on the Warr against France
and for establishing a Nationall Land Bank and for taking off the Duties upon Tunnage of Shipps and upon
Coals the aforesaid Rates and Duties upon Glass or Glass Wares Stone Bottles and Earthen Bottles are continued
and granted to His Majesty His Heires and Successors for ever And whereas by another Act made and passed
in the Parliament holden at Westminster in the Ninth Yeare of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for takeing
away Halfe the Duties imposed on Glass and the whole Duties lately laid on Stone and Earthen Wares and
Tobacco Pipes and for granting (in lieu thereof) new Duties upon Whale Finns and Scotch Linnen It is (amongst
other things) enacted That from and after the First Day of August One thousand six hundred ninety eight One
Moyety or Halfe part of the severall Rates and Duties by the aforesaid Acts or either of them charged and made
payable for or upon the said Glass and Glass Wares should cease determine and be no longer payable to His
Majesty His Heires or Successors as by the said severall Acts of Parliament relation being thereunto severally had
may more fully appeare And whereas it is found by experience that the remaining Duties on Glass and Glass
Wares are very vexatious and troublesome in the levying and collecting the same and of small Advantage to the
Crowne and should the same be continued would lessen the Duty on Coals much more than the said Duties on
Glass Wares will amount to will hinder the imploying great Numbers of Poor and endanger the Loss of soe
beneficiall a Manufacture to this Kingdom Be it therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the First Day of August One thousand six
hundred ninety nine the remaining Moiety or Halfe Part of the severall Rates and Duties by the aforesaid Acts
any or either of them charged or imposed for and upon the said Glass or Glass Wares shall cease determine and
be no longer payable paid or collected to or to the use of His Majesty His Heires or Successors in any manner
of wise Any thing in the said Acts any or either of them contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">This is Cap. XVIII. in the common Printed Editions.</note>
	</section>
</report>


