<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46956" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIII. An Act for suppressing of Lotteries.[Rot. Parl. 10 Gul. III. p. 4. n.8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head><ref idref="n1">1</ref> Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Lotteries declared Public Nuisances, and Grants, &amp;c. for the same void</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas severall evill-disposed Persons for divers Yeares last past have sett up many mischievous and
unlawfull Games called Lotteries not only in the Cities of London and Westminster and in the Suburbs
thereof and Places adjoyning but in most of the eminent Townes and Places in England and in the Dominion of
Wales have thereby most unjustly and fraudulently gott to themselves great Sums of Money from the Children and
Servants of severall Gentlemen Traders and Merchants and from other unwary Persons to the utter Ruine and
Impoverishment of many Families and to the Reproch of the English Laws and Government by Colour of severall
Patents or Grants under the Great Seale of England for the said Lotteries or some of them which said Grants
or Patents are against the Common Good Trade Welfare and Peace of His Majesties Kingdoms for Remedy whereof
Be it enacted adjudged and declared and it is hereby enacted adjudged and declared by the Kings most Excellent
Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present
Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That all such Lotteries and all other Lotteries are common
and publick Nusances and that all Grants Patents and Licences for such Lotteries or any other Lotteries are
void and against Law.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. After 29th Dec. 1699, no Person publicly or privately to keep open, &amp;c. Lotteries.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;500</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the Nyne and twentieth Day of
December which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred ninety nine no Person or
Persons whatsoever shall publickly or privately exercise keep open show or expose to be plaid at drawne at or
throwne at or shall draw play or throw at any such Lottery or any other Lottery either by Dice Lotts Cards
Balls or any other Numbers or Figures or any other Way whatsoever And that every Person or Persons that
shall after the said Nine and twentieth Day of December exercise expose open or show to be plaid throwne or
drawne at any such Lottery Play or Device or other Lottery shall forfeite for every such Offence the Sum of
Five hundred Pounds to be recovered by Information Bill Plaint or Action at Law in any of His Majesties Courts
at Westminster wherein no Essoigne Wager of Law nor any more than one Imparlance shall be allowed one
Third part thereof to the Use of His Majesty His Heires and Successors one other Third part thereof to the Use
of the Poor of the Parish where such Offence shall be committed and the other Third part thereof together with
double. Costs to the Party that shall informe and sue for the same and the said Parties so offending shall likewise
be prosecuted as Common Rogues according to the Statutes in that Case made and provided.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Persons drawing, &amp;c. at Lotteries,</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further enacted That every Person or Persons that after the said Nine and twentieth Day of
December shall play throw or draw at any such Lottery Play or Device or other Lotteries shall forfeite for every
such Offence the Sum of Twenty Pounds to be recovered by Information Bill Plaint or Action at Law in any
of His Majesties Courts at Westminster wherein no Essoigne Wager of Law nor any more than one Imparlance
shall be allowed one Third part thereof to the Use of His Majesty His Heires and Successors one other Third
part thereof to the Use of the Poor of the Parish where such Offence shall be committed and the other Third
part thereof together with double Costs to the Party that shall informe and sue for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for the Remainder of the Term in the Royal Oak Lottery.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided neverthelesse That nothing in this Act contained shall extend or be construed to extend to affect or
to enforce the suppressing of a Lottery commonly called the Royall Oake Lottery for the Remainder only of
the Terme for which it now stands granted by Letters Patents under the Great Seale of England Any thing
herein before contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for the Charitable Adventure, for the Benefit of Greenwich Hospital.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided alsoe That nothing in this Act contained shall extend to affect restraine or prejudice the Undertaking
now in being called The Charitable Adventure for the Benefit of Greenwich Hospitall by the present Undertakers
thereof with the Approbation of the Governors and Commissioners appointed for the Management of the said
Hospitall for any time before the Four and twentieth Day of June One thousand seaven hundred.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This is Cap. XVII. in the common Printed Editions.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


