<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46950" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVII.An Act to enable such Officers and Soldiers as have been in His Majesties Service during the late Warr to exercise Trades and for Officers to account with their Soldiers. [Rot. Parl. 10 Gul. III. p. 4. n. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head><ref idref="n1">1</ref> Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">5 Eliz. c.4. &sect; 3t; Officers and Soldiers who have not deserted, and who have heretofore exercised Trades, or were Apprentices, or are able to practice Trades, may set up the same; If any Officer or Soldier be Sued, &amp;c. and making it appear he has served His Majesty, shall, upon the General Issue, be found not guilty; or Plaintiff discontinue, &amp;c.; Treble Costs. Judges, &amp;c. to conform to this Act
</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas there hath been and are divers Officers and Soldiers who have served His Majesty in the late
Wars and were instrumentall by the Blessing of Almighty God in obtaining an advantagious Peace for
these Kingdoms some of which are Men that used Trades others that were Apprentices to Trades who had not
served out their times and others who by their owne Industry have made themselves apt and fitt for Trades many
of which (the Wars being now ended) would willingly imploy themselves in those Trades which they were formerly
accustomed to or which they are apt or able to follow and make use of for the getting their Liveing by their
owne Labour but are or may be hindred from exerciseing those Trades in certaine Cities and Corporations and
other Places within this Kingdom because of certaine By-Lawes and Customs of those Places and of the Statute
made in the Fifth Yeare of Queene Elizabeth prohibiting the use of certaine Trades by any Person who hath not
served as an Apprentice to such Trade for the Space of Seaven Yeares For Remedy whereof Be it enacted by
the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall
and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That all such Officers and
Soldiers who have been at any time imployed in His Majesties Service since His happy Accession to the Crowne
and have not since deserted the said Service and that have heretofore used or exercized any Trade or that were
Apprentices to any Trade though they did not serve out the time of their Apprenticeship or any other Officer or
Soldier imployed as aforesaid that is apt and able to practice any Trade may sett up and exercize such severall and
respective Trades Misteries or Occupations whereunto he or they have been bound Apprentices and served any part
of his or their time or any Handicraft or other Trade exercised about Manufactures though he was never bound
Apprentice to the same in manner following (that is to say) such of them as have been Apprentices as aforesaid
may sett up and exercise such severall and respective Trades whereunto he or they have been so bound Apprentices
as fully as if they had served out their respective Termes or Times for which they have been bound and shall
have and enjoy the same Immunities as they should have had and enjoyed if they had served out their said Termes
or Times And all others of the said Officers and Soldiers may sett up and exercise such Trades as they are apt
and able for in any Towne or Place within the severall and respective Counties wherein they were borne without any
Lett Suite or Molestation of any Person or Persons whatsoever for or by reason of the Useing of such Trade And
if any such Officer or Officers Soldier or Soldiers shall be sued impleaded or indicted in any Court whatsoever
within this Kingdom for useing or exerciseing any such Trades as aforesaid then the said Officer or Officers Soldier
or Soldiers makeing it appeare to the same Court where they are soe sued impleaded or indicted that they have
served the Kings Majesty as aforesaid shall upon the Generall Issue pleaded be found not Guilty in any Plaint
Bill Information or Indictment exhibited against them And such Persons who notwithstanding this Act shall prosecute
their said Suite by Bill Plaint Information or Indictment and shall have a Verdict passe against them or become
Nonsuite therein or discontinue their said Suite such Person or Persons shall pay unto such Officer or Officers
Soldier or Soldiers Treble Costs of Suite to be recovered as any other Costs at Common Law may be recovered
And all Judges and Jurors before whom any such Suite Information or Indictment shall be brought and all other
Persons whatsoever are to take Notice of this present Act and shall conforme themselves thereunto Any Statute
Law Ordinance Custom or Provision to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. No Officer or Soldier to have the Benefit of this Act, who shall not prove his Service.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided That no Officer or Soldier shall have the Benefit of this Act that shall not prove his Service as aforesaid
either by a Certificate under the Hand and Seale of some Field Officer or Two Commission Officers of the Regiment
wherein he served or some Generall Officer of the Army certifying his Knowledge of the Service aforesaid and the
same Certificate to be proved by one Witness at least to be a true Certificate or for Default of such Certificate by
the Oath of Two Credible Witnesses at least</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Persons pretending to be Officers, &amp;c. producing a false Certificate,</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">Provided alsoe That if any Person or Persons pretending themselves to have been Officers or Soldiers within
the Qualifications aforesaid shall produce a false Certificate to the Intent to have the Benefit of this Act and thereof
be convicted by Confession or due Proofed of Law shall suffer. Imprisonment not exceeding Three Months and to
loose the Benefit of this Act Any thing therein contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Paymasters to state their Accounts on or before 1st June 1699; and pay Arrears.</head>
			<para id="p6">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Paymaster on or before the First Day of June
One thousand six hundred ninety and nine shall state their Accounts respectively of each Regiment disbanded or
not disbanded and shall deliver such Accounts so stated under their Hands, to the respective Colonels of each
Regiment and if thereon it shall appeare there be any Moneys due to the said Regiments issued for that Purpose
and remaining in the Paymasters Hands that then the Moneys soe in Arreare shall be forthwith paid over unto
the said Colonels respectively</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Colonels of disbanded Regiments in the late Wars, to state Accounts with Captains of Troops, &amp;c., and pay Money in their Hands; and Captains in like Manner to account with and pay to inferior Officers.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the severall Colonels of the respective disbanded
Regiments which served in the late Warrs shall forthwith state the Account with the severall Captains of the severall
Troops and Companies or their Agents in their behalfe and within Ten Daies after the Receipt of such Moneys
pay over such Moneys as shall be found in their Hands due to such Captains and their Troops and Companies
which Captains are hereby required in like manner within Ten Daies to account with and pay over to every
particular inferiour Officer Private Centinel and Soldier or to such other Person or Persons as have Right to receive
the same such Moneys as shall appeare to be justly due to them and soe comeing to their Hands as aforesaid
under the Penalty of forfeiting Double the Sum which shall soe appeare to be due from every Colonel Agent or
Captaine who shall neglect or refuse to doe and performe their Duties hereby enjoyned</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Disbanded Soldiers setting up their Trades, freed from Arrest, and their Goods from Seizure, in respect of Debts due at the Time of their first enlisting</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And for the better enabling and encourageing the said disbanded Soldiers (other than Commission Officers) to
[and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] sett up [and exercise<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] their Trades in such manner as aforesaid It is hereby further enacted and declared by
the Authority aforesaid That such of the said disbanded Soldiers (other than Commission Officers) as shall soe
sett up and exercise their Trades as aforesaid with their Stock and Tooles used in or about the exerciseing their
said Trades shall be and are hereby freed for the space of Three Yeares to be accounted from the First Day of
May One thousand six hundred ninety nine from haveing their Persons arrested or imprisoned or their said Stock
or Tooles seized distrained or taken in Execution for any Debt or Moneys which was or were owing by them
either or any of them at the time when they respectively were first listed into His Majesties Service Any thing
to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This is Cap. XI. in the common Printed Editions.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


