<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46964" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698-9</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act for the Repaire of Dover Harbour. [Rot. Parl. 11 Gul. III. p. 2. n. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">23 Eliz. c. 6. 1 Jac. I. c.32. 13 &amp;14 Car. II. c. 27.; From 1st May 1700 to 1st May 1709, Duty on Ships, &amp;c. from 20 to 300 Tons, for loading and discharging in England, for, from, to, or by Dover, &amp;c. 3d. per Ton.; Aliens the like.; Duty upon Coals, Grindstones, Three Halfpence per Ton. No Goods to be entered till Oath made of Ship's Burthen, &amp;c.; Receivers to keep Account, and pay once a Month to Receiver General of Customs at London, &amp;c.; Who is to pay to Treasurer of Dover Harbour, for Repair of Harbour.; Collector making Default, &amp;c.; Penalty &pound;20</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas it is found by long Experience that Dover Harbour is and hath beene of very great Use and
Benefitt to the Merchants of this Realme and others passing through the Narrow Seas whereunto they have
and doe enter to avoid eminent Danger of Tempests Pirates and the Common Enemy in Time of Warr And
whereas the said Harbour hath beene of late by Tempests and Violence of the Seas soe broken and decayed that
it is in very great Danger of being intirely lost unlesse timely prevented by repairing thereof which cannot be done
without great Charge and Expences To the End therefore that the said Harbour may be effectually repaired and
soe restored to its former good Condition as to be rendered againe of Service to the Nation Trade and Navigation
And that such Provision may be now made in order thereunto and for keeping the same in good Repaire (former
Acts of Parliament for that Purpose made in the Twenty third Yeare of the Reigne of Queene Elizabeth the First
Yeare of King James the First and the Fourteenth of King Charles the Second being expired) Be it enacted by
the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the First
Day of May in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand and seaven hundred to the First Day of May in the Yeare
of our Lord One thousand seaven hundred and nine there shall be paid by the Master Owner or Skipper of every
English Ship Vessell or Crayer of the Burthen of Twenty Tons or upwards and not exceeding the Burthen of
Three hundred Tons for every loading and dischargeing within this Realme for from to or by Dover or comeing
into the Harbour there not haveing a Cocquet testifying his Payment before that Voyage towards the Repaire of
Dover Harbour the Summe of Three Pence for every Ton and of all Aliens Ships Vessells and Crayers of the
Burthen aforesaid the like Summe of Three pence for every Ton of the Burthen of the said Ship Vessell or Crayer
(except Ships loaden with Coales Grindstones or Purbeck or Portland Stones) and for every Chaldron of Sea-Coals
or Ton of Grindstones the Summe of One Penny Halfe Penny the same to be paid to the Customer or Collector
of the Customs or Subsidies or their Deputies within this Realme in such Port or Place whence such Ship Vessell
or Crayer shall sett forth or where such Ship Vessell or Crayer shall arrive before they load or unloade the Goods
therein the Account of the Number of the said Tons to be made according to the Entry of the Goods of every
such Ship Vessell or Crayer in the Custome-house or Place respectively and no Entry of the said Goods to be
allowed in any Office of Customes or Subsidies without true Information before made on Oath by the Master
Owner or Skipper of such Ship Vessell or Crayer containing the Burthen thereof and Payment by him made of
the Summs aforesaid of which Payment the Master Owner or Skipper paying the same shall have Allowance of
the Merchants according to the Rates of the Goods in the same Ship Vessell or Crayer by way of Average and
the Customers or Collectors or their Deputies receiving the Summs aforesaid or any of them shall keepe a faire
and true Account thereof in a Booke or Books distinct and apart for that Purpose to which all Persons may have
free Accesse at all seasonable Times without Fee or Charge and shall Once in every Month returne and pay over
the Summs soe received by him to the Receiver Generall and Cashier of His Majesties Customes or Subsidies for
the Time being in the Port of London who is alsoe hereby directed to receive and give Receipts for the same
and alsoe to keepe a true faire and distinct Account in a Booke or Books apart for that Purpose (to which all
Persons may have free Accesse at all seasonable Times without Fee or Charge) of all Moneys soe received by or
paid to him by vertue of this Act and alsoe Once in every Month if required to disburse and pay the same to
the Treasurer of Dover Harbour or to such Person or Persons as he shall assigne to receive the same to be by
him (as he shall from Time to Time be ordered and directed by the Warden or his Lieutenant with the major
Part of the other Assistants for the Time being of Dover Harbour under their Hands and not otherwise) expended
in and about the Repaire of the said Harbour and every Customer or Collector or their Deputies that shall make
any Entries of Customes or Subsidies of any Goods in the said Ships Vessells or Crayers before such Information
as aforesaid concerning the Burthen thereof shall be made and before Payment made of the Summes before limitted
to be paid by vertue of this Act or shall make any wilfull Default in not collecting the said Summes or any of
them or in not keeping a fair and true Account thereof as aforesaid or in not paying the same over from Time
to Time according to the Direction of this Act shall forfeite to the Use of the Reparations of the said Harbour
the Summe of Twenty Pounds for every such Default to be recovered by Action of Debt in any Court of Record
in the Name of the Wardens and Assistants of Dover Harbour for the Time being (who are hereby impowered
to bring such Action or Actions) in which no Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Coaster or Fisherman to pay but once a Year.</head>
			<para id="p3">[Provided alwaies That no Coaster or Fisherman shall pay the Duty charged by this Act oftner than Once in
any One Yeare Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding
<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Warden, &amp;c. to cause Repair of Harbour to be set upon, and give Order therein, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Treasurer of Harbour to give Security</emph>; 
					<emph type="i">and to keep Account, &amp;c</emph>.
				</para>
			<para id="p5">And to the End all the Moneys which shall be collected by virtue of this Act may be duely and truly applyed
to the Uses hereby directed Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Warden or his Lieutenant with the
major Part of the other Assistants of the said Harbour shall and doe with all convenient Speed cause the Repaire
of the said Harbour to be sett upon and shall from Time to Time direct and give Order in all that shall be
necessary thereunto and shall alsoe see that all the Moneys to be raised for the same be rightly and duely imployed
in the said Works untill the same shall be perfected and shall take good Security of the Treasurer of the said
Harbour before he enter on the Execution of his said Office for his due and true issueing and paying of and
					accounting for all Moneys that shall come or be paid to him by virtue of this Act and how the same hath
beene by him (on due Order as aforesaid) issued for the Repaire of the said Harbour according to the true Intent
and Meaneing hereof of all which the said Treasurer is hereby required to keepe a true and distinct Account in
a Booke or Books faire and apart for that Purpose to which all Persons may have free Accesse at all seasonable
Times without Fee or Charge</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Warden, &amp;c. to have a yearly Account from Receiver General, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Receiver General neglecting; Penalty &pound;500</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And it is alsoe hereby further enacted That the said Warden or his Lieutenant with the major Part of the other
Assistants as aforesaid shall in every Yeare at the least during the Continuance of this Act require an Account of
the aforesaid Receiver-Generall or Cashier and of the respective Customers and their Deputies aforesaid and alsoe
of the said Treasurer of all the Moneys by them or any of them respectively received or paid by virtue of this
Act. And if the afore-mentioned Receiver-Generall and Cashier Customers Collectors Deputies or Treasurer shall
not within Twenty Daies next after Demand made of such Account give in the same accordingly or if thereupon
it shall appeare that all the [said<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Moneys shall not have beene duely paid to and for or disbursed in and about
the said Repaires and Works according to the Intent and Directions of this Act the Person or Persons soe offending
and every of them respectively shall for every such Default forfeite the Summe of Five hundred Pounds to be
recovered by the said Warden and Assistants in the Manner and for the Uses aforementioned</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Treasurer may convey the Duties for Five Years for &pound;6,000, to be lent at &pound;6 per Cent</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And forasmuch as the Moneys to be levyed and collected by virtue of this Act may not in any one Yeare
amount to soe much as the Necessities of the said Repaires may in that Time require to be expended thereon
Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Person or
Persons at any Time during the Continuance of this Act to advance and lend any Summe or Summs of Money
on the Credit thereof to the Treasurer of the said Harbour (after his haveing given Security as aforesaid) who
is hereby impowered by Indenture under his Hand and Seale (by and with the Consent and Approbation of the
Warden and Assistants of the said Harbour or the major Part of them for the Time being) to transferre grant
and convey the Duties and Profitts to be raised by virtue of this Act for any Time not exceeding the Terme of
Five Yeares unto such Person or Persons as shall or will upon such Security advance or lend any Summe not
exceeding at any one Time during the Continuance of this Act the Summe of Six thousand Pounds and alsoe not
exceeding Six Pounds per Centum for the Interest thereof per Annum for every One hundred Pounds and soe
proportionable more or lesse for every Summe lent or advanced</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Persons disbursing Monies for Repair of the Harbour, to be accountable on Oath.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Account to remain in the Navy Office</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And for the more sure and certaine Application of all the Moneys ariseing by virtue of this Act to the Uses
intended by it Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all and every Person or Persons who shall
pay or disburse any of the said Moneys for the Use and Repaire of the said Harbour shall for the same be
accountable on Oath to the Justices of the Peace in every Midsummer Quarter Sessions to be holden for the
Easterne Division of the County of Kent who are hereby authorized and required to examine take and state the
said Account accordingly and after Allowance thereof under the Hands of Seaven or more of them to transmitt
the same (by the Clerke of the Peace who is hereby required to obey such Orders as he shall from them receive
therein) to the Commissioners of His Majesties Navy there to remaine as a Record in the said Office to which all
Persons may at all seasonable Times have free Accesse without Fee or Charge</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">If Harbour sufficiently repaired within Time limited; Collection to cease</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And that no more Moneys may be received or collected by virtue of this Act than Thirty thousand and one
hundred Pounds at most or no more (though under the saide Summe) than shall be necessary and sufficient to
repaire and secure the said Harbour Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if the said Harbour shall within
the Time limitted for the Continuance of this Act be sufficiently repaired and secured and the same be soe certified
to His Majesty and His Successors in Councill by the said Justices of the Peace from their aforementioned generall
Quarter Sessions to be holden for the Easterne Division of the County of Kent that then and from thenceforth all
and every further Collection and Collections to be made (by virtue of this Act) shall cease and determine Any
thing in this Act contained to the contrary hereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for Ships belonging to Weymouth, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">On Certificate thereof</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Shipps and Vessells belonging to the
Ports of Weymouth and Melcomb-Regis and Lyme Regis haveing Piers and Cobbs of their owne which by reason
of their Poverty at present they are not able to maintaine shall be exempted from contributing or paying any thing
to the Harbour of Dover mentioned in this Act Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding soe
as they shall bring a Certificate made upon Oath before the Mayor under the Common Seale of the said Corporations
that the said Shipps and Vessells doe properly belong thereunto and that the Inhabitants of the said Corporations
are Owners of the major Part of the said Vessells</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">The like as to Ships belonging to Great Yarmouth</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And whereas the Inhabitants of the Towne of Great Yarmouth in the County of Norfolke are at a very great
and Constant Charge and Expence for the repaireing maintaining and clearing the Haven and Piers belonging to
the said Towne without the least Aid or Contribution from any other Port or Place whatsoever Be it therefore
enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Shipps and Vessels English built and manned according to the Act of
Navigation belonging to the said Towne of Great Yarmouth shall be free and exempt from all and every the
Duties Summe or Summs of Money charged and payable by this Act towards the Repaire of Dover Harbour Any
thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding soe as the Master of every such Shipp or Vessell belonging
to the said Towne of Yarmouth or some other Mariner on his behalfe respectively shall produce and shew to any
Person lawfully authorized to demand the Duties imposed by this Act a Certificate made upon Oath before the
Bayliffs of Yarmouth aforesaid or one of them which Oath they the said Bayliffs or either of them are hereby
impowered to administer and under the Seal of Office of Bayliwick that such Ship or Vessell dos belong to the
said Towne of Great Yarmouth and that the Inhabitants thereof are Owners of the Whole or major Part of every
such Ship or Vessell</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. The like as to Ships belonging to Ramsgate.</head>
			<para id="p18">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Ships and Vessells belonging to the
Port of Ramsgate in the Isle of Thanet and County aforesaid having a Pier of their owne (which by reason of their
Poverty at present they are not able to maintain) shall be exempted from contributing and paying any thing towards
Dover Harbour aforesaid Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding so as they shall bring
Certificate upon Oath made before the Mayor of the Corporation of which the said Port of Ramsgate is a Member
that the said Ships and Vessells doe belong thereunto and that the Inhabitants of the Port of Ramsgate aforesaid
are Owners of the major Part of such Vessell.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


