<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46960" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698-9</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for taking away the Bounty Money for exporting Corn from the Ninth Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety nine to the Nine and twentieth Day of September One thousand seaven hundred.[Rot. Parl. II Gul. III. p. 1. n. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Stat. I W. &amp; M. c. 12</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">From the 9th Feb. 1699 until the 29th Sept. 1700, Bounty Money allowed by the said Act, not to be paid</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act made Primo Gulielmi &amp; Marie intituled An Act for the Encouragement of the
Exportation of Corn It is enacted That when Malt or Barley (Winchester Measure) is or shall be
Twenty four Shillings p[er] Quarter or under Rye at Thirty two Shillings p[er] Quarter or under and Wheat at Forty
eight Shillings p[er] Quarter or under in any Port or Ports of this Kingdom or Dominion of Wales every Merchant
who shall ship off any such Corn or Sorts of Corn as therein is mentioned with an Intent to export the same
to Parts beyond the Sea every such Merchant or Merchants shall receive from the Commissioners Collector or
Officer collecting the Duties of Customs within the respective Port For every Quarter of Barley ground or unground
Two Shillings and Six Pence For every Quarter of Rye ground or unground Three Shillings and Six Pence And
for every Quarter of Wheat ground or unground Five Shillings Which said Act giveing the said Allowances for
Corn exported was grounded upon the highest Wisdom and Prudence and has succeeded to the greatest Benefitt
and Advantage to the Nation by the greatest Encouragement of Tillage But forasmuch as it appeares that the
present Stock and Quantity of Corn in this Kingdom may not be sufficient for the Use and Service of the People
at home should there be too great an Exportation into Parts beyond the Seas which many Persons may be prompted
to doe for their own private Advantage and the Lucre of the said Bounty or Allowance-Money Be it enacted by
the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the Ninth
Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety nine untill the Twenty ninth Day of September One thousand
seaven hundred and no longer no such Bounty-Money as is allowed by the said Act shall be due or payable by
any such Officer of the Customs in any such Port to any such Person or Persons who by the said Act may be
intituled to any such Sum or Sums of Money for Exportation of any such Corn within the Time limitted as in
the said Act is mentioned Any thing in the said Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
</report>


