<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46969" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698-9</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for the more effectuall imploying the Poor by incourageing the Manufactures of this Kingdom. [Rot. Parl. 11 Gul. III. p. 3. n]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Regulations for Use of Wrought Silks, Bengals, &amp;c. imported</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas it is most Evident That the Continuance of the Trade to the East-Indies in the same Manner
and Proportions as it hath been for Two Yeares last past must inevitably be to the great Detriment of
this Kingdom by exhausting the Treasure thereof and melting downe the Coine and takeing away the Labour of
the People whereby very many of the Manufacturers of this Nation are become excessively burdensome and
chargeable to their respective Parishes and others are thereby compelled to seeke for Employment in Forreigne
Parts For Remedy whereof Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and
Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the
Authority of the same That from and after the Twenty ninth Day of September One thousand seaven hundred
and one All Wrought Silks Bengalis and Stuffs mixed with Silk or Herba of the Manufacture of Persia China
or East India and all Callicoes painted dyed printed or stained there which are or shall be imported into this
Kingdom shall not be worn or otherwise used within this Kingdom of England Dominion of Wales or Town of
Berwick upon Tweed but under such Limitations as are hereinafter mentioned and expressed</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Wrought Silks, Bengals, &amp;c. imported after Entry, to be warehoused, and not carried out but for Exportation, nor until Security for due Exportation, &amp;c. given.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Such Security discharged without Fee, upon Certificate of Landing, or Loss of Goods at Sea, as herein mentioned; Such Goods found in any Shop, &amp;c. forfeited; Liability to Search and Seizure, as by Stat. 14 Car. 11. c. 11; Such Goods, upon Condemnation, to be sold by Candle; Security for Exportation by Buyer; Application of Monies made by Sale; Penalty, &pound;200 besides Loss of Goods, upon Person in whose Custody the same are found</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the better effecting the same Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said
Twenty ninth Day of September One thousand seaven hundred and one all such Wrought Silks Bengalls and
Stuffs mixed with Silk or Herba of the Manufacture of Persia China or East India as aforesaid and all Callicoes
painted dyed printed or stained there which are or shall be imported into this Kingdom of England Dominion of
Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed shall after Entry thereof be forthwith carried and putt into such
Warehouse or Warehouses as shall be for that Purpose approved of by the Commissioners of His Majesties
Customs for the Time being soe as none of them shall be taken or carried out thence upon any Account
whatsoever other than in order for Exportation and not untill sufficient Security be first given to the Kings
Majesty His Heires and Successors (which the said Commissioners are hereby required and impowered to take)
that the same and every Part thereof shall be exported and not landed again in any Part of this Kingdom of
England Dominion of Wales [and <ref idref="n1">1</ref>Towne of Berwick upon Tweed which said Securities shall be discharged
without any Fee or Reward upon Certificate returned under the Common Seale of the Chiefe Magistrate in any
Place or Places beyond the Seas or under the Hands and Seales of Two knowne English Merchants upon the
Place that such Goods were there landed or upon Proofe by credible Persons that such Goods were taken
by Enemies or perished in the Seas The Examination and Proofe thereof being left to the Judgment of the
said Commissioners And all such of the aforesaid Goods whether the same shall be mixed sewed or made up
together for Sale with any other Goods or Materials or otherwise which shall be found in any House Shopp or
Ware-house or other Place whatsoever (other than in such Ware-houses as shall be approved of by the said
Commissioners as aforesaid) shall be forfeited and subject and liable to be searched for and seized in like Manner
as prohibited and uncustomed Goods are by an Act (intituled An Act for preventing Frauds and regulating
Abuses in His Majesties Customs) made in the Fourteenth Yeare of the Reigne of our late Sovereigne Lord King
Charles the Second And all such Goods soe forfeited as aforesaid shall upon Seizure thereof be carried to the
next Custome-house and after Condemnation shall be sold to the best Advantage for Exportation at Publick Sale
by the Candle The Buyer and Buyers giveing Security for the Exportation thereof in Manner as aforesaid And
One Third Part of the Moneys to be raised by such Sale shall be paid to the Kings Majesty His Heires and
Successors and the other Two Third Parts thereof to him her or them that shall seize or prosecute for the same
And over and above the Losse of the said Goods the Person or Persons in whose Custody knowing thereof the
same shall be found or seized or that shall sell or dispose thereof to any Person or Persons whatsoever shall
forfeite and loose the Summe of Two hundred Pounds One Third Part thereof to the Kings Majesty His Heires
and Successors and the other Two Third Parts thereof to such Person or Persons that shall sue for the same to be
recovered by Action of Debt Bill Plaint Suite or Information in any of His Majesties Courts of Record at
Westminster wherein no Essoigne Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed or any more than one
Imparlance</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">After 29th Sept. 1701, importing, except into the Port of London, and not making due Entry, taken to be a clandestine Running; Loss of Goods and Penalty &pound;500</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And for preventing all Clandestine importing or bringing into this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or
Towne of Berwick upon Tweed any of the aforesaid Goods hereby prohibited or intended to be prohibited from
being worne or used in England Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Person or Persons
or Bodies Corporate from and after the said Twenty ninth Day of September One thousand seaven hundred and
one shall import or bring into any Port of or in this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of
Berwick upon Tweed other than the Port of London any of the aforesaid prohibited Goods or into the Port of
London and shall not make due Entries of such Goods soe imported or brought in, the same shall be and is
hereby adjudged deemed accounted and taken to be Clandestine running thereof and such Person or Persons or
Bodies Corporate soe offending therein and their Abettors shall not only forfeite and loose the said Goods soe
clandestinely run as aforesaid but alsoe the Summe of Five hundred Pounds to be recovered and divided in such
Manner as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Onus probandi upon Owner of Goods.</head>
			<para id="p7">And be it further enacted That if any Question or Doubt shall arise where the said Goods were manufactured
the Proof shall lie upon the Owner or Owners thereof and not upon the Prosecutor any Law Usage or Custome
to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. In Action for executing Act,</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">General Issue may be pleaded; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any Action Bill Plaint Suite or Information shall
be commenced or prosecuted against any Person or Persons for any Seizure or other thing to be made or done
in pursuance or in execution of any thing before in this Act contained such Person or Persons soe sued in any
Court whatsoever may plead the Generall Issue and give this Act and the speciall Matter in Evidence for their
Excuse or Justification And if the Plaintiffe or Plaintiffs or Prosecutor or Prosecutors shall become Nonsuit or
forbeare Prosecution or suffer Discontinuance or if a Verdict passe against him her or them in any such Action
Bill Plaint Suite or Information as aforesaid the Defendant or Defendants shall have Treble Costs for which they
shall have the like Remedy as in any Case where Costs by Law are given to the Defendant</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Warehouse-keepers to keep Books and enter Goods warehoused;and every Six Months render Account to Commissioners; Commissioners to appoint Inspectors of Books and Warehouses; and lay Accounts before Parliament; Warehouse-keeper offending; Disability and Penalties</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And for preventing clandestinely carrying out of the said Ware-houses any of the said Goods hereby prohibited
and by this Act intended for Exportation as aforesaid Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the
Warehouse-keeper or Warehouse-keepers shall keepe one or more Book or Books wherein he or they shall fairly
enter or write downe an exact particular and true Account of all and every Chest Bail and Number of Pieces
therein contained of such of the aforesaid Goods only which shall be brought into and carried out of his or their
said Ware-house or Ware-houses and the Daies and Times when the same shall be soe brought in and carried
out and shall every Six Months in the Yeare transmitt in Writing an exact Account thereof upon Oath to the
said Commissioners together with an exact Account how much shall be remaining in his or their said Ware-house
or Ware-houses respectively And the said Commissioners are hereby impowered and enjoyned within one Month
after the same shall be transmitted to them as aforesaid to appoint one or more Person or Persons to inspect the
said Booke or Books Warehouse or Warehouses and examine the said Accounts and to lay a true Account of
the same before the Parliament within the First Weeke of every Sessions thereof And if upon Examination it
shall appeare That any of the aforesaid Goods were carried out unlesse for Exportation or before sufficient Security
given for their Exportation as aforesaid that then the Ware-house-keeper or Ware-house-keepers soe offending
therein shall not onely forfeite and loose the Value of the said Goods soe carried out as aforesaid and be for
ever disabled from any publick Employment for the future but shall alsoe forfeite the Summe of Five hundred
Pounds for every such Offence to be recovered and divided in manner as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Goods made up into Apparel, &amp;c. before 29th Sept. 1701.</head>
			<para id="p12">Provided alwaies and it is hereby enacted That this Act shall not extend to any Silks Bengalis Stuffs mixed
with Silke or Herba or painted dyed printed or stained Callicoes manufactured in Persia China or East-India
which shall have been made up and used in any sort of Apparell or Furniture before the said Twenty ninth of
September One thousand seaven hundred and one</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for Owner of Goods ware housed, fixing Lock to Warehouse, and sorting and delivering Goods for Exportation.</head>
			<para id="p13">Provided alwaies and be if further enacted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Proprietor or Proprietors
of the said Goods so lodged in any Warehouse or Warehouses as aforesaid to affix one Lock to every such Warehouse
or Warehouses the Key of which shall remaine in the Custody of the said Proprietor or Proprietors and that he or
they may view sort or deliver the said Goods in order for Exportation as aforesaid in the presence of the said
Warehouse-keeper or Warehouse-keepers who is and are hereby obliged at seasonable times to give Attendance for
that purpose</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Allowance upon Exportation, within Three Years, of Goods imported.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided alsoe and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Person or Persons or Bodies Corporate
who shall on or before the said Twenty ninth Day of September One thousand seaven hundred and one import
into this Kingdom Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed any of the Comodities aforesaid and
shall within the space of Three Years from such Importation export the same again shall be allowed and paid the
severall Duties payable upon the Exportation thereof as fully as if the same had been exported within Twelve
Months after the Importation thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Half Subsidy to be the only Duty on the said Goods imported.</head>
			<para id="p15">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said Twenty ninth Day of September
which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seaven hundred and one there shall be no Customs or
Duties whatsoever paid or secured to be paid for any of the said Goods or Commodities which shall be imported
at any time from and after the said Twenty ninth Day of September One thousand seaven hundred and one other
than and except the Halfe Subsidy which is to remain by Law after the Goods are exported But that all other
Customs and Duties now chargeable upon or payable for the said Goods shall from that time cease and determine.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


