<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46965" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698-9</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act to enable His Majesties naturall borne Subjects to inherite the Estate of their Ancestors either lineall or collaterall notwithstanding their Father or Mother were Aliens. [Rot. Parl. 11 Gul. III. p. 2. n. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Natural-born Subjects, within the King's Dominions, of Alien Ancestors, inheritable as if those through whom they make Title had beennatural-born Subjects</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas divers Persons borne within the Kings Dominions are disabled to inherite and make their Titles
by Descent from their Ancestors by Reason that their Fathers or Mothers or some other Ancestor (by
whom they are to derive their Descent) was an Alien and not borne within the Kings Dominions For Remedy
whereof Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same. That
all and every Person or Persons being the Kings naturall borne Subject or Subjects within any of the Kings Realmes
or Dominions shall and may hereafter lawfully inherite and be inheritable as Heire or Heires to any Honnours
Mannors Lands Tenements or Hereditaments and make their Pedegrees and Titles by Descent from any of their
Ancestors lineall or collaterall although the Father and Mother or Father or Mother or other Ancestor of such
Person or Persons by from through or under whom he she or they shall or may make or derive their Title or
Pedegree were or was or is or are or shall be borne out of the Kings Allegiance and out of His Majesties Realms
and Dominions as freely fully and effectually to all Intents and Purposes as if such Father or Mother or Fathers
or Mothers or other Ancestor or Ancestors by from through or under whom he she or they shall or may make
or derive their Title or Pedegree had beene naturalized or naturall borne Subject or Subjects within the Kings
Dominions Any Law or Custome to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
</report>


