<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46971" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698-9</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII. An Act to punish Governors of Plantations in this Kingdom for Crimes by them committed in the Plantations. [Rot. Parl. 11 Gul. III. p. 3. n. 11. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">How and where Oppressions by Governors, &amp;c. of Plantations Abroad tried</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas a due Punishment is not provided for severall Crimes and Offences committed out of this His
Majesties Realme of England whereof divers Governors Lieutenant Governors Deputy Governors or
Commanders in Chiefe of Plantations and Colonies within His Majesties Dominions beyond the Seas have taken
Advantage and have not been deterred from oppressing His Majesties Subjects within their respective Governments
and Commands nor from committing severall other great Crimes and Offences not deeming themselves punishable
for the same here nor accountable for such their Crimes and Offences to any Person within their respective
Governments and Commands For Remedy whereof be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and
with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in Parliament assembled and by
the Authority of the same That if any Governor Lieutenant Governor Deputy Governor or Commander in Chiefe of
any Plantation or Colony within His Majesties Dominions beyond the Seas shall after the First Day of August One
thousand seaven hundred be guilty of oppressing any of His Majesties Subjects beyond the Seas within their
respective Governments or Commands or shall be guilty of any other Crime or Offence contrary to the Laws of
this Realme or in force within their respective Governments or Commands such Oppressions Crimes and Offences
shall be enquired of heard and determined in His Majesties Court of Kings Bench here in England or before such
Commissioners and in such County of this Realme as shall be assigned by His Majesties Commission and by good
and lawfull Men of the same County and that such Punishments shall be inflicted on such Offenders as are usually
inflicted for Offences of like Nature committed here in England.</para>
	</section>
</report>


