<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46976" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698-9</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVII. An Act to prevent Disputes that may arise by Officers and Members of Corporations haveing neglected to signe the Association and takeing the Oaths in due Time. [Rot. Parl. 11 Gul. III. p. 3. n. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that divers Persons who, under Stat. 7 W.III. c.27., were obliged to subscribe the Association, had been prevented, by Causes herein mentioned, from so doing, but that they nevertheless ought not to be subject to Penalties, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Members of Corporations to be indemnified in respect thereof</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas divers Persons Members of Corporations within this Realme who by virtue of an Act of Parliament
made in the Seaventh Yeare of His present Majesties Reigne intituled An Act for the better Security of
His Majesties Royall Person and Government were obliged to subscribe the Association in the said Act conteined
have notwithstanding through mistake or by the not regular holding the Courts where the same ought to have
been subscribed or for other such like Reasons neglected to doe the same as the said Act requires, and are
neverthelesse very well affected to His Majesties Royall Person and Government and therefore it is not reasonable
they should be any Waies subject to the Disabilities Incapacities and Penalties in the said Act contained Be it
therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That all and
every Member and Members of any Corporation who subscribed the Voluntary Association before the makeing of
the said Act of Parliament or hath or have already subscribed or shall subscribe the said Association before the
First Day of August One thousand seaven hundred in any Court of Record although it were not done according
to the strict Letter of the said Act of Parliament shall neverthelesse for such Neglect only be indempnified against
all the Incapacities Disabilities and Penalties in the said Act Any thing in the same contained to the contrary in
any wise notwithstanding</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Reciting that Disputes had arisen whether certain Officers, &amp;c. were within Stat. 25 Car. II. c. 2. and Stat. 1 W. &amp; M. c.8.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Certain Officers, &amp;c. indemnified in respect thereof</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And whereas some Disputes have arisen whether some certaine Officers and Members of Corporations (not being
Justices of the Peace Recorder or Towne-Clerke for such Corporations) are comprehended within the Act of
Parliament made in the Five and twentieth Yeare of the Reigne of King Charles the Second intituled An Act
for preventing Dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants And alsoe an Act made in the First Yeare of
His present Majesty and the late Queene Mary intituled An Act for the abrogating of the Oaths of Supremacy
and Allegiance and appointing other Oaths and some such Officers and Members (except as aforesaid) not thinking
themselves comprehended within the said Acts have neglected to take the Oaths and subscribe the Declaration as
in the said Acts is prescribed Bee it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every such Officer and
Member (except as aforesaid) who hath since his being an Officer or Member of such Corporation already taken
the said Oaths and subscribed the said Declaration or shall take and subscribe the same before the First Day of
August One thousand seaven hundred in the Courts and in the Manner prescribed by the said last mentioned Acts
shall for such Neglects only be indempnified against all the Incapacities Disabilities and Penalties in the said Acts
contained as if he or they had formerly fully observed the Directions of the said Acts of Parliament Any thing
in the same contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Offices lost, which have been filled up.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwaies That nothing in this Act contained shall extend or be construed to extend to restore any
such Officer or Member to any Office or Membership who hath for such Neglect been removed and any other
Person hath been duely elected in his Roome or Place.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


