<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46975" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698-9</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVI. An Act for the better ascertaining the Tythes of Hemp and Flax. [Rot. Parl. 11 Gul. III. p. 3. n. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Stat. 3 W. &amp; M. c. 3.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Persons sowing Hemp or Flax, to pay Tithe of 5s. per Acre</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an Act made in the Third Yeare of the Reigne of His Majesty and the late Queen intituled An
Act for the better ascertaining the Tythes of Hemp and Flax was made to continue but for Seaven Yeares
and to the End of the next Session of Parliament after such Term ended and is now expired And whereas the
said Act hath by Experience been found very usefull and necessary Be it therefore enacted by the Kings most
Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in
this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the Five and twentieth
Day of March which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seaven hundred all and every Person or
Persons who shall sow or cause to be sowne any Hemp or Flax in any Parish or Place in the Kingdom of
England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed shall pay or cause to be paid to every Parson
Vicar or Impropriator of any such Parish or Place Yearely and every Yeare the Summe of Five Shillings and no
more for each Acre of Hemp and Flax soe sowne before the same be carried off the Ground and so proportionably
for more or lesse Ground soe sowne For the Recovery of which Summe or Summs of Money the Parson Vicar
or Impropriator shall have the common and usuall Remedy allowed of by the Laws of the Land</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Lands already discharged of Tithe.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided That this Act or any thing therein contained shall not extend to charge any Lands discharged by
any Modus Decimandi ancient Composition or otherwise discharged of Tythes by Law</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Payment of Tithe of Flax and Hemp in Modes already established.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwaies That nothing herein contained shall extend or be construed to extend to make any Alteration
in the Right or Manner of Payment of Tythes of Flax and Hemp to any Ecclesiasticall Person incumbent of any
Parsonage Vicarage or Curacy or to any Impropriator or Body Corporate having or holding any Impropriation for
such Ground as hath at any Time since the Second Day of February One thousand six hundred eighty four
and before the Second Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety one been sowne with Flax or Hemp
and paid Tythe in Kind to such Incumbent Impropriator or Body Corporate respectively but that the same shall
continue and be payable and paid as fully and in such Manner as formerly Any thing in this Act to contrary
notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Contituance of Act.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided That this Law shall continue in force for Seaven Yeares to be accounted from the said Five and
twentieth Day of March and from thence to the End of the next Sessions of Parliament and no longer.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


