<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46973" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698-9</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIV. An Act for raiseing the Militia for the Yeare One thousand seaven hundred although the Months pay formerly advanced be not repaid. [Rot. Parl. 11 Gul. III. p. 3. n. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Stat. 14 Car. II. c. 3. &sect; 6 and that upon Invasion, it was neccessary to draw out Soldiers and to charge for Pay although Month's Pay advanced could not be repaid.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">If before 24th June 1701, it shall be necessary to draw out Soldiers, &amp;c. Lieutenants of Counties, &amp;c. may draw out Soldiers and charge Pay, although Month's Pay before advanced not repaid</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an Act of Parliament made in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth Yeares of the Reigne of the
late King Charles the Second intituled An Act for ordering the Forces in the severall Counties of this
Kingdom it was (amongst other Things) enacted that in case of Invasions Insurrections [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Rebellions whereby
Occasion should be to draw out the Soldiers mentioned and appointed in and by the said (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) into actuall Service the
Persons charged by the said Act with Horses Horsemen and Arms should provide each their Soldier respectively
with Pay in Hand not exceeding One Months Pay as should be in that Behalfe directed by the respective
Lieutenants of the severall Counties and in their Absence or otherwise by their Directions by their Deputies or
any Two or more of them for Re-payment of which said Moneys and for Satisfaction of the Officers for their
Pay during such Time not exceeding One Month as aforesaid as they should be with their Soldiers in such actuall
Service It was thereby declared that Provision should be made for the same by His said Majesty His Heires and
Successors out of His or their Publick Treasury or Revenue Neverthelesse it was thereby further provided and
enacted that in Case a Months Pay should be provided and advanced as aforesaid that no Person who should
have advanced his Proportion thereof should be charged with any other like Months Payment untill he or they
should be re-imbursed the said Months Pay And soe from Time to Time the said Months Pay by him or them
last before provided and advanced as aforesaid And whereas upon the Invasion of the Coasts of this Kingdom by
the French it was found necessary for the Publick Defence and Safety to draw out the said Soldiers into actuall
Service and to charge the said Persons to provide each their Soldier respectively with Pay in Hand although the
Months Pay by severall of them before that Time provided and advanced was not nor could be re-embursed And
whereas it may be necessary for the Publick Safety and Defence of this Realme to draw the said Forces into
actuall Service Be it therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority
of the same That if at any Time before the Four and twentieth Day of June which shall be in the Yeare of
Our Lord One thousand seaven hundred and one it shall be found by His Majesty to be necessary for the
Defence and Safety of this Kingdom to draw out the said Soldiers into actuall Service and the same shall be
declared and signified to the respective Lieutenants or Deputy Lieutenants and the Lord Warden of the Cinque
Ports Two ancient Townes and the Members or in his Absence his Lieutenant or Lieutenants by His Majesty
it shall be lawfull for the said Lieutenants or their Deputies or any Three or more of them as aforesaid and the
Lord Warden of the Cinque-Ports Two ancient Townes and their Members or in his Absence his Lieutenant or
Lieutenants in pursuance of such Orders from His Majesty notwithstanding that One or more Months Pay before
that Time advanced be not re-imbursed to raise and draw out the said Soldiers into actuall Service and to cause
the Persons charged as aforesaid to provide each their Soldiers with Pay in Hand not exceeding One Months Pay
in such Manner as if all the Pay before that Time advanced and provided had been fully reimbursed and paid</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. 14 Car. II. c. 3. &sect; 6.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">12 Car. II. c. 29.; Lieutenants not to lay further Rate for Trophy Money till Quarter Sessions have allowed the Accounts for the last Three Years</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And whereas by an Act made in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth Yeares of the Reign of King Charles the
Second intituled An Act for ordering the Forces in the severall Counties of this Kingdom it is enacted that for
the furnishing Ammunition and other Necessaries the respective Lieutenants and Deputies or any Three or more
of them shall have Power to lay fitting Rates upon the respective Counties and Places not exceeding in the
whole in any one Year the Proportion of a Fourth Part of One Months Assessment in each County after the
Rate of Seaventy thousand Pounds by the Month charged by an Act in the same Year intituled An Act for
raising of Seaventy thousand Pounds for the further Supply of His Majesty which Moneys are to be assessed
collected and paid by such Persons &amp; according to such Directions as shall be given from Time to Time by the
said respective Lieutenants and Deputies or any Three or more of them under the like Penalties and by the like
Waies &amp; Means as are prescribed in the said Act for the Seaventy thousand Pounds by the Month. And whereas
it is further provided that the said respective Lieutenants shall appoint one or more Treasurer or Treasurers Clerk
or Clerks for receiving and paying such Moneys as shall be levied by vertue thereof of all which Receipts and
Disbursements the said Treasurer Clerk and Clerks are every Six Months to give their Accounts in Writing upon
Oath to the said Lieutenants &amp; their Deputies or any Three or more of them And whereas the said Proportion
of a Fourth Part of One Months Assessment hath usually been raised collected and paid in each County annually
for and in the Name of Trophy-Money but the Accounts of the Moneys so raised collected and paid have not
been transmitted according to the Directions of the said Act Be it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid
That the said Lieutenants or their Deputies shall not lay any further Rate or Assessment for the raising of such
Trophy Money till the Justices of the Peace or the Major Part of such Justices at their severall and respective
Generall Quarter Sessions for their respective Counties Ridings Divisions and Places shall have examined stated
and allowed the Accounts of the said Money so raised levied and collected as aforesaid for Three Yeares
last past</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Act <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


