<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46972" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698-9</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An Act for continueing severall Laws therein mentioned, and for explaining the Act intituled An Act to prevent the Exportation of Wooll out of the Kingdoms of Ireland and England into Forreigne Parts and for the Incouragement of the Woollen Manufactures in the Kingdom of England. [Rot. Parl. 11 Gul. III. p. 3. n. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Stat. 14 Car. II. c. 20</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">as revived by 1 Jac. II. c. 11. &sect; 2; and 4 W. &amp; M. c. 24. &sect; 1; further continued</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas divers temporary Laws which by Experience have been found usefull and beneficiall are expireing
Therefore for continueing the same be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice
and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the
Authority of the same That an Act made in the Session of Parliament held in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth Yeares of
the Reigne of King Charles the Second intiruled An Act for providing Carriages by Land and by Water for the Use of
His Majesties Navy and Ordnance which was thereby to have Continuance and be in Force untill the End of the First
Session of the next Parliament and no longer, which said [Act<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] being expired was by one Act made in the First
Yeare of the Reigne of the late King James the Second revived and was enacted to have Continuance during the
Space of Seaven Yeares from the Four and twentieth Day of June in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred eighty five and from thence to the End of the First Session of Parliament then next ensueing which said
Act was by an Act made in the Fourth and Fifth Yeares of the Reigne of His present Majesty continued during the
Space of Seaven Yeares from the Thirteenth Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety two and from
thence to the End of the First Session of Parliament then next ensueing shall be and is hereby continued and
shall be in Force for and during the Space of Seaven Yeares from the Nine and twentieth Day of September One
thousand seaven hundred and from thence to the End of the next Session of Parliament</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Stat. 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 26.;
as continued by 1 Jac. II. c. 17. &sect; 13; and by 4 W. &amp; M. c. 24. &sect; 5; further continued.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further enacted by the Authority [aforesaid<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] That an Act made at the Session of Parliament holden in
the Two and twentieth and Three and twentieth Yeares of the Reigne of the said King Charles the Second intituled
An Act to prevent the planting of Tobacco in England and for regulating the Plantation-Trade which by an Act
made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of the late King James the Second was enacted to have Continuance from
the First Day of the then present Session of Parliament for Seaven Yeares and from thence to the End of the next
Session of Parliament which by an Act made in the Fourth and Fifth Yeares of the Reigne of His present
Majesty and the late Queene was continued for the Space of Seaven Yeares from the Thirteenth Day of February
One thousand six hundred ninety two and from thence to the End of the next Session of Parliament shall be
and is hereby continued and shall be in Force for and during the Space of Seaven Yeares from the Nine and
twentieth Day of September One thousand seaven hundred and from thence to the End of the next Session of
Parliament</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Stat. 19 &amp; 20 Car. II. c. 4.;
as continued by 1 Jac. II. c. 17. &sect; 9.; and by 4 W. &amp; M. c. 24. &sect; 6.; further continued.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That an Act made in the Nineteenth Yeare of the Reigne
of King Charles the Second intituled An Act for assigning Orders in the Exchequer without Revocation which Act
in the First Yeare of the Reigne of the late King James the Second was enacted to be in Force from the First Day
of the then prsesent Session of Parliament and to continue for Seaven Yeares and from thence to the End of the
next Session of Parliament Which said Act was by an Act made in the Fourth and Fifth Yeares of the Reigne of
His present Majesty and the late Queene continued for the Space of Seaven Yeares from the Thirteenth Day of
February One thousand six hundred ninety two and from thence to the End of the next Session of Parliament
shall be and is hereby continued and shall be in Force for and during the Space of Seaven Yeares from the Nine
and twentieth Day of September One thousand seaven hundred and from thence to the End of the next Session of
Parliament</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Stat. 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 23.;
as continued by I Jac. II. c. 17. &sect; 12; and by 4 W. &amp; M. c. 24. &sect; 7.; further continued.</head>
			<para id="p5">And whereas by an Act made at the Session of Parliament holden in the said Two and twentieth and Three
and twentieth Yeares of the Reigne of the said King Charles the Second intituled An Act to revive an Act intituled
An Act to prevent the Disturbance of Seamen and others and to preserve the Stores belonging to His Majesties
Navy Royall with some Alterations and Additions was by an Act made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of the late
King James the Second enacted to be in Force from the First Day of the then present Session of Parliament for
Seaven Yeares and from thence to the End of the First Session of the next Parliament Which said last mentioned
Act was by an Act made in the Fourth and Fifth Yeares of the Reigne of His present Majesty and the late Queene
continued for the Space of Seaven Yeares from the Thirteenth Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety
two and from thence to the End of the next Session of Parliament Be it enacted That the same be continued and
be in Force for and during the Space of Seaven Yeares from the Nine and twentieth Day of September One
thousand seaven hundred and from thence to the End of the next Session of Parliament</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Stat. 22 &amp; 23 Car. II. c. 19.;
as revived by 1 Jac. II. c. 17. &sect; 10; and continued by 4 W. &amp; M. c. 24. &sect; 8.; further continued.</head>
			<para id="p6">And whereas an Act was made at the said Session of Parliament held in the Two and twentieth and Three and
twentieth Yeares of the Reigne of the said King Charles the Second intituled An Act to prevent Frauds in the
buying and selling of Cattle in Smithfeild and elsewhere which was thereby to continue in Force from the Four and
twentieth Day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy one and from thence to the End of the next Session
of Parliament And whereas the said Act being expired was afterwards by an Act made in the First Yeare of
the Reigne of the late King James the Second enacted to be in Force from the Twenty fourth Day of June One
thousand six hundred eighty five for Seaven Yeares and from thence to the End of the next Session of Parliament
Neverthelesse it was thereby provided that neither the said Act nor any thing therein contained should extend to
Salesmen or Factors imployed by Farmers or Feeders which said Act together with the said Proviso was by an Act
made in the Fourth and Fifth Yeares of the Reigne of His present Majesty and the late Queene continued for the
Space of Seaven Yeares from the Thirteenth Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety two and from
thence unto the End of the next Session of Parliament Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Act
together with the said Proviso shall continue and be in Force for and during the Space of Seaven Yeares from the
Nine and twentieth Day of September One thousand seaven hundred and from thence to the End of the next
Session of Parliament</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Stat. 14 Car. II. c. 12.; as further continued by I Jac. II. c. 17. &sect; 2.; and by 3 W. &amp; M. c. 11. &sect; 1.;
<emph type="i">and by 4 W. &amp; M. c. 24. &sect; 10.; further continued as herein mentioned</emph>.
</head>
			<para id="p7">And whereas an Act made in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth Yeares of the Reigne of King Charles the Second
intituled An Act for the better Reliefe of the Poor of this Kingdom was enacted to have Continuance (except what
related to the Corporations therein mentioned and thereby constituted) untill the Nine and twentieth Day of May
One thousand six hundred sixty five and from thence to the End of the First Session of the next Parliament
which said Act by an Act made in the First Yeare of the Reigne of the late King James the Second (except as to
what related to the Corporations therein mentioned and thereby constituted) was enacted to be in Force from the
First Day of May One thousand six hundred eighty five and soe to continue for the Space of Seaven Yeares
and from thence to the End of the next Session of Parliament And whereas by an Act made in the Third and
Fourth Yeares of the Reigne of His present Majesty and the late Queene the said last mentioned Act (as to what
therein related to the Settlement of the Poor) was enacted to be in Force from the First Day of March One
thousand six hundred ninety one but no Provision was thereby made for continuing of divers other Parts of the
said Act which said Act for the better Reliefe of the Poor of this Kingdom as to all Parts thereof not mentioned
and continued in and by the said Act made in the Third and Fourth Yeares of the Reigne of His present Majesty
and the late Queen (other than and except what relates to the Corporations mentioned in the said Act for the
better Releife of the Poor of this Kingdom and thereby constituted) was by an Act made in the Fourth and Fifth
Yeares of the Reigne of His present Majesty and the late Queene continued for the Space of Seaven Yeares from
the Thirteenth Day of February One thousand six hundred ninety two and from thence to the End of the next
Session of Parliament Be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Act for the better Releife of the
Poor of this Kingdom as to all Parts thereof which were continued by the said Act made in the Fourth and Fifth
Yeares of the Reigne of His present Majesty and the late Queen shall be continued and be in Force for and during
the Space of Seaven Yeares from the Nine and twentieth Day of September One thousand seaven hundred and
from thence to the End of the next Session of Parliament</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Stat. 8 &amp; 9 W. III. c. 32.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">further continued</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That an Act made in the Eighth and Ninth Yeares of His
present Majesties Reigne intituled An Act to restraine the Number and Practice of Brokers and Stock-Jobbers
which was enacted to continue from the First Day of May One thousand six hundred ninety seaven for the Space
of Three Yeares and from thence to the End of the next Session of Parliament shall be continued and be in
force for and during the Space of Seaven Yeares from the Nine and twentieth Day of September One thousand
seaven hundred and from thence to the (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) of the next Session of Parliament</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Recital of Stat. 6 &amp; 7 W. III. c. 18. &sect; 16.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Duty to be paid for Seven Years, &amp;c. by Coals exported in Foreign Bottoms; in English Bottoms</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And whereas by an Act made in the Sixth and Seventh Yeares of His present Majesties Reigne intituled An
Act for granting to His Majesty certain Duties upon Glasse Wares Stone and Earthen Bottles Coals and Culm
for carrying on the Warr against France reciting that the Imposition upon Coals exported to Forreign Parts was
so great that it was almost a Prohibition to the great Diminution of His Majesties Customs the lessoning of the
English Navigation and the Exportation of Coals beyond the Seas For Remedy whereof it was thereby enacted
That all Coals exported beyond the Seas in Forreign Bottoms should during the Continuance of the said Act only
pay Tenn Shillings the Chaldron and in English Bottoms only Three Shillings the Chaldron which Part of the
said Act will determine on or about the Twenty ninth Day of September in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand
seaven hundred if timely Care be not taken for continueing of the same which hath been found very beneficiall
and usefull to the Publick and fully to have answered the good End and Intent of the said Act of Parliament Be
it therefore enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Coals exported beyond the Seas in Forreigne Bottoms shall
from and after the said Nine and twentieth Day of September in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand seaven
hundred for and during the Space of Seaven Yeares and from thence to the End of the next Session of Parliament
only pay Tenn Shillings the Chaldron and in English Bottoms only Three Shillings the Chaldron Any Law to
the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Recital of Stat. 10 W. III. c. 16. &sect; 19.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">The said Act not to extend to Wool Fells, &amp;c. necessary for Gunners and Boatswains' Stores; Proviso for Cloth, &amp;c. to the Value of 40s. as shall be necessary for Seamen or Passengers' Clothes</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And whereas by an Act made in the Tenth and Eleaventh Years of His Majesties Reigne intituled An Act to
prevent [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Exportation of Wooll out of the Kingdoms of Ireland and England into Forreigne Parts and for
the Encouragement of the Woollen Manufactures in the Kingdom of England It is enacted and declared That no
Wooll Wooll-fells Shortlings Mortlings Wooll-flocks Worstead-Bays or Woollen Yarne Cloth Serge Bays Kerseys
Says Frizes Druggets Cloth-Serges Shalloons or any other Drapery Stuffs or Woollen Manufactures whatsoever
made up or mixed with Wooll or Wooll-flocks shall be exported transported shipped off carried or conveyed out
of or from the said Kingdom of Ireland into any Forreigne Realme States or Dominions or into any Parts or
Place whatsoever other than the Parts within the Kingdom of England or the Dominion of Wales under severall
Penalties and Forfeitures in the said Act mentioned And whereas severall Disputes have arisen concerning the
true Intent and Meaning thereof Be it therefore enacted and declared by the Authority aforesaid That neither the
said Act nor any Thing therein contained shall be construed to extend to subject any Person or Persons or any
Ship or Vessell to any of the Pains Penalties or Forfeitures in the said Act contained for or touching such
Wooll-fells Shortlings or Mortlings as shall be necessary for the Use of the Gunner or Boatswains Stores for the
Ship or Vessell only and as for soe much Cloth Serge Bays Kersies Says Frizes Druggets Cloth-serges Shalloons
or other Draperies Stuffs or other Manufactures as shall be for the proper Use for Clothes only of any Marriner
or Passenger for his or her Wearing Apparell or Furniture on board such Ship in the Voyage and shall not
exceed in the Whole for any one Marriner or Passenger the Value of Fourty Shillings Any thing in the said
Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">afore O.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">end <emph type="i">O.</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


