<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46982" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1698-9</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIII. An Act for the better preserving the Navigation of the Rivers Avon and Froome and for cleansing paving and inlightning the Streets of the City of Bristoll.[Rot. Parl. 11 Gul.III. p.4.n.2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act, arising from the Trade of Bristol, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Recital of Stat. 34 &amp; 35 Hen.VIII. c.9.
and that the same is insufficient. Further Reasons for passing this Act, arising from Obstructions by Glasshouses, &amp;c. and from the Situation of Bristol, and the Obstructions arising in consequence thereof, from throwing Ballast, Ashes, &amp;c. into the Rivers; and from the Losses sustained by the Obstinacy and Carelessness of Pilots and others; Throwing Dust, &amp;c. into the Rivers of Froome, Avon, and Severn, as herein mentioned, deemed a common Nuisance</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the City of Bristoll is a Place of great Trade and Commerce depending chiefely on the Navigation
of the Rivers Avon and Severne for the Importation of Corne and all sorts of Provisions for the Citizens
and Inhabitants there and from whence by Water many Counties of England and Wales are supplyed with Goods
and Merchandizes and great Quantities of the Product and Manufactures of this Kingdome are exported into
Forreigne Parts and Forreigne Goods and Merchandizes are there imported to the great Advantage of the Trade of
this Kingdome and the Advancement of Navigation and the Kings Revenue which Navigation cannot be carried on
unlesse the Rivers Avon and Froome running through the said City into the River Severne and the Harbours and
Creeks thereof and alsoe the Port of King-Road or Avon-Road into which the said Rivers empt themselves be kept
free and cleare from all Obstructions and Impediments And whereas the Statute made in the Thirty fourth and
Thirty fifth Yeares of the Reigne of King Henry the Eighth intituled An Act for the better Preservation of the

River Severne (which by the Purport thereof was designed to preserve the Navigation to and from the said City)
is insufficient to answer the good Ends therein proposed and designed particularly because it has not provided
against severall Nusances and Obstructions daily committed by digging of Stones and makeing of Quarries in divers
Rocks hanging over and adjoyning to the said River Avon aswell above the said City as below the same from
whence great Quantities of Stones and Rubbish doe arise and wilfully or negligently are throwne or permitted and
suffered to fall into the said River Avon and being carried downe by Tides and Freshes make Shelves and Hills
under Water in the Bottom and on the Sides or Banks of the said River to the Hazard Hindrance and Obstruction
of the Navigation of Shipps and Vessells trading to the said City And whereas severall Glasse-houses Smelting-places
for Lead and Copper and other Houses Edifices and Buildings have been lately erected and built upon the Banks
of or very neare the said River Avon aswell within the Liberties of the said City as in the Counties of Gloucester
and Somersett below the said City towards the Sea and alsoe above the said City to a certaine Place called
Hannams-Mills which Glasse-houses Smelting-places for Lead and Copper and other Houses Edifices and Buildings
doe from their Fuell Materialls and otherwise produce great Quantities of Ashes Cinders and other Filth and
Rubbish which for the Ease and saveing of Expence to the Occupiers of those Houses and Places are very often
throwne into the River or soe carelessly or negligently laid and placed on the Banks thereof that Rains Floods
and Spring-Tides wash it into the said River to the great Prejudice and Annoyance thereof and the said River
Avon being the Bounds and Division of the Counties of Somersett and Gloucester and often shifting and changing
its Channell from one Side to the other soe that it cannot well be proved in which of the said Counties such
Annoyances and Obstructions in the said River are made or done by reason whereof the said Annoyances and
Obstructions are continued and the Offenders escape unpunished And whereas alsoe the Scituation of the said
City of Bristoll it selfe being for the most Part upon Eminencies and small Hills which have a Declivity and Fall
to the said River Avon and the River Froome running by the Key through great part of the said City great
Quantities of Ashes Dirt Filth and other Rubbish (occasioned and made by the great number of Citizens and
Inhabitants within the said City) being for the most part throwne into the Streets and Lanes of the said City are
thence washed into the said Rivers which cannot be prevented for want of sufficient Powers and Authority to hinder
or prevent the throwing of such Ashes and Filth into the said Streets and Lanes and to appoint Scavengers and
other necessary Officers for the cleansing of them and proper Places to receive such Ashes Dirt Filth and Rubbish
and for raiseing and levying of Money to defray the necessary Charges and Expences thereof by reason whereof
the said Rivers are greatly obstructed and if not prevented may in time be choaked up and the Navigation thereof
will be absolutely destroyed And whereas alsoe severall great Losses have been lately sustained and much Damage
done and suffered by the Obstinacy Wilfulnesse and Carelessnesse of Pilotts and Masters of Shipps Barkes and
other Vessells passing up and downe the said Rivers by their comeing to Anchor at inconvenient Places and undue
times of Tide and other Irregularities to the Hazard often of Sinking not only their owne Shipps and Vessells but
likewise the Shipps and Vessells that are lying and abiding in the said Rivers Creeks and Havens to the great
Losse and Prejudice of divers Merchants and Traders and thereby hazarding a Stoppage of the said Rivers To the
Intent therefore that such Nusances Obstructions Impediments and Inconveniencies which at this time are in any
Part or Place within the said River Avon from Hannams-Mills to the Port of King-Road or Avon-Road where the
said River empts it selfe into the Severne or in any Part or Place of the said River Froome within the Jurisdiction
of the said City may be removed abated and remedied And that the same Rivers: within the said Boundaries and
Limitts aforesaid may for ever hereafter be kept and maintained free from any Nusances Obstructions and Impediments
of any sort or kind whatsoever and may be made and preserved easie and safe for Navigation And to the end
that all Mischeifes Damages and Inconveniencies by the Wilfulnesse Obstinacy Ignorance or Irregularity of Pilotts
Masters of Shipps Barkes and other Vessells may be prevented And that the Ashes Dirt Rubbish and Filth of
the said City may be soe disposed of for the future that no Annoyance may come to the said Rivers thereby Be
it enacted and it is hereby enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the
same That the throwing of any Ballast Cinders Ashes Dust Dirt Stones Rubbish or any other Filth into any Part
of the said River Avon from Hannams-Mills aforesaid downwards to the River Severne or the said Rivers Froome
and Severne within the Road or Harbour of King-Road or Avon-Road or into any of the Creeks or Havens of
the said Rivers Avon or Froome within the Boundaries and Limitts before mentioned or the placeing or putting
of any Ballast Cinders Ashes Dust Dirt Rubbish or any other Filth in or upon any of the Wharffes Backs or
Keyes within the said City or Suburbs thereof or in or upon any of the Banks of the said Rivers within the
Limitts aforesaid which may be washed into the said Rivers except for the Maintenance of such publick and
lawfull Shipps as are now in being on the said River or hereafter shall be made or continued by the Allowance
and Consent of the Mayor and the Common Councill of the said City for the time being shall be deemed and
adjudged and is hereby declared to be a common Nusance</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Mayor and Justices of Bristol in Quarter Sessions, to appoint fit Places for laying Ashes, &amp;c; Not carrying to such Places, Penalty 20s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And to the Intent and Purpose that proper and convenient Places for laying and putting the Ashes Dust Dirt
Filth and Rubbish made and ariseing within the County of the said City may for ever hereafter be soe directed
and appointed that no washing of Floods Rains or Spring-Tides may annoy or be the Occasion or cause of
any Damage Obstruction or Prejudice to the said Rivers It is hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid
That the Mayor and Justices of the said City for the Time being shall at their Generall Quarter Sessions as often as
need shall require direct and appoint such fit and convenient Places whereon to lay the said Ashes Dust Dirt
Rubbish or other Filth from whence no Damage or Prejudice may happen to the said Rivers the Charge of which
Place and Places soe to be appointed is from time to time to be paid out of the Moneys collected by the publick
Assessments and Rates which by virtue of this Act shall be made and collected for cleansing the Streets of the
said City and Suburbs thereof to which Places soe to be appointed and no other all Scavengers Rakers and other
Persons imployed for that purpose are hereby required to carry and bring all the said Ashes Dust Dirt Rubbish
and other Filth under the Penalty of Twenty Shillings for every such Offence.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Housekeepers, Churchwardens, &amp;c. twice a Week to cleanse the Streets, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Scavenger, &amp;c. to carry away Ashes, &amp;c; Penalty 3s. 4d; Throwing Ashes otherwise than in Places so appointed, or not keeping the same until Scavenger, &amp;c. come; Penalty 5s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And it is hereby further enacted That all and every Housekeeper and Housekeepers inhabiting and resideing
within the said City and the Churchwarden and Churchwardens of the respective Churches and all Keepers of
Halls and other publick Places shall Twice in every Weeke (that is to say) on every Wednesday and Satturday at
the least sweepe and cleanse or cause to be swept and cleansed all the Streets Lanes and Alleys before their
respective Houses Buildings and Walls and the Buildings and Walls of Churches and other publick Places to the
end the Dirt and Soyle in the said Streets may be ready to be carried away by the Scavenger Raker or other
Officer appointed for that Purpose upon paine to forfeite Three Shillings and Four Pence for every Offence and
Neglect And that no Person or Persons whatsoever shall throw cast or lay or cause permitt or suffer to be throwne
cast or laid any Ashes Dust Dirt Rubbish Dung or other Filth or Annoyance in any open Streete Lane or Alley
within the said City or Places aforesaid before his her or their owne Dwelling-houses Stables Buildings or Walls
or the Buildings or Walls of Churches Church-yards or other Public Places within the said City or on the Wharffs
Backs Keyes or Banks of the said River or any other of the open Places Streets or Lanes there except in or upon
such publick Places as shall be appointed for that Purpose in manner herein before directed or shall cast lay or
throw or cause to be cast laine or throwne into any common or publick Sinke Vault Watercourse Common-Sewer
or Highway within any of the Parishes Precincts or Places aforesaid any Ashes Dirt Filth Ordure or any other
Noisome thing whatsoever but shall keepe or cause the same to be kept in their respective Houses Yards or Backsides
or the Yards or Backsides of Churches and other publick Buildings untill such Time as the Raker or other Officer
thereto appointed shall come by or neare their Houses Doors or Places with his Cart or Carriage used for the
cleansing the Streets and carrying away thereof and then shall carry or cause to be carried the said Ashes Dirt
Dung or other such Filth or Annoyance as aforesaid out of their Houses Yards and Backsides and deliver it to the
Raker Scavenger or other Officer to putt the same into his Cart or Carriage as aforesaid upon paine to forfeite
the Summ of Five Shillings for every such Offence.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Housekeepers and Churchwardens, &amp;c. in Places adjoining the City, on Notice, to pave Streets before Houses or Churches.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And be it further enacted That every Occupier or Owner of any House or Houses or Lands Churchwardens
and Keepers of Halls or publick Places next adjoyning to any Street or Lane within the said City shall alsoe from
time to time within Tenn Daies after Notice given by the Surveyors of [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Streets and Highwaies herein after
mentioned well and sufficiently pitch or pave or cause to be pitched or paved the Street before his or their Houses
Habitations and Lands Churches Church-yards Halls and publick Places respectively unto the Middle of the Streete
under the Penalty of Tenn Shillings for each Perch not soe pitched paved or amended and soe in Proportion for
any greater or lesser Quantity or Space of Ground and the like Summ of Tenn Shillings for every Month untill
the same shall be pitched paved or amended</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Tenants may deduct the Expence out of Rent; Proviso for Agreements</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And whereas by the Custome of the said City the Landlords of all such Houses or Lands as are next adjoyning
to any of the publick Streets or Lanes of the said City and lett at a Rack Rent are liable to repaire and amend
the pitching before their respective Houses and Lands to the Middle of the Street or Lane Be it therefore further
enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for any such Tenant haveing repaired or
amended the pitching in the Street or Lane before his House or Lands in Manner aforesaid to abate and defalke
out of his or her Rent the reasonable and necessary Charges thereof which every such Landlord is hereby required
to allow Provided alwaies that it shall not extend to make void or alter any Covenant or Agreement betweene
any Landlord and Tenant for or concerning the Repaire of the pitching of the said Streets or Lanes</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Laying empty Carriages, Timbers, &amp;c. in the Streets, &amp;c. or suffering Wood, &amp;c. landed out of, or to be laden on board Ships, &amp;c., to lie in the Streets, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And further That if any Person or Persons whatsoever shall lay or put or suffer to be laid or put any empty
Drayes Carriages Timber Casks full or empty or worke up sawe or bore any Timber in any of the publick Streets
or Lanes Wharffs Backs or Keyes within the said City or shall suffer any Wood Faggots Goods or Commodities of
any Sort or Kind whatsoever landed out of or to be loaden in any Ship Barke or Vessell to lye and remaine in
any of the said publick Streets or Lanes or on any of the Wharfes Backs or Keys of the said City above the
Space of Twenty four Houres without the Licence of the Mayor for the time being and One of the Justices of the
Peace of the said City shall for every such Offence for every Twenty four Houres till the same be removed
forfeite the Summ of Five Shillings</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Mayor and Common Council may make Rules for regulating the Markets in Broad Street and Wine Street, 
and for removing Dirt, &amp;c; Persons not obeying such Regulations; Penalty 10s., or committed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And whereas the Dirt and Filth of the said City is very much increased upon Satturdaies weekely by reason of
Two great Marketts on that Day the one in Broadstreete and the other in Highstreete and Winestreete in the said
City and the People resorting to the said Marketts are very disorderly in their Standing and not observing fitt and
seasonable Houres and Times in leaving and departing from the said Marketts which occasions great Inconveniencies
to the Citizens in many respects and particulerly by their long Stay in the said Marketts soe that the Dirt and
Filth ariseing thence cannot be removed timely before Sunday Morning Be it therefore hereby enacted That the
Mayor and Common Councill of the said City shall have full Power and Authority from time to time to make
good wholsome and reasonable Rules Orders and Constitutions for the regulating ordering and governing the said
Two Marketts and all People thereto resorting in all Matters which doe or may concerne or relate to the said

Marketts and what Space of Time and how long Persons comeing to the said Marketts shall or may remaine and
abide there and for the Removall and carrying away of all Dirt and Filth which shall be made there on the said
Markett Daies in such due Time as the said Streets may be conveniently cleansed before Sunday Morning which
said Rules Orders and Constitutions soe to be made as aforesaid all Persons comeing and resorting to the said
Marketts are hereby required to observe and keepe And all and every such Person and Persons who shall
wilfully and obstinately refuse to obey observe and keepe such Rules Orders and Constitutions shall pay and
forfeite the Summ of Tenn Shillings for every such Offence and in case of Refusall to pay the same such Person
or Persons shall or may be committed untill he or she find good Sureties to appeare at the next Quarter Sessions
of the Peace to be held for the said City and County to answer the said Contempt and Offence</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Mayor, Burgesses, and Commonalty constituted Conservators of the River Avon, as herein mentioned; Persons indicted for Offences, bound over to appear by Recognizance at the next Quarter Sessions</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And whereas the Mayor Burgesses and Commonalty of the City of Bristoll are already Conservators of the
River Avon from Tower Harratz above the Bridge of Bristoll to King-Road or Avon-Road and soe downe the
River Severne to the Two small Islands called the Stipe-Holme and Flat-Holme Be it hereby enacted That the said
Mayor Burgesses and Commonalty and their Successors be and are hereby alsoe made constituted and appointed
Conservators of the said River Avon from Tower Harratz aforesaid to Hannams-Mills aforesaid being about Four
Miles Eastward of the said City upon the said River And that the said Court of Quarter Sessions of the Peace
to be held for the said City and County have and are hereby authorized to have and take Cognizance of and
to punnish all Nusances Obstructions and Impediments whatsoever committed done or suffered or to be committed
done or suffered in or upon the said River Avon from High Watermarke to the Bottom of the said River from
Hannam-Mills aforesaid downe to the said City and from thence to the said Port of King-Road or Avon-Road
And that every Person and Persons who shall be indicted in the said Court for such Nusances Obstructions or
Impediments upon any Part of the said River within the Bounds and Limitts aforesaid upon Notice and Certificate
under the Hand and Seale of the Mayor of the said City of the Contents of such Indictments to any Justice or
Justices of the Peace of the County where such Offender lives or shall be found such Person or Persons soe
indicted shall by the said Justice or Justices be bound over by Recognizance of good Penalty with sufficient Sureties
to appeare at the next Quarter Sessions of the Peace to be held for the said City and County of Bristoll to
answer to the said Indictment soe found against him</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Mayor and Justices in Quarter Sessions may make Rules and appoint Officers for Government of the said River and of Pilots, Masters of Ships, &amp;c. and may impose Fines</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And whereas all things necessary for the Conservation of the said Rivers and the Navigation thereof and the
well ruleing governing and ordering of Pilotts Masters of Shipps Barkes and other Vessells and the anchoring
mooring and removing [of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] such Shipps and Vessells cannot be foreseene It is hereby further enacted by the
Authority aforesaid That the Mayor and Justices of (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) the said City may at the Generall Quarter Sessions to (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) be held
for the said City from time to time as Occasion shall require make such good Rules Orders and Constitutions and
nominate and appoint such Officer or Officers as shall be necessary for the Preservation of the said Rivers and
Regulation and Government of all Pilotts Masters of Shipps and other Vessells navigating to and from the said City
and of all Shipps Barks and other Vessells comeing into lying or abideing within the said Rivers Avon and Froome
or either of them and the Creekes and Harbours within the same and for the anchoring mooring and removeing
of such Shipps and Vessells and in the said Court to impose such reasonable Fines and Forfeitures upon voluntary
and obstinate Infringers and Violaters of such Orders and Constitutions as shall be consistent with Reason Justice
and the Laws of this Kingdom and alsoe to appoint and sett downe the Methods how such Fines and Forfeitures
shall be levied and recovered</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Such Fines to be reasonable, and may be levied by Distress.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Application thereof</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">Provided alwaies neverthelesse That all Fines and Forfeitures to be imposed and laid upon Offenders by such
Rules Orders and Constitutions by virtue of this Act be reasonable and no greater or more penall than the Nature
of the Offence shall require or more grievous or greater to and upon Strangers or Forreigners trading to the said
City than to the Citizens and Inhabitants thereof And alsoe that all Fines and Forfeitures imposed or to be imposed
and laid by vertue of this Act shall upon Conviction of the Party soe offending upon the Oath or Oaths of One or
more credible Witnesses before the Mayor and any One other Justice of the Peace for the said City be levied by
Distresse and Sale of the Offenders Goods rendring to him the Overplus if any shall be necessary Charges for
takeing such Distresse being first deducted and when levied shall from time to time be solely applied for the
Preservation and Benefitt of the Navigation of the said Rivers or for the repairing and amending of the High waies
within the Liberties of the said City as to the Justices of the Peace in their Generall Quarter Sessions of the Peace
to be held for the said City or the major Part of them it shall seeme most reasonable and convenient</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Surveyors under Stat. 3W.&amp;M. c. 12. to be continued; Their Duty. Refusing to take Office or neglecting the Performance of it; Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And to the Intent and Purpose That the Streets Lanes and Publick Places within the said City of Bristoll
may alwaies hereafter be kept free from all Filth Ashes Dirt and Dust which may any way annoy or prejudice
the said Rivers or either of them or be offensive to the Citizens and Inhabitants of the said City and that proper
Officers for that Purpose may be appointed with the least Burden to the Inhabitants It is hereby enacted That
all and every such Person and Persons who now are or shall from henceforth within the said City be nominated
and appointed to be Surveyor or Surveyors of the Highwaies within the severall Parishes and Precincts of the said
City by force and virtue of an Act of Parliament made in the Third and Fourth Yeare of His present Majesties
Reigne and the late Queene Mary of ever blessed Memory intituled An Act for the better repairing and amending
of the High waies and for settling the Rates of Carriage of Goods shall for the Time that he or they shall
continue in that Office have alsoe the Care of cleansing of the said Streets Lanes and Publick Places within the
severall Precincts and Parishes for which he or they were or shall be chosen as aforesaid subject to such Orders
and in such Manner as shall be directed by the said Mayor and Justices as aforesaid and all and every Person
and Persons soe chosen or to be chosen and appointed by vertue of the said Act are hereby required within
Six Daies after such Appointment to take upon them the Charge and Care of cleansing the said Streets Lanes
and Publick Places as well as the said Office of Surveyor or Surveyors of the Highwaies within their respective
Parishes and Precincts And whosoever of them shall refuse deny or delay to take upon him the said Office or
wilfully neglect the Performance of the Duty thereof according to the true Intent and Meaneing of this Act
shall forfeite for every such Refusall Deniall or Neglect the Summ of Five Pounds to be levied by Distresse
in Manner as is aforesaid and for want of such Distresse by Imprisonment of the Offender untill Payment thereof
be made and in case of absolute Deniall or Refusall to serve the said Office or Offices others shall be chosen
into the Roome or Place of such Person or Persons soe refuseing or denying in Manner as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Churchwardens, &amp;c. of the City to meet, upon Notice, and settle Rates; to be allowed and confirmed by Two or more Justices, and the Mayor or One Justice may levy the same Quarterly.</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Such Persons not meeting or not collecting Rate; Penalty &pound;5; Persons assessed refusing or neglecting to pay; Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Church-wardens Overseers of the Poor and
Surveyors of the High-waies of the severall Parishes and Precincts within the said City respectively shall and are
hereby required to convene within Fourteene Daies after the Election of the said Surveyors at some Publick Place
within their respective Parishes or Precincts upon Notice of the Day and Place to be given by One of the
Churchwardens of the said Parish who is hereby required to give Notice accordingly and they or the greater
Number of them there present are hereby required to make and settle a Rate or Rates Assessment or Assessments
upon the severall Inhabitants of the said respective Parishes and Precincts according to their severall Abilities for
the Yeare following for the cleanseing of the said Streets Lanes and Publick Places which shall be allowed and
confirmed by Two or more Justices of the Peace of the said City whereof the Mayor for the Time being to be
one And after the said Rate soe made and confirmed the said Mayor and any one of the said Justices shall have
Power and are hereby required to cause the same to be levied and to appoint Collectors for collecting the same
by Quarterly Payments within the severall Parishes or Precincts of the said City for which they are soe appointed
Collectors and if any such Person or Persons shall wilfully and obstinately refuse or neglect to convene assesse
or collect as aforesaid being thereunto summoned and appointed as aforesaid every such Person and Persons shall
forfeite the Summ of Five Pounds and in case any Person or Persons soe assessed shall refuse or neglect to pay
the same by the Space of Four Daies next after Demand thereof made it shall and may be lawfull for the said
Collectors by Warrant under the Hands and Seales of the said Mayor and any one or more of the said Justices
to levy the same by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of any such Person or Persons rendring to him or them
the Overplus if any shall be after the necessary Charge for takeing such Distresse is first deducted</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Persons aggrieved by Penalties or Assessments may appeal to Quarter Sessions.</head>
			<para id="p25">Provided alwaies That if any Person or Persons shall find themselves aggrieved by any Summ or Summs
soe charged upon him or them by any Assessment or by any Penalty imposed for refusall or neglect to serve
such Office of Surveyor of the High waies and takeing care of the cleansing of the said Streets Lanes and
Publick Places or for not conveneing assessing or collecting as aforesaid such Person or Persons may appeale
to the next Quarter Sessions of the Peace held for the said City and County who have hereby Power and
Authority finally to determine the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Surveyors and Collectors to account yearly to the Persons herein mentioned,
and pay over Money in Hand to succeeding Surveyor; refusing or neglecting to account or pay, committed.</head>
			<para id="p26">And be it further enacted That such Summ or Summs of Money as shall be assessed and collected in the
said Parishes or Precincts for cleansing the Streets shall be Yearly accounted for by the said Surveyors or Collectors
thereof for the Time being to Two or more of the Justices of the Peace of the said City the Mayor for the Time
being or the Alderman of each respective Ward or Precinct to be one within Ten Daies after the Election of
the new Surveyors of the High waies for the ensueing Yeare and such Summ or Summs of Money as shall be
remaining in their Hands shall be by them paid over to the next succeeding Surveyor of the High waies elected
and appointed for such Parish or Precinct And the Mayor for the Time being and any Two Justices of the
Peace of the said City shall and may by vertue hereof committ to Prison such Surveyors or Collectors who shall
refuse or neglect to account or pay the Money remaining in his or their Hands there to remaine without Baile
or Mainprize untill he or they have made a true Account and satisfied and paid soe much as upon the said
Account shall be remaining in his or their Hands</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Proceedings to be had by the Ward of the Castle Precinct for repairing Highways, and settling Rates for Carriage of Goods.</head>
			<para id="p27">And whereas the Ward of the Castle Precinct hath no such Officers as Churchwardens within the same Be
it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Alderman of the Ward of the said Precinct for the Time being
shall within the Time for that Purpose mentioned in the Act for the better repairing and amending of the High
waies and for settling the Rates of the Carriage of Goods give Notice to the Guardians of the Poor Overseers
of the Poor and Six other Principall Inhabitants of the said Precinct to meet and convene at some certaine Time
and Place to be appointed by the Alderman of the said Precinct which Notice they are hereby required to obey
and such Persons soe mett or the major Part of them shall have the same Power in the Premisses to all Intents
and Purposes as the Church-wardens and Overseers of the Poor have in other Parishes of the said City</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Proviso for Rights of Fishing, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p28">Provided alwaies That nothing in this Act contained shall be construed to abridge [dimish<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] or take away the
Right Benefitt or lawfull Use that the Lord or Lords of any Mannor or Mannors adjoyneing to or bordering
upon the said Rivers or any other Person or Persons whatsoever have to the said Rivers or Banks thereof or any
Fishery or Royalties therein but shall be only construed strongly to remove prevent and punish all Obstructions
Nusances and Impediments committted or suffered to be done by any Person or Persons whatsoever to or upon
the said Rivers which may any waies obstruct incommode interrupt or hinder Navigation in and upon the said
Rivers within the Bounds and Limmitts aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Proviso for Rights of the City upon the Rivers of Avon, Froome, and Severn.</head>
			<para id="p29">Provided alsoe That nothing herein contained shall extend to abridge diminish or limmitt any former or other
Jurisdiction or Right into or upon the said Rivers of Avon Froome and Severne which the Mayor Burgesses and
Commonalty of the said City of Bristoll were possessed of or had a Right unto by Charter Custome or otherwise
howsoever before the passing of this Act.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. In Actions for executing Act,</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">General Issue may be pleaded; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">And for preventing Vexatious and Troublesome Prosecutions in or by Reason of the Execution of this Act
Be it further enacted That if any Action Suit Plaint or Information shall at any Time hereafter be commenced
or prosecuted against any Person or Persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in Execution of this
Act such Person or Persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall and may plead the Generall Issue and upon
Issue joyned may give this Act and the Speciall Matters in Evidence as the Case shall require And if the Plaintiffe
or Prosecutor shall become Nonsuite or suffer Discontinuance or if a Verdict passe against him or her the Defendant
and Defendants shall recover their Treble Costs for which they shall have the like Remedy as in any Case
wherein Costs by Law are given to Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Householders herein described to hang out Lanthorns at Night.</head>
			<para id="p32">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every Householder chargeable with Two Pence or
more by the Weeke to the Releife of the Poor and whose House adjoynes to any Publick Street or Lane within
the said City from Michaelmas to Lady Day Yearly shall every Night set or hang out Candles or Lights in
Lanthorns on the outside of their respective Houses next the Street or Lane to inlighten the same for the
Conveniency of Passengers from Time to Time as it shall grow Darke untill Twelve of the Clock at Night upon
Paine of forfeiting Two Shillings for every Default.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Proviso for such Inhabitants as agree to use Lamps approved by Quarter Sessions.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided alwaies and it is hereby enacted That if the Inhabitants of any Parish or Precinct within the said
City paying as aforesaid towards the Releife of the Poor of that Parish or Precinct or the major Part of them
shall agree to make use of Lamps of such Sort and soe to be placed as shall be approved of by the Justices of
the Peace in their Generall Quarter Sessions of the Peace for the said City that then and in such Case nothing
herein before contained shall extend to oblige any of the Inhabitants of such Parish or Precinct to sett or hang
out any Candles or other Lights before their respective Houses.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Persons who are authorized to make Rates may make also an Assessment for Lamps.</head>
			<para id="p34">And be it further enacted That it shall and may be lawfull for the Persons herein before authorized and
appointed to make a Rate for cleansing of the Streets of the said City And they are hereby required in the
severall Parishes or Precincts where such Agreements shall be to make alsoe an Assessment or Assessments for
erecting and maintaining from Time to Time such Publick Lamps within their respective Parishes or Precincts
to be assessed allowed of levied collected and accounted for in such Manner and under the like Penalties as is
herein before directed and appointed for and concerning the Assessments for the cleansing of the Streets of the
said City.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll; omitted in King's Printer's Copy.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">diminish <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


