<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46986" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1700 &amp; 1701</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act for the further Limitation of the Crown and better securing the Rights and Liberties of the Subject [Rot. Parl. 12 &amp; 13 Gul. III. p. 1. n. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Stat. 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 2. s.2;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that the late Queen and Duke of Gloucester are dead; and that His Majesty had recommended from the Throne a further Provision for the Succession 
of the Crown in the Protestant Line; The Princess Sophia, Electress and Duchess Dowager of Hanover, Daughter of the late Queen of Bohemia.; Daughter of King James the First, to inherit after the King and the Princess Anne, in Default of Issue of the said Princess and His Majesty, respectively; and the Heirs of her Body, being Protestants</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in the First Year of the Reign of Your Majesty and of our late most gracious Sovereign Lady
Queen Mary (of blessed Memory) An Act of Parliament was made intituled [An Act for declaring the
Rights and Liberties of the Subject and for setling the Succession of the Crown] wherein it was (amongst other
things) enacted established and declared That the Crown and Regall Government of the Kingdoms of England
France and Ireland and the Dominions thereunto belonging should be and continue to Your Majestie and the said
late Queen during the joynt Lives of Your Majesty and the said Queen and to the Survivor And that after the
Decease of Your Majesty and of the said Queen the said Crown and Regall Government should be and remain to
the Heirs of the Body of the said late Queen And for Default of such Issue to Her Royall Highness the Princess
Ann of Denmark and the Heirs of Her Body And for Default of such Issue to the Heirs of the Body of Your
Majesty And it was thereby further enacted That all and every Person and Persons that then were or afterwards
should be reconciled to or shall hold Communion with the See or Church of Rome or should professe the Popish
Religion or marry a Papist should be excluded and are by that Act made for ever [incapable<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to inherit possess or
enjoy the Crown and Government of this Realm and Ireland and the Dominions thereunto belonging or any part
of the same or to have use or exercise any regall Power Authority or Jurisdiction within the same And in all
and every such Case and Cases the People of these Realms shall be and are thereby absolved of their Allegiance
And that the said Crown and Government shall from time to time descend to and be enjoyed by such Person or
Persons being Protestants as should have inherited and enjoyed the same in case the said Person or Persons so
reconciled holding Communion professing or marrying as aforesaid were naturally dead After the making of which
Statute and the Settlement therein contained Your Majesties good Subjects who were restored to the full and free
Possession and Enjoyment of their [Religion<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Rights and Liberties by the Providence of God giving Success to
Your Majesties just Undertakings and unwearied Endeavours for that Purpose had no greater temporall Felicity to
hope or wish for then to see a Royall Progeny descending from Your Majesty to whom (under God) they owe
their Tranquility and whose Ancestors have for many Years been principall Assertors of the reformed Religion and
the Liberties of [Europe<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and from our said most gracious Sovereign Lady whose Memory will always be precious
to the Subjects of these Realms And it having since pleased Almighty God to take away our said Sovereign Lady and
also the most hopefull Prince William Duke of Gloucester (the only surviving Issue of Her Royall Highness the
Princess Ann of Denmark) to the unspeakable Grief and Sorrow of Your Majesty and Your said good Subjects
who under such Losses being sensibly put in mind that it standeth wholly in the Pleasure of Almighty God to
prolong the Lives of Your Majesty and of Her Royall Highness and to grant to Your Majesty or to Her Royall
Highness such Issue as may be inheritable to the Crown and Regall Government aforesaid by the respective
Limitations in the said recited Act contained doe constantly implore the Divine Mercy for those Blessings And
Your Majesties said Subjects having Daily Experience of Your Royall Care and Concern for the present and future
Wellfare of these Kingdoms and particularly recommending from Your Throne a further Provision to be made for
the Succession of the Crown in the Protestant Line for the Happiness of the Nation and the Security of our
Religion And it being absolutely necessary for the Safety Peace and Quiet of this [Realm<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to obviate all Doubts
and Contentions in the same by reason of any pretended Titles to the [Crown<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and to maintain a Certainty in
the Succession thereof to which Your Subjects may safely have Recourse for their Protection in case the Limitations
in the said recited [Act<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] should determine Therefore for a further Provision of the Succession of the Crown in
the Protestant Line We Your Majesties most dutifull and Loyall Subjects the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
Commons in this present Parliament assembled do beseech Your Majesty that it may be enacted and declared and
be it enacted and declared by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Co[m]mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same
That the most Excellent Princess Sophia Electress and Dutchess Dowager of Hannover Daughter of the most
Excellent Princess Elizabeth late Queen of Bohemia Daughter of our late Sovereign Lord King James the First
of happy Memory be and is hereby declared to be the next in Succession in the Protestant Line to the Imperiall
Crown and Dignity of the [said<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Realms of England France and Ireland with the Dominions and Territories
thereunto belonging after His Majesty and the Princess Ann of Denmark and in Default of Issue of the said
Princess Ann and of His Majesty respectively and that from and after the Deceases of His said Majesty our now
Sovereign Lord and of Her Royall Highness the Princess Ann of Denmark and for Default of Issue of the said
Princess Ann and of His Majesty respectively the Crown and Regall Government of the said Kingdoms of England
France and Ireland and of the Dominions thereunto belonging with the Royall State and Dignity of the said
Realms and all Honours Stiles Titles Regalities Prerogatives Powers Jurisdictions and Authorities to the same
belonging and appertaining shall be remain and continue to the said most Excellent Princess Sophia and the Heirs
of Her Body being Protestants And thereunto the said Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons shall and
will in the Name of all the People of this Realm most humbly and faithfully submitt themselves their Heirs and
Posterities and do faithfully promise That after the Deceases of His Majesty and Her Royall Highness and the
failure of the Heirs of their respective Bodies to stand to maintain and defend the said Princess Sophia and the
Heirs of Her Body being [Protestants<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] according to the Limitation and Succession of the Crown in this Act
specified and contained to the utmost of their Powers with their Lives and Estates against all Persons whatsoever
that shall attempt any thing to the contrary.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The Persons inheritable by this Act, holding Communion with the Church of Rome, incapacitated as by the former Act;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">to take the Oath at their Coronation, according to Stat. 1 W. &amp; M. c. 6</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided always and it is hereby enacted That all and every Person and Persons who shall or may take or
inherit the said Crown by vertue of the Limitation of this present Act and is are or shall be reconciled to or shall
hold Communion with the See or Church of Rome or shall profess the Popish Religion or shall marry a Papist
shall be subject to such Incapacities as in such Case or Cases are by the said recited Act provided enacted and
established And that every King and Queen of this Realm who shall come to and succeed in the Imperiall Crown
of this Kingdom by vertue of this Act shall have the Coronation Oath administred to him her or them at their
respective Coronations according to the Act of Parliament made in the First Year of the Reign of His Majesty and
the said late Queen Mary intituled An Act for establishing the Coronation Oath and shall make subscribe and
repeat the Declaration in the Act first above recited mentioned or referred to in the Manner and Form thereby
prescribed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Further Provisions for securing the Religion, Laws, and Liberties of these Realms.</head>
			<para id="p5">And whereas it is requisite and necessary that some further Provision be made for securing our Religion Laws
and Liberties from and after the Death of His Majesty and the Princess Ann of Denmark and in default of Issue
of the Body of the said Princess and of His Majesty respectively Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent
Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same</para>
			<para id="p6">That whosoever shall hereafter come to the Possession of this Crown shall joyn in Communion with the Church
of England as by Law established</para>
			<para id="p7">That in case the Crown and Imperiall Dignity of this Realm shall hereafter come to any Person not being a
Native of this Kingdom of England this Nation be not obliged to ingage in any Warr for the Defence of any
Dominions or Territories which do not belong to the Crown of England without the Consent of Parliament</para>
			<para id="p8">That no Person who shall hereafter come to the Possession of this Crown shall go out of the Dominions of
England Scotland or Ireland without Consent of Parliament.</para>
			<para id="p9">That from and after the Time that the further Limitation by this Act shall take Effect all Matters and Things
relating to the well governing of this Kingdom which are properly cognizable in the Privy Councill by the Laws
and Customs of this Realme shall be transacted there and all Resolutions taken thereupon shall be signed by such
of the Privy Councill as shall advise and consent to the same.</para>
			<para id="p10">That after the said Limitation shall take Effect as aforesaid no Person born out of the Kingdoms of England
Scotland or Ireland or the Dominions thereunto belonging (although he be naturalized or made a Denizen (except
such as [are<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] born of English Parents) shall be capable to be of the Privy Councill or a Member of either House
of Parliament or to enjoy any Office or Place of Trust either Civill or Military or to have any Grant of Lands
Tenements or Hereditaments from the Crown to himself or to any other or others in Trust for him</para>
			<para id="p11">That no Person who has an Office or Place of Profit under the King or recieves a Pention from the Crown shall
be capable of serving as a Member of the House of Commons.</para>
			<para id="p12">That after the said Limitation shall take Effect as aforesaid Judges Commissions be made Quam diu se bene
Gesserint and their Salaries ascertained and established but upon the Address of both Houses of Parliament it may
be lawfull to remove them.</para>
			<para id="p13">That no Pardon under the Great Seal of England be pleadable to an Impeachment by the Commons in
Parliament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The Laws and Statutes of the Realm confirmed.</head>
			<para id="p14">And whereas the Laws of England are the Birthright of the People thereof and all the Kings and Queens who
shall ascend the Throne of this Realm ought to administer the Government of the same according to the said
Laws and all their Officers and Ministers ought to serve them respectively according to the same The said Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons do therefore further humbly pray That all the Laws and Statutes of this
Realm for securing the established Religion and the Rights and Liberties of the People thereof and all other Laws
and Statutes of the same now in Force may be ratified and confirmed And the same are by His Majesty by and
with the Advice and Consent of the said Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons and by Authority of the
same ratified and confirmed accordingly.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">uncapable <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


