<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46987" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1700 &amp; 1701</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for preventing any Inconveniencies that may happen by Priviledge of Parliament [Rot. Parl. 12 &amp; 13 Gul. III. p. 1. n. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Actions may be brought against Peers and Members of Parliament, and Judgment given therein during the Intervals of Parliament, as herein mentioned</head>
		<para id="p1">For the preventing all Delays the King or His Subjects may recieve in any of His Courts of Law or Equity
and for their Ease in the Recovery of their Rights and Titles to any Lands Tenements or Hereditaments and
their Debts or other Dues for which they have Cause of Suit or Action Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent
Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present
Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That from and after the Four and twentieth Day of June
One thousand seven hundred and one any Person and Persons shall and may commence and prosecute any Action
or Suit in any of His Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster or High Court of Chancery or [Court of Exchequer
or the Dutchy Court of Lancaster or in the Court of Admiralty and in all Causes matrimoniall and testamentary in
the Court of the Arches the Prerogative Courts of Canterbury and York and the Delegates and all Courts of Appeal<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
against any Peer of this Realm or Lord of Parliament or against any of the Knights Citizens and Burgesses of the
House of Commons for the Time being or against their or any of their meniall or other Servants or any other
Person intituled to the Priviledge of Parliament at any Time [from and immediately after the Dissolution or Prorogation
of any Parliament until a new Parliament shall meet or the same be reassembled and from and immediately after
any Adjournment of both Houses of Parliament for above the Space of Fourteen Days untill both Houses shall meet
or reassemble<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] And that the said respective Courts shall and may after such Dissolution Prorogation or Adjournment
as aforesaid proceed to give Judgment and to make finall Orders Decrees and Sentences and award Execution
thereupon Any Priviledge of Parliament to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso against Arrest of Members during Time of Priviledge; but Process may be had against Peers, as herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Proceedings against Members of the House of Commons during the Intervals of Parliament; and for Proceedings against Peers and Members in Courts of Equity and Duchy Court; Members not to be arrested during Time of Priviledge</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">Provided neverthelesse that this Act shall not extend to subject the Person of any of the Knights Citizens and
Burgesses of the House of [Commons<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] [or any other Person intituled to the Priviledge of Parliament to be arrested
during the Time of Priviledge<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Nevertheless if any Person or Persons having Cause of Action or Complaint against
any Peer of this Realm or Lord of Parliament [such Person or Persons after any Dissolution Prorogation or
Adjournment as aforesaid or before any Sessions of Parliament or Meeting of both Houses as aforesaid shall and
may have such Process out of His Majesties Courts of Kings Bench Common Pleas and Exchequer against such
Peer or Lord of Parliament as he or they might have had against him out of the Time of Priviledge and if any
Person or Persons having Cause of Action<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] against any of the said Knights Citizens or Burgesses or any other Person
intituled to Priviledge of Parliament after any Dissolution Prorogation or such Adjournment as aforesaid or before
any Sessions of Parliament or Meeting of both Houses as aforesaid such Person or Persons shall and may prosecute
such Knight Citizen or Burgess or other Person intituled to the Priviledge of Parliament in His Majesties Courts of
Kings Bench Common Pleas or Exchequer by Summons and Distress infinite or by originall Bill and Summons
Attachment and Distress infinite thereupon to be issued out of any of the said Courts [of Record<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] which the said
respective Courts are hereby impowered to issue against them or any of them until he or they shall enter a common
Appearance or file common Bail to the Plaintiffs Action according to the Course of each respective Court [And any
Person or Persons having Cause of Suit or Complaint may in the Times aforesaid<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] exhibit any Bill or Complaint
against any Peer of this Realm or Lord of Parliament or against any of the said Knights Citizens or Burgesses or
other Person intituled to the Priviledge of Parliament in the High Court of Chancery Court of Exchequer or Dutchy
Court of Lancaster and may proceed thereupon by Letter or Subpena [as is usuall<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and upon leaving a Copy of
the Bill with the Defendant or at his House or Lodging or last Place of Abode may proceed thereon and for Want
of an Appearance or Answer or for Non Performance of any Order or Decree or Breach thereof may sequester
the Reall and Personall Estate of the Party as is used and practised where the Defendant is a Peer of this Realm
but shall not arrest or imprison the Body of any of the said Knights Citizens &amp; Burgesses or other priviledged
Person during the Continuance of Priviledge of Parliament</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso in respect of Bar by Statute of Limitations, where Plaintiff stayed by Priviledge of Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That where any Plaintiffe shall by Reason or Occasion of Priviledge
of Parliament be stayed or prevented from prosecuting any Suit by him commenced such Plaintiff shall not be
barred by any Statute of Limitation or nonsuited dismissed [or<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] his Suit discontinued for Want of Prosecution of the
Suit by him begun but shall from Time to Time upon the rising of the Parliament be at Liberty to proceed to
Judgment and Execution</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proceedings at Law or in Equity against Debtors to the King, not stayed by Priviledge of Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Freedom from Arrest</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And it is hereby enacted That no Action Suit Process Order Judgment Decree or Proceeding in Law or Equity
against the Kings originall and immediate Debtor for the Recovery or obtaining of any Debt or Duty originally and
immediately due or payable unto His Majesty His Heirs or Successors or against any Accomptant or Person
answereable or liable to render any Account unto His Majesty His Heirs or Successors for any Part or Branch of
any of his or their Revenues or other originall [or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] immediate Debt or Duty or the Execution of any such Process
Order Judgment Decree or Proceedings shall be impeached stayed or delayed by or under the Colour or Pretence
of any Priviledge of Parliament yet so nevertheless that the Person or Persons of any such Debtor or Accomptant
or Person answereable or liable to account being a Pee of this Realm or Lord of Parliament shall not be liable to
be arrested or imprisoned by or upon any such Suit Order Judgment Decree Process or Proceedings or being a
Member of the House of Commons shall not during the Continuance of the Priviledge of Parliament be arrested or
imprisoned by or upon any such Order Judgment Decree Process or Proceedings.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No further Jurisdiction given to Courts than before this Act.</head>
			<para id="p7">[Provided novertheless That neither this Act nor any thing therein contained shall extend to give any Jurisdiction
Power or Authority to any Court to hold Plea in any reall or mixt Action in any other Manner than such Court
might have done before the making this Act<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">nor <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


