<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46990" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1700 &amp; 1701</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act for continuing the Acts therein mentioned for preventing Theft and Rapine upon the Northern Borders of England [Rot. Parl. 12 &sect; 13 Gul. III. p. 1. n. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Stat. 14 Car. II. c. 22</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">18 &amp; 19 Car. II. c. 5; 29 &amp; 30 Car. II. c. 2; 1 Jac. II. c. 14; and 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c.17; All the said Acts continued</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in the Session of Parliament holden in the Thirteenth and Fourteenth Years of the Reign of
our late Sovereign King Charles the Second an Act was made intituled An Act for preventing [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
Theft and Rapine upon the Northern Borders of England which was thereby to continue in force for and during
the Term of Five Years And whereas another Act was made in the Eighteenth Year of the said late King intituled
An Act to continue a former Act to prevent Thest and Rapine upon the Northern Borders of England both which
Acts were revived and continued by another Act made in the Twenty ninth and Thirtieth Years of the Reign
of the said late King intituled An Act for continuing of Two former Acts for preventing of Theft and Rapine
upon the Northern Borders of England for and during the Space and Terme of Seven Years and also from thence
untill the End of the First Session of the then next Parliament which Three aforementioned Acts were continued
by an Act made in the First Year of the late King James the Second for and during the Space and Term of
Eleven Years and also from thence untill the End of the First Session of the then [next<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Parliament and were
further continued by another Act made in the Seventh and Eighth Years of His present Majesties Reign for and
during the Space and Term of Five Years and from thence [to<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] the End of the First Session of the next Parliament
which Laws have been found necessary for the Preservation of those Places from that great Number of lewd
disorderly and lawless Persons that usually frequented and infested those Parts and are now near expiring Be it
therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons in Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That the said Acts and
[all and<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] every of them and all and every Matter Clause and Clauses therein contained and all and every the
Powers and Authorities thereby given be and continue and are hereby continued in full force from and after the
Expiration of the last mentioned Act for and during the Space and Term of Eleven Years and from thence to the
End of the First Session of the next Parliament and no longer.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The said Acts to be taken as Public Acts</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided always and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the said Acts shall be accepted taken and
reputed to be Generall and Publick Acts of Parliament of which all and every the Judge and Judges of this
Kingdom in all Courts shall take Notice on all Occasions whatsoever as if they were Publick Acts of Parliament
relating to the whole Kingdom Any thing therein contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


