<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46998" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1700 &amp; 1701</title>
	<subtitle>The Private Acts</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Item quedam Petitiones privatas Personas concernentes in se form Actuum continentes exhibite fuerunt predicto Domino Regi in Parliamento predicto quorum Tituli subscribuntur viz<ref idref="n1">1</ref>.</head>
		<para id="p1">i. An Act for the more speedy Payment of the Creditors of James late Duke of Ormond and of the present
Duke of Ormond</para>
		<para id="p2">ij. An Act to enable the Right Honourable Elizabeth Viscountess Bulkley of Cashells in the Kingdom of
Ireland to sell certain Lands in the County of Devon and City and County of the City of Exon for the Payment
of Debts.</para>
		<para id="p3">iij. An Act to enable Robert Lord Viscount Kilmorey of the Kingdom of Ireland (being an Infant) to settle
divers Mannors [Lands<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] and Hereditaments in the Kingdom of England upon a Treaty of Marriage.</para>
		<para id="p4">iiij. An Act to enable Sir Charles Barrington Baronet to settle a Joynture and make Provision for his younger
Children</para>
		<para id="p5">v. An Act to enable Sir Robert Marsham Knight and Baronet to dispose of Lands in Hertfordshire and to settle
other Lands of better Value in Kent to the same Uses as the Lands in Hertfordshire are settled</para>
		<para id="p6">vj. An Act for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the Borough of Kings Lynn in the County of Norfolke
for the better imploying and maintaining the Poor there.</para>
		<para id="p7">vij. An Act for erecting a Court of Request or Conscience in the City and County of the City of Norwich for
the Recovery of small Debts under Forty Shillings.</para>
		<para id="p8">viij. An Act to enable Stephen Jermyn to make Provision for his Younger Children and for the Advancement
of his eldest Son.</para>
		<para id="p9">viiij. An Act for the vesting and settling divers Mannors and Lands in South Pickenham and other Places in the
County of Norfolke in Trustees to be sold and for laying out the Moneys arising by Sale thereof in the Purchase
of other Lands to be settled to such and the same Uses as the said Mannors and Lands so to be vested are and
stand settled</para>
		<para id="p10">x. An Act for discharging a Mortgage upon the Estate of Peter Trevisa Esquire deceased and providing a
Maintenance for his Widow and Children</para>
		<para id="p11">xj. An Act for the more speedy Payment of the Debts of Christopher Killiow Esquire and for the raising Portions
and Maintenance for his Brothers and Sisters in pursuance of his Fathers Will</para>
		<para id="p12">xij. An Act for vesting the Estate of Humphrey Hide Esquire deceased in Trustees for raising Portions for his
younger Children.</para>
		<para id="p13">xiij. An Act for furnishing the Town of New Deal with fresh Water.</para>
		<para id="p14">xiiij. An Act for vesting a Messuage and Lands in Stevenage in the County of Hertford the Estate of Richard
Nodes in Trustees to be sold for making a Provision for his Wife and Children equal to the Provision secured to
them out of the said Estate</para>
		<para id="p15">xv. An Act for Sale of the Estate of William Davison Esquire deceased for Payment of Debts and raising his
Childrens Portions charged thereupon.</para>
		<para id="p16">xvj. An Act for separating James Earl of Anglesea from Katharine Countess of Anglesea his Wife for the Cruelty
of the said Earl</para>
		<para id="p17">xvij An Act for dissolving the Marriage of Sir John Dillon with Mary Boyle and for other Purposes therein
mentioned</para>
		<para id="p18">xviij. An Act to dissolve the Marriage of Ralph Box with Elizabeth Eyre and to enable him to marry again</para>
		<para id="p19">xviiij An Act for the vesting several Messuages Lands and Tenements belonging to John Fawconer Esquire in
Trustees to be sold for Payment of Debts</para>
		<para id="p20">xx. An Act for transferring a Trust in Lands belonging to the City of London unto new Trustees</para>
		<para id="p21">xxj. An Act for removing the County Goal of Hertford</para>
		<para id="p22">xxij. An Act for the better performance of the last Will of Henry Apsley Esquire deceased</para>
		<para id="p23">xxiij. An Act for vesting the Estate of Thomas Bennet late of Newton cum Barton in the County of Chester in
Trustees for the Use of the poor of Westkirby pursuant to the Will of the said Thomas Bennet</para>
		<para id="p24">xxiiij. An Act to enable William Vaughan Esq<emph type="p">r</emph>
 and Frances Vaughan his intended Wife (being both under the
Age of One and twenty Years) to perform Articles made for their Marriage</para>
		<para id="p25">xxv. An Act to change the Sirname of Ellis Mews and his Heirs to the Sirname Saint John.</para>
		<para id="p26">xxvj. An Act for making [good<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] the Deficiency of the Charges of making a Way out of Chancery Lane into
Lincolns Inn Fields</para>
		<para id="p27">xxvij. An Act for declaring the Will of Sir Joseph Herne Knight dated the Twenty fifth Day of February One
thousand six hundred ninety eight to be taken and esteemed the last Will of the said Sir Joseph Herne.</para>
		<para id="p28">xxviij. An Act for naturalizing Jane Barkstead Widow and vesting several Mortgages and Securities in her to enable
her to convey or assign the same</para>
		<para id="p29">xxviiij. An Act for naturalizing Archibald Arthur and enabling him to dispose of his Estate</para>
		<para id="p30">xxx. An Act for naturalizing Jacob Auguste Pyngot and others.</para>
		<para id="p31">xxxj. An Act for naturalizing Adrian Lofland and others</para>
		<para id="p32">xxxij. An Act to enable Sir Thomas Stanley Bar<emph type="p">t</emph> to charge certain Mannors and Lands in the County of Lancaster
with Three hundred Pounds for Payment of his Sisters Portions and his Debts</para>
		<para id="p33">xxxiij. An Act for the Sale of the Estate of James Deane and for securing the Moneys raised thereby for the
benefit of himself and Family according to the Settlement thereof</para>
		<para id="p34">xxxiiij. An Act to enable Richard Bigg to charge Part of his Estate in the County of Hertford and Bedford
with the Payment of his Debts</para>
		<para id="p35">xxxv. An Act for naturalizing Peter Bagneol Daniel Senault and others</para>
		<para id="p36">xxxvj. An Act for naturalizing Gasper Cordoso Herman Vant Wedde and others.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>

