<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="46997" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1700 &amp; 1701</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An Act to enable His Majesty to make Leases and Copies of Offices Lands and Hereditaments Parcel of His Dutchy of Cornwall or annexed to the same and for Confirmation of Leases already made. [Rot. Parl. 12 &amp; 13 Gul. III. p. 3. n. 2.(<ref idref="n1">1</ref>)]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Former Leases and Grants of Manors, Offices, Lands, &amp;c. in the Duchy of Cornwall, in the Time of Car. II. and Jac. II., or by His Majesty and the late Queen, or by His Majesty alone, as herein mentioned, good and effectual in Law against the Crown, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas many of the Lands belonging to the Dutchy of Cornwall have been granted by Lease to the
Tennants some for the Team of One Two or Three Lives and some for divers Years determinable upon
One Two or Three Lives and others for Thirty one Years or under which Leases are desired to be renewed by
many of the said Tennants And whereas several Years next following after the happy Restauration of His late
Majesty King Charles the Second divers increased Rents were reserved as well upon the said Leased Lands as upon
many Copyhold Estates of the said Dutchy for the Improvement of that Revenue whereof the Tennants made Complaint
[to<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] His said late Majesty who was gratiously pleased that they might compound with His Officers for discharge
of the said increased Rents continuing only the old Rents formerly paid for their respective Tenements and Lands
Now to the End the same may be accordingly effected and the said Tennants may be incouraged to renew their
Leases and Estates and thereby the better enabled to repair their Houses and provide for their Families and to
improve their Lands holden of the said Dutuhy Be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with
the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled
and by the Authority of the same That all Leases and Grants made in the Time of His said late Majesty king
Charles the Second or in the Time of the late King James or by His Majesty King William or the late Queen
Mary or by His said present Majesty since his happy Accession to the Crown or to be made by Copy of Court
Roll according to the Custom of the respective Mannor or Mannors of the said Dutchy or thereunto annexed or
belonging and all Leases and Grants so made by His said Majesty King Charles the Second or by the late King
James or by His Majesty King William and the late Queen Mary or by His present Majesty since His happy.
Accession to the Crown or to be made within Seven Years next ensuing by Letters Patents or Indentures under
the Great Seal of England or Seal of the Court of Exchequer or by Coppy of Court Roll according to the
Custom of the respective Mannors of any Offices Messuages Parks Lands Tenements or Hereditaments (other than
Honors Lordships or Mannors) Parcel of the Possessions of the said Dutchy of Cornwall or annexed to the same
shall be good and effectual in Law according to the Purport and Contents of the same Coppies Leases and Grants
against our Sovereign Lord the King His Heirs and Successors and against all and every other Person and Persons
that shall at any Time hereafter have inherit or enjoy the said Dutchy by force of any Act of Parliament or by
other Limitation whatsoever.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso as to the Estate to be made by such Leases and Grants; and as to the Rent to be reserved.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided always That every such Lease or Grant so made or to be made be not for more than One Two
or Three Lives or for Thirty one Years or under (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) or for some Term of Years determinable upon One Two or Three.
Lives and not above and if such Leases or Grants be made in Reversion or Expectancy that then the same
together with the Estates in Possession do not exceed Three Lives or the Term of Thirty one Years and not in
any wise dispunishable of West and so as upon every such Lease shall be reserved the ancient or most usual
Rent or more or such Rent as hath been reserved yielded or paid for the same Lands for the greater Part of
Twenty Years next before the Year of our Lord One thousand six hundred and sixty hath and shall be reserved
due and payable to him or her that shall have the Inheritance or other Estate of the said Dutchy And where no
such Rent hath been reserved or payable that then upon every such Lease there shall be reserved a reasonable
Rent not being under the Twentieth Part of the clear Yearly Value of the Messuages Parks and Lands Tenements
or Hereditaments contained in such Lease and all Leases and Grants otherwise made or to be made shall be null
and void.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. How and against whom the Covenants, &amp;c. in such Leases, or Grants, &amp;c. are to be good and effectual in Law.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it further ordained and enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Covenants Conditions Reservations
and other Agreements contained in every Lease Grant or Copy of Court Roll made or to be made as aforesaid
shall be good and effectual in Law according to the Words and Contents of the same as well for and against
them to whom the Reversions of the same Lands Tenements and Hereditaments [shall come<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] as for and against
them to whom the Interest of the said Leases Grants or Copies shall come respectively as if our Sovereign Lord
the Kings Majesty at the Time of making such Covenants Conditions and Reservations and other Agreements
were seized of an absolute Estate in Fee Simple in the same Lands Tenements or Hereditaments</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. General Saving.</head>
			<para id="p5">Saving always to all and every Person and Persons Bodies Politick and Corporate their Heirs and Successors
Executors Administrators and Assigns (other than to our said Sovereign Lord the King and His Heirs and Successors
and the Duke and Dukes of Cornwall for the Time being and his and their Heirs and all and every other Person
and Persons that shall hereafter have inherit or enjoy the said Dukedom of Cornwall by force of any Act of
Parliament or other Limitation whatsoever) all such Rights Titles Estates Customs Interests Tenures Claims and
Demands whatsoever of what Nature Kind or Quality soever of in to or out of the said Offices Lands Tenements
or Hereditaments or any of them as they or any of them had or ought to have had before the making of this Act
to all Intents and Purposes and in as large and ample Manner and Form as if this Act had never been had or
made This Act or any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Leasehold and Copyhold Tenants of the Duchy compounding with the Treasury within the next Seven Years for discharging increased Rents.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Upon Composition paid, increased Rent to cease, and the old Rent or Rent upon Composition to be charged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That in case any of the Leasehold or Coppyhold Tennants
of the said Dutchy shall at any Time within Seven Years next ensuing compound or agree with the Lord High
Treasurer of England or Commissioners of the Treasury for the Time being or Chancellor and Undertreasurer of
the Exchequer for the Time being or with any such other Person or Persons as the Lord High Treasurer or
Commissioners of the Treasury for the Time being or Chancellor of the Exchequer for the Time being shall
authorize nominate and appoint for the taking off and discharging [of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] any increased Rent reserved as aforesaid
according to such Rules and Directions as in that behalf shall be given in Writing under the Hands of the said
Lord Treasurer or Commissioners of the Treasury for the Time being or Chancellor of the Exchequer for the
Time being then upon such Composition so made and the Money thereby arising duly paid to the Reciever General
of the said Duchy for the Time being according to the Tenor and Contents of such Composition and Agreement
and accordingly inrolled before the Auditor of the Premisses from thenceforth such increased [Rent<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] shall cease
and become void and the old Rent only or such other Rent as in pursuance of this Act shall be directed in or
by such Composition or Agreement shall be charged on all and every such Tenements Lands and other Hereditaments
for which such Composition Agreement Payment and Inrollment shall be so made and none other Any Reservation
Condition or other Matter whatsoever to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for additional Grants by the Crown of Lands, Part of the Manor of Greenwich</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And whereas His Majesty hath given and granted some Parcells of Ground and part of his Pallace at East Greenwich
in the County of Kent for the erecting theron an Hospital for the Relief of disabled Seamen which may not
appear to be of sufficient extent and Capacity for all the Occasions for Buildings or otherwise as the same may
hereafter necessarily require It is hereby declared and enacted That it is and shall be lawful for His [Majesty<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] His
Heirs or Successors to make any further Grant of Grounds Lands or Edifices lying near or adjoyning to the said
before granted Premisses being Part of his Mannor of Greenwich aforesaid which he shall see necessary and think
fitt to give for the aforesaid Use Any Law Act or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This Act is numbered 2, on the Roll, although it stands the Third Act on this Part, the last Act not being numbered.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">or under <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Majesties <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


