<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47001" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>William III, 1701</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for the Attainder of the pretended Prince of Wales of High Treason [Rot. Parl. 13 &amp; 14 Gul. III. n.3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The pretended Prince of Wales convicted and attainted of High Treason</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the pretended Prince of Wales (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) since the Decease of the late King James by the Incitation and
Encouragement of the French King (being bred up and instructed to introduce the Romish Superstition
and French Government into these Your Majesties Kingdoms) openly and traiterously with design to dethrone
Your Majesty assumed the Name and Title of James the Third King of England Scotland and Ireland and caused
himself to be so proclaimed in the Kingdom of France in manifest Violation of Your Majesties most lawfull and
rightful Title to the Crown of these Realms and of the several Acts of Parliament made as well for recognizing
of the same as for settling the Succession of the Crown contrary to the Duty of his Allegiance and to the
disturbing of the Peace of these Your Majesties Kingdoms to the End therefore that Your Majesties good and
loyal People of England assembled in Parliament may in the most solemn Manner express their utmost Resentment
of so great an Indignity done to Your Majesties most sacred Person and Government and that the said Traitor
may be brought more certainly and speedily to condign Punishment May it please Your Majesty that it may be
enacted And be it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the
Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the
same That the said pretended Prince of Wales stand and be convicted and attainted of High Treason and that
he suffer Pains of Death and incurr all Forfeitures as a Traitor [convicted<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and attainted of High Treason</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Holding Correspondence with, or aiding with Money, &amp;c. the said pretended Prince of Wales or his Agents;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">High Treason</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And for preventing traiterous Correspondence between Your Majesties Subjects and the said pretended Prince
of Wales or his Adherents Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any of the Subjects of the
Crown of England from and after the First Day of March One thousand seven hundred and one shall within
this Realm or without hold entertain or keep any Intelligence or Correspondence in Person or by Letters Messages
or otherwise with the said pretended Prince of Wales or with any Person or Persons imployed by him knowing
such Person to be so imployed or shall by Bill of Exchange or otherwise remitt or pay any Sum or Sums of
Money for the Use or Service of the said pretended Prince of Wales knowing such Money to be for such Use
or Service such Person so offending being lawfully convicted shall be taken deemed and adjudged to be guilty
of High Treason and shall suffer and forfeit as in Cases of High Treason.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Offences out of the Realm, laid in England.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further enacted That where any of the Offences against this Act shall be committed out of this
Realm the same may be alledged and laid enquired of and tryed in any County of this Kingdom of England.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">hath <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


