<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE index SYSTEM "../dtd/index.dtd">
<index id="47018" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>Index</title>
	<subtitle>N</subtitle>
<section id="s1"><head>N.</head>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>National Land Bank</key></head>
		<table id="t1">
			<tr>
				<td cols="3"/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/><th>
Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Established.</td>
				<td>7&amp;8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 31. &sect;10.</td>
				<td>132</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The King, by Commission under the Great Seal, may appoint Persons to take Subscriptions for raising &pound;2,564,000 as herein mentioned, and the said Yearly Sum of &pound;179,480, applied to the Use of Subscribers.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Treasury to direct their Warrant Yearly for the Payment of the said Yearly Sum of &pound;179,480, and the Exchequer to issue the same without Fee.</td>
				<td>&sect;11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The King, by Letters Patent, may incorporate Subscribers by the Name of the Governor of the National Land Bank, who may sue and be sued, &amp;c. and make Bye-Laws.</td>
				<td>&sect; 12.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso if the said &pound;2,564,000, not subscribed before 1st Jan. 1696.</td>
				<td>&sect;13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>After Incorporation, the said Yearly Sum of &pound;179,480, or a proportionable Part thereof, to be paid to the said Bank and their Successors.</td>
				<td>&sect;14.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stock and Interest, Personal Estate.</td>
				<td>&sect;15.</td>
				<td>133</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If the said &pound;2,564,000, not subscribed before 1st August 1696, Power for creating Corporation to cease, and the said Yearly Sum of &pound;179,480 transferrable by Subscribers as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect;16.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Subscriber to pay One-fourth at Time of Subscription, and forfeited on Nonpayment of Residue.</td>
				<td>&sect;17.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons interested as herein mentioned, not to have Interest or Office in Corporation&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect;18.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Company or any Members purchasing Lands or Revenues of the Crown, or advancing Money to the Crown on the Revenues, otherwise than as herein mentioned&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>7&amp;8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 31.&sect;19.</td>
				<td>133</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Corporation not to deal, or suffer Dealings with the Stock&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect;20.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for Sale of Goods being the Produce of Land purchased by Corporation.</td>
				<td>&sect;21.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Fines and Issues against Corporation not pardoned by Privy Seal, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect;22.</td>
				<td>134</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said yearly Sum liable in the Exchequer for Estreats of Fines, &amp;c. on Nonappearance.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said yearly Sum not a Fund for Payment of further Bills of Credit or other Monies, save as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Monies payable by this Act Tax-free.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Upon One Year's Notice, and Repayment of the said &pound;2,564,000, and Arrear of the said yearly Sum, Corporation, &amp;c. to cease as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect;24.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Redemption of the said Fund, or Default of Corporation, nor Judgment against the same, construed a Forfeiture of Estate of Corporation.</td>
				<td>&sect;25.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 20. &sect; 1. &ndash;6 &amp; 7 W. &amp; M. c. 18. &sect; 12., continued as to Duties on Tonnage, Coals, and Culm, until 17th May 1696.</td>
				<td>&sect;26.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The several Sums of &pound;560,000, &pound;140,000, and &pound;140,000, out of the Monies of this Act, appropriated for certain Payments herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 27.</td>
				<td>135</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. I W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 1. applied for the due Application of Monies hereby appropriated.</td>
				<td>7 &amp;8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 31. &sect;28.</td>
				<td>135.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Company to lend &pound;500,000 per Annum on sufficient Land Securities, at Interest. </td>
				<td>&sect;29.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Conveyances of such Lands, or a Note thereof, to be registered by Corporation.</td>
				<td>&sect;30.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How such Lands transferrable and chargeable by Owners.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Bills of Credit by Company on taking Conveyance of Land, to be a Charge on Lands, &amp;c. of the said Corporation, and render them liable to Action of Debt.</td>
				<td>&sect;31.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>In case the Company cannot deliver such Bills of Credit to Owner, repaying Money lent&mdash;Proceedings. </td>
				<td>&sect;32.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Lands discharged and redeemed. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>136</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso where Company charge such Lands with greater Sums of Money than they have lent thereon&mdash;Penalty. </td>
				<td>&sect;33.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Bearer of Company's Bills may have Action of Debt. </td>
				<td>&sect;34. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Forging Common Seal or Bills of Company or Bank of England&mdash;Death. </td>
				<td>&sect;35. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If Interest of Money lent by Company run in Arrear for Two Years together, and Principal Money not paid within Three Years after Demand as herein mentioned, Estate of Debtor may be sold on Notice. </td>
				<td>&sect;36. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Members of House of Commons may be a Member, &amp;c. </td>
				<td>&sect;37.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Infant may become a Contributor. </td>
				<td>&sect; 38.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>It is to be inserted in the Letters Patent that no Person shall execute Office in Corporation without taking the Oath of Stat. I W. &amp; M.c. 8. and the Oath herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect;39.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The Company may subscribe Dockets of Extents, &amp;c. kept in Courts of Record. </td>
				<td>&sect; 40. </td>
				<td>137</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Members, as such, not liable to the Bankrupt Laws. </td>
				<td>&sect; 41.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Naturalization</key>.</head>
		<table id="t2">
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<td/>
				<td/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<th>
Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>
For naturalizing the Children of such Officers and Soldiers, and others, the Natural born Subjects of this Realm, who have been born abroad during the War, the Parents of such Children having been in the Service of this Government. </td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>.20.<emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>380</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Children of Persons, Natural born Subjects, and in the Service of the King, or of the King and the late Queen, born out of the King's Dominions since 13th Feb.1688, and since the beginning, of the War, and before 25th March 1698, declared Natural born Subjects. </td>
				<td>&sect; 1. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And may take Lands, &amp;c. and enjoy Immunities as Natural born Subjects. </td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso respecting Persons expressly named in this Act, attaining the Age of 14 Years, and not within the Space of Five Years, receiving the Sacrament and taking the Oaths of Stat. I W. &amp; M. c.8.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The like Provision as to Persons not expressly named, and respecting the Proof of their Birth, &amp;c. required from such Persons.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>.20. &sect;4.</td>
				<td>380</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons expressly named may at any Time during the said Five Years, be admitted into Courts of Record, to take Oath of having qualified.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>381</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The like Provisions for Persons not expressly named.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And on their so doing, the same to be recorded.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And on Certificate thereof, such Persons entitled to benefits of this Act.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For enabling His Majesty's Natural born Subjects to inherit the Estate of their Ancestors, either Lineal or Collateral, notwithstanding their Father or Mother were Aliens.</td>
				<td>11 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>.6.</td>
				<td>590</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Natural born Subjects within the King's Dominions of Alien Ancestors, inheritable, as if those through whom they make Title had been Natural born Subjects.<br/>
				<emph type="i">This Act explained 25 G. II. c. 39. and extended to Scotland 16 G. III. c</emph>.52.&sect;1. <emph type="i">See</emph> 58 <emph type="i">G.III. c</emph>.98.</td>

				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
				</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Navy</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t3">
			<tr>
				<td cols="3"/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<th>
Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>
For the better preventing the Embezzlement of His Majesty's Stores of War; and preventing Cheats, Frauds, and Abuses in paying Seamen's Wages.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>.41.</td>
				<td>423</td></tr>
<tr><td>No Warlike or Naval Stores, except for the King's Use, to be made with the King's Marks, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Having in Custody such marked Stores, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;200, unless Certificate, &amp;c.<br/>
<emph type="i">Extended to Persons having Timber, &amp;c. marked with the Broad Arrow</emph>,9 <emph type="i">G. I. c</emph>. 8. &sect; 3. <emph type="i">Power to mitigate Penalty</emph>, &sect; 4., and for Reward to Informers, &sect; 8&mdash;10. See further 39&amp;40 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 89. &sect; 1, 2.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>424</td></tr>
<tr><td>Penalty on personating Seamen, or forging Letters of Attorney, Bills of Sale, &amp;c.<br/>
<emph type="i">See 1 G.I. Stat. 2.c. 25. &sect;7. but as to Repeal of this Section, see</emph> 55 <emph type="i">G. III.c</emph>. 60. &sect;1.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td><emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Commissioners of the Navy, Ordnance, &amp;c. may sell, and Buyer may hold any of the said Stores so marked, &amp;c. on producing Certificate of Commissioners.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Quantities to be expressed in Certificate.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>In Actions for executing Act, General Issue may be pleaded&mdash;Treble Costs.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Seamen's Will not to be written on the same Paper with a Letter of Attorney.<br/>
<emph type="i">As to Repeal of this Section, see</emph> 55 <emph type="i">G. III.c</emph>. 60. &sect;1.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>425</td></tr>
<tr><td>Fee to Ecclesiastical Court, &amp;c. for suing forth Letters of Administration of Sea-men dying in the Navy&mdash;Taking-greater Fee, Penalty.<br/>
<emph type="i">As to the Repeal of this Section, see</emph> 31 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 10. &sect;32.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
					<tr>
				<td>King's Stores may be lent to any Ship in Distress, to be restored&mdash;Borrower to have a Certificate.<br/>
				<emph type="i">This Act to be deemed a Public Act,1 G. I. Stat. 2. c. 25. &sect; 14. Who may try Offences</emph>, 17 <emph type="i">G. II. c. 40.&sect; 10. This Act extended to Ireland as therein mentioned, 52 G. III. c. 12. and to all public Stores, 53 G. III. c. 126. which Act is repealed, 55 G. III. c. 127. &sect; 1. see 2. and see 54 G. III. c</emph>.60.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 41. &sect; 8.</td>
				<td>425</td>
			</tr>
			</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Navy and Ordnance</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t4">
			<tr>
				<td cols="3"/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<th>
Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>
For applying to the Use of His Majesty's Navy and Ordnance Overplus of the Money and Stores which were provided (a) for the building 27 Ships of War.<br/>
(a) 2 <emph type="i">W.&amp; M. Sess</emph>. 2.<emph type="i">c</emph>.10. &sect; 6.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 34. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>408</td></tr>
<tr><td>How Overplus Monies, Part of said &pound;570,000, after Payment of Building said Ships, &amp;c. applied.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Treasurer of the Navy accountable for such Overplus Monies.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Needlework</key><emph type="i">See</emph>Importation.
		</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Needwood Forest</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t5">
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<td/>
				<td/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<th>
Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>
For revesting in His Majesty the Honor of Tutbury Forest of Needwood, several Manors, Parks, Lands, and Offices, and other Profits thereunto belonging, and for vacating certain Letters Patents therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>.40.</td>
				<td>157</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Letters Patent 21st Nov. 1683, of Honor and Manor of Tutbury, &amp;c. to Rupert Browne and Samuel Boheme, declared void.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And the said Manor and Honor vested in the Crown as part of the Duchy of Lancaster.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>All Letters Patent, &amp;c. made by Car. II. and Jac.II. relating to the several Offices of the said Honor, &amp;c. declared void.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for certain Keepers, and for certain Letters Patent granted by Car. II.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Divers Officers herein named, or any Five of them, of whom the Axe bearer of the said Forest, or his Deputy, to be one, appointed Commissioners for setting out Wood already fallen, and to be felled, if necessary for Payment to R.Browne of &pound; 3,300 and Interest.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>After such setting out by the said Commissioners, the Property of the said Wood vested in the said Rupert Browne, &amp;c. with Liberty to the said R.Browne, &amp;c. for 10 Years, to enter and cut and carry away
				such Wood, without rendering Account for same; and to make Saw Pits, &amp;c., and to dig Turf and Sand for Coaling such Wood.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>158</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso in case of Payment of the said &pound;3,300 and Interest by the Crown to R.Browne, before 25th March 1697.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>On such Payment, all Securities for the same to be assigned to the Crown or its Appointee.</td>
				<td>7 &amp;8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 40. &sect; 5.</td>
				<td>158</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said Honor and Manor, &amp;c. not to be aliened from the Crown without: the Consent of Parliament.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Such Alienation void.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>General Saving.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Negroes</key>
			<emph type="i">See</emph>Africa.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>New Forest</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t6">
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<td/>
				<td/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<th>
Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>
For the Increase and Preservation of Timber in the New Forest, in the County of Southampton.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W.III. c</emph>.33.</td>
				<td>405</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>2,000 Acres, Part of New Forest, inclosed for Growth of Timber, &amp;c., and set out by Commissioners, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Inclosures, how to be made.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>406.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>200 Acres more to be inclosed yearly for 20 Years, &amp;c. and to remain in Possession of the Crown for ever, as a Nursery for Wood only.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Decayed Trees to be set out for making the Inclosures.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Whenever the Woods growing in the said Inclosures are past Danger of browsing of Deer, &amp;c., so that the same may be laid open, the King may inclose the like Quantity of Acres for so much laid open, &amp;c. free from Common, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Wood not to be felled unless allowed, &amp;c. by Officer.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Nor Coppice Woods cut, &amp;c. until marked, &amp;c. by Officer&mdash; Penalty &pound;50.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Inclosures not to be ploughed or sowed, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Forrester, Keeper, &amp;c. browsing or lopping any Oak or Beech Tree&mdash; Penalty &pound;10 and Incapacity.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Charcoal not to be made in the Forest within 1,000 Paces of any Inclosure, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Coal Hearths to be fenced with Heath, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Penalties 32 Hen. VIII. c. 13. &sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>407</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Breaking down Inclosures, &amp;c.&mdash; Penalties and Imprisonment.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Double Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for Forest Laws, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And for Right of Common of Pasture, &amp;c. in the Forest.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>After Michaelmas 1716, Right of Common of Pasture, continued in Waste Ground (Times excepted.)</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Right of Fuel to adjacent Inhabitants, provided they do not sell the same, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Grant of any the said Inclosures, Trees, &amp;c. void.</td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>When Sale of Wood in the Forest, &amp;c. Notice, and Officer to value before Sale.</td>
				<td>&sect; 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Best Bidder the Purchaser.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Fee, &amp;c. for filling up Trees, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>.33. &sect;12.</td>
				<td>408</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Penalty.<br/>
				<emph type="i">See 29 G. II. c</emph> 36. &sect;1. &ndash;39 &amp; 40 <emph type="i">G.III. c</emph>. 86. &sect;1.&ndash;48 <emph type="i">G.III.c</emph>.72.<br/>
					<emph type="i">See Daby.</emph></td>
				<td>&sect;13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Newfoundland</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t7">
			<tr>
				<td cols="3"/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<th>
Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For encouraging the Trade to.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W.III.c</emph>14.</td>
				<td>515</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Subjects trading to Newfoundland, &amp;c. to enjoy the same, and the Freedom of taking Bait and fishing in the Rivers, &amp;c., and of curing Fish, making Oil, &amp;c. on Shore.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Aliens, &amp;c. not to take Bait or use Trade or Fishing.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Ballast, &amp;c. not to be thrown out of Ships to prejudice the Harbours.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons departing from Newfoundland not to damage Stages or Cook Rooms, &amp;c. which they may have fallen into on coming into the Country.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for Repair of Stages used, by Per-sons coming to Newfoundland.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>What Person is to be Admiral of the Harbour during the Season, who may take such Beech or Flakes as may be needful.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>What Person is to be Vice Admiral and Rear Admiral.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Masters of Fishing Ships to content themselves with such Beech and Flakes as shall be necessary.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons having more Places than one to elect, and send his Election to the next After-comer demanding the same.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>
				</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>In case of Difference, Two of the Admirals may determine the same.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>516</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons who since the Year 1685, have seized and detained Stages, Cook Rooms, &amp;c. to relinquish the same for the public Use.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Fisherman, &amp;c. to possess himself of Stages, &amp;c., which since the Year 1685, belonged, or hereafter shall belong to Ships, &amp;c. before the Arrival of Fishing Ships, and until they shall be provided.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for Persons who since the 25th March 1685, have built Stages, &amp;c. that did not since the said Year 1685, belong to Fishing Ships.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>By-Boatkeepers not to meddle with Stages, Cook Rooms, &amp;c. that since the said Year 1685, belonged to Fishing Ships.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Masters of By-Boats to carry Two fresh Men at least.</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Inhabitants to employ such Two fresh Men.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Masters of Fishing Ships to carry one fresh Man in every Five Men.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Oath by Masters of By-Boats and Ships.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III.c</emph>.14.&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>516</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Certificate of Oath without Fee.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Masters or Owners of Ships to have every Fifth Man a Green Man.</td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons not to expunge or change the Marks of Boats or Trainfats, or use or remove the same without Notice to Admiral and Consent of Owner.</td>
				<td>&sect; 11</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons not to rind Trees, set fire to Woods, or do other unnecessary Damage&mdash; Nor cast Anchor, or do other Acts to hinder the haling of Sayns, &amp;c.&mdash;Nor steal Bait, Nets, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 12.</td>
				<td>517</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Capital Crimes committed in Newfoundland, &amp;c. tried in any County in England.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Admirals to see the Rules and Orders of this Act executed&mdash; And to keep a Journal of Ships, &amp;c. employed, and deliver Copy to Privy Council.</td>
				<td>&sect; 14.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Differences between Masters of Ships, &amp;c: and Inhabitants herein mentioned, to be determined by Admirals.</td>
				<td>&sect; 15.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Appeal.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Sunday to be observed.</td>
				<td>&sect; 16.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tavern Keepers not to sell Wine, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Whale Fins, Oil, and Blubber imported by Greenland Company, not liable to the Duty of 12d. charged by Stat. 8 &amp; 9 W.III. c.24. and 9 W.III. c.23.<br/>
				<emph type="i">Bounties payable as by this Act</emph>, 15 <emph type="i">G. III.c</emph>.31. &sect; 1. <emph type="i">and see</emph>51 <emph type="i">G.III.c</emph>.45.<emph type="i">see</emph> &sect; 13.<emph type="i">of that Act</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>518</td>
			</tr>
			</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>New Hithe</key>
			<emph type="i">See</emph> Colchester.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Northern Borders</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t8">
			<tr>
				<td cols="3"/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<th>
Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For continuing Four former Acts for preventing Theft and Rapine upon the
				Northern Borders of England.</td>
				<td>7&amp;8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 17.</td>
				<td>86</td></tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 13 &amp; 14 Car. II. c.22.(a)&mdash;18 Car. II.c. 3.&ndash; 29 &amp; 30 Car. II. c. 2.&ndash;1 Jac. II. c. 14. continued for Five Years, &amp;c.<br/>
				<emph type="i">(a) Made perpetual</emph>,31 <emph type="i">G.II. c</emph>. 42.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For continuing the Acts therein mentioned, for preventing Theft and Rapine upon the Northern Borders of England.</td>
				<td>12&amp; 13 <emph type="i">W. III. c. </emph>6.</td>
				<td>641</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 14 Car. II. c.22. &ndash;18 &amp; 19 Car.II. c. 3.&ndash;29 &amp; 30 Car. II. c. 2. &ndash;1 Jac.II.c.14. and 7 &amp; 8 W.III. c. 17. continued.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said Acts to be taken as Public Acts.<br/>
				<emph type="i">The several Acts relating to the Northern Borders made perpetual</emph>, 31 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 42. &sect;1.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					</tr>
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Norwood</key>, Chomas <emph type="i">See</emph> Creditors.</head>
	</entry>
</section>
</index>


