<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE index SYSTEM "../dtd/index.dtd">
<index id="47016" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>Index</title>
	<subtitle>L</subtitle>
<section id="s1"><head>L.</head>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Lace</key>
			<emph type="i">See</emph> Importation.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Land Car.</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t1">
			<tr>
				<td cols="3"/>
			</tr>
			<tr><td/>
				<th>Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For granting an Aid to His Majesty by a Land Tax in England.</td>
				<td>11 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>.2.</td>
				<td>545</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Leather</key>
			<emph type="i">See</emph>Ercise.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Lenthall</key>, William <emph type="i">See</emph>Creditors.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Local Acts</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t2">
			<tr>
				<td cols="3"/>
			</tr>
			<tr><td/>
				<th>Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Alveston (in the County of Gloucester) for vesting the Manor of, in Trustees to be sold for Payment of Debts, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III.</emph>
				</td>
				<td>450</td></tr>
<tr><td>Baliol College (Oxford). See Saint Lawrence, Old Jewry.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>159</td></tr>
<tr><td>Barkhamstead (Manor of) to enable Trustees to sell Part of.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Bridgewater, in the County of Somerset, for the enlarging, repairing, and preserving the Bridge and Quay of the Borough of.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 12.</td>
				<td>365</td></tr>
<tr><td>Bristol, for supplying the City of, with Fresh Water.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>160</td></tr>
<tr><td>Bristol, for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the City of, &amp;c. <br/><emph type="i">See</emph> 28 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 65.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Chancery Lane, for making good the Deficiency of the Charges of making a Way out of, into Lincoln's Inn Fields.</td>
				<td>12 &amp; 13 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 12.</td>
				<td>730</td></tr>
<tr><td>Colchester (Essex) for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the Town of, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W.III</emph>.</td>
				<td>450</td></tr>
<tr><td>Crediton, for erecting Hospitals, Workhouses, and Houses of Correction within the Town and Parish of, in the County of Devon, and for the Relief of the Poor there.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>449</td></tr>
<tr><td>Exeter, Charles Flyboat, for that Ship to trade as a free Ship.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>523</td></tr>
<tr><td>&mdash; for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the City and County of.<br/>
<emph type="i">See</emph> 14 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 61.&ndash;25 <emph type="i">G. III.c</emph>.21.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>450</td></tr>
			<tr>
				<td>
Great Queen Street, for the Improvement of a House and Ground in.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>160</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Hawke Rainbow For those Ships to trade as English-built Ships.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W.III.</emph>
				</td>
				<td>524</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Hereford, for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the City of, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III.</emph>
				</td>
				<td>450</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Hertford, for removing the County Gaol. of.</td>
				<td>12 &amp;13 <emph type="i">W. III.</emph>
				</td>
				<td>730</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>King's Lynn, Norfolk, for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the Borough of, &amp;c.<br/><emph type="i">Amended and Powers enlarged</emph>, 48<emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. xxii</td>
				<td>12 &amp; 13 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>729</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Kingston upon Hull, for erecting Workhouses and Houses of Correction in the Town of.<br/>
				<emph type="i">See</emph>15 <emph type="i">G. II.c</emph>. 10.&mdash;28 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 27&mdash;4 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 74. &mdash;50 <emph type="i">G.III. c</emph>. xli.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>
				</td>
				<td>450</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Leicester, Derby, and Stafford, for making and keeping the River Trent in the Counties of, navigable.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 26.</td>
				<td>538</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Limerick, (Ireland) Proviso for Grant of &pound;1,500 for Repair of Churches in.</td>
				<td>11 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 2. &sect; 48.</td>
				<td>557</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Lincoln's Inn Fields, for the speedy and effectual making a convenient Way out of Chancery Lane to, and Parts adjacent.</td>
				<td>11 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>632</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Liverpool, for enabling the Town of, to build a Church, and endow the same, and for making the said Town and Liberties thereof, a Parish of itself distinct from Walton</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W.III</emph>.</td>
				<td>523</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>London, for transferring a Trust in Lands belonging to the City of, unto new Trustees.</td>
				<td>12 &amp; 13 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>730</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Lordington alias Lurtington and Whitney (in the County of Sussex) for Sale of the Manor of, and other Lands in the said County of Sussex, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>523</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Madley (Manor of) in the County of Salop, for vesting in Trustees.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>159</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Margam, for the Ship Martha of, to trade as a free Ship.</td>
				<td>11 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>634</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Margaret For the Ships to trade as freefriendship Ships.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>522</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maryland, Merchant Ship of Bristol, for giving Leave for her Arrival and importing her Lading into this Kingdom.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>450</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maydwell (County of Northampton) for settling Lands, &amp;c. on the Rector of the Church of, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>160</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Merchants of London, for continuing the Governor and Company of, trading to the East Indies, a Corporation. </td>
				<td>11 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>632</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Newcastle upon Tyne, for supplying the Town of, with Fresh Water. </td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>450</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>New Deal, for furnishing the Town of, with Fresh Water. </td>
				<td>12 &amp; 13 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>729</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Norfolk, for repairing the Highways between Wymondham and Attleborough, in the County of. <br/>
				<emph type="i">See 56 G. III. c. lxviii</emph>.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>. c. 26.</td>
				<td>111</td>
			</tr>
				<tr>
				<td>Norwich, for enlightening the Streets of the said City.</td>
				<td>11 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>633</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Norwich, for erecting a Court of Request or Conscience in the City or County of the City of, for the Recovery of Small Debts, under 40s.</td>
				<td>12 &amp; 13 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>729</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Princethorpe, (Town of). <emph type="i">See</emph> Stretton.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W.III</emph>.</td>
				<td>160</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Saint Lawrence Old Jewry, to ascertain and settle the Payment of the Tithes of the Parish of, to the Masters and Scholars of Baliol College, Oxford; and for confirming an Award concerning the same.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>159</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Saint Martin's Ongar, for confirming a Lease of a Piece of Ground from the Rector, &amp;c. of the Parish of, in London, for Liberty to build a Church thereon, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>11 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>633</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Shaftesbury, for erecting Workhouses and Houses of Correction in the Town of.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>450</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Ships, Friendship, For enabling the, to Margaret, trade as free Ships.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>522</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Martha, (of Margam) for enabling the, to trade as a free Ship.</td>
				<td>11 <emph type="i">W.III</emph>.</td>
				<td>634</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Hope, for enabling the, to trade as an English-built Ship.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>524</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maryland, Merchant Ship, of Bristol, for giving Leave for her Arrival and importing her Lading into this Kingdom.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>450</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Panther, Gloucester Frigate, Scarborough, and Antelope, for those Ships to have the Freedom of trading as English-built Ships.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
					<tr>
				<td>For discharging the Ships King William and Charles the Second from the Penalties of the Act of.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>524</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Ruby Prize, Plymouth, For those Ships to have the Freedom of trading as English-built Ships.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>450</td>
			</tr>
				<tr>
				<td>Sally Rose, for giving Leave for, to arrive and import her Lading, and to trade as an English-built Ship.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>45</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>South Pickenham, for the vesting and settling divers Manors and Lands in and other Places in the County of Norfolk in Trustees, to be sold, and for laying out the Monies arising by the Sale thereof in the Purchase of other Lands, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>12&amp;13 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>729</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stretton, Princethorpe, For making the Towns of, a separate Parish from Wolston, in the County of Warwick.</td>
				<td>7 &amp;8 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>160</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Surrey and Sussex, for repairing the Highway between Ryegate and Crawley, in the Counties of.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>. c. 15.</td>
				<td>207</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tiverton, for erecting Hospitals and Workhouses within the Town and Parish of, in the County of Devon, and for employing and maintaining the Poor thereof.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>449</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Turkey, for importing Goods and Merchandizes laden in, on board certain Ships, paying Customs as if imported by English Ships.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>293</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tutbury, Forest of Needwood, for revesting in His Majesty the Honor of several Manors, Parks, Lands, and Offices thereunto belonging, and for vacating certain Letters Patent.<br/>
				<emph type="i">See Needwood forest</emph>.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>160</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Vicarages, for settling Augmentations on certain, for ever.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>523</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Wells (Manor of) for vesting Moiety of, in Trustees, for vesting Moiety of, in Trustees, for Payment of a Mortgage charged thereon, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>160</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Westminster, to enable the Parish of Saint James within the Liberty of the City of, to raise Money for building their Parish Church, Rector's House, Vestry, and other publick Works there.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.159</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Westminster (Liberty of) for paving and regulating the Haymarket, in the Parish of Saint Martin in the Fields, and Saint James, within the said Liberty.</td>
				<td>8&amp;9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>. c. 17.</td>
				<td>212</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Whitborne (Herts) for annexing the Rectory of, to the Bishoprick Hereford.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>.</td>
				<td>449</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>York, East Riding of, for the Repair of the Piers of Bridlington alias Burlington, in the County of.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 29.</td>
				<td>279</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>London and Westminster</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t3">
			<tr>
				<td cols="3"/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td/><th>Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For explaining and enforcing the Act for paving and cleansing the Streets within the Cities of London and Westminster, and Borough of Southwark and Weekly Bills of Mortality, and Streets adjoining thereto, and for widening the Street at the South End of London Bridge.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III</emph>. c. 37.</td>
				<td>291</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons inhabiting within the Bills of Mortality, to cause the Streets, &amp;c. before their Houses, &amp;c. to be swept Twice a Week &mdash;Penalty 10s.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Penalties, how applied.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Where one Side only of Street, Lane, &amp;c. within Bills of Mortality are paved, Jus-ortices -may cause the Side without the Bills to be paved also&mdash;Penalty</td>
				<td>8&amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>.37. ? 3.</td>
				<td>291</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 8. &sect; 20. to be put in Execution.</td>
				<td>&sect;4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If any Liberty, Precinct, &amp;c. within the Weekly Bills of Mortality, be unable to repair their own Highways, and perform the Days Work on other Highways, the Justices may allow so many Days Work as they may think fit, for repairing the same, and the Residue to be employed on the other Highways.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>291,292</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Highway leading from Tottenham Court towards Tyburn, to be paved by such Persons as heretofore used to pave the same.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>292</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners Names.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners empowered to treat with the Owners of such Houses on London Bridge as they shall think fit to be pulled down, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>In case of Refusal to treat, or through Disability by Nonage, &amp;c. Sheriffs of London or Surrey to return a Jury to assess Damage and Recompence, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Verdict of Jury binding, and a full Authority to Commissioners.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners to take Oath for executing Act.</td>
				<td>&sect;8.
</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Lotteries</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t4">
			<tr>
				<td cols="3"/>
			</tr>
			<tr><td/>
				<th>Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Managers and Directors of Lottery appointed.</td>
				<td>8&amp;9 <emph type="i">W.III.c</emph>.22. &sect;28.<emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>252</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>To meet, and cause Books of Tickets to be prepared as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Books to be delivered to Receivers, who, on Receipt of Contribution, are to deliver a Ticket to Contributor.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Receiver to account for the Monies, &amp;c. so received into the Exchequer, and to redeliver Books to the said Managers; and also an Account of Monies received for the Tickets.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Managers to cause Tickets herein mentioned, not disposed of to Contributors, to be delivered as Money into the Exchequer, and to be issued accordingly.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Owners, &amp;c. of Tickets deemed Contributors.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Certain Tickets herein mentioned to be rolled up, and marked A.</td>
				<td>&sect; 29.</td>
				<td>253</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said Managers to prepare another Bookof Tickets as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 30.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Certain Tickets herein mentioned to be rolled up, and marked B.</td>
				<td>&sect; 31.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said rolling up, &amp;c. to be performed on or before 2d Aug. 1697.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said Lottery to be drawn on 10th Aug. 1697.</td>
				<td>? 32.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Manner of drawing the same.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>To continue until the whole Number of Tickets shall be drawn.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If Proceedings of drawing cannot be performed in One Day, the same to be adjourned from Day to Day.</td>
				<td>8&amp;9<emph type="i">W.III.c</emph>. 22.&sect; 32. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>253</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>By what Means the Holders of Fortunate Tickets may be made acquainted there with.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>254</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Forging Tickets, or knowingly bringing the same to the Managers&mdash;Felony.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Managers may cause the Bringers of such Tickets to be apprehended, and may commit.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Managers to cause a Book to be prepared, and enter the Number of the FortunateTickets, and sign and transmit same into Exchequer by 10th Sept. 1697.</td>
				<td>&sect; 33.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons, whose Numbers shall be so transmitted, to enjoy the Benefit thereof.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Contributors of &pound;10, and who are not entitled to a Fortunate Ticket, to receive &pound;10 in the Coin of the Realm, with One Farthing per Diem Interest, from 24th June 1697, until paid.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Holders of Fortunate Tickets not exceeding &pound;20, to have &pound;10, with said Interest over and above.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tickets paid to Bearer.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proceedings for ascertaining the due Course of Payment.</td>
				<td>&sect; 34.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Times of Payment published on the First Monday in every Month.</td>
				<td>&sect; 35.</td>
				<td>255</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Interest to cease when Money ready to be paid.</td>
				<td>&sect; 36.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Managers before acting, to take Oath herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 37.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Which may be administered by Two Managers.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>After the aforesaid Payments, the Residue of the appropriated Fund to be applied in paying the Managers, Clerks, and other Officers.</td>
				<td>&sect; 38.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Receivers to pay Interest to Contributors, at the Rate of &pound;14 per Cent. per Annum, from Payment of Contribution.</td>
				<td>&sect; 39.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>To be allowed the same in his Accounts, and also a Remuneration not exceeding 2d. in the Pound upon Monies paid by him into the Exchequer.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Receipts, &amp;c. done and given without Fee.</td>
				<td>&sect; 40.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Money contributed Tax-free.</td>
				<td>&sect; 41.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>A distinct Office appointed in the Exchequer for Payments under this Act, and Officers appointed by the Treasury.</td>
				<td>&sect; 42.</td>
				<td>256</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Monies of the Fund appointed by this Act to be paid by the Treasury without further Warrant.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers to apply the same as herein mentioned, and to be subject to Inspection, &amp;c. as the Treasury shall order.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Managers, Receivers, and the said Officers in the Exchequer to obey the Orders of the Treasury.</td>
				<td>&sect; 43.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Clause of Loan for &pound;200,000 Tax-free, Interest &pound;8 per Cent. per Annum.</td>
				<td>&sect; 44.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For the suppressing of Lotteries.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 23.</td>
				<td>532</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Lotteries declared public Nuisances, and Grants, &amp;c. for the same void.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>After 29th Dec. 1699, no Person publicly or privately to keep open, &amp;c. Lotteries&mdash;Penalty &pound;500.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>533</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons drawing, &amp;c. at Lotteries&mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for the Remainder of the Term in the Royal Oak Lottery.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for the charitable Adventure for the Benefit of Greenwich Hospital.<br/>
				<emph type="i">This Act e nforced</emph>, 9 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 6. ? 56.&ndash;10 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 26. ? 109.&mdash;<emph type="i">and see</emph> 12 <emph type="i">G.II. c</emph>. 28.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Lottery Tickets</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t5">
			<tr>
				<td cols="3"/>
			</tr>
			<tr><td/>
				<th>Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For the better and more orderly Payment of the Lottery Tickets now payable out of certain additional Duties of Excise, and of other Annuities lately payable out of Tunnage Duties.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 37. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>410</td></tr>
<tr><td>From the 15th May 1698, the Duties of Excise of Stat. 5 &amp; 6 W.&amp; M. c.7. applied as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 37. ? 1.</td>
				<td>410</td></tr>
<tr><td>How the subsequent or growing Produce of the said Duties to be applied.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Course of Payment of said Annuities.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Officer making Payment contrary to the Tenor hereof&mdash;Penalty &pound;100 and Loss of Office.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>How Benefit Tickets to be paid.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Not undue Preference if Officer pay subsequent Tickets first brought, if Money reserved for preceding Ticket.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>411</td></tr>
<tr><td>Officers not to pay Annuities when preceding Quarterly Payments unpaid.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Notice fixed up in the Office&mdash;Officer of fending&mdash;Loss of Office, and Penalty &pound;100.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Lom Wines.</key>
		</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Lustrings.</key>
			<emph type="i">See </emph>Importation.</head>
	</entry>
</section>
</index>


