<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE index SYSTEM "../dtd/index.dtd">
<index id="47010" pubid="353" publish="true">
	<title>Index</title>
	<subtitle>E</subtitle>
<section id="s1"><head>E.</head>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>East Country Linen</key>
			<emph type="i">See</emph>Customs.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>East India Company</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t1">
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<td/>
				<td/>
			</tr>
			<tr><td/>
				<th>
Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For raising a Sum not exceeding &pound;2,000,000 upon a Fund for Payment of Annuities at the Rate of &pound;8 per Cent, per Annum, and for settling the Trade to the East Indies.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c. </emph>. 44.</td>
				<td>429</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>From 29th Sept. 1698. &pound;160,000 additional out of Duties on Salt and Stamps to be the Yearly Fund for answering Annuities to Subscribers of &pound;2,000,000&mdash;Proviso for Deficiency.<br/><emph type="i">Fund reduced, &amp;c</emph>.3 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>.14. <emph type="i">and reduced Annuity charged on the Aggregate Fund, </emph>3 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>.20.</td>
				<td>&sect; 36.</td>
				<td>436</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said additional Duties appropriated towards making good the said Yearly Fund.</td>
				<td>&sect; 37.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers of the Exchequer not issuing or misapplying Money&mdash;Dismission&mdash;Incapacity and Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>His Majesty may appoint Commissioners for taking Subscriptions till 29th Sept. 1698, from any Persons except the Bank of England for &pound;2,000,000.</td>
				<td>&sect; 38.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners to provide Books for said Subscriptions, to lie open every Day except Sundays until 29th Sept. 1698, unless the &pound;2,000,000 be sooner completed.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>437</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>His Majesty may appoint a Cashier to receive the Money subscribed.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Any Sums not less than &pound;100 may be subscribed.</td>
				<td>&sect; 39.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The Monies subscribed to be answered by Ten equal Payments, the First Payment to be made at the Time of subscribing.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Each subsequent Payment to be made at the End of every Two Months, reckoning 60 Days for each Two Months, till the whole be paid.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The last Payment to be liable to make good any Deficiency which may happen during the Time for making the said last Payment, in the Produce of the said Duties.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>.44. &sect; 39.</td>
				<td>437</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If the First Payment be not made at the Time of subscribing, such Subscription to be void.</td>
				<td>&sect; 40.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And if all the subsequent Payments be not complied with, the First Tenth Part for feited, and the Annuity payable for such Subscription reduced according to the Money actually paid, after an Abatement of the First Tenth Part.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tallies of Assignment or Anticipation may be levied on the Commissioners or Receivers General of the Money to be subscribed.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said Tallies to bear an Interest of &pound;8 per Cent, per Annum.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The Sums subscribed to be written in Words at length as well as Figures, and attested.</td>
				<td>&sect; 41.</td>
				<td>438</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>After 29th Sept. 1698, or Subscription completed, Duplicates of Subscriptions to be returned into the Exchequer before 20th Oct. 1698.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duplicates to be recorded.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Free Access to Registers.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Copies of Books inrolled to be delivered to Commissioners for the Use of Subscribers, gratis.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Each Subscriber to have an Annuity after the Rate of &pound;8 per Cent, per Ann. to commence from Michaelmas 1698, and to be paid Quarterly.</td>
				<td>&sect; 42.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The First Payment at Christmas 1698, subject to Redemption and Reduction, in case of Failure in Payment of Part of Subscription Money.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>
				</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons paying down One Tenth Part of Subscription may defaulk after the Rate of &pound;10 per Cent. per Annum, as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 44. &sect; 43.</td>
				<td>438</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners, &amp;c. to give Receipts to Subscribers, and enter same, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 44.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Account thereof to be delivered to Auditor attested before 24th June 1700.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Treasury to issue Sums necessary for incident Charges.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners may be Subscribers.</td>
				<td>&sect; 45.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>His Majesty may incorporate the Subscribers by Letters Patent, by the Name of the General Society, intitled to Advantages given by an Act of Parliament for advancing a Sum not exceeding &pound;2,000,000, for the Service of the Crown of England, subject to the aforesaid Proviso for Redemption.<br/><emph type="i">As to Delivery of Salt Petre into the Queen's Stores by the United Companies, see </emph>1 <emph type="i">Ann. Stat</emph>. 1. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 12. &sect; 113.</td>
				<td>&sect; 46.</td>
				<td>439</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>Sum Total of Subscriptions to be, and be called the Principal Stock of the said Corporation.</td>
				<td>&sect; 47.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Subscribers of &pound;500 and upwards may meet at Guildhall, in London, 10 Oct. 1698, or within 20 Days after Subscription completed, to elect Trustees.</td>
				<td>&sect; 48.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Elector to have only One Vote.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Each Trustee must have subscribed &pound;2,000 at least in his own Right.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons elected to be inserted in Charter of the Corporation.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Further Rules, &amp;c. may be inserted in Charter.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If &pound;2,000,000 not subscribed by 29th Sept. 1698, Subscribers to have only a proportionable Part of Yearly Fund.</td>
				<td>&sect; 49.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>After the Charter is passed, the Yearly Sum of &pound;160,000, or a proportionable Part thereof, to be paid to General Society or their Treasurer in Trust for Members.</td>
				<td>&sect; 50.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If &pound;2,000,000, or a Moiety thereof, be subscribed on or before 29th Sept. 1698, Subscribers, their Executors, Successors, or Assigns, and all Persons licensed by them, may trade to the East Indies, &amp;c.<br/><emph type="i">Company to trade within Limits of this Act, &amp;c</emph>. 33 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 52. &sect; 71.</td>
				<td>&sect; 51.</td>
				<td>439, 440</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>None to trade by himself or others in any One Year, to be computed from 29th Sept. 1698, for more than Amount of his Stock.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>440</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If the said &pound;2,000,000, or a Moiety thereof, be subscribed on or before 29th Sept. 1698, all or any Persons intitled to particular Shares in the Principal Stock may be incorporated into a Company to trade with a joint Stock by such proper Name as His Majesty shall think fit.</td>
				<td>&sect; 52.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>After the incorporating of such Company, the proportionable Part of Yearly Fund belonging to Members to be paid to said Company or their Treasurer in Trust for Members.</td>
				<td>&sect; 53.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Payments to be made at the Exchequer weekly.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 44.	&sect; 53.</td>
				<td>440</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Every Member of the General Society, before permitted to trade, to take Oathbefore Two or more of the Trustees to be faithful to the Society, and not to trade for more than allowed.</td>
				<td>&sect; 54.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons trading by Licence to enter their Licences in the Books of the Society, and take Oath to the like Effect.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>441</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Member of any Company trading to the East Indies, during his Continuance in the said Company, to trade otherwise than in the joint Stock thereof.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Every Member to take Oath to be faithful, and not to trade to the Indies, during his Continuance in the Company, upon private Account.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Person to be entrusted to trade upon the joint Stock, or for a Company, before he hath taken Oath as herein mentioned to be faithful to such Company, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Quakers may make a solemn Declaration the same Effect.</td>
				<td>&sect; 55.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>All Persons trading in pursuance of this Act shall enter the Goods they export (Exception) in a Book before the lading thereof.</td>
				<td>&sect; 56.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons concerned may view the Books, to see whether Traders trade for more than is allowed.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said Entries to be attested upon Oath or Solemn Affirmation.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Entries and Affirmations to be made before Two or more Trustees till a Company be erected, and afterwards before Two or more Directors.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The General Society and Companies in joint Stock may be impowered by Charters to make Bye Laws and inflict Penalties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 57.</td>
				<td>442</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Not making true Entries and Affirmations&mdash; Forfeiture of Goods, and Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 58.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Company or particular Person to trade before he has given Security to Commissioners of Customs, that the Goods to be laden by or for them in the East Indies, shall be brought to England without breaking Bulk (the Dangers of the Seas excepted).</td>
				<td>&sect; 59.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Disputes in Acceptance of Security, determined by Baron of Exchequer.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Goods imported, to be sold by Inch of Candle&mdash; Penalty.<br/><emph type="i">This Clause explained as to Securities to be given, and also as to breaking Bulk</emph>, 6 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 3. &sect; 1. <emph type="i">As to Exportation of Tea by Company, see</emph> 13 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 44. &sect; 4.; <emph type="i">and as to Trade to China, and in Tea</emph>, 53 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 155. &sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>His Majesty by Commission or Charters, to direct in what Manner the Shares in the Yearly Fund, and in the Stock in Trade, shall be assigned or transferred.</td>
				<td>&sect; 60.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stock to be deemed Personal Estate.</td>
				<td>&sect; 61.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said Annuities and Shares in Trade, exempt from Taxes.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 44. &sect; 62.</td>
				<td>442</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Guardian or Trustee for Infant, may subscribe a Moiety of Money in Trust.</td>
				<td>&sect; 63.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Member in respect of his Stock to be judged Bankrupt.</td>
				<td>&sect; 64.</td>
				<td>443</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Not liable to Foreign Attachment.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>General Society or Company established in pursuance of this Act, not to borrow or give Security for any Sums on Credit of Funds by Act granted, nor to borrow, owe, or give Security for any other or greater Sum than shall be employed in their Trade.</td>
				<td>&sect; 65.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Such Moneys to be borrowed only on their Common Seal, and not be made payable less than Six Months from Time of borrowing.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Not to discount Bills of Exchange, &amp;c. or keep Cash for other Persons.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>An Additional Duty of &pound;5 per Cent. (<emph type="i">a</emph>) laid on all East India Goods imported after 29th Sept. 1698, by any Persons trading pursuant to this Act.<br/>(<emph type="i">a</emph>) <emph type="i">Repealed, and a Duty of &pound;3. per Cent. granted, 33 G. III. c</emph>. 52. &sect; 99. &amp; <emph type="i">see</emph> 53 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 155. &sect; 26, 27.</td>
				<td>&sect; 66.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
						<tr>
				<td>To be paid over to the General Society, or such Companies as may be erected, or their respective Treasurers, for maintaining Ambassadors, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Overplus of such Duty to be disposed of for the Benefit of the Members as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Security before landing of Goods to be given for Payment of said additional Duty of &pound;5 per Cent. as soon as the Goods shall be sold.</td>
				<td>&sect; 67.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 444</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Goods landed before Duty secured, or without Warrant, forfeited.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said Duty to be managed by Commissioners of Customs.<br/><emph type="i">See Note to</emph> &sect; 66.</td>
				<td>&sect; 68.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Upon Three Years' Notice after 29th Sept. 1711, and Repayment by Parliament of the said &pound;2,000,000, or such Part thereof as shall be advanced, and all Arrears of said Annuities, then all Things granted by this Act to cease.<br/><emph type="i">See Note at the End of this Act</emph>.</td>
				<td>&sect; 69.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
				<tr>
				<td>Additional Duty of 1s. 10d. per Pound Weight, upon all Wrought Silks imported from the East Indies, after 29th Sept. 1698.<br/><emph type="i">No Duty except the Half Subsidy</emph>, 11 W. III. c. 10. &sect; 10.</td>
				<td>&sect; 70.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons who may trade pursuant to this Act, to have the sole Trade to the East Indies, after 29th Sept. 1698.</td>
				<td>&sect; 71.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons trading to East Indies other than such as by this Act are allowed&mdash;to incur Forfeiture of Ship and Goods, and Penalty.<br/><emph type="i">See</emph>5 <emph type="i">G. I. c</emph>. 21. &sect; 1.&ndash;13 <emph type="i">G. I. c</emph>. 8.&ndash;33 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 52. &sect; 146. <emph type="i">Proviso for Duty granted to Company on Pearls, &amp;c. imported from Places within Limits of the Charter</emph>, 6 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 7. &sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 445</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If in any One Year after 29th Sept. 1699, the said Duties shall not be sufficient to satisfy the Payments appointed, such Deficiency made good out of the next Aids.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 44. &sect; 72.</td>
				<td>445</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for present East India Company trading 'till 29th Sept. 1701.<br/><emph type="i">See Note to </emph>&amp;. 45. <emph type="i">ante</emph>.</td>
				<td>&sect; 73.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
						</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Ships not in the Service of the said Company cleared from England for the East Indies, before 1st July 1698, not liable to Forfeitures.</td>
				<td>&sect; 74.<emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The present East India Company to pay their just Debts, and their Estates made liable thereto.</td>
				<td>&sect; 75.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said Company making Dividends after 24th June 1698, before Payment of their Debts, the respective Members liable so far as their Shares upon such Dividends shall extend to pay, besides Double Costs.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Every Society or Company to be erected in pursuance of this Act, not to owe at any one Time more than the Value of their Capital Stock undivided.</td>
				<td>&sect; 76.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If by any Dividends their Debts at any Time exceed their Capital Stock, the respective Members liable so far as the Shares they received upon such Dividends will extend, besides Costs.<br/><emph type="i">See further Time granted to the Company</emph>, 6 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 17. <emph type="i">and although Fund redeemed</emph>, 10 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 28. <emph type="i">For the Recovery of Penalties by this Act. See</emph> 7 <emph type="i">G. I. Stat. 1. c</emph>. 21. &amp; 6. <emph type="i">Treasury may grant Licences to Company to export Tea to America, free of Customs</emph>, 13 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 44. &amp; 4. pany, 6 <emph type="i">Ann. c.</emph> 17. <emph type="i">and although Fund redeemed, </emph> 10 <emph type="i">Ann. c.</emph> 28. <emph type="i">Forthe Recovery of Penalties by this Act. See</emph> 7 <emph type="i">G. I Stat. 1. c.</emph> 2r &sect; 6</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key> East India Goods</key>, Linens, and Manufactures <emph type="i">See</emph> Customs.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key> Ecclesiastical Persons</key>
			<emph type="i">See</emph> The Crown.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Embezzling the Kings Stores</key> <emph type="i">See</emph> Daty.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Embroidery</key>
			<emph type="i">See</emph> Importation.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Escape from Prison</key>
			<emph type="i">See</emph> Creditors.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Exchequer</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t2">
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<td/>
				<td/>
			</tr>
<tr><td/>
				<th>Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>			
			<tr>
				<td>&pound;6,000 out of Hereditary and Temporary Excise Duties applied Weekly in Payment of unsatisfied Tallies, with Interest at &pound;6 per Cent. per Ann.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 30. &amp; 33.</td>
				<td>128</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And then in Payment of &pound;400,000 and Interest, as herein mentioned, borrowed upon Credit of Act.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
				<tr>
				<td>Interest upon Tallies paid every Three Months &mdash; Commissioners of Excise to cause same to be paid &mdash;Penalty.<br/><emph type="i">Explained as to Tallies</emph>, 8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 3.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 30. &sect; 33.</td>
				<td>128</td>
			</tr>
						<tr>
				<td>If Weekly Receipt not sufficient, Deficiency made good out of whole Receipt of Excise.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tallies assignable &mdash; Monies lent Tax free &mdash;Access thereto without Fee &mdash; Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 34.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Register of Tallies kept at head Office of Excise.</td>
				<td>&sect; 35.</td>
				<td>129</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>What held not undue Preference.</td>
				<td>&sect; 36.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for Payment of Salaries and Incidents.</td>
				<td>&sect; 37.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&pound;600 Weekly out of Post Office Duties applied Weekly in Payment of unsatisfied Tallies, with Interest at &pound;6 per Cent. per Ann.</td>
				<td>&sect; 38.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And then in Payment of &pound; 45,000 and Interest at &pound;7 per Cent. per Ann.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Interest upon Tallies paid every Three Months, Postmaster General to cause same to be paid.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Penalty.<br/><emph type="i">The Duties granted by this Act seem to be expired, but the Remainder of the Act appears to be in force, and is declared in its original Intention to extend to Scotland</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Talley to be taken at more than the Interest allowed thereupon, with a further Allowance of &pound;6 per Cent.&mdash; Penalty.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 20. &sect; 57.</td>
				<td>234</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And the Buyer deemed a common Extortioner.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>235</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Assignment of Order or Talley to be good unless made in Writing and signed by Party making same &mdash; Or under the Common Seal of a Corporation, &amp;c.; and if of Money payable at the Ex-chequer, then to be entered in the Exchequer in 10 Days after signing, and Oath made thereon &mdash; And an Afficavit that no further Allowance taken.</td>
				<td>&sect; 58.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If Assignment of Money payable by Talley of Pro, payable at the Excise or General Post Office, &amp;c. then to be entered in the Excise or Post Office, &amp;c. and on the like Affidavit.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers in the Exchequer, Excise, and Post Office, to attend daily for registering Assignments and administering the Oaths without Fee&mdash;Penalty.<br/><emph type="i">As to repeal of Sect</emph>. 58. <emph type="i">see</emph> 11 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 3. &sect; 14.</td>
				<td>&sect; 59.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>Brokers, &amp;c. taking above 2s. 6d. per Cent. for Brokerage, &amp;c. &mdash; Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>&sect; 60.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Or making Bargain in which greater Allowance made than herein mentioned&mdash; Penalty &pound;500.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And deemed a common Extortioner.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>236</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Claimers of Orders purchased before 10th June 1697, not obliged to take the Oath concerning the Premium.</td>
				<td>&sect; 61.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Affidavit to be in Writing and filed.<br/><emph type="i">As to repeal of Section</emph> 61 &amp; 62. <emph type="i">see</emph> 11 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 3. &sect; 14.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 20. &sect; 62.</td>
				<td>236</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>For the better Observation of the course anciently used in the Receipt of Exchequer.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 28.</td>
				<td>275</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tellers of the Exchequer on Receipt of Money on Loan, &amp;c. to throw down a Bill into the Talley Court for a Talley to be struck for the same, and be charged with the Sum received.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Teller, &amp;c. refusing to receive, or not duly charging himself with Monies lent or paid to the King&mdash;Loss of Office, Incapacity, and Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>276</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tellers Clerks offending&mdash;Penalty and Removal.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Teller to charge himself with Receipt of Monies, but when Officers of the Talley Court are present, nor throw down a Bill for a Talley to be struck until the Money be actually received and had in the Office&mdash; Exception.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Teller offending&mdash;(Exception) Loss of Office, Incapacity, and Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Clerk, &amp;c. offending&mdash;Penalty and Removal.<br/><emph type="i">As to Treasury directing Tellers to receive Bank Bills, see</emph> 10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 11. &sect; 13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Teller, &amp;c. after Bill thrown down, to dispose of Money out of his Office without an Order from Auditor of Receipt, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers of the Talley Court to attend daily, Sundays and Holidays excepted; and in case of Sickness their Place to be supplied.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>277</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer absenting without Leave&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers of Exchequer not giving due Attendance&mdash; Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>First Clerk of Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, and Tellers to take an Oath for due Performance of Duty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Money not to be paid out of the Exchequer but by Authority as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>A Table to be set up at the Door of the Auditor's Office, shewing the State of Repayment of Loans, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Auditor to enrol all Letters Patents, &amp;c. draw Orders for issuing Money, and keep Entries thereof, and take and certify Teller's Accounts Weekly, make out imprest Certificates, and transmit to the Treasury Declaration of Receipts, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Clerk of the Pells to enrol Letters Patent for issuing Money, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>278</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers of the Receipt, Clerks, &amp;c. to demean themselves according to their Duties.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Penalties, how recovered.</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for the Power of the Treasury over the Officers of Receipt.</td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And for Receipts and Payments by Exchequer Bills.</td>
				<td>&sect; 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Money to be kept in Chests under Three Locks.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 28. &sect; 12.</td>
				<td>278</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Keys by whom to be kept.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Debentures to be paid the same Day they are sent up to the Clerk of the Pells, except Orders for the Navy, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tellers to have Money left with them every Morning for satisfying Debentures for that Day.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Money received to be weighed, and then secured in the said Chests.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Payments not to be deferred.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Clerk of the Pells, &amp;c. not attending, eldest Clerk, &amp;c. to keep the Keys.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Money to be taken out but in the Presence of the Teller, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Auditor once in Twenty-eight Days to visit every Teller's Cash, and once in Three Months examine their Vouchers.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>279</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For giving further Time for administering of Oaths relating to Tallies and Orders, and for the easier Dispatch of the Public Business in the Exchequer and in the Bank of England.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 3.</td>
				<td>298</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Recital of Stat. 8 &amp;9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 20. &sect; 58.</td><td/><td/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons having purchased since 10th June 1697, or who may before 10th June 1698 purchase Tallies, &amp;c., and neglect to take Assignments, &amp;c., as by the said Act, may do so on or before the 10th June 1698.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons having, before 10th June 1697, purchased Orders of Loan, &amp;c., and neglected to have their Assignments registered, &amp;c. and making Oath thereof upon or before 10th June 1698, notobliged, on claiming such Orders, &amp;c., to take the Oath concerning the Premium, &amp;c., and in such Case the Assignment, &amp;c. to be good in Law.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td><emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 299.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers of the Exchequer, &amp;c. empowered to take in and cancel certain Orders and Tallies, and to give fewer Orders and Tallies of the same Value, &amp;c. in the whole, as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No new Order to contain more than &pound;5,000.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Indorsement thereon.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>New Orders valid.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>,</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Principal and Interest thereon paid.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>
				</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 20. &sect; 58. repealed, and Assignments of Tallies of the same force, as if the said Clause had not been enacted.</td>
				<td>11 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 3. &sect; 14.</td>
				<td>585</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Exchequer Bills</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t3">
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<td/>
				<td/>
			</tr>
			<tr><td/>
				<th>Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Exchequer Bills to be taken for Taxes, &amp;c. granted this Parliament, and in all Payments at the Exchequer due to the King.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 20. &sect; 63.</td>
				<td>236</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Bills to bear 5d. a Day per Cent. Interest till paid into the Exchequer.</td>
				<td>&sect; 64.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Bills paid into the Exchequer to be signed by Persons paying, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 65.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Treasury may contract for lending Money to exchange Exchequer Bills not accepted in Payment.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 20. &sect; 66.</td>
				<td>237</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons so lending Monies to have the said Bills for Security, or other good Security agreed upon, and Interest at &pound;10 per Cent. per Annum.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Contractors Names, &amp;c. to be registered in the Auditor's Office, and Interest to be paid Quarterly.</td>
				<td>&sect; 67.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The King by Proclamation to make known when Exchequer Bills may be exchanged for ready Money; the said Bills to be current only for Aids, &amp;c. of 1697, afterwards for all Revenues, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 68.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tellers in the Exchequer to receive the said Monies and discharge the Receiver.</td>
				<td>&sect; 70.</td>
				<td>238</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For the making out new Exchequer Bills, where the former Bills are or shall be filled up by Indorsement.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 2.</td>
				<td>297</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Treasury may cause new Bills to be made forth in lieu of such Bills, and the old Bills cancelled.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td><emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 298</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The new Bills to be current, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>298</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso as to the Interest incurred on the old Bills.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For renewing the Bills of Credit, commonly called Exchequer Bills.</td>
				<td>12 &amp; 13 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 1.</td>
				<td>635</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>When Bills paid into the Exchequer and Principal and Interest cast up, Bills cancelled, and new Bills of &pound;100, &pound;50, or &pound;25 made.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The new Bills to bear an Interest at the Rate of 4d. per Cent. per Diem, and applicable to the same Uses and under the same Penalties as the cancelled Bills.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>635, 636</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And to have the like Currency and Management.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>636</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for the present Contract for circulating the Exchequer Bills.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Exchequer Orders</key>, Callies, etc. <emph type="i">See</emph> Exchequer.</head>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Excise</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t4">
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<td/>
				<td/>
			</tr>
			<tr><td/>
				<th>Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For enlarging the Times to come in and purchase certain Annuities therein mentioned, and for continuing the Duties formerly charged on Low Wines or Spirits of the first Extraction for carrying on the War against France.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 2.</td>
				<td>4</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Annuitants for Life may before 24th of June 1690 purchase a Term for Years in the said Annuities, to take Effect after the Estate for Life.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If such Annuitants do not purchase before 24th June, then any Person having or not having an Interest in such life Estate may purchase before 29th Sept. 1696, and such Persons paying the Consideration to be immediately intitled.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>5</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Directions of Stat. 6 &amp; 7 W. &amp; M. c. 5. in force for and in respect of such Annuities.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties under Stat. 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 9. to be levied from 24th Dec. 1695 to 25th March 1696.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For laying several Duties upon Low Wines or Spirits of the first Extraction, and for preventing the Frauds and Abuses of Brewers, Distillers, and Persons chargeable with the Duties of Excise</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 30.</td>
				<td>122</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Directions for Distillers, &amp;c. drawing Brandy, &amp;c. from Corn.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Gauger to keep Account.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Materials &mdash;Duty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Unduly preparing or receiving Wash &mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Gauger making false Charge &mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Upon Oath, and Certificate as herein mentioned, Drawback allowed upon Exportation of Spirits.<br/><emph type="i">Drawback made to cease</emph>, 27 <emph type="i">G</emph>. 3. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 13. &sect; 35&ndash; 43 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 69. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
		
			<tr>
				<td>Duties collected, &amp;c. as by Stat. 12 Car. II. c. 24. and other former Acts.</td>
				<td>&sect;.6.</td>
				<td>123</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Gauger finding a certain Quantity of decayed Wines, &amp;c. with Distillers or Stills as herein described &mdash;Proceedings.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Obstructing Gauger &mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stills, Utensils, &amp;c. charged with Duties and Penalties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Gauger to take Account of Wash, &amp;c. and Low Wines, and missing Wash, &amp;c. and not receiving Satisfaction what is become thereof &mdash;Proceedings.</td>
				<td>&sect;9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Notice to Officer of distilling</td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Hours&mdash;Penalty &pound;10.<br/><emph type="i">See</emph> 42 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 93. &sect; 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>Making of Vinegar, &amp;c. concealing from Gauger &mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 124</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maker, &amp;c. of Vinegar refusing Entrance to Gauger, and to take Account, &amp;c.&mdash; Penalty &pound;15.</td>
				<td>&sect; 12.</td>
				<td>124</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Notice by Maker of Vinegar to Officer of Delivery, &amp;c. to Customer, unless at Hours herein mentioned &mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 9. &sect; 11. continued.</td>
				<td>&sect; 14.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewers to declare to Officer how much of Party Guile they intend to make into Strong Beer, &amp;c.<br/><emph type="i">How far repealed</emph>, 8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 19. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>&sect; 15.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
						<tr>
				<td>And not to permit Strong Beer to be carried until Small Beer be carried &mdash;Proceedings.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewer increasing Strong Beer, &amp;c. after such Declaration &mdash; Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>In what Case Brewer liable although Strong Beer, &amp;c. increased by adding Strong Beer that remained of a former Guile</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Cleansing or removing Guile, &amp;c. before the whole brewed off, and Account taken without Notice to Officer&mdash;Penalty</td>
				<td>&sect;16.</td>
				<td>125</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewer refusing Entrance to Officer or to continue while Guile brewing and to take Account &mdash;Penalty &pound;20, and Officer not obliged to prove that Brewer carried, &amp;c. Guile before Duties paid.</td>
				<td>&sect;17.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewers, &amp;c. mixing, &amp;c. Beer upon carrying out &mdash;Penalty &pound;5.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 30. &sect; 18.</td>
				<td>125</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Gaugers may taste Drink upon Drays and in Cellars &mdash;Brewers, &amp;c. refusing Entrance or tasting &mdash;Penalty &pound;5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners of Excise, &amp;c. may summon Parties to give Evidence, refusing to appear or give Evidence&mdash;Penalty &pound;10.</td>
				<td>&sect;19.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Gauger within Three Days from the End of every Week to deliver to Brewer a Copy of Charge&mdash;Penalty &pound;10.<br/><emph type="i">No Penalty unless Copy required in Writing</emph>, 12 <emph type="i">G. I. c</emph>. 28. &sect; 30.</td>
				<td>&sect;20.</td>
				<td>126</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>Gauger delivering Charge not liable to Penalties of former Acts.</td>
				<td>&sect;21.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer may break open Door, &amp;c. of Brewhouse, &amp;c. to search for private Backs, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 22.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And on finding private Pipe, &amp;c. may follow the same into House, &amp;c. of any other Person, making Satisfaction to Owner.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Opposing Officer &mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Making, &amp;c. Verjuice for Sale, Duties as for Cyder.</td>
				<td>&sect;23.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Penalties sued for and disposed of</td>
				<td>&sect;24.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Inferior Officers to continue notwithstanding Death or Removal of Commissioners by whom they were appointed, or Alteration of Commissioners, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 25.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>His Majesty or the Exchequer may borrow &pound;70,000 on Credit of Duties</td>
				<td>&sect; 26.</td>
				<td>127</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Interest as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners of Excise to cause Duties to be paid weekly into Exchequer, and entered apart from other Monies</td>
				<td>&sect; 27.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners refusing, &amp;c. to pay, or diverting Monies &mdash;Incapacity and Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 28.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Comptroller of Excise to keep Account of Duties, to which Access may be had without Fee.</td>
				<td>&sect; 29.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Notes in Writing of Gauge left by Gauger with Brewer &mdash;Penalty 40s.</td>
				<td>&sect;41.</td>
				<td>130</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For continuing to His Majesty certain Duties upon Salt, Glass Wares, Stone, and Earthen Wares; and for granting several Duties upon Tobacco Pipes and other Earthen Wares, for carrying on the War against France.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 31.</td>
				<td>130</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Recital of Stat. 5 W. &amp; M. c. 7. &sect; 1. Duties upon Salt levied as by this Act, and by the said Act made perpetual.<br/><emph type="i">See National Land Bank</emph>.</td>
				<td>&sect;1.</td>
				<td>131</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>Certain Salt declared to be charged with the Duty of 1&frac12;d. per Gallon.</td>
				<td>&sect; 42.</td>
				<td>137</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Bushel of Salt, 56 lbs. Weight.</td>
				<td>&sect; 43.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Salt brought from Scotland by Land, and all imported Salt landed, &amp;c. before Entry and Duty paid, forfeited.</td>
				<td>&sect; 44.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer to provide Scales, Weights, &amp;c. at Salt Work, and may fix the same.</td>
				<td>&sect; 45.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Weigher sworn. &mdash;Salary.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Permit delivered gratis to Carriers of Salt.</td>
				<td>&sect; 46.</td>
				<td>138</td>
			</tr>
		
			<tr>
				<td>How Duties on Fish of Stat. 5 W. &amp;M. c. 20. to be paid. </td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III. c.</emph>31. &sect; 47.</td>
				<td>138</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Salt to be sold at 56 Ib. to the Bushel&mdash; Penalty &pound;5. </td>
				<td>&sect; 48.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties on Glass, &amp;c. under Stat. 6 &amp; 7 W. &amp; M. c. 18. to be levied, as by this Act and the said Act continued. </td>
				<td>&sect; 49.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Certain other Duties hereby granted on unglazed Tobacco Pipes, glazed Tobacco Pipes, and Easthen Wares.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties on manufactured Goods paid by Maker. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>139</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties on Goods manufactured under Commissioners for Duties on Glass and Eartern Wares. </td>
				<td>&sect; 52. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Treasury may order Salaries and other Incidents to be paid out of Duties, and make Order for collecting the said Duties.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Regulations for adjusting the value of Goods charged with ad valorem Duty </td>
				<td>&sect; 53.</td>
				<td>139</td>
							</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proceedings in case of Fraud. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>140</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Notice of usual Place of Baking, &amp;c. to be given to Officer, and also of change of Workhouse, Names and Places of Abode, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;20. </td>
				<td>&sect; 54.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>On charging Pots, &amp;c. and before uncovering, &amp;c., Marker to give Notice to Officer. </td>
				<td>&sect; 55. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Pots, &amp;c. not to be uncovered, &amp;c. but in the Presence of Officer, and on Notice.&mdash; Penalty. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties to be paid on Entry, or bonded. </td>
				<td>&sect; 56.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowance on prompt Payment.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers to have Ingress, &amp;c. to Work-houses by Night or by Day ; and by Day into Warehouses, &amp;c. </td>
				<td>&sect; 57.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Refusal&mdash;Penalty &pound;5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Burning new and old Pipes together&mdash;Penalty. </td>
				<td>&sect; 58.</td>
				<td>141.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Building, &amp;c. Kiln, &amp;c. without Notice, or burning new an old Pipes together, or not making due Entries, or removing before Entry made or Permit, or notgiving Notice of drawing Pots, or concealing Commodities &mdash;Penalty &pound;20.1</td>
				<td>&sect; 59.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Fee, &amp;c. for Permit.</td>
				<td>&sect; 60.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No duty on broken goods, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 61.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>On Oath, on Exportation of Commodities, administered by Officers at Port of Exportation, Re-payment of Duty. </td>
				<td>&sect; 62.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for certain Bricks and Tiles.</td>
				<td>&sect; 63.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners, &amp;c. of Duties upon Glass to keep Account of Duty, and pay weekly into Exchequer, where distinct Account kept.</td>
				<td>&sect; 64.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners, &amp;c. neglecting, &amp;c. or misapplying Monies &mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For explaining Part of Stat. 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 330. </td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 W. III. c.</td>
				<td>164</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Rectial of Stat. 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 30. &sect; 33 &ndash; 38. All Tallies of Pro, &amp;c. charged upon Excise or upon weekly Payments thereout to be satisfied in course without undue Preference. </td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Interest to be paid every Three Months &mdash; Tallies charged on the weekly Revenue of the Post Office to be paid in like manner &mdash; Penalty on Officers offending.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c.</emph> 3. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>165</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For granting to His Majesty several Duties upon Paper, Vellum, and Parchment. </td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 7.</td>
				<td>189</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties upon Paper, &amp;c. made within the Kingdom for Two Years from 1st March 1695, to be paid by Markers,</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>190</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Treasury to appoint Commissioners or Surveyors for the said Duties on Paper, &amp;c. made in England, &amp;c. who may substitute Deputies, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners may settle Orders, &amp;c. for Guidance of Officers. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>191</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Value of Goods made in England, &amp;c. estimated in case of dispute as to Value, the same to be estimated by Affidavit of Maker. </td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Officers to proceed in case of apparent Fraud in such Affidavit. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Before 25th March 1697, Makers to give Notice to Commissioner or Officer of Manufactory, and Name and Place of Abode. </td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The like on charge on change of Manufactoruy. &mdash; Penalty P20. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Places for drying, &amp;c. not to be used before Notice. </td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Makers to permit Officers to take Notice of Stock of Rags, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Entry to be made of Paper, &amp;c. within Five Days after drying, &amp;c. and before Removal, and Duty paid within Six Months. &mdash;Penalty. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Permit for Removal gratis. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>
				</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowance of &pound;10 per Cent. on prompt Payment. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>192</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers may search drying Goods. </td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Owner refusing Entrance. &mdash;Penalty &pound;10. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maker using private drying Rooms, &amp;c. or not making due Entries, or unduly removing, &amp;c. &mdash;Penalty P50, and Goods forfeited. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duty to be paid for Stock in hand on 1st March 1696. </td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Paper Maker, &amp;c. to deliver to Officer a Particular in Writing signed, of Stock in hand, liable to Duty. </td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers may enter Shops, &amp;c. for the Purpose of receiving and comparing Valuation with the Goods. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>
				</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Refusing Entrance. &mdash;Penalty &pound;20. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If Officer is satisfied of Valuation he is to collect the Duty. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>
				</td></tr><tr>
				<td>If such Duty not paid by 11th March 1696, or not secured. &mdash; Distress. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>193</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowance of &pound;10 per Cent. on prompt Payment of Duty for Stock in hand.</td>
				<td>&sect; 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Valuation of Stock in case of dispute, estimated by Oath of Owners. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>In case of apparent Fraud. &mdash;Proceedings. </td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Paper Makers, &amp;c. not giving Particulars, &amp;c. of Stock in hand, or omitting or concealing Stock &mdash; Penalty &pound;50, and
			Goods omitted or concealed, &amp;c. forfeited.-</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 7. &sect; 12.</td>
				<td>193</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Information of Seizure to be laid within Eight Days before Two Justices.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Appeal to Quarter Sessions final.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Fees for Entries, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 14.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Using White Linen Rags for making Brown Paper, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;5.</td>
				<td>&sect; 27.</td>
				<td>196</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For repealing a Clause in a former Act relating to Party guilty, and for the better preventing Frauds and Abuses on Brewers and others, chargeable with the Duties of Excise.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i"> W. III. c</emph>. 19.</td>
				<td>215</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c.30. &sect; 15. in Part pealed.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.-</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewer to declare how much Strong and Small Beer or Ale he intends to make of each Guile, otherwise the Whole charged as Strong, and Duty accordingly, and Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewer after such Declaration, increasing Strong Beer, or laying off &mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>216</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewers Servants assisting&mdash;Penalty or Imprisonment.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Increasing Beer by adding former Guile&mdash;Penalty, unless added in Sight of Gauger.<br/><emph type="i">Brewer, &amp; c laying off Beer, &amp;c. contrary to this Act, Penalty </emph>&pound;100 42 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 38. &sect; 16.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
		
			<tr>				<td>Beer or Ale left and added to a new Guile, charged as new Drink, and Brewer to pay the Duties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewers to take up, &amp;c. their Pipes, Stop Cocks, and other Conveyances under Ground, and stop up the Hole in every Tun, Batch, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewer keeping such Pipe, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;100.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers of Excise may break up the Ground in a Common Brewhouse, &amp;c. and search for Private Pipes, and may turn Cocks, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If no Pipe, &amp;c. found, Officer to make Satisfaction.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Opposing Officers&mdash;Penalty &pound;50.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewers may use Pipes, Stop Cocks, &amp;c. that are Public.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>217</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewer setting up or altering any Tun, &amp;c. without Notice to Excise Office, or having Private Tun, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;200.<br/><emph type="i">See 5 G. III. c</emph>. 43. &sect; 25. <emph type="i">as to altering the Situation of Brewing Utensils, without Notice to Officer.</emph></td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewer or Cyder Maker delivering to Distiller or Vinegar Maker, Wash, &amp;c. without Notice to Gauger&mdash;Penalty 20s.</td>
				<td>&sect;9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Common Distiller, &amp;c. setting up Tun Cask, &amp;c. or keeping Private Tun Warehouse, &amp;c. without giving Notice&mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Concealing such Tun, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;50.<br/><emph type="i">Distiller to enter Vessels for Distillation</emph>, 24 <emph type="i">G.II. c</emph>. 40. &sect; 18.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
		
			<tr>
				<td>Persons keeping Wash, &amp;c. and having a Still of 20 Gallons, deemed a Common Distiller, and liable to the Duties of Excise.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 19. &sect; 11.</td>
				<td>217</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Penalties how to be sued for and disposed of.</td>
				<td>&sect; 12.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons having set up Works may distil for Sale Low Wines from Drink brewed from malted Corn, &amp;c. on Notice, and paying the Duties.<br/><emph type="i">This Act declared in its original Intention to extend to Scotland</emph>, 5.<emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 43. &sect; 24.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 218</td>
			</tr>
					<tr>
				<td>Proviso for any Clauses in Stat. 12 Car. II.c. 19.&ndash;14 Car. II. c.II.&ndash;22 Car. II.c. 13.&ndash; 25 Car.II. c. c. 6, 7.&ndash;1 Jac.II.c. 19.&ndash;6 W. &amp; M. c. 1. intended to be perpetual. Such as would otherwise determine continued until 1st Aug. 1706.</td> <td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 20. &sect; 3. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>221</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties on Wines and Vinegar, by Stat. 1 Jac. II. c. 3. continued, and the said Act continued until 1st August 1706.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 1 Jac. II., c.4. which was continued as to Tobacco only, continued til 1st August 1706.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duty on Tobacco to be paid according to Stat.7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 10.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Additional Duties on Salt for One Year.</td>
				<td>&sect; 53.</td>
				<td>233.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For Salt and Rock Salt made at the Salt Works, 1d. per Gallon.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>To be levied as by Stat. 5 W. &amp; M. c. 7. and 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 31.</td>
				<td>&sect; 54.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for Allowances herein mentioned for Fish and Salt exported, over and above Allowances by former Act, to be paid by Debentures.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>234</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>On Exportation of Salt, Securities for Duties discharged, upon Certificate and Oath.</td>
				<td>&sect; 55.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Application of the Duties upon Salt.</td>
				<td>&sect; 56.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For laying a Duty upon Leather for the Term of Three Years.-</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 21. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>238</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duty upon Leather, over and above all other Duties, for Three Years, to be paid by Tanner.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>239</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Mayors, Lords of Liberties, &amp;c. to execute and comply with the said Statute.&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>240</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The King or Treasury, may appoint Commissioners, who may substitute Deputies, &amp;c., and who are to pay Duties collected into the Exchequer.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Value of Goods how to be taken and without Allowance for Duties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tanners, &amp;c. to give Notice in Writing to the Officer, of using Tan Houses, &amp;c. and of Number of Pits and other Particulars herein mentioned, and of changing the same.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And of their Names and Places of Abode, &amp;c.&mdash;Neglecting, &amp;c. to give such Notice.&mdash;Penalty &pound;50.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Tanners, &amp;c. to use no Place other than that mentioned in Notice.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>	<td>And to suffer Commissioners or Officers to take Account of the Number and Quality of Hides, &amp;c. taken out of the Wooze, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III.c</emph>. 21 &sect; 8. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>240</td></tr><tr><td>
And within Three Days after taking out of Wooze, and before carrying to drying Places, make Entry thereof</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>241</td></tr><tr><td>
Tanner, &amp;c. not to remove Hides, &amp;c. from Yards, &amp;c. without Permit or Certificate of Account taken and Entry made, or without Notice to Officer.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Permits gratis.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
How far Tanner obliged to travel to give Notice.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Officer, at seasonable Times, may enter Tan Yards, &amp;c. and search.</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Owner, &amp;c. of Tan Yard, &amp;c. refusing Entrance to Officer&mdash;Penalty &pound;5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Tanner, &amp;c. using private Tan Yards, &amp;c. or not making Entries, or removing without Permit or Notice, or concealing Hides, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Leather found in Places not entered, &amp;c. forfeited.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
No Fee for any of the said Entries, Certificates, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Leather not to be sold, otherwise than in open Market.</td>
				<td>&sect; 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Such Sale to be entered with Officer before Delivery of Goods sold.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph></td></tr><tr><td>
The Duty to be thereupon paid, and Collector to give Tanner, &amp;c. a Copy of such Entry, and a Receipt for the Duties.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Proceedings in case of Dispute touching the Value of the Leather so to be sold.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Buyer not to take away Goods till Entry made.</td>
				<td>&sect; 12.</td>
				<td>242</td></tr><tr><td>
Selling otherwise than in open Market, or not making Entry, or Buyer removing Goods before Entry made&mdash; Penalty &pound;40, and Leather forfeited.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Where Leather seized, and Information laid, or Complaint made as herein mentioned, the same may be determined by Two Justices of Peace.</td>
				<td>&sect; 14.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>Appeal.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Tanner, &amp;c. every Three Months to account with Officer for Hides, &amp;c. taken out of Wooze, &amp;c. and for Entries, and to discharge such Account in Manner herein mentioned.&mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>&sect; 15.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Officers, upon taking such Account, to inform themselves of the Truth thereof.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Tanner, &amp;c. defrauding the Crown&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Collar Makers, Glovers, &amp;c. accounted Tawers.</td>
				<td>&sect; 17.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Persons making their Leather into Wares not obliged to carry the same to Fairs, or sell or register there, but to enter the same with the Officer of the Place where they dwell, and make Oath of Value as herein mentioned, and pay Duties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 18.</td>
				<td>242, 243</td></tr><tr><td>
Collar Maker, &amp;c. making Leather into Wares, or selling before Entry&mdash;Penalty &pound;5.</td>
				<td>&sect; 19.</td>
				<td>243
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>
Tanners, Collar Makers, &amp;c. having Stock of Leather not made into Wares on the 20th April 1697, to pay an ad valorem Duty as herein mentioned within Three Months after the said 20th April.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 21. &sect; 20.</td>
				<td>243</td></tr><tr><td>
Tanners, &amp;c. to deliver to the Officer a Particular in Writing, signed, of Stock of Leather not made into Wares.</td>
				<td>&sect; 21.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Officer may enter Shops, &amp;c. and view and take Account, and compare Goods with Valuation.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Refusing Entrance to Officer&mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
If Officer satisfied of Quantity and Value of Stock, he is to collect Duty, and give Acquittances gratis.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
If Duties not paid or secured within Three Months&mdash;Distress.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Allowance for prompt Payment of Duty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 22.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
In case of Dispute, the Value of Stock taken upon the Oath of Owner; and if Officer suspect Fraud, then he may take them at such Value, paying down ready Money.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>244</td></tr><tr><td>
Tanners, Collar Makers, &amp;c. neglecting, &amp;c. to give Particular and Valuation on or before 1st May 1697, or giving fraudulent Particulars, or unduly removing or concealing Stock&mdash;Penalty &pound;20, and such Stock forfeited.</td>
				<td>&sect; 23.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Surplus of Duty on Leather, after Payment of Charges of collecting, to be applied as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 33.</td>
				<td>246</td></tr><tr><td>
The said Duties, after Payment of Charges, to be paid weekly into the Exchequer, and applied as herein mentioned&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Deficiencies of Duties to make good the Sum of &pound;564,700 and Interest, to be supplied out of next Aid.</td>
				<td>&sect; 34.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
The like, as to Deficiency of Contribution for Annuities, to make good the Sum of &pound;280,000.<br/><emph type="i">See</emph> 1 <emph type="i">Ann. Stat</emph>. 1. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 13. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
For granting to His Majesty certain Duties upon Malt, Mum, Sweets, Cyder, and Perry, as well towards carrying on the War against France, as for the necessary Occasions of His Majesty's Household and other Occasions.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 22.</td>
				<td>247</td></tr><tr><td>
Duty upon Malt in Hand the 20th April 1697, to be paid by Maltster, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Duty upon Malt to be paid by Maker.</td>
				<td rows="3"><emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td rows="3">
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Duty upon Mum to be paid by Maker.</td></tr>
<tr><td>Duty upon Sweets to be paid by Maker.</td>	</tr>				
					<tr><td>Duty upon Cyder and Perry to be paid by First Buyer or Retailer.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
What Persons deemed Retailers of Cyder and Perry.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Duties under Management of Commissioners of Excise.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Inferior Officers for Duties upon Beer, &amp;c. to be so for collecting, &amp;c. the said Duties.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Who may be made, altered, or dismissed by Commissioners.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maltsters, &amp;c. having Malt in Possession upon 20th April 1697, to make Entry thereof&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 22. &sect; 4.</td>
				<td>248</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And to pay or give Security for Duties within Six Days after Entry.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowance for prompt Payment.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer to take Account of Malt in Hand upon 20th April 1697.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maltsters, &amp;c. to permit Officers to enter Premises&mdash;Penalty &pound;10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers upon Request to be permitted Entrance to gauge Cisterns, and take Account of Barley, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers to report thereon to the Commissioners, and to leave Copy of Report with Maltster, which shall be a Charge upon him.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Refusing Entrance, or to permit Officer to take Account, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maltsters to make Monthly Entries&mdash;Penalty &pound;10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maltster to pay Duty within Three Months after Entry.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Neglecting, &amp;c. to make such Payment&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Bushel to be according to Winchester Bushel.</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Rule for Return of Bushel by Officer.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>249</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maltster, erecting, altering, &amp;c. Cisterns, Fat, &amp;c. for steeping Barley, &amp;c. without giving Notice, or using Private Cisterns, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;50.</td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Makers of Sweets, setting up, or using steeping Tubs, &amp;c. without giving Notice, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;50.</td>
				<td>&sect; 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Powers &amp; Penalties of Stat. 12 Car. II. c. 24. &amp; all former Acts in force for levying the said Duties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 12.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Except as enacted otherwise by this Act.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Penalties imposed by this Act to be sued for.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners or other Officers herein named, may compound for Duties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 14.</td>
				<td>249</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Terms of such Composition.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Malthouses, &amp;c. of Persons compounding, not liable to Duty of 6d. per Bushel upon Malt, or to Survey.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Selling, &amp;c. Malt, or Malt Liquor after Composition&mdash;Penalty &pound;50.</td>
				<td>&sect; 15.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And to lose Benefit of Composition.</td><td><emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowance for Difference of Quantity between Corn when wet, and when converted into Dry Malt.</td>
				<td>&sect; 16.</td>
				<td>250</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Liberty to Persons having paid Duty on Malt, and to Purchasers from such Persons, to export Malt (except to Scotland) on Security not to reland</td>
				<td>&sect; 17.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If any Malt so shipped for Exportation shall be relanded, such Malt forfeited, over and above the Penalty of the Bond.</td>
				<td>&sect; 18.</td>
				<td>250</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Exporters of Malt to produce Certificate from Officer of Duty paid.</td>
				<td>&sect; 19.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Such Certificate to be given on Oath made that Duty paid, and that the Malt exported is the same mentioned in Certificate.</td>
				<td>8 &amp; 9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 22. &sect; 19.</td>
				<td>250</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And thereupon the Officer to, give to Exporter a Certificate of Quantity, upon Production of which Duty repaid</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If Officers have not Money in Hand; Commissioners to repay the same.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Where Malt sold before 20th April 1697, and not delivered or contracted so to be, Buyer to pay to Seller the Duty upon Delivery, or Bargain void.</td>
				<td>&sect; 20.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Where Rent is payable in Malt, or to be ascertained by the Price of Malt, Tenant may make such Deduction as herein mentioned, which the Landlord is to allow, and Tenant discharged.</td>
				<td>&sect;21.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Importing Malt.</td>
				<td>&sect;22.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Forfeiture of the Malt or Value thereof.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>251</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duty upon Malt, how appropriated</td>
				<td>&sect;26.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Deficiency to be made good out of the First Aid granted in Parliament, after 20th April 1698.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If Duties upon Malt, before 29th Sept. 1699, and Monies supplied to make good the Deficiency, do not amount to &pound;1,515,000, Deficiency supplied out of the First Aid, after the said 29th Sept.<br/><emph type="i">See </emph>1 <emph type="i">Ann. Stat.</emph> 1. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 13. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>252</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>Retailers of Salt to sell by weight</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 6.</td>
				<td>302</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Retailer, &amp;c. to sell Salt otherwise than by Weight, after the Rate of 56 lb. to the Bushel&mdash;Penalty &pound;5.<br/><emph type="i">No Person to buy Salt but by Weight;</emph>1 <emph type="i">Ann. Stat.</emph> 1. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 21.&sect;28.</td>
				<td>&sect;1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>Two Justices of peace may determine Offences.</td>
				<td>&sect;2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Appeal to Quarter Seesions final&mdash;How Justices to proceed on Complaint.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Forfeitures to be levied on Offenders Goods.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For want of Distress&mdash;Imprisonment.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer to attend the weighting out of Salt entered to be shipped, and on whom the Duty has been paid, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty 40s.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For explaining an Act made in the last Session of Parliament, for granting to His Majesty certain Duties upon Malt,Mum, Sweets, Cyder, and Perry</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 8.</td>
				<td>304</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties of the said Act appropriated.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Rules of Stat. 1 W. &amp; M. Sess. 2. c. 1. applied to this Act.</td>
				<td>&sect;2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For repealing and Act 39 Eliz. for restraining the excessive making of Malt, and to discharge and vacate Orders made by Justices of Peace by virtue thereof, for restraining Maltsters from making Malt.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 22.</td>
				<td>382</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 39 Eliz. c. 16. repealed, and Orders of Justices herein mentioned to have been made, therein discharged</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For raising a Sum not exceeding &pound;2,000,000 upon a Fund for Payment of Annuities after the Rate of &pound;8 per Cent. per Annum; and for settling the Trade to the East Indies.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 44.</td>
				<td>429</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>An Additional Duty of 5d. per Gallon on Salt imported from 1st July 1698 to 25th Dec. 1699&mdash;and from 24th Dec. 1699 for ever, 7d. per Gallon</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For Home-made Salt from 1st July 1698 to 25th Dec. 1692, 2&frac12;d. per Gallon.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>430</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And from 24th Dec. 1699 for ever, 3&frac12;d. per Gallon; subject nevertheless to Redemption.<br/><emph type="i">The Duties on Home-made Salt repealed</emph>, 3 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 20. &sect; 1. <emph type="i">all the Salt Duties revived as therein mentioned</emph>, 5 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 6. <emph type="i">made perpetual</emph> 26 <emph type="i">G. II.c</emph>. 3. &sect; 1. <emph type="i">and made to cease</emph>, 27 <emph type="i">G.III.c</emph>. 13. &sect; 1. 35.&ndash;38 <emph type="i">G.III. c</emph>. 89. &sect; 1. &ndash;43 <emph type="i">G.III. c</emph>. 68. &sect; 1. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 69. &sect; 1.&ndash;49 <emph type="i">G.III. c</emph>. 98. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The Duty on Foreign Salt to be paid by Importer.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Imported Salt landed before due Entry, &amp;c. forfeited and Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Importer giving Security to have Six Months for Payment, and at the Rate of &pound;10 per Cent. per Ann. for ready Money.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The Duties to be managed by Commissioners of Excise and Officers appointed by them.<br/><emph type="i">See</emph> 38 <emph type="i">G.III. c</emph>. 89. &sect; 6.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
			<td>Penalties sued for, &amp;c. as by Stat. 12 C. II.c. 24., or any other Law in force.</td><td/><td/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Makers and Proprietors of Salt to make true Entries with the Officers&mdash;and to take Warrant for removing Salt gratis, upon Payment of or Security for Duty within Six Months after Entry.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Discount at the Rate of &pound; 10 per Cent. per Ann. for ready Money.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers may seize Salt conveying away before due Entry made, and without Warrant for Removal.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How seized Salt to be disposed of.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>431</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If not claimed within 10 Days forfeited, One Moiety to the King the other to the Seizer.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Or if claimed without Proof of Entry upon Oath, forfeited as aforesaid.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Carrying away Salt before Entry and Warrant had, Salt forfeited and Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Oath by Retailer or Shopkeeper that Duty paid or secured before Salt shipped.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Masters of Ships, before Warrant for landing, &amp;c. had, to deliver Particulars to the Collectors and make Oath as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If Ship be to deliver her Salt at different Ports, Officer to certify the same on Back of Cocquet&mdash;Penalty.<br/><emph type="i">Proviso for Boats, &amp;c. carrying Salt to be reshipped</emph>, 5 <emph type="i">G. I. c</emph>. 18. &sect; 25.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
					<tr>
				<td>No Fee for Debentures, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowances for Fish exported, viz.</td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For every Cask of Pilchards or Scads, from 1st July 1698 to 25th Dec. 1699, 20s. and after 24th Dec. 1699, 28s.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 44. &sect; 10.</td>
				<td>431</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For every Barrel of White Herrings, from 1st July 1698 to 25th Dec. 1699, 4s. 2d.; and from 24th Dec. 1699, 5s. 10d.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For every Barrel of Red Herrings, from 1st July 1698 to 25th Dec. 1699, 3s. 4d; and after 24th Dec. 1699, 4s. 8d.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>432</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For every Barrel of Salmon, from 1st July 1698 to 25th Dec. 1699, 8s. 4d.; after 24th Dec. 1699, 11s. 8d.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For every 100 of Cod Fish, after 1st July and before 25th Dec. 1699, 25s.; after 24th Dec. 1699, 35s.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For every Last of dried Red Sprats, after 1st July 1698, 6s. 8d.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowances to be paid in Port from whence exported as here in mentioned.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Oath of Exporter that Fish were English taken, &amp;c. before Debenture allowed.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Fee for Debenture.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proceeding where Officer has not sufficient Money to pay.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer refusing, &amp;c. to pay Debenture&mdash;Penalty.<br/><emph type="i">The above Allowances appear to be expired</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>Officer to deliver Certificates of Duty paid gratis to Exporter of Salt.</td>
				<td>&sect; 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Debenture given on Production of Certificate, without Fee.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Upon Production of Debenture, Security discharged.<br/><emph type="i">Extended to Exportation to Scotland, Isle of Man, Jersey, and Guernsey</emph>, 2 &amp; 3 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 14. &sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Salt not made in England, Wales, or Berwick, to pay as Foreign.</td>
				<td>&sect; 12.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Scotch Salt to be entered at Carlisle or Berwick.<br/><emph type="i">See as to Duty</emph>, 5 &amp; 6 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 8. <emph type="i">art</emph>. 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>In Action for executing Act, General Issue may be pleaded&mdash;Double Costs.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Writ of Certiorari to supersede Proceedings upon Orders of the Commissioners, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 14.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Salt delivered without Notice to Officer&mdash;Forfeiture and Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 15.</td>
				<td>433</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Salt, after Duty repaid, landed before Duty be again paid, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 16.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Subjects of England exporting Salt in a Ship which perishes at Sea, &amp;c. allowed to buy like Quantity without Duty, upon Proof made of Loss and Certificate thereof.</td>
				<td>&sect; 17.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Salt, after Entry, may be warehoused on Warrant for the same.</td>
				<td>&sect; 18.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
 	</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Warrant had without fee.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			
<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>			
			
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Person obliged by Contract made before 25th Dec. 1698, to deliver Salt, unless Buyer pay Seller the Duty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 19.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Rock Salt to be entered by Weight, 120 lbs. Weight, Winchester Bushel.<br/>75 <emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 11. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>&sect; 20.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Refiners of Rock Salt, having before paid the Duty, to have an additional Abatement of 2s. 4d. per Bushel.<br/><emph type="i">See</emph> 5 &amp; 6 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 8. <emph type="i">art</emph>. 8.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 44. &sect; 21.</td>
				<td>433</td>
			</tr>
						<tr>
				<td>Salt weighed in the Presence of Officer, and Oath taken as herein mentioned.<br/><emph type="i">See as to Scotland</emph>, 5 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 8. <emph type="i">art</emph>. 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Charge of Management to be paid out of Duties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 22.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Salt made from Rock Salt, and from Salt either imported or home-made, charged.</td>
				<td>&sect; 23.</td>
				<td>434</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>All Salt, except Rock Salt, to be ascertained at 56 lbs. Weight to the Bushel.</td>
				<td>&sect; 24.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Salt brought from Scotland, and all imported Salt brought in or landed before Entry, forfeited, and Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 25.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Collectors to provide Scales, &amp;c. at every Salt Work.</td>
				<td>&sect; 26.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Weighers to be sworn.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Justice may administer Oath.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Collector to pay Weigher.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer to deliver as many Warrants or Permits to Salt Carriers as they desire, gratis.</td>
				<td>&sect; 27.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Salt, except Foreign, sold at 56 lbs. Weight a Bushel&mdash;Penalty &pound;5.</td>
				<td>&sect; 28.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Lord Mayor and Court of Aldermen of London to ascertain and publish the Price of Salt within the City of London and Bills of Mortality.</td>
				<td>&sect; 29.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And Justices of Peace in their General Sessions for other Places.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And the said Lord Mayor, Aldermen, and Justices in Sessions, by Writing, may alter and correct Rates, which Rates are to be observed.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 435</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Selling for higher Prices&mdash;Penalty &pound;5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>435</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Distress&mdash;In Default of Distress, Imprisonment until Penalty be paid.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The Duties on Salt by this Act granted, and the Stamp Duties of Cap. 25. ante, to be kept apart and paid weekly into the Exchequer.</td>
				<td>&sect; 30.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Entries to be made thereof in Books in the Exchequer</td>
				<td>&sect; 31.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners for managing the said Duties respectively not paying duly into the Exchequer, &amp;c.&mdash;Forfeiture of Office, and Incapacity and Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 32.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Offices for Duties continued with Commissioners and Comptrollers of the Duties.<br/><emph type="i">Particular Commissioners for Salt Duties may be appointed</emph>, 1 <emph type="i">Ann. Stat</emph>. 1. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 21.&sect; 26. <emph type="i">Duties to be under the Management of Commissioners of Excise in England and Scotland</emph>, 38 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 89. &sect; 6.</td>
				<td>&sect; 33.</td>
				<td>436</td>
			</tr>
						<tr>
				<td>Comptrollers to keep distinct Accounts.</td>
				<td>&sect; 34.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Neglecting, Forfeiture of Office&mdash;Incapacity, and Penalty, &pound;100.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Collectors detaining Money, Dismission; to pay Interest at &pound;12 per Cent., and liable to Treble Damages</td>
				<td>&sect; 35.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Misaplying any Part of Money&mdash;Dismission, Incapacity, and Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>From 29th Sept. 1698, &pound;160,000 additional out of Duties on Salt and Stamps to be the yearly Fund for answering Annuities to Subscribers of &pound;2,000,000. Proviso for Deficiency.<br/><emph type="i">As to the free Enjoyment of this</emph> &pound;160,000 <emph type="i">per Annum by the East India Company, see</emph> 10 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 28.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 44. &sect; 36.</td>
				<td>436</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Appropriation of the said Duties.</td><td/><td/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers of the Exchequer not issuing or misapplying the Money, Dismission, Incapacity, and Penalty.<br/><emph type="i">What Persons subject to the Penalties of this Act</emph>, 6 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 11. &sect; 7. <emph type="i">Officers, &amp; c. for Duties on Hops liable to this Act</emph>, 9 <emph type="i">Ann. c. 12. &sect; 29. So. on Hackney Coaches, &amp;c. 9 Ann. c</emph>. 23.&sect; 48. <emph type="i">So Officers, Cashiers, and others as therein mentioned</emph>, 1 <emph type="i">G. I. stat</emph>. 2. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 19. &sect; 2. <emph type="i">So Officers for Duty on Plate, &amp; c</emph>. 6 <emph type="i">G.I. c</emph>. 11. &sect; 23. <emph type="i">On Coffee, &amp; c</emph>. 10 <emph type="i">G. I. c</emph>. 10. &sect; 45. <emph type="i">Stamp Duties</emph>, 12 <emph type="i">G. I. c</emph>. 33. &sect; 12.</td>
				<td>&sect; 37.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>One Moiety of the Duties granted by Stat. 6 &amp; 7 W. III. c. 18. and 7 &amp; 8 W. III.c. 31. upon Glass and Glass Wares, and the whole of the Duties thereby granted upon Stone Bottles, &amp;c. determined, and in lieu thereof Duties on Whale Fins, Scotch Twills and Ticking.<br/><emph type="i">See this Index, tit. customs; and the Duties upon Glass appear to be determined</emph>, 10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 24.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 45.</td>
				<td>447</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>Makers of Glass, after 1st Aug. 1698, removing Glass, &amp;c. without Presence of or Notice to Officer&mdash; Penalty &pound;10.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>448</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For prohibiting the excessive distilling of Spirits and Low Wines from Corn, and against the exporting of Beer and Ale, and to prevent Frauds in Distillers.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 4.</td>
				<td>456</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Unduly making Aqua Vit&aelig;, &amp;c.&mdash; Penalty, and Stills, &amp;c. forfeited.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Penalties divided and recovered.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Servants, &amp;c. aiding&mdash;Imprisonment.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>457</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for using Yeast in certain Distillations.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Distillers keeping private Conveyance before 28th Feb. 1698, to take up and demolish the same, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Distiller, after 28th Feb. 1698, keeping private Conveyance&mdash; Penalty &pound;100.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer in the Day-time and with Constable, may search for private Pipes, &amp;c. and may break up Ground, &amp;c. of any House, &amp;c. into which the same may lead, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If no Pipe, &amp;c. found, Officer to make good the Ground, or make Satisfaction to Owner, to be adjudged by Two
			Justices, or Party may bring his Action.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Damages paid out of Excise Revenue.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Opposing Officer&mdash; Penalty &pound;100.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Distiller may use Pipe, &amp;c. above Ground.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer suspecting concealed Stills, &amp;c. on Affidavit thereof, may in the Day-time and with Constable, &amp;c. break open Doors, and search and seize such Stills, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>458</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And if the same not claimed within 20 Days, then forfeited, and may be sold.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Proceeds of Sale disposed of.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 4. &sect; 7.</td>
				<td>458</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If such Stills, &amp;c. claimed, then Claimant to pay&mdash; Penalty of &pound;200.<br/><emph type="i">As to Owners of private Stills refusing to claim, see</emph> 10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 10. &sect; 20. <emph type="i">and further</emph>, 19 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 50. &sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
						<tr>
				<td>If no Still, &amp;c. found, then Officer to make good Place broken up, or make Satisfaction to Owner to be adjudged by Two Justices, or Party may bring his Action.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Damages paid out of Revenue of Excise.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Opposing Officer&mdash; Penalty &pound;200.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Spirits made from Mixture of Spirits with Wash, &amp;c., except with Water, chargeable.</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The Owners of Houses, &amp;c. used as open Distilleries as herein described, may, between 31st Jan. 1698, and 1st Feb. 1699, distil Spirits or Low Wines as herein mentioned, so as the Whole does not exceed the Quantity herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Controversy respecting the Quantity to be determined by Accounts, and Vouchers returned into the Head Office of Excise of the Year already ended.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>459</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Access gratis to such Accounts.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners of Excise to give to Owners a true Account in Writing of Quantities charged in such Vouchers, ending 30th Sept. 1698.</td>
				<td>&sect; 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Exporting or lading for Exportation Beer; Ale, Wash, &amp;c. &mdash; Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 12.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for Exportation of Beer and Ale for Ship's Crews, and Passengers, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And to Colonies, Forts, &amp;c. in America, Persia, and East Indies, for their Sustentation, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 14.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>On Security by Exporter for the due Landing thereof.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Such Security to be taken without Fee.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso in favour of Charles Bennett.</td>
				<td>&sect; 15.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For laying further Duties upon Sweets, and for lessening the Duties upon Vinegar, Low Wines, and Whale Fins, and the Duties upon Brandy imported, and for raising the Duties upon Leather, and for charging Cinders, and for permitting the Importation of Pearl Ashes, and for preventing Abuses in brewing Beer and Ale, and Frauds in Importation of Tobacco.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 10.</td>
				<td>501</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Additional Duties upon Sweets.<br/><emph type="i">See</emph> 5 &amp; 6 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 19. &sect; 5.; <emph type="i">but see Note to Section</emph> 7.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>What Liquors deemed Sweets.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Duties upon Sweets by former Acts chargeable.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>What Persons deemed Makers of Sweets.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Refiners of Sugar, before 1st June 1699, entering into Bond, not chargeable with the Duties of this Act upon Sweets made from Sugar and Syrups, until they shall have sold the same.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How the said Duties on Sweets appropriated.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 10. &sect; 4.</td>
				<td>502</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties of former Acts upon Rape, Vinegar, &amp;c. from the 10th May 1699, made to cease.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duty upon Vinegar, &amp;c. paid by the Maker.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For what Terms the Duties on Vinegar to be paid.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How the same applied.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>6d. per Barrel, Part thereof to His Majesty for Life, in lieu of the like Duty of Stat. 2 W. &amp; M. c. 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>6d. per Barrel, other Part thereof to His Majesty and His Successors, in lieu of the like Duty of Stat. 12 Car.II. c. 24.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>2s. 4d. other Part thereof to His Majesty and his Successors, for the Remainder of a Term of 99 Years, commencing 28th January 1692, in lieu of certain Duties of Stat. 4 W. &amp; M. c. 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>2s. 4d. other Part thereof to His Majesty and his Successors, for the Remainder of a Term of 16 Years, commencing 17th May 1697, in lieu of certain Duties of Stat. 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>2s. 4d. Residue thereof to His Majesty and His Successors, in lieu of certain Duties of Stat. 5 &amp; 6 W. &amp; M. c. 20.<br/><emph type="i">These Duties made to cease so far as not previously expired</emph>, 27 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 13. &sect; 35.&ndash; 43 <emph type="i">G.III. c</emph>. 69. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>What Liquors deemed Vinegar, or Liquors preparing for Vinegar.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>503</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>After 10th May 1699, Vinegar Maker receiving Stale Beer, &amp;c. or sending out Vinegar without Notice, as herein mentioned&mdash;Penalty &pound;50.</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Vinegar Makers receiving the said Liquors to shew same to Gauger before mixing with other Liquors&mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>503</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Vinegar Makers using Storehouse, &amp;c. without Notice to Officer of Excise&mdash;Penalty &pound; 50.</td>
				<td>&sect; 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How a Barrel of Vinegar to be accounted and returned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 12.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How far Vinegar Makers, having in Custody Vinegar, &amp;c. on the 10th May 1699, charged with former Duties, are to be charged for the same.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Fourpence, Part of the Duty of 8s. per Gallon of Low Wines, and a Moiety of the Duty of 3d. per Gallon, Exception, to cease.</td>
				<td>&sect; 14.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for Duties due before 10th May 1699.</td>
				<td>&sect; 15.</td>
				<td>504.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And for Clauses in Stat. 7 &amp; 8 W. III.c. 30. respecting the Payment and Appropriation of said Duties, and of the Duties not hereby determined.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 12 Car. II. c. 24., and other Acts, to remain in force for levying the said Duties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 16.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Penalties of this Act recovered.</td>
				<td>&sect; 17.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>In Actions for executing this Act, General Issue may be pleaded.&mdash;Treble Costs.</td>
				<td>&sect; 18.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers of Excise to keep Accounts of Wash found with Distillers, and to make Charges upon Decrease thereof as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W.III. c</emph>. 10. &sect; 19.</td>
				<td>504</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Distillers to pay Duty according to such Charge.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Penalty of &pound;200 upon Proprietors of private Stills, &amp;c.<br/><emph type="i">As to Seizure of private Stills by Officer, see</emph> 19 <emph type="i">G.III. c</emph>. 50. &sect; 2.</td>
				<td>&sect; 20.</td>
				<td>505</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>Distiller abating Quantities of Low Wines which he might draw equal to those he exceeded, as herein mentioned, not liable to Prosecution.</td>
				<td>&sect; 21.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Two Justices may determine the Penalties of Stat. 8 W. III. c. 20., and may issue Warrant for levying the same, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 22.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Power to such Justices to mitigate Penalties, allowing Costs over and above such Mitigation.</td>
				<td>&sect; 23.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 8 W. III. c. 20. declared to charge the Duties herein mentioned from the Commencement and during the Continuance of the said Act.</td>
				<td>&sect; 24.</td>
				<td>506</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Common Brewers using Molasses, &amp;c. in brewing, or receiving Molasses, &amp;c. exceeding 10lbs.&mdash;Penalty &pound;100.</td>
				<td>&sect; 31.</td>
				<td>507</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons aiding, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;20, and in Default Imprisonment.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For the more full and effectual charging of the Duties upon Rock Salt.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III. c.</emph> 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>75lbs. weight of Rock Salt or Salt Rock (<emph type="i">a</emph>) deemed a Winchester Bushel, and to be entered and rated accordingly, instead of 120lbs. weight, as by former Acts.<br/>(<emph type="i">a</emph>) 65 <emph type="i">lbs</emph>. 1 <emph type="i">Ann. stat</emph>. 1. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 21. &sect; 9.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
		<tr>
				<td>Owners of Rock Pits taking Rock. Salt thereout, to cause the same, before Removal, to be weighed in the Presence of Officer, who is to make Return to Commissioners of Excise, and leave a Copy with Owner of Pit to be a Charge upon him.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 509</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Owner refusing to weigh, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Owners of Pits to clear off Duty or give Security to pay within Nine Months.&mdash;Penalty.<br/><emph type="i">Enlarged to Twelve Months</emph>, 5 &amp; 6 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 29. &sect; 5.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowance on Payment of Duty &pound;10 per Cent.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowance to Refiners of Rock Salt for which Duties have been paid at the Rate of 75lbs (<emph type="i">a</emph>) Weight to the Bushel&mdash;Condition.<br/>(<emph type="i">a</emph>) <emph type="i">See Note to Section</emph> 1.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
						<tr>
				<td>Oath to be made of particular Quantities of Salt employed in refining, &amp;c. which Oath Justices may administer.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proof made that Duties paid or secured.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowances on Rock Salt exported, and charged and paid at the Rate of 75lbs. (<emph type="i">a</emph>) Weight per Bushel.<br/>(<emph type="i">a</emph>) <emph type="i">See Note to Section</emph> 1.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>At the Rate of 56lbs. Weight per Bushel on Debenture.<br/><emph type="i">No greater Allowance on Exportation than what was before paid for Duty</emph>, 5 &amp; 6 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 29. &sect; 16.; <emph type="i">but see</emph> 5 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 6. &sect; 5.&ndash; 25 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 63. &sect; 1. 3.; <emph type="i">and as to Exportation to the Isle of Man</emph>, 26 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 36. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W.III. c</emph>. 11. &sect; 6.</td>
				<td>509</td>
			</tr>
			
			<tr>
				<td>Quantity verified by Searcher, and Oath of Exporter that Duties paid, and Salt not intended to be relanded.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Fee for Debenture.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If Officer has not sufficient Money in hand to pay Allowances, Commissioners of Excise to pay same.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
<tr>	<td>Officer neglecting, &amp;c. to pay or give certificate&mdash;Penalty.<br/><emph type="i">As to Drawback on Exportation to Scotland, Isle of Man, &amp; c</emph>., 2 &amp; 3 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 14. &sect; 9.&ndash;20 <emph type="i">G. III.c</emph>. 34. &sect; 3, 4.&ndash; 25 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 63. &sect; 2. &ndash; 26 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 36. &sect; 1.</td>	
	<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>

</tr>
						<tr>
				<td>Duties to be levied as by former Acts (Exception.)</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>510</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Penalties recovered and distributed.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How said Duties to be brought in and applied.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons aggrieved, by Order of Two Justices relating to the said Duties, may appeal to Quarter Sessions.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Determination final.<br/><emph type="i">See</emph> 25 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 63. &sect; 25.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
						<tr>
				<td>Rock Salt shipped for Exportation or Coastwise, to be weighed at Place of loading.</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Loading the same before weighing, &amp;c. and Permit obtained&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer not granting Permit gratis&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso in case of Officer refusing or not attending to weigh Salt, or refusing Permit.</td>
				<td>&sect; 10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer at Port of unlading may go on board and demand Sight of Permit, and may weigh.</td>
				<td>&sect; 11.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If Salt found more than expressed in Permit, the Surplus, forfeited.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Master of Ship refusing to shew Permit, Officer may seize and detain Salt.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If Permit not shewn in Four Days, Salt forfeited.</td>
				<td>&sect; 12.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For taking off the remaining Duties upon Glass Wares.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 24.</td>
				<td>533</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The remaining Moiety of the said Duties upon Glass and Glass Wares to cease.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For granting to His Majesty several Duties upon Low Wines or Spirits of the First Extraction, and continuing several additional Duties upon Coffee, Tea, Chocolate, Spices, and Pictures, and certain Impositions upon Hawkers, Pedlars, and Petty Chapment, and the Duty of &pound;15 per Cent. upon Muslins, and for improving the Duties upon jap[p]anned and lacquered Goods, and for continuing the Coinage Duty for the several Terms and Purposes therein mentioned.</td>
							<td>12 &amp; 13 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 11.</td>
				<td>716</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties payable from 24th March 1700, to 29th March 1706, by way of Excise.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said Rates to be raised as under Stat. 12 Car. II. c. 24. and Stat. 7 W. III. c. 30. and by former Laws of Excise in force (Exception.)</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>
					Upon the Oath by Distillers and others herein mentioned, Distillers, &amp;c. may export Spirits made as aforesaid, and upon Certificate of Quantity, a Drawback of 3d. per Gallon allowed on Exportation.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>716, 717</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 2 W. &amp; M. Sess. c.9. &sect; 11. continued.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>717</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Penalties for Offences relating to Duties upon Low Wines, how applied and recovered.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The additional Duties on Coffee, Tea, Chocolate, and Spices and Pictures, &amp;c. of Stat. 6 &amp; 7 W. &amp; M. c. 7. and continued by Stat. 9 W. III. c. 14. continued from 30th April 1701, to 1st May 1706.&mdash; The said Stat. 6 &amp; 7 W. &amp; M.c.7. continued until 1st May 1706.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Limitation of Information against Distillers, &amp;c. for Offences committed after 24th June 1701.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>719</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Notice thereof to Person against whom Information laid to be left at Dwelling House.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>No Brandy or distilled Liquors to be sold by Retail after 29th Sept. 1701, without Licence.</td>
				<td>&sect; 14.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Such Retailers to be subject to the like Penalties as common Alehouse Keepers &mdash;and Justices, &amp;c. to have the same Jurisdiction over them.<br/><emph type="i">See</emph> 1 <emph type="i">Ann. Stat</emph>. 2. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 14. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 11 W. III. c. 15. &sect; 5. not to extend to the Privileges of the Two Universities to stamp Ale and Beer Measures.</td>
				<td>&sect; 15.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>After 29th Sept. 1701, Foreign Brandy and Spirits in Vessels under 15 Tons Burthen (Exception) forfeited.</td>
				<td>&sect; 16.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Clause of Loan for &pound;300,000 upon Credit of the said Duties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 17.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Interest at the Rate of &pound;6 per Cent. per Ann. for first &pound;150,000, &pound; 7 per Cent. per Ann. for last &pound;150,000.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties to be paid Weekly into the Exchequer, and entered separate from other Duties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 18.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Sums lent and raised under this Act (Exception), and Monies lent between 18th Feb. and 10th June 1701&mdash; And Monies further lent upon the Credit of Two Thirds of the Aid granted by this Act&mdash;And Monies lent upon Credit of the &pound;3,700 per Week out of Civil List Funds, Exception, and Overplus of the Funds appropriated by Stat. 11 W. III. c. 2. Exception, and Arrears of Tunnage and Poundage, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 22.</td>
				<td>720</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>And Duties of 5s. per Ton upon French Shipping under Stat. 12 Car. II. c.4. from 25th Dec. 1700, till 25th March 1702&mdash;And Duties under Stat. 7 &amp; 8 W. III. c. 20. &mdash;And Duties of is. 10d. per Ton upon East India Wrought Silk imported under 9 W. III. c. 44. &sect; 70. from 25th Dec. 1700.</td>
			
				<td>12 &amp; 13 <emph type="i">W. III. c.11</emph>.&sect; 22.</td>
				<td>720</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Treasury to issue Monies above appropriated to the Uses of this Act, (Exception), and to allow Interest upon Tallies at &pound;6 per Cent. per Annum.</td>
				<td>&sect; 23.</td>
				<td>722</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Rules of Stat. 1 W. 8c M. Sess. 2. c. 1. revived and applied to the Application of Monies appropriated by this Act.</td>
				<td>&sect; 24.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers who are to account for Money imprested in the Exchequer, to charge themselves upon Oath with the Interest Monies received as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 25.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Such Charge to be examined by the Auditor of the Exchequer, with Vouchers and attested, who may surcharge.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Treasury may compound for Debts due from insolvent Collectors and other Persons in respect of Duties of Excise and Salt, and upon Payment of Composition give a Discharge.</td>
				<td>&sect; 26.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for Discharge of Monies due to Marine Regiments.<br/><emph type="i">Auditor of the Exchequer to examine Interest Accounts pursuant to this Act</emph>, 2 &amp; 3 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 17. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>&sect; 27.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For appropriating &pound;3,700 weekly out of certain Branches of Excise for public Uses; and for making a Provision for the Service of His Majesty's Household and Family, and other his necessary Occasions.</td>
				<td>12 &amp; 13 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 12.</td>
				<td>723</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>From 25th Dec. 1700, for Five Years, &pound;3,700 per Week out of the Excise Duties, to be paid into the Exchequer in Manner herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>724</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Weekly Deficiency, if any, how supplied.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How &pound;96,200 for the First 26 Weeks to be paid into the Exchequer, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Residue of the Branches of Excise, &amp;c. chargeable with the yearly Sum of &pound;700,000, to be for the Use of the King's Household and Family, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>725</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Clauses touching the Overplus in Stat. 9 W.III. c. 23. repealed.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners of Excise to make the said weekly Payments into the Exchequer.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Neglecting, &amp;c. to pay the same&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Comptroller of Excise to keep Account of Monies arising by Particular Branches of Excise.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Forfeiture of Place, Incapacity, and Penalty &pound;100.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Auditor of Exchequer to enter in a Book the Monies brought in weekly.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Clause of Loan for &pound;820,000 on the weekly Payments, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>In lieu of the perpetual annual Payments out of the Excise granted by King Charles the Second, the hereditary Excise, after 25th Dec. 1705, shall stand charged with the annual Payments of &pound;3 per Cent. without Fee or further Warrant.</td>
				<td>12 &amp; 13 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 13. &sect; 24.</td>
				<td>727</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>For granting an Aid to His Majesty, by laying Duties upon Malt, Mum, Cyder, and Perry.</td>
				<td>13 &amp; 14 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 5.</td>
				<td>740</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duty of 6d. per Bushel upon Malt ground and unground in Possession of Maltster, &amp;c. on the 9th March 1701.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The like Duty on Malt made between the said 9th March and the 24th June 1703.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duty of 10s. per Barrel upon Mum made or imported between the said 9th March and 24th June 1703.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duty of 4s. per Hogshead upon Cyder and Perry made for Sale between the said 9th March and 24th June 1703.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>What Persons shall be deemed and charged as Retailers of Cyder and Perry.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>All the said Duties to be under the Com-missioners of Excise upon Beer, Ale, and other Liquors, and the Officers for the Duties upon Beer, &amp;c. to be Officers for the Duties under this Act.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 741</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Power to Commissioners to dismiss, &amp;c. such Officers.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons having Malt in their Custody on the said 9th March 1701, to enter the same on or before 10th April 1702&mdash;Penalty &pound;50, and Forfeiture of Malt.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duty to be paid or secured within Six Days after Entry.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&pound;8 per Cent. allowed for prompt Payment.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers to take an Account and Measurement of Malt in the Possession of Persons upon the said 9th March 1701; and may enter Houses, Outhouses, &amp;c. for that Purpose; and may cast Malt into Form, for better ascertaining the Quantity&mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officers upon Request to be admitted into Houses, &amp;c. of Persons making Malt after 9th March 1701, and to gauge Cisterns, &amp;c. and to take account of Barley, &amp;c. steeping, and make Return thereof to Commissioners, &amp;c. and leave Copy thereof with Maltster.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Such Report to be a Charge upon Maltster.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Refusing Admission, &amp;c. to Officer&mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Monthly Entry of Malt made after the said 9th March 1701&mdash;Penalty &pound;10.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Duties owing, to be cleared off within Three Months after Entry.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>742</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Neglecting, &amp;c. to make such Payments, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>After such Default, Maltster, &amp;c. not to sell, &amp;c. until Duty paid.&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>What deemed a Bushel of Malt, and charged and returned as such.</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>On or before 10th April 1702, Maltsters, &amp;c. to give Notice in Writing to Officer of Situation of Cisterns, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 10. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maltster, &amp;c. making Malt for Sale not to erect or use, &amp;c. Cisterns, &amp;c. without Notice to Office, nor keep or use private Cisterns, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound;50.</td>
				<td>13 &amp; 14 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 5. &sect; 11.</td>
				<td>742</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Maltster, &amp;c. conveying Malt from Sight of Gauger, and not giving Notice thereof before the said 10th April 1702&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 12.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons having the same in Custody, and not giving Notice&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Stat. 12 Car. II. c. 24. relating to Excise upon Beer, &amp;c. applied to the Duties under this Act&mdash;Exception.</td>
				<td>&sect; 13.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How Penalties to be sued for and divided.</td>
				<td>&sect; 14.</td>
				<td>743</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Malt in Custody of Makers, and that is liable to the said Duties, and to Seizure for Penalties, &amp;c. as if the Debtor were Owner.</td>
				<td>&sect; 15.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Commissioners or Officers appointed may compound for Duties as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>&sect; 16.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The Houses, &amp;c. of Persons compounding free from Duties, Search, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Persons compounding, permitting others to make Malt on their Premises without Notice to Officer, and paying or securing Composition for such Persons, to lose Benefit of Composition, pay the Duty, and Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 17.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowance of Four Bushels out of every Twenty Bushels of Malt for wetting.</td>
				<td>&sect; 18.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for Exportation of Malt, except to Scotland, by Persons having paid the Duties.</td>
				<td>&sect; 19.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Security not to reland, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Relanding such Malt to obtain Drawback&mdash;Penalty.</td>
				<td>&sect; 20.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 744</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Exporters of Malt to produce Certificate of Duty paid or secured.</td>
				<td>&sect; 21.</td>
				<td>744</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Certificates of Duty paid or secured, to be given upon Oaths made as hereby required; also Certificate of Quantity shipped, upon Production of which Duty repaid.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>If Officer have not Money, Commissioners to pay.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Buyer to pay to Seller the Duty upon Malt sold before the said 9th March 1701 and not delivered, or Bargain void.</td>
				<td>&sect; 22. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Proviso for Rent reserved and payable in Malt.</td>
				<td>&sect; 23.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Importing Malt after the said 9th March 1701, during Continuance of Act, Malt forfeited.</td>
				<td>&sect; 24.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>What Bushel deemed a Winchester Bushel.</td>
				<td>&sect; 25.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Malt destroyed by Fire, or perishing by Water, on Proof thereof by Oath of Two Witnesses, and of Duty paid or secured at next Quarter Sessions, and Certificate thereof&mdash;Duty repaid.</td>
				<td>&sect; 26.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>. 745</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Allowance of Four Bushels out of every Twenty Bushels of Grain charged upon the Floor.</td>
				<td>&sect; 27.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The Duty of Stat. 1 W. &amp; M. c. 12. not reckoned towards the Price of 24s. per Quarter limited by the said Act.</td>
				<td>&sect; 28.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Like Allowance upon Exportation of Maltground as upon Exportation of wholeMalt, upon Debentures, Certificate, and Oath; &amp;c. as herein mentioned.</td>
				<td>13 &amp; 14 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 5. &sect; 29.</td>
				<td>745</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>How such ground Malt to be computed</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Officer to leave Copy of Gauge with Maker&mdash;Penalty 40s.</td>
				<td>&sect; 30.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Brewer, Innkeeper, &amp;c. using or mixingSugar, Honey, &amp;c. in making Beer orAle or in Cask&mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>&sect; 31.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>The said Duties, after Payment of Charges,to be paid into the Exchequer.</td>
				<td>&sect; 32.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Clause of Loan for &pound;600,000 upon Interest at &pound;6 per Cent. per Ann. &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Exportation</key>
		</head>
		<table id="t5">
			<tr>
				<td/>
				<td/>
				<td/>
			</tr>
			<tr><td/>
				<th>Statute</th>
				<th>Page</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Loading and shipping for ExportationFrames for making and knitting Stock-ings&mdash;Forfeiture of Frames and Penaltyof &pound;40 for each Frame.</td>
				<td>7 &amp; 8 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 20. &sect; 3.</td>
				<td>98</td></tr><tr><td>
On Removal of Frame, Notice to Masterand Wardens of Company of FrameKnitters&mdash;Penalty &pound;5.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
For the exporting Watches, Sword Hilts,and other Manufactures of Silver.</td>
				<td>9 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 28.</td>
				<td>399</td></tr><tr><td>
Watches, Sword Hilts, Wrought Plate, &amp;c.may be exported as shall be yearly al-lowed by the Commissioners of theCustoms.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>399, 400</td></tr><tr><td>
No Case or Dial Plate, &amp;c. for Clock orWatch to be exported without theMovement, &amp;c. nor made up withoutengraving Maker's Name&mdash;Penalty &pound;20.</td>
				<td>&sect; 2.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
To prohibit the Exportation of Corn, Malt,Meal, Flour, Bread, Biscuit, or Starchfor one Year, from 10th Feb. 1698.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 3. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
				<td>454</td></tr><tr><td>
Exporting or lading on board of Ship forExportation, from 10th Feb. 1698 to10th Feb. 1699, Wheat, &amp;c. Exception&mdash;Forfeiture of Goods and Penalty, andShip, &amp;c. forfeited.</td>
				<td>&sect; 1.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Master and Mariner of Ships offending&mdash;Imprisonment.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>455</td></tr><tr><td>
Commissioners and Officers of Customs, orPersons authorized by Treasury, may seize Corn, &amp;c. unduly laden for Ex-portation, or for Scotland, and take sameto the King's Warehouse.</td>
				<td>10 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 3. &sect; 2.</td>
				<td>455</td></tr><tr><td>
Proviso for Exportation of Corn, &amp;c. forSustenance of Crews and Passengers of Ships on Voyages.</td>
				<td>&sect; 3.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Proviso for Exportation of Corn, &amp;c. forForts, &amp;c. in Africa, Colonies in Ame-rica, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>&sect; 4.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Or for the Benefit of the English Fisheriesin those Parts, upon Security by Exporterthat such Corn, &amp;c. shall not be un-duly landed.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
No Fee for taking such Security.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Proviso for Exportation of Malt fromSouthampton to Jersey and Guernsey,on Security by Exporter for due landing.</td>
				<td>&sect; 5.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
No Fee for Security.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Malt exported between 10th Feb. 1698and 10th Feb. 1699 not to exceed 4,000Quarters.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Proviso for carrying Corn, &amp;c. Coastwiseupon Sufferance, and Security for dulydischarging the same, and returning aCertificate as required by Law.</td>
				<td>&sect; 6.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Proviso for carrying Corn, &amp;c. in Boats,&amp;c. upon Navigable Rivers to Market.</td>
				<td>&sect; 7.</td>
				<td>456</td></tr><tr><td>
And for the Custom of so taking thesame without Cocquet, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
No Fee for Coast Cocquet, &amp;c.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
On Decrease of Price the King may byProclamation permit Exportation ofCorn, &amp;c. before 10th Feb. 1699.</td>
				<td>&sect; 8.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
Commissioners of Customs to render Ac-counts to Parliament of Corn exported by Licence.</td>
				<td>&sect; 9.</td>
				<td>
					<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td></tr><tr><td>
One Moiety of the Duty on Tallow Candlesimported repaid on Exportation.<br/><emph type="i">The whole Duty made to cease</emph>, 27 <emph type="i">G. III.c</emph>. 13. &sect; 1. <emph type="i">and see Table B. to that Act</emph>.&mdash;43 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 68. &sect; 1.&ndash;49 <emph type="i">G. III.c</emph>. 98. &sect; 1.</td>
				<td>11 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 3. &sect; 16.</td>
				<td>585</td></tr>
				</table>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<head>
			<key>Extraparochial Places</key>
			<emph type="i">See</emph> Dwelling Houses.</head>
	</entry>
</section>
</index>


