<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47196" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Chronological table of the titles of all the acts of parliament</title>
	<subtitle>Passed in the reigns of King Charles I and King Charles II</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>CHRONOLOGICAL TABLE
OF THE TITLES OF ALL
THE ACTS OF PARLIAMENT
PASSED IN THE REIGNS OF KING CHARLES I.
AND KING CHARLES II.</head>
		<table id="t1">
			<tr>
				<td cols="7"/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td cols="2">DATE.</td>
				<td>TITLE or DESCRIPTION of the ACT.</td>
				<td cols="3">NUMBER</td>
				<td rows="2">Page of this Volume.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>A.D.</td>
				<td>King's Reign.</td>
				<td>IN CHANCERY.</td>
				<td>Of the Chapter as printed.</td>
				<td>On the Roll in Chancery.</td>
				<td>Of the Original Act in Parliament.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
			<td/>
				<td>Car. I.</td>
				<td/>
				<td/>
				<td/>
				<td/>
				<td/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1625.</td>
				<td>An. 1.</td>
				<td>An Acte for punishing of divers abuses co[m]mitted on the Lords day called Sunday.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>1</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Acte to enable the King to make Leases of Lands parcell of his Highnes Duchie of Cornewall, or annexed to the same.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>2</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Acte for the ease in the obtayning of Licenses of Alienacion, and in the pleading of Alienacions with License, or of pardons of Alienacions without License, in the Court of Exchequer and elsewhere.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>2</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Acte for the further restraint of Tipling in Innes, Alehouses, and other Victualling Houses.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>3</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Acte for the confirmacion of the Subsidies graunted by the Clergie.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>3</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Acte for the Graunt of two entire Subsidies graunted by the Temporaltie.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>9</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act, that this Session of Parliament shall not determyne by his Majesties Royall assent to this and some other Actes.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>21</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1627.</td>
				<td>An. 3.</td>
				<td>The Peticion Exhibited to His Majestie by the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Co[m]mons in this p[re]sent Parliament assembled conc[er]ning divers Rights and Liberties of the Subjects: with the Kings Majesties Royall Aunswere thereunto in full Parliament.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>23</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the further reformacion of sondry abuses co[m]mitted on the Lords Day co[m]monlie called Sonday.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>25</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to restraine the Passing or Sending of any to be popishly bred beyond the Seas.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>25</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Suppressing of unlicenced Alehouse keepers.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>26</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Contynuance and Repeale of divers Statuts.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>27</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the establishing of the Estates of the ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nts of Bromfeild and Yale in the Countie of Denbigh and of the Tenures Rents and Servics thereuppon reserved according to a late Composicion made for the same with the Kings most Excellent Majestie then Prince of Wales.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>31</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the confirmacion of the Subsidies graunted by the Clergie.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>[<emph type="i">See Note in Vol. V</emph>.]</td>
				<td>33</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Acte for the Graunt of five entire Subsidies graunted by the Temporaltie.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>39</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1640.</td>
				<td>An. 16.</td>
				<td>An Act for the p[re]venting of inconveniencies happening by the long intermission of Parliaments.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>p. 1. 1</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>54</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act, for the relief of His Majesties Army and the Northern Parts of the Kingdome.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>58</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the reforming of some things mistaken in the late Act made this P[re]sent Parliament for the granting of four Subsidies entituled An Act for the releife of His Majesties Army and the Northern Parts of this Kingdome and to make good the Acts of the Commissioners and other Officers by them authorized or appointed and to be authorized or appointed.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>78</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the further releife of His Majesties Army and the Northern Parts of the Kingdome.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>79</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better raising and leavying of Mariners Sailers and others for the present guarding of the Seas and necessary defence of the Realme.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>p. 2. 1</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>101</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act concerning the Limitation and Abbreviation of Michaelmas Terme.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>102</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent inconveniencies which may happen by the untimely adjourning proroguing or dissolving of this present Parliament.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>103</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>A Subsidie granted to the King of Tunnage Poundage and other sums of money payable upon Merchandize exported and imported.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>104</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the speedie provision of money for disbanding the Armes and setling the peace of the two Kingdomes of England and Scotland.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>105</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for [the Regulating<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] <emph type="i">the Privy Councell and for taking away the Court commonly called the Star Chamber. </emph>.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>110.</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for repeal of a branch of a Statute primo Elizabethe concerning Commissioners for causes Ecclesiasticall.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>112</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>A Subsidy granted to the King of Tonnage and Poundage and other sums of money paiable upon Merchandizes exported and imported.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>114</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the securing of such moneys as are or shall be due to the Inhabitants of the Countie of Yorke and the other adjoyning Counties wherein his Majesties Army is or hath beene billetted for the billet of the Souldiers of the said Army as also to certain Officers of the said Army who do forbear part of theire pay according to an Order in that behalfe made in the Commons House of Parliament this present Session for such part of theire pay as they shall so forbeare.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>115</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the declaring unlawful and void the late proceedings touching Ship money and for the vacating of all Records and Processe concerning the same.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>116</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act against diverse Incroachments and Oppressions in the Stannarie Courts.</td>
				<td>XV.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>117</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the certainty of Forests and of the Meers Meets Limits &amp; Bounds of the Forests.</td>
				<td>XVI.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>16</td>
				<td>119</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Pacification between England and Scotland.</td>
				<td>XVII.</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>120</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for securing by publique faith the Remainder of the friendly assistance and releife promised to our brethren of Scotland.</td>
				<td>XVIII.</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>18</td>
				<td>128</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better ordering and regulating of the Office of Clarke of the Market allowed &amp; confirmed by this Statute and [and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] for the reformation of false Weights and Measures.</td>
				<td>XIX.</td>
				<td>p. 2. 15</td>
				<td>19</td>
				<td>129</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the prevention of vexatious proceedings touching the Order of Knighthood.</td>
				<td>XX.</td>
				<td>16</td>
				<td>20</td>
				<td>131</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the free bringing in of Gun-powder and Salt peter from Forraign parts and for the free making of Gunpowder in this Realme.</td>
				<td>XXI.</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>21</td>
				<td>131</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>A Subsidie granted to the King of Tonnage Poundage and other sums of money payable upon Merchandize exported &amp; imported.</td>
				<td>XXII.</td>
				<td>18</td>
				<td>22</td>
				<td>132</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better raising and levying of Mariners Saylers and others for the present guarding of the Seas &amp; necessary defence of the Realme &amp; other his Majesties Dominions.</td>
				<td>XXIII.</td>
				<td>19</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>133</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the reliefe of the Captives taken by Turkish Moorish and other Pirates and to prevent the taking of others in time to come.</td>
				<td>XXIV.</td>
				<td>20</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>134</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>A Subsidy granted to the King of Tonnage Poundage and other summes of money payable upon Merchandize exported and imported.</td>
				<td>XXV.</td>
				<td>21</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>135</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better raising and levying of Mariners Sailers and others for the present guarding of the Seas &amp; necessary defence of this Realme &amp; other his Ma[jes]ties Dominions.</td>
				<td>XXVI.</td>
				<td>22</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>137</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for disinabling all persons in Holy Orders to exercise any temporall Jurisdicc[i]on or authoritie.</td>
				<td>XXVII.</td>
				<td>23</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>138</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better raising and leavying of Souldiers for the present defence of the Kingdoms of England and Ireland.</td>
				<td>XXVIII.</td>
				<td>p. 3. 1</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>138</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>A Subsidy granted to the King of Tonnage Poundage and other su[m]mes of money payable upon merchandize exported and imported.</td>
				<td>XXIX.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>139</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for a speedie contribuc[i]on and loan towards the releife of his Majesties distressed Subjects of the Kingdome of Ireland.</td>
				<td>XXX.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>141</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>A Subsidy graunted to the King of Tonnage Poundage and other su[m]ms of money payable upon Merchandize exported &amp; imported.</td>
				<td>XXXI.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>143</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the raising and leavying of Moneys for the necessary defence and great affaires of the Kingdomes of England and Ireland and for the payment of debts undertaken by the Parliament.</td>
				<td>XXXII.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>145</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the speedy and effectuall reducing of the Rebells in his Majesties Kingdome of Ireland to theire due obedience to his Majesty &amp; the Crowne of England.</td>
				<td>XXXIII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>168</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for adding unto &amp; explaining of certain Clauses in another Act made this Parliament Intituled An Act for the speedy &amp; effectuall reducing of the Rebels in his Majesties Kingdome of Ireland to theire due obedience to his Majestie and the Crowne of England.</td>
				<td>XXXIV.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>172</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to inable Corporations &amp; Bodies Politique to participate of the benefit of an Act lately passed entituled An Act for the speedie and effectuall reducing of the Rebells in his Majesties Kingdome of Ireland to their due obedience to his Majestie and the Crowne of England.</td>
				<td>XXXV.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>173</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>A Subsidy graunted to the King of Tonnage Poundage &amp; other su[m]ms of money payable upon Merchandize exported and imported</td>
				<td>XXXVI.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>174</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the further advancement of an effectuall and speedy reduction of the Rebels in Ireland to the obedience of his Majestie and the Crowne of England.</td>
				<td>XXXVII.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>176</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1660.</td>
				<td>An. 12.</td>
				<td>An Act for removing and preventing all Questions and Disputes concerning the Assembling and Sitting of this present Parliament.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>p. 1. 1</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>179</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for putting in execution an Ordinance mentioned in this Act.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>179</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Continuance of Processe and Judiciall Proceedings.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>180</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>A Subsidy granted to the King of Tonnage and Poundage and other summes of Money payable upon Merchandize Exported and Imported.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>181</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing the Excise untill the twentyeth of August One thousand six hundred and sixty.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>206</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the present Nominating of Commissioners of Sewers.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>206</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>[15. An Act for restoreing unto James Marquesse of Ormond all his Honours Mannours Land and Tenements in Ireland whereof he was in possession on the 23<emph type="p">th</emph> of October 1641 or at any time since.]<br/>[<emph type="i">This Act has been called Chap. VII. in the various printed Editions of the Statutes, but it is not entered on the Roll, the Title is entered on the Roll amongst the Titles of Private Acts in the above Manner, and is herein inserted in order to keep up the usual arrangement of Chapters</emph>.]</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>206</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing of the Excise till the five and twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred and sixty.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>p. 2. 5</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>207</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the speedy provision of money for disbanding and paying off the forces of this Kingdome both by Land and Sea.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>207</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for supplying and explaining certaine defects in an Act entituled An Act for the speedy provision of money for disbanding and paying off the forces of this kingdome both by Land and Sea.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>22</td>
				<td>225</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act of Free and Generall Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>226</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Confirmation of Judiciall Proceedings.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>p. 1. 7</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>234</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for restraining the takeing of Excessive Usury.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>236</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for a Perpetuall Anniversary Thanksgiveing on the nine and twentyeth day of May.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>237</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the speedy disbanding of the Army and Garrisons of this Kingdome.</td>
				<td>XV.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>238</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for inabling the Souldiers of the Army now to be disbanded to exercise Trades.</td>
				<td>XVI.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>18</td>
				<td>241</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Confirming and Restoreing of Ministers.</td>
				<td>XVII.</td>
				<td>p. 3. 2</td>
				<td>19</td>
				<td>242</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Encourageing and increasing of Shipping and Navigation.</td>
				<td>XVIII.</td>
				<td>p. 2. 6</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>246</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent Fraudes and Concealments of His Majestyes Customes and Subsidyes.</td>
				<td>XIX.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>16</td>
				<td>250</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for raising seavenscore thousand pounds for the compleate disbanding of the whole Army and paying off some part of the Navy.</td>
				<td>XX.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>21</td>
				<td>250</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the speedy raising of Seaventy thousand pounds for the present Supply of his Majestye.</td>
				<td>XXI.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>20</td>
				<td>252</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Regulating of the Trade of Bay makeing in the [Dutchy<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Bay Hall in Colchester.
</td>
				<td>XXII.</td>
				<td>P. 3. 1</td>
				<td>30</td>
				<td>253</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>A Grant of certaine Impositions upon Beere Ale and other Liquors for the encrease of His Majestyes Revenue dureing His Life.</td>
				<td>XXIII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>44</td>
				<td>255</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act takeing away the Court of Wards and Liveries and Tenures in Capite and by Knights Service and Purveyance, and for setling a Revenue upon his Majesty in Lieu thereof.</td>
				<td>XXIV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>37</td>
				<td>259</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Ordering the Selling of Wines by Retaile, and for preventing Abuses in the Mingling Corrupting and Vitiating of Wines, and for Setting and Limitting the Prices of the same.</td>
				<td>XXV.</td>
				<td>P. 3. 5</td>
				<td>43</td>
				<td>266</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the levying of the Arreares of the twelve moneths Assessment commenceing the fower and twentyeth [day<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of June One thousand six hundred fifty nine, and the six moneths Assessment commenceing the five and twentyeth [day<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of December One thousand sixe hundred fifty nine.
</td>
				<td>XXVI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>48</td>
				<td>268</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting unto the Kings Majestie Fower hundred and twenty thousand pounds by an Assessment of three score and ten thousand pounds by the moneth for six moneths for disbanding the remainder of the Army, and paying off the Navy.</td>
				<td>XXVII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>47</td>
				<td>269</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for further suplying and explaining certaine defects in an Act intituled An Act for the speedy provision of money for disbanding and paying off the forces of this kingdome both by land and sea.</td>
				<td>XXVIII.</td>
				<td>p. 4. 1</td>
				<td>46</td>
				<td>277</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the raiseing of seaventy thousand pounds for the further supply of his Majestie.</td>
				<td>XXIX.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>45</td>
				<td>282</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Attainder of severall persons guilty of the horried Murther of his late Sacred Majestie King Charles the first.</td>
				<td>XXX.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>36</td>
				<td>288</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Confirmation of Leases and Grants from Colledges and Hospitalls.</td>
				<td>XXXI.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>42</td>
				<td>291</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for prohibiting the Exportation of Wooll Woolfells Fullers Earth or any kinde of Scouring Earth.</td>
				<td>XXXII.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>38</td>
				<td>293</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Confirmation of Marriages.</td>
				<td>XXXIII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>40</td>
				<td>296</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Prohibiting the Planting Setting or Sowing of Tobaccho in England and Ireland.</td>
				<td>XXXIV.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>41</td>
				<td>297</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Erecting and Establishing a Post Office.</td>
				<td>XXXV.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>39</td>
				<td>297</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act impowering the Master of the Rolls for the time being to make Leases for yeares in order to new build the old houses belonging to the Rolls.</td>
				<td>XXXVI.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>49</td>
				<td>301</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1661.</td>
				<td>An: 13. Stat. 1.</td>
				<td>An Act for Safety and Preservation of His Majesties Person and Government against Treasonable and Seditious practices and attempts.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>304</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Repeal of an Act of Parliament entituled An Act for disinabling all persons in Holy Orders to exercise any Temporall Jurisdic[i]on or Authority.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>306</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the declaring vesting and setling of all such Moneys Goods and other things in His Majesty which were Received Levied or Collected in these late times and are remaining in the hands or possession of any Treasurers Receivers Collectors or others not pardoned by the Act of Oblivion.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>306</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for a free and voluntary p[re]sent to his Majesty.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>307</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act against Tumults and Disorders upon p[re]tence of p[re]paring or p[re]senting publick Petic[i]ons or other Addresses to His Majesty or the Parliament.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>308</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act declaring the sole Right of the Militia to be in (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) King and for the present ordering and disposing the same.
</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>308</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for confirming Publique Acts.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>309</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for providing necessary Carriages for His Majestie in His Royall Progresse and Removalls.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>310</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Establishing Articles and Orders for the regulateing and better Government of His Majesties Navies Ships of Warr &amp; Forces by Sea.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>311</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent the unlawfull Coursing Hurting or Killing of Deere.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>314</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Confirming of three Acts therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>315</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Explanation of a Clause contained in (<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) Act of Parliament made in the seventeenth yeare of the late King Charles Entituled An Act for Repeal of a Branch of a Statute primo Elizabethe concerning Commissioners for Causes Ecclesiasticall.
</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>315</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting the Arreares of the Excise and New Impost in His Majesty.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>316</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Confirming an Act Entituled An Act for encouraging and encreasing of Shipping &amp; Navigation and severall other Acts both publique and private mentioned therein.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>316</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act declaring the Paines Penalties and Forfeitures imposed upon the Estates and Persons of certaine notorious Offenders excepted out of the Act of Free and Generall Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion.</td>
				<td>XV.</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>317</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An. 13. Stat. 2.</td>
				<td>An Act for the well Governing and Regulating of Corporations.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>p. 2. 1</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>321</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing of Vexations and Oppressions by Arrests and of Delaies in Suits of Law.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>323</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting unto the Kings Majestie twelve hundred and threescore thousand pounds to bee assessed and levied by an assessment of threescore and ten thousand pounds by the moneth for eighteene moneths.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>34</td>
				<td>325</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the Kings Majestie to make Leases Grants and Copies of Offices Lands Tenements and Hereditaments parcell of his Highnes Dutchy of Cornwall or annexed to the same and for Confirmac[i]on of Leases and Grants already made.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>348</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1662.</td>
				<td>An. 14.</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing the Mischeifs and Dangers that may arise by certaine Persons called Quakers and others refusing to take lawfull Oaths.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>350</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for repairing the High wayes and Sewers and for paving and keeping clean of the Streets in and about the Cities of London &amp; Westminster and for reforming of Annoyances and Disorders in the Streets of and places adjacent to the said Cities and for the Regulating and Licensing of [Hackey<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Coaches and for the enlarging of several strait &amp; inconvenient Streets and Passages.
</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>351</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for ordering the Forces in the several Counties of this Kingdom.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>31</td>
				<td>358</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Uniformity of Publique Prayers and Administrac[i]on of Sacraments &amp; other Rites &amp; Ceremonies and for establishing the Form of making ordaining and consecrating Bishops Preists and Deacons in the Church of England.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>364</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for regulating the making of Stuffs in Norfolke and Norwich.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>21</td>
				<td>370</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enlarging and repairing of Common High wayes.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>28</td>
				<td>374</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to restrain the Exportation of Leather and Raw Hides out of the Realme of England.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>378</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Distribution of Threescore thousand pounds amongst the truly Loyal &amp; Indigent Commission Officers and for assessing of Offices and distributing [the<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Moneys thereby raised for theire further supply.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>p. 2. 1</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>380 </td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the releife of poore and maimed Officers and Souldiers who have faithfully served His Majesty and His Royal Father in the late Wars.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>389</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for establishing an additional Revenue upon His Majestie His Heires &amp; Successors for the better support of His and theire Crown and Dignity.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>32</td>
				<td>390</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing Frauds and regulating Abuses in His Majesties Customes.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>33</td>
				<td>393</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Releife of the Poore of this Kingdom.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>401</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act prohibiting the Importac[i]on of Forreign Bonelace Cutt worke Imbroidery Fringe Band-strings Buttons and Needle worke</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>19</td>
				<td>405</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act directing the Prosecution of such as are accomptable for Prize Goods.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>30</td>
				<td>406</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for regulating the Trade of Silk throwing.</td>
				<td>XV.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>407</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the more speedy and effectual bringing those persons to accompt whose Accompts are excepted in the Act of Oblivion.</td>
				<td>XVI.</td>
				<td>P. 3. 1</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>409</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Reliefe of Collectors of Publick Moneys and theire Assistants and Deputies.</td>
				<td>XVII.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>410</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act against exporting of Sheepe Wooll Woolfells Mortlings Shorlings Yarn made of Wool Woolstocks Fullers Earth Fulling Clay and Tobacco pipe Clay.</td>
				<td>XVIII.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>410</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act against importing of Foreign Wool cards Card wire or Iron wire.</td>
				<td>XIX.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>16</td>
				<td>412</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for providing Carriage by Land and by Water for the use of His Majesties Navy and Ordnance.</td>
				<td>XX.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>413</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing the unnecessary charge of Sheriffes and for case in passing theire Accompts.</td>
				<td>XXI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>414</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing of Theft and Rapine upon the Northern Borders of England.</td>
				<td>XXII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>25</td>
				<td>417</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Addic[i]onal Act concerning matters of Assurance used amongst Merchants.</td>
				<td>XXIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>26</td>
				<td>418</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act declaratory concerning Bankrupts.</td>
				<td>XXIV.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>27</td>
				<td>419</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for [the<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] restoring [of<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] all such Advowsons Rectories Impropriate Gleeb Lands &amp; Tithes to His Majesties Loyal Subjects as were taken from them and making void certain charged imposed on them upon theire Compositions for Delinquency by the late usurped Powers.</td>
				<td>XXV.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>420 </td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for reforming of Abuses committed in the Weight and false Packing of Butter.</td>
				<td>XXVI.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>18</td>
				<td>421</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for repairing of Dover Harbour.</td>
				<td>XXVII.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>23</td>
				<td>422</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the [regulating<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] of the Pilchard Fishing in the Counties of Devon and Cornwall.</td>
				<td>XXVIII.</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>24</td>
				<td>423 </td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the reversing the Earle of Strafford his Attainder.</td>
				<td>XXIX.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>424</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the importing of Madder pure and unmixed.</td>
				<td>XXX.</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>425</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent the Inconvenience arising by melting the Silver Coyn of this Realm.</td>
				<td>XXXI.</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>20</td>
				<td>425</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better regulating of the Manufacture of Broad Woollen Cloath within the West Riding of the County of Yorke.</td>
				<td>XXXII.</td>
				<td>P. 3. 16</td>
				<td>29</td>
				<td>425</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing the frequent Abuses in printing seditious treasonable and unlicensed Bookes and Pamphlets and for regulating of Printing and Printing Presses.</td>
				<td>XXXIII.</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>428</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1663.</td>
				<td>An. 15.</td>
				<td>An Act for repairing the Highwayes within the Countyes of Hertford Cambridge and Huntington.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>28</td>
				<td>436</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Punishment of unlawfull cutting or stealing or spoiling of Wood and Underwood and Destroyers of young Timber Trees.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>P. 2. 1</td>
				<td>27</td>
				<td>441</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to explaine and supply a former Act for destribution of Threescore thousand Pounds amongst the truely loyall and indigent Commission Officers and for assessing of Offices and destributing the moneyes thereby raised for their further supply.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>442</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Additional Act for the better ordering the Forces in the severall Counties of this Kingdome.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>443</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for regulating Select Vestryes.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>446</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Releife of such Persons as by Sicknes or other Impediment were disabled from subscribeing the Declaration in the Act of Uniformity and Explanation of part of the said Act.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>447</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Encouragement of Trade.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>449</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent the selling of live fatt Catle by Butchers.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>452</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting Fower intire Subsidies to His Majestie by the Temporaltie.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>P. 1. 1</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>453</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for confirming of Fower Subsidyes granted by the Clergy.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>481</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Additionall Act for the better ordering and collecting the Duty of Excise and preventing the Abuses therein.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>P. 2. 10</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>488</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Explanatory Act for Recovery of the Arreares of Excise.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>493</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Additionall Act for the better ordering and collecting the Revenue ariseing by Hearth Money.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>493</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for setling the Proffitts of the Post Office and Power of graunting Wyne Lycences on his Royall Highnes the Duke of Yorke and the Heires Males of his Body.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>495</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for encourageing the Manufactures of makeing Linen Cloath and Tapistry.</td>
				<td>XV.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>498</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for regulateing the Herring and other Fisheries, and for repeale of the Act concerning Madder.</td>
				<td>XVI.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>498</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for settling the dreyning of the Great Levell of the Fenns called Bedford Levell.</td>
				<td>XVII.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>22</td>
				<td>499</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for settling the dreyning of the Great Levell of the Fenns called Bedford Levell.</td>
				<td>XVII.</td>
				<td>22</td>
				<td>499</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1664.</td>
				<td>An. 16.</td>
				<td>An Act for the assembling and holding of Parliaments once in Three Yeares at the least and for the repeale of an Act entituled An Act for the preventing of Inconveniencies happening by the long Intermission of Parliaments.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>513</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing of Abatements of Writts of Error upon Judgements in the Exchequer.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>514</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for collecting the Duty ariseing by Hearth-money by Officers to be appointed by His Majestie.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>514</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent and suppresse seditious Conventicles.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>516</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent the Disturbances of Seamen and others and to preserve the Stores belonging to His Majestyes Navy Royall.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>520</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent the delivering up of Merchants Shipps.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>521</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act against deceitfull disorderly and excessive Gameing.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>523</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuance of a former Act for regulateing the Presse.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>524</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1664&mdash; 5.</td>
				<td>An. 16, 17.</td>
				<td>An Act for granting a Royall Ayd unto the Kings Majestie of Twenty fower hundred threescore and seaventeene thousand and five hundred Pounds to be raised leavyed and paid in the Space of Three Yeares.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>525</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for regulateing the Measures and Prices of Coales.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>552</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the returning of able and sufficient Jurors.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>553</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Additional Act for the better ordering and collecting the Duty of Excise.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>554</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent Delayes in extending Statutes Judgements and Recognizances.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>554</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for repealing of part of an Act of Parlyament intituled An Act directing the prosecution of such as are accomptable for Prize Goods.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>555</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuance of a former Act for regulateing the Presse.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>556</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent Arrests of Judgement and superseding Executions.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>556</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to impower the Chauncellour of the Dutchy to grant Commissions for takeing Affidavits within the Dutchy Liberty.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>558</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuance of a former Act for repairing the Highwayes within the County of Hertford.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>558</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for drayning of the Fenn called Deeping Fenn and other Fenns therin mentioned.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>21</td>
				<td>559</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for making the River Avon navigable from Christ Church to the City of New Sarum.<br/> [<emph type="i">This Act had been called Chap. XII. in various printed Editions of the Statutes, but it is not upon the Roll; the Title is entered on the Roll amongst the Titles of Private Acts in the above manner, and is here inserted in order to keep up the usual arrangement of Chapters</emph>.]</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>568</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1665.</td>
				<td>An. 17.</td>
				<td>An Act for granting the summe of Twelve hundred and fiftie thousand pounds to the Kings Majestie for His present further Supply.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>570</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for restraining Non-Conformists from inhabiting in Corporations.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>575</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for uniting Churches in Cittyes and Townes Corporate.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>576</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuance of a former Act for regulateing the Presse.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>577</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for attainting Thomas Dolman Joseph Bampfield and Thomas Scott of High-Treason if they render not themselves by a day.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>578</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for takeing away of Damage Cleere.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>578</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for a more speedy and effectuall Proceeding upon Distresses and Avowryes for Rents.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>579</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for avoiding unnecessary Suites and Delayes.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>580</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting One Months Assessment to His Majestie.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>580</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1666.</td>
				<td>An. 18, 19.</td>
				<td>An Act for raising Moneys by a Poll, and otherwise towards the Maintenance of the present Warr.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>584</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act against importing Cattell from Ireland and other parts beyond the Seas and Fish taken by Forreigners.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>597</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to continue a former Act for preventing of Thefte and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders of England.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>598</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for burying in Woollen onely.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>598</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for encourageing of Coynage.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>598</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act Explanatory of the Act for raiseing Moneyes by a Poll and otherwise towards the Maintenance of this present Warr.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>601</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting a Judicature for Determination of Differences touching Houses burned or demolished by reason of the late Fire which happened in London.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>601</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for rebuilding the Citty of London.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>603</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for reliefe of Poore Prisoners and setting of them on worke.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>16</td>
				<td>613</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act extending a former Act concerning Replevins and Avowries to the Principallity of Wales and the County Palatines.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>17</td>
				<td>614</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Redresse of Inconveniencies by want of Proofe of the Deceases of Persons beyond the Seas or absenting themselves, upon whose Lives Estates doe depend.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>18</td>
				<td>614</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent the Disturbances of Seamen and others and to preserve the Stores belonging to His Majesties Navy Royall.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>15</td>
				<td>615</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting the Summe of Twelve hundred fifty six thousand three hundred forty seaven pounds thirteene shillings to the Kings Majesties towards the Maintenance of the present Warr.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>616</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1667&ndash;68.</td>
				<td>An. 19, 20.</td>
				<td>An Act for taking the Accompts of the severall Su[m]mes of Money therein menc[i]oned.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>624</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for banishing and disenabling the Earl of Clarendon.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>628</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to make Prize Ships free for Trade.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>628</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for assigning Orders in the Exchequer without Revocation.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>629</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for setling Freedome and Intercourse of Trade between England and Scotland.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>630</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for raising Three hundred and ten thousand pounds by an Imposition on Wines and other Liquors.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>630</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Payment of Moneys received for the Use of the Crown.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>636</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Increase and p[re]servation of Timber within the Forest of Deane.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>636</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for proceeding to Judgement on Writs of Error brought in the Exchequer.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>639</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for giving Liberty to buy and export Leather and Skins tanned or dressed.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>640</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to regulate the Trade of Silk Throwing.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>640</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Additional Act against the Importation of Forreign Cattel.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>641</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the taxing and assessing of the Lands of the Adventurers within the Great Levell of the Fenns.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>643</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1670.</td>
				<td>An. 22.</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent and suppresse Seditious Conventicles.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>648</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for repaireing of the Haven and Peers of Great Yarmouth.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>651</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting unto his Majestie an Imposition upon all Wines and Vinegar imported betweene the Fower and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy and the Fower and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred and seaventy eight.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>653</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for setleing the Imposition on Brandy.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>656</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for takeing away the Benefitt of Clergy from such as steale Cloth from the Racke and from such as shall steale or imbezill his Majestyes Ammunition [and Stores<ref idref="n11">11</ref>.]
</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>657</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for advanceing the Sale of Fee-Farme Rents and other Rents.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>657</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the Kings Majestie to make Leases, Grants and Copyes of Offices, Lands Tenements and Hereditaments Parcell of his Highnesse Dutchy of Cornwall, or annexed to the same.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>661</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for ascertaining the Measures of Corne and Salt.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>662</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act authorizing certaine Commissioners of the Realme of England to treat with Commissioners of Scotland for the Weale of both Kingdomes.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>663</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for sale of part of the Estate of Sir John Prittiman for satisfaction of a Debt by him due to the Kings Majestie.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>664</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Additionall Act for the rebuilding of the Citty of London, uniteing of Parishes and rebuilding of the Cathedrall and Parochiall Churches within the said City.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>665</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Additionall Act for the better repairing of Highwayes and Bridges.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>682</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Improvement of Tillage and the Breede of Catle.</td>
				<td>XIII.</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>685</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for settling the drayneing of the Fennes in Lincolneshire called Deepeing Fennes.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>28</td>
				<td>687</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1670&ndash;71.</td>
				<td>An. 22, 23.</td>
				<td>An Act to p[re]vent Malitious maiming and wounding.</td>
				<td>I. </td>
				<td>p. 1. 1</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>691</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Continuance of a former Act entituled An Act to p[re]vent Delayes in extending Statutes Judgements and Recognizances.</td>
				<td>II. </td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>693</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting a Subsidy to his Majestie for Supply of his Extraordinary Occasions.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>693</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuance of a former Act to prevent Arrests of Judgements and superseding Executions.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>703</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for an Additionall Excise upon Beere Ale and other Liquors.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>704</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for revesting the Power of granting Wine Licences in his Majesty his Heires and Successors and for setleing a Recompence on his Royall Highnesse in liew thereof.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>706</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent the malitious burning of Houses Stackes of Corne and Hay and killing or maiming, of Catle.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>709</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the regulateing the makeing of Kidderminster Stuffes.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>710</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for laying Impositions on Proceedings at Law.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>25</td>
				<td>712</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better setling of Intestates Estates.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>37</td>
				<td>719</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent the delivery up of Merchants Shipps and for the Increase of good and serviceable Shipping.</td>
				<td>XI.</td>
				<td>11</td>
				<td>28</td>
				<td>720</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Additionall Act for ascertaining the Measures of Corne and Salt.</td>
				<td>XII.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>38</td>
				<td>722</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for exporting of Beere Ale and Mum.</td>
				<td>XIII. </td>
				<td>p. 2, 1.</td>
				<td>30</td>
				<td>723</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for determination of Differences touching Houses burnt or demolished within fower yeares since the late dreadfull Fire in London.</td>
				<td>XIV.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>26</td>
				<td>724</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Setlement of the Maintenance of the Parsons Vicars and Curates in the Parishes of the Citty of London burnt by the late dreadfull Fire there.</td>
				<td>XV.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>32</td>
				<td>725</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the discovery of such as have defrauded the Poore of the Citty of London of the Moneys given for their Releife at the times of the late Plague and Fire and for recovery of the Arreares thereof.</td>
				<td>XVI.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>34</td>
				<td>728</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better paveing and cleansing the Streets and Sewers in and about the Citty of London.</td>
				<td>XVII.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>33</td>
				<td>729</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better regulateing of Workehouses for setting the Poore on Worke.</td>
				<td>XVIII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>35</td>
				<td>732</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to prevent Fraudes in the buying and selling of Cattell in Smithfeild and elsewhere.</td>
				<td>XIX.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>39</td>
				<td>733</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Releife and Release of poore distressed Prisoners for Debt.</td>
				<td>XX.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>40</td>
				<td>734</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for takeing the Accompts of Sixty thousand pounds and other Moneys given to the loyall and indigent Officers.</td>
				<td>XXI.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>41</td>
				<td>737</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better and more certaine Recovery of Fines and Forfeitures due to his Majestie.</td>
				<td>XXII.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>26</td>
				<td>739</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to revive an Act Entituled An Act to prevent the disturbances of Seamen and others and to preserve the Stores belonging to his Majestyes Navy Royall, with some Alterations and Additions.</td>
				<td>XXIII.</td>
				<td>p. 2. 11</td>
				<td>29</td>
				<td>741</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for vesting certaine Fee-farme Rents and other small Rents in Trustees.</td>
				<td>XXIV.</td>
				<td>12</td>
				<td>27</td>
				<td>743</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better preservation of the Game, and for secureing Warrens not inclosed, and the severall Fishings of this Realme.</td>
				<td>XXV.</td>
				<td>13</td>
				<td>42</td>
				<td>745</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to p[re]vent the planting of Tobacco in England, and for regulateing the Plantation Trade.</td>
				<td>XXVI.</td>
				<td>14</td>
				<td>37</td>
				<td>747</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for explaining of a Proviso conteyned in an Act, entituled An Act for setting the Profitts of y<emph type="p">e</emph> Post-Office and Power of granteing Wine-Licences on His Royal Highnes y<emph type="p">e</emph> Duke of Yorke and the Heyres Males of his Body.</td>
				<td>XXVII.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>44</td>
				<td>749</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1672.</td>
				<td>An. 25.</td>
				<td>An Act for raising the summe of twelve hundred thirty eight thousand seaven hundred and fifty pounds for supply of his Majesties extraordinary occasions.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>I</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>752</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for preventing Dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>782</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for enableing his Majestie to make Leases of his Lands belonging to the Dutchy of Cornwall.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>785</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for repeale of a Clause in a former Act to prohibit Salesmen from selling Fatt Cattell.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>786</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Kings Majestyes most Gratious, Generall and Free Pardon.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>786</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for takeing off Aliens Duty upon Commodities of the Growth, Product and Manufacture of the Nation.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>791</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the incouragement of the Greeneland and Eastland Trades, and for the better secureing the Plantation Trade.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>792</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuing a former Act concerning Coynage.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>794</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable the County Palatine of Durham to send Knights and Burgesses to serve in Parlyament.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>795</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for reviveing the Judicature for determination of Differences touching Houses burnt downe and demolished by reason of the late Fire, which happened in London, and for rebuilding of the Navy Office.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>795</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1675.</td>
				<td>An. 27.</td>
				<td>An Act for the better and more easy rebuilding the Towne of Northampton.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>798</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1677.</td>
				<td>An. 29.</td>
				<td>An Act for raising the Summe of Five hundred eighty foure thousand nine hundred seaventy eight pounds two shillings and two pence halfe-penny for the speedy building Thirty Shipps of Warr.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>p. 1.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>802</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for an additionall Excise upon Beere, Ale and other Liquors for Three yeares.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>p. 2. 1</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>837</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for prevention of Frauds and Perjuryes.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>839</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for erecting a Judicature to determine Differences touching Houses burnt and demolished by the late dreadfull Fire in Southwarke.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>842</td>
			</tr>
		<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for takeing of Affidavits in the Country to be made use of in the Courts of Kings Bench Common Pleas and Exchequer.</td>
				<td>V.p. 2.4</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>846</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Naturalizing of Children of his Majestyes English Subjects borne in Forreigne Countryes dureing the late Troubles.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>847</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better Observation of the Lords day commonly called Sunday.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>848</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for confirming and perpetuating Augmentations made by Ecclesiasticall Persons to small Vicarages and Curacies.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>849</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for takeing away the Writt De Heretico cumburendo.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>850</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the better repairing and maintaining the Piere of Great Yarmouth.</td>
				<td>X.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>850</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1677&ndash;78</td>
				<td>An. 29, 30.</td>
				<td>An Act for raising Money by a Poll and otherwise to enable His Majestie to enter into an actuall Warr against the French King and for prohibiting severall French Commodities.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>852</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for continuance of two former Acts for preventing of Theft and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders of England.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>864</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1678.</td>
				<td>An. 30.</td>
				<td>An Act for granting a Supply to His Majestie of Six hundred nineteene thousand three hundred eighty pounds eleaven shillings and nine pence for disbanding the Army and other Uses therein mentioned.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>p. 1. 1</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>867</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for granting an additionall Duty to His Majestie upon Wines for Three yeares.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>883</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for burying in Woollen.</td>
				<td>III. 3 </td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>885</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the further Reliefe and Discharge of poore distressed Prisoners for Debt.</td>
				<td>IV.</td>
				<td>4</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>887</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for repealeing certaine words in a Clause in a former Act entituled An Act for enlargeing and repaireing of Common Highwayes.</td>
				<td>V.</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>890</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for reviveing a former Act entituled An Act for avoiding unnecessary Suits and Delayes and for continuance of one other Act entituled An Act for the better settleing of Intestates Estates.</td>
				<td>VI.</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>6</td>
				<td>890</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act to enable Creditors to recover their Debts of the Executors and Administrators of Executors in their owne wrong.</td>
				<td>VII.</td>
				<td>7</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>890</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for the Admeasurement of Keeles and Boates carrying Coales.</td>
				<td>VIII.</td>
				<td>8</td>
				<td>5</td>
				<td>891</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for Preservation of Fishing in the River of Seaverne.</td>
				<td>IX.</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>9</td>
				<td>892</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>Stat. 2.</td>
				<td>An Act for the more effectuall preserving the Kings Person and Government by disableing Papists from sitting in either House of Parlyament.</td>
				<td>I. </td>
				<td>p. 2.</td>
				<td>10</td>
				<td>894</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1679.</td>
				<td>An. 31.</td>
				<td>An Act for granting a Supply to His Majestie of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred sixtie two pounds seaventeene shillings and three pence for paying off and disbanding the Forces raised since the Nine and twentyeth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy seaven.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>1</td>
				<td>897</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td> An Act for the better secureing the Liberty of the Subject and for Prevention of Imprisonments beyond the Seas.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>2</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>935</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act for reingrossing of the Records of Fines burnt or lost in the late Fire in the Temple.</td>
				<td>III.</td>
				<td>3</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>938</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>1680.</td>
				<td>An. 32.</td>
				<td>An Additional Act for burying in Woollen.</td>
				<td>I.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>940</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>An Act prohibiting the Importation of Catle from Ireland.</td>
				<td>II.</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>&mdash;</td>
				<td>941</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
		<note id="n1" number="1">regulating of 0</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">
			<emph type="i">O. omits</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">
			<emph type="i">Dutch O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">
			<emph type="i">O. omits</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">
			<emph type="i">the O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">
			<emph type="i">an O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n7" number="7">
			<emph type="i">Hackney O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n8" number="8">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n9" number="9">
			<emph type="i">interlined on the Roll</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n10" number="10">
			<emph type="i">Regulation O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n11" number="11">
			<emph type="i">of Wars O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


