<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47205" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1627</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act for the further reformacion of sondry abuses c&bhooov;mitted on the Lord&bholngs; Day c&bhooov;monlie called Sonday.[Rot. Parl. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Carriers, Drovers, &amp;c. not to travel on Sunday.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Penalty 20s; Butchers not to kill or sell on Sunday; Penalty 6s. 8d.; Such Offences being committed in view of Justice, &amp;c. or proved by Oath of Witnesses, or Confession of the Party.; Penalties how levied.; Distress.; Penalties to the Poor; but Justice, &amp;c. may give Part to Informer</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">FORASMUCH As the Lord&bholngs; Day c&bhooov;monlie called Sunday is much broken and &bhopubrc;faned by Carriers Waggoners
Carters Waynemen Butchers and Drovers of cattell to the great dishonor of God and reproach of Religion,
Be it therefore Ena&bholigct;ed by the King&bholngs; most excellent Majestie and the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and by the
C&bhooov;mons in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same, That no Carrier with any Horse or
Horses nor Waggonmen with any Waggon or Waggons nor Carremen with any Cart or Cart&bholngs; nor Waynemen with
anie Wayne or Waynes nor Drovers with any Cattell shall after fortie daies next after the end of this &bhopcrl;sent Session
of Parliament by themselves or any other travell uppon the said Day, uppon paine that every &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons so
offending shall lose and forfeit twentie shilling&bholngs; for every such offence, Or if any Butcher by himselfe or any
other for him by his privitie or consent shall after the end of the said fortie daies kill or sell any Vi&bholigct;uall uppon the
said Day, That then every such Butcher shall forfait and lose for every such offence the s&bhooov;me of six shilling&bholngs; and
eight pence The said offences and every of them being done in view of anie Justice of (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Peace Mayor or other head
Officer of any Cittie or Towne Corporate within their lymitt&bholngs; respe&bholigct;ivelie or being proved uppon oath by two or
more witnesses or by the Confession of the partie offending before any such Justice Mayor or head Officer within
their severall limitt&bholngs; respe&bholigct;ivelie wherein such offence shalbe c&bhooov;mitted, To which end every such Justice Mayor or
Head officer shall have power by this A&bholigct; to minister an Oath to such witnesse or witnesses. All which s&bhooov;mes
or penalties shall or may be levied by any Constable or Churchwarden by warrant from any such Justice or Justices
of the Peace Mayor or other Head officer as aforesaid within their severall lymitt&bholngs; where such offence shalbe c&bhooov;mitted
or done by distresse and sale of the offendors good&bholngs; rendring to the partie the overplus or shalbe recovered by any
&bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons that will sue for the same by Bill Plaint or Informacion in any of His Majesties Court&bholngs; of Record
in anie Cittie or Towne Corporate before His Majesties Justices of the Peace in their generall Sessions of the Peace.
All which forfeitures shalbe imployed to and for the use of the poore of the Parishes where the said offences shalbe
c&bhooov;mitted or done Saving onelie that it shalbe lawfull to and for any such Justice Mayor or Head officer out of the
said forfeitures to reward any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons that shall informe or otherwise &bhopubrc;secute any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons
offending against this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; according to their discrecions so that such reward exceed not the third part of
the forfeiture.</para>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Information, &amp;c. prosecuted in County where Offence committed; 
General Issue.; Limitation of Information, &amp;c.; Continuance of A&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">Provided that such Bill Plaint or informacion shalbe c&bhooov;menced sued and &bhopubrc;secuted in the Countie City or Towne
Corporate where such offence shalbe c&bhooov;mitted and done and not elsewhere, wherein no Essoyne Proteccion or wager
of Lawe shall be allowed to the Defendant, Provided allwaies that it shalbe lawfull for any Constable or Churchwarden
that shall have any Suit or Accion brought against them for any distresse by them or any of them to be taken by
force of this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; to pleade the generall issue, and to give the speciall matter in evidence. Provided
likewise that no &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons whatsoever shalbe impeached by this A&bholigct;, unlesse he be thereof questioned
within six Monethes after the offence c&bhooov;mitted. Provided further that this A&bholigct; shall not in any sort abridge or
take away the Authoritie of the Courts Ecctiasticall, This A&bholigct; to continue to the end of the first Session of the
next Parliament.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


