<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47206" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1627</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act to restraine the Passing or Sending of any to be popishly bred beyond the Seas.[Rot. Parl. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Stat. 1 Jac. I. c. 4. to be put in due Execution.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Conveying, &amp;c. any Child or other Person to Parts beyond Sea, to be popishly bred, or maintaining them there; on Convi&bholigct;ion thereof, Disability to sue, &amp;c. and Forfeiture of Goods absolutely and of Lands for Life</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">FORASMUCH as divers ill affe&bholigct;ed &bhopubr;sons to the true Religion established within this Realme have sent their
Children into forraine Part&bholngs; to be bred upp in Popery notwithstanding the Restraint thereof by the Statute
made in the First Yere of the Raigne of our late Soveraigne Lord King James of famous Memory, Be it ena&bholigct;ed
That the said Statute shalbe put in due Execucion. And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the King&bholngs; most excellent Majestie
and the Lord&bholngs; Spirituall and Temporall and C&bhooov;mons in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of
the same, That in case any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons under the Obedience of the King His Heires and Successors at any
Tyme after the End of this Session of Parliament shall passe or goe or shall convey or send or cause to be sent or
conveyed any Child or other &bhopubr;son out of any of the King&bholngs; Dominions into any the Part&bholngs; beyond the Seas out of
the King&bholngs; Obedience to the Intent and Purpose to enter into or be resident or trayned upp in any Priory Abby
Nunnery Popish Univ[er]sitie Colledge or Schoole or House of Jesuit&bholngs; Preist&bholngs; or in any private Popish Familie and
shalbe there by any Jesuite Seminary Priest Fryer Monke or other Popish &bhopubr;son instru&bholigct;ed &bhopubr;swaded or strengthened
in the Popish Religion in any Sort to &bhopubrc;fesse the same or shall convey or send or cause to be conveyed or sent by
the Hand&bholngs; or Meanes of any &bhopubr;son whatsoever any s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of Mony or other Thing for or toward&bholngs; the
maynten<emph type="p">a</emph>nce of any Child or other &bhopubr;son already gone or sent or to goe or to be sent and trayned and instru&bholigct;ed as
is aforesaid or under the Name or Colour of any Charitie Benevolence or Almes towards the Releife of any Priorie
Abby Nunnery Colledge Schoole or any Religious House whatsoever. Every &bhopubr;son so sending conveying or causing
to be sent and conveyed as well any such Child or other &bhopubr;son as any s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of Mony or other Thing
and every &bhopubr;son passing or being sent beyond the Seas being thereof lawfullie convi&bholigct;ed in or uppon any
Informacion &bhopcrl;sentment or Indi&bholigct;ment as is aforesaid shalbe disabled from thenceforth to sue or use any Accion
Bill Plaint or Informacion in Course of Lawe or to &bhopubrc;secute any Suite in any Court of Equitie or to be
C&bhooov;mittee of any Ward or Executor or Administrator to any &bhopubr;son or capable of any Legacie or Deed of Gift
or to beare any Office within the Realme; and shall loose and forfeite all his Good&bholngs; and Chattell&bholngs; and shall
forfeit all his Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; and Hereditament&bholngs; Rent&bholngs; A&bhonov;uities Offices and Estates of Freehold for and during
his naturall Life.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Persons so sent abroad conforming after Return.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided allwaies That no &bhopubr;son sent or conveyed as aforesaid that shall within Six Monethes after his Retorne into
this Realme conforme himselfe unto the &bhopcrl;sent Religion established in this Church of England and receive the
Sacrament of the Lord&bholngs; Supper according to the Statutes made concerning Conformitie in other Cases required from
Popish Recusant&bholngs; shall incurre any the Penalties aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Offences where and before whom determined.</head>
			<para id="p4">(<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) And it is ena&bholigct;ed That all and every (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) the Offences against this Statute may be enquired heard and determined
before the Justices of the King&bholngs; Bench or Justices of Assise or Gaole delivery or of Oyer and Terminer of
such Counties where the Offenders did last dwell or abide, or whence they departed out of this Kingdome or wher&egrave;
they were taken.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Persons returning and conforming, to have their Lands restored during Conformity.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided also That if any &bhopubr;son or Childe so passing or sent or now being beyond the Seas shall after his
Retorne into this Realme conforme himselfe [unto this<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Religion established in this Church of England and receive the
Sacrament of the Lord his Supper according to the Statut&bholngs; made for or concerning Conformity in other Cases
required from Popish Recusant&bholngs; for and during such tyme as he or she shall so contynue in such Conformitie and
Obedience according to the true Intent and Meaning of the said Lawes and Statuts shall have his or her Land&bholngs;
restored to them againe.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">The Two following Clauses are annexed to the original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">to the present <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


