<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47202" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1625</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Acte for the Graunt of two entire Subsidies graunted by the Temporaltie.[ Rot. Parl. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Grant of Two entire Subsidies; viz. on Personal Estates (after Payment of Debts, &amp;c.) 2s. 8d. in the Pound.</head>
		<para id="p1">Most Excellent and most Gracious Soveraigne, wee your Majesties most humble, faithfull and loving Subje&bholigct;&bholngs;,
your C&bhooov;mons assembled in your High Court of Parliament, taking into our due and serious Consideracion
the manifold occasions which at your Majesties first entrance into the Governement of these your Realmes and
Dominions doe presse your Majestie; and your most important Affaires, which both at home and abroad are now
in Accion, and cannot but exhaust your Treasure beyond the ordinarie &bhopubrc;porcion of your setled Revenue; and
with joy and comfort unexpressable, calling to minde the great hopes wee have received heretofore, and the
&bhopcrl;sent Assurance wee now enjoy of your Majesties most Wise Religious and Gracious Government; As a pledge
of our most bounden dutie and thankefullnes Wee humblie &bhopcrl;sent your Majestie with the free and cheerefull Gift
of two entire Subsidies, which wee humblie beseech your Majestie graciouslie to accept, as the first fruit&bholngs; of the
most dutifull Affeccions of your loyall and loving Subje&bholigct;&bholngs; devoted to your Service: And wee shall dailie and
devoutlie pray unto the Almightie God, the King of King&bholngs; for a blessing from heaven upon your high and great
Designes, that they may be successefull and prosperous to the glory of God, your Majesties eternall Honour and
the restoring of the auncient renowne and glory of this Nacion.</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Aliens and Popish Recusants Convi&bholigct;, 5s. 4d. in the Pound; 
Poll Tax on Aliens and Popish Recusants Convi&bholigct; not contributory as above 8d</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">And therefore wee humbly beseech your Majestie, That it may be ena&bholigct;ed, and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the King&bholngs;
most Excellent Majestie, the Lord&bholngs; Spirituall and Temporall, and C&bhooov;mons in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled, and
by the authoritie of the same, that our said Soveraigne Lord the King&bholngs; Majestie, his Heires and Successors shall
have receive and enjoy two entire Subsidies, to be rated taxed levied and paid at two severall payments, of every
&bhopubr;son Spirituall and Temporall of what estate or degree he or they be of, according to the tenor of this A&bholigct; in
manner and forme following, That is to saie; Aswell that every &bhopubr;son borne within this Realme of England Wales,
or other the King&bholngs; Dominions, as all and every Fraternitie Guild Corporacion Misterie Brotherhood and
Commonaltie corporate &amp; not corporate within this Realme of England, Wales, or other the King&bholngs; Dominions
being worth three pound&bholngs;, for every pound, as well in coine and the value of every pound that every such
&bhopubr;sons, Fraternitie, Guild, Corporacion, Misterie Brotherhood and Commonaltie corporate or not corporate, hath
of his or their owne, or any other to his or their use, As also Plate stocke of Merchandise, all manner of corne
and graine, housholdstuffe, and of all other good&bholngs; moveable, aswell within this Realme as without, and of all
such s&bhooov;mes of mony as to him or them is or shalbe owing whereof he or they trust in his or their conscience. surelie
to be paid (except and out of the &bhopubrc;misses dedu&bholigct;ed such s&bhooov;mes of mony as he or they doe owe, and in his and
their consciences intend trulie to pay, and except also the apparell of every such &bhopubr;sons, their wives and children
belonging to their owne bodies, saving jewells gold silver stone and pearle) shall pay to and for either of the
said Subsidies, two shillings eight pence of every pound. And also every Alien and Straunger borne out of
the King&bholngs; obeysance, aswell Denizen and others inhabiting within this Realme; and also every Popish
Recusant convi&bholigct;, or which before the tyme of the Assessement of the severall Subsidies by this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;
graunted shalbe a Popish Recusant convi&bholigct;, or which are or shalbe indi&bholigct;ed for Popish Recusancie, and their
indi&bholigct;ments are or shalbe removed by Cerciorare, of every pound that he or they shall have in coine and the
value of every pound in plate corne graine merchandize housholdstuffe or other good&bholngs; jewells chattell&bholngs; moveable
and unmoveable as is aforesaid, as well within this Realme as without, and of all s&bhooov;mes of money to him
or them owing, whereof he or they trust in his or their conscience to be paid (except and out of the &bhopcrl;misses
dedu&bholigct;ed, every such s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of mony which he or they doe owe, and in his or their conscience or consciences
intend trulie to pay) shall pay to and for each of the said Subsidies, five shillings foure pence of every pound.
And also that every Alien and stranger borne, borne out of the King&bholngs; Dominions, being denizen or not denizen,
not being contributorie to any the Rates aforesaid, and being of the age of seaven yeares or above, And every Popish
Recusant convi&bholigct;, or which before the time of the Assessement of the severall Subsidies by this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; graunted
shalbe a Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; and being of the age of seaventeene yeares, or which being of the age of one
and twentie yeares have not received the holy C&bhooov;munion within one yeare then last past, shall pay to and for the
said first Subsidie eight pence for every poll, and to and for the said second Subsidie eight pence for every poll,
And the master or he or shee, with whome the said Alien is or shalbe abiding at the tyme of the taxacion or
taxacions thereof to be charged with the same for lacke of payment thereof.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Two Subsidies on Real Estates 4s. in the Pound.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Aliens, &amp;c. 8s. in the Pound</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That every &bhopubr;son borne under the King&bholngs; obeisance, and
every Corporacion, Fraternitie Guild Misterie Brotherhood, and Commonaltie, corporate or not corporate for every
pound that every of the same &bhopubr;sons, and every Corporacion, Fraternitie Guild Misterie Brotherhood &amp; C&bhooov;monaltie
corporate or not corporate, or any other to his or their use hath in fee simple fee taile for terme of life terme of
yeares by Execucion Wardship or by Coppie of Court Roll of and in any Honors Castles Mannors Land&bholngs; Ten[an]ts
Rent&bholngs; s[er]vices Hereditam[en]ts A&bhonov;uities Fees Corrodies or other yearelie proffits of the yearelie value of twentie shillings,
as well within auncient demesne and other places priviledged as elsewhere, and so upward, shall pay to and for the
said first subsidie, foure shillings of and for every pound and to and for the second Subsidie foure shillings of
and for every pound: And every Alien denizen or not denizen borne out of the King&bholngs; obeysance; and every
Popish Recusant convi&bholigct;, or which before the tyme of the assessement of the severall Subsidies by this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;
graunted, shalbe a Popish Recusant convi&bholigct;, which shalbe indi&bholigct;ed for Popish Recusancie, and their indi&bholigct;ments
are or shalbe removed by Cerciorare, in such case to pay to and for the said first Subsidie eight shillings for every
pound, And to and for the said second Subsidie eight shillings of every pound.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Plate, &amp;c. held for Corporations to be rated.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Lands, Corodies, Fees, &amp;c.; Proviso for Ornaments, &amp;c. of Churches and Chappels</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And that all s&bhooov;mes to be &bhopcrl;sented and chargeable by this A&bholigct;, either for good&bholngs; and debt&bholngs;, or either of them, or for
Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; and other the &bhopcrl;misses, as is in this A&bholigct; contained, shalbe at every of the said payments, set and
taxed after the rate and &bhopubrc;porcion [and<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct;; Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; chargeable
to the dismes of the Clergie and yearelie wages due to the servaunts for their yearelie service (other then the King&bholngs;.
servaunts taking yearelie wages of five pound&bholngs; or above) onelie excepted and foreprised. And that all Plate, Coyne,
Jewells, Good&bholngs;, Debt&bholngs; and Chattell&bholngs; &bhopubr;sonalls, and all Land&bholngs;, Tenement&bholngs;, and other the &bhopcrl;misses as aforesaid, being
in the rule and custodie of any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons to the use of any Corporacion, Fraternitie, Guild, Misterie, Brotherhood,
or any Commonaltie, being corporate or not corporate, be, and shalbe rated, set, and charged by reason of this A&bholigct;,
at the value certified by the &bhopcrl;senters of that Certificate of every pound in good&bholngs; and debt&bholngs; as is aforesaid, And
for every pound in Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; A&bhonov;uities Fees Corrodies, and other yearelie proffitts as is aforesaid, and
the s&bhooov;mes that are above rehearsed sett and taxed to be levied and taken of them that shall have such good&bholngs; in
custodie, or otherwise charged for Land&bholngs; as is before rehearsed, And the same &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons, and bodies
corporate by authoritie of this A&bholigct; shalbe discharged against him or them that shall or ought to have the same at
the time of the payment or deliverie thereof, or at his otherwise departure from the custodie or possession of the
same: Except and alwaies foreprised from the charge and assessement of the said Subsidies all Good&bholngs; Chattell&bholngs;
Jewells and ornaments of Churches and Chappell&bholngs;, which have beene ordayned and used in Churches and Chappell&bholngs;
for the honor and service of Almightie God.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Subsidies when rated in Shires, Towns,&amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Names, Places,&amp;c. of Persons liable sent to the Exchequer.; Names of Collectors certified to the Exchequer; Payments in Liberties,&amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And the said first Subsidie, shalbe by authoritie aforesaid taxed, sessed, and rated according to this A&bholigct;, in every
Shire, Riding, Lath, Wapentake, Rape, Citie, Borough, Towne, and every other place within this Realme of
England, and Wales, and other the King&bholngs; Dominions before the last day of September now next c&bhooov;ming, And
the said second Subsidie, shall by the authoritie aforesaid, be taxed sessed and rated before the last day of March
now next ensuing, And the particuler s&bhooov;mes of every Shire Riding, Borough, Towne, and other place aforesaid,
with the particular names of such as are or shalbe chargeable, to, and for the payment of the said first Subsidie,
to be taxed and sett by the C&bhooov;missioners to the same to be lymitted, or two of them at the least, with the names of
the high Colle&bholigct;ors, and in the same forme shalbe certified into the King&bholngs; Exchequer, before the twentith day
of O&bholigct;ober next c&bhooov;ming: And the particuler s&bhooov;mes of every Shire, Riding, Borough, Towne, and other places
aforesaid, with the particular names of such as are chargeable for the said second Subsidie to be taxed and sett by
the C&bhooov;missioners to the same to be lymitted or two of them at the least, with the names of the high Colle&bholigct;ors,
and in the same forme shalbe certified into the King&bholngs; Exchequer, before the twentith of Aprill now next c&bhooov;ming,
And the said s&bhooov;mes in forme aforesaid to be taxed to and for the payment of the said first Subsidie, shalbe paid
in one entire s&bhooov;me into the King&bholngs; receipt of Exchequer aforesaid to the use of our said Soveraigne Lord, at or
before the last day of O&bholigct;ober now next c&bhooov;ming, And the said s&bhooov;mes in manner and forme aforesaid, to be taxed for
the payment of the said second Subsidie shalbe paid in one entire s&bhooov;me into the receipt aforesaid, to the use aforesaid
at or before the last day of Aprill now next c&bhooov;ming, And the s&bhooov;mes abovesaid, of and for the said Subsidies shalbe
taxed, set, asked, and demaunded, taken, gathered, levied, and paid to the use of our said Soveraigne Lord his
Heires and Successors in forme aforesaid, as well within Liberties Franchesies San&bholigct;uaries Auncient demesnes and
other whatsoever places exempt or not exempt, as without, except such Shires places and &bhopubr;sons as shalbe foreprised
in and by this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;, any Grant Charter &bhopcrl;scripcion, Use or Libertie, by reason of any l[ia]res patents, or other
priviledge &bhopcrl;scripcion, allowance for the same, or whatsoever other matter or discharge heretofore to the contrary
made, granted, used, or obtayned notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Absentees whether Natives or Aliens charged by Certificate of Inhabitant of Place where Lands,&amp;c. be.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Rule by which they are to be charged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, That every such &bhopubr;son aswell such as be
borne under the King&bholngs; obeysance, as every other &bhopubr;son Stranger borne, Denizen or not Denizen, inhabiting within
this Realme, or within Wales, or other the King&bholngs; Dominions, which at the tyme of the same assesings or Taxacions
or ev[er]y of them to be had or made, shalbe out of this Realme, or out of Wales, and have good&bholngs; chattell&bholngs; land&bholngs;
[and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] tenement&bholngs; fees or a&bhonov;uities, or other proffitts within this Realme, or in Wales shalbe charged and chargeable for
the same by the Certificate of the inhabitants of the place where such good&bholngs; chattell&bholngs; land&bholngs; tenement&bholngs; or other
the &bhopcrl;misses then shalbe, or in such other place where such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons, or his or their Fa&bholigct;or Deputie, or Attorny
shall have their most resort unto, within this Realme or in Wales, in like manner as if the said &bhopubr;son were or had
byn at the tyme of the said assessing within this Realme: And that every &bhopubr;son abiding or dwelling [within<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] or without
this Realme, shalbe charged or chargeable to the same Subsidies graunted by this A&bholigct;, according and after the rate
of such yearelie substance, or value of land&bholngs;, or tenement&bholngs; good&bholngs; chattell&bholngs; and other the &bhopcrl;misses, as every &bhopubr;son
so to be charged, shalbe set at, the tyme of the said assessing or taxacion upon him to be made and no otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Commissioners to be appointed by Lord Chancellor, Lord Treasurer, and other great Officers.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners for Boroughs and Towns Corporate, not being Counties, not to execute A&bholigct; out of their Boroughs or Towns.; Penalty.; Certificate thereof by the other Commissioners to the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that for the assessing and ordering of the said two Subsidies
to be dulie had the Lord Chauncellor of England, or the Lord Keep of the Great Seale, the Lord Treasurer of
England, the Lord President of the King&bholngs; Councell, the Lord Privie Seale, the Lord Steward of the King&bholngs; houshold, the
Lord Admirall of England, the Lord Chamberlaine of the King&bholngs; most honorable Houshold for the tyme being or
two of them at the least (whereof the Lord Chauncellor of England, or Keep of the Greate Seale for the tyme being to
be one) shall and may name and appoint of and for every Shire Riding and other places, aswell within this Realme
as in Wales, and other the King&bholngs; Dominions, as also of and for every Citie and Towne being a Countie of it selfe,
and of and for the Isle of Wight, such certaine nomber of &bhopubr;sons of every of the same Shires Ridings Lathes
Wapentakes Rapes Cities Townes and Isle of Wight and every other place, as they shall thinke convenient to be
C&bhooov;missioners of and within the same place whereof they be Inhabitants: and also of and for the honorable houshold
of the King&bholngs; Majestie, in what Shire or other place the said houshold shall [then happen<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] to be, And the Lord
Chauncellor or Lord Keep of the great Seale for the tyme being, and other with him before named, or two of them
as is aforesaid in like manner may name and appoint of every other such Borough, Townes corporate, as well in
England as in Wales, and other the King&bholngs; Dominions, as they shall thinke fitt and requisite, six, five, foure, three or
two of the head Officers, and other honest inhabitants in every of the said Cities Boroughes and Townes corporate,
according to the nomber and multitude of the people being in the same, The which &bhopubr;sons (if any such be) thereunto
named of the said Inhabitants of the said Boroughs and Townes corporate, not being Counties of themselves, shalbe
joyned and putt in as C&bhooov;missioners, with the &bhopubr;sons named for such Shires and Ridings, as the said Boroughes and
Townes corporate, not being Counties in themselves, be set and have their being: which &bhopubr;sons so named for and of
the said Boroughs and Townes corporate, not being Counties, by reason of their dwelling in the same, shall not take
uppon them, nor none of them to put any part of their C&bhooov;mission in execucion for the &bhopcrl;misses out of the said
Boroughs and Townes corporate wherein they be so named onelie, nor to execute the said C&bhooov;mission within the
Borough or Towne corporate where they shalbe so dwelling, but at such daies and tymes as the said other
C&bhooov;missioners for the same Shire and Riding shall thereunto lymitt and appoint within the said Borough and Towne
corporate not being a Countie, whereof they be so named, and not out of such Borough or Towne, and in that
manner to be ayding and assisting with the said other C&bhooov;missioners, in and for the good executing of the effe&bholigct; of
the said C&bhooov;mission, uppon paine of every of the said C&bhooov;missioners soe named, for every such Citie Borough and
Towne corporate, not being a Countie, to make such Fine as the said other C&bhooov;missioners in the C&bhooov;mission of and
for the same Shire or Riding so named, or three of them at the least, shall by their discrecions sett and certifie into
the King&bholngs; Exchequer, there to be levied to the use of the King&bholngs; Majestie in like manner as if such or like s&bhooov;mes
had byn sett and rated uppon every such &bhopubr;son for the said Subsidies.</para>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Commissions dire&bholigct;ed out of Chancery; Schedules to Commissions.; Commissioners to divide themselves.; Commissioners not compellable to a&bholigct; out of Shires</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">The which C&bhooov;missioners soe named of and for the said Citties, Boroughs and Townes not being Counties, and
onelie put into the said C&bhooov;mission by reason of their dwelling in the same, shall not have any part or porcion of
the Fees and rewards of the C&bhooov;missioners and their Clerks in this A&bholigct; afterwards specified and allowed, And the
Lord Chauncellor of England or Keep of the greate Seale of England for the tyme being, shall make and dire&bholigct; out
of the Court of Chauncery under the great Seale severall C&bhooov;missions: That is to saie, For every Shire Riding
Lath Wapentake Rape Citie Towne Borough Isle and houshold unto such &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons as by his discrecion, or
any of the other with him before named and appointed, as is before rehearsed shalbe thought sufficient for the
sessing and levying of the said two Subsidies in all Shires and places, according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct;e:
which C&bhooov;mission for the payment of the said first Subsidie shalbe dire&bholigct;ed and delivered to the said C&bhooov;missioners, or
to one of them, before the last day of August next c&bhooov;ming, And the C&bhooov;mission for the payment of the said second
Subsidie shalbe dire&bholigct;ed and delivered to the said C&bhooov;missioners, or to one of them before the last day of Februarie
next c&bhooov;ming, And to every of the said C&bhooov;missions tenne Schedules conteyning in them the tenor of this A&bholigct; shalbe
affiled: By the which C&bhooov;mission, the C&bhooov;missioners in every such C&bhooov;mission named according to this A&bholigct;e, and
as many of them as shalbe appointed by the said C&bhooov;mission shall have full power and authoritie to putt the effe&bholigct;
of the said C&bhooov;mission in Execucion: And that by the authoritie of this A&bholigct;, after such C&bhooov;mission to them dire&bholigct;ed
they may by their assents and agreements sever themselves for the execucion of their C&bhooov;mission, in Hundreds
Lathes, Wards, Rapes, Wapentakes, Townes, Parishes, and other places within the lymitts of the said C&bhooov;mission,
in such forme as to them shall seeme expedient to be ordered, and betweene them to be c&bhooov;muned and agreed,
according to the tenor and effe&bholigct; of the C&bhooov;mission to them therein dire&bholigct;ed, Uppon which severance every &bhopubr;son
of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament that shalbe C&bhooov;missioner shalbe assigned unto the Hundred where he dwelleth. Provided
alwaies that no &bhopubr;son be or shalbe compelled to be any C&bhooov;missioner to and for the execucion of this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;,
but onelie in the Shire where he dwelleth and inhabiteth. And that any &bhopubr;son assigned to the contrary thereof in
any wise, shall not be compelled to put in execucion the effe&bholigct; of this A&bholigct; or any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Commissioners to execute. A&bholigct; according to the tenor thereof.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to direv&bholigct; Precepts to certain number of Inhabitants in Hundreds,&amp;c. to appear before Commissioners.; Persons who receive Precepts are to shew such Precepts to the other Inhabitants named therein.; Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, That the C&bhooov;missioners and every of them
which shalbe named lymitted and appointed according to this A&bholigct; to be C&bhooov;missioners in every such Shire Riding
Lathe Wapentake Rape Citie Towne Borough Isle and the said houshold, or any other place, and none other,
shall trulie effe&bholigct;uallie and diligentlie for their part execute the effe&bholigct; of this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;, according to the tenor thereof
in every behalfe, and no otherwise by any other meanes without omission, favour, dread, malice, or any other thing
to be attempted or done by them or any of them to the contrary thereof, And the said C&bhooov;missioners, or as many
of them as shalbe appointed by the said C&bhooov;mission, and none other, for the execucion of the said C&bhooov;mission and
A&bholigct;, shall for the taxacion of the said first Subsidie, before the twentith day of September next ensuing; And for
the Taxacion of the said second Subsidie, shall before the twentith [day<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] of March next c&bhooov;ming by vertue of the
C&bhooov;mission delivered unto them in forme [aforesaid,<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] dire&bholigct; their severall or joynt&bhopcrl;cept or &bhopcrl;cepts unto eight, seaven,
sixe, five, foure, three or two, as for the nomber of the Inhabitants shalbe requisite of the most substanciall
discreet and honest &bhopubr;sons inhabitants to be named by the said C&bhooov;missioners, or by as many of them as shalbe
appointed by the said C&bhooov;mission of and in Hundreds Lathes Rapes Wapentakes Wards Parishes Townes and other
places aswell within Liberties, Franchesies, Auncient demesne, places exempted and San&bholigct;uaries, as without, within
the lymitts of the Shires, Ridings, Lathes, Wapentakes, Rapes, Citties, Townes, Boroughs, and Isle aforesaid, and other
Places within the lymitts of their C&bhooov;mission, and to the Constables, Subconstables, Bailiffs and other like Officers
and Ministers of every of the said Hundreds, Townes, Wards, Lathes, Wapentakes, Parishes and other Places
aforesaid, as to the said Commissioners and every nomber of them or unto three or two of them by their discrecion
in division shall seeme expedient, as by the manner and use of those part&bholngs;, shalbe requisite, straitlie by the said
&bhopcrl;cept charging and c&bhooov;maunding the said Inhabitants Constables and other Officers aforesaid, to whome such &bhopcrl;cept
shalbe so dire&bholigct;ed to appeare in their &bhopubrc;per &bhopubr;sons before the said C&bhooov;missioners or such nomber of them, as they
shall divide themselves, according to the tenor of the said C&bhooov;mission at certaine daies and places by the said C&bhooov;missioners
or any nomber of them as is aforesaid, within Cities Boroughs or Townes corporate or without in any other Places
as is aforesaid, by their discrecion shalbe lymitted thereunto, to doe and accomplish all that to them on the part of
the King&bholngs; Majestie shalbe enjoyned touching this A&bholigct;: C&bhooov;maunding further by the same &bhopcrl;cept, that hee to whose
hand&bholngs; such &bhopcrl;cept shall come, shall shew and deliver the same to the other Inhabitants or Officers named in the same
&bhopcrl;cept, And that none of them faile to accomplish the same uppon paine of fortie shillings to be forfeited to the
King&bholngs; Majestie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Persons named in Precept to appear before Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Such Persons making Default or refusing to serve.; Penalty 40s. ; Upon Appearance charged to make enquiry into the Substance of Persons to be charged, but such Enquiry not to be taken on Oath, and to certify before Commissioners.; Penalty &pound;5. or more.; Commissioners to read the Rates openly.; Afterwards another Day appointed by Commissioners for such Persons to appear.; Not appearing.; Penalty 40s.; or refusing to make Certificate.; Penalty 40s.; Commissioners to examine Presenters of Certificate.; Further Proceedings on Assessments by Precept to Constables,&amp;c. to warn Persons named therein to appear.; Oath not allowed on Enquiry into the Substance of Persons charged.; Persons named in the said Precept called upon not appearing.; Penalty double Rate.; On Enquiry into the Substance of Persons charged, Commissioners may increase Taxation</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And it is further ordeyned by the Authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, that at the said day and place &bhopcrl;fixed and
lymitted in the said &bhopcrl;cept, every of the said C&bhooov;missioners then being in the Shire, and not having sufficient excuse
for his absence, at the day and place &bhopcrl;fixed for that part whereunto he was lymitted, shall appeare in his owne
&bhopubrc;per &bhopubr;son, and there the same C&bhooov;missioners being &bhopcrl;sent or as many of them as shalbe appointed by the King&bholngs;
Majesties C&bhooov;mission, shall call or cause to be called before them the said Inhabitants and officers to whome they have
dire&bholigct;ed their said &bhopcrl;cepts, and which had in c&bhooov;maundement there to appeare by vertue of the said &bhopcrl;cept. And
if any &bhopubr;son so warned make default, unlesse he then be letted by sicknes or lawfull excuse, and that lett be then
witnessed by the oathes of two credible &bhopubr;sons, or if any appearing refuse to serve in forme following, Then every
such &bhopubr;son so making default or refusing to serve shall forfeit to the King&bholngs; Majestie fortie shillings, and so at every
tyme appointed by the saide C&bhooov;missioners for the same Taxacion, untill such Tyme the nomber of every such &bhopubr;sons
have appeared and certified in forme underwritten, every of them so making default or refusing to serve, shall
forfeit to the King&bholngs; Majestie fortie shillings, and uppon the same appearance had, they shalbe charged before the
C&bhooov;missioners by all convenient waies and meanes (other then: by corporall Oath) to enquire of the best and most
value of the substance of every &bhopubr;son dwelling and abiding within the lymitts of the places that they shalbe
charged with, and of other which shall have his or their most resort unto any of the said places and chargeable with
any s&bhouov;me of mony by this A&bholigct;e of the said [Subsidies<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] and of all other thing&bholngs; requisite touching the said A&bholigct;, and
according to the intent of the same, and thereuppon as neere as it may be or shall come to their knowledge, without
respe&bholigct; of any former taxacion heretofore had, trulie to &bhopcrl;sent and certifie before the said C&bhooov;missioners the names
and surnames, and the best and uttermost substance and values of every of them, as well of Landes Tenement&bholngs; and
other Hereditament&bholngs; Possessions and Proffitts, as of goodes chattell&bholngs; debt&bholngs; and other thing&bholngs; chargeable by the same
A&bholigct;, without any concealement, love, favour, affeccion, dread or malice, uppon paine of forfeiture of five pound&bholngs;
or more, to be taxed, extra&bholigct;ed, and levied in forme as hereafter in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; shall be lymitted or appointed:
and thereuppon the said C&bhooov;missioners shall openlie there read, or cause to be read unto them the said rates in
this A&bholigct; mencioned, and openlie declare the effe&bholigct; of their charge unto them in what manner and forme they ought
and should make their certificates according to the rates and s&bhooov;mes thereof abovesaid, and of all manner of &bhopubr;sons
aswell Aliens and Strangers Denizens or not Denizens inhabiting within this Realme, as of such &bhopubr;sons as be borne
under the King&bholngs; obeisance chargeable to this A&bholigct;, and of the possessions goodes and chattell&bholngs; of Fraternities
Guilds Corporacions Brotherhoods Misteries C&bhooov;monalties, and other as is abovesaid, and of &bhopubr;sons being in the
part&bholngs; beyond the Seas, having Good&bholngs; and Chattell&bholngs; Land&bholngs; or Tenement&bholngs; within this Realme as is aforesaid, and
of all good&bholngs; being in the Custodie of any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons, to the use of any other as is abovesaid, by the which
Informacion and shewing, the said &bhopubr;sons should have such plaine knowledge of the true intent of this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;,
and of the manner of their Certificate, That the same &bhopubr;sons shall have no reasonable cause to excuse them by
ignorance. And after such charge, and the Statute of the said [Subsidies<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] and the manner of the said Certificate to
be made in writing, conteyning the names and surnames of every &bhopubr;son, and whether he be borne without the King&bholngs;
obeysance, or Within, and the best value of every &bhopubr;son, in every degree, aswell of the yearelie value of Land&bholngs; and
Tenement&bholngs;, and of such like possessions and proffitts, as of the value of good&bholngs; and chattell&bholngs; debt&bholngs; and every
thing to their certificate requisite and necessary to them declared, the said C&bhooov;missioners there being, shalby their
discrecions lymitt and appoint unto the said &bhopubr;sons another day and place to appeare before the said C&bhooov;missioners,
and charging the said &bhopubr;sons, that they in the meane tyme shall make diligent inquirie by all waies and meanes of the
&bhopcrl;misses, and then and there every of them uppon paine of forfeiture of fortie shillings to the King&bholngs; Majestie, to
appeare att the said new &bhopcrl;fixed day and place there to certifie unto the said C&bhooov;missioners in writing according to
their said charge and according to the true intent of the said Graunt of Subsidie and as to them in manner aforesaid
hath bene declared and shewed by the C&bhooov;missioners, Att which daie and place so to them &bhopcrl;fixed, if anie of the said
&bhopubr;sons make default, or appeare and refuse to make the said Certificate that then everie of them so offending, to
forfeite to the King&bholngs; Majestie fortie shillings except there be a reasonable excuse of his default, by reason of his
sicknes or otherwise by the oathes of two credible &bhopubr;sons there witnessed, and of such as appeare readie to make
Certificate as is aforesaid, the said C&bhooov;missioners there being, shall take and receave the same Certificate and every
part thereof, and the names values and substance of everie &bhopubr;son so certified And if the said C&bhooov;missioners see cause
reasonable they shall examine the said Presenters thereof, and thereupon the said C&bhooov;missioners att the said daies
and place by their agreement amongest themselves, shall from time to time there openlie &bhopcrl;fixe a day at a certaine
place or places within the limitts of their C&bhooov;mission by their discrecion for their further &bhopubrc;ceeding to the said
Assessing of the same [Subsidies,<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] And thereuppon att the said day of the said Certificate, as is aforesaid taken, the same
C&bhooov;missioners shall make their &bhopcrl;cept or &bhopcrl;cepts to the Constables Subconstables Bailiffs or other Officers of such
Hundreds Wapentakes Townes or other places aforesaid as the same C&bhooov;missioners shalbe of comprysing and
conteyning in the said &bhopcrl;cepts the names and surnames of all &bhopubr;sons &bhopcrl;sented before them in the said Certificate, of
whome if the said C&bhooov;missioners or as many of them as shalbe thereunto appointed by the King&bholngs; C&bhooov;mission shall
then have vehement suspe&bholigct; to be of more greater value or substance in Land&bholngs; Good&bholngs; Chattell&bholngs; or s&bhooov;mes of
money owing unto them or other substance aforesaid then uppon such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons soe certified and specified
as aforesaid, the same C&bhooov;missioners shall make their &bhopcrl;cepts or &bhopcrl;cept dire&bholigct;ed to the Constables Bailiffs or other
Officers c&bhooov;manding the said Constables Bayliffs or other officers to whome such &bhopcrl;cept shalbe dire&bholigct;ed to warne
such &bhopubr;sons whose names shalbe comprised in the said &bhopcrl;cepts att their mansions, or to their &bhopubr;sons, that the same
&bhopubr;sons named in such &bhopcrl;cepts and everie of them shall &bhopubr;sonallie appeare before the said C&bhooov;missioners at the said new
&bhopcrl;fixed day and place there to be examined by all waies and meanes (other then by corporall oath) by the said
C&bhooov;missioners of their greatest substance and best value, and of all and everie somes of money owing to them and
other whatsoever matter con&bhoccrl;ning the &bhopcrl;misses or anie of them according to this A&bholigct;. At which day and place so
&bhopcrl;fixed the said C&bhooov;missioners then and there being, or as many of them as shalbe thereunto appointed by the
King&bholngs; C&bhooov;mission, shall cause to be called the said &bhopubr;sons whose names shalbe comprised in the said &bhopcrl;cept as
is aforesaid for their examinacion, And if anie of [these<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] &bhopubr;sons which shalbe warned as aforesaid to be examined,
which at anie time after the warning, and before the day &bhopcrl;fixed shalbe within such place as he may have knowledge
of his said appearance to be made make default and appeare not, unlesse a reasonable cause, or els a reasonable
excuse by the oathes of two credible &bhopubr;sons, before the said C&bhooov;missioners, be truelie alleaged for his discharge,
that then everie of them so making default to be taxed and charged to the King&bholngs; Majestie, with and at the double
s&bhooov;me of the rate, that he should or ought to have bene sett att, for and after the best value of his landes
or substance uppon him &bhoccrl;tified if he had appeared by the discrecion of the C&bhooov;missioners there being which
Commissioners shall travaile with every of the other &bhopubr;sons soe then and there appearing, whose names shalbe ex&bhopcrl;ssed
in the said &bhopcrl;cept or &bhopcrl;cepts and in whome anie vehement suspe&bholigct; was or shalbe had in forme aforesaid by all such
waies and meanes they can, other then by corporall oath for the better knowledge of their best value, either in
hereditament&bholngs; or possessions, or els in good&bholngs; or debt&bholngs; and thereuppon shall have power and authoritie by virtue
of this A&bholigct; according to their discrecions to enlarge and increase the taxa&bhocotil;n of such &bhopubr;sons as they shall soe find
by due examinacion to be of greater value or substance in landes or goodes, then the were &bhopcrl;sented att.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Spiritual Persons how rated for Temporal Possessions.</head>
			<para id="p20">And that everie Spirituall &bhopubr;son at everie of the said taxacions of the said two Subsidies, shalbe rated and sett
according to the rate abovesaid, of and for everie pound that the same Spirituall &bhopubr;son, or anie other to his use,
hath by discent bargaine or purchase in Fee simple, or fee taile, terme of life, terme of yeres, by execucion, by
wardshipp, or by coppie of court Roll, in anie mannors land&bholngs; tenement&bholngs; rent&bholngs; services offices fees corrodies
a&bhonov;uities and hereditament&bholngs; after the true just and yereley value thereof and according as other the King&bholngs; Majesties
Subje&bholigct;&bholngs; borne within this Realme be charged in forme above remembred, soe that it extend to the yereley value of
twentie shillings or above.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Assessors misbehaving.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may set a Fine upon them; estreated into the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed That if the said Taxors or Assessors shall not dulie behave themselves in their inquirie,
taxacion, Assessement, or Certificate, but shall affeccionately corruptlie or parciallie demeane themselves in that behalfe,
in such wise, that the C&bhooov;missioners shalby their consideracions deeme them offenders worthie of punishment, for
not doeing their duties therein, that then foure or more of the C&bhooov;missioners in that Countie for the said Subsidie,
shall have power and authoritie by their discrecions either to charge the said Assessors uppon their corporall oathes,
for the better service aforesaid in that behalfe, or els by their discrecions to taxe and sett uppon the said Assessors
for their misdemeanors in that behalfe, such a fine or paine as they shall thincke good, soe that it exceed not
the s&bhooov;me of ten pound&bholngs;, and the same fine or paine att their discrecions to estreat into the Courte of Exchequer:
Everie which Fine soe taxed and sett, by foure of the said C&bhooov;missioners or more, and being estreated with the
Schedule and Bookes of that limitt shalbe levied and answered to the King&bholngs; use in [like<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] manner, and forme to all
intent&bholngs; and purposes, as anie other s&bhooov;mes that shalbe taxed and become due by virtue of this Statute and A&bholigct; of
Subsidie, and not in any other wise or manner.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Remedy for Persons aggrieved by the Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may abate or increase Assessment.; False Oath of Value of Lands,&amp;c.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And if anie &bhopubr;son certified or rated by virtue of this A&bholigct; whether he be a C&bhooov;missioner or other to anie manner of
value doth find himselfe greived with the same &bhopcrl;sentment, sessing or rating, and thereuppon complaine to the
C&bhooov;missioners before whome he shalbe called sessed or taxed, or before two of them before the same taxacion be
certified in the Court of Exchequer that then the said C&bhooov;missioners, or two of them, shall by all waies and meanes
examine particularlie and distin&bholigct;lie the &bhopubr;son so complayning uppon his oath and other his neighbours by their
discrecions of every his Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; above specified, and of every his good&bholngs; chattell&bholngs; and debt&bholngs; above
mencioned: And after due examinacion and &bhopubr;fe&bholigct; knowledge thereof had and &bhopcrl;ceived by the said C&bhooov;missioners,
or two of them, which shall have power by authoritie aforesaid, the said C&bhooov;missioners or two of them, to whome
any such complaint shalbe made, by their discrecion uppon the oath of the said &bhopubr;son so complayning may
abate, defaulke, increase or inlarge the said assessements, according as it shall appeare unto them just uppon the
same examinacion, and the same s&bhooov;me so abated, defaulked, increased, or inlarged, shall be by them estreated
in forme as hereafter ensueth. And if it be proved by witnesses, or by the parties owne confession, or other
lawfull waie or meanes, within a yeare after any such oath made, that the same &bhopubr;son so rated and sworne, was
of any better or greater value in land&bholngs; goodes or other thing&bholngs; above specified at the tyme of his said oath, then
the same &bhopubr;son so sworne did declare uppon his said oath, that then every such &bhopubr;son so offending shall lose and
forfeit to the King&bholngs; Majestie so much lawfull mony of England, as he the same &bhopubr;son so sworne was set at or
taxed to pay.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Commissioners to be rated at such Place where they shall be Commissioners; other Persons where they have resided for the most Part of the Year preceding.</head>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Absentees assessed where last abiding.; Rate to be according to the Substance of Persons liable</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">And also it is ena&bholigct;ed by the same authoritie, that every &bhopubr;son to be rated and taxed as is aforesaid, shalbe rated
and set, and the s&bhooov;me on him set to be levied at such place, where he and his familie were resident for the most
part of the yeare next before the same &bhopcrl;sentment and taxacion made, and no where else. And that no C&bhooov;mission[er]
for his Subsidie shall be rated or taxed for his good&bholngs; or land&bholngs;, but in the Shire or in other place where he shalbe
C&bhooov;missioner. And that if any &bhopubr;son chargeable to this A&bholigct;, at the tyme of the said assessings happen to be out of
this Realme, and out of Wales, or farre from the place where he shalbe knowen: then he to be set, where he was
last abiding in this Realme, or within Wales, and after the substance, value, and other proffitts of every &bhopubr;son, to be
knowen by the examinacion, certificate or other manner of way as is aforesaid, And that the said C&bhooov;missioners, or
as many of them as shalbe appointed by the King&bholngs; Majesties C&bhooov;mission or C&bhooov;missions shall after the rate and rates
aforesaid cause every &bhopubr;son so to be set rated and taxed, according to the rate of the substance and value of his
land&bholngs; goodes chattell&bholngs; and other &bhopubrc;ffitts chargeable by this A&bholigct;, whereby the greatest or most best s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes
according to his most substance, by reason of this A&bholigct; might or may be set or taxed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Remedy for Commissioners and other Persons taxed in other Place than where they are Commissioners or were resiant for most Part of the preceding Year.</head>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">Fee for Allowance</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p28">And that every &bhopubr;son taxed in any Countie or Place, other then where he and his family were resiant for the
most part of the yeare, then next before, or in any Countie or place, other then where he is a C&bhooov;missioner for
the Subsidie, if he be a C&bhooov;missioner, uppon certificate made to the said Court of Exchequer under the hand&bholngs; and
seales of two C&bhooov;missioners for the same Subsidie in the same Countie or place where such &bhopubr;son and his family were
resiant for the most part of the yeare then next before, or where he is a C&bhooov;missioner for the taxacion and payment
of the same Subsidie, testifying his most resiance, having of familie, or being a C&bhooov;missioner, shalbe a sufficient
discharge for the taxacion of that &bhopubr;son in any other places, and of and for all other s&bhooov;mes of mony uppon such
&bhopubr;sons so set and taxed, save only the taxacions made in that Countie or place from which such certificate shall be
made as is aforesaid, and for the s&bhooov;me of mony uppon such &bhopubr;son there assessed or taxed, And that such certificate
without any Plea or other circumstance, shalbe a sufficient warrant aswell to the Barons and Auditor and Auditors
of the said Court of Exchequer, as to all and every other Officers, to whome the allowance thereof shall appertaine,
paying for such discharge and allowance onelie six pence and no more.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Double Charges not to be allowed.</head>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">Remedy in respe&bholigct; of Double Charges</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p30">Provided alwaies, that every such &bhopubr;son that shall be rated or taxed according to the intent and true meaning of
this A&bholigct; for paying of and to these Subsidies for and after the yearelie value of his Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs;, and other
reall possessions or proffitts, at any of the said taxacions, shall not after be sett and rated for his good&bholngs; and chattell&bholngs;,
or other moveable substance at the same taxacion, and that he that shalbe sett charged or taxed for the same Subsidies
for his goodes chattell&bholngs; and other moveables at any of the said taxacions according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct;,
shall not after be charged taxed or chargeable for his land&bholngs; or other reall possessions and proffitts abovesaid at the
same taxacions or any of them, nor that any &bhopubr;son by any taxacion be double charged for the said Subsidies, nor set
or taxed at severall places by reason of this A&bholigct;, But if any &bhopubr;son happen to be double set taxed or charged, either
in one place, or at severall places, then he to be discharged of the one taxacion, and charged with the other, according
to the meaning and intent of this A&bholigct;, any thing contayned in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Proviso for Persons having two Mansions, or being Houshold Servants or Waiting Servants to the King or others.</head>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">Persons unduly escaping Taxation,; on Proof thereof before Commissioners or Barons of the Exchequer,; taxed at Double Value</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p32">And that it be ordeyned and ena&bholigct;ed by the said authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, That no &bhopubr;son having two
Mansions, or two places to resort unto, or calling himselfe Houshold servant, or waiting servant to the King&bholngs; Majestie, or other Lord or Lady, Master or Mistresse, be excused uppon his saying, from the taxes of the said
Subsidies, in neither of the places, where he may be set or taxed, unlesse he bring a Certificate in writing from the
C&bhooov;missioners where that he is so set or taxed indeed at one place. And if any &bhopubr;son that ought to be set and
taxed to these &bhopcrl;sent Subsidies by reason of his removing or resorting to two places, or by reason of his saying
that he elsewhere was taxed, or by reason of any priviledge of his dwelling or abiding in any place not being foreprised
in this A&bholigct;, or otherwise by his covine or crafte, or by any words or sayings or otherwise: or if any that is a
C&bhooov;missioner or Assessor of others, happen to escape from the said taxacions for the payment of these Subsidies, or
any of them, and be not set and taxed according to the true intent of this A&bholigct;, and that proved by &bhopcrl;sentment,
Examinacion, Informacion, or otherwise before the said C&bhooov;missioners, or two of them, or before the Barons of the
King&bholngs; Ma<emph type="p">t</emph>s Exchequer, or two Justices of the Peace of that Countie where such &bhopubr;son dwelleth: Then every such
&bhopubr;son that by such meanes or otherwise, willinglie by covin or without just cause, shall happen to escape from the
said taxacions or payments aforesaid or any of them, and shall not be rated taxed and set shall be charged upon
the knowledge and proofe thereof, with, and at the double value of so much as he should, might or ought to have
bene set or taxed at by vertue of this A&bholigct;: And the same double value to be levied gathered and paid of his
Good&bholngs; and Chattell&bholngs;, Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; towards the said Subsidies, and further to be punished according to the
discrecion of the Barons, Justices and C&bhooov;missioners, before whome he shalbe convi&bholigct;ed for his offence and deceit in
that behalfe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. The Power of Commissioners to tax other Commissioners, and also Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">Barons and Persons of higher Estate taxed by the Lord Chancellor, Lord Treasurer, and other Persons named by the King.; Rate estreated and certified</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p34">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, That the said C&bhooov;missioners in every C&bhooov;mission, which shalbe
or inhabite in any Countie or Place within the lymitts of their C&bhooov;mission, or the more part of them, shall have full
power and authoritie by this A&bholigct; to set taxe and sesse every other C&bhooov;missioner joyned with them in every such
C&bhooov;mission, and the said C&bhooov;missioners within their Division shall also assesse every Assessor within their Division,
for his or their good&bholngs; land&bholngs; and other the &bhopcrl;misses as is abovesaid, by which [said<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] C&bhooov;mission the said C&bhooov;missioners,
to whome it shall appertaine, shall indifferentlie set taxe and sesse themselves and the said Assessors.; and that aswell
the s&bhooov;mes uppon every of the said C&bhooov;missioners and Assessors so sessed rated and taxed as the s&bhouov;mes made and
&bhopcrl;sented by the Presenters, as is abovesaid, shalbe written certified, set and estreated, and the Estreats thereof to be
made with other the inhabitants of that part, and within the lymitts of the same C&bhooov;mission and Division, so to be
gathered and levied, in like manner as it ought or should have bene, if the said C&bhooov;missioners had not bene in
the said C&bhooov;mission, And that all &bhopubr;sons of the estate of a Baron or Baronesse, and every estate above shalbe charged
with their freehold and value as is aforesaid by the Chauncellor or the Lord Keeper of the great Seale of England,
the High Treasurer of England for the tyme being or one of them, together with other such &bhopubr;sons as by the King&bholngs;
Majesties authoritie or c&bhooov;maundement shalbe named and appointed, and they to be charged for the said severall
payments of the said Subsidies after the forme of the said Graunt according to the taxacion aforesaid and the s&bhooov;me
of and uppon them to be taxed and set with the names of the Colle&bholigct;ors appointed for gathering and paying of the
same, to be estreated delivered and certified at dayes and places above specified by the Lord Chauncellor or Keep
of the great Seale, and Lord Tresurer, or one of them, together with other such &bhopubr;sons, as thereunto shalbe named,
as is aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Rates estreated under the Sign Manual and Seal of the Commissioners, and Estreat delivered to sufficient; Inhabitants,&amp;c. of Hundreds,&amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p35">
				<emph type="i">By virtue of Estreat Officers,&amp;c. to levy Rate.; Distress.; If Rate not paid in Eight Days then Distress appraised and sold.; Officers,&amp;c. to answer for the Portion limited to them, only</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p36">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, That after the taxes and assesses of the said s&bhooov;mes uppon
and by the said assessing and certificate as is aforesaid made, the said C&bhooov;missioners or as many of them as shalbe
thereunto appointed, and have authoritie by the King&bholngs; Majesties C&bhooov;mission, shall with all speed, and without delay
by their writing estreate the said taxes thereof, under the Seales and Signes Manuell of the said C&bhooov;missioners, or
as many of them as shalbe appointed at the least. and the same shall deliver unto sufficient and substanciall Inhabitants,
Constables, Subconstables, Bayliffs, and other Officers joyntlie of Hundreds, Townes, Parishes, and other Places
aforesaid within their lymitts, and to other sufficient &bhopubr;sons, Inhabitants of the same, onelie by the [discrecions<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] of the
said C&bhooov;missioners, with the assent of the high Colle&bholigct;or, and as the place and parties shall require, aswell the
particuler names&amp; surnames, as the remembrance of all [s&bhooov;mes<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] taxed and sett of and uppon every &bhopubr;sons, aswell man
as woman chargeable to this A&bholigct;e, Housholders and all other Inhabitants and Dwellers within the said Parishes,
Townes and Places contributorie to this A&bholigct; of Subsidies, by authoritie of which writing and estreat so delivered,
the said Officers and other &bhopubr;sons so named and deputed, severally shall have full power and authoritie by vertue of
this A&bholigct;, imediatelie after the delivery of the said writing or estreat, to demaund levie and gather of every &bhopubr;son
therein specified the s&bhouov;me and s&bhouov;mes in the same writing or estreat comprised, and for non payment thereof, to
distreine the same &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons so being behinde, by their good&bholngs; and chattell&bholngs;, and the distresse so taken to keepe
by the space of eight daies, at the costs and charges of the owner thereof, And if the said owner do not pay such
s&bhooov;me of money as shalbe taxed by authoritie of this A&bholigct; within the same eight daies, then the same distresse to be
appraised by foure or three or two of the inhabitants where such distresse is taken, and also then to be sold by
the Constable or other Colle&bholigct;or for the payment of the said money, and the overplus c&bhooov;ming of the sale and keeping
thereof (if any be) to be imediatelie restored to the owner of the same distresse, Which said Officers and other
&bhopubr;sons so deputed to aske, take, gather and levie the said s&bhooov;mes, shall aunswere and be charged for the porcion onelie</para>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">Allowance to Officers on Rate recovered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p38">to them assigned and lymitted to be gathered levied and comprised in the said writing or estreat, so to them as
aforesaid, delivered to the use of our Soveraigne Lord the King&bholngs; Majestie, and his Heires and Successors, and the
said s&bhooov;me in that writing or Estreat to be comprised to pay unto the high Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors of that place for
the colleccion of the same, in manner and forme underwritten, thereunto to be named and deputed, and the same.
Inhabitants and Officers, so gathering the same particular s&bhooov;mes for their colleccion thereof, shall retaine for every
twentie shillings so by them received and paid, two pence, And that to be allowed at the payment of their colleccion
by them to be made, to the high Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Commissioners may appoint Colle&bholigct;ors</head>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">to be High Colle&bholigct;ors.; Commissioners to deliver Estreats under their Seals and Sign Manual to Colle&bholigct;ors.; Colle&bholigct;ors to answer the Sums comprized in Estreat</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p40">And further be it ena&bholigct;ed by the said Authoritie, that the said C&bhooov;missioners, or the more part of them, as shall
take uppon (<ref idref="n15">15</ref>) the execucion and busines of the said C&bhooov;mission, shall for every of the said payments of the said
Subsidies name such sufficient and able &bhopubr;sons, which then shall have and possesse land&bholngs; and other Hereditament&bholngs; in
their owne right of the cleare yearelie value of fortie pound&bholngs;, or goodes to the value of foure hundred pound&bholngs;, at
the least, as he shalbe taxed in the Subsidie Booke, if any such be in the said lymitts, and for want of such so
assessed, then those to be appointed Colle&bholigct;ors that then shalbe sufficient, and rated and taxed in the Subsidie
Bookes in land&bholngs; and good&bholngs; neerest to the values aforesaid, as by their discrecions shalbe thought good in Shires,
Ridings, Lathes, Wapentakes, Rapes, Cities, Townes, corporate, and other whatsoever places, as well within places
priviledged, as without, not being foreprised within this A&bholigct;, to be high Colle&bholigct;ors, and to have the colleccion and
receipt of the said s&bhooov;mes set and leviable within the &bhopubr;cin&bholigct; lymitts and bounds, where they shalbe so lymitted and
appointed to be high Colle&bholigct;ors, And to every of the said Colle&bholigct;ors so severally named, the said C&bhooov;missioners
or two of them at the least, with all speed and without delay, after the said whole s&bhooov;me of any payment of the
said Subsidies be set by all the lymitts of the same their C&bhooov;mission, or in such lymitts as the high Colle&bholigct;ors shalbe
so severallie assigned, shall under their Seales and Signe manuall, deliver one estreate indented in Parchment
comprising in it the names of all such &bhopubr;sons as were assigned to levie the said particuler s&bhooov;mes, and the s&bhooov;mes of
every Hundred, Wapentake, Towne, or other place aforesaid, with the names and surnames of the &bhopubr;sons so
chargeable according to the Estreat so thereof first made, and delivered as is aforesaid. And the Colle&bholigct;ors
to be assigned, shalbe charged to aunswere the whole s&bhooov;me comprised in the said Estreat lymitted to his colleccion,
as is aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Commissioners to take Recognizances of Colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
			<para id="p41">
				<emph type="i">Condition of Recognizance for first Subsidy.; Condition of Recognizance for Second Subsidy.; Commissioners to certify Recognizances,&amp;c. into the Exchequer.; Penalty &pound;10.; Colle&bholigct;or not making Recognizance.; Penalty &pound;20l.; Exchequer to cancel Recognizances on Payment of Colle&bholigct;ion into Exchequer without Fee.; Colle&bholigct;or may appoint Days and Places for Payment of Colle&bholigct;ion.; Assessor,&amp;c. not paying Colle&bholigct;ion to High Colle&bholigct;ors,; after Allowance of 2d. in the Pound for Colle&bholigct;ion; Distress.; Proceedings thereon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p42">Provided alwaies, and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that the said C&bhooov;missioners having authoritie by
this A&bholigct; to name and nominate the same high Colle&bholigct;ors of every of the said Subsidies, shall ymediatelie uppon
their nominacion and eleccion, take by authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, sufficient Recognizances or Obligacions,
without any Fee or reward to be paid therefore, of every &bhopubr;son so by them to be named to be high Colle&bholigct;ors,
to be bound to the King&bholngs; Majestie in the double s&bhooov;me of the s&bhooov;me of his colleccion, and to be indorsed and made
uppon such condicion, that is to saie, for the colleccion of the payment of the said first Subsidie: That if the said
Colle&bholigct;or his Heires or Executors doe trulie content and pay to the use of the King&bholngs; Majestie, his Heires or Successors
in the receipt of the said Exchequer, at or before the last day of O&bholigct;ober, next ensuing, so much of the said s&bhooov;me
of money allotted and appointed to his colleccion, as hee shall colle&bholigct;s and gather, and content and pay the residue
of his colleccion and charge within one moneth next after such tyme, as hee hath colle&bholigct;ed and gathered the same
residue, that then the saide Recognizances or Obligacions to be void, or els to stand in full strength and vertue,
And for the colleccion of the said second Subsidie, uppon condicion, That if the said Colle&bholigct;or his heires or
executors doe trulie content and pay to the use of the King&bholngs; Majestie his Heires or Successors in his receipt of
Exchequer, at or before the said last day of Aprill which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God, one thousand six
hundred twentie and sixe, so much of the said s&bhooov;me of mony allotted and appointed to his colleccion, as he shall
colle&bholigct; and gather, and content and pay the residue of his colleccion&amp; charge within one moneth next after such
tyme, as he hath colle&bholigct;ed and gathered the same residue, that then the said Recognizances or Obligacions to be
void, or els to stand in full force and vertue: Which said severall Recognizances or Obligacions so taken, the said
C&bhooov;missioners shall severallie certifie and deliver into the King&bholngs; Majesties Exchequer with the severall Certificates of
the said Taxacions and Rates of the payment of the said Subsidies, at and by the tyme to them &bhopcrl;scribed and appointed
by this A&bholigct;, for the certificate of the said severall Taxacions of the said Subsidies, uppon paine of forfeiture of ten
pound&bholngs; to the King&bholngs; Majestie for every such Recognizance or Obligacion not so certified, And that every such
Colle&bholigct;or so ele&bholigct;ed named and chosen uppon request to him made, shall knowledge and make the said Recognizance
or Obligacion, uppon paine and forfeiture of twentie pound&bholngs; to the King&bholngs; Majestie for the refusall thereof; And
that the Treasurer and Barons of the Exchequer for the tyme being uppon payment of the said severall colleccions
of the Subsidies at the daies and tymes herein lymitted for the payment thereof shall cancell and deliver the
Recognizances or Obligacions for the payment thereof to the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors without any other warrant,
and without any fee or reward to be paid for the same to any &bhopubr;son. And every Colle&bholigct;or so deputed, having the
said Estreat in parchment as is aforesaid, shall have authoritie by this A&bholigct; to appoint daies and places within the
circuit of his colleccion, for the payment of the said Subsidies to him to be made and thereof to give warning by
&bhopcrl;clamacion or otherwise, to all the Constables or other &bhopubr;sons or inhabitants, having the charge of the particular
colleccion within the Hundreds, Parishes, Townes, or other places by him or them lymited, to make payment for
the said particuler colleccion of every s&bhouov;me as to them shall appertayne. And if at the same day and place so
lymitted and &bhopcrl;fixed by the said high Colle&bholigct;or, the said Constable Officers, or other &bhopubr;sons or inhabitants as is
aforesaid, for the said particuler colleccion assigned and appointed within such Hundred Citie Towne or other place
do not pay unto the said high Colle&bholigct;ors, the some within their severall Hundreds, Townes, Parishes, and other
places due and comprised in the said Estreat thereof, to them delivered by the said C&bhooov;missioners or s&bhooov;me of them as
is aforesaid, or so much thereof as they have by any meanes received two pence for every pound for the said
particuler colleccion as is aforesaid, alwaies thereof to be allowed, excepted, and abated, that then it shalbe lawfull
to the said high colle&bholigct;ors and every of them and to their assignes, to distraine every of the said Constables
Officers and other inhabitants for their said severall and particuler colleccion of the said s&bhooov;mes comprised in the said
Estreat and writing thereof to them and every of them as is before expressed, delivered or for so much of the same
s&bhooov;me, as so then shall happen to be gathered and levied, and behinde and unpaid, by the good&bholngs; and chattell&bholngs; of
every of them so being behinde, and the distresse so taken, to be kept and appraised and sold as is aforesaid, and
thereof to take and levie the s&bhooov;mes so then being behinde and unpaid, and the overplus c&bhooov;ming of the sale of the said
distresse (if any be) to be restored and delivered unto the owner in for me above remembred.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Persons having been Colle&bholigct;ors of First Subsidy not to be appointed Colle&bholigct;ors of Second Subsidy, unless they shew Quietus est. Penalty &pound;100.</head>
			<para id="p43">Provided alwaies, and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, That no &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons shalbe nominated or
appointed to be a high Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors for the second Subsidie, graunted by this A&bholigct;e, which before that
tyme hath bene a Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors for the first Subsidie, unlesse such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons so to be nominated and
appointed high Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors for the said second Subsidie, doe first shew forth before him or them by
whome he shalbe nominated and appointed, his Quietus est for his discharge of his colleccion before appointed to
his charge, uppon paine of one hundred pound&bholngs; to be paid and forfeited by him or them that so shall nominate
and appoint any such Colle&bholigct;or contrary to this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Persons living in Cities,&amp;c. not to be appointed Colle&bholigct;ors or Assessors out of them.</head>
			<para id="p44">Provided alwaies that no &bhopubr;son inhabiting in any City. Borough or Towne corporate, shalbe compelled to be any
Assessor or Colle&bholigct;or, of or for any part of the said Subsidies, in any place or places out of the said City, Borough
or Towne corporate, where he dwelleth.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Assessors, Attornies, Fa&bholigct;ors,&amp;c. after being charged with Receipt of Assessment, dying or removing or concealing their Good&bholngs;,</head>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">or when Monies comprised in Estreat cannot be levied by Distress; or where Distress cannot be sold; Process out of the Exchequer, and the Commissioners may dire&bholigct; Precepts to Officer to levy such Money.; Who may distrain.; Distress appraised and sold.; If Distress taken out of Limit assigned, Allowance</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p46">And it is also by the said authoritie ena&bholigct;ed, That if any Inhabitants or Officers, or whatsoever &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons
charged to and for the colleccion and receipt of any part or porcion of the said Subsidies by any manner of meanes
according to this A&bholigct;, or any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons for themselves, or as Keep, Guardian, Deputie, Fa&bholigct;or or Attorny,
of or for anie other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons for any good&bholngs; or chattell&bholngs; of the owner thereof, at the tyme of the said assessing
to be paid being out of this Realme, or in any other part&bholngs; not knowen, or of and for the good&bholngs; and chattell
of any other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons of any corporacion, Fraternitie, Misterie or other whatsoever C&bhooov;monaltie, being corporate
or not corporate, and all &bhopubr;sons having in their rule, governance and custodie any good&bholngs; or Chattell&bholngs; at the tyme
of the said assessing, or any of them to be made, or which for anie cause, for and by colleccion, or for himselfe, or
for any other, or by reason that he hath the rule, governance, or custodie of any good&bholngs; or chattell&bholngs; of any other
&bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons, Corporacion, C&bhooov;monaltie, Fraternitie, Guild or Misterie, or any such other like, or as Fa&bholigct;or,
Deputie or attorney of or for any &bhopubr;son, shalbe taxed valued rated and set, to any s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes by reason of
this A&bholigct;e, and after the taxacion and assessing uppon any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons, as shalbe charged with the receipt
of the same, happen to die or depart from the place where he was so taxed and set, or his good&bholngs; or chattell&bholngs; to be
so eloined, or in such privie or covert manner kept, as the said &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons charged with the same by Estreats
or other writings from the said C&bhooov;missioners, or as many of them as shalbe thereunto appointed by the said C&bhooov;mission
as is aforesaid, can, ne may levie the same s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes comprised within the same Estreats, by distresse within
the Lymitts of their colleccion, as is aforesaid, or cannott sell such distresse or distresses as be taken for any of the
said payments before the tyme lymited to the high Colle&bholigct;or for his payment to be made in the King&bholngs; Majesties
Receipt, then uppon relacion thereof, with due examinacion by the oath or examinacion of such &bhopubr;son. or &bhopubr;sons as
shalbe charged with and for the receipt and colleccion of the same before the said C&bhooov;missioners, or as many of
them, as by the said C&bhooov;mission shalbe thereunto appointed, where such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons, or other, as is aforesaid, their
Good&bholngs; and Chattell&bholngs; were set and taxed, and uppon plaine Certificate thereof made into the King&bholngs; Majesties
Exchequer by the same C&bhooov;missioners, as well of the dwelling place names and s&bhooov;mes of the said &bhopubr;sons of whome the
same s&bhooov;mes cannott be levied and had as is aforesaid: Then as well the Constable and other Inhabitants appointed
for the same particuler colleccion against the high Colle&bholigct;ors, as the high Colle&bholigct;or uppon his account and Oath in
the said Exchequer, to be discharged thereof, and &bhopcrl;cesse to be made for the King&bholngs; Majestie out of the same Exchequer
by the discrecion of the Barons of the same Exchequer against such &bhopubr;son his Heires or Executors so being behinde
with his payment. And over that the same C&bhooov;missioners, to whome any such declaracion of the &bhopcrl;misses shalbe
made in forme aforesaid from tyme to tyme, shall have full power and authoritie to dire&bholigct; their &bhopcrl;cept or &bhopcrl;cepts
to the said &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons charged with any s&bhooov;me, of for and uppon any such &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons or other as is
aforesaid, or to any Sheriffe, Steward, Bailiffe or other whatsoever Officer Minister, &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons of such place
or places, where any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons so owing any such s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes shall have Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; and
other Hereditament&bholngs; or reall possessions, good&bholngs; and chattell&bholngs;, whereby any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons so indebted, his
Heires Executors or Assignes, or other having the Custodie governance or disposicion of any good&bholngs; or chattell&bholngs;,
land&bholngs; tenement&bholngs; or other Hereditament&bholngs; which ought or may by this A&bholigct; be lawfully distreyned or taken for the
same hath and shall have good&bholngs; chattell&bholngs; landes tenement&bholngs; or other possessions, whereof such s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes, which
by any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons may or ought to be levied, be it within the lymitts of such C&bhooov;mission, where such &bhopubr;son
or &bhopubr;sons was or were taxed or without in any place within this Realme of England, Wales, or other the King&bholngs;
Majesties Dominions Marches or Territories, by which &bhopcrl;cept, aswell such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons shalbe charged to levie such
monie, as the Officer of the place or places where such distresse may be taken, shall have full power and authoritie
to distreyne every such &bhopubr;son indebted, charged or chargeable by this A&bholigct;, or his Executors or Administrators of his
Goodes and Chattell&bholngs;, his Guardians, Fa&bholigct;ors, Deputies, Leassees, Farmors, and Assignes, and all other &bhopubr;sons, by
whose hand&bholngs;, or out of whose land&bholngs; any such &bhopubr;son should have Fee, Rent, A$$$uitie, or other proffitt, or which at
the tyme of the said assessing shall have good&bholngs; or chattell&bholngs;, or any other thing moveable of any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons
being indebted or owing such s&bhouov;me, and the distresses so taken, cause to be kept appraised and sold in like manner
and forme, as is aforesaid, for the distresse to be taken uppon such &bhopubr;sons to be taxed to the said Subsidies, and being
sufficient to distreyne within the lymitts of the Colle&bholigct;ors, Inhabitants or other officers charged with or for the said
s&bhooov;mes so uppon them to be taxed. And if any such distresse for non payment happen to be taken out of the lymitt</para>
			<para id="p47">
				<emph type="i">Persons charged discharged by Distress.; Persons distrained having no Lands,&amp;c.; Proceedings.; Imprisonment until Sums due, and also Fee for Arrest paid.; Officer not executing Process.; Penalty 2cs.; Gaoler suffering Escape.; Penalty 40s. and Double Value of Rate and Fees.; Like Process for Subsidies due by any Person charged for another unpaid.; In Default of Payment Imprisonment.; Certificate by Commissioners.; Colle&bholigct;ors,&amp;c.; disobeying Commissioners.; Persons suspe&bholigct;ed to be not indifferently taxed refusing to appear or be examined,; Penalty 40s. or under, at Discretion of Commissioners.; Commissioners may punish by Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p48">of the said &bhopubr;sons charged and assigned to levie the said &bhopubr;sons so charged for the levying of any such s&bhooov;mes by distresse,
shall &bhopcrl;ceive and take of the same distresse, for the labour of every &bhopubr;son going for the execucion thereof, for every
mile that every &bhopubr;son so laboureth for the same, two pence, And every Farmor, Guardian, Tenant, Fa&bholigct;or, or other
whatsoever &bhopubr;son being distreyned, or other &bhopubr;son charged for [the<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] payment of any such s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes or any
other s&bhooov;me by reason of this A&bholigct;, shalbe of such s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of him or them so levied and taken, discharged
and acquited at his next day of payment for the same, or at the delivery of such Good&bholngs; and Chattell&bholngs; as he
that is so distreyned, had in his custodie or governance against him or them that shalbe so taxed&amp; set. Any
Graunt or Writing obligatorie, or other whatsoever, matter to the contrary made heretofore notwithstanding. And
if any such &bhopubr;son that should so be distreyned have no Land&bholngs; or Tenement&bholngs; sufficient, whereby he and his Tenants
and Farmors may be distreyned, or have aliened eloyned, or hid his Good&bholngs; and Chattell&bholngs; whereby he should
or might be distreyned, in such manner that such good&bholngs; or chattell&bholngs; should not be knowen or found, so that the
s&bhooov;me of or by him to be paid in the said forme, shall not, ne can be convenientlie levied, then uppon relacion
thereof to the C&bhooov;missioners, or to as many of them as by the said C&bhooov;mission shalbe thereunto appointed where
such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons was taxed and sett by the oathes of him or them that shalbe charged with the levying and
payment of that s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes, the same C&bhooov;missioners shall make a &bhopcrl;cept in such manner as is aforesaid, for to
attach take and arrest the body of such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons, that ought to pay the said s&bhooov;mes, and by this A&bholigct; shalbe
charged with and for the said s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes, and them so taken safelie to keepe in prison within the Shire or
other place where any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons shalbe taken and attached, there to remaine without baile or Mainsprise
untill he hath paid the said s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes, that such &bhopubr;son for himselfe or for any other by this A&bholigct; shalbe chargeable,
or ought to be charged withall, and also for the Fees of every such Arrest, to him or them that shall execute such
&bhopcrl;cept, twentie pence; And that every Officer, unto whome such &bhopcrl;cept shalbe dire&bholigct;ed doe his true diligence and
execute the same uppon every &bhopubr;son so being indebted, upon paine to forfeite to the King&bholngs; Majestie for every default
in that behalfe, twentie shillings. And that no keep of any Gaole, from his Gaole suffer any such &bhopubr;son to goe at
large, by letting to Baile, or otherwise to depart out of his prison before he have paid his said debt, and the said
twentie pence for his Arrest, upon paine to forfeit to the King&bholngs; Majestie fortie shillings: And the same Gaoler to
pay to the King&bholngs; Majestie the double value as well of the rate, which the said &bhopubr;son so imprisoned was taxed at, as
of the said twentie pence for the fees. And like &bhopcrl;cesse and remedie in like forme shalbe graunted by the said
C&bhooov;missioners or as many of them as by the said C&bhooov;mission shalbe thereunto appointed at like Informacion of every
&bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons being charged with any s&bhooov;me of mony for any other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons by reason of the said Subsidies,
and not thereof paid, but willfully withdrawen, nor the same leviable within the lymitts where such &bhopubr;sons were
thereunto taxed. And if the s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes being behind unpaid by any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons as is aforesaid, be levied and
gathered by force of the said &bhopcrl;cesse to be made by the said C&bhooov;missioners, or if in default or for lacke of payment
thereof, the &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons so owing the said s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes of mony, by &bhopcrl;cesse of the same C&bhooov;missioners to be
made, as is aforesaid, be c&bhooov;mitted to prison in forme abovesaid, that then the said C&bhooov;missioners, which shall award
such &bhopcrl;ces shall make Certificate thereof in the said Exchequer of that shalbe done in the &bhopcrl;misses in the Terme
next following after such s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of mony, so being behinde shalbe levied and gathered, or such &bhopubr;son or
&bhopubr;sons for non payment of the same, c&bhooov;mitted to prison. And if it happen any of the said Colle&bholigct;ors to be assigned,
or any Maiors, Sheriffs, Stewards, Constables, the Headborough, Bursholder, Bayliffe or any other Officer or
Minister, or other whatsoever &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons to disobey the said C&bhooov;missioners, or any of them in the reasonable
request to them made by the said Commissioners for the execucion of the said C&bhooov;mission, or if any of the Officers,
or other &bhopubr;sons d&oacute;e refuse that to them shall appertaine and belong to doe by reason of anie &bhopcrl;cept to him or them
to be dire&bholigct;ed, or any reasonable c&bhooov;maundement instance or request touching the &bhopcrl;misses or other default in any
appearance or colleccion to make, or if any &bhopubr;son being suspe&bholigct;ed not to be indifferentlie taxed, as is aforesaid, doe
refuse to be examined according to the tenor of this A&bholigct; before the said C&bhooov;missioners, or as many of them as shalbe
thereunto assigned, as is aforesaid, or will not appeare before the said C&bhooov;missioners upon warning to him made, or
else make resistance or rescues upon any distresse, upon him to be taken for anie parcell of the said Subsidies, or
committ any misbehavior in any manner of wise contrarie to this A&bholigct; or c&bhooov;mitt any willfull omission, or other
whatsoever willfull doing or misdoing contrary to the tenor of this A&bholigct; or Graunte; The same C&bhooov;missioners, and
every nomber of them above remembred or two of them at the least uppon probable knowledge of any such
misdemeanors had by Informacion or Examinacion, shall and may sett upon every such offendor for every such
offence in the name of a Fyne by the same offendor to be forfeited, fortie shillings or under, by discrecion of the
same C&bhooov;missioners. And further the said C&bhooov;missioners and every nomber of them or two of them at the least, shall
have authoritie by this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;, to punish every such offender by imprisonment, there to remaine and to be delivered
by their discrecion,<ref idref="n16">16</ref> as shall seeme to them convenient, the said Fynes (if any such be) to be certified by the said
C&bhooov;missioners that so assessed the same into the King&bholngs; Majesties Exchequer there to be levied and paid by the
Colle&bholigct;ors of that part for the said Subsidies retorned into the said Exchequer to be therewith charged with the
payment of the said Subsidies in such manner as if the said Fines had bene sett and taxed uppon the said offenders
for the said Subsidies.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Allowance to High Colle&bholigct;ors and their Accountants.</head>
			<para id="p49">
				<emph type="i">Allowance to be paid by Colle&bholigct;ors to Commissioners for Expences and Labours of their Clerks.; Remedy for the same for Commissioners against Colle&bholigct;ors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p50">And be it also ena&bholigct;ed by the said authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament That every of the said high Colle&bholigct;ors,
which shall account for any part of the said Subsidies in the said Exchequer uppon their severall accounts to be
yeilded, shalbe allowed at every of the said payments of the said Subsidies for every pound lymited to his colleccion,
whereof any such Colle&bholigct;or shalbe charged and yeild account, sixe pence as parcell of their charge, that is to saie,
of every pound thereof for such &bhopubr;sons as then have had the particuler colleccion of the Townes and other places
as is aforesaid specified in his colleccion, two pence and other two pence of every pound thereof, every of the said
cheife Colle&bholigct;ors, or their Accomptants to retaine to their owne use, for their labour and charge in and about the
&bhopcrl;misses, and two pence of everie pound residue, to be delivered allowed and paid by the said Colle&bholigct;or so being
thereof. allowed, to such of the C&bhooov;missioners, as shall take uppon them the busines and labour for and about the
&bhopcrl;misses, that is to saie, Every Colle&bholigct;or to pay that C&bhooov;missioner or C&bhooov;missioners, which had the ordering of the
writings of and for every of the said Subsidies, where the said Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors had their colleccion, for the
expences for the said C&bhooov;missioners, so taking uppon them the said businesse, and labour of their Clarkes writing
the said &bhopcrl;cepts and Ext<emph type="p">a</emph>cts of the said Colleccions, the said last two pence of every pound to be devided amongest
the said C&bhooov;missioners, having regard to their labour and busines taken by them and their said Clarkes in and about
the &bhopcrl;misses, for which part, so to the said C&bhooov;missioners appertayning, the said C&bhooov;missioners six, five, foure, three,
or two, or as many of them as shalbe thereunto appointed by the Kinges Majesties C&bhooov;mission, and every of them
joyntlie and severallie for his and their said part, may have his remedie against the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors, which
thereof byn or might have bin allowed by accion of debt, in which the Defendant shall not wage his Lawe, neither
Proteccion, neither Injunccion or Essoine shalbe allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Commissioners,&amp;c. not compellable to make Presentments other than to Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p51">And that no &bhopubr;son, now being of the nomber of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, nor any C&bhooov;missioner shalbe named or
assigned to be any Colle&bholigct;or or Subcolle&bholigct;or or Presenter of the said Subsidies, or any part thereof, nor any
C&bhooov;missioners shalbe compelled to make any &bhopcrl;sentment or Certificate, other then [into<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] the King&bholngs; Majesties said
Exchequer, of for or concerning the said Subsidies, or any part or parcell thereof. And likewise that no other
&bhopubr;son that shalbe named and assigned to be C&bhooov;missioners in any place to and for the execucion of this A&bholigct; of
Subsidies, be or shalbe assigned or named head Colle&bholigct;or of any of the Payments of the said Subsidies [neither<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] of
any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Head Colle&bholigct;ors for First Subsidy not compellable to be Colle&bholigct;ors of Second Subsidy.</head>
			<para id="p52">
				<emph type="i">Taking Fees of Accountants.; Penalty.; Imprisonment.; Commissioners at Meetings to shew Certificates and Presentments to the other Commissioners.; Indenture of Colle&bholigct;ors Names and of Sums written to Colle&bholigct;ors, Fines.&amp;c. to be certified by Commissioners into the Exchequer.; Colle&bholigct;ors answerable for their own Colle&bholigct;ion only</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p53">And that every such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;son which shalbe named and appointed as is aforesaid to be head Colle&bholigct;ors of
and for the payment of the said first Subsidie, or of any part thereof, shall not be compelled to be Colle&bholigct;or for
the payment of the said second Subsidie nor any part thereof. . And the said Colle&bholigct;ors which shalbe assigned for
the colleccion of the said two Subsidies, or of any part thereof and every of them, be and shalbe acquited and
discharged of all manner Fees and Rewards and of every other charge in the King&bholngs; Majesties Exchequer, or elswhere,
of them, or any of them by reason of that colleccion payment or accompt, or any thing con&bhoccrl;ning the same to
be asked, And that if any &bhopubr;son receive or take any Fees, Rewards or pleasures of any such Accomptants, or use
any unnecessary delay in their accompt, that then he shall forfeit to the King&bholngs; Majestie for every penny or value
of every pennyworth so taken, five shillings, and five pound&bholngs; to the partie greived for every such delay, and suffer
imprisonment at the Kinges Majesties pleasure. And after every taxing and assessing of the said severall Subsidies
(as is aforesaid) had or made, and the said ext<emph type="p">a</emph>cts thereof in Parchment, unto the Colle&bholigct;or in manner and forme
before rehearsed, delivered, The said C&bhooov;missioners, which shall take uppon them the execucion of this A&bholigct;e within
the limitts of their C&bhooov;mission by their agreements, shall have meetings together, At which meeting every of the
said C&bhooov;missioners, which then shall have taken uppon them the execucion of any part of the said C&bhooov;mission, shall
by himselfe or his sufficient Deputie trulie certifie and bring forth unto the said C&bhooov;missioners named in the said
C&bhooov;mission, the Certificate and Presentment made before him and such other C&bhooov;missioners as were lymitted with him
in one limitt, so as the same certificate may be accompted and cast with the other Certificates of the other limitts
within the same C&bhooov;mission, and then the said C&bhooov;missioners and every nomber of them, unto two at the least, as is
aforesaid, if any be in life, or their Executors or Administrators of their good&bholngs;, if they then be dead, shall joyntlie
and severallie as they were divided within their lymitts under their seales, by their discrecion make one or severall
writings indented, contayning in itt aswell the names of the said Colle&bholigct;ors by the C&bhooov;missioners for such colleccions
and accounts in the Exchequer and payments in the said receipt, deputed and assigned, as the grosse and severall
s&bhooov;mes written unto every such Colle&bholigct;ors to receive the said Subsidies, and also all Fynes, Amerciaments, and other
Forfeitures, if any such by reason of this A&bholigct;e, happen to be within the limitt and &bhopcrl;cin&bholigct; of their C&bhooov;mission, to be
certified into the King&bholngs; Majesties said Exchequer by the said C&bhooov;missioners. In which writing or writings indented
so to be certified, shalbe plainelie declared and expressed the whole and entire s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of the said Subsidies
severally lymited to the colle&bholigct;ion of the said Colle&bholigct;ors, severally deputed and assigned to the said s&bhooov;mes, Soe as
none of the said Colle&bholigct;ors, so certified in the said Exchequer, shalbe compelled there to account, or to be charged,
but onelie to and for the s&bhooov;mes lymitted to his colleccion, and not to or for any s&bhooov;me lymited to the colleccion of
his fellowes: But every of them shalbe severallie charged for their, part lymited to their Colleccion.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Commissioners, if they cannot agree,&amp;c. may make several Indentures.</head>
			<para id="p54">
				<emph type="i">Colle&bholigct;ors not chargeable for other Colle&bholigct;ors.; Commissioners or Colle&bholigct;ors or Persons taxed, dying before discharged, Heirs and Executors chargeable as such Persons would have been if alive</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p55">And if the said C&bhooov;missioners joyned in one C&bhooov;mission amongest themselves in that matter cannott agree, or if any
of them be not ready, or refuse, to make certificate with other of the same C&bhooov;missioners, that then the said
C&bhooov;missioners may make severall Indentures [in forme<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] aforesaid, of their, sev[ers]all lymitts or separacions of Colle&bholigct;ors
within the limitts of their C&bhooov;mission, uppon and in the Hundreds, Wards, Wapentakes, Rapes, or such other like
divisions, within the said severall lymitts of their C&bhooov;mission, as the places there shall require to be severed and
divided, and as to the same C&bhooov;missioners shall seeme good to make divisions or other lymitts or Colleccions, for
the severall charges of the same Colle&bholigct;ors, so that alway one Colle&bholigct;or shalbe charged, and account for his part to
him to be lymitted onely by himselfe, and not for any some lymitted to the part of any of his fellowes: And the
charges of every of the colle&bholigct;ors to be set and certified severally uppon them. And every such Colle&bholigct;or uppon
his account and payment of the s&bhooov;me of monie lymited within [his<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] colleccion to be severallie by himselfe acquited
and discharged in the said Exchequer without paying any manner Fees or Rewards to any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons for the
same, upon paine and Penaltie last abovesaid, and not to be charged for any porcion of any other Colle&bholigct;or. And
if any C&bhooov;missioner after he hath taken certificate of them, that, as is aforesaid, shalbe before any C&bhooov;missioners
exaied and the s&bhooov;mes rated and set, and the bookes and writings thereof being in his handv, or if any Colle&bholigct;or
or other &bhopubr;son charged with anie receipt of anie part of the said Subsidies, or any other &bhopubr;son taxed or otherwise
by this A&bholigct; charged with or for any parcell of the said Subsidies, or with any other s&bhooov;me Fine An&bhotcrl;ciament Penaltie,
or other Forfeiture, happen to die before the C&bhooov;missioners Colle&bholigct;or or other whatsoever &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons have
executed, accomplished satisfied, or sufficientlie discharged that, to which every such &bhopubr;son shall appertaine or belong
to doe according to this A&bholigct;, Then the Executors and Heires of every such &bhopubr;son, and all other seized of any Land&bholngs;
and Tenement&bholngs; that any such &bhopubr;son being charged by this A&bholigct; and deceasing before he be discharged thereof, or
any other to his use onelie, had of an Estate of Inheritance at the tyme that any such &bhopubr;son was named C&bhooov;missioner,
Colle&bholigct;or, or otherwise charged with or for any manner of thing to be done satisfied or paid by reason of this A&bholigct;.
And all those that have in their possession or hand&bholngs; any Good&bholngs;, Chattell&bholngs;, Leases, or other thing&bholngs; that were to
any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons at the time of his death, or any Land&bholngs; or Tenement&bholngs; that were the same &bhopubr;sons at the time
that he was, as is aforesaid, charged by this A&bholigct; shalbe by the same compelled and charged to doe, and accomplish
in every case, as the same &bhopubr;son so being charged should have done, or might have byn compelled to doe, if he
had bene in plaine life, after such rate of the Land&bholngs; and Good&bholngs; of the said C&bhooov;missioner or Colle&bholigct;or, as the partie
shall have in his Hand&bholngs;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Commissioners not thinking fit to join in one Certificate Proceedings.</head>
			<para id="p56">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners making Default of Certificate, Process out of Exchequer against them</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p57">And if the said C&bhooov;missioners for causes reasonable them moving, shall thinke it not fitt to joyne in one Certificate,
as is aforesaid, then the said &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons, that shall first joyne together, or hee that shall first certifie the said
writing indented as is aforesaid, shall certifie all the names of the C&bhooov;missioners of that C&bhooov;mission, whereuppon such
writing shalbe there then to be certified, with division of the Hundreds, Wapentakes, Wards, Tything&bholngs;, and other
places, to and among such C&bhooov;missioners of the same C&bhooov;mission, with the names of the said C&bhooov;missioners, where such
Separacions and Divisions shalbe, with the grosse s&bhooov;mes of money, aswell of and for the said Subsidies taxed or
set, of or within the said Hundreds, Wards, Wapentakes, or other places to him or them divided or assigned, that
shall so certifie the said first Writings, as of the Fines, Amerciaments, Penalties and other Forfeitures, if any happen
to be within the same Limitts, whereof the same writings shalbe certified: And after such writings indented, which,
as is aforesaid, shalbe certified, and not contayne in it the whole and full s&bhooov;mes set and taxed within the Limits
of the same C&bhooov;mission, the other C&bhooov;missioners of the same, before the day of payment of the said Subsidie, shall
certifie into the said Exchequer, by their writing or writings indented to be made, as is aforesaid, the grosse and
severall s&bhooov;mes, set and taxed within the places to them limited, for every of the said Subsidies, and other fines,
an&bhotcrl;ciaments, penalties and forfeiture, with the names of the [Hundreds,<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] Wards, Wapentakes, and other Places
to them assigned, or else by their said writings indented, to certifie at the same place, before the same day of
payment, such reasonable causes for their excuses, why they may not make such certificate of and for the said
Subsidies Fines Amerciaments and other forfeitures growing or set by reason of the causes of their lets, or of their
not certifying, as is aforesaid, or else in default thereof, &bhopcrl;cesse to be made out of the King&bholngs; Majesties said Exchequer,
against the said C&bhooov;missioners, and every of them not making certificate, as is aforesaid, by the discrecion of the
Tresurer and Barons of the said Exchequer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Proviso for Stamford Baron.</head>
			<para id="p58">Provided alwaies, and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, That the inhabitants of the Parishe of Saint
Martine called Stamford Baron in the Suburbs of the Borough and Towne of Stamford, in the South part [of<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] the
waters there, called Welland&bholngs;, which hereafter shalbe contributory to the payment of these &bhopcrl;sent Subsidies, graunted
to the King&bholngs; Majestie, his Heires and Successors, shalbe assessed, rated, and taxed for the same, by such C&bhooov;missioners,
which shalbe appointed for the taxing, rating, and sessing of the same Subsidies within the Countie of Lincolne,
and shalbe for the same contributorie, and pay the said Subsidies, to the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors, which shalbe
assigned and appointed for the levying and gathering of the same, with the Aldermen and Burgesses of the same
Borough and Towne of Stamford.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Persons having Spiritual and Temporal Possessions, and also Personal Property, not to be doubly charged.</head>
			<para id="p59">Provided alwaies, and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, That all and every &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons
having Mannors Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs;,. and other Hereditament&bholngs; chargeable to the payment of the said Subsidies
graunted to the King&bholngs; Majestie by this A&bholigct;e, and also having Spirituall possessions chargeable to his said Majestie
by anie graunt made or to be made by the Clergie of this Realme in their Convocacion, and over this, having substance
in good&bholngs; and chattell&bholngs; chargeable by this said A&bholigct;e, that then, if any of the said &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons be hereafter charged,
assessed and taxed for the said Mannors Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs;, and Spirituall possessions, and also charged assessed
and taxed for his and their good&bholngs; and chattell&bholngs;, that then he or they shalbe onelie charged by vertue of this A&bholigct;
for his and their said Mannors Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; Hereditament&bholngs; and Spirituall possessions, or onelie for his said
good&bholngs; and chattell&bholngs;, the best thereof to be taken for the King&bholngs; Majestie, and not to be charged for both, or double
charged for any of them; Any thing in this A&bholigct; conteyned to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Exception for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey and Guernsey.</head>
			<para id="p60">Provided alwaies, that this graunte of Subsidies, or any thing therein conteyned, in any wise extend not to
charge the Inhabitants dwelling in Scotland, Ireland, Jersey, and Garnesey, or any of them, of, for or concerning
any Mannors, Land&bholngs;, Tenement&bholngs;, or other possessions, good&bholngs;, chattell&bholngs;, or other moveable substance, which the
said Inhabitants or dwellers, or any others to their use have within Scotland, Ireland, Jersey and Garnesey, or in
any of them, or of, for, or concerning any Fees or Wages, which any of the said Inhabitants or dwellers have of
the King&bholngs; Majestie for their attendance and doing service to our Soveraigne Lord the King&bholngs; Majestie in Scotland,
Ireland, Jersey and Garnesey, or in any of them. Any thing in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Exception for English Inhabitants of Berwick-upon-Tweed.</head>
			<para id="p61">Provided also, That this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; of Subsidies, ne any thing therein conteyned, extend to any of the English
Inhabitants or resiants in the Towne of Berwicke, for or concerning any Mannors, Land&bholngs;, Tenement&bholngs;, or other
possessions, goodes, chattell&bholngs;, or other moveable substance, which the same English Inhabitants or dwellers, or any
other to their use, have within the said Towne of Berwick, or for or concerning any Fees or wages, which any of
the English inhabitants or dwellers have of the King&bholngs; Majestie for their attendance or doing service to the King&bholngs;
Majestie, for, or, within the said Towne, but that the English inhabitants and resiants, and every of them shalbe
of, and from the said Subsidies, and every parcell thereof, onelie for their said Mannors, Land&bholngs;, Tenement&bholngs;, Fees,
Wages, Good&bholngs;, and Chattell&bholngs;, lying and being in the said Towne of Berwicke, utterlie acquitted and discharged,
Any thing in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; before rehearsed to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Proviso for Patents of Liberties,&amp;c. to Cities,&amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p62">Provided also, that all l[ia]res Patents graunted by the King&bholngs; Majestie, or any of his most noble Progenitors, to
any Cities, Boroughes, or Townes within this Realme, of any manner of Liberties Priviledges or exempcions from
the burthen and charge of any such graunt&bholngs; of Subsidies, which be at this &bhopcrl;sent tyme in force and availeable, shall
remaine good and effe&bholigct;uall to the said Cities, Boroughes, and Townes hereafter according to the purports thereof,
although the Inhabitants of the same, and also the said Corporacions, shall uppon the great and weightie
consideracions of the Graunte aforesaid, be for this Graunt charged and contributorie in like manner forme and sort,
as other Cities, Boroughes, and Townes, which be not in any wise priviledged, but by this A&bholigct; charged.</para>
			<para id="p63">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Orphans and Infants</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p64">Provided alwaies, and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid,' That no Orphan or Infant within the age of one
and twentie yeares, borne within any of the King&bholngs; Majesties Dominions, shalbe charged to any payment of these
Subsidies, for his or their Good&bholngs; and chattell&bholngs; to him or her left or bequeathed. Any thing in this A&bholigct; contayned
to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Proviso for Universities of Oxford and Cambridge and Winchester College and Eaton College and the poor Knights of Windsor and Free Schools and Readers,&amp;c. in the Universities of Oxford and Cambridge and for Hospitals,&amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p65">Provided also that this A&bholigct;, nor any thing therein contayned, shall extend to the land&bholngs; or good&bholngs; of any Colledge,
Hall or Hostell, within the Univ[er]sities of Oxford and Cambridge, or any of them, or to the Good&bholngs; or Land&bholngs; of
the Colledge of Winton founded by Bishopp Wickham, or to the good&bholngs; or land&bholngs; of the Colledge of Eaton next
Windsor, or to the Land&bholngs;, Tenement&bholngs;, or revenues onelie assigned and appointed for the sustentacion and living
of the poore Knights founded in the Castle or Colledge of Windsor by our late Soveraigne Lord King Henry the
eight, or to any the Good&bholngs; or Chattell&bholngs; of the same Knights or any of them, or to the Good&bholngs; or land&bholngs; of any
c&bhooov;mon free Grammar Schoole within the Realme of England or Wales, or to the good&bholngs; of any Reader Schoolemaster
or Scholler, or any Graduate or Resiant, or remayning for studie without fraude or covin within any the said
Univ[er]sities and Colledges or townes of Oxford and Cambridge, or Suburbes of the same, or to any of them, or to
any their servants attending dailie uppon any of them, nor to the good&bholngs; of any Officer Minister Almes men or
servants belonging to any of the said Univ[er]sities, Colledges, Halls, or Hostells, and dwelling and resiant within
the said Univ[er]sities, or either of them, or within either of the said Townes of Oxford and Cambridge&amp; the Suburbes
of the same without fraude or covin, or to the good&bholngs;, and land&bholngs; of any Hospitall, Maisondieu, or Spittle house
&bhopcrl;pared and used for the sustentacion and releife of poore people, Any thing in this A&bholigct; contayned to the contrary
in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. Inhabitants of Cinque Ports for the most part of the Year before the Grant chargeable during Resiance only.</head>
			<para id="p66">Provided also, and be it further ena&bholigct;ed, that the said Grant of Subsidies, or any thing therein contayned, doe
not in any wise extend or be &bhopcrl;judiciall or hurtfull to any of the inhabitants or resiants having dwelt for the
most part of the yeare next before the taxing and assessing of the said Subsidies as aforesaid, within the five ports
corporate, or to anie their members incorporated, or united to the said five Ports, or to anie of the said five Ports,
but that such the inhabitants or Resiants as aforesaid, in the said five Ports corporate, and their members, be and
shalbe of and from the said Graunt and payment of every of the said Subsidies, and every part thereof, and onelie
during their resiance as aforesaid, and no longer, clearelie acquited and discharged, Any matter or whatsoever thing
in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; had or made to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. Proviso for Inhabitants of Rumney Marsh.</head>
			<para id="p67">Provided also that the said Grant of Subsidies doe not in any wise extend to be &bhopcrl;judiciall or hurtfull to the
English Inhabitants or Resiants at this &bhopcrl;sent tyme within the Liberties of Rumney Marsh, of or for any part of
the said s&bhooov;mes graunted in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, of the said English Inhabitants now there Resiants, or any of
them, to be taxed, set, asked, levied, or paid, but that the said English Inhabitants, and now Resiants of Rumney
Marsh aforesaid and every of them, be and shalbe of and from, the graunt and payment of the said Subsidies during
their [Resiance<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] there, and no longer acquited and discharged, Any matter, and whatsoever thing in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;
made to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Alien or Denizen assigning his Land&bholngs;v,&amp;c. to his Child with Intent to defraud the Subsidy, such Child chargeable as an Alien.</head>
			<para id="p68">Provided neverthelesse, and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, That if any Alien or Straunger borne,
Denizen, or not Denizen, and dwelling and inhabiting within this Realme of England, shall assigne and convey over
unto any his or their childe or children borne within the said Realme of England, any his or their Land&bholngs;, Tenement&bholngs;,
Good&bholngs; or Chattell&bholngs;, to the intent thereby to defraud the King&bholngs; Majestie of his said Subsidies of or for the same,
that then all and every such childe and children, so being seised of any such Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs;, and possessed
of any such good&bholngs; or chattell&bholngs; shalbe charged and chargeable to and with the payment of double the said
Subsidies for the same Land&bholngs;, Tenement&bholngs;, Good&bholngs;, and Chattell&bholngs; at the said rates and values, as Aliens and Straungers,
Denizens, and not Denizens are before limited and appointed to pay.</para>
			
			
			<note id="n1" number="1"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">within this <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">happen then <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">abovesaid <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Subsidie <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Subsedy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Subsidie <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">those <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>			
			<note id="n11" number="11">the like <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>			
			<note id="n12" number="12"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">discre&bhocotil;n <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">s&bhooov;mes of Money <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>			
			<note id="n15" number="15">them <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>			
			<note id="n16" number="16"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">either <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">in the forme <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">this <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">Hundred <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">of of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		  <note id="n23" number="23">1 Resiancie <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


