<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47204" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1627</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. The Peticion Exhibited to His Majestie by the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and C&bhooov;mons in this &bhopcrl;sent
Parliament assembled con&bhoccrl;ning divers Right&bholngs; and Liberties of the Subje&bholigct;&bholngs;: with the King&bholngs; Majesties Royall
Aunswere thereunto in full Parliament.[ Rot. Parl. nu. I.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reciting that by (25) 34 Ed. I. st. 4. c. I. by Authority<ref idref="n1">1</ref> of Parliament holden 25 Ed. III. and by other Laws of this Realm, the King's Subje&bholigct;s should not be taxed but by Consent in Parliament;</head>
		<para id="p1">To the king&bholngs; most Excellent Majestie.<br/>
Humbly shew unto our Soveraigne Lord the King the Lord&bholngs; Spirituall and Temporall and C&bhooov;mons in
Parliament assembled, That whereas it is declared and ena&bholigct;ed by a Statute made in the tyme of the
Raigne of King Edward the first c&bhooov;monly called Statutum de Tallagio non concedendo, That no Tallage or Ayde
should be layd or levyed by the King or his Heires in this Realme without the good will and assent of the Archbishopps
Bishopps Earles Barons Knight&bholngs; Burgesses and other the Freemen of the C&bhooov;monaltie of this Realme, And by
Authoritie of Parliament holden in the five and twentith yeare of the raigne of King Edward the third, it is declared
and ena&bholigct;ed, That from thenceforth no &bhopubr;son should be compelled to make any Loanes to the King against his will
because such Loanes were against reason and the franchise of the Land, And by other Lawes of this Realme it is
&bhopubrc;vided, that none should be charged by any charge or Imposicion called a Benevolence nor by such like Charge by
which the Statutes before mencioned and other the good Lawes and Statutes of this Realme your Subje&bholigct;&bholngs; have
inherited this Freedome That they should [not<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] be compelled to contribute to any Taxe Tallage Ayde or other like
Charge not sett by c&bhooov;mon consent in Parliament.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. and that Commissions have of late issued on which Proceedings have been had contrary to Law.</head>
			<para id="p2">Yet neverthelesse of late divers C&bhooov;missions dire&bholigct;ed to sundry C&bhooov;missioners in severall Counties with Instruccions
have issued, by meanes whereof your people have been in divers places assembled and required to lend certaine s&bhooov;mes
of mony unto your Majestie, and many of them uppon their refusall soe to doe have had an Oath administred unto
them not warrantable by the Lawes or Statutes of this Realme and have been constrayned to become bound to
make apparance and give attendance before your Privie Councell and in other places; and others of them have
been therefore imprisoned confined and sondry other waies molested and disquieted And divers other charges have
been laid and levied upon your people in severall Counties by Lord Lieuten'nt&bholngs; Deputie Lieuten'nt&bholngs; C&bhooov;missioners
for Musters Justices of Peace and others by C&bhooov;and or Direccion from your Majestie or your Privie Councell
against the Lawes and free Customes of the Realme.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Reciting 9 Hen. III. M.C. c. 29.</head>
			<para id="p3">And where alsoe by the Statute called The great Charter of the Liberties of England, It is declared and ena&bholigct;ed, That
no Freeman may be taken or imprisoned or be disseised of his Freehold or Liberties or his free Customes or be outlawed
or exiled or in any manner destroyed, but by the lawfull Judgment of his Peeres or by the Law of the Land.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. 28 Edw. III. c. 3.</head>
			<para id="p4">And in the eight and twentith yeere of the raigne of King Edward the third it was declared and ena&bholigct;ed
by authoritie of Parliament, that no man of what estate or condicion that he be, should be put out of his Land or
Tenement&bholngs; nor taken nor imprisoned nor disherited nor put to death without being brought to aunswere by due
&bhopubrc;cesse of Lawe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. and that divers Subje&bholigct;s have been imprisoned without Cause shewn, or Cause of Detainer certified;</head>
			<para id="p5">Neverthelesse against the tenor of the said Statutes and other the good Lawes and Statutes of your Realme
to that end &bhopubrc;vided, divers of your Subje&bholigct;&bholngs; have of late been imprisoned without any cause shewed: And when
for their deliverance they were brought before your Justices by your Majesties Writts of Habeas corpus there to
undergoe and receive as the Court should order, and their Keepers c&bhooov;maunded to certifie the causes of their detayner,
no cause was certified, but that they were deteined by your Majesties speciall c&bhooov;maund signified by the Lord&bholngs; of your
Privie Councell, and yet were returned backe to severall prisons without being charged with any thing to which they
might make aunswere according to the Lawe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. and that Soldiers have been dispersed in divers Counties, and Inhabitants compelled to receive them.</head>
			<para id="p6">And whereas of late great Companies of Souldiers and Marriners have been dispersed into divers Counties of
the Realme, and the inhabitant&bholngs; against their will&bholngs; have been compelled to receive them into their houses, and there
to suffer them to sojourne against the Lawes and Customes of this Realme and to the great greivance and vexacion
of the people.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. 25 E. III.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">and that Commissions have issued under the Great Seal for Proceedings according to Martial Law</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And whereas alsoe by authoritie of Parliament in the five and twentith yeare of the Raigne of King Edward the
third it is declared and ena&bholigct;ed that no man should be forejudged of life or limbe against the forme of the Great
Charter and the Lawe of the Land, And by the said Great Charter, and other the Lawes and Statutes of this your
Realme no man ought to be adjudged to death but by the Lawes established in this your Realme, either by the
customes of the same Realme or by A&bholigct;&bholngs; of Parliament. And whereas no offendor of what kinde soever is exempted
from the &bhopubrc;ceeding&bholngs; to be used and punishment&bholngs; to be infli&bholigct;ed by the Lawes and Statutes of this your Realme,
Neverthelesse of late [tyme<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] divers C&bhooov;missions under your Majesties great Seale have issued forth, by which certaine
&bhopubr;sons have been assigned and appointed C&bhooov;missioners with power and authoritie to &bhopubrc;ceed within the land according
to the Justice of Martiall Lawe against such Souldiers or Marriners or other dissolute &bhopubr;sons joyning with them as
should c&bhooov;mitt any murther robbery felony mutiny or other outrage or misdemeanor whatsoever, and by such
s&bhouov;mary course and order as is agreeable to Martiall Lawe and as is used in Armies in tyme of warr to &bhopubrc;ceed to the
tryall and condemnacion of such offenders, and them to cause to be executed and putt to death according to the
Lawe Martiall.</para>
			<para id="p9">By &bhopcrl;text whereof some of your Majesties Subje&bholigct;&bholngs; have been by some of the said C&bhooov;missioners put to death,
when and where, if by the Lawes and Statut&bholngs; of the land they had deserved death, by the same Lawes and Statut&bholngs;
alsoe they might and by no other ought to have byn judged and executed.</para>
			<para id="p10">And alsoe sundrie greivous offendors by colour thereof clayming an exempcion have escaped the punishments
due to them by the Lawes and Statutes of this your Realme, by reason that divers of your Officers and ministers
of Justic[e] have unjustlie refused or forborne to &bhopubrc;ceed against such Offendors according to the same Lawes and Statutes
uppon &bhopcrl;tence that the said offendors were punishable onelie by Martiall law and by authoritie of such C&bhooov;missions
as aforesaid. Which C&bhooov;missions and all other of like nature are wholly and dire&bholigct;lie contrary to the said Lawes
and Statutes of this your Realme.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. The Petition.</head>
			<para id="p11">They doe therefore humblie pray your most Excellent Majestie, that no man hereafter be compelled to make or
yeild any Guift Loane Benevolence Taxe or such like Charge without c&bhooov;mon consent by A&bholigct;e of Parliament, And that
none be called to make aunswere or take such Oath or to give attendance or be confined or otherwise molested or
disquieted concerning the same or for refusall thereof. And that no freeman in any such manner as is before
mencioned be imprisoned or deteined. And that your Majestie would be pleased to remove the said Souldiers and
Mariners and that your people may not be soe burthened in tyme to come. And that the aforesaid C&bhooov;missions for
&bhopubrc;ceeding by Martiall Lawe may be revoked and annulled. And that hereafter no C&bhooov;missions of like nature may
issue forth to any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons whatsoever to be executed as aforesaid, lest by colour of them any of your Majesties
Subje&bholigct;s be destroyed or put to death contrary to the Lawes and Franchise of the Land.</para>
			<para id="p12">All which they most humblie pray of your most Excellent Majestie as their Right&bholngs; and Liberties according to
the Lawes and Statutes of this Realme, And that your Majestie would alsoe vouchsafe to declare that the Award&bholngs;
doing&bholngs; and &bhopubrc;ceeding&bholngs; to the &bhopcrl;judice of your people in any of the &bhopcrl;misses shall not be drawen hereafter into
consequence or example. And that your Majestie would be alsoe graciouslie pleased for the further comfort and
safetie of your people to declare your Royall will and pleasure, That in the things aforesaid all your Officers and
Ministers shall serve you according to the Lawes and Statutes of this Realme as they tender the Honor of your
Majestie and the prosperitie of this Kingdome.</para>
			<para id="p13">Qua quidem Peti&bhocotil;e al[ia]ca &amp; plenius intettca &bhopubr; Dem Regem tali&bhotcrl; est responsum in pleno Parliamento vide&bhoalias;t.
R&deg;. Soit droit fait come est desire.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


