<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47214" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER III. An A&bholigct; for the reforming of some things mistaken in the late A&bholigct; made this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament for the granting of four Subsidies entituled An A&bholigct; for the releife of His Majesties Army and the Northern Parts of this Kingdome and to make good the A&bholigct;s of the Commissioners and other Officers by them authorized or appointed and to be authorized or appointed. [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 1. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners named in cap. 2. ante, and others in this A&bholigct; named, empowered to levy the Subsidies granted by the said Act; and to appoint Assessors, &amp;c. for the first Two of the said Subsidies, as they may find convenient; and as to the other Two, as the said A&bholigct;, cap. 2. dire&bholigct;s. Names of Commissioners appointed by this A&bholigct;. Power to such Commissioners to a&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Forasmuch as by reason of the shortnes of the time Commissions could not issue forth in convenient time
into divers parts of this Kingdome for the assessing rating and leavying of the two first Subsidies granted in
this present Parliament according to the dayes &amp; times in the said A&bholigct; limited and expressed upon which some
question and doubts have beene and are conceived whether the power of the said Commissioners for assessing and
taxing of the said two Subsidies were determined before the said Commissioners had received theire severall Commissions
for the taking away of which Scruple and other doubts and supplying of other defects of the said A&bholigct; Be it ena&bholigct;ed	
by the Kings most Excellent Majesty the Lords Spirituall &amp; Temporall and the Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same that all Commissioners in the said A&bholigct; named and such other persons
as in this A&bholigct; hereafter shall be named and any twoe or more of them for and towards the payment of every of
the said foure Subsidies by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall have within theire severall and respe&bholigct;ive limits power to assesse
tax and leavy the said Subsidies and to assesse rate and taxe every Spirituall Person or Clergyman for all the Mannors
Lands Tenements Rents Services Offices Fees Corrodies Annuities and Hereditaments which he hath or any other
to his use have by descent bargaine or purchase in Fee Simple Fee Taile for Terme of life or yeares or by execution
Wardshipp or Copy of Court Roll according to the yearely value thereof as other the Kings Majesties Subje&bholigct;s borne
within this Realme in and by the said A&bholigct; are limited &amp; appointed to be rated and taxed soe that it extend to the
yearely value of twenty Shillings or above and to authorize nominate and appoint Taxers Assessors Colle&bholigct;ors and
other Officers for the taxing assessing leavying and paying in of the said Subsidies and take such bonds and
Recognizances and use such meanes for the compelling such Officers to undertake and execute such Offices as by
the said A&bholigct; is &bhopcrl;scribed as for and concerning the two first of the said Subsidies at such convenient times and
places before the eighth day of May next ensuing as to them shall seeme convenient And as concerning the other
twoe of the said Subsidies at such times and in such manner as in the said A&bholigct; is limited and &bhopcrl;scribed And that
by vertue of this A&bholigct; Sir John Lawrence Baronet Sir Arthur Manwaring Sir Edward Salter Sir John Parsons Sir
Robert Lovett Knights Thomas Hampson Francis Cheyney the elder William Bowyer Henry Bulstrode Thomas
Stafford Edmond West Gabriel Hipesley John Crooke Anthony Ratcliffe Edmond Waller of Gregories William
Wheeler Raynes Love Esquires with the residue of the Commissioners for the County of Buckingham and Sir
Humphrey Tracy Baronet Sir Richard Ducy Baronet Sir John Tracy Knight John Chamberlain William Mooreton
John Keyt William Leigh Michael Rutter and Anthony Hodges Esquires with the residue of the Commissioners for
the County of Gloucester by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall have full power and authority to make Taxes and Assessments
send forth Warrants and Precepts authorize nominate and appoint Assessors Taxers Colle&bholigct;ors and other, Officers
for the assessing taxing leavying gathering and paying in of the said foure Subsidies within theire severall and
respe&bholigct;ive Counties and take Bonds and Recognizances of the said Colle&bholigct;ors and Officers and use all other meanes
in and by the said Statute limited and appointed and to authorize and compell the said Colle&bholigct;ors and Officers to
doe theire duties in the &bhopcrl;misses and to doe and execute all things in as ample manner and forme as if the said
persons had in the said A&bholigct; and the Commissions thereupon issued beene nominated Commissioners for theire severall
and respe&bholigct;ive Counties.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Former A&bholigct;s of Commissioners ratified.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by Authority aforesaid that all A&bholigct;s heretofore done by the said Commissioners and
every of them or any Colle&bholigct;ors Assessors or other Officers authorized or appointed by them or any of them
concerning the taxing leavying or gathering of the said Subsidies shall bee deemed and adjudged to be good and
effe&bholigct;uall in Law as if the same had beene done within the times in the said A&bholigct; limited and expressed and as
if the purport and effe&bholigct; of this A&bholigct; had beene fully contained and expressed in the said former A&bholigct; any thing
in the said former A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided that the passing of this present A&bholigct; or His Majesties Assent thereunto shall not be any determination
of this present Sessions of Parliament but that this present Sessions of Parliament and all Bills and Matters whatsoever
depending in Parliament and not fully ena&bholigct;ed or determined and all Statutes and A&bholigct;s of Parliament which have
theire continuance untill the end of this present Sessions of Parliament shall remaine continue and bee in full force
as if this had not beene.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


