<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47213" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER II. An Act for the releif of His Majesties Armie and the Northern Parts of the Kingdome. [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 1. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Distresses of the Army and People in the Northern Parts</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">For Relief whereof, Four entire Subsidies granted. What Persons and what Property to be rated. Aliens. Popish Recusants Convict</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">MOST gracious Soveraign Your Majesties most humble and loyall Subje&bholigct;s the Commons in your high Court of
Parliament now assembled haveing duly considered the great wants and distresses that your Army and People
in the Northern Parts of this your Kingdome doe sustain and the eminent danger that your Kingdome is in Albeit
Subsidies or the supply or support of publike affaires (by what name or names soever the same be called) are
not used to be granted at the begining of Parliaments but after such time as the grievances of the people have
beene heard and redressed which can never soe cleerely appeare to soveraigne Majestie as in Parliaments where
people have theire immediate accesse unto theire soveraigne yet for the avoiding the eminent danger that your
Kingdome is in for the present reliefe of your Army and of those distressed Countreys the safety of your Majestie
and Children (soe that it bee not drawne into President for future times) they humbly beseech your Majestie that
it may be ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by authority of the same that foure entire Subsidies shall be rated taxed levied and paid att two
severall payments att the times hereafter in this A&bholigct; expressed of every person Spirituall and Temporall of what
estate or degree he or they be of according to the tenor of this A&bholigct; in manner and forme following (that is to say)
that aswell every person borne within this Realme of England Wales or other the Kings Dominions as all and every
Fraternity Guild Corporation Mysterie Brotherhood and Comunaltie Corporate and not Corporate within this Realme
of England Wales or other the Kings Dominions being worth three pounds as well in Coin and the value of every
pound that every such person Fraternity Guild Corporation Mysterie Brotherhood and Comunalty Corporate or not
Corporate hath of his or theire owne or any other hath to his or theire use As alsoe in Plate Stocke of Merchandize
all manner of corne and grain Housholdstuffe and of all other goods moveable as well within this Realme as without
and of all such s&bhouov;ms of money as to him or them is or shall be owing whereof he or they trust in his or theire
conscience surely to be paid (except and out of the &bhopcrl;misses dedu&bholigct;ed) such S&bhouov;ms of money as he or they doe owe
and in his or theire consciences intend truly to pay and except alsoe the Apparell of every such persons their wives
and children belonging to theire owne bodies (saving Jewells Gold Silver Stone and Pearle) shall pay to and for every
of the said Subsidies twoe shillings eight pence of every pound And alsoe every Alien and Stranger borne out of the
Kings obeysance aswell denizens as others inhabiting within this Realme and alsoe every popish recusant convi&bholigct;or which before the time of the Assesment of the severall subsidies by this present A&bholigct; granted shall be a popish
recusant convi&bholigct; or which are or shall be indi&bholigct;ed for popish recusancy and theire Indi&bholigct;ments either are or shall be
removed by certiorari or being not removed shall not by appearance and traverse legally be discharged before the
said Assesment soe to be made or shall not have received the holy Comunion according to the rites of the Church of
England within one whole yeare next before the said Assesment shall be made of every pound that hee or they or
any other to his or theire use in trust or otherwise shall have in Coine and the value of every pound in Plate Corn
Grain Merchandize Housholdstuffe or other Goods Jewells Chattels moveables and immoveable as is aforesaid as well
within this Realme as without and of all S&bhouov;ms of money to him or them owing whereof hee or they trust in his or
theire conscience to be paid (except and out of the &bhopcrl;misses dedu&bholigct;ed every such sum and summes of money which he
or they doe owe and in his or theire conscience or consciences intend truly to pay) shall pay to and for every of the
said Subsidies five shillings and four pence of every pound And alsoe that every Alien and Stranger born out of
the Kings Dominions being Denizen or not Denizen not being contributary to any the rates aforesaid and being of
the age of seaven yeares or above and every Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; or which before the time of the Assesment of
the severall Subsidies by this present A&bholigct; granted shall be a Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; being of the age of seaventeen
yeares or which being of the Age of one and twentie yeares hath not received the Holy Communion within one
yeare then last past shall pay to and for every [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the said severall Subsidies eight pence for every poll And the Master
or he or shee with whom the said Alien-or such Papist is or shall be abiding att the time of the taxation or taxations
thereof to be charged with the same for lacke of Payment thereof.</para></section>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Lands, &amp; of the Yearly Value of 20s. 4s. in the Pound.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Aliens, Denizen or not, and Popish Recusant Convicts, 8s. in the Pound. Value of Property charged certified; First Two Subsidies rated and set before the 27th Feb. 1640, and the Two other before the 1st April next ensuing. Names of Persons charged to be certified to Exchequer. Names of Persons to whom Sums of first Two Subsidies to be paid. The like of the Sums of the last Two Subsidies. Acquittances to be given to the Colle&bholigct;ors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that every person borne under the Kings obeysance and every
Corporation Fraternity Guild Mysterie Brotherhood and Communalty Corporate or not Corporate for every pound
that every of the same persons and every Corporation Fraternity Guild Mysterie Brotherhood and Communalty
Corporate or not Corporate or any other to his or theire use in trust or otherwise hath in Fee Simple Fee Tail
for term of life term of yeares by execution Wardshipp or by Copy of Court Roll of and in any Honours Castles
Mannors Lands Tenements Rents Services Hereditaments Annuities Fees Corrodies or other yearely Proffits of the
yearely value of twenty shillings as well within ancient demeasne and other places priviledged as elsewhere and soe
upward shall pay to and for every the said Subsidies four shillings of and for every pound And every Alien Denizen
or not Denizen born out of the Kings obeysance and every Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; of what Estate or degree soever
they bee of or which before the time of the Assesment of the severall Subsidies by this present A&bholigct; granted shall be a
Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; or which shall bee indicted for Popish Recusancie and theire Indi&bholigct;ments are or shall be
removed by Certiorari or being not removed shall not by appearance and traverse legally be discharged before the
said Assessement soe to be made or being of the age of twenty and one yeares shall not have received the Holy
Communion according to the rites of the Church of England within one whole yeare next before the said Assessement
shall be made in such case to pay to and for every the said severall Subsidies eight shillings for every pound.
And that all summs to be presented and chargeable by this A&bholigct; either for goods and debts or either of them or for
Lands Tenements and other the &bhopcrl;misses as is in this A&bholigct; contained shall bee att the said payments set and taxed
after the rate and proportion according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; Lands and Tenements chargeable to the
Dismes of the Clergy and yearely wages due to servants for theire yearely service (other then the Kings Servants
taking yearely wages of five pounds or above onely excepted and foreprized) And that all Plate Coyn Jewels
Goods Debts and Chattels Personalls and all Lands Tenements and other the premisses as aforesaid being in the rule
and custody of any person or persons to the use of any Corporation Fraternity Guild Mysterie Brotherhood or any
Communalty being Corporate or not Corporate be and shall be rated set and charged by reason of this A&bholigct; att the
value certified by the presenters in theire Certificate for every pound in goods and debts as is aforesaid and for every
pound in Lands Tenements Annuities Fees Corrodies and other yeerely profits as is aforesaid and the Sums that are
above rehearsed set and taxed to be levied and taken of them that shall have such goods in custodie or otherwise
charged for Lands as is before rehearsed and the same person and persons and Bodies Corporate by authority of this
A&bholigct; shall bee, discharged against him or them that shall or ought to have the same att the time of the payment or
delivery thereof or att his otherwise departure from the custodie or possession of the same (except and alwaies
foreprized from the charge and assessement of the said Subsidies all goods chattels jewells and ornaments of Churches
and chappels [which have beene ordained &amp; used in Churches &amp; Chappells<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] for the honour and service of
Almighty God). And the twoe first of the said four Subsidies shall be by authority aforesaid taxed sessed and
rated according to this A&bholigct; in every Shire Riding Lathe Wapentake Rape Cities, Borough Town, and in every
other place within this Realme of England and Dominion of Wales before the seaven and twentieth day of
February in the yeare of our Lord God 1640 and the two other of the said four Subsidies shall by the
authority aforesaid be taxed sessed rated before the first day of Aprill next ensuing and the particular Sums of
every Shire Riding Borough Towne and other place aforesaid with the particular names of such as are or shall
bee chargeable to and for the payment of the said Subsidies to bee taxed and sett by the Commissioners for
the same to be limited or two of them att the least with the names of the high Colle&bholigct;ors and in the same forme
shall be certified into the Kings Court of Exchequer the first twoe of the said Subsidies before the fourth day
of March next coming and the other twoe of the said Subsidies before the [twentieh<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] day of Aprill next coming.
And the said s&bhouov;ms in forme aforesaid to be taxed to and for the payment of the said two first Subsidies shall
be paid in one intire Sum unto Sir Thomas Barrington Knight and Baronet Sir Robert Pye Knight Arthur Capell
Esquire Thomas Soame &amp; Isaac Penington Aldermen of the City of London now Members of the House of Commons
in this present Parliament assembled and unto Robert Bateman Chamberlaine of the City of London att or before
the tenth day of March next coming at or in a place within the Guildhall of the City of London comonly called
The Chamberlains Office and the said s&bhouov;ms in manner and forme aforesaid to be taxed for the payment of the
two last of the said four Subsidies shall be paid att one intire sum unto the said Sir Thomas Barrington Sir Robert Pye
Arthur Capell Thomas Soame Isaac Penington and Robert Bateman att or before the tenth day of May next coming
at or in the said place called The Chamberlains Office and that the said Treasurers or Receivers or any one or
more of them upon the receipt of any money from the high Colle&bholigct;ors by this Statute to be authorised shall make
unto every of the said Colle&bholigct;ors one or more Acquittances under the hands and Seales of the respe&bholigct;ive Treasurers
or Receivers that shall receive the same testifying the receipt of soe much money as hee shall receive and that the
producing of the said Acquittances soe made shall be as a sufficient Warrant for the said Colle&bholigct;ors to passe theire
Account as any Tally or Constat out of the Receipt and the sums above said of and for the said Subsidies shall be
taxed set asked and demanded taken gathered levied and paid to the persons and uses in this present A&bholigct; expressed
aswell within liberties franchises san&bholigct;uaries ancient demeasnes and other whatsoever places exempt or not exempt
as without (except such shires places and persons as shall be foreprized in and by this present A&bholigct;) any Grant
Charter Prescription Use or Libertie by reason of any Letters Patents or other Priviledge Prescription Allowance
for the same or whatsoever other matter or discharge heretofore to the contrary made granted used or obtained
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Aliens and others, who at the time of the said Assessments are out the Realm,</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">to be charged by the Certificate of Inhabitants of the Place where Property taxed is situate</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by authority of this present Parliament That every such person aswell such as be born
under the Kings Obeysance as every other person stranger born denizen or not denizen inhabiting within this Realme
or within Wales or other the Kings Dominions which att the time of the same assessings or taxations or any or
every of them to be had or made shall be out of this Realme or out of Wales and have Goods Chattels Lands or
other Tenements Fees or Annuities or other Profits within this Realm or in Wales shall be charged and chargeable
for the same by the Certificate of the Inhabitants of the place where such Goods Chattels Lands Tenements or other
the &bhopcrl;misses then shall be or in such place where such person or persons or his or theire Fa&bholigct;or Deputy or Atturney
shall have his or theire most resort unto within this Realm or in Wales in like manner as if the person were or had
beene att the time of the said assessing within this Realm and that every person abiding or dwelling within or
without this Realm shall be charged and chargeable to the said severall Subsidies granted by this A&bholigct; according and
after the rate of such yearely substance or value of Lands or Tenements Goods Chattels and other the premisses
as every person soe to be charged shall be set at at the time of the said assessing or taxation upon him to be made
and no otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. For the assessing the said Subsidies great Officers of State to appoint Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p8">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That for the assessing and ordering of the said Subsidies to
be duely had the Lord Chancellour of England or the Lord Keeper of the Great Seal the Lord Treasurer of
England the Lord President of the Kings Councell the Lord Privie Seal the Lord Admirall of England the Lord
Steward of the Kings Household and the Lord Chamberlain of the Kings most honourable Household for the time
being or two of them att the least (whereof the Lord Chancellour or Lord Keeper of the Great Seale or the Lord
Treasurer for the time being to be one) shall and may name and appoint such and soe many persons as they in theire
discretion shall thinke fitt to be Commissioners for the rating and taxing of the honourable Household of the Kings
Majestie in what Shire or other place the said Houshold shall happen then to be And the said Chancellour of England
or Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the time being or such C&bhooov;missioners as shall have the Custodie thereof
shall make and dire&bholigct; out of the Court of Chancery under the Great Seale severall Commissions for the sessing
and levying of the said severall Subsidies according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; in manner and forme hereafter
expressed (viz.)</para>
			<para id="p9">For his Majesties houshold Unto the persons in manner aforesaid to be nominated.</para>

		<section id="s5">
			<head>Names of Commissioners</head>
</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>And for the County of Bedford</head>
			<para id="p10">Unto Sir Robert Napper Knight and Baronet Sir Beecham St John Sir Oliver Luke Sir Peter Osborne Sir Lewes
Dive Sir Samuel Luke Sir William Bryers Sir George Russell Knights Richard Taylor Serjeant att Law William
Duncombe William Boteler Thomas Rolt William Palmer James Beverley John Wingate Henry Chester Humphrey
Fish Walter Rolt John Vaux and Thomas Sadler Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>For the Towne of Bedford</head>
			<para id="p11">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir Samuel Luke Knight Richard Taylor, Serjeant at Law Francis Bannister
Do&bholigct;or of Phisick Thomas Paradyne Thomas Hanse Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>For the County of Buckingham</head>
			<para id="p12">Sir Peter Temple Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Tyrrell Baronet Sir Edmund Varney Sir Alexander Denton
Sir Thomas Littleton Sir Richard Ingoldsby Sir Robert Dormer Sir William Andrews Sir Thomas Sanders Sir Henry
Croke Knights Peter Dorrell Robert Busby Thomas Risley Raph Varney Richard Greenvile John Dormer Richard
Winwood Thomas Tirringham [John Tirringham<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Thomas Egleston of Rainslow Thomas Duncombe of Brickhill
Thomas Tyrrel Thomas Longevile Thomas Lea the Elder Richard Serjeant William Hakewill Thomas Westall Esquires
John Duncombe Gentleman.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>For the Town and Borough of Buckingham</head>
			<para id="p13">The Bailiefs for the time being Sir Peter Temple Knight and Baronet Sir Alexander Denton Knight Robert
Smith and John Nicolls Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>For the County of Berk</head>
			<para id="p14">Sir John Backhouse Knight of the Bath Sir Richard Harison Knight Thomas Manwaring John Harison George
Purefey Thomas Fetiplace Samuel Dunch Henry Pole Humphrey Dolman William Barker and Roger Knight of
Gwinham Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>For the Borough of New Windsor</head>
			<para id="p15">Unto the Maior for the time being John Hersy William Tayleur Edmund Eyre William Stebing Thomas Johnson
Esquires John Spencer Do&bholigct;or in Physick William Boles Gentleman.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>For the County of Cornwall</head>
			<para id="p16">Unto Sir John Trelawny Knight and Baronet John Sentaubyn John Arundell de Sithine William Harris John
Trefusis Rennattus Bellot William Pendarvis Charles Trevanin Thomas Herl Hugh Boscawen Peter Courtney John
Carter Samuel Cosworth Samson Manaton Humphrey Nichols Hender Moulsworth Charles Roscarrock Paul Speccot
Christopher Worthiall George Hele Timothy Brawning John Moyle Nicholas Trefusis William Courtney William Glin
Walter Langdon and John Carew Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>For the County of Cumberland</head>
			<para id="p17">Unto Sir Patricius Curwen Baronet Sir George Dalson and Sir Thomas Dacres Knights Henry Fletcher Richard
Barwis John Skelton Peter Senhouse Richard Tolson William Lawson and William Briscoe Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>For the County of Cambridge</head>
			<para id="p18">Unto Sir John Cuts and Sir James Reynolds Knights Francis Russell John Cotton James Reynolds William Allington
Robert Peyton Michael Dalton Thomas Wendy Thomas Willis Isaac Barron Thomas Tyrrell William March Robert
Lukin John Layer Edward Buckworth Besney Betts William Barnes John Craine Esquires James Ayliff Thomas
Simonds William Fisher Robert Castle John Hubbard John Ducket John [Wildbore<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] and John Whistler Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>For the Towne of Cambridge</head>
			<para id="p19">Unto Sir John Cuts Knight the Maior for the time being Isaac Barrow Talbot Pepys Recorder Esquires Samuel
Spalding John Sherwood Robert Twells Aldermen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>For the Countie of Chester</head>
			<para id="p20">Unto Sir George Booth Sir Richard Wilbraham Sir Thomas Delves Sir Richard Grosvenor [Knighs<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] and Baronets
Sir Edward Fitton Sir William Brereton Baronets Sir Tho. Brereton Knight Richard Brereton Henry Leigh Thomas
Stanley William Davenport William Downs Peter Venables George Cotton Roger Wilbraham Hugh Wilbraham Peter
Warburton of the Grange Henry Bunbury William Whitmore Henry Burkenhead William Glegg John Crewe
George Purstowe Thomas Crackstone William Liversage Philip Manwaring William Marbury and Thomas
Cholmeley Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>For the City and the County of the City of Chester</head>
			<para id="p21">Unto Thomas Aldersey Maior Sir Thomas Smith Knight Robert Brerewood Esquire Serjeant att Law Recorder
Francis Goonall William Goonall Esquires Christopher Bleasse Charles Walley Nicholas Ince Aldermen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>For the County of Derby</head>
			<para id="p22">Unto Sir George Greasley Sir Thomas Burdet Baronets Sir Edward Vernon Sir John Fitzherbert Sir John
Fitzherbert Knights Thomas Greasley Christopher Horton William Cooke John Agard Samuel Sleigh John Bullock
Simon Every Es&bhoqesq; John Gell Esquire Henry Gilbert Gentleman the Maior of Chesterfield Christopher Fulwood John
Milward John Manners John Shawcroft Randall Ashenhurst Francis Rhodes Edward Revell and Francis Revell Esquires
and Lionell Fanshawe Gentleman.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>And for the Borough of Derby</head>
			<para id="p23">Unto Edward Long Maior John Hope Henry Wandell Luke Whittington Aldermen John Bullock Esquire Roger
Allestry and Robert Meller Gentlemen</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>For the County of Devon</head>
			<para id="p24">Sir Edward Seymer Knight and Baronet Sir George Chudleigh Sir Lewes Pollard Sir John Pole Sir Peter Prideaux
Baronets Sir John Speccot Sir Samuel Role Sir Shilston Calmady Sir John Chichester Sir Nicholas Martin Sir John
Young Knights John Bampfeild Arthur Basset John Ackland Arthur Champernoun John Harris Hugh Fortescue
John Gifford Anthony Dennis Thomas Southcott Edward Arscote Samson Hele John Berry William Tothill Robert
Savery Henry Waldron John Davy Francis Bluet Richard Columbe Walter Hele James Welsh Edward Yarde Richard
Cabell Richard Duke Alexander Maynard William Maurice Thomas Risden Robert Stafford Edmond Fowell William
Fry Humphrey Prouz John Peter and John Yeo Esquires</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>For the City and County of Exon</head>
			<para id="p25">John Penney Esquire Maior Thomas Crossing John Lynn Nicholas Spicer John Hackwell Adam Bennet Roger
Mallecke and James Tucker Esquires</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>For the County of Dorset</head>
			<para id="p26">Unto Sir Thomas Trenchard Knight Sir John Miller Knight John Browne Angel Graye Gregory Gibs Richard
Brodrip John Arnold James Frampton George Williams Richard Bingham Thomas Tregumell William Savage Esquires
John Dolling Bampfeild Chafing Edmund Ogden John Hannam Esquires and Robert Tooe Gentleman</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Pool</head>
			<para id="p27">Unto Richard Mayer Maior George Scot Alexander Wayte Gentlemen</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>For the County of Yorke and for the Westrid of the County of Yorke</head>
			<para id="p28">Unto Sir Francis Wortley Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Goodrick Sir William Lyster Sir Arthur Ingram junior
Sir John Ramsden Sir Edward Rhodes Sir Thomas Wentworth Sir William Fairfax Sir Jerves Cutler Sir Richard
Hutton Knights William Ingleby Henry Arthington John Key Robert Rockley Ingram Hopton William West Jerves
Hamond Henry Cholmeley Nicholas Yarbrough John Farrar William White Thomas Parker William Wombwell
George Marwood Thomas Lister John Robinson Gregory Armitage Thomas Stockdale Esquires Benjamin Wade
and Joseph Hillary Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>For the Northrid of the County of Yorke</head>
			<para id="p29">Unto Sir Marmaduke Wyvell Sir Thomas Gore Knights and Baronets Sir Coniers Darcy Sir William Sheffield
Sir Richard Darley Sir Thomas Layton Sir Thomas Gore Sir Henry Frankland Knights Henry Fowls Mathew Hutton
John Dalton Henry Anderson John Calverley John Wastall John Dodsworth junior Arthur Awdbrough Roger Wyvell
William Caley John Cholmely Christopher Perchehay Charles Tanckard John Talbot George Metcalf George Trotter
James Pennyman Richard Wyn Christopher Waters Stephen Jackson Francis Rookeby Mathew Smelt Francis Lassels
Esquires Robert Wild John Robinson Stephen Jackson James Cholmeley George Coniers Francis Tompson William
Ford Richard Tompson William Standley James Moore Thomas Lassels William Pinckney John Dent Robert
Colchester &amp; William Fish Gentlemen</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>For the Eastrid of the County of Yorke</head>
			<para id="p30">Unto Sir Henry Griffith Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Metham Sir William Alford Sir. Philip Mountain Sir Michael
Wharton Sir John Vavasor Sir Thomas Rennington Sir Arthur Robinson Knights Thomas Anlaby John Legard
Richard Remington William Saint Quyntin Thomas Heblethwait Christopher Appleyard John Constable William
Grimston Robert Crompton Francis Thorpe Christopher Ridley Gregory Crake John Anlaby Charles Bowes Stephen
Tompson and John Overton Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>For the City and County of the City of [the<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Yorke</head>
			<para id="p31">Sir Robert Belt Knight Lord Maior Sir William Allanson and Sir Roger Jaques Knights and Aldermen Sir Thomas
Widdrington Knight Recorder Leonard Betson Christopher Croft Edmund Cooper Robert Hemsworth Thomas
Hoyle James Hutchinsen Thomas Hodgson Henry Tompson John Vaux and William Scot Aldermen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Hull</head>
			<para id="p32">John Barnard Esquire Maior Robert Legard Esquire James Watkinson Christopher Legard Henry Barnard John
Gaton Gentlemen</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>For the County of Essex</head>
			<para id="p33">Robert Lord Rich Sir Thomas Barrington Sir Harbottle Grimston Knights and Baronets Sir Thomas Bendish Sir
Benjamin Ayloffe Sir William Hicks Sir William Masham Sir Richard Everard Sir William Luckin Sir William
Wiseman Baronets Sir Henry Mildmay Knight Master of the Jewell house Sir Thomas Cheeke Sir Henry Mildmay
of Moulsham Sir William Maxey Sir Henry Holcroft Sir Thomas Bowes Sir Francis Cooke Sir Henry Saint George
Sir William Rowe Sir William Martin Sir Thomas Honywood Sir Humphrey Mildmay Sir John Harrington (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) Sir John
Barrington [Knights<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Harbottle Grimston Esquire Sir Martin Lumley Knight and Baronet Robert Kempt John Argoll
Edward Keightley John Wakering William Gouldingham Euseby Wright Edward Palmer William Coniers Thomas
Fanshawe John Wright William Atwood George Walton James Altham Timothy Middleton Nathaniel Bacon Anthony
Luther Thomas Smith John Meade John Brooke Cary Harvey Mildmay Deane Tindall Henry Wiseman Robert Mildmay
de Tarling Edward Berket Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>For the Town of Colchester</head>
			<para id="p34">The Maior for the time being Harbottle Grimston Esquire Recorder Robert Buckston Esquire Henry Barret
Aldermen Roger Coleman.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>And for the Towne of Malden</head>
			<para id="p35">Unto the two Bailiffs for the time being Jeremiah Browning and John Francis.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>For the Towne of Harwich</head>
			<para id="p36">Unto the Maior for the time being Harbottle Grimstone Esquire Recorder Richard Hankins Robert Hawkes.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>For the County of Gloucester</head>
			<para id="p37">Unto Sir Baynham Throckmorton Baronet Sir William Masters Sir Ralph Dutton Sir John Seamor Sir Maurice
Berkley Sir Robert Cooke Knights Richard Berkley Henry Poole John Prettyman John Stephens Thomas Escourt
John Fetyplace Esquires William Trye John Howe Robert Hope Esquires Stephen Fowler Gentleman Thomas Chester
Edward Stephens John Cothrington Samuel Cothrington John Smith junior Anthony Kinscot Esquires William Stratford
John Berrow Thomas Morgan William Jones Richard Ayleworth Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>For the City and County of the City of Gloucester</head>
			<para id="p38">Unto Thomas Hill Esquire Maior Anthony Robinson Toby Bullock John Brewster John Web William Singleton
William Capell and James Powell Aldermen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>For the County of Huntington</head>
			<para id="p39">Unto Sir Sidney Mountague Knight Sir William Armyn Baronet Onslow Winche John Castle James Ravenscroft
Valentine Walton Robert Page Whetehill Audley Torrell Josselin William Cater Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>And for the County of Hertford</head>
			<para id="p40">Unto the Lord Viscount Cranbourn Sir John Boteler Knight of the Bath Sir John Jeninges Knight of the Bath Sir
Thomas Fanshaw Knight of the Bath Sir Richard Lucy Baronet Sir Charles Cesar Sir William Litton Knights Sir
John Gerrard Baronet Sir Charles Harbert Sir Thomas Fotherby Sir John Colte Sir Thomas Dacres Sir Edward Bash
Sir John Wats Sir John Cesar Sir Peter Saltonstall Knights William Priesley George Tooke Francis Taverner Graveley
Norton Edward Wingate Henry Anderson John Brocket James Mayne Francis Combes Esquires Thomas Blunt John
Heydon Robert Dewhurst Edward Atkins Serjeant at Law Thomas Tooke Richard Hale Thomas Hewit (<ref idref="n10">10</ref>) John Harrison
Henry Gardner John Gulston Arthur Poulton Ralph Freeman William Newce John Brograve Edward Chester Edward.
Cason Arthur Capell</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>For the Towne and Borough of Saint Albans</head>
			<para id="p41">Unto Richard Ruth Maior Sir John Jenings Knight of the Bath John Robotham Thomas Cooley Ralph Pemberton
Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>For the County of Hereford</head>
			<para id="p42">To John Kirle Baronet Sir Richard Hopton Sir Robert Whitney Sir Humphrey Baskervile Sir William Croft Knights
Wallop Brabazon Esquire Henry Lingen Roger Vaughan John Scudamore of Kent Church John Vaughan Ambrose
Elton James Kirle William Rudhall William Scudamore William Smallman Thomas Price Harbert Westfaling John
Cornwall Paul Abrahall Epiphan Howorth Thomas Tomkins Walter Vaughan John Coles John Patshall Richard
Barrowe Arnold Burghill William Cartwright Edward Broughton Henry Jones Henry Poole Bailiffe of the Borough
of Leominster.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>For the City of Hereford</head>
			<para id="p43">Unto Edmond Ashton Esquire Maior of the said City James Rodes Anthony Pembridge Esquires James Lane
Gentleman.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>For the County of Kent</head>
			<para id="p44">Unto Sir Edward Hales Sir Edward Dering Knights and Baronets Sir George Sandys Knight of the Bath Sir
Michael Levisey Baronet Sir William Brooke and Sir Edward Scot Knights of the Bath Sir Humphrey Style Baronet
Sir John Sedley Knight and Baronet Sir Roger Twisden Knight and Baronet Sir William Stock Knight of the Bath
Sir Thomas Palmer Barronet Sir Humphrey Tufton Sir James Oxenden Sir Edward Boys Sir Peter Wroth Sir John
Honywood Sir Peter Heyman Sir Thomas Walsingham Sir Edward Gilburne Sir Francis Barnham Sir John Culpeper
Sir Cheyney Culpeper Sir Percivall Hart Sir Robert Filmer Sir William Brockman Sir Anthony Weldon and Sir
Henry Grimston Knights Edward Monyngs Anthony Hammond Thomas Blechenden Edward Boys Reynold Edwards
William Boys Samuel Short John Henden William Boys Edward Dering Nicholas Tooke Henry Heyman John Harvey
Peter Godfrey Thomas Diggs Norton Knatchbull Richard Lee George Strode Thomas Blunt Thomas Selyard Stephen
Leonard Robert Barnham William James Edward Partrich Henry Dixon and Henry Gilburne Esquires</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>For the City and County of the City of Canterbury</head>
			<para id="p45">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir Edward Masters Knight John Nutt Esquire Francis Lovelace Esquire William
Man Esquire Thomas Courthope Esquire Avery Savyn and James Masters Aldermen</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>For the City of Rochester</head>
			<para id="p46">Unto Philip Ward Maior Henry Clearke Esquire Serjeant att Law Recorder Richard Lea George Newman Esquires
and John Cobham Gentleman</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>For the Parts of Lyndsey in the County of Lyncolne</head>
			<para id="p47">Unto Edmund Lord Sheffeild Sir John Wray Knight and Baronet Sir Philip Tirwhit Sir John Rowles Baronets
Sir Edward Askew Sir William Pelham Sir Charles Bowles Sir Christopher Wray Sir John South Sir Henry Roodley
Knights Nathaniel Fynes John Bellasis Thomas Grantham Samuel Oldfeild Anthony Meeres Thomas Sanderson Edmund
Anderson Willoughby Hickman Charles Pelham John Broxholm Vincent Sheffeild Marmaduke Darell Edward Rositer
Richard Toothby Thomas Ayscough senior John Bradley William Godfrey Francis Wolbey Esquires William Loddington
Gentleman the Maior of Grimsby William Coney Esquire Rutland Snowden Esquire.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>For the Citie of Lincolne</head>
			<para id="p48">Unto the Maior of Lincolne Thomas Grantham Esquire John Broxholm Esquire Richard White William Watson
Stephen Dawson Aldermen and Richard Ward Citizen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>For the Borough of Boston</head>
			<para id="p49">Unto Edward Tilson John Whiting Thomas Askham Thomas Welby Gentlemen and the Maior of Boston.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>For the Parts of Holland in Com. &bhopcrl;d</head>
			<para id="p50">Unto Sir Anthony Irby Knight Thomas Ogle Thomas Reade Bevill Wimberley William Ellis Dymock Walpole Philip
Welby Thomas Ogle Esquires John Hobson Charles Empson Gentlemen John Harrington Esquire.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>For the Parts of Kestaven in the County of Lincolne</head>
			<para id="p51">Unto Sir Robert Carr Sir William Armyn Baronets Sir Hamond Whitchcot Sir Jerves Nevil Knights Thomas Hussey
Charles Dymock Thomas Hatcher Edmund Hall Thomas Harrington John Brownelowe William Brownelowe Edward
King Henry Pelham Esquires Edward Skipworth Robert Treadway William Savile John Archer Esquire the Alderman
of Stamford and the Alderman of Grantham</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>For the County of Leicester</head>
			<para id="p52">Unto William Halford Esquire Thomas Brewdnell Richard Bent Henry Font Arthur Staveley William Roberts
William Quarles William Jerves Peter Temple George Puchin Simon Ridgeley Thomas Babington William Davers
Roger Smith John Saint Johns Thomas Merry Francis Hacker senior William Standley and Gilbert Fosset of Leicester</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>For the County Palatine of Lancaster</head>
			<para id="p53">Unto Sir Gilbert Houghton Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Stanley Baronet Sir Thomas Barton Knight Sir Ralph
Ashton Baronet Richard Holland John Atherton Robert Holt Ralph Ashton Roger Kirkby Richard Shuttleworth
John More Thomas Standish Ralph Ashton Alexander Rigby Hugh Rigby Alexander Rigby of Burgh William
Farrington Thomas Preston John Gerlington George Dodding Edmund Hopwood Nicholas Townly Henry Ashhurst
John Bradshaw Edward Veale Esq<ref idref="n11">11</ref> Henry Ogle Savile Radclif John Starkey Edward Butterworth William Ambrose
Thomas Whittingham John Bradell Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s50">
			<head>For the County of Middlesex</head>
			<para id="p54">Unto Sir Edward Spencer Knight Sir Thomas Fowler Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Barkham Knight and
Baronet Sir William Balfour Knight Leiutenant of the Tower of London Sir Francis Darcey Sir John Davers Sir
Thomas Lake Sir Edward Wardour Sir William Roberts Sir Henry Roe Sir John Bennet Sir Thomas Allen Sir
Robert Wood Sir Nicholas Raynton Knights John Page Esquire one of the Masters of the Chancery Thomas Gardiner
Esquire Recorder of the City of London William Hill Justinian Povey John Hawtrey Francis Poulton John Herne
John Huxley George Long Edward Roberts Richard Blower Anthony Croft Richard Sprygenell Esq<ref idref="n12">12</ref> John Smith
Thomas March John Hoker Edward Noell Gideon Awnsham Thomas Jenings Richard Page and Thomas
Wilcox Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s51">
			<head>For the Citie of Westminster</head>
			<para id="p55">Unto Sir Richard Winn Knight and Baronet Treasurer to the Queenes most excellent Majestie Sir William Uvedall
Knight Sir Edmund Verney Sir William Ashton Sir Gregory Fennor Sir Randolph Crew Sir Robert Pye Sir Arthur
Ingram Sir Edward Wardour Knights Thomas Baldwyn Robert Dixon Michael Oldesworth Mathew Hale Edward
Nicholas John Parker Arthur Squibb John Glynn Peter Heyward Henry Lyde Robert Dixon George Bleverhaset
William Bell William Wheler Esquires John Brigham Gentleman John Chicheley John Trenchard Robert Scawen
Anthony Wither Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s52">
			<head>And for the Dutchy of Lancaster</head>
			<para id="p56">Edward Lord Newburgh Chancelor of the Dutchy Sir Thomas Bedingfeild Knight Attorney Edward Harbert
Esquire Solicitor Generall to the Kings most excellent Majestie and Challenor Chute Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s53">
			<head>For the City of London</head>
			<para id="p57">Unto Edmund Wright Lord Maior Sir James Cambell Sir George Whitmore Sir Nicholas Raynton Sir Christopher
Cletherow Sir Maurice Abbot and Sir Henry Garway Knights and Aldermen Thomas Gardiner Esquire Recorder
Thomas Soame Isaac Pennington Aldermen Nathaniel Cradock and Samuel Vassell Citizens.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s54">
			<head>For the County of Monmouth</head>
			<para id="p58">Unto Edward Lord Herbert Sir Edmund Morgan and Sir William Morgan Knights William Harbert Richard
Harbert Thomas Morgan de Maughen Trevor Wynns John Harbert of Coulbrock Nicholas Kemeyes John Milbury
Henry Probert David Lewes William Baker Philip Jones John Morgan de Pemrick William Jones de Usk George
Probert Thomas Morgan de Layfore William Morgan of Tredonock Gentleman and Thomas Williams Gentleman.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s55">
			<head>For the County of Northampton</head>
			<para id="p59">Unto William Lord Fitzwilliams of Milton Sir Rowland St. John of Woodston Knight of the Bath Sir Lewes
Watson of Rockingham Sir John Isham Knights and Baronets Sir Christopher Yelverton Sir William Chancey Sir
Richard Samuel Sir William Milmore Sir Edward Watson Sir Humphrey Ormes Knights Richard Lane Esquire
Attorney to the Prince his Highnes Richard Knightley the elder Charles Edmonds Francis Nicholls William Elmes
Edward Harby John Barnard Robert Mildmay John Cartwright Philip Houleman John Creswell Richard Trist
William Pargiter John Wyrley James Anyan Edward Farmer Richard Owsby Clifton Catesby Robert Britton George
Clarke Lawence Manley Thomas Andrew Thomas Genison John Gayes John Sawyer Thomas Pentlow Thomas Dove
Francis Quarles John Claypool Edward Dudley Thomas Elmes John Norton Edward Hanbury Edward Shugborough
John Norwich John Syres Edward Palmer Robert Kirkeham and Thomas Rud Esquires and William Hack Esquire</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s56">
			<head>For the Borough of Northampton</head>
			<para id="p60">Unto John Fisher Maior Richard Lane Esquire Recorder Attorney Generall to the Princes Highnes Sir Richard
Samuel Knight Francis Nicolls Tho. Martin Joseph Sergeant John Gifford John Herbert &amp; John Bret Aldermen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s57">
			<head>For the County of Nottingham</head>
			<para id="p61">Francis Peirpoint Esquire Sir Bardolph Wastneys Baronet Sir Gervas Clifton Knight and Baronet Sir Francis
Thornhigh Sir Thomas Hutchinson Knight Sir Mathew Palmer Knight Isham Parkins Anthony Eyre Richard Byron
John Nevill Thomas Williamson John Wood senior Timothy Pusey John Digby John Odingsels Gervas Lee Hugh
Cartwright John Wood junior William Sanderson Robert Sutton Gilbert Millington Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s58">
			<head>For the Towne of Nottingham</head>
			<para id="p62">Unto William Drury Maior Francis Peirpoint Esquire Sir Gervas Clifton Knight &amp; Baronet Sir Thomas Hutchinson
Knight A&bholigct;on Burwell William Gregory John James Aldermen Huntington Plumtree Do&bholigct;or in Phisick Robert
Greeves Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s59">
			<head>For the County of Norfolk</head>
			<para id="p63">Thomas Knivet John Spelman of Narborough Robert de Grey Thomas Dereham Roger Townsend Clement Herne
John Smith John Spelman of Haydon Robert Wilton John Palgrave Francis Jermy Gregory Gawsell Jeoffry Cobb
Charles Suckling Philip Beddingfeild Edward Gurney Philip Calthrop George Fowler Robert Walpoole Edward
Mileham John Houghton Robert Houghton Brigg Fountain James Scambler Robert Mapes Thomas Wright Thomas
Fincham Martin Sidley Edward Chamberlaine Henry Taylor Thomas Reeve and John Kendall Esquires</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s60">
			<head>For the Towne of Thetford</head>
			<para id="p64">Thomas Lincolne Maior to the Coroner Edward Moore John Chapman Robert Snelling Thomas Snelling Giles
Alden John Salman Edmund Mobbs Gentlemen and Henry Mendham Gentleman.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s61">
			<head>And for the City of Norwich</head>
			<para id="p65">Unto Henry Lane Maior Sir William Denny Knight Francis Bacon Sergeant at Law Richard Rose Thomas Shipdham
Christopher Barret Robert Sumpter John Tooley John Thacker Lynewell Sherwood Francis Norris Thomas Barret
Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s62">
			<head>For the Towne of Lynne Regis</head>
			<para id="p66">To William Doughtie Esquire Maior Thomas Gurlin Thomas Greennell Joshua Frene John Percivall Bartholomew
Warmell John Mayo Thomas Toll Thomas Nelson John Basset Edmond Hudson Esquires Thomas Slaney Nathaniel
Maxey Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s63">
			<head>For the Towne of Yarmouth</head>
			<para id="p67">Thomas Greene Robert Wakeman Henry Davis Thomas Johnson Aldermen</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s64">
			<head>For the County of Oxford</head>
			<para id="p68">Sir Thomas Pope Sir John Curton Sir Giles Bray Sir Robert Dormer Sir Robert Jenkinson Sir John Lacy Sir
Francis Norris Sir William Cobb and Sir Peter Wentworth Knights John Doyly Thomas Chamberlaine William
Walter Thomas Tipping Robert Scroope Edmund Symeon Unton Croke Humphrey Elmes Richard Hampden John
Taverner John Goddier William Tipping John Griffith Edmond Chamberlaine Bartholomew Hone Rice Jones
and Walter Duns Esq<ref idref="n13">13</ref>.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s65">
			<head>And for the City of Oxon</head>
			<para id="p69">Unto the Maior of the said City for the time being William Potter Henry Southam John Sayer Martin Wright
John Nixon Aldermen Timothy Carter Town Clerk</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s66">
			<head>For the County of Rutland</head>
			<para id="p70">To Sir Edward Harrington Knight and Baronet Sir Francis Bodenham and Sir Henry Mynn Knights Henry Noell
Alexander Noell Brian Palms Edward Heath Evers Ermyn John Osborne Edward Falkener Edward Cheseldine and
Andrew Burton Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s67">
			<head>For the County of Surrey</head>
			<para id="p71">Unto Sir Anthony Vincent Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Young Sir Ambrose Browne Baronets Sir Nicholas
Carew Sir Richard Onslow Sir Arthur Manwaring Sir Thomas Grymes Sir Francis Howard Sir Charles Howard
Sir Francis Stidolph Sir John Howland Sir John Lenthall Sir John Lydcote Sir John Tunstall Sir Thomas Evelyn
Sir William Elliot Sir Dudley Carleton Sir Robert Parkhurst Knights Nicholas Stoughton Henry Hilliard George
Evelyn Arthur Squibb George Mynn John Duncombe William Muschamp Robert Hutton John Evelyn Robert
Goodwin Edmond Sanders John Turner Henry Weston Robert Holman Edward Bish the elder Edward Bish the
younger Haward Bickerstaffe Esquires and John Wayte Gentleman</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s68">
			<head>For the Borough of Southwarke</head>
			<para id="p72">Sir John Lenthall Knight Samuel Warcop Esquire Robert Haughton Cornelius Cocke.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s69">
			<head>For the County of Stafford</head>
			<para id="p73">To Sir Harvy Bagot Sir Edward Littleton Baronets Sir Charles Egerton Sir William Bowyer Knights Ralph Snede
Walter [Wrotresleye<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] George Digby Thomas Crumpton Humphrey Worley Mathew Morton John Scrimshire William
Cotton John Fowke Edward Manwaring Walter Grosvenor Richard Pygot Michael Biddulph John Wedgewood
William Brooke Esquires Richard Jeven Richard Hinton Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s70">
			<head>For the City and County of the City of Litchfeild</head>
			<para id="p74">Unto the Bailiffes of the City for the time being John Burnes Humphrey Mathewe Randall Terrick Richard
Baxter Richard Drafgate Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s71">
			<head>For the County of Salop</head>
			<para id="p75">Unto Sir Paul Harris Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Newport Sir William Whitmore Sir William Owen Sir
Robert Eyton Knights Edward Kynaston Francis Charleton Walter Berker Edward Jones Thomas Exton Peter Corbet
Edward Cresset Thomas Otley Thomas Corbet Adam Littleton Thomas Kettleby Francis Harbert William Littleton
Henry Bromley Morton Briggs Thomas Wolrich Walter A&bholigct;on Humphrey Walcott John Newton Thomas Nicholls
Arthur Sandford William Fowler Thomas Mitton Andrew Lloyd Richard Lloyd Francis Thornes Robert Powell
Thomas Screven William Blunden Richard Oakeley Walter Waring Thomas Sotherne Esquires Roland Hill Arthur
Ward Thomas Lochard Gentlemen</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s72">
			<head>For the Towne of Shrewsbury</head>
			<para id="p76">Unto Hugh Harris Esquire Maior Sir Richard Prince Knight Timothy Turner Thomas Jones senior Esquires
Edward Jones Thomas Owen Humphrey Mackworth Esquires William Rowley Simon Weston Charles Benyon
Robert Betton Thomas Winfeild John Studley Aldermen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s73">
			<head>For the County of Southampton</head>
			<para id="p77">Unto Sir John Milles Baronett Sir Richard Gifford Sir Francis Dowse Sir Thomas Bilson Sir Henry Clarke Sir
John Compton Knights Henry Sands John Doddington William Kingsmill Richard Norton Thomas Neale Edward
Pit Benjamin Tichburne Dowse Fuller Edward Goddard Thomas Edmonds Edward Hooper John Hooke John
Bunkley Thomas Betsworth Joseph Wale Richard Major Esquires</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s74">
			<head>For the Isle of Weight</head>
			<para id="p78">Unto Sir Robert Delington and Sir William Lisle Knights Barnaby Ligh William Boreman John Richards Arthur
Bromfeild William Wither John Worsley Richard Goddard Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s75">
			<head>For the City of Winchester</head>
			<para id="p79">Unto Edward White Maior Ralph Riggs William Longland John Trussell Aldermen</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s76">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Southampton</head>
			<para id="p80">Nicholas Peascodd Peter Seale Thomas Mason Peter Clungeon Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s77">
			<head>For the County of Suffolke</head>
			<para id="p81">Unto William Spring Esquire Sheriffe of the said County Sir Edmond Bacon Sir William Playters Sir Robert
Crane Knights and Baronets Sir John Barker Baronet Sir Roger North Sir Nathaniel Barnardiston Sir Philip Parker
Sir Simon Dewes Sir William Soames Sir Charles Crofts Sir Robert Brooke Sir John Wentworth Sir William Harvey
Sir John Rowse Knights Thomas Jermin William [Hevingham<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] John Gurdaine Wiseman Bokenam Morrice Barrow
William Ryvet of Bilson Isaac Appleton Henry North Thomas Cole Richard Pepys Edmond Harvey of Wickhamsith
Thomas Playters Francis Bruster John Scrivener Henry North the elder Arthur Jenney Nicholas Bacon of Dennington
Nathaniel Bacon of Fristow Nicholas Ryvet of Drinson Nicholas Ryvet of Brandston John Laney Francis Bacon
William Bloys of Grand Boroners and John Clench junior Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s78">
			<head>For the Towne of Ipswich</head>
			<para id="p82">Unto the Bayliffes of the said Towne of Ipswich William Cage John Laney Esquires Robert Sparrow John Sicklemore
Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s79">
			<head>For the Borough of Saint Edmonds Bury</head>
			<para id="p83">Unto William Grigg Alderman Robert Brown Alderman Richard Gipps and John Lelham</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s80">
			<head>For the Town of Aldborough</head>
			<para id="p84">Unto John Bence and Richard Browne Bayliffs and unto John Wall and Thomas Johnson</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s81">
			<head>For the Towne of Orford</head>
			<para id="p85">Unto the Maior of Orford for the time being, and to Daniel Harbert and Francis Burwell</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s82">
			<head>For the Towne of Hadleigh</head>
			<para id="p86">Unto the Maior for the time being Francis Bacon John Gale Thomas Allablaster and Thomas Richardson</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s83">
			<head>For the County of Somerset</head>
			<para id="p87">Unto Sir John Horner Sir Charles Berkley Sir Edward Berkley Sir Francis Doddington Knights John Mallet
Thomas Smith Edward Phillipps John Harrington William Walrond Thomas Mallet Serjeant at Law George Powlett
Richard Cole Anthony Stocker William Capell John Symms the elder John Symms junior William Every William
Bull Robert Harbyn Thomas Bridges Francis Hawley Edward Orainge John Bourne John Trevillian Amias Bampfeild
John Saint Alban Edward Bisse John Hunt John Preston Charles Stenings William Blanchard Edward Dyer Thomas
Prynn William Hill Edward Weekes William Barnes senior John Babor &amp; John Merefield Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s84">
			<head>For the City and County of the City of Bristow</head>
			<para id="p88">Unto John Taylor Maior John Goning the elder John Tomlinson Andrew Carleton Aldermen Richard Aldworth
Alexander James Francis Creswicke and Giles Elbridge Merchants</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s85">
			<head>For the County of Sussex</head>
			<para id="p89">Unto Sir Thomas Pelham Sir Thomas Bowyer Baronets Sir John Chapman Sir William Morley Sir Henry Dawtry
Sir Thomas Parker Knights Anthony Stapeley Edward Ford Thomas Grey John Alford Thomas Milles Nicholas
Wolfe Ralph Cooper Henry Goring Edward Goring Thomas Maye Thomas Middleton Hall Ravenscroft William
Marlott Edward Apsley William Michelborne James Rivers Harbert Morley Anthony Fowle Henry Shelley John
Ashburnham William White Harbert Hay John Baker Laurence Ashburnham Harbert Bourd John Busbridge Peter
Farneden &amp; Thomas Eversfeild Esquires</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s86">
			<head>For the Citie of Chichester</head>
			<para id="p90">Unto the Maior of Chichester George Green Gent William Margerom Merchant Henshaw Stephen
Humphreys Gent.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s87">
			<head>For the County of Westmerland</head>
			<para id="p91">Unto Sir John Lowther Baronet Sir Richard Sandford Knight Christopher Phillipson Gawen Brathwaite Allen
Bellingham George Gilpin Richard Crackenthorpe Edward Fisher Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s88">
			<head>For the County of Wiltes</head>
			<para id="p92">Unto Sir John S<ref idref="n16">16</ref> Johns Sir John Danvers and Sir William Button Knights and Baronets Sir Charles Pleydall Sir
George Ayloffe Sir John Lambe Sir Thomas Hall and Sir John Earneley Knights George Vaughan Laurence Hide
Richard Goddard Alexander Thistlethwaite Edward Tucker Francis Swanton Francis Baskervile Vincent Goddard
Edward Goddard of Upton William Daniel John Sadler William Sadler Francis Wroughton of Wilcott Robert
Drew Edward Earneley William Bower John Hiscocke John Penruddocke Robert Hide Thomas Bennet John Tapp
William Willoughby John Marvin William Gifford Jasper Moore Robert Eyres William Wallis Walter Long
Edward Long Edward Earbury John Ducket Edward Escourt Thomas Hungerford of the Lee Henry Baylie Charles
Gore Esquires John Inge Stephen Bowman Thomas Newbye and Philip Francklyn Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s89">
			<head>For the Citie of New Sarum with the Close</head>
			<para id="p93">Unto Emanuel Gauntlet Gentleman Maior Richard Goddard Esquire Mathew Bee Thomas Hancocke the elder
James Abbotts John Ivy and John Dove.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s90">
			<head>For the County of Worcester</head>
			<para id="p94">Unto Sir Walter Devereux Knight and Baronet Sir John Rows Knight Edward Dingle Edward Pitt William Jefferyes
of Hamm Castle Philip Brace Henry Townsend Henry Ingram John Savage John Nawfan Edward Vernon Thomas
Cooke Thomas Good William Child Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s91">
			<head>For the City and County of the City of Worcester</head>
			<para id="p95">The Maior for the time being Daniel Tyas Roger Gough John Hadslocke John Hamburye Francis Streete Esquires</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s92">
			<head>For the Borough of Evesham</head>
			<para id="p96">The Maior of the said Borough for the time being Sir John Rows Knight Francis Hurwell William Martyn Samuel
Gardiner Thomas Cresheld Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s93">
			<head>For the County of Warwick</head>
			<para id="p97">Unto Sir Thomas Holte Knight and Baronet Sir Peter Wentworth Knight of the Bath Sir Simon Clarke Sir Job
Fisher Baronets Sir Grevill Verney Sir Edward Underhill Sir Hercules Underhill Sir Henry Gibbs Sir Thomas Lee Sir
Francis Willoughby Sir Simon Archer and Sir George Devereux Knights William Boughton William [Comb Robert
Lee William Browne Robert Andrew Richard<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Chamberlain Spencer Lucy Rowley Ward Serjeant at Law Walter
Chetwyn Clement Throckmorton Richard Shugborough John Lisle James Onyon John Temple Thomas Boughton
Anthony Stoughton Robert Shelton Thomas Combe and John Fetherston Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s94">
			<head>For the City of Coventrey</head>
			<para id="p98">Samson Hopkins Maior Henry Million John Clarke Thomas Ware Aldermen John Hayles Richard Greene Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s95">
			<head>For the County of Anglesey and Town of Bewmares</head>
			<para id="p99">Unto Sir Arthur Terringham Sir Thomas Holland Knights Thomas Bulkeley John Bodnel Hugh Owen de Boden
Owen Woods William Robinson Richard Owen Henry White William Bold Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s96">
			<head>For the County of Brecknocke</head>
			<para id="p100">Unto Henry Williams Thomas Guynn John Williams Richard Games John Walbieffe Jeoffry Jefferyes Edward
Rumsey Edward Williams Meredith Lewis Roger Vaughan Esquires William Harbert Bailiffe of Brecknock and William
Watkins Daniel Winter Lewis Meredith Hugh Meredith.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s97">
			<head>For the County of Cardigan</head>
			<para id="p101">Unto Sir Marmaduke Lloyd Knight Richard Price James Lewis Henry Vaughan Evan Gwynn John Stedman
Thomas Price John Pugh David Evans John Phillips Esquires and John Vaughan Esquire.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s98">
			<head>For the County of Carmarthen</head>
			<para id="p102">Unto Sir Richard Vaughan Knight of the Bath and Earle of Carbery Sir Rees Rudd Baronet Sir William
Vaughan Knight Henry Jones David Gwynn Richard Vaughan Rowland Gwynn Richard Phillips John Harris Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s99">
			<head>For the Borough and County of the Borough of Carmerthen</head>
			<para id="p103">Unto Morris James Esquire Maior Sir Richard Vaughan Knight of the Bath and Earle of Carbery Griffith Lewes
Martin Bynon Thomas Wood Lewes Jones [Thomas Jones<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] Rowland Phillips and John Bloome Aldermen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s100">
			<head>For the County of Carnarvan</head>
			<para id="p104">Unto Sir Richard Wynn Knight and Baronet Sir William Williams Baronet and unto Thomas Glynn Griffith
Jones John Griffith Owen Wynn William Thomas John Owen Griffith Thomas Humphrey Jones Thomas Glynn of
Wanley William Glynn John Bodarda John Robins Thomas Madryn William Griffith William Lloyd Arthur Williams
Hugh Griffith Hugh Wynn Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s101">
			<head>For the County of Denbigh</head>
			<para id="p105">Unto Sir Thomas Salisbury Baronet Sir Thomas Middleton Sir Edward Broughton Knights William Wynn Robert
Wynn Roger Holland John Lloyd Simon Theloall Gerard Eyton Thomas Trafford Edward Thelloall John
Roden Richard Lloyd Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s102">
			<head>For the County of Flint</head>
			<para id="p106">Unto Sir Thomas Hanmer Baronet Sir Roger Mostyn Knight [Sir<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Thomas Brewerton Knight Sir Thomas Mostyn
Knight Richard Grosvenor Thomas Ravenscrofte Humphrey Dymocke Robert Davies Thomas Mostyn John Mostyn
and John Pilson Esquires John Salisbury John Eaton Robert Morgan William Mostyn Peter Griffith and Peter
Evans Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s103">
			<head>For the County of Glamorgan</head>
			<para id="p107">Unto Philip Lord Harbert of Cardiff Sir William Lewes Sir Thomas Lewes Knights Edward Stradling John Carne
John Awbrey Nicholas Kemes Thomas Mathews Richard Basset William Harbert of Swansey Anthony Gwinn William
Harbert of Cogan Edward Thomas Thomas Lewis Thomas Carne David Evans Marmaduke Mathewes Watkin
Lougher Jenkin Morgan Walter Thomas Esquires and Richard Seyes Gentleman.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s104">
			<head>For the County of Merioneth</head>
			<para id="p108">Unto Sir James Price Knight William Salisbury Edmond Merrick Hugh Nanny William Lewes Lewes Anwell
William Wynn John Lloyd [Esquires<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] and John Morgan</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s105">
			<head>For the County of Pembroke</head>
			<para id="p109">Unto Sir Richard Phillips Baronet John Langhorne Thomas ap Rice Hugh Bowen Arthur Owen George Bowen
David Parry Lewis Barlowe and Hugh Phillips Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s106">
			<head>And for the Towne of Pembroke.</head>
			<para id="p110">Unto Phillip Thomas Esquire Maior</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s107">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Haverford West</head>
			<para id="p111">Unto William Williams Esquire Maior Sir John Stepney Baronet Maurice Cannon William Mayler John Davies
Gentlemen Jenkyn Howell Roger Bevens Aldermen William Bowen Esquire</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s108">
			<head>For the County of Mountgomery</head>
			<para id="p112">Unto Arthur Price Francis Herbert Lloyd Perce John Price and Thomas Owens Esquires and unto Edward Wynn
Charles Lloyd de Hem William Cuffyn Gentlemen Rowland Pugh Edward Corbet Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s109">
			<head>For the County of Radnor</head>
			<para id="p113">Unto William Vaughan James Price Richard Johnes John Powell Rodericke Gwyn Morgan Vaughan Nicholas
Meredith Hugh Lloyd Harbert Weston Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p114">
				<emph type="i">Commission to be delivered to Commissioners before Feb. 10th, 1640, and Ten Schedules, and also Schedules and Certificates of Popish Recusants, and to execute Commission and sever themselves</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p115">Which Commissions for the payment of the said Subsidies shall be severally and respe&bholigct;ively delivered to the said
Commissioners or to one of them before the tenth day of February in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand
six hundred fourty And to every of the said Commissions ten Schedules containing in them the tenour of this A&bholigct;
shall be affiled. And for the Commissioners better discovery of Popish Recusants severall Schedules shall be delivered
unto them with theire severall Commissions out of the Exchequer and Certificates from the Clerkes of the Assizes and
of the Peace and other the like Officers and from the Ministers and Church Wardens of every Parish of the names of
such Popish Recusants as are to bee charged by this A&bholigct;. by the which Commission the Commissioners in every such
Commission named according to this A&bholigct; and as many of them as shall bee appointed by the said Commission shall
have full Power and Authority to put the effe&bholigct; of the said Commission in execution and that by authority of this
A&bholigct; after such Commission to them delivered they may by theire assents and agreements sever themselves for the
execution of theire Commission in Hundreds Lathes Wards Rapes Wapentakes Townes Parishes and other Places
within the Limitts of the said Commission in such forme as to them shall seeme expedient to be ordered and
betweene them to be communed and agreed according to the tenour and effe&bholigct; of the Commission to them therein
dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section></section>
		<section id="s110">
			<head>V. Commissioners to execute A&bholigct; according to the tenor thereof.</head>
			<para id="p116">
				<emph type="i">Persons who receive Precepts are to shew such Precepts to the other Inhabitants or Officers named therein. Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p117">And be it alsoe Ena&bholigct;ed by authoritie of this present Parliament That the Commissioners and every of them
which are named limited and appointed according to this A&bholigct; to be Commissioners in every such Shire Ryding
Lathe [Wapetake<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] Rape City Town Borough Isle and the said Houshold or any other place and none other
shall truly effe&bholigct;ually and diligently for theire parts execute the effe&bholigct; of this present A&bholigct; according to the tenour thereof
in every behalfe and no otherwise by any meanes without omission favour dread malice or any other thing
to be attempted or done by them or any of them to the contrary thereof And the said Commissioners or as many
of them as shall bee appointed by the said Commission and none other for the execution of the said Commission and
A&bholigct; shall for the taxation of the said two first Subsidies before the fifteenth day of February in the Yeere of our
Lord God One thousand six hundred fourty And for the taxation of the said twoe other of the said four Subsidies
before the twoe and twentieth day of Aprill next ensuing by vertue of the Commission delivered to them in form
aforesaid dire&bholigct; theire severall or joynt precept or precepts unto eight seaven six five foure three or twoe (as for
the number of the Inhabitants shall be requisite) of the most substantiall discreet and honest persons Inhabitants
to bee named by the said Commissioners or by as many of them as shall be appointed by the said Commission
of and in Hundreds Lathes Rapes Wapentakes Wards Parishes Townes and other places aswell within Liberties
Franchises ancient demesne places exempted and Sanctuaries as without within the limits of the Shires Rydings
Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Cities Townes Boroughs and Isle aforesaid and other Places within the limits of theire
Commission and to the Constables Subconstables Bailiffes and other like Officers &amp; Ministers of every of the
said Hundreds Towns Rapes Wapentakes Wards Parishes and other places aforesaid as to the said Commissioners
and every number of them or to three or two of them by theire discretion in division shall seeme expedient and
as by the manner and use of those parts shall be requisite straightly by the said Precept charging and commanding
the said Inhabitants Constables and other Officers aforesaid to whom such Precept shall be soe dire&bholigct;ed to appeare
in theire proper persons before the said Commissioners or such number of them as they shall divide themselves
according to the tenour of the said Commission at certain dayes and places by the said Commissioners or any such
number of them as is aforesaid within Cities Boroughs or Towns Corporate or without in any other place as is
aforesaid by theire discretion to be limited thereunto to do and accomplish all that to them on the part of the
Kings Majestie shall be enjoyned touching this A&bholigct;-Commanding further by the said Precept that he to whose
hands such Precept shall come shall shew and deliver the same to the other Inhabitants or Officers named in the same
Precept And that none of them faile to accomplish the same upon pain of forty shillings to be forfeited to the
Kings Majestie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s111">
			<head>VI. Persons named in Precepts to appear before the Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p118">
				<emph type="i">Such Persons making, Default, or refusing to serve. Penalty 40s. Upon Appearance charged; to make Enquiry into the Substance of Persons to be charged; but such Enquiry not to be taken on Oath, and to certify before Commissioners. Penalty &pound;5. Commissioners thereupon to read the Rates openly, and to declare how Certificates to be made, &amp;c. Afterwards another Day appointed by Commissioners for such Persons to appear. Not appearing. Penalty 40s; Or refusing to make Certificate. Penalty 40s. Commissioners may examine Presenters of Certificate. Further Proceedings on Assessments by Precept to Constables, &amp;c. to warn Persons named therein to appear. Oath not allowed on Enquiry into the Substance of Persons charged. Persons named in the said Precept called upon and not appearing. Penalty, Double Rate. On Enquiry into the Substance of Persons charged, Commissioners may increase Taxation. Spiritual Persons how rated for Temporal Possessions</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p119">And it is further ordained by the authority of this present Parliament that at the said day and place prefixed and
limited in the said precept every of the said Commissioners then being in the Shire and not having sufficient excuse
for his absence at the day and place prefixed for that part whereunto he was limited shall appeare in his owne
proper person and there the same Commissioners being present or as many of them as shall be appointed by the
Kings Majesties Commission shall call or cause to be called before them the said Inhabitants and Officers to whom they
have dire&bholigct;ed theire said Precepts and which had in Commandment there to appeare by vertue of the said Precept
And if any person soe warned make default unlesse he then be letted by sicknes or lawfull excuse and that let be
then witnessed by the Oathes of two credible persons [or<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] of any appearing refuse to serve in forme following then
every such person soe making default or refusing to serve shall forfeite to the Kings Majestie Forty shillings and soe
att every time appointed by the said Commissioners for the said severall taxations untill such time as the number
of every such persons have appeared and certified in forme underwritten every of them soe making default or
refusing to serve shall forfeit to the Kings Majestie fourty shillings and upon the same appearance had they shall
be charged before the Commissioners by all convenient wayes &amp; meanes other then by corporall oath to enquire
of the value of the substance after the usuall manner of every person dwelling and abiding within the limits of
the places that they shall be charged with and of other which shall have his or theire most resorte unto any of
the said places and chargeable with any s&bhouov;me of money by this A&bholigct; of the said Subsidies and all other thinges
requisite touching the said A&bholigct; and according to the intent of the same and thereupon as neere as it may be or shall
come to theire knowledge without respe&bholigct; of any former taxation heretofore had truly to present and certifie before
the said Commissioners the names and surnames and the substance and values of every of them after the usuall
manner as aforesaid aswell of Lands Tenements and other Hereditaments Possessions and Profits as of Goods Chattels
Debts and other things chargeable by the same A&bholigct; without any concealment love favour affe&bholigct;ion dread or malice
upon paine of forfeiture of five Pounds at the most to be taxed extra&bholigct;ed and levied in forme as hereafter in this
present A&bholigct; shall be limited or appointed And thereupon the said Commissioners shall openly there read or cause to
be read unto them the said rates in this A&bholigct; mentioned and openly declare the effe&bholigct; of theire charge unto them in
what manner and forme they ought and should make theire Certificates according to the rates and sums thereof
abovesaid and of all manner of persons aswell Aliens and Strangers denizens or not denizens inhabiting within this
Realme as of such Popish Recusants and [other<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] persons as be borne under the Kings obeysance chargeable to this A&bholigct;
and of the Possessions Goods and Chattells of Fraternities Guilds Corporations Brotherhoods Mysteries Communalties
and other as is abovesaid and of persons being in the parts beyond the Seas having Goods and Chattels Lands
or Tenements within this Realme as is aforesaid and of all Goods being in the custody of any person or persons to
the use of any other as is abovesaid by the which information and shewing the said persons may have such plaine
knowledge of the true intent of this present A&bholigct; and of the manner of theire Certificate that the same persons shall
have no reasonable cause to excuse them by ignorance And after such charge and the Statute of the said Subsidies
and the manner of the said Certificate to [be<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] made in writing conteyning the names &amp; sirnames of every person
and whether he be borne without the Kings Dominions or within and the value of every person in every degree
aswell of the yearely value of Lands and Tenements and of such like Possessions and Profits as of the value of
Goods and Chattells Debts and every thing to theire Certificate requisite and necessary to them declared the said
Commissioners there being shall by theire discretions limit and appoint unto the said persons another day and place
to appeare before the said Commissioners and chargeing the said persons that they shall in the meane time make
diligent enquiry by all wayes and meanes of the premisses and then and there every of them upon pain of forfeiture
of fourty shillings to the Kings Majesty to appeare att the said next prefixed day and place there to certifie unto the
said Commissioners in writing according to theire said charge and according to the true intent of the said Grant of
Subsidies and as to them in manner aforesaid hath beene declared and shewed by the Commissioners At which day
and place soe to them prefixed if any of the said persons make default or appeare and refuse to make the said
Certificate then every of them soe offending to forfeite to the Kings Majesty forty shillings (except there be a
reasonable excuse of [this<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] default by reason of his sicknesse or otherwise by the oaths of two credible persons there
witnessed) and of such as appeare ready to make Certificate as is aforesaid the said Commissioners there being shall
take and receive the same Certificate and every parte thereof and the names values and substance of every person soe
certified And if the said Commissioners see cause reasonable they shall examine the said presenters thereof and
thereupon the said Commissioners att the said dayes and places by theire Agreement amongst themselves shall from
time to time there openly prefix a day att a certain place or places within the limits of theire Commission by theire
discretion for theire further proceeding to the said assessing of the same Subsidies. And thereupon att the said day
of the said Certificate as is aforesaid taken the same Commissioners shall make theire Precept or Precepts to the
Constables Subconstables Bailiffes or other Officers of such Hundreds Wapentakes Townes or other places aforesaid
as the same Commissioners shall be of comprising and conteyning in the said Precepts the names and sirnames of
all persons presented before them in the said Certificate of whom if the said Commissioners or as many of them as
shall bee thereunto appointed by the Kings Commission shall then have vehement suspe&bholigct; to be of more greater value
or substance in Lands Goods Chattels or sums of money owing unto them or other substance aforesaid then is upon
such person or persons soe certified and specified as aforesaid the same Commissioners shall make theire Precept or
Precepts dire&bholigct;ed to the Constables Bailiffes or other Officers commanding them to whom such Precepts shall be
directed to warn such persons whose names shall be comprised in the said Precepts at theire Mansions or to theire
persons that the same persons named in such Precepts and every of them shall personally appeare before the said
Commissioners att the said new prefixed day and place there to be examined by all wayes and meanes (other then by
corporall oath) by the said Commissioners of theire Substance and value in manner as aforesaid and of all and every
sums of money owing to them and other whatsoever matter concerning the premisses or any of them according to
this A&bholigct;. At which day and place soe prefixed the said Commissioners then and there being or as many of them
as shall be thereunto appointed by the Kings Commission shall cause to be called the said persons whose names shall
be comprised in the said Precept as is aforesaid for theire examination. And if any of those persons which shall
bee warned as aforesaid to bee examined which at any time after the warning and before the day prefixed shall be
within such place as he may have knowledge of his said appearance to be made shall make default and appeare
not unlesse a reasonable cause or excuse by the Oathes of two credible witnesses before the said Commissioners
be truly alleadged for his discharge that then every of them soe making default to be taxed and charged with
and att the double sum of the rate that he should or ought to have beene set att for and after the value aforesaid
of his Lands or substance upon him certified if he had appeared by the discretion of the Commissioners there being
which Commissioners shall travell with every of the other persons soe then and there appearing whose names shall
be expressed in the said precept or precepts and in whom any vehement suspition was or shall bee had in forme
aforesaid by all wayes and meanes they can (other then by corporall oath) for there better knowledge of theire value
as aforesaid either in Hereditaments or Possessions or else in Goods or debts and thereupon shall have power and
authority by vertue of this A&bholigct; according to theire discretions to inlarge and increase the taxation of such persons
as they shall soe finde by due examination to be of greater value or substance in lands or goods then they were
presented at. And that every Spirituall Person at every of the said taxations of the said Subsidies shall be rated
and set according to the rate abovesaid of and for every pound that the same Spirituall Person or any other to
his use hath by descent bargain or purchase in Feesimple or Feetail terme of Life terme of Yeares by execution
wardshipp or copy of Court Roll in any Mannors Lands Tenements Rents Services Offices Fees Corrodies Annuities
and Hereditaments after the true just and yearely value thereof and according as other the Kings Majesties Subje&bholigct;s
born within this Realme be charged in form above remembred soe the same extend not to the yearely value of
twenty shillings or above.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s112">
			<head>VII. Assessors misbehaving.</head>
			<para id="p120">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may set a Fine upon them not exceeding &pound;10, and certify the same. Persons aggrieved by Assessment may complain to Commissioners. Proceedings thereon; Commissioners may abate or increase Assessment. False Oath of Value of Lands, &amp;c. Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p121">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed That if the said Taxers or Assessors shall not duely behave themselves in the Inquiry
Taxation Assessement or Certificate but shall affe&bholigct;ionately corruptly or partially demeane themselves in that behalfe
in such wise that the Commissioners shall by theire considerations deem them offenders worthy of punishment for
not doing theire duties therein that then four or more of the Commissioners in that County for the said Subsidies
shall have power and authority by theire discretions either to charge the said Assessors upon theire corporall oaths
for the better Service aforesaid in that behalfe or els by theire discretion to tax and set upon the said Assessors for
theire misdemeanours in that behalfe such a Fine or Pain as they shall thinke good soe that it exceed not the Sum
of ten Pounds and the same Fine or Pain at theire discretions to certifie to the persons nominated as aforesaid every
which fine soe taxed and set by foure of the said Commissioners or more and being certified with the Schedule
and Books of that limit shall be levied and answered in like manner and forme to all intents &amp; purposes as any
other sums that shall bee taxed and become due by vertue of this Statute and A&bholigct; of Subsidie and not in any otherwise
or manner. And if any person certified or rated by vertue of this A&bholigct; whether he be a Commissioner or other to
any manner of value doth find himselfe greived with the same presentment sessing or rating and thereupon complain
to the Commissioners before whom he shall be called sessed or taxed or before twoe of them before the same
taxation be certified in the Court of Exchequer that then the said Commissioners or twoe of them shall by all
wayes and meanes examine particularly and distin&bholigct;ly the person soe complaining upon his oath and other his
neighbours by theire discretions of every his Lands and Tenements above specified and of every his Goods Chattels
and Debts above mentioned and after due examination and perfe&bholigct; knowledge thereof had and perceived by the said
Commissioners or twoe of them which shall have power by authority aforesaid the said Commissioners or any twoe
of them to whom any such complaint shall be made by theire discretions upon the oath of the said person soe
complaining may abate defaulk increase or inlarge the said Assessements according as it shall appeare unto them
just upon the same examination and the same sum soe abated defaulked increased or inlarged shall be by them
certified in forme as is hereafter specified and if it be proved by witnesses or by the parties owne confession or other
lawfull wayes or meanes within a yeare after any such Oath made that the same person soe rated and sworn was
of any better or greater value in Lands Goods or other things above specified at the time of his said Oath then the
same person soe sworne did declare upon his said Oath that then every such person soe offending shall lose and
forfeit to the Kings Majestie soe much lawfull money of England as he the same person soe sworn was sett at
or taxed to pay.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s113">
			<head>VIII. Commissioners to be rated at such Place where they shall be Commissioners;</head>
			<para id="p122">
				<emph type="i">other Persons where they have resided for the most Part of the Year preceding. Absentees assessed where last abiding. Remedy for Commissioners and other Persons taxed in any Place other than where they were Commissioners, or where resiant for most Part of the preceding Year. Fee for Allowance. Double Charges not allowed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p123">And alsoe it is ena&bholigct;ed by the same authority that every person to be rated and taxed as is aforesaid shall be
rated and sett and the Sum on him set to be levied att such place where he and his family were resident for the
most part of the yeare next before the presentment and taxation made and noe where els And that noe Commissioner
for his Subsidie shall be taxed or rated for his Goods or Lands but in the shire or other place where he shall be
Commissioner And that if any person chargeable by this A&bholigct; at the time of the said Assessings happen to be out
of this Realme and out of Wales or far from the place where he shall be knowne then he to be sett where he
was last abiding in this Realm or in Wales and after the substance value and other Profits of every person to be
knowne by examination certificate or other manner of way as is aforesaid and that every person taxed in any County
or Place other then where he or his family were resiant for the most part of the yeere then next before or in any
County or Place other then where he is a Commissioner for the Subsidie If he be a Commissioner upon Certificate
made to the said Court of Exchequer under the hands and seales of two Commissioners for the same Subsidie in
the same County or place where such person and his family where resiant for the most part of the yeere then next
before or where he is a Commissioner for the taxation and payment of the same Subsidie testifying his most resiance
having a family or being a C&bhooov;missioner shall be a sufficient discharge for the taxation of that person in any other
places and of and for all other sums of money upon such persons soe set and taxed save onely the taxations made
in that county or place from which such Certificate shall be made as is aforesaid and for the sum of money upon
such person there assessed or taxed and that such Certificate without any plea or other circumstance shall be a
sufficient Warrant aswell to the Barons and Auditors of that said Court of Exchequer as to all and every other Officers
to whom the allowance thereof shall appertain paying for such discharge and allowance onely six pence and noe
more. Provided alwaies that every such person that shall be rated or taxed according to the true meaning of this
A&bholigct; for paying of and to the said Subsidies for and after the yeerely value of his Lands Tenements or other reall
Possessions or Profits at any of the said Taxations shall not after be set and rated for his Goods and Chattels or other
moveable substance at the same taxation and that he that shall be set charged or taxed for the same Subsidy for
his Goods Chattels and other moveables at any of the said taxations according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; shall
not after be taxed charged or chargeable for his Lands or other Reall Possessions or Profits aforesaid nor that any
person by any taxation be doubly charged for the said Subsidies nor set or rated at severall places by reason of
this A&bholigct; any thing contained in this present A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s114">
			<head>IX. Proviso for Persons having Two Mansions, or being Household Servants or Waiting Servants to the King or others.</head>
			<para id="p124">
				<emph type="i">Persons unduly escaping Taxation; on Proof thereof before Commissioners or Barons of the Exchequer; Taxed at Treble Value</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p125">And be it ordained and ena&bholigct;ed by the authority of this [present<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] Parliament that noe person having two Mansions
or two places to resort unto or calling himselfe Household Servant or waiting Servant to the Kings Majestie or other
Lord or Lady Master or Mistres be excused upon his saying from the taxes of the said Subsidies in neither of the
places where he may be set or taxed unlesse he bring a Certificate in writing from the Commissioners where he is
so set or taxed in deed at one place And if any person that ought to be set and taxed to these present Subsidies
by reason of his removing or resorting to two places or by reason of his saying that he was else where taxed or
by reason of any priviledge of his dwelling or abiding in any place not being foreprised in this A&bholigct; or otherwise
by his covin or craft or by any words or sayings or otherwise or if any that is a Commissioner or Assessor of others
happen to escape from the said taxations for the payment of the said Subsidies or either of them and be not set
and taxed according to the true intent of this A&bholigct; and that proved by presentment examination information or
otherwise before the said Commissioners or twoe of them or before the Barons of the Kings Majesties Exchequer
or two Justices of Peace of that County where such person dwelleth then every such person that by such meanes
or otherwaies willingly by covin or without just cause shall happen to escape from the said taxations or payments
aforesaid or any of them and shall not be rated taxed and set shall be charged upon the knowledge and proofe
thereof with and att the treple value of soe much as he should might or ought to have beene set or taxed at by
vertue of this A&bholigct; and the same treple value to be leavyed gathered and paid of his Goods and Chattels Lands
and Tenements towards the said Subsidies.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s115">
			<head>X. The Power of Commissioners to tax other Commissioners, and also Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p126">
				<emph type="i">Barons, and Persons of higher Estate, taxed by the Lord Privy Seal and others. Rate estreated and certified</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p127">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said Commissioners in every Commission which
shall be or inhabite in any County or Place within the limits of theire Commission or the more parte of them
shall have full power and authoritie by this A&bholigct; to set tax and sesse every other Commissioner joyned with them
in every such Commission. And the said Commissioners within theire division shall alsoe assesse every Assessor
within theire division for his or theire Goods Lands and other the Premisses as aforesaid by which said Commission
the C&bhooov;mission[er]s to whom it shall appertain shall indifferently set tax and sesse themselves and the said Assessors
and that aswell the s&bhouov;ms upon every of the said Commissioners and Assessors soe assessed rated and taxed as the
Sums made and presented by the Presentors as abovesaid shall be written certified set and estreated and the Estreats
thereof to be made with other the Inhabitants of that part and within the limits of the same Commission and
division soe to be gathered and leavied in like manner as it ought and should have been if the said Commissioners
had not been in the said Commission And that all persons of the Estate of a Baron or Baronesse and every
Estate above shall be charged with theire Freehold and value as is aforesaid [by Henry Earle of Manchester
Lord Privie Seale Thomas Earle of Arundell and Surrey Earle Marshall of England Phillip Earle of Pembroke
and Mountgomery Lord Chamberlain of His Majesties Household Henry Earle of Bathe Thomas Earle of Southampton
Robert Earle of Essex Edward Earle of Dorset William Earle of Salisbury Robert Earle of Warwick John Earle
of Bristoll Oliver Earle of Bullingbrooke Thomas Earle of Berks Henry Earle of Dover William Lord Viscount
Say &amp; Seale Mountague Lord Willoughby de Er Ferdinando Lord Hastings Phillip Lord Wharton Edward Lord
Mountague Charles Lord Howard de Char William Lord Grey de Warke John Lord Roberts John Lord Paulet
George Lord Goring and Thomas Lord Savill or any eleven of them or more<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] for the severall Payments of the said
Subsidies after the form of the said Grant according to the taxation aforesaid and the S&bhouov;ms of and upon them to be
taxed and set with the names of the Colle&bholigct;ors [which Colle&bholigct;ors shall bee appointed by the Lord Chancellor or
Lord Keeper of the Great Seale for the time being<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] for gathering and paying of the same to be estreated delivered
and certified at the dayes and places above specified [by the said Henry Earle of Manchester Lord Privy Seale
Thomas Earle of Arundell &amp; Surrey Earle Marshall of England Phillip Earle of Pembrooke and Mountgomery
Lord Chamberlain of His Majesties Household Henry Earle of Bathe Thomas Earle of Southampton Robert
Earle of Warwick John Earle of Bristoll Oliver Earle of Bullingbrook Thomas Earle of Berks Henry Earle of
Dover William Lord Viscount Say and Seale Mountague Lord Willoughby de Er Fardinando Lord Hastings Phillip
Lord Wharton Edward Lord Mountague Charles Lord Howard de Char William Lord Grey de Warke John Lord
Roberts John Lord Paulet George Lord Goring &amp; Thomas Lord Savill or any eleven of them or more.<ref idref="n25">25</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s116">
			<head>XI. Rates estreated under the Seals and Sign Manual of the Commissioners; and Estreats delivered to sufficient Inhabitants, &amp;c. of Hundreds, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p128">
				<emph type="i">By authority of Estreat. Officers, &amp;c. to levy Rate. Distress. If Rate not paid in Eight Days, then Distress appraised and sold. Officers, &amp;c. to answer for the Portion limited to them only, and to pay same to High Colle&bholigct;ors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p129">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that after the taxes and assesses of the said Summes upon
and by the said assessing and certificate as is aforesaid made the said Commissioners or as many of them as shall
be thereunto appointed and have authority by the Kings Majesties Commission shall withall speed and without
delay by theire writing estreat the said taxes thereof under the seales and signes manuall of the said Commissioners
or as many of them as shall be appointed att the least and the same shall deliver unto sufficient and substantiall
Inhabitants Constables Subconstables Bayliffes and other Officers jointly of Hundreds Townes Parishes and other
Places aforesaid within theire limits and to other sufficient persons Inhabitants of the same onely by the discretion
of the said Commissioners with the assent of the high Colle&bholigct;ors and as the place and parties shall require as well
the particular names and sirnames as the remembrance of all Sums of Money taxed and set of and upon every
person as well man as woman chargeable by this A&bholigct; householders and all other Inhabitants and dwellers within
the said Parishes Townes and Places contributary to this A&bholigct; of Subsidies by authority of which writing and estreat
soe delivered the said Officers and other persons soe named and deputed severally shall have full power and authority
by vertue of this A&bholigct; immediately after the delivery of the said writing or estreat to demand levie and gather of
every person therein specified the Summe and Summes (<ref idref="n26">26</ref>) the same writing or estreat comprised and for non payment
thereof to distreyne the same person or persons soe being behinde by theire Goods and Chattels and the distresse
soe taken to keepe by the space of eight dayes att the Costs and Charges of the owner thereof and if the said
owner doe not pay such summe of money as shall be taxed upon him or her by authority of this A&bholigct; within the
same eight dayes then the same distresse to be appraised by foure three or two of the Inhabitants where such distresse
is taken and alsoe then to bee sold by the Constable or other Colle&bholigct;or for the payment of the said money and the
overplus coming by the Sale (if any be) over and besides the charge of keeping the said distresse to be immediately
restored to the owner thereof which said Officers and other persons soe deputed to aske take gather and levie the
said Summes shall answeare and be charged for the Portion onely to them assigned and limited to be gathered
levied and comprised in the said writing or estreat soe [to<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] them as aforesaid delivered to the persons and uses in this
A&bholigct; expressed and the said Summe in that writing or estreat to be comprised to pay unto the high Colle&bholigct;or or
Colle&bholigct;ors of that place in manner and forme underwritten thereunto to be named &amp; deputed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s117">
			<head>XII. Commissioners may appoint Colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
			<para id="p130">
				<emph type="i">Qualification. Commissioners to deliver Estreats under their Seals and Sign Manual to Colle&bholigct;ors. Colle&bholigct;or to answer Sum comprized in Estreat</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p131">And further be it ena&bholigct;ed by the said authority (<ref idref="n28">28</ref>) that such of the said Commissioners or the more part of them as
shall take upon them the execution and businesse of the said Commission shall for the payment of the said Subsidies
name such sufficient and able persons which then shall have and possesse Lands or other Hereditaments in theire
owne right of the cleere yearely value of fourty pounds or goods to the value of foure hundred pounds at the
least as hee shall be taxed in the Subsidy booke (if any such be in the said limits) and for want of such soe assessed
then those to be appointed Colle&bholigct;ors that then shall be sufficient and rated and taxed in the Subsidy bookes in lands
and goods neerest to the values aforesaid as by theire discretions shall be thought good in Shires Ridings Lathes
Wapentakes Rapes Cities Townes Corporate and other whatsoever places as well within places priviledged as without
not being foreprised in this A&bholigct; to be high Colle&bholigct;ors and to have the Colle&bholigct;ion and receipt of the said S&bhouov;ms set
and leviable within the Precin&bholigct;s limits and bounds where they shall be soe limited and appointed to be high
Colle&bholigct;ors and to every of the said Colle&bholigct;ors soe severally named the said Commissioners or twoe of them att the
least with all speed and without delay after the said Subsidies be set by all the limits of the same theire Commission
or in such limits as the high Colle&bholigct;ors shall be soe severally assigned shall under theire seales and signes manuall
deliver one Estreat indented in Parchment comprising in it the names of all such persons as were assigned to levy
the said particular S&bhouov;ms of every Hundred [and<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] Wapentake Towne or other Place aforesaid with the names and
Sirnames of the persons soe chargeable according to the Estreat soe hereof first made and delivered as is aforesaid
and the Colle&bholigct;ors to be assigned shall be charged to answeare the whole S&bhouov;me comprised in the said Estreat limited
to his Colle&bholigct;ion as is aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s118">
			<head>XIII. Commissioners to take Recognizances of Colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
			<para id="p132">
				<emph type="i">Condition of Recognizance for first Two Subsidies; for Third and Fourth Subsidies. Commissioners to certify Recognizances into the Exchequer. Penalty, &pound; 10. Colle&bholigct;ors not making Recognizance, Penalty &pound; 20. Exchequer to cancel Recognizances on Payment of Colle&bholigct;ion into Exchequer without Fee. Colle&bholigct;ors may appoint Days and Places for Payment of Colle&bholigct;ion. Assessor, &amp;c. not paying Colle&bholigct;ion to High Colle&bholigct;or, abating the Allowance of 1d. in the Pound. Distress. Proceedings thereon. Persons living in Cities, &amp;c. not to be appointed Colle&bholigct;ors or Assessors out of them</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p133">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said Commissioners having authority by
this A&bholigct; to nominate the high Colle&bholigct;ors of the said Subsidies shall immediately upon that nomination and ele&bholigct;ion
take by authority of this present Parliament sufficient Recognizances or Obligations without any Fee or Reward to be
paid therefore of every person soe by them to be named to be high Colle&bholigct;ors to be bound to the Kings Majestie
in the double sum of the sum of his Colle&bholigct;ion and to be endorsed and made upon such condition that is to say for
the due [Colle&bholigct;ions<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] and payment of the said twoe first Subsidies that if the said Colle&bholigct;or his heires or executors
doe truly content and pay to the persons aforesaid at the place aforesaid at or before the tenth day of February now
next comeing soe much of the said s&bhouov;me of money allotted and appointed to his Colle&bholigct;ion that he shall colle&bholigct;
and gather and content and pay the residue of his Colle&bholigct;ion and Charge within one moneth next after such time as
he hath colle&bholigct;ed and gathered the same residue that then the said recognizance or obligation to be void And for the
colle&bholigct;ion of the said two other of the said foure Subsidies upon condition that if the said Colle&bholigct;or his heires or
executors doe truly content and pay to the persons aforesaid at the place aforesaid at or before the tenth day of May
next ensuing soe much of the said s&bhouov;me of money allotted and appointed to his Colle&bholigct;ion as he shall colle&bholigct; and
gather and content and pay the residue of his colle&bholigct;ion and charge within one moneth next after such time as hee
hath colle&bholigct;ed and gathered the same residue that then the said Recognizance or Obligation to be void or else to
stand in full strength and vertue which said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Recognizance or Obligation soe taken the said
Commissioners shall severally certifie and deliver into His Majesties Court of Exchequer with the severall Certificates
of the said taxations and rates of the payment of the said Subsidies at and by the times to them prescribed and
appointed by this A&bholigct; for the certificate of the said taxations of the said Subsidies upon paine of forfeiture of ten
pounds to the Kings Majestie for every Recognizance or Obligation not soe certified And that every such Colle&bholigct;or
soe named and chosen upon request to him made shall acknowledge and make the said Recognizance or Obligation
upon pain of forfeiture of twentie pounds to the Kings Majestie for [the<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] refusall thereof And that the Treasurer
and Barons of the Exchequer for the time being upon payment of the said severall colle&bholigct;ions of the subsidies at the
dayes and times herein limited for the payment thereof shall cancell and deliver the Recognizances or Obligations for
the payment thereof to the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors without any other Warrant and without any fee or reward to bee
paid for the same to any person And every Colle&bholigct;or soe deputed having the said Estreat in parchment as is aforesaid
shall have authority by this A&bholigct; to appoint dayes and places within the circuit of his Colle&bholigct;ion for the payment of the
said Subsidies to him to be made and thereof to give warning by Proclamation or otherwise to all the Constables or
other persons or inhabitants having the charge of the particular Colle&bholigct;ion [with<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] the Hundreds Parishes Townes or
other places by him or them limited to make payment of the said particular colle&bholigct;ion of every sum as to them shall
appertein and if at the same day and place so limited and &bhopcrl;fixed by the said high Colle&bholigct;or the said Constable Officers
or other persons or inhabitants as is aforesaid for the said particular Colle&bholigct;ion assigned and appointed within such
Hundred City Towne or other Place doe not pay unto the said high Colle&bholigct;or the Sum within theire severall Hundreds
Townes Parishes and other Places due and comprised in the said Estreat thereof to them delivered by the said
Commissioners or some of them as is aforesaid or so much thereof as they have by any meanes received (one penny
for every pound for the said particular colle&bholigct;ion as is aforesaid alwaies thereof to be allowed excepted and abated)
that then it shall be lawfull to the said high Colle&bholigct;ors and every of them and to theire Assignes to distrain every
of the said Constables Officers and other Inhabitants for theire said severall and particular colle&bholigct;ion of the said Sums
comprised in the said Estreat and writing thereof to them and every of them as is before expressed delivered or for
soe much of the same s&bhouov;m as soe then shall happen to be gathered and leavied and behinde and unpaid by the
Goods and Chattels of every of them soe being behinde and the distresse soe taken to be kept and appraised and
sold as is aforesaid and thereof to take and leavy the sums soe then being behinde and unpaid and the overplus
coming of the Sale of the said distresse (if any bee) to be restored and delivered unto the owner in form above
remembred. Provided alwaies that noe person inhabiting in any City Borough or Towne Corporate shall be compelled
to be any Assessor or Colle&bholigct;or of or for any part of the said Subsidies in any place or places out of the said City
Borough or Towne Corporate where he dwelleth.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s119">
			<head>XVII. Assessors, Attornies, Fa&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. after being charged with Receipt of Assessment, dying or removing or concealing their Goods, &amp;c. or when Monies comprized in Estreat cannot be levied by Distress, or where Distress cannot be sold;</head>
			<para id="p134">
				<emph type="i">Process out of the Exchequer, and the Commissioners may dire&bholigct; Precepts to Officer to levy such Money; 
Commissioners to dire&bholigct; Precepts to Officers, who by virtue thereof may distrain. Distress appraised and sold. If Distress taking out of Limit assigned, Allowance. Persons charged discharged by Distress. Persons distrained having no Lands, &amp;c. Proceedings. Imprisonment until Sums due, and also Fee for Arrest paid. Officer not executing Process. Penalty 20s. Gaoler suffering Escape. Penalty 40s. and Double Value of Rate and Fees. Like Process for Subsidies due by any Persons charged for another unpaid. Certificate of Default, Imprisonment, &amp;c. by Commissioners. Colle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. disobeying Commissioners; 
or Persons suspe&bholigct;ed not to be indifferently taxed refusing to be examined, or resisting Distress, &amp;c. Penalty 40s. or under, at Discretion of Commissioners. Commissioners may punish by Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p135">And it is alsoe by the said authority ena&bholigct;ed that if any Inhabitants or Officers or whatsoever other person or
persons charged to and for the Colle&bholigct;ion and receipt of any part or portion of the said Subsidies by any manner of
meanes according to this A&bholigct; or any person or persons for themselves or as keeper guardian deputy fa&bholigct;or or atturney
of or for any other person or persons for any Goods or Chattels of the owner thereof at the time of the said
assessing to be paid being out of this Realm or in any other parts not knowne or of or for the Goods and Chattels
of any other person or persons of any Corporation Fraternity Mystery or other whatsoever Comunalty being Corporate
or not Corporate and all persons having in theire rule governance and custody any Goods or Chattels at the time
of the said assessing to be made or which for any cause for or by colle&bholigct;ion or for himselfe or for any other or by
reason hee hath any rule governance or custody of any goods or chattels of any other person or persons Corporation
C&bhooov;munalty Fraternity Guild or Mystery or any such other like or as fa&bholigct;or deputy or atturney of or for any person
shall be taxed valued rated and set to any sum or sums by reason of this A&bholigct; and after the taxation and assessing
upon any such person or persons as shall be charged with the receipt of the same happen to die or depart from
the place where he was soe taxed and set or his goods or chattels to be soe eloyned or in such privy or covert manner
kept as the same person or persons charged with the same by estreats or other writings from the said Commissioners or
as many of them as shall be thereunto appointed by the said Commission as is aforesaid can ne may leavy the same
sum and sums comprised within the same Estreats by distresse within the limits of theire Colle&bholigct;ion as is aforesaid or
cannot sell such distresse or distresses as be taken for any of the said payments before the time limited to the high
Colle&bholigct;or for his payment to be made as aforesaid then upon relation thereof with due examination by the oath or
examination of such person or persons as shall be charged with and for the receipt and colle&bholigct;ion of the same before
the said Commissioners or as many of them as by the [same<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] Commission shall be thereunto appointed where such
person or persons or other as is aforesaid theire Goods and Chattels were set and taxed and upon plain Certificate
thereof made by the same Commissioners as well of the dwelling place names and sums of the said persons of whom
the said Sums cannot be leavied and had as is aforesaid then as well the Constable and other Inhabitants appointed for
the same particular Colle&bholigct;ion against the high Colle&bholigct;or as the high Colle&bholigct;or upon his account and oath in the
said Exchequer to be discharged thereof and Processe to bee made in the Kings Majesties name out of the same
Exchequer by the discretion of the Barons of the same Exchequer against such person his heires or executors soe
being behinde with his payment And over that the same Commissioners to whom any such declaration of the
&bhopcrl;misses shall be made in forme aforesaid from time to time shall have full power and authority to dire&bholigct; theire precept
or precepts to the said person or persons charged with any sum of for and upon any such person and persons or
other as is aforesaid or to any Sheriffe Steward Bailiffe or other whatsoever Officer Minister person or persons of such
place or places where any such person or persons soe owing any such sum or sums shall have Lands or Tenements
and other Hereditaments or reall Possessions Goods and Chattells whereby any such person or persons so indebted his
heires executors or assignes or other having the custody governance or disposition of any goods or chattells Lands
Tenements or other hereditaments which ought or may by this A&bholigct; be lawfully distreined or taken for the same hath
and shall have Goods Chattels Lands Tenements or other possessions whereof such Sum and Sums which by any such
person or persons may or ought to be leavied be it within the limits of such Commission where such person or persons
was or were taxed or without in any place within this realme of England Wales or other the Kings Majesties Dominions
Marches or Territories by which Precept as well such person or persons shall be charged to leavy such money as the
Officer of the place or places where such distresse may be taken shall have full power and authority to distreyn every
such person indebted charged or chargeable by this A&bholigct; or his Executors or Administrators of his goods and chattels
his guardians fa&bholigct;ors deputies lessees farmours and assignes and all other persons by whose hands or out of whose
lands any such person should have Fee Rent Annuity or other profit or which at the time of the said assessing shall
have goods or Chattels or any other thing moveable of any such person or persons being indebted or owing such
summe and the distresses soe taken cause to be kept appraised and sold in like manner and forme as is aforesaid
for the distresse to be taken upon such persons to be taxed to the said Subsidies and being sufficient to distrein within
the limits of the Colle&bholigct;ors Inhabitants or other Officers charged with or for the said Sums soe upon them to be taxed
and if any such distresse for non payment happen to be taken out of the limit of the said persons charged and
assigned to leavy the said persons soe charged for the levying of any such sums by distresse shall perceive and take
of the same distresse for the labour of every person goeing for the execution thereof for every mile that every person
soe laboureth for the same two pence and every farmour guardian tenant fa&bholigct;our or other whatsoever person being
distreined or other person charged for payment of any such sum or sums or any other summe by reason of this
A&bholigct; shall be of such sum or sums of him or them soe levied and taken discharged and acquitted at his next day of
payment for the same or at the delivery of such goods and chattels as he that is so distreyned had in his custody or
governance against him or them that shall bee soe taxed and set (any Grant or writing obligatory or other whatsoever
matter to the contrary made heretofore notwithstanding) And if any such person that should [be soe<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] distreined have
no Lands or Tenements sufficient whereby he and his Tenants and Farmours may be distreined or have aliened eloyned
or had his Goods and Chattels whereby he should or might be distreyned in such manner that such goods or chattels
should not be knowne or found soe that the sum of or by him to be paid in the said forme shall not ne can (<ref idref="n35">35</ref>) be
conveniently levied then upon relation thereof to the Commissioners or to as many of them as by the said Commission
shall be thereunto appointed where such person or persons was taxed and set by the oathes of him or them that
shall be charged with the levying and payment of that summe or summes the same Commissioners shall make a
precept in such manner as is aforesaid for to attach take and arrest the body of such person or persons that ought
to pay the said sums and by this A&bholigct; shall be charged with and for the said Sum and Sums and them soe taken
safely to keepe in prison within the shire or other place where any such person or persons shall be taken and attached
there to remaine without baile or mainprise untill he have paid the (<ref idref="n36">36</ref>) Sum or Sums that such person for himselfe or
for any other by this A&bholigct; shall be chargeable or ought to be charged withall and alsoe for the Fees of every such
Arrest to him or them that shall execute such Precept twentie pence and that every Officer unto whom such Precept
shall be dire&bholigct;ed do his true diligence and execute the same upon every person soe being indebted upon pain to
forfeit to the Kings Majestie for every default in that behalfe twenty shillings And that no keeper of any Gaole
from his Gaole suffer any person to goe att large by letting to baile or otherwise to depart out of his prison before
he hath paid the said debt and the said twenty pence for his arrest upon pain to forfeit to the Kings Majestie
fourtie shillings and the said Gaoler to pay to the Kings Majestie the double value aswell of the rate which the said
person soe imprisoned was taxed at as of the said twentie pence for the Fees and like Processe and remedy in like
manner forme shall be granted by the said Commissioners or as many of them as by the said Commission shall be
thereunto appointed at like information of every person or persons being charged with any sum of money for any
other person or persons by reason of the said Subsidies and not thereof paid but wilfully withdrawne nor the same
levyable within the limits where such persons were thereunto taxed and if the Sum or Sums being behinde unpaid
by any person or persons as is aforesaid be leavyed &amp; gathered by force of the said Processe to be made by the
said Commissioners or if in default or for lack of payment thereof the person or persons soe owing the said Sum
and Sums of money by processe of the same Commissioners to be made as is aforesaid be committed to prison in
forme abovesaid that then the said [Commissioner<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] which shall award such Processe shall make certificate of that
shall be done in the &bhopcrl;misses after such sum or sums of money soe being behinde shall be leavyed and gathered
of such person or persons for non payment of the same comitted to prison And if it happen any of the said
Colle&bholigct;ors to be assigned or any Maiors Sheriffes Stewards Constables Headboroughs Bursholders Bailiffes or any
other Officer or Minister or other whatsoever person or persons to disobey the said Commissioners or any of them
in the reasonable request to them made by the said Commissioners for the execution of the said Commission or if
any of the Officers or other persons doe refuse that to them shall appertain and belong to doe by reason of any
Precept to him or them to be dire&bholigct;ed or any reasonable commandement instance or request touching the &bhopcrl;misses
or other default in any appearance or colle&bholigct;ion to make or if any person [be<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] suspe&bholigct;ed not to bee indifferently taxed
as is aforesaid do refuse to be examined according to the tenour of this A&bholigct; before the said Commissioners or as
many of them as shall be thereunto assigned as is aforesaid or will not appeare before the same Commissioners upon
warning to him made or else make resistance or rescues upon any distresse upon him to be taken for any parcell
of the said Subsidies or commit any misdemeanour in any manner or wise contrary to this A&bholigct; or commit any wilfull
omission or other whatsoever wilfull doeing or misdoing contrary to the tenour of this A&bholigct; or grant the same
Commissioners and every number of them above remembred or two of them at the least upon certaine knowledge
of any such misdemeanour had by information or examination shall and may set upon every such offendour for
every such offence in the name of a fine by the same offendour to be forfeited forty Shillings or under by discretion
of the same Commissioners And further the said Commissioners and every number of them or twoe of them
att the least shall have authority by this present A&bholigct; to punish every such offendor by imprisonment there to
remaine and to be delivered by theire [discretions<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] as shall seeme to them convenient the said fines if any such be
to be certified by the said Commissioners that soe assessed the same into the Kings Majesties Exchequer to be levyed
and payed by the Colle&bholigct;ors of that part for the said Subsidies returned into the said Exchequer to be therewith
charged with the payment of the same Subsidies in such manner as if the said fines had beene set and taxed upon
the said Offendors for the said Subsidies.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s120">
			<head>XVII. Allowance to High Colle&bholigct;ors and their Accountants.</head>
			<para id="p136">
				<emph type="i">Allowance to be paid by Colle&bholigct;ors to Commissioners for their Expences and the Labour of their Clerks. Remedy for the same for Commissioners against Colle&bholigct;ors. Commissioners, &amp;c. not to be named Colle&bholigct;ors, nor compellable to make Presentment other than to Exchequer. Head Colle&bholigct;ors discharged of Fees, &amp;c. Taking Fees of Accountants Penalty. Imprisonment. Commissioners at Meetings to shew Certificates and Presentments to the other Commissioners. Indenture of Colle&bholigct;ors Names, and of Sums written to Colle&bholigct;ors, Fines, &amp;c. to be certified by Commissioners into the Exchequer; 
Colle&bholigct;ors answerable for their own Colle&bholigct;ion only. Commissioners, if they cannot agree, may make several Indentures of their several Limits, &amp;c. Colle&bholigct;ors not chargeable for other Colle&bholigct;ors. Commissioners or Colle&bholigct;ors or Persons taxed, dying before discharged, Heirs and Executors chargeable as such Persons would have been if alive. Commissioners not thinking fit to join in one Certificate, Proceedings. Commissioners making Default of Certificate, Process out of Exchequer against them</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p137">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by the said Authority of this present Parliament that every of the said high Colle&bholigct;ors
which shall accompt for any part of the said Subsidies upon theire severall Accompts to be yeilded shall be allowed
upon payment of the money chargeable upon his colle&bholigct;ion for every pound limited to his Colle&bholigct;ion whereof any
such Colle&bholigct;or shall be charged and yeeld accompt three pence as parcell of theire charge (that is to say) of every
pound thereof for such persons as then have had the particular colle&bholigct;ion of the Towns and other places (as is aforesaid)
specified in his colle&bholigct;ion one penny and one other peny of every pound thereof (every of the said cheife Colle&bholigct;ors
or theire accomptants to retain to theire owne use for theire labour and charge in and about the premisses and
one peny of every pound residue to be delivered allowed and payed by the said Colle&bholigct;or soe being thereof allowed
to such of the Commissioners as shall take upon them the busines and labour for and about the &bhopcrl;misses) that is
to say every Colle&bholigct;or to pay that Commissioner or Commissioners which had the ordering of the writing of and
for the said Subsidies where the said Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors had theire Colle&bholigct;ion for the expences for the said
Commissioners soe taking upon them the said busines and labour of theire Clerks writing the said Precepts and
Extra&bholigct;s of the said Colle&bholigct;ions the said last peny of every pound to be devided amongst the said Commissioners
having regard to theire labour and busines taken by them and theire said Clerks in and about the &bhopcrl;misses For which
part soe to the said Commissioners appertaining the said Commissioners six five foure three or two or as many of
them as shall be thereunto appointed by the Kings Majesties Commission and every of them jointly and severally
for his and theire said part may have his remedy against the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors which thereof been or might have
beene allowed by A&bholigct;ion of debt in which the defendant shall not wage his law neither prote&bholigct;ion neither Injun&bholigct;ion
or Essoine shall be allowed And that no person now being a member of this present Parliament nor any Commissioner
shall be named or assigned to be any Colle&bholigct;or or Subcolle&bholigct;or or Presentor of the said Subsidies or any part thereof
nor any Commissioner shall be compelled to make any Presentment or Certificate other then into the Kings Majesties
said Exchequer of for or concerning the said Subsidies or any part or parcell thereof and likewise that noe other
person that shall be named and assigned to be Commissioners in any place to and for the execution of this A&bholigct; of
Subsidies be or shall be assigned or named head colle&bholigct;or of any [of<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] the said Subsidies neither of any part thereof
and that every such person and persons which shall be nominated and appointed as is aforesaid to be head Colle&bholigct;ors
of and for the payment of the said Subsidies or of any part thereof be and shall be acquitted and discharged of
all manner of Fees and rewards and of every other charge in the Kings Majesties Exchequer or else where of them
or any of them by reason of that colle&bholigct;ion payment or accompt or any thing concerning the same to be asked and
that if any person receive or take any Fees Rewards or Pleasures of any such Accomptants or use any unnecessary
delay in theire account that then he shall forfeit to the Kings Majestie for every peny or value of every peny soe
taken five Shillings and five pounds to the party greived for every such delay and suffer imprisonment at the Kings
Majesties pleasure And after every taxing and assessing of the said Subsidies (as is aforesaid) had or made and the
said Extra&bholigct;s thereof in Parchment unto the Colle&bholigct;or in manner and forme before rehearsed delivered the said
Commissioners which shall take upon them the execution of this A&bholigct; within the limits of theire said Commission
by theire Agreements shall have meetings together at which meeting every of the said Commissioners which then
shall have taken upon them the execution of any part of the said Commission shall by himselfe or his sufficient
Deputy truly certifie and bring forth unto the said Commissioners named in the said Commission the Certificate and
Presentment made before him and such other Commissioners as were limited with him in one limit (soe as the
same Certificate may be accompted and cast with the other Certificates of the other limits within the same
Commission) and then the said Commissioners and every number of them unto twoe at the least as is aforesaid if
any be in life or theire Executors or Administrators of theire goods if they then be dead shall joyntly and severally
as they were divided within theire limits under theire seales by theire discretions make one or severall writings indented
containing in it aswell the names of the said Colle&bholigct;ors by the Commissioners for such Colle&bholigct;ions and Accompts in
the Exchequer and payments and assigned as the grosse and severall sums written unto every such Colle&bholigct;ors to
receive the said Subsidies and alsoe all Fines Amerciaments and other Forfeitures if any such be by reason of this
A&bholigct; happen to be within the limit and precin&bholigct; of theire Commission to be certified into the Kings Majesties said
Exchequer by the said Commissioners in which writing or writings indented so to be certified shall be plainly declared
&amp; expressed the whole and entire Sum and Sums of the said Subsidies severally limited to the Colle&bholigct;ion of
the said Colle&bholigct;ors severally deputed and assigned to the said Sums soe as none of the said Colle&bholigct;ors so certified
in the said Exchequer shall be compelled there to accompt or be charged but onely to and for the Sums limited
to his Colle&bholigct;ion and not to or for any Sum limited to the colle&bholigct;ion of his Fellowes but every of them shall be severally
charged for theire part limited to theire Colle&bholigct;ion And if the said Commissioners joyned in one Commission
amongst themselves in that matter cannot agree or if any of them be not ready or refuse to make certificate with
the other of the same Commissioners that then the said Commissioners may make severall Indentures in form aforesaid
of theire severall limits or separations of Colle&bholigct;ors within the limits of theire Commission upon and in the Hundreds
Wards Wapentakes Lathes Rapes or such other like divisions within the said severall limits of theire Commission
as the places there shall require to be severed and devided and as [to<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] the same Commissioners shall seeme good to
make divisions or other limits or colle&bholigct;ions for the severall Charges of the same Colle&bholigct;ors soe that alway one
Colle&bholigct;or shall be charged and [accompted<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] for his part to him to be limited onely by himselfe and not for any Sum
limited to the part of any of his Fellowes and the Charges of every of the Colle&bholigct;ors to be set and certified severally
upon them and every such Colle&bholigct;or upon his Accompt and payment of the Sum of Money limited within his
Colle&bholigct;ion to be severally by himselfe acquitted and discharged in the said Exchequer without paying any manner
of Fees or Rewards to any person or persons for the same upon pain and penalty last abovesaid and not to be
charged for any portion of any other Colle&bholigct;or. And if any Commissioner after he hath taken Certificate of
them that as is aforesaid shall be before any Commissioners examined and the Sums rated and set and the Books
and Writings thereof being in his hands or if any Colle&bholigct;or or other person charged with any receipt of any part
of the said Subsidies or any other person taxed or otherwise by this A&bholigct; charged with or for any parcell of the
said Subsidies or with any other Sum Fine Amerciament penalty or other forfeiture happen to die before the
Commissioners Colle&bholigct;ors or other whatsoever person or persons have executed accomplished satisfied or sufficiently
discharged that which to every such person shall appertain or belong to do according to this A&bholigct; then the Executors
and Heires of every such person and all other seised of any Lands and Tenements that any such person being
charged by this A&bholigct; and deceasing before he be discharged thereof or any other to his use onely had of an
Estate of Inheritance at the time that any such person was named Commissioner Colle&bholigct;or or otherwise charged with
or for any manner of thing to be done satisfied or paid by reason of this A&bholigct; And all those that have in theire possession
or hands any Goods Chattels Leases or other things that were to any such person or persons at the time of his death
or any Lands or Tenements that were the same persons at the time that he was as is aforesaid charged by this
A&bholigct; shall be by the same compelled and charged to doe and accomplish in every case as the same person so being
charged should have done or might have beene compelled to doe if he had bene in plene life after such rate of the
Lands and Goods of the said Commissioner and Colle&bholigct;or as the party shall have in his hands And if the said
Commissioners for causes reasonable then moving shall think it not fitt to joyne in one Certificate as is aforesaid
then the said person or persons that shall first joyne togeather or hee that shall first certifie the said Writing
indented as is aforesaid shall certifie all the names of the Commissioners of that Commission whereupon such
writing shall be there then to be certified with the division of the Hundreds Wapentakes Wards Tithings and other
places to and among other such Commissioners of the same Commission with the names of the said Commissioners
where such separations and divisions shall be with the grosse Sums of Money as well of and for the said Subsidies
taxed or set of or within the said Hundreds Wards Wapentakes or other places to him or them divided or assigned
that shall soe certifie the said first Writings as of the fines Amerciaments Penalties and other forfeitures if any happen
to be within the same limits whereof the same writings shall be certified And after such writings indented which as is
aforesaid shall be certified and not contain in it the whole and full Sums set and taxed within the limits of the
same Commission the other Commissioners of the same before the day of payment of the said Subsidies shall
certifie into the said Exchequer by theire Writing or Writings indented to be made as is aforesaid the grosse and
severall Sums set and taxed within the places to them limited for every of the said Subsidies and other Fines
Amerciaments Penalties and Forfeitures with the names of the Hundreds Wards Wapentakes and other places to
them assigned or else by theire said Writings indented to certifie at the same place before the same day of payment
such reasonable causes for theire excuses why they may not make such certificate of and for the said Subsidies
Fines Amerciaments and other Forfeitures growing or set by reason of the causes of theire lets or of theire not
certifying as is aforesaid or else in default thereof Processe to be made out of the Kings Majesties said Exchequer against
the said Commissioners every of them not making Certificate as is aforesaid or else in default thereof Processe to
be made out of the Kings [Majestie<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] said Exchequer against the said Commissioners and every of them not making
Certificate as is aforesaid by the discretion of the Treasurer and Barons of the said Exchequer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s121">
			<head>XIX. Proviso for Stamford Baron.</head>
			<para id="p138">Provided alwayes and be [<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] it enacted by the authority aforesaid that the Inhabitants of the Parish of Saint Martin
called Stamford Baron in the Suburbs of the Borough and Town of Stamford in the South Part of the Waters there
called Wellands which hereafter shall be contributary to the payment of the said Subsidies shall be assessed rated
and taxed for the same by such Commission[er]s which shall be appointed as aforesaid for the taxing rating &amp; assessing
of the same Subsidies within the County of Lincoln and shall be for the same contributary and pay to the Colle&bholigct;or
or Colle&bholigct;ors which shall be assigned and appointed for the levying and gathering of the same as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s122">
			<head>XX. Persons having Temporal and Spiritual Possessions, and also Personal Property, not to be doubly charged.</head>
			<para id="p139">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey, and Guernsey. Proviso for Patents of Liberties, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p140">Provided alwaies and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that all and every person and persons
having Mannors Lands Tenements and other Hereditaments chargeable to the payment of the said Subsidies granted
by this A&bholigct; and alsoe having Spirituall Possessions chargeable to his Majestie by any Grant made or to be made by
the Clergie of this Realme in theire Convocation and over this having substance in goods and Chattels chargeable
by the said A&bholigct; that then if any of the said person or persons be hereafter charged assessed and taxed for the said
Mannors Lands and Tenements and spirituall Possessions and alsoe charged assessed and taxed for his and theire
Goods and Chattels that then he or they shall be onely charged by vertue of this A&bholigct; for his and theire said
Mannors Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Spirituall Possessions or onely for his said Goods and Chattels the
best thereof to be taken and not to be charged for both or doubly charged for any of them any thing in this A&bholigct;
contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding Provided alwaies that this Grant of Subsidies or any thing therein
contained in any wise extend not to charge the Inhabitants of Scotland Ireland Jersey and Garnsey or any of them
of for or concerning any Mannors Lands Tenements or other Possessions Goods Chattels or other moveable substance
which the said Inhabitants or dwellers or any others to theire Use have within Scotland Ireland Jersey and Garnsey
or in any of them or of for or concerning any Fees or Wages which any of the said Inhabitants or dwellers have
of the Kings Majestie for theire attendance and doing Service to our Soveraigne Lord the Kings Majestie in Scotland
Ireland [Jersey<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] and Garnsey or any of them any thing in this present A&bholigct; to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding
Provided alsoe that all Letters Patents granted by the Kings Majestie or any of his noble Progenitors to any Cities
Boroughs or Townes within this Realme of any manner of Liberties Priviledges or Exemptions from the burthen
and charge of any such Grants of Subsidies which be at this present time in force and available shall remaine
good and effe&bholigct;uall to the said Cities Boroughs and Townes hereafter according to the purports thereof although
the Inhabitants of the same and alsoe the said Corporations shall upon the great and weighty considerations of
the Grant aforesaid be for this Grant charged and contributary in like manner forme and sort as other Cities
Boroughs and Townes which be not in any wise priviledged but by this A&bholigct; charged.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s123">
			<head>XVIII. Orphans and Infants not chargeable to Subsidies.</head>
			<para id="p141">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That no Orphant or Infant within the age of one
and twenty yeares borne within any of the Kings Majesties Dominions shall be charged to the payment of the
Subsidies for his or theire Goods and Chattels to him or her left or bequeathed any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to
the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s124">
			<head>XIX. Proviso for Universities of Oxford and Cambridge, Winchester College, Eton College, Poor Knights of Windsor, and Free Schools, and Readers, &amp;c. in the Universities, and for Hospitals, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p142">Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend to the Lands or Goods of any
Colledge Hall or Hostell within the Universities of Oxon and Cambridge or any of them or to the Goods or
Lands of the Colledge of Winton founded by Bishop Wickham or to the Goods or Lands of the Colledge
of Eaton next Windsor or to the Lands Tenements or Revenues onely assigned and appointed for the sustentation
and living of the poore Knights founded in the Castle or Colledge of Windsor by our late Soveraigne Lord
King Henry the Eight or to any the Goods or Chattels of the same Knights or any of them or to the Goods or
Lands of any C&bhooov;mon Free Grammar Schoole within the Realme of England or Wales or the Goods of any Reader
Schoolmaster or Scholer or any Graduate resiant or remaining for studie without fraud or covin within any the said
Universities and Colledges or Townes of Oxford and Cambridge or Suburbes of the same or to any of them or to
any of theire Servants attending dayly upon any of them nor to the Goods of any Officer Minister Almesmen or
Servants belonging to any of the said Universities Colledges Halls or Hostells and dwelling and resiant within the
said Universities or either of them or within either of the said Townes of Oxford &amp; Cambridge and the Suburbs of
the same without fraud or covin or to the Goods and Lands of any Hospitall Measondieu or Spittlehouse prepared
and used for the sustentation and reliefe of poore people any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s125">
			<head>XX. Inhabitants of Cinque Ports for the most Part of the Year before the Grant not chargeable during Resiance only.</head>
			<para id="p143">Provided alsoe and be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the said Grant of Subsidies or any thing therein contained do
not in any wise extend or be prejudiciall or hurtfull to any of the Inhabitants or resiants having dwelt for the most
part of the yeare next before the taxing and assessing of the Subsidies aforesaid within the Five Ports Corporate or
to any theire members incorporated or united to the said Five Ports but such the Inhabitants or Resiants as aforesaid
in the said Five Ports Corporate and theire members be and shall be of and from the same Grant and payment of
every of the said Subsidies and every part thereof and onely during theire resiance as aforesaid and no longer clearly
acquitted and discharged any matter or whatsoever thing in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; had or made to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s126">
			<head>XXI. Like Proviso for Inhabitants of Rumney Marsh.</head>
			<para id="p144">Provided alsoe that the said Grant of Subsidies do not in any wise extend tobe prejudiciall or hurtfull to the English
Inhabitants or Resiants at this present time within the liberties of Rumney Marsh of or for any part of the said
Sums granted in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament of the said English Inhabitants now there resiants or any of them to be taxed
set asked levied or paid but that the English Inhabitants and now resiants of Rumney Marsh aforesaid and every of
them be and shall be of and from the Grant and Payment of the said Subsidies during theire resiance there and
no longer acquitted and discharged any matter and whatsoever thing in this present A&bholigct; made to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s127">
			<head>XXII. Alien or Denizen assigning his Lands, &amp;c. to his Child with Intent to defraud the Subsidy, such Child chargeable as an Alien.</head>
			<para id="p145">Provided neverthelesse and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that if any Alien or Stranger born denizen or
not denizen and dwelling and inhabiting within this Realme of England shall assigne and convey over unto any his
or theire Child or Children borne within the said Realm of England his or theire Lands Tenements Goods or
Chattels to the intent thereby to defraud or safeguard themselves of and from the payment of the Subsidies aforesaid
or any part thereof that then all and every such Child and Children soe being seized of any such Lands &amp; Tenements
or possessed of any such Goods or Chattels shall be charged &amp; chargeable to and with the payment of double the
said Subsidies for the Lands Tenements Goods and Chattels at the said rates and values as Aliens and Strangers
Denizens or not Denizens are before limited and appointed to pay. Provided alwaies that the said Grant of and
for the Subsidies aforesaid or any Clause matter or thing whatsoever therein contained shall not in anywise extend
or be construed to extend to charge the Shire or County of Northumberland the Towne Borough or County of
Newcastle upon Tyne the Towne or Borough of Barwick upon Tweede or unto the Bishopprick of Duresme or
Countie Palatine of Duresme or any Parts or Places within them or any of them or any the resiants or inhabitants
thereof but that the said Shire and County of Northumberland the Towne Borough and County of Newcastle upon
Tyne the said Towne or Borough of Barwick and the Bishopprick and County Palatine of Duresme and alsoe all and
every the resiants and inhabitants of and within them and every of them respe&bholigct;ively be and shall be of and from the
said Grant and payment of the said Subsidies and every part thereof cleerely acquitted &amp; discharged any matter or
whatsoever thing in this present A&bholigct; had or made to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s128">
			<head>XXIII. Recital that &pound;50,000 had been advanced by the City of London, &pound;50,000 by Sir John Harrison Knight, Member for the Town of Lancaster, and William Harrison Esq. Member for the Town of Queenborough in Kent.</head>
			<para id="p146">
				<emph type="i">The Repayment of the said Sums provided for out of the Subsidies together with Interest at the Rate of &pound;8. per Cent. per Ann. Surplus of the Subsidies to be applied to the Purposes of this A&bholigct;. Warrant of Commissioners &amp; Receipt of Colle&bholigct;ors a sufficient Discharge to the Treasurers named in this A&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p147">And whereas the Sum of Fifty thousand pounds hath beene laid out and advanced before hand by the Citizens
of the City of London and the Sum of Fifty thousand pounds by Sir John Harrison Knight one of the Members
of the House of Commons Burgesse for the Towne of Lancaster in the County Palatine of Lancaster and William
Harrison Esquire Son of the said Sir John Harrison alsoe one of the Members of the House of Commons and
Burgesse for the Towne of Quinborough in the County of Kent for the present supply of your Majesties Army
and the releife of the Northerne Parts of this your Majesties Kingdome of England. Be it enacted by the Authority
of this present Parliament That the said Sir Thomas Barrington Sir Robert Pye Arthur Capell Robert Bateman
Thomas Soame Alderman and Isaac Penington Alderman nominated by the said Citizens and Sir John Harrison &amp;
William Harrison his Son and by this present A&bholigct; of Parliament constituted and ordained to be Receivers of the
said Subsidies shall and may satisfie pay and deliver unto the Chamber of the City of London out of the said
Subsidies and Moneys by this A&bholigct; appointed to be received the said S&bhouov;me of Fifty thousand Pounds and unto the
said Sir John Harrison and William Harrison his Son the Sum of Fifty thousand Pounds Togeather with such
other and further Sum and Sums of Money as the damages of and for the said Sums shall amount unto after the
rate of eight pounds per centum for a yeere from the day and time that the same was laid out and advanced as
aforesaid untill they shall respe&bholigct;ively have received the said Sums so disbursed and the surplusage of the said Sums
so to be received shall pay imploy and disburse for the reliefe of the Kings Army and of the Northern Counties
and for payment of such person and persons as shall lend or advance any Sum or Sums of Money for the use
and purposes last before men&bhocotil;ned with theire damages in such manner and forme as Francis Earle of Bedford
William Earle of Hertford Robert Earle of Essex William Earle of Salisbury Robert Earle of Warwick John Earle
of Bristoll Henry Earle of Holland Thomas Earle of Berkshire Philip Lord Wharton William Lord Paget Robert
Lord Brooke Edward Mountague Lord of Kimbolton John Lord Paulet Edward Howard Lord Howard of Estcrick
Thomas Savill Lord Savill of Pomfret Francis Leigh Lord Dunsmore or any foure or more of them Denzill Hollis
Esquire John Pymm Esquire Sir Christopher Wray Knight Sir John Hotham Baronet Thomas Lord Weynman Sir
Peter Heyman Knight William Cage Esquire Henry Martin Esquire Sir Dudley North Knight Sir Thomas Bowyer
Baronet Sir Edward Aiscough Knight Sir John Culpeper Knight Sir Robert Crane Knight and Baronet John
Hampden Esquire Sir Edmund Mountford Sir Walter Earle Sir Arthur Ingram Knights Sir Gilbert Gerard Baronet Sir
Guy Palmes Knight Samuel Owfeild Esquire William Mallory Esquire John Ashburnham Esquire Edward Kirton
Esquire Sir Hugh Cholmeley Knight Harbottell Grimstone Esquire Sir Philip Stapleton Knight Sir Edward Hales
Knight Sir Thomas Widdrington Knight Thomas Lord Gray Norton Knatchbull Esquire Edmund Waller Esquire
Henry Lord Gray of Ruthyn or any eight or more of them and soe proportionably in such manner and quality by
any one or more writing or writings under theire hands during this sitting of Parliament shall limit appoint and
declare And that the Warrant or Warrants of the said Commissioners before named or of such number of them as
before is expressed proportionably togeather with the acquittance and acquittances from the person or persons which
shall be appointed as aforesaid by the said Commissioners or of such number of them proportionably as before is
expressed for the receipt of the said Sum or Sums of money to the uses and purposes in this present A&bholigct; expressed
shall be a sufficient discharge to the Treasurers in this A&bholigct; named for so much money as shall be comprehended in
such Acquittance or Acquittances for the issuing out and payment of the said Sum and Sums of Money respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s129">
			<head>XXIV. Treasurer not to pay Monies on any other Warrant.</head>
			<para id="p148">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said Treasurers shall not at all pay any Sum or
Sums of money to be by them received upon any other dire&bholigct;ion warrant or command whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s130">
			<head>XXV. The passing of this A&bholigct; not to determine the Session.</head>
			<para id="p149">Lastly provided that [the passing of<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] this present A&bholigct; or His Majesties Assent thereunto shall not be anydetermina&bhocotil;n of this present Sessions of Parliament [but that this &bhopcrl;sent Sessions of Parliame<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] and all Bills and
Matters whatsoever depending in Parliament and not fully ena&bholigct;ed or determined &amp; all Statutes and A&bholigct;s of Parliament
which have theire continuance untill the end of this present Sessions of Parliament shall remaine continue and be
in full force as if this A&bholigct; had not beene.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3"> twentieth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5"> Wilbore <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6"> Knights</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8"> Knights <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10"> Sir <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11"> Wrottesleye <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12"> Heveningham <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15"> Esq. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16"> Wapentake <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18"> others <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19"> his <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21"> annexed to the Original Act in separate Schedules.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22"> in <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24"> by the said Authority <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26"> colle&bhocotil;n <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28"> w[i]thin <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29"> said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30"> soe bee <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31"> can <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32"> said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33"> Com[er]s <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34"> being <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35"> discre&bhocotil;n <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38"> accompt <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39"> Ma<emph type="p">t</emph>s <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41"> Jernsey <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n42" number="42">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	
</report>


