<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47218" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER VII. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) An A&bholigct; to prevent inconveniences which may happen by the untimely adjourning proroguing or dissolving of this present Parliament. [Rot.Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.; The present Parliament not to be dissolved but by A&bholigct; of Parliament.; Houses of Peers and Commons not to be adjourned but by themselves or their own Order</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas great sums of money must of necessity be speedily advanced and provided for the reliefe of his
Majesties Army and People in the Northern parts of this Realm and for preventing the imminent danger this
Kingdome is in and for supply of other his Majesties present and urgent occasions which cannot be soe timely effe&bholigct;ed
as is requisite without credit for raising the said moneys which credit cannot be obtained until such obstacles be first
removed as are occasioned by fears jealousies and apprehensions of diverse his Majesties Loyall Subje&bholigct;s that this
present Parliament may be adjourned prorogued or dissolved before Justice shalbe duly executed upon Delinquents
publike greivances redressed a firme Peace betweene the two Nations of England and Scotland concluded and before
sufficient provision be made for the repayment of the said moneys so to be raised All which the Commons in this
present Parliament assembled having duly considered Do therefore humbly beseech your Most Excellent Majestie that it
may be declared and ena&bholigct;ed And be it declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the King our Soveraign Lord with the assent of the
Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That this present
Parliament now assembled shall not be dissolved unlesse it be by A&bholigct; of Parliament to be passed for that purpose
nor shall be at any time or times during the continuance thereof prorogued or adjourned unlesse it be by A&bholigct; of
Parliament to be likewise passed for that purpose And that the House of Peers shall not at any time or times
during this present Parliament be adjourned unlesse it be by themselves or by theire owne order And in like manner
that the House of Commons shall not at any time or times during this present Parliament be adjourned unlesse it
be by themselves or by theire owne Order And that all and every thing and things whatsoever done or to be done
for the adjournment proroguing or dissolving of this present Parliament contrary to this A&bholigct; shall be utterly void
and of none effe&bholigct;.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">This A&bholigct; was not found amongst the original Public A&bholigct;s of this Session at the Parliament Office, but is annexed to the A&bholigct;
for the Attainder of The Earl of Strafford amongst the Private A&bholigct;s, and both the said A&bholigct;s received the Royal Assent by Commission;
being the only A&bholigct;s which appear to have passed in that manner during this Session.</note>
	</section>
</report>


