<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47226" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER XV. An Act against diverse Incroachments and Oppressions in the Stannarie Courts. [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 11.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>E. I. Charter to Tinners of Devon.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Explained 50 E. III.; Request of the Commons.; Answer.; Further Request of the Commons.; Answer.; 8 R. II. Charter to be executed.; The like Charter to Tinners in Cornwall.; Declarations that Tinners of Cornwall and Devon have enjoyed Liberties.; Abuse of Liberties recited; The former Declarations confirmed.; In locis ubi operantur, how expounded.; None but Tinners to be sued, unless by working Tinners.; Oath by Plaintiff.; Persons not Tinners sued by others not Tinners shall have their Action.; Such Action to be brought within Two Years, or before the Warden, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas King Edward the first of famous memory did for the Amendment of the Stannaries in the Countie
of Devon grant diverse Franchises and Liberties to the Tynners there And whereas in the Parliament in the
fiftieth yeare of King Edward the third upon the Petition of the Commons of the Countie of Devon certaine Branches
and Articles of the said Charter were explained in manner following That is to say whereas one Article of the said
Charter is in these words following viz. Sciatis nos ad emendationem Stannariarum nostra[rum] in Com. Devo&ntilde; ad
tranquilitatem et utilitatem Stannato[rum] n[ost]ro[rum] &bhopcrl;dco[rum] earundem Concessisse pro nobis et heredib[us] n[o]stris Quod omnes
Stannatores &bhopcrl;d[i]cti operantes in Stannariis illis que sunt Dominica nra dum operantur in eisdem Stannariis liberi sint et
quieti de placitis nativo[rum] et de omnib[us] placitis et querelis Curiam n[ost]ram et heredum n[ost]ro[rum] qualitercunq[ue] tangen Ita
quod non respondeant coram aliquib[us] Justiciariis vel Ministris n[ost]ris seu hered&umacr; n[ostr]o[rum] de aliquo placito seu querela
infra &bhopcrl;ictas Stannarias emergen nisi coram Custode n[ost]ro Stannaria[rum] n[ost]ra[rum] &bhopcrl;dicta[rum] qui pro tempore fuit (except
placitis terr vite et membro[rum]) nec recedant ab operationib[us] suis per summoni&bhocotil;nem alicujus Ministro[rum] n[ostr]o[rum] seu
hered&bhouov; n[ost]ro[rum] nisi per summoni&bhocotil;nem communem dci Custodis n[ost]ri Et quod quieti sint de omnib[us] tallag Theolo&ntilde;
stallag auxiliis et aliis custumis quibuscunq[ue] in villis portub[us] feriis et mercatis infra Com. &bhopcrl;d de bonis suis &bhopubrc;priis &amp;c.
Whereupon the said Commons prayed a Declaration as followeth: Requeste Sur qoi plese declarer si auters persons
q les Esteymos onerantz in les Estemeryes avont et enjoyeront la franchise gnte per la dite chartre du Roy desicome
la dite chartre voet Quod omnes Stannatores &bhopcrl;d[i]c[t]i operantes in Stannariis illis sint liberi &#x0026;c. Et auters &bhopubr;sons q les
o&ntilde; ours cestassavoir l&tilde;os Maistres que les lovent et l&otilde;s servants et auters claymont mesme la Franchise Et auxint plese
declarer si les ditz o&ntilde;ours y av&otilde;nt les Franchises in auters temps q quant ils av&otilde;nt in mesme Lestemery desicome la
ctire voet Dum operantur in eisdem Stannariis sint liberi &amp;c. Upon which request answer was made as followeth
Respons En droit de les dites paroles operantes in Stannariis illis et dum operantur in eisdem Stannariis. Soient
clerement entenduz de operariis laborantib[us] duntaxat in Stannariis illis sine fraude et dolo et non de aliis nec alibi
laborantib[us] And whereas the said Commons prayed a further Declaration as followeth Requeste Item soit declarrez
si le Gardein de Lestemery puisse tenir plee inter Esteymo et Forreyn de querele sourdante aillos q en les lieux ou
ils sont onantz desicome la Chire voet. Quod Custos noster &bhopcrl;dcus vel ejus locum tenens teneat omnia placita inter
Stannatores &bhopcrl;dcos emerge&ntilde; et etiam inter ipsos et alios forinsecos de omnib[us] transgressionib[us] querelis et contractib[us]
factis in locis in quib[us] operantur infra Stannarias &bhopcrl;dcas similiter emerge&ntilde; &amp;c. Quar il tient plee des tieux quereles
sourdantz in chescune parte deins le dit Counte. Upon which answer was made in these words viz. Resp. Et en
droit de ceste Article se ent extend la Jurisdiction clerement solone les paroles del dit Chre Cestassavoir In locis
ubi iidem operarii operantur et nemy aillours ne en autre manere Which Charter so declared was repeated again
And in the eighth yeare of the Reigne of King Richard the second commanded to be put in execution And
whereas the said King Edward the first made the like Charter to the Tynners in the Countie of Cornwall which
Charter was in the foresaid Parliament upon the request of the Commons of the County of Cornwall declared in
the same manner and words. And whereas the Tynners of the Counties of Devon and Cornewall have by vertue
of the said Charters enjoyed diverse and great Liberties and are quit from all Tolls Tallages Aydes and other
Customes in the Villes Ports Fairs and Markets within the said Counties respectively Which great Liberties do of
right belong to the working Tynner working without fraud or deceit in the Stannaries aforesaid and not to any
other nor else where working and were granted to the said Tynners for theire encouragement in theire works And
whereas of late yeares sundry Inhabitants within the said Countyes and others to entitle themselves to the said
Liberties have by fraud and covine for small or no considerations bought &amp; acquired and do buy and acquire to
themselves decayed Tynneworkes and small and inconsiderable parts in the same and other Tynneworks which abuses
are done principally to inable the said false and fained Tynners to vex and sue theire Neighbors in the Stannary Courts
where for the most part the Defendant is unjustly debarred his costs although the cause be adjudged with him and
the Jurisdiction of the said Stannaries hath contrary to ancient right and usage and the said Charters been endeavoured
to be extended out of the places where the Tynners doe worke through the whole Counties of Devon and Cornwall
respectively which is no way for the benefit of his Majestie but for the singular lucre of some private persons And
whereas by the said abuses great inconveniences doe follow (That is to say) the Inhabitants of the said Counties
are miserably vexed oppressed and imprisoned His Majesty defrauded of His Aides and Customes and the Lords and
Owners of Faires Markets and other Franchises of their Tolls and Duties and the Government of the Countrey
exceedingly confounded and eluded the said false and fained Tynners claiming when they list to be Tynners and
when they list to bee forreiners besides that if timely provision be not made the certaine decay of his Majesties
profit in the Tynneworkes will ensue for that the same being divided into so many hands and parts cannot conveniently
be set on worke nor Contribution raised for the working the same Be it therefore Enacted by his Majestie and the
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled That the said Declarations
be henceforth held and duely observed with this that the words of the said Charters and Declarations In locis ubi
operantur be expounded of the Vill Tithing and Hamlet where some Tynne worke in worke is scituate and not
else where and no longer then the same Tynne worke is or shall be in working And if any person or persons that shall
be sued in the said Stannaries shall swear or tender his or theire Oath in the said Court where he or they shall be
sued that he or they are not nor is nor time of the Suit commenced was not nor were a Tynner or Tynners then
such Defendant or Defendants shall be forthwith discharged of such Suit unlesse that the Plaintiffe or Plaintiffs
do forthwith make Oath that the said Plaintiffe or Plaintiffs is or are true and working Tynners without fraud or
deceit and that the cause of his or theire Suit arose within the said Stannaries or concerneth Tynne or Tynne works
And if any person being not re vera and without fraud a working and labouring Tynner in or about some
Tynne worke set on worke within one halfe yeare next before his Suit shall sue prosecute or implead in any the
said Courts or before the Warden Vice Warden or Steward of the said Stanaries any Person or Persons that is or
are not a Tynner or Tynners at the time of such Suit c&bhooov;menced Then the Defendant and Defendants [in<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] every
such case shall have his and theire Action at the Common Law against such person suing or prosecuting wherein he
shall recover ten pounds and his dammages and costs of Suit Provided that such Action be brought within two
yeares next after the Action or Suit brought in the said Stannary Courts or before the said Warden Vice Warden
or Steward.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Costs in Stannary Courts.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it declared and enacted That in all cases where the Plaintiffe or Defendant Plaintiffes or Defendants are
to have costs by the Lawes or Statutes of this Realm there alsoe the Plaintiffs and Defendants shall have the
like costs in the Stannarie Courts</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Tinners may sue Foreigners at the Common Law.</head>
			<para id="p4">And in regard that the said Charters were granted for the ease and advantage of the Tynners and not for theire
disadvantage or oppression and yet diverse of them who for speciall reasons have desired to sue at the Common Law
have beene restrained Bee it declared and Enacted That it shall be lawfull to and for the said Tynners if they thinke
fit to sue any Forreiners at the Common Law the said Charter or any usage to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Abuses by Poor Bailiffs in the Stannaries recited.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">How Sureties may be sued</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And whereas the Bailiffs of the said Stannary Courts are very numerous and are persons of small or no credit
and yet upon their return that any person is become Surety for any other upon Arrest by Proces out of the said
Courts such person who sometimes knowes nothing of the matter is by false Returns of the said Bayliffes made
lyable to the debt or demand which Bailiffes by reason of theire poverty are often not responsible and so the party
without remedie Be it Enacted That no Person or Persons be charged or troubled as surety by any Return of
any Bayliffe or Bailiffes of the said Stannaries unlesse that the person or persons returned Surety or Sureties shall
in the presence of two witnesses subscribe or signe a Note in writing that such person or persons is or are become
Surety or Sureties which Note shall mention the names of the Plaintiffes and Defendants in the Suit and the sum or
dammages in demand and the nature of the Action and shall be signed or subscribed by the said Witnesses and
returned and filed in the Court out of which such Processe shall issue and no Bailiffe or Bailiffs of the said Stannaries
shall be admitted as witnesses to any such Note.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Execution sometimes had before Arrest.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">No Defendant condemned on Bailiffs Return, unless on a Note subscribed by Party.; No Bail, unless Note given</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And whereas in the said Stannaries it is used that if the Bailiffs return any Person arrested that if such person
make default at the day he shall be condemned and Execution is suddenly awarded when as often the party was
not arrested. Be it further enacted That no Defendant shall be condemned upon such Return for not appearing
unlesse alsoe a Note under the Hand or Signe of the partie arrested and subscribed by two such Witnesses as aforesaid
be returned into the said Court at or before the day of Appearance and the said Bailiffe or Bailiffs shall take but
foure pence for every such Note as aforesaid and it is provided that none shall be bailed upon arrest there till he
give such Note.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Return of Rescous.</head>
			<para id="p9">And in case any the said Bailiffe or Bailiffs shall return a Rescous against any Person or Persons he or they
shall be admitted to Traverse the said Return which Traverse if it be found with him or them so traversing then
he or they shall be no further troubled or occasioned by reason of such return.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


