<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47236" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER XXV. A Subsidy granted to the King of Tonnage Poundage and other summes of money payable upon Merchandize exported and imported.[Rot. Par. p. 2. nu. 21.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>c. 8. ante, recited.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reason for granting the Subsidy by the said a&bholigct;.; c. 12. ante, recited.; c. 22. ante, recited.; Reasons for the present Grant.; Grant of Tonnage, for every Ton of Wine imported, 3s</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas An A&bholigct; was made this present Parliament intituled A Subsidy granted to the King of Tonnage and
Poundage and other s&bhouov;mes of money payable upon merchandize exported and imported Whereby it is
declared &amp;ena&bholigct;ed that it is and hath beene the ancient right of thesubje&bholigct; of this Realme that no Subsidy custome
impost or other charges whatsoever ought or may be laid [or imposed<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] upon any Merchandize exported or imported
bysubje&bholigct; Denizens or Aliens without c&bhooov;mon consent in Parliament And the said C&bhooov;mons then taking into theire
consideration the great perill that might have ensued by not guarding of the Seas and other inconveniencies which
might have followed in case the said su&bhomtild;s of money in the said a&bholigct; mentioned should not have beene granted to
your Majestie as in and by the said a&bholigct; is expressed Did therefore by [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] advice of the Lords in this present
Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same give and grant unto your Majestie our leige Lord and
Soveraigne One Subsidie of Tonnage and one other subsidie of Poundage in such manner and according to such rates
as in the said a&bholigct; is expressed To have take perceive and enjoy the Subsidies and other s&bhouov;mes soe granted by the
said a&bholigct; and every of them and every part and parcell of them to your Highnes from the five and twentieth day
of May One thousand six hundred forty one unto the fifteenth Day of July then next ensuing And Whereas the
said a&bholigct; being determined one other a&bholigct; of the same title was likewise made this present Parliament with like
declaration of the right of thesubje&bholigct; of this your Realme by which second a&bholigct; your said C&bhooov;mons did by the
like advice of the Lords in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same give and grant to your
Majestie One subsidy of Tonnage and one other subsidy of Poundage in such manner and according to such rates
as in the said last recited a&bholigct; is specified and conteyned To have take perceive and enjoye the Subsidies and other
s&bhouov;ms so granted by the said last recited a&bholigct; and every of them and every part and parcell of them to your Highnes
from the said fifteenth day of July One thousand six hundred forty one unto the tenth day of August then next
ensuing And whereas the said a&bholigct; being determined one other a&bholigct; of the same title was likewise made this present
Parliament by which third a&bholigct; your said C&bhooov;mons did by the like advice of the Lords in this present Parliament
assembled and by the authority of the same give and grant to your Majestie one subsidy of Tonnage and one other
subsidy of Poundage in such manner and according to such Rates as in the said last recited a&bholigct; is specified and
conteyned To have take enjoye and perceive the said subsidies and other s&bhouov;mes soe granted by the said last recited
a&bholigct; and every of them and every part and parcell of them to your Highnes from the ninth day of August One
thousand six hundred forty one to the first day of December then next ensuing The said C&bhooov;mons now likewise
againe takeing into theire consideracon the great perill that might ensue to this Realme by the not guarding
of the Seas &amp; the other inconveniencies that might follow in case the said s&bhouov;mes of money should upon the
suddaine be forborne to be paid By and with the consent of the Lords in this present Parliament assembled
and by the authority of the same Doe give and grant to you our Supreame Lord &amp; Soveraigne One subsidy
called Tonnage that is to say Of every Tun of Wine that is or shall come into this Realme or any your
Majesties Dominions by way of Merchandize the sume of three shillings and soe after that rate And of every</para>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">The like Duty over and above for Sweet Wine imported by Merchant Aliens. Every Awme of Rhenish Wine imported, 12d.; Grant of Poundage; every 20s. worth of Goods exported, 12d.; The like Duty on Tin and Pewter Vessels exported. Proviso for Woollen Cloth wrought within the Realm, and exported by Merchant Denizens; and for Wools, Woolfels, Hides, and Backs of Leather exported; and for all Wines not before mentioned</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">tonn of sweete Wines as well malmesey as other that is or shall come into this Realme by any Merchant Alien
three shillings and soe after the rate over and above the three shillings above mentioned And of every Awme
of Rhenish Wine that is or shall soe come in twelve pence And alsoe one other Subsidy called Poundage that
is to say of all manner of Goods and Merchandize of every Merchant Denizen and Alien carried or to be carried
out of this Realme or any your Majesties Dominions or to be brought into the same by way of Merchandize
of the value of every twenty shillings of the same goods and merchandize twelve pence and soe after the rate
and of every twenty shillings value of Tynn and Pewter Vessell carried out of this Realme by every or any
Merchant Alien twelve pence over and above the twelve pence aforesaid Except and foreprized out of this [Grant
of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] subsidy of Poundage all manner of Woollen Cloth made or wrought or which shall be made or wrought within
this Realme of England and by every or any Merchant Denizen and not born Alien carried or to be carried out
of this Realme And all manner of Woolls Woolfels Hydes and Backs of Leather that is or shall be carried out
of this Realme and all Wines not before limited to pay subsidy or tonnage And all manner of fresh fish and
bestiall coming or that shall come into this Realme</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Merchant Denizen to pay, every Sack of Wool, 33s. 4d.; every 240 Woolfels, 33s. 4d.; every Last of Hides and Backs, &pound;3. 6s. 8d.; and so in Proportion for every greater or less Quantity.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Merchant Strangers to pay, every Sack of Wool, &pound;3. 6s. 8d.; every 240 Woolfels, &pound;3. 6s. 8d.; every Last of Hides and Backs &pound;3. 13s. 4d.; and also certain Duties by Letters Patent or Great or Privy Seal, since I Jac. 1</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And further the said c&bhooov;mmons by the advice assent &amp; authority aforesaid Doe give and grant unto (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) our said leige
Lord our Soveraigne for the causes aforesaid One other Subsidy that is to say Of every Merchant borne Denizen
of and for every Sacke of Wooll thirty three shillings foure pence and of and for every two hundred and forty
Woolfels thirty three shillings foure pence and of and for every Last of Hides and Backs three pounds six shillings
eight pence and so after the same rate for every lesse or greater quantity for any the same merchandize more or
lesse And of every Merchant Stranger not borne Denizen of &amp; for every Sacke of Wooll three pounds six shillings
eight pence and of and for every two hundred forty Woolfels three pounds six shillings eight pence and for
every Last of Hides and Backs three pounds thirteene shillings foure pence And so of all the said Wools Woolfels
Hydes and Backs and every of them after the rate And such other s&bhouov;ms of money as have beene imposed upon
any Merchandize either outward or inward by pretext of any Letters Patents Commission under the Great Seale of
England or Privie Seale since the first yeare of the reigne of his late Majestie King James of Blessed memory and
which were continued and paid at the begining of this present Parliament To have take enjoye and perceive the
Subsidies aforesaid and other the aforementioned s&bhouov;mes and every of them and every part and parcell of them to
you our said leige Lord and Soveraigne from the last day of November One thousand six hundred forty one to the
first day of February next ensuing</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The said Subsidy to be applied according to I Jac. 1. c. 33.</head>
			<para id="p7">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that the said Subsidy of Tonnage Poundage Woole and other
s&bhouov;mes of money shall be taken and employed dureing the time aforesaid to and for the intents and purposes and
upon and under such provisions clauses and limitations as are conteyned in one a&bholigct; made in Parliament held in the
first yeare of the reigne of his said late Majestie King James of Blessed Memory entituled An a&bholigct; for the granting of
a Subsidy to the King of Tonnage Poundage Wools &amp;c</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The above Rates to be altered in this Parliament as shall be thought fit.</head>
			<para id="p8">And it is hereby declared that the s&bhouov;mes of money hereby granted upon merchandize are not the rates intended
to be continued but the same to be hereafter in this present Parliament altered in such manner as shall be
thought fit</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Penalty in this a&bholigct;, or in 1 Jac. 1. c. 33. to attach, unless on Persons refusing to compound for Goods imported or exported.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided that no penalty or forfeiture conteyned in this present a&bholigct; or in the said a&bholigct; made in the first yeare
of King James doe or shall ensue to any person or persons unlesse they refuse to compound to any merchandize or
goods imported or exported after notice given of this a&bholigct; penalty &amp; forfeiture by proclamation where the said goods
are or ought to be entred</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Officer, after the Determination of this Grant, receiving the Subsidy; Premunire, and Disability to sue.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed that any Customer or Comptroller or any other Officer or person that after the
determina&bhocotil;n of this grant shall take or receive or cause to be taken or received the said subsidy s&bhouov;mes of
money or any imposition upon merchandize whatsoever exported or imported except the same by Grant in Parliament
be due or by such graunt shall become due or have beene continually paid from the end of the reigne of the late
King Edward the Third untill the begining of the Reigne of the late Queene Mary shall incur and sustain the paines
penalties and forfeitures ordeined and provided by the Statute of Provision and premunire made in the sixteenth yeare
of King Richard the Second and shall alsoe from henceforth be disabled during his life to sue or impleade any person
in any a&bholigct;ion reall mixt or personall in any Court whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Tobacco of English Plantations.</head>
			<para id="p12">Provided alwaies That this a&bholigct; shall not extend to any imposition or charge upon any sort of Tobacco of
English Planta&bhocotil;ns But that the said Tobacco shall be charged only with the payment of two pence in the pound
and no more</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Persons not to be charged by this a&bholigct; with pretermitted Customs.</head>
			<para id="p13">Provided alwaies And it is further ena&bholigct;ed that this a&bholigct; shall not extend or be construed to charge any person
imposition or charge of late yeares imposed upon Woollen Cloath and Woolen Comodities knowne
by the name of the pretermitted customes</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Grants of Subsidies by Letters Patent, &amp;c. void.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided alsoe And be it [further<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that all Grants and Letters Patents under the
Great Seale Privy Seale or otherwise conteyning the Grants of any Subsidies or Imposts heretofore made or granted
unto any person or person for or in respe&bholigct; of the transportation exportation or importa&bhocotil;n of any goods or</para>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Allowance of Duties on Goods exported</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">merchandize pretended to be due or payable to your Majestie or by any such Grants or Letters Patents covenanted
to be enjoyed or had out of such Subsidies Imposts or Payments as hereafter should be setled by Parliament or
otherwise And all Letters Patents or other Grants of the Colle&bholigct;ion of any impositions heretofore set without
consent in Parliament made or granted to any person whatsoever And also All Pen&bhocotil;ns Assigna&bhocotil;ns of moneys
and all other payments whatsoever charged or hereafter to be charged on this Subsidy by this a&bholigct; other then for
the uses before in this a&bholigct; intended shalbe from henceforth utterly voide Provided that if any Merchant shall export
any Goods and merchandize which have beene formerly imported and the customes and other duties for the same
truly paid that in such case the same allowance shalbe made unto every such merchant as have been formerly by
vertue of your Highnes Privy Seale.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">you <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


