<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47238" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXVII. An Act for disinabling all persons in Holy Orders to exercise any temporall jurisdicc[i]on or authoritie. [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 23.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Spiritual Persons ought not to be entangled with secular Jurisdiction.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Archbishops, &amp;c. and Persons in Holy Orders, not to have Seat or Voice in Parliament, &amp;c. or execute any Temporal Authority</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas Bishops and other persons in Holy Orders ought not to be intangled with secular jurisdi&bholigct;ion the
Office of the Ministerie being of such great importance that it will take up the whole man And for that it is
found by long experience that theire intermedling with secular jurisdi&bholigct;ions hath occasioned great mischeifs and scandall
both to church and state His Majestie out of his religious care of the church and souls of his people is gratiously
pleased that it be ena&bholigct;ed And by authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Parliament Be it ena&bholigct;ed that no Archbishop or Bishop or
other person that now is or hereafter shall be in Holy Orders shall at any time after the fifteenth day of February
in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred forty one have any Seat or place suffrage or Voice or use or
execute any power or authority in the Parliaments of this Realm nor shall be of the Privy Councell of his Majestie
his heires or successours or Justice of the Peace of Oyer and Terminer or Goal Delivery or execute any temporall
authoritie by vertue of any Commission but shall be wholly disabled and be uncapable to have receive use or execute
any of the said Offices Places Powers Authorities and things aforesaid.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. All Acts, &amp;c. done by such Persons, void.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that all Acts from and after the said fifteenth day of
February which shall be done or executed by any Archbishop or Bishop or other person whatsoever in Holy Orders
and all and every suffrage or voice given or delivered by them or any of them or other thing done by them or
any of them contrary to the purport and true meaning of this present Act shall be utterly void to all intents
constructions and purposes.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


