<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47245" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXIV. An Act for adding unto &amp; explaining of certain Clauses in another Act made this Parliament Intituled An Act for the speedy &amp; effectuall reducing of the Rebels in his Majesties Kingdome of Ireland to theire due obedience to his Majestie and the Crowne of England. [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 3. nu. 7.]
</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>c. 33. ante.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Time for Subscriptions by Persons residing within 60 miles of London.; Persons inhabiting 60 Miles or more distant from London</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the said A&bholigct; could not be so timely passed and published that his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s in and
about the City of London might conveniently take notice of the dayes therein limited for theire
Underwriting according to that A&bholigct; upon which and other Clauses of the said A&bholigct; doubts have beene raised For
explanation thereof and for the cleere satisfa&bholigct;ion of all such persons as by underwriting any s&bhouov;ms of Money
according to that A&bholigct; shall advance so honourable and pious a Worke as the reducing of that Kingdome Be it
Ena&bholigct;ed by the King our Soveraigne Lord and by the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled
and by the Authoritie of the same That all and every his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s inhabiting or residing within the said
City of London or within threescore miles distance thereof which at any time before the twentieth day of Aprill
in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six hundred fourty two have underwritten or shall underwrite any
such s&bhouov;m of money as in the said A&bholigct; is mentioned and pay the fourth part thereof on or before the said twentieth
day of Aprill aforesaid and the other three parts of the s&bhouov;me or s&bhouov;ms so to be subscribed within three moneths
three moneths and three moneths by equall por&bhocotil;ns accounting eight and twentie dayes to every moneth to be
accounted to begin from the said twentieth day of Aprill aforesaid and all the said s&bhouov;ms to be paid at the Chamber
of the Citie of London to the four persons appointed to attend there by the said A&bholigct; or to any two of them who
are hereby authorized and required to give Receipts for the same and to enter the said s&bhouov;m and the times of
such subscription as aforesaid And all and every his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s inhabiting sixtie miles or more from the
said Citie of London and all and every his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s of the Scotch Nation which at any time before the
tenth day of May in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six hundred fourty two have underwritten or shall
underwrite any such s&bhouov;m of Money as in the said A&bholigct; is mentioned and pay the fourth part thereof on or before
the said tenth day of May aforesaid and the other three parts of the sum or s&bhouov;ms so to be subscribed within
three Moneths three Moneths and three Moneths by equall por&bhocotil;ns accounting eight and twentie dayes to every
Moneth to be accounted to begin from the said tenth day of May aforesaid and at such place and to such
persons as in and by the said A&bholigct; is appointed shall have a proportionable share of the said Rebels Lands and
of other Lands forfeited and to be forfeited by the said A&bholigct; according to the s&bhouov;ms to be by them underwritten
and paid in as aforesaid under all [other<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the Conditions and Limitations in the said A&bholigct; or Propositions mentioned
to all intents and purposes and in as large and beneficiall manner as if such underwriting had beene at the dayes
in the said recited A&bholigct; or the Propositions therein expressed Any thing therein contained to the contrary
notwithstanding</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Persons of the Dutch Nation, being Protestants, &amp;c. admitted to Underwriting.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">The Monies to be paid at the Chamber of the City of London</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further declared and Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all such persons of the Dutch Nation
being Protestants and Subje&bholigct;s to the Government of the States of the United Provinces of the Low Countreys as
shall be desirous to underwrite any s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of Money according to the said A&bholigct; shall be admitted to such
underwriting untill the full s&bhouov;m of two hundred thousand pounds shall be by them underwritten And so as the
Million of Money propounded to be underwritten by His Majesties Subje&bholigct;s of England Scotland and Ireland be not
subscribed before the admittance of any of the said Dutch Nation to subscribe as aforesaid And that such of the
said Dutch Nation as shall be admitted to underwrite according to this A&bholigct; shall underwrite theire severall s&bhouov;ms
of money within this Kingdome before the tenth day of May in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six
hundred fourty two and shall pay the fourth part of the s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms to be by them underwritten at or before
the said tenth day of May aforesaid and the other three parts of the s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms so to be subscribed within
three monthes three monthes and three monthes by equall Por&bhocotil;ns accompting eight and twenty dayes to every
moneth to be reckoned to begin from the said tenth day of May aforesaid And all the said s&bhouov;ms to be paid at
the Chamber of the City of London to the foure Persons appointed to attend there by the said A&bholigct; or to any
two of them which said four persons or any two of them are hereby authorized and required to give receipts
for the same and to enter the said s&bhouov;ms and times of subscription as aforesaid and upon such underwriting and
payment as aforesaid shall have a proportionable share of the said Rebels Lands and of other Lands forfeited and
to be forfeited by the said A&bholigct; according to the s&bhouov;ms to be by them Underwritten and paid in as aforesaid
under all other the Condi&bhocotil;ns and Limitations in the said A&bholigct; or Propositions mentioned to all intents and purposes
and in as large and beneficiall manner as his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s of England shall or may enjoye theire severall and
respe&bholigct;ive shares according to the said A&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Persons paying in Money sooner than the Time allowed;</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Allowance at the Rate of &pound;8. per Cent. per Ann</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That in case any Person that shall underwrite according
to this A&bholigct; theire Heires Executors Administrators or Assignes shall pay in the three latter payments of the s&bhouov;ms
of money by them subscribed or to be subscribed or any part thereof sooner then the times in this present A&bholigct;
limited for the same there shall be rebated and allowed unto them by way of rebate so much of the said moneys
underwritten as the Interest of the said money so paid in before hand from thenceforth to the time and times
respe&bholigct;ively whereon the same is by this present A&bholigct; limited to be paid after the rate of eight Pounds for one
hundred pounds for a yeare shall amount unto And John Warner John Towse Thomas Andrewes and Lawrence
Haulstead in the said recited A&bholigct; named or any two of them are hereby authorized &amp; required to make the said
allowances by way of rebate accordingly And the same shall upon theire Accompts be allowed unto them
And the said money so rebated shall be accompted and adjudged to be paid by the said underwriters theire
Heires Executors Administrators or Assignes and shall be as beneficiall unto them as if the same had beene a&bholigct;ually
paid according to the Propositions in the said recited A&bholigct; men&bhocotil;ned</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Members of either House of Parliament subscribing.</head>
			<para id="p7">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the Members of either House of Parliament which
shall underwrite any s&bhouov;ms of money and pay in the same or any part thereof at the Chamber of the City of
London shall neverthelesse have the same dayes and times of payment for theire severall s&bhouov;ms by them underwritten
or to be underwritten as they should have had in case they had subscribed theire severall s&bhouov;ms and paid in the
same in the severall Counties where they had theire ordinary residence and habitation before the begining of this
Parliament</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Allowance to the Receivers 1d. in the pound.</head>
			<para id="p8">[And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said John
Warner John Towse and such other Persons as are appointed by the said A&bholigct; to receive such summs of money as shall
be paid in by vertue of that A&bholigct; to dedu&bholigct; and retaine to theire owne use one peny out of every Pound of all such
s&bhouov;ms of money as they shall receive according to this A&bholigct; towards theire charges and Paines in attending and receiving
the said Subscriptions and s&bhouov;ms of money and in issuing out and returning up the same.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


