<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47249" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for removing and preventing all Questions and Disputes concerning the Assembling and Sitting of this present Parliament. [Rot. Parl. 12. C. II. p. 1. nu. 1.]
</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Parliament begun 3d Nov. 16 Car. 1. dissolved.; Lords and Commons now sitting declared to be the Two Houses of Parliament.; This Parliament may be dissolved by the King in the usual Manner.; Lords and Commons now sitting declared to be the Two Houses of Parliament.; This Parliament may be dissolved by the King in the usual Manner</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the preventing all Doubts and Scruples concerning the Assembling, Sitting and Proceeding of this present
Parliament: Bee it Declared and Ena&bholigct;ed, and it is Declared and Ena&bholigct;ed by the King Our Soveraigne
Lord, and by the Lord&bholigct; and Commons in Parliament assembled and by Authoritie of the same That the Parliament
begun and holden at Westminster the third day of November in the Sixteenth yeare of the Raigne of the late
King Charles of Blessed Memory is fully dissolved and determined; And that the Lords and Commons now
sitting at Westminster in this present Parliament are the two Houses of Parliament, and soe shalbe, and are
hereby Declared Ena&bholigct;ed and Adjudged to be to all Intents Constru&bholigct;ions and Purposes whatsoever, notwithstanding
any want of the Kings Majesties Writt or Writts of Summons or any Defe&bholigct; or Alteration of or in any Writt or
Writts of Summons or any other Defect or Default whatsoever; as if this Parliament had beene summoned by
Writt or Writts in His Majesties Name according to the usuall Forme, and as if his Majestie had beene present
in person at the Assembling, and Commencement of this present Parliament. [Provided alwaies That this present
Parliament may be_dissolved by His Majestie after the usuall manner as if the same had beene summoned by
Writt or Writts in his Majesties Name.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The King's Assent to this Act shall not determine this Session.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alsoe and it is hereby enacted That His Majesties Royall Assent to this Bill shall not determine this
present Session of Parliament.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


