<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47241" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER XXX. An Act for a speedie contribu&bhocotil;n and loan towards the releife of his Majesties distressed Subjects of the Kingdome of Ireland. [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 3. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Murders and Massacres of Protestants in Ireland, and Distresses of those that have been obliged to flee, recited.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Churchwardens, &amp;c. to ask and gather Charitable Donations within their Parishes;; and the Sums received, and the Names of the Persons giving, to note and deliver to High Constables, who are to pay and deliver the same to the Sheriffs, who, and the said Constables, are to give Acquittances for the same. ; How such Monies are to be collected, &amp;c. in London</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas sithence the begining of the late Rebellion in Ireland diverse cruell Murthers and Massacres of
the Protestants there have beene and are daily comitted by Popish Rebells in that Kingdome by occasion
whereof great multitudes of godly and religious people there inhabiting togeather with theire wives children and
families for the preservation of theire lives have been inforced to forsake theire habitations meanes and livelihood
in that kingdome and to [flee<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] for succour into severall parts of his Majesties Realme of England and Dominion of (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>)
Wales having nothing left to depend upon but the charitable benevolence of well disposed persons. The Lords and
Commons now assembled in Parliament taking the same into theire charitable considera&bhocotil;n for the honour of
Almightie God and the preservation of the true Protestant Religion and Professours thereof have resolved presently
themselves to contribute towards the necessities of the said poore distressed christians who being many in number it
is thought expedient that through all his Majesties Realm of England and Dominion of Wales a generall colle&bholigct;ion
should with all expedition be made for that purpose. And forasmuch alsoe as a present supply of money is necessary
for the raising of men to suppresse the said Rebellion which otherwise may indanger the peace and safety of this
kingdome May it therefore please your most excellent Majestie that it may beena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the
Kings Most Excellent Majestie and the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by authoritie
of the same that all and every the Churchwardens and Overseers of the poore within all and every the severall places
and parishes in all and every county or counties Cities or Townes whatsoever within his Majesties said Realm of
England and Dominion of Wales shall and may forthwith and before the first day of June which shall be in the yeare
of our Lord God 1642. within theire respe&bholigct;ive parishes and places aforesaid and for the purpose aforesaid aske take
receive and gather the severall gifts and charitable benevolences of all and every person and persons to and for the
uses aforesaid and the sums soe received and gathered in each severall place or parish togeather with the persons
names that shall give the same they or some or one of them to set downe in a Note in writing in words at large
and not in figures and the same Note togeather with the said s&bhouov;ms of money forthwith to pay and deliver to the
severall High Constables of every hundred circuit or division where such colle&bholigct;ion is or shall be made who shall
forthwith pay and deliver the said severall s&bhouov;ms and notes thereof to the severall Sheriffes of each countie which said
Sheriffs and Constables are to give severall acquittances or discharges for the same respectively saving and except
that within the citie of London the s&bhouov;ms soe to be colle&bholigct;ed and the notes thereof in writing so taken shall be
immediately delivered to Sir Edmund Wright Sir James Cambell and Sir George Whitmore Knights Aldermen of the
Citie of London and Robert Bateman Esquire Chamberlain of the said Citie And the s&bhouov;ms to be colle&bholigct;ed within the
Citie of Westminster and Notes thereof taken to Sir Arthur Ingram and Sir Robert Pye Knights William Wheeler
and William Bell Esquires which persons before named are by this a&bholigct; appointed Receivers and Treasurers for that
purpose and to give acquittances and discharges for the same.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Sheriff to pay and deliver the said Money and Notes to Receivers, &amp;c. appointed by thisa&bholigct; who are to give acquittances.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it furtherena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said severall Sheriffes from and after such receipt of
the said severall s&bhouov;ms of money shall with all possible speede and before the first day of July which shall be in the
said yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred fourty and two pay over all the said severall sums of money
and deliver the said notes to the Receivers and Treasurers by this a&bholigct; appointed or some or one of them who alsoe
are to give severall acquittances and discharges for the same and are by this a&bholigct; to be accomptable and responsable
to the Parliament for the said severall s&bhouov;ms</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Commissions to issue under the Great Seal for Collecting such Monies to the Commissioners named in c. 2. ante.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Commission to Bristol.; To the Cinque Ports. ; Dover.; Folkstone</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that for the better colle&bholigct;ing and receiving of the said
severall s&bhouov;mes by this a&bholigct; appointed or intended severall Commissions shall forthwith be made and dire&bholigct;ed by
the Lord Chancellour or Lord Keeper for the time being out of the Court of Chancerie under the Great Seale
unto the severall Commissioners named in one a&bholigct; lately made in this present Parliament intituled An a&bholigct; for the
releife of his Majesties Army and the Northerne parts of this Kingdome And alsoe one other Commission for the
Citie of Bristoll to the Maior for the time being and to John Taylor John Gunning John Tomlinson Andrew
Carleton Richard Helworth William Jones Ezechiell Wallis George Knight and John Lock Esquires And other
Commissions to every of the Cinque Ports that is to say To the Maior for the time being Steven Munnings Thomas
Day John Brome William Richards Samuel Dell Robert Brome Jurates for the towne and port of Dover and theire
eight members For the towne and port of Folstone The Maior for the time being Robert Culverdown Thomas</para>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">New Romney. ; Lid. ; Hithe. ; Sandwich. ; Rye. ; Tenterden. ; Winchelsea. ; Schedule of Tenor of a&bholigct; to be affixed to Commission.; Commissioners to exhort the people in their respective Limits to contribute; ; and to collect Monies; ; and such Monies, together with Notes in Writing of the Names, of the Persons contributing, to transmit, under their Hands, to the Sheriffs, who are to give Acquittances.; Monies contributed in London and Westminster to be paid to the Receivers before mentioned, who are to give Acquittances. Interest at &pound; 8. per Cent. on Monies lent</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">Inneth For Feversham To the Maior for the time being Master Bois Master Marlow Master Crump For the towne
and port of New Rumney To the Maior for the time being Robert Wivell Steven Etherick John Wilcock William
Lancaster Gentlemen For the towne of Lid To the Bayliffe for the time being Thomas Tapp Thomas Struggle
John Bate William Godfrey Gent For the towne and port of Heith and the members thereof To the Maior for the
time being William Deede John Down John Hogben John Crump John Lambert For the towne and port of
Sandwich and the Members thereof To the Maior for the time being [Stephen Inckpet William Nelson George
Wood Mathew Peak Jurats For Rye with y<emph type="p">e</emph> members of it To y<emph type="p">e</emph> Maior for y<emph type="p">e</emph> time being<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Robert Ewen Richard
Cockram Joseph Bembrick Allen Gribble Jurates For Tenterden To the Maior for the time being Robert Pope
Samuel Short Esquires John Austen Thomas Short Jurates For the town of Winchelsea To the Maior for the time
being and Daniel White a Jurate And to every of the said Commissions one or more Schedules containing in them
the tenor of this a&bholigct; shall be affixed by which Commission the Commissioners in every such Commission named
according to this a&bholigct; or any three or more of them shall by vertue of this a&bholigct; before the first day of March
which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred fourty and one summon and call togeather
at such places and times and by such waies and meanes as they or any three or more of them shall appoint
such person and persons residing within the severall Counties where they shall be appointed Commissioners as they
in theire discretions shall thinke fitt and earnestly to move and perswade them liberally to contribute and lend money
toward so good a worke And the said Commissioners are alsoe required to colle&bholigct; and gather such sums of money
as themselves or any of them shall thinke fitt to give or lend to the uses aforesaid it being hoped and expected
that by theire good example herein they will incourage others to doe the like and such s&bhouov;ms of money as shall be soe
lent to the uses aforesaid by any person or persons whatsoever together with notes in writing of the said severall
s&bhouov;mes and of the names of the severall Lenders thereof under the hands of the said Commissioners or any twoe
or more of them to be paid and delivered over with all possible speed to the Sheriffes of the said severall
Counties respe&bholigct;ively where such person or persons so lending shall be resident the said Sheriffes giving severall
Acquittances for receipt thereof (saving and except) that within the Cities of London and Westminster the sums
which shall be there so lent shall be immediately by the persons lending the sum paid and delivered to the
Treasurers and Receivers before men&bhocotil;ned for the said respe&bholigct;ive Cities who shall give severall acquittances for
the same All which acquittances shall be a sufficient Warrant for the persons producing the same to receive the
severall s&bhouov;ms of money soe by them lent as aforesaid with interest for the forbearance thereof after the rate of
eight pound per centum for a yeare out of such moneys as shall be raised by an a&bholigct; of Parliament to be made
for that purpose for the well and true payment whereof this present a&bholigct; doth give publique faith and security</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Sheriffs to pay and deliver Monies and Notes to Treasurers, who are to give Acquittances;</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">and to be responsible to Parliament</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that from and after such receipt of the said severall s&bhouov;ms
which shall be so lent as aforesaid the said severall sheriffs shall with all possible speed and before the first day
of July which shall be in the yeare One thousand six hundred fourty and two pay and deliver over all the said
severall s&bhouov;ms of money so lent as aforesaid together with the said severall Notes of the said severall s&bhouov;ms and
of the severall lenders thereof in writing under the hands of the said Commissioners or any two or more of them
to the said Treasurers before mentioned or some or one of them who alsoe are to give severall acquittances to the
said Sheriffes respe&bholigct;ively for the same and are by this a&bholigct; alsoe to be accountable and responsable to the Parliament
for the same as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. The said Monies to be distributed as by both Houses of Parliament appointed.</head>
			<para id="p10">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that all the said severall s&bhouov;ms which shall be given or
lent as aforesaid shall be issued out and distributed to the uses aforesaid to such persons and in such manner
as from time to time appointed by the Lords and Commons in Parliament assembled and not otherwise or in any
other manner</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Notes, &amp;c. of colle&bholigct;ions to be printed and published.</head>
			<para id="p11">And for the better discovery of the true payment of all and every the severall s&bhouov;ms of money aforesaid
and the avoiding of all deceits and evil dealing touching all and every the &bhopcrl;misses Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by
the authority aforesaid that all and every the said severall Notes or Schedules of colle&bholigct;ions (after the, same shall
be so returned to the said Receivers and Treasurers aforesaid) shall be imprinted and published</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Members of the Commons to send Copy of a&bholigct; to Sheriffs, who, together with Mayors, &amp;c. are to publish and execute the same.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Sheriffs, Mayors, &amp;c. in England and Wales, to take Notice of a&bholigct;, and all Parsons, &amp;c. are to make the same known</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And for the more speedy execution of this &bhopcrl;sent a&bholigct; in respe&bholigct; of the said &bhopcrl;sent and pressing necessity
of the said poore distressed persons. Be it further likewise ena&bholigct;ed that immediately after the imprinting of this
Act the severall Knights Citizens Burgesses and Barons of the Cinque Ports for this present Parliament shall
forthwith respe&bholigct;ively send unto the Sheriffs of the said severall Counties and to the Cities Boroughs and Ports
for which they serve one or more severall books of this present a&bholigct; of Parliament which said a&bholigct; the said
severall Sheriffs of each severall Countie and the Maiors Bayliffs and Head Officers of each severall City Borough
and Towne Corporate or Port are hereby required to receive and forthwith by all good and lawfull wayes and
meanes to publish and put the same in due execution And all Sheriffs Maiors Bayliffs Head Officers Ministers
Parsons Vicars Curates Church Wardens and Overseers of the Poore whatsoever within this Realme of England
&amp; Dominion of Wales are by this a&bholigct; required to take notice of the &bhopcrl;misses And also all Ministers Parsons
Vicars Curates Churchwardens and Overseers of the poor to use theire best endeavors for the performance
thereof by publishing the same in the severall Parish Churches and Chappels within [this<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Realme of England and
Dominion of Wales as by all other good wayes and meanes whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Sheriff, &amp;c. neglecting to execute a&bholigct; answerable in Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p14">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that in case any Sheriffe Commissioner Maior Bailiffe Head
Officer Minister Parson Vicar Curate Churchwarden Overseer of the Poore or other Officer or Officers or other
person or persons whatsoever by this a&bholigct; nominated or required to be aiding or assisting in the due execution
thereof shall negle&bholigct; the due performance of his or theire duties therein that he or they shall be accomptable
and answerable in Parliament for such his or theire negle&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Continuance of a&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided alwaies That this a&bholigct; shall not be put in execution touching any such colle&bholigct;ion Loan or
contribution as aforesaid longer then or from or after the first day of June which shall be in the yeare of our
Lord God 1642.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">flye <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


