<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47248" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXVII. An Act for the further advancement of an effectuall and speedy reduction of the Rebels in Ireland to the obedience of his Majestie and the Crowne of England. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 3. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>c. 33. ante.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">c. 34. ante.; c. 35. ante.; All Persons, English, Scottish, Irish, and Dutch, being Protestants, may subscribe.; The Time for Payment.; On Payment, entitled to Allotments</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in pursuance of three severall A&bholigct;s of Parliament made this present Session (the first intituled
An A&bholigct; for the speedie and effe&bholigct;uall reducing of the Rebells in His Majesties Kingdome of Ireland to theire
due obedience to His Majestie and to the Crowne of England And the second intituled An A&bholigct; for adding unto and
explaining of certaine Clauses in another A&bholigct; made this Parliament intituled An A&bholigct; for the speedie and effe&bholigct;suall
reducing of the Rebels in His Majesties Kingdome of Ireland to theire due obedience to His Majestie and the
Crowne of England And the third intituled An A&bholigct; to inable Corporations and Bodies Politique to participate of the
benefit of an A&bholigct; lately past intituled An A&bholigct; for the speedie and effe&bholigct;uall reducing of the Rebels in His Majesties
Kingdome of Ireland to theire due obedience to his Majestie and the Crowne of England diverse great s&bhouov;ms of money
have beene subscribed some part whereof is already paid in to the purposes and persons mentioned in the said A&bholigct;s and
diverse other well affe&bholigct;ed persons Bodies Politique and Corporate would subscribe and pay in diverse great s&bhouov;ms of
money for the purposes and intents in the said A&bholigct;s expressed if the times limited in the said A&bholigct;s for subscribing and
paying in of the same were not already elapsed Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the King our Soveraigne Lord and by the
Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That all and every
person and persons of the English Scotish Irish or Dutch Nation being Protestants in Religion and every Body
Politique and Corporate of this Realme which at any time before the twentieth day of July in the yeare of our Lord
one thousand six hundred fourty two shall underwrite or cause to be underwritten to the intents and purposes in all
or any the said A&bholigct;s men&bhocotil;ned any s&bhouov;m of money not being under the s&bhouov;m of ten pounds and shall pay or cause to
be paid the fourth part thereof on or before the said twentieth day of July and the other three parts of the s&bhouov;m or
s&bhouov;ms so to be underwritten within three monthes three monthes and three monthes by equall por&bhocotil;ns accompting
eight and twenty dayes to every moneth to be accompted to begin from the twentieth of July aforesaid and all the
said s&bhouov;ms to be underwritten at the Chamber of the City of London and to be paid to the four persons appointed to
attend there by the said A&bholigct;s or to any two of them who are hereby authorised and required to give Receipts for the
same and to enter the said s&bhouov;ms and times of such subscription as aforesaid shall have to all and every such person
and persons Bodies Politique and Corporate theire Heires Successors or Assignes respe&bholigct;ively a proportionable share
of the Rebels Lands and of other Lands forfeited or to be forfeited by all or any of the said A&bholigct;s according to the
s&bhouov;ms to be by him or them underwritten and paid in as aforesaid under all other the Condi&bhocotil;ns Limita&bhocotil;ns and
Provisions which in all or any of the said A&bholigct;s are expressed and in as large and beneficiall manner to all intents
and purposes as if such underwriting and payment had been at the dayes in the said A&bholigct;s or either of them appointed
or expressed</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Time for Payment by such as have subscribed.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Allowance to such Persons of proportionable Number of Two Million and a Half of Acres</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And the better to invite all well affe&bholigct;ed persons Bodies Politique and Corporate to the bringing in of present
money for this service which will be the most effe&bholigct;uall meanes under God for the speedy subduing of the said
Rebels. Be it therefore Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every person and persons of the English Scotish Irish or Dutch Nation being of the Protestant Religion and every Body Politique or Corporate in this
Realme which hath at any time heretofore underwritten or have caused to be underwritten or shall underwrite
or cause to be underwritten any s&bhouov;m of money to the purposes in all or any of the said A&bholigct;s mentioned and hath or
shall have according to the times and places in the said A&bholigct;s limited paid in a fourth part or more of the same and
shall pay in or cause to be paid in the residue of the s&bhouov;m so underwritten before the said twentieth day of July
And every such person or body politique which shall underwrite or cause to be underwritten to the purposes aforesaid
any summ of money by vertue of this A&bholigct; at the said Chamber [of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] London and shall pay in or cause to be paid in the
whole s&bhouov;m which he or they shall soe underwrite or cause to be underwritten unto the said four persons or any two
of them who are to give Receipts for the same as aforesaid and to enter the summs and times of subscription before
the said twentieth of July shall have to all and every such person and persons Bodies Politique and Corporate theire
Heires Successors and Assignes respe&bholigct;ively a proportionable number of Acres out of the two millions and halfe of
Acres in the said former A&bholigct; mentioned with Woods Boggs Loughes and barren Mountaines cast in over and above
with the Houses and Edifices thereupon built according to the s&bhouov;m so underwritten and paid in which said
proportionable number of Acres shall be measured out and enjoyed according to the Plantation measure (that is to
say) every Acre thereof shall consist of eightscore Pearches or Poles and every Pearch or Pole shall consist of one
and twentie foot and shall enjoye the said proportionable number of Acres under the same Conditions Limitations
and Provisions and in as large and beneficiall manner to all intents and purposes as any other underwriter which shall
pay in his money underwritten at four payments shall enjoye his proportionable number of English Acres Any thing
in the said A&bholigct;s or either of them conteyned to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The Proportion of Poles to every Acre for those who shall have paid in their Subscriptions before the 20th of July.</head>
			<para id="p5">And whereas the two Millions and halfe of Acres men&bhocotil;ned in the said first recited A&bholigct; to be for the satisfa&bholigct;ion
of such persons as shall underwrite and pay in any s&bhouov;m of money according to the said first recited Act or Propositions
mentioned in the said first recited A&bholigct; are to consist of English measure Now to the intent that all such well affe&bholigct;ed
persons Bodies Politique and Corporate as have underwritten or shall underwrite or have caused or shall cause to be
underwriten to the purposes in all or any of the said A&bholigct;s expressed any s&bhouov;m of money and shall pay in or cause to be
paid in all theire summs which are or shall be so underwritten as aforesaid before the said twentieth of July may have
Lands sufficient to give them satisfaction according to the proportion of one and twenty foot to the Pole for every Acre.
Therefore be it Ena&bholigct;ed That every Acre of the said two Millions and halfe of Acres shall consist of eightscore Pearches
or Poles and every Pearch or Pole shall consist of one and twenty foot And all the said two Millions and halfe of Acres
shall be measured forth out of the said Rebells Lands and the other Lands forfeited by the said first recited A&bholigct; according
to that measure Any thing in the said Propositions or in the said A&bholigct;s contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The Proportion for those who shall not have paid in the whole of their Subscription before the 20th July.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided neverthelesse That all and every person and persons Bodies Politique and Corporate which have
underwritten or shall underwrite or have caused or shall cause any other to underwrite for him or them any s&bhouov;m
of money to the purposes aforesaid and have paid or shall pay in theire moneys according to the said recited A&bholigct;s
or according to the times limited in the first Clause of this A&bholigct; and shall not pay in all theire respe&bholigct;ive s&bhouov;ms
underwritten or to be underwritten as aforesaid before the said twentieth of July shall have theire proportionable
number [of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Acres according to the English measure viz. consisting of sixteen foot and an halfe to the Pole and no
other or greater measure Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso respecting Persons paying in by way of Rebate, having Benefit of Act.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided alsoe and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no Person Body Politique or Corporate which
hath paid in any s&bhouov;m of Money according to the said A&bholigct;s or any of them by way of Rebate shall have any advantage
of this A&bholigct; unlesse such person Body Politique or Corporate shall repay or cause to be repaid before the said twentieth
of July to the said four persons or any two of them who are to give Receipts for the same the s&bhouov;m so to him or
them formerly rebated Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Allowance to Receivers 1d. in the Pound.</head>
			<para id="p8">And be it lastly Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said four
Receivers or any two of them to dedu&bholigct; and retain to theire owne use one penie out of every pound of all such
s&bhouov;ms of money as they shall receive according to this A&bholigct; towards theire charges and paines in attending and
receiving the said Subscriptions and s&bhouov;ms of Money and in issuing out of the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>CHAPTER XXXVIII. An Act for the Attainder of Thomas Earle of Strafford of High Treason. (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) [O. nu. 23.]</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Earl of Stafford attainted of High Treason.; Proviso for the Law relating to Treason</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">Whereas the Knight&bholngs; Cittizens and Burgesses of the Howse of C&bhooov;mons in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled
have in the name of themselves and of all the C&bhooov;mons of England impeached Thomas Earle of Strafford of
High Treason for endeavouring to subvert the auncient &amp; fundamentall Lawes and Governement of His Ma<emph type="p">t</emph>&bholngs; Realmes
of England and Ireland and to introduce an arbitrary &amp; tyranicall Government against Lawe in the said Kingdomes
And for exercizing a tyranous and exorbitant Power above and against the Lawes of the said Kingdomes over the
Liberties Estates and Lives of His Ma<emph type="p">t</emph>&bholngs; Su<emph type="p">t</emph> And likewise for haveing by his owne Authoritie comanded the laying and
sessing of Souldiers uppon His Ma<emph type="p">t</emph>&bholngs; Su<emph type="p">t</emph>s in Ireland against their consent&bholngs; to compell them to obey his unlawfull s&bhouov;mons
&amp; Orders made uppon paper Peti&bhocotil;ns in causes betweene partie and partie w<emph type="p">ch</emph> accordingly was executed uppon divers
of His Ma<emph type="p">t</emph>&bholngs; Sub<emph type="p">t</emph>&bholngs; in a warlike manner w<emph type="p">th</emph>in the said Realme of Ireland and in soe doeing did leavy warr against
the King&bholngs; &bhomtie; and his liege people in that Kingdome;. And alsoe for that hee uppon the unhappy dissolu&bhocotil;n of the
last Parliament did slaunder the Howse of C&bhooov;mons to His &bhomtie; and did councell and advise His &bhomtie; that hee was
loose and absolved from Rules of Government. And that hee [had<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] an Army in Ireland which hee might imploy to reduce this Kingdome. For wh<emph type="p">th</emph>hee deserveth to undergoe the Paines and Forfeitures of High Treason. And the said
Earle hath bin alsoe an Incendiary of the Warrs betweene the two Kingdomes of England &amp; Scotland. All wh<emph type="p">th</emph>
Offences hath bin sufficiently prooved against the said Earle upon his Impeachment. Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the
Kings most excellent &bhomtie; And by the Lord&bholngs; and C&bhooov;mons in this present Parliament assembled, and by Authority
of the same That the said Earle of Strafford for the haynous Crymes and Offences aforesaid stand and bee adjudged
attainted of High Treason and shall suffer such paines of Death and incur the Forfeitures of his Good&bholngs; and Chattell&bholngs;
Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; &amp; Hereditament&bholngs; of anie Estate of Freehold or Inheritance in the said Kingdomes of England and
Ireland w<emph type="p">ch</emph>the said Earle or anie other to his use or in trust for him have or had the daie of the first sitting of this
present Parliament or at anie tyme since; Provided That noe Judge or Judges Justice or Justices whatsoever shall adjudge
or interpret anie A&bholigct; or Thing to be Treason nor heare or determine anie Treason nor in anie other manner then hee or
they should or ought [to<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] have done before the makeing of this A&bholigct;, and as if this A&bholigct; had never bin had nor made,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>II. General Saving.</head>
			<para id="p11">Saveing alwaies unto all and singuler Persons and Bodies Pollitique &amp; Corporate theire heires and successors others
then the said Earle and his heires and such as clayme from by or under him, all such right title and interest of in and
to all and singuler such of the said Land&bholigct; Tenements and Hereditament&bholigct;e they or anie of them had before the
first daie of this present Parliamen<emph type="p">t</emph> Anie thing herein contained to the contrarie notwithstanding: Provided that the passing
of this present A&bholngs;is Ma<emph type="p">t</emph>&bholngs;
assent thereunto shall not be anie determina&bhocotil;n of this present Sessions of Parliament,
But that this present Sessions of Parliament and all bills and matters whatsoever depending in Parliament and not fully
ena&bholigct;ed or determined, And all Statut&bholngs; and A&bholigct;
of Parliament w<emph type="p">ch</emph> have theire continuance untill the end of this present
Session of Parliament shall remaine continue and bee in full force as if this A&bholigct; had not bin.</para>
			<para id="p12">ITEM quedam peti&bhocotil;es privatas &bhopubr;sonas concernentes in se formam Actus continentes exhibita fuerunt &bhopubrc;d&bhocotil; D[omin]o
Regi in Parlam &bhopcrl;d qua[rum] tituli subscribuntur viz.</para>
			<para id="p13">PRIVATE ACTS.</para>
			<para id="p14">1. An Act for the Attainder of Thomas Earle of Strafford of High Treason.</para>
			<para id="p15">2. An Act to enable the Marquesse of Winchester to grant estates for three lives or one and twentie yeares
&amp;c of Lands in the County of Southampton &amp;c reserving the old rents.</para>
			<para id="p16">3. An Act for naturalizing of Dorothy Spencer daughter of Henry Lord Spencer Baron Spencer of Wormleighton.</para>
			<para id="p17">4. An Act for the enabling of the sale and leasing of Lands for payment of the debts of Thomas late Earle
of Winchelsea.</para>
			<para id="p18">5. An Act for the setling and estating upon the Right Honourable the Lady Elizabeth Countesse Dowager of Exceter
her heires and assignes for ever the Scite of the Hospitall of Saint Leonards without the Towne of Newarke upon Trent
in the County of Nottingham with the Dwelling House and other Buildings thereupon built and of certaine Closes and
Grounds parcell of the possessions of the said Hospitall and for the annexing of diverse Lands and Tenements of better
value being the inheritance of the said Countesse unto the possessions of the said Hospitall for ever in liew of the same.</para>
			<para id="p19">6. An Act for the making of the Chappell of Hoole in the Countie of Lancaster a Parish Church and no part
of the parish of Croston.</para>
			<para id="p20">7. An Act for John Eggars Free School within the parish of Alton in the Countie of Southampton.</para>
			<para id="p21">8. An Act for the setling of certaine Manors Lands Tenements &amp; Hereditaments on Katherine Countesse Dowager
of Bedford William now Earle of Bedford John Russell and Edward Russell Esquires sons of Francis Earle of Bedford
deceased.</para>
			<para id="p22">9. An Act for the confirmation of his Majesties Letters Patents to the Town of Plimouth and for dividing the
parish &amp; building of a new Church there.</para>
			<para id="p23">10. An Act for the alteration of the Estate and Tenure of some Lands within the parish of Fulham in the
County of Middlesex held of the Lord Bishop of London as of his Mannor of Fulham</para>
			<para id="p24">11. An Act to setle the Mannor of Belgrave and other Lands in the County of Leicester to and upon William
Byerly Esquire his heires &amp; assignees for &amp; towards payment of the debts of William Davenport Esquire deceased.</para>
			<para id="p25">12. An Act to inhable Sir Alexander Denton Knight to sell the Manor of Great Barvard alias Barford Saint Michael
and other Lands in this present Act mentioned for the payment of his debts &amp; preferment of his younger Children.</para>
			<para id="p26">13. An Act for the assuring of a Messuage called Duresme House alias Durham House and certaine Stables part
of the possessions of the Bishop of Duresme scituate in the parish of Saint Martins in the Feilds in the Countie of
Middlesex unto the Right Honourable Philip Earle of Pembrooke and Mountgomerie and his heires and of a yearely
rent of two hundred pounds per annum to the said Bishopp of Duresm and his successors in leiw thereof.</para>
			<para id="p27">The whole of the Acts of this Session are here printed as having passed in the 16th Year of King Charles the First, there not appearing upon the
Roll any thing to distinguish what Acts passed in the 16th and 17th, and in the 17th and 18th Years; the Three Parts of the Roll being a regular
Continuation of Acts under the same Head as to the Session.</para>
			<para id="p28">At the Parliament Office the first 22 Acts are in a Bundle, indorsed, "16 &amp; 17 Car." and by "The long Calendar" in the same Office are
stated to have passed, "Att the first Recesse of Parliament begunn at Westm' the Third Day of November An&deg; R. R. Car. 16&deg; &amp; 17&deg; 1640. 1641."
And the remaining 15 Acts are in another Bundle; indorsed, "17 and 18 Car." and in the same Calendar are stated to be, "Acts of Parliament
"passed after the first Recesse A&deg; 17 &amp; 18 Car. Regis in the Parliament begunn on the Thirde Day of November An&deg; 16 Car. Regis."</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This Act is not in the Bundles of Original Acts of this Year at the Parliament Office, although the Title appears in the Calendar.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">from the Original Act in the Parliament Office.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


