<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47258" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for supplying and explaining certaine defe&bholigct;s in an A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy provision of money for disbanding and paying off the forces of this kingdome both by Land and Sea.[Rot. Parl. 12. C. II. p. 2. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>c. 9. ante.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Householders, within Two Days after Demand, to deliver to Assessor, &amp;c. List of all Persons above 16 residing in their Families.; Penalty &pound;5, and for every Person omitted 10s</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the supplying and explaining of certaine defe&bholigct;s in an A&bholigct; of this present Parliament (entituled An A&bholigct;
for speedy provision of money for disbanding and paying off the forces of this kingdome both by Land and
Sea) It is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings Most Excellent Majesty and by and with the consent and advice of the
Lord&bholngs; and Commons in Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That every Householder being
Master or Mistris of a family shall within two dayes after demand made by any Assesser or other Officer therunto
appointed deliver unto such Assessor or Officer of every parish towne or place wherin such Householder being
Master or Mistresse shall dwell a true and perfe&bholigct; list of all persons above the age of sixteen yeares as shall
be inhabiting or residing in their respe&bholigct;ive families together with the names sur-names degrees and qualities of such
persons and if any such Master or Mistris shall make default of such delivery being therof convi&bholigct;ed before any
two of the Commissioners in the said A&bholigct; named, he or she shall forfeit the summe of five pound&bholngs; to the uses
in this A&bholigct; expressed and for every person ommitted out of such list as aforesaid the summe of ten shillings, the
one moyety of such forfeiture to be imployed to the Informer, the other moyety to the uses in the said A&bholigct;
expressed, which forfeitures shall be leavyed by distresse and sale of the offenders good&bholngs; rendering the overplus
to the Owner.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners before 20th O&bholigct;. next to return into Exchequer Duplicates of Rates and Names of Colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
			<para id="p3">And Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the Commissioners of the severall and respe&bholigct;ive
Countyes Cityes and Places in the said A&bholigct; mentioned shall at or before the twentyeth day of O&bholigct;ober next returne
into the Court of Exchequer true and perfe&bholigct; duplicates of all summes of money taxed rated and assessed by
vertue of the said A&bholigct; together with the names of the respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;ors appointed for receiving of the same,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Commissioners for London and Middlesex to pay Monies received by them to the Treasurers appointed by the said A&bholigct;, whose Acquittance shall be a Discharge.</head>
			<para id="p4">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the Commissioners in the said A&bholigct; named and appointed
for taxing and assessing of all and every person within the Citty of London and Liberties thereof and the County
of Midlesex shall (after the receipt of all and every summe and summes of money paid unto them by the
severall Colle&bholigct;ors within the said County Citty and Liberties) immediately pay over the same unto the Treasurers
in and by the said A&bholigct; appointed (and not unto the Sheriffes of the said Citty) whose acquittance or acquittances
shall be from time to time a sufficient discharge in that behalfe,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The 1d. in the Pound allowed by the said A&bholigct; to be taken by the Treasurers as well in Discharge of incident Charges as for rewarding Persons employed by them.</head>
			<para id="p5">And whereas the Treasurers in the said A&bholigct; named are authorized thereby to take unto themselves one penny
in the pound out of such moneyes paid in by vertue of the said A&bholigct; to be distributed unto such person or persons
as they shall imploy in receiving and issueing of the said moneyes in such manner and proportion as they shall
thinke fitt, It is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that the said one penny in the pound shall be
taken by the said Treasurers as well in discharge of all incident charges as the said Treasurers shall be putt unto
for carrying on the said service as for rewarding such persons as they shall thinke fitt to imploy in and about the
service aforesaid in such manner and proportion as the said Treasurers shall thinke fitt,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Persons having Estates in one or more Counties, and paying in one for his greatest Proportion in the several Counties, in what case discharged in all the other Counties.</head>
			<para id="p6">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that if any person have an estate in one or more Counties
and shall pay in any one County or place what he shall or can be charged withall as his greatest proportion
for his degree or whole estate in the severall Counties and places (if the same shall exceed his degree, and
produceing an acquittance or certificate thereof, the Commissioners in the said A&bholigct; named are hereby authorised
and required to discharge such person in all other Countyes and places where he shall happen to be taxed and
assessed,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Commissioners to issue out Warrants under Hand and Seal to Officers to distrain on Tenants for Default of Landlords.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Officers to distrain accordingly</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that the said Commissioners or any three of them are
hereby required and impowered to issue out their warrant or warrants under their hands and seales or under the
hand&bholngs; and seales of any three of them to the Constables Pettie Constables or other his Majesties Officers Ministers
or other persons inhabiting within the severall Countyes Cittyes Townes and places respe&bholigct;ively requireing them or
any of them to distraine the good&bholngs; and chattells of all and every person and persons and every tennant and tennants
for and on the behalfe of his her or their respe&bholigct;ive Landlord, who shall refuse or negcle&bholigct; to pay the respe&bholigct;ive
summes charged upon him her or them by vertue of the aforesaid A&bholigct;, And the said Constables Petty Constables
and other his Majesties said Officers and Ministers and other persons inhabiting as aforesaid are hereby required to
make such distresse accordingly</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Stewards, &amp;c. of Peers to deliver Lists of the Families of Peers.</head>
			<para id="p9">[Provided alwayes That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend or be construed to extend
to any Peere or Peeres of this Realme, but that the Steward of any of the Peeres or some other servant of the
said Peeres shall deliver in the lists of their families to such as are appointed by this A&bholigct;, and that noe Peere or
Peeres shall be assessed otherwise then as in the said recited A&bholigct;.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


