<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47256" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for continuing of the Excise till the five and twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred and sixty. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p. 2. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Excise continued.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Persons to whom the same to be paid.; Commissioners named.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty and the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in Parliament assembled that
the imposition called Excise shall continue to be colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid (together with all arrears thereof
from Farmers since the twenty fifth day of March One thousand six hundred fifty seaven and [from Merchant&bholngs; &#x0026; other
&bhopubr;sons since the twenty fifth day of March 1658)<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] by and to Nathaniell Manton Benjamin Goodwin Thomas Lenthall
and Edward Wingate Esquiers Commissioners hereby appointed for the Grand Excise and their Deputyes from the
twentyeth day of August inclusively in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and sixty untill the five
and twentyeth day of December in the same yeare according unto and after the rates rules and proportions and upon
the same Good&bholngs; and Merchandizes as the same was payable and colle&bholigct;ed the five and twentyeth day of Aprill One
thousand six hundred and sixty, And Sir Richard Browne Sir William Doyley John Birch William Prinne Edward
King and Robert Scawen Esquiers hereby appointed Commissioners for appeales, and regulating the Excise, the aforesaid
Commissioners for Excise their Sub-Commissioners and other Officers respectively under the regulations and rules in
all matters and things in that case provided, and as it was used and collected the said five and twentyeth day of April
are hereby authorized and required to a&bholigct; accordingly.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Certain Goods imported discharged from Excise.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided that all sorts of Oyles Wines Tobaccoes of the English Plantation&bholngs; [Tapes Silkes<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Incles Linnens Tiles
called Pan tiles Playing Cards Girdles of all sorts, Cabinets of all sortes, Copperice Hopps all sorts of Lace imported
after the twenty fourth of July One thousand six hundred and sixty shall be thence [forth<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] discharged of the Duty
of Excise.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Silkes Tapes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


