<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47259" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XI. An Act of Free and Generall Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p.2. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>The Causes and Ends of this Pardon and Indemnity.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The general Pardon.; Treasons and other Offences mentioned since 1st Jan. 1637</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">THE Kings most Excellent Majesty taking into His Gratious and Serious consideration the long and great
Troubles Discord&bholngs; and Warrs that have for many Yeares past beene in this Kingdome, And that diverse
of His Subje&bholigct;s are by occasion thereof and otherwise falne into, and be obnoxious to great paines and penaltyes,
Out of a hearty and pious Desire to put an end to all Suites and Controversies that by occasion of the late
Distra&bholigct;ions have arisen and may arise betweene all His Subje&bholigct;s, And to the intent that noe Crime whatsoever
committed against His Majesty or His Royall Father shall hereafter rise in Judgement or be brought in Question
against any of them to the least endamagement of them either in their Lives Libertyes Estates or to the prejudice
of their Reputations by any Reproach or Terme of Distin&bholigct;ion, And to bury all Seed&bholngs; of future Discord&bholngs; and
remembrance of the former as well in His owne Breast as in the Breasts of His Subje&bholigct;s one toward&bholngs; another,
And in performance of His Royall and Gratious Word signified by His Letters to the severall Houses of Parliament
now assembled, and His Declarations in that behalfe published Is pleased that it may be Ena&bholigct;ed, And be it
Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty with the advice and consent of the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in this
present Parliament assembled First That all and all manner of Treasons, Misprisions of Treason, Murthers Felonies
Offences Crimes Contempts and Misdemeanors Counceled Commanded A&bholigct;ed or done since the first day of January
in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred thirty seaven by any person or persons before the [twenty
fourth<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and sixty other then the persons hereafter
by name excepted, in such manner as they are hereafter excepted by vertue or colour of any Command Power
Authoritie Commission Warrant or Instru&bholigct;ions from his late Majesty King Charles or his Majesty that now is,
or from any other person or persons deriving or pretending to derive authority mediately or immediately from
both or either of their Majestyes, or by vertue or colour of any Authority derived [mediately or immediately<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of or
from both Houses or either House of Parliament or of or from any Convention or Assembly called or reputed,
or taking on them the name of a Parliament, Or by from or under any Authority stiled or knowne by the Name
of The Keepers of the Liberty of England by Authority of Parliament, Or by vertue or colour of any Writ,
Commission Letters Patents Instru&bholigct;ion or Instru&bholigct;ions of or from any person or persons Tituled reputed or taken
to be Lord Prote&bholigct;or of the Commonwealth of England Scotland and Ireland and the Dominions therunto belonging,
or Lord Prote&bholigct;or of the Commonwealth of England Scotland and Ireland and the Dominions and Territories therto
belonging, or assumeing the authority or reputed to be Cheife Magistrate of the Commonwealth, or Commander in
cheife of the Forces or Armies of this Nation by Sea or Land or by any pretence Warrant or Command whatsoever
from them, or any of them, or their or either of their respe&bholigct;ive Councills or Councill, or any Member of such
Councill or Councills, or from any person or persons whatsoever deriving or pretending to derive Authority from
them or any of them be Pardoned Released Indempnified Discharged and put in utter Oblivion.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Abettors of such Treasons and other Crimes pardoned,</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i"> and restored to their Lands</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And that all and every the person and persons A&bholigct;ing Advising Assisting Abetting and Counceling the same
they their Heires Executers and Administrators (except as before is excepted) be and are hereby pardoned Released
Acquitted Indempnified and discharged from the same, And of and from all paines of death and other paines,
Judgements Indi&bholigct;ments Convi&bholigct;ions Attainders Outlawries Penaltyes Escheats and Forfeitures therefore had or given
or that might accrew for the same, And that all such Judgements Indi&bholigct;ments Convi&bholigct;ions Attainders Outlawries
Penaltyes Escheats and Forfeitures and every of them, and all Grants therupon made, and all Estates derived
under the same be and are hereby Declared and Ena&bholigct;ed to be from henceforth null and void, And that all
measne proffits not yet received by such Grantees shall be and are here hereby discharged: And that all and
every Person and Persons Bodyes Politique and Corporate their and every of their Heires Executors Administrators
and Successors shall be, and are hereby restored to all [&amp; every<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] their Lands Tenements and Hereditaments Goods
Chattels and other things forfeited, which to his Majesty doe or shall appertaine by reason of any offence herein
before mentioned, and not hereafter in this present A&bholigct; excepted and Foreprised,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. All Appeals, Personal A&bholigct;ions, and Suits, &amp;c. by reason of any Trespass, &amp;c. pardoned.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That all appeales [and all<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] personall A&bholigct;ions Suites Molestations and Prosecutions
whatsoever for or by reason of any A&bholigct;. of Hostility Trespasse Assault Imprisonment or breach of the Peace
Advised Councelled Commanded Appointed Happened A&bholigct;ed or done by reason of the late Troubles or the late
Warrs in his Majestyes Dominions or relating therunto, and all Judgements and Executions therupon had before
the first day of May in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred fifty &amp; eight stand and be from
henceforth discharged; But not to restore to any Person or Persons any summes of money, meane Proffitts or
Good&bholngs; already received or taken upon such Execution, or to give any [accompt<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>VI. The like by reason of any Commission by the late or present King, or by Colour of any Ordinance of one or both Houses of Parliament, or the late Prote&bholigct;or, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p6">And be it likewise Ena&bholigct;ed That all Appeales and all Personall A&bholigct;ions and cause of such A&bholigct;ions Suites
Molestations and Prosecutions whatsoever for or by reason of any A&bholigct; or thing Advised Counceled Commanded
A&bholigct;ed or done by vertue or colour of any Authority or Commission granted by his late Majesty or his Majestie
that now is, or by vertue or colour of any Order or Ordinance of one or both Houses of Parliament siting at
Westminster, Or by any A&bholigct; or Order made by any Persons assumeing the name of a Parliament, and siting as
a Parliament at Westminster after the death of the late King Charles the First, Or by the Authority of the said
Keepers of the Libertyes of England, Or by any Ordinance of either of the late Prote&bholigct;ors and Councill, Or by
or upon any Commission Writt Processe or Warrant by them or any of them, or by Authority derived from
them or any of them, And all demands of Arrearages of Rents and meane Profits of Lands Tenements or
Hereditaments heretofore incurred or growne due, which have beene paid received or disposed by vertue or colour
of any the Authorities or pretended Authorityes aforesaid, other then such Arrearages or meane profits as are
or shall be otherwise disposed by any A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s of this present Session of Parliament be from henceforth
discharged.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Pardon of all Treasons, &amp;c.; (Except Arrears of Customs, &amp;c. due from Farmers.) Tenths, First Fruits, &amp;c.; Pains of Death, &amp;c.; before and unto 24th June 1660</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And it is further by the Authority aforesaid Ena&bholigct;ed in the second place That all and every the Subje&bholigct;s
of these his Majestyes Realmes of England and Ireland the Dominion of Wales the Isles of Jersey and Garnsey
and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweed and other his Majestyes Dominions the Heires Executors and Administrators
of them and every of them, and all and singular Bodyes in any manner of wise corporated Citties Burroughs
Shires Ridings Hundreds Lathes Rapes Wappentakes Townes Villages Hamlets and Tythings and every of them
and the [Successors and Successor<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] of every of them shall be and are by the authority of this present Parliament
Acquitted Pardoned Released Indempnified and Discharged against the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors and
every of them of and from all manner of Treasons Misprisions of Treason, Felonies [Offences<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Contempts Trespasses
Entryes Wrongs Deceits Misdemeanours Forfeitures Penaltyes and summs of Money Intrusions Meane profits
Wardships Mariages Reliefes Liveries Ouster le maines Meane Rates Respits of Homage Fines and Seisures for
Alienation without Licence Arrearages of Rents (other then the Arrearages of Rents due from the late Farmers
or pretended Farmers of the Excise or Customes respe&bholigct;ively, and other then such Arrearages of Rents or meane
Proffits as are or shall be otherwise disposed by any A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s of this present Parliament) and of and from
all Arrearages of Tenths and First fruites Fines post-fines Issues and Amercements and all Recognizances Bonds
or other Securities given for payment of them or any of them, Concealments of Customes and Excise Arrearages
of purveyance and of compositions for the same and of and from all paines of Death paines corporall and
pecuniary and generally of and from all other Things Causes Quarels Suites Judgements and Executions in this
present A&bholigct; hereafter not Excepted nor Foreprised which may be or can be by his Majesty in any wise or by
any meanes pardoned before and unto the [twenty fourth<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred and sixty to every or any of his said Subje&bholigct;s Bodyes corporate Cittyes Burroughes Shires Ridings
Hundred&bholngs; Lathes Rapes Wapentakes Townes Villages and Tythings or any of them,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Grants of Wardships since 25th March 1641 discharged.</head>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all Grants and Patents since the [twenty fifth<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] of March
One thousand six hundred forty one touching the Wardship and custody of the Body and Lands, or touching the
mariage of any Heire within age and all meane profits yet unreceived and demandable by reason therof shall be and
are hereby from henceforth Discharged.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. All things not excepted shall be pardoned by</head>
			<para id="p10"><emph type="i">general words, as if particularly named.; Proviso for Exceptions</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And alsoe the Kings Majesty is contented That it be further Ena&bholigct;ed by authority of this present Parliament And be
it Ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that this His said Free pardon Indempnity and Oblivion shall be as good and
effe&bholigct;uall in the Law to every of his said Subje&bholigct;s Bodyes Corporate and others before rehearsed in for and against
all things which be not hereafter in this present A&bholigct; Excepted and Foreprized as the same Pardon Indempnity and
Oblivion should have beene if all Offences Contempts Forfeitures Causes Matters Suites Quarrels Judgements Executions
Penaltyes and all other things not hereafter in this present A&bholigct; Excepted and Foreprized had beene perticularly
singularly especially and plainely named rehearsed and specified and alsoe pardoned by proper and expresse Word&bholngs;
and Names in their Kindes Natures and Qualityes by Words and Termes thereunto requisite to have beene putt in
and expressed in this present A&bholigct; of free Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion, And that His said Subje&bholigct;s nor any of
them nor the Heires Executors or Administrators of any of them, nor the said Bodyes Corporate and others before
named and rehearsed nor any of them be nor shall be sued Vexed [nor<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Inquieted by or on the behalfe of the Kings
Majesty His Heires or Successors in their Bodyes Good&bholngs; Chattels Land&bholngs; or Tenements for any manner of Matter
Cause Contempt Misdemeanour Forfeiture Trespasse Offence or any other thing suffered done or committed before
the said [twenty fourth<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] day of June One thousand six hundred and sixty against his late Majesty King Charles, or his
Majesty that now is His Crowne Dignity Prerogative Lawes or Statutes, but onely for such Matters Causes and
Offences as be Excepted and Foreprized by this present A&bholigct; out of the same Any Statute or Statutes Laws Customes
or Usages heretofore had made or used to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding, And that all and every the
Kings said Subje&bholigct;s, and all and singular Bodyes Corporate and others before rehearsed may by him or themselves
or by his or their Deputy or Deputyes or by his or their Attourney or Attourneys according to the Lawes of this
Realme plead and minister this present A&bholigct; of Free Pardon for his or their Discharge of or for any thing that is by
vertue of this present A&bholigct; Pardoned Discharged Given or Granted without any Fee, or other thing paying to any
person or persons for writing or entry of the Judgements or other cause concerning such Plea Writing or Entry, but
onely sixteene pence to be paid to the Officer or Clarke that shall enter such Plea Matter or Judgement for the
Partyes Discharge in that behalfe Any Law Statute Usage or Custome to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. This Pardon, &amp;c. to be expounded in all Courts most beneficially for the Subje&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p12">And furthermore the Kings Majestye is contented and pleased that it be Ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority
aforesaid That this his said Free Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion by the generall Words Clauses and Sentences before
rehearsed shall be reputed deemed adjudged expounded allowed and taken in all manner of Courts of his Highnesse
and elsewhere most beneficiall and available to all and singular the said Subje&bholigct;s bodyes corporate and others before
rehearsed and to every of them in all things not in this present A&bholigct; excepted or foreprized without any ambiguity
question or other delay whatsoever it shall be, to be made pleaded obje&bholigct;ed or alleadged by the King our Soveraigne
Lord his Heires or Successors or by his or any of their generall Attourney or Attourneys or by any person or persons
for his Highnes or any of His Heires or Successors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Officer, &amp;c. of the Court of Chancery, &amp;c. Sheriff, &amp;c. issuing Process against or going about to disquiet or trouble any Person pardoned;</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Penalty; and such Process void</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And furthermore be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the King our Soveraigne Lord and by the Authority aforesaid That if any
Officer or Clerke of any of his Highnes Courts commonly called The Chauncery Kings bench and Common pleas or
of his Exchequer or any other Officer or Clerke of any other of his Highnesse Courts within this Realme at any time
after the passing of this present A&bholigct; make out or write out any manner of Writts Processe Summons or other Precepts
whereby any of the said Subje&bholigct;s or any of the said Bodyes corporated or others before rehearsed or any of them shall
be in any wise arreasted attached distrained summoned or otherwise vexed inquieted or grieved in his or their
Bodyes, Land&bholngs; Tenements Good&bholngs; or Chattels or in any of them for or because of any manner of thing pardoned
or discharged by vertue of this A&bholigct; of Free Pardon, Or if any Sheriffe or Escheater or any of their Deputy or
Deputyes, or any Bailiffe or other Officer whatsoever by colour of his or their Office or otherwise after the passing
of this [present<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] A&bholigct; doe levy receive take or withhold of or from any person or persons any thing pardoned or
discharged by this A&bholigct;, That then every such person soe offending, and therof lawfully convi&bholigct;ed or condemned
by any sufficient testimony witnesse or proofe, shall yeild and pay for recompence therof to the party soe grieved or
offended thereby his or their treble dammages besides all costs of the Suite, and shall alsoe forfeit and loose to the
Kings Majesty for every such default ten pound&bholngs;. And neverthelesse all and singular such Writts Processe and
Precepts soe to be made for or upon any manner of thing pardoned or discharged by this present A&bholigct; of Free
Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion shall be utterly void and of none effe&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Exceptions of Murder not comprized in the First Clause.; Piracy.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Buggery.; Rapes, and wilful taking away any Maid, &amp;c.; Bigamy.; 1 Jac. I. c. II.; Witchcraft.; Accounts of certain Treasurers and Receivers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">Except and alwayes foreprized out of this Free and Generall Pardon all murders done or committed by any
person or persons other then such which are pardoned and discharged in the first clause of pardon abovementioned,
And alsoe excepted and alwayes foreprized out of this Generall and Free Pardon all and every offences of Piracy
and Robery done upon the Seas not done in relation to the Differences and Warrs aforesaid, and every procureing
or abetting of any such Offenders, and the comforting and receiving of them or any of them or any good&bholngs; taken
by way of such Piracy or Robery upon the Seas as aforesaid, And alsoe excepted the detestable and abominable Vice
of Buggery commited with Mankind or Beast, And alsoe excepted all Rapes and carnall Ravishments of Women,
And alsoe excepted all Ravishments, and wilfull taking away or marrying of any Maid Widow or Damzell against
her will, or without the assent or agreement of her Parents or of such as then had her in custody, and alsoe all
Offences of aiding comforting procureing or abeting of any such Ravishment willfull takeing or marrying had
committed or done, And alsoe excepted all Offences made Felony by a certaine A&bholigct; made and ordained intituled
An A&bholigct; to restraine all persons from [Mariages<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] untill their former Wives and former Husband&bholngs; be dead. And alsoe
excepted all Offences of Invocations Conjurations Witchcrafts Sorceries Inchantments and Charmes and all Offences
of procuring abeting or comforting of the same, and all persons now attainted or convi&bholigct;ed of any the said
excepted Offences, And alsoe excepted all and singular the accompts of all and every person and persons appointed
by any of the Authorityes or pretended Authorityes aforesaid to be Treasurer Receiver Farmer or Colle&bholigct;or (other
then the Subcolle&bholigct;ors of the severall Parishes Townes and Hamlets respe&bholigct;ively for and concerning their Receipts
before the foure and twentyeth day of June in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred fifty nine) who have
received or colle&bholigct;ed any Subsidy Custome Subsidy of Tonnage and Poundage Prize-Good&bholngs; Assesment Sequestration
New Impost or Excise or of any the Rents and Revenewes of any Land&bholngs; or Hereditaments of or belonging to the
late King Queene or Prince or King that now is, or belonging [to<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] the late Archbishopricks Bishopricks Deanes or
Deanes and Chapters Canons Prebend&bholngs; and other Officers belonging to any Cathedrall or Collegiate Church, or
Popish Recusants convi&bholigct; or of persons Sequestred for their Recusancy or other Sequestred Estates received or
colle&bholigct;ed by or paid unto them since the thirtyeth of January in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred
forty two, and of all Moneyes and other dutyes growne due or contra&bholigct;ed upon the Sale or Disposition of them
or any of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. The Heirs and Lands of Accountants excepted.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Accountants in respe&bholigct; of Monies disbursed by them by virtue of any Order, &amp;c. of Parliament, or the late Prote&bholigct;or</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p18">Provided that the Heires Executors Administrators or Tertennants of the Land&bholngs; of any Accomptant within
this Exception now deceised shall not be charged with nor lyeable unto any accompt for the matters in this Exception
mentioned, Except for such summe or summes of money as remaine due upon any of their accompts already Stated
and Determined and are not yet paid in, and that noe Accomptant as aforesaid now liveing shall be lyeable to make
accompt of any summe or summes of money paid or disbursed or otherwise allowed or discharged by vertue or
colour of any Order or Ordinance of both or either House or Houses of Parliament, or any Convention or Assembly
called or Reputed or takeing on them the name of a Parliament, or of Oliver Cromwell pretended Prote&bholigct;or or of
Richard his Sonne while he continued or was stiled or obeyed as Prote&bholigct;or, or by any persons a&bholigct;ing as a Committee
appointed by the said two Houses or either of them, or by any such Convention or Assembly or any Order or
Dire&bholigct;ion of such Committee or Committees or any person or persons a&bholigct;ing as a publique Councell, though haveing
noe legall authority soe to doe, or by their or any their Order or Orders or Dire&bholigct;ion.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Fees and Salaries, &amp;c. not to be accounted for.</head>
			<para id="p19">It being further declared and Ena&bholigct;ed, and is Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe person nor persons
shall be charged for any Moneyes by him received for the Fees Salaries and Wages then allowed, or for Moneyes
by him disbursed upon any publique use or pretence though the Dire&bholigct;ion or Authority whereby the same Money
was issued was not or be not Legall and Warrantable in Law.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Military or Naval Payments not to be accounted for.</head>
			<para id="p20">And be it further provided That noe Military or Commissioned Officer of the Armies or Navies or Souldier
or Mariner who before the twenty fifth of March one thousand six hundred fifty nine hath received any Moneyes
for his owne pay or the pay of other Soldiers, or for any other Contingencies of the Soldiers or Garisons under
his command, or by way of reward shall be called to accompt therefore.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. No Persons to be called to an account for Matter mentioned in this Exception after the 24th June 1662.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Persons who have received Monies since 1st Jan.1642, and before 30th Jan. 1648, taking Oath as herein mentioned.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p22">And that noe person whatsoever shall be called to [an<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] accompt for any the matters in this Exception mentioned
after the fower and twentyeth day of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six hundred
sixty and two now next ensueing, And that in case any person who stand&bholngs; accomptable for any Moneyes received
since the first of January One thousand six hundred forty(<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) two, and before the thirtyeth of January One thousand
six hundred forty(<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) eight have beene robbed or plundered by Souldiers or others of the moneyes in their hand&bholngs;, or
of any Notes, or Bookes of Receipts or Acquittances touching their payments or discharge, then the Oath or Oathes
of such party or partyes of the same respe&bholigct;ively shall be a good discharge for soe much of their accompt, And that
the Oath of every Accomptant in or betweene the yeares One thousand six hundred forty two and One thousand
six hundred forty eight of what they have paid to any publique use by or according to any publique or pretended
Order or Authority whatsoever shall be a good discharge as to soe much of the accompt of such person or persons,
And except all First fruites and Tenthes in the hand&bholngs; of any Receiver not having disbursed as in the last Exception
is expressed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Discharges given in the Exchequer not to be avoided, except Accounts of the Revenues of Churches in Wales, Bribery, Perjury, Subornation, Forging Writings or Examinations of Witnesses.</head>
			<para id="p23">Provided That all and every Judgement of Discharge or Quietus est had or given at any time upon any accompt
in the publique Exchequer, since the yeare One thousand six hundred forty eight be allowed and shall not be
avoided except all accompts of the [Revenewes<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] of Churches and Viccaridges in Wales and the County of Monmouth
and all Judgements of Discharge or quietus therupon obtained And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all offences
of Bribery Perjuries and the Subornation of Perjury [of<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Witnesses and offences of forging or counterfeiting any
Deeds Debentures Bills of publique Faith, Escripts Wills or other Writings whatsoever or of any Examinations or
Testimonies of any witnesse or witnesses tending to bring any person or persons in danger of his Life Liberty or
Estate and the giving the same in evidence and the councelling or procuring of any such counterfeiting or forgeing
to be had or made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Exception of Persons embezzling the Goods of the late King, Queen, Prince, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p24">And alsoe excepted all offences in detaining imbezeling or purloyning any the Good&bholngs; Money [Chattels<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] or
Jewells of the late King Queene or Prince or any of the children of the late King and Queene other then Shipping
Stores and Ammunitions of Warr and other then such Good&bholngs; and Chattels as have beene sold or disposed of to
any of the Servants or Creditors of his late Majesty in or toward&bholngs; satisfa&bholigct;ion of their debts or wages.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Exception of Fines,; Amerciaments, &amp;c. received by Sheriffs, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p25">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all Issues Fines and Amerceaments Rents and other publique Dutyes being
leavied received or colle&bholigct;ed by any Shiriffe Undersheriffe Bailiffe Minister or other Officer to or for the use of the
late King the Parliament or the said Keepers of the Liberty of England, or any other person stiling himselfe Prote&bholigct;or
or for his Majesty that now is, and not accompted for and discharged.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Exception of Jesuits and Romish Priests, 27 Eliz. c. 2.</head>
			<para id="p26">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all and every offence and offences committed or done by any Jesuit
Seminary or Romish Priest whatsoever contrary to the tenor or effe&bholigct; of the Statute made in the Seaven and twentyeth
yeare of the Raigne of the late Queene Elizabeth intituled An A&bholigct; against Jesuits Seminaries Priests and other
disobedient persons or of any part therof and all out lawries proceedings judgements and executions for the same
offences or any of them,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Proviso for Issue of Writs of Capias Utlagatum; and for any Party outlawed suing out Scire-Facias against the Plaintiff.</head>
			<para id="p27">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for all
and every Clerke and other Officer of the Courts at Westminster to award and make Writs of Capias Utlagatum
at the suite of the party plaintiffe against such persons outlawed as be pardoned by this A&bholigct; to the intent to compell
the defendent or defendents to make answere to the plaintiffe or plaintiffes at whose Suite he or they were outlawed, and
that every person soe outlawed shall sue [out<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] a Writt of Scire facias [againt<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] the party or partyes at whose suite he
or they were soe outlawed before this pardon in that behalfe shall be allowed [to<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] him or them soe outlawed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Exception of Persons outlawed upon Capias ad satisfaciendum, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p28">Provided and be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That this A&bholigct; of generall pardon shall not in any wise
extend to pardon any Outlawries upon any Writt of Capias ad satisfaciendum untill such time as the party soe
outlawed shall satisfie or otherwise agree with the party at whose suite the same person was soe oulawed or
condemned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Exception of Informations and Proccedings concerning High Ways, Bridges, &amp;c. Recognizances by Receivers, &amp;c. in the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p29">And alsoe excepted out of this pardon all informations and other proceedings depending concerning any common
Highwayes or Bridges and all issues returned upon any processe concerning the same since the thirtyeth of January
One thousand six hundred forty eight, Except alsoe all Recognizances Obligations and other Securityes given or
entred into since the five and twentyeth of March One thousand six hundred and forty by any Receiver Reeve
Bailiffe Colle&bholigct;or or other accountant in the Court of the publique Exchequer and their suretyes and their accounts
respe&bholigct;ively</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Exception of Obligations, &amp;c. not yet forfeited.</head>
			<para id="p30">Provided alwayes and be it Ena&bholigct;ed that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be construed
to pardon or discharge any Recognizance Obligation or Bond which is not yet forfeited.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Pardon extended to all A&bholigct;s of Hostility, Injuries, &amp;c. between the King and his Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">No mention thereof in Judicial Proceedings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p32">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that all a&bholigct;s of Hostility and Injuries whether betweene the
late King and the Lord&bholngs; and Commons then in Parliament assembled, or between any of the people of this Nation
which did arise upon any a&bholigct;ion attempt assistance councell or advice haveing relation unto, or falling out by reason
of the late troubles or in the late warrs [and<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] publique differences betweene the late King and Parliament or betweene
His now Majesty or any of his Subje&bholigct;s, and which are not in this A&bholigct; excepted That the same and whatsoever hath
ensued therupon whether trenching upon the Lawes and Liberties of this Nation or upon the Honour of His Majesty
or upon the Honour or Authority of the Parliament or to the prejudice of any perticular or private person shall in
noe time from and after the foure and twentyeth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
and sixty be called in question whatsoever be the quality of the person, or of whatsoever kinde or degre civill or
criminall the Injury is supposed to be, And that noe mention be made therof in time to come in Judgement or
Judiciall proceedings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Persons, within Three Years, using any words tending to revive the Memory of the late Differences; if a Gentleman, or above, Penalty &pound;10; if under that Degree, Penalty 40s.</head>
			<para id="p33">And to the intent and purpose that all names and termes of distin&bholigct;ion may [likewise be<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] putt into utter Oblivion
Be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any person or persons within the space of three yeares
next ensueing shall presume malitiously to call or alledge of, or obje&bholigct; against any other person or persons any
name or names, or other word&bholngs; of reproach any way tending to revive the memory of the late Differences or the
occasions thereof, That then every such person soe as aforesaid offending shall forfeit and pay unto the party grieved
in case such party offending shall be of the degree of a Gentleman or above ten pound&bholngs;, and if under that degree
the summe of forty shillings to be recovered by the party grieved by A&bholigct;ion of Debt to be therefore brought in any
of His Majestyes Courts of Record [where<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or wager of Law shall be allowed, or any more
then one Imparlance soe as the same A&bholigct;ion be commenced or prosecuted within six monthes [next<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] after the Offence
committed, And if the Jury sworne to try any Issue or Issues that shall be joyned in such A&bholigct;ion shall finde for
the plaintiffe they shall likewise give to every such plaintiffe forty shillings d&bhoaovm;mages over and above the penalty
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Exception of Persons plotting or designing the Irish Rebellion, 16 Car.I.c.33.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Marquis of Ormond and others</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">Provided alwayes that this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained shall not extend or give any benefit unto any
person or persons who have had any hand in the ploting contriving or designing the great and heinous Rebellion
of Ireland mentioned in one A&bholigct; passed in the Parliament begun at Westminster the third day of November in the
sixteenth yeare of King Charles intituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy and effe&bholigct;uall reduceing of the Rebells in His
Majestyes Kingdome of Ireland to their due obeidience to His Majesty and Crowne of England Or in aiding assisting
or abeting the same, [(Other then such as by another A&bholigct; intended hereafter to be passed shall be therin named
mentioned or expressed to be pardoned)<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] nor to enure to restore to any person or persons bodyes politique or
corporate (other then the Marquesse of Ormond Lord Steward of his Majestyes Household and other the Protestants
of Ireland [and their Heires and such other person and persons as in and by an A&bholigct; intended [to be<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] hereafter passed
shall be therin named mentioned or expressed in that behalfe<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] any Estate Libertyes Franchises or Hereditaments in
England or Ireland sold or disposed of by both or either Houses of Parliament, or any Convention assumeing the
Stile or name of a Parliament, or any person or persons deriving authority from them or any of them, or which was
approved or confirmed by them or any of them, nor to the meane proffits rents or contingencies of advantage
of the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Every Person pardoned may plead the general Issue.</head>
			<para id="p36">And it is further provided and ena&bholigct;ed That every person or persons hereby pardoned may plead the generall
Issue without speciall pleading of this pardon, and give this A&bholigct; of Pardon in evidence for his discharge, and that the
same shall be therupon allowed and the advantage thereof had as fully to all intents and purposes as if the same
had beene fully and well pleaded, And in such manner as any Justice of the peace Constable or other Officer
questioned for matters a&bholigct;ed by them as Officers or in execution of their Offices may have advantage of the matter
of their Justification upon the generall Issue by them pleaded by the Lawes and Statutes of this Kingdome,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Exception of Thefts and Felonies since 4th March 1659.</head>
			<para id="p37">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; nor any thing therin contained shall extend or be interpreted to extend to pardon
any person or persons whatsoever for any Theft or Stealing of any Good&bholngs; or other Felonies since the fourth day of
March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred fifty and nine, Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the
contrary therof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Exception of Goods to be restored under an A&bholigct; for Repeal of Two A&bholigct;s for Sequestrations.</head>
			<para id="p38">Provided alsoe that neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therin contained shall extend to acquit or discharge any
person or persons from makeing restitution of all such Rents summes of Money Horses Cattle or other Good&bholngs;
which by a certaine A&bholigct; or pretended A&bholigct; lately made entituled An A&bholigct; for repeale of two A&bholigct;s for Sequestrations
are required to be restored to those from whom they were taken, Nor shall this present A&bholigct; be construed to disable
or barr the respe&bholigct;ive owners or proprietors of and from their severall and respe&bholigct;ive A&bholigct;ions or Suites at Law or
in equity, for or by reason of the said or any other Rents Moneyes Horses Catle or Good&bholngs; which since the five
and twentyeth day of July One thousand six hundred fifty and nine have beene by any person or persons wrongfully
received or taken away, and for which the said wrong doers are not in any wise Indempnified by the said [A&bholigct;,<ref idref="n25">25</ref>]
or any other A&bholigct; of Repeale.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. A&bholigct; extended to Persons in respe&bholigct; of Goods, &amp;c. sequestrated and a&bholigct;ually paid into any public Treasury by virtue, &amp;c. of any Order of the late or present King or Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p39">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe person or persons who by vertue of any Order
or Warrant mediately or immediately derived from his late Majesty or his Majesty that now is, or by vertue of any
A&bholigct; Ordinance or Order of any or both Houses of Parliament, or any of the authorityes aforesaid, or any Committee
or Committees a&bholigct;ing under them or any of them have seised sequestred leavyed advanced or paid to any publique
use or into any publique Treasury within this Kingdome any Good&bholngs; Chattels Debts Rents summe or summes of
Money belonging to any person or persons whatsoever shall hereafter be sued molested or drawne into question for
the same, but that they and every of them shall be discharged against all persons for soe much and noe more of
the said Good&bholngs; Chattels Debts Rents summe or summes of money as their severall and respe&bholigct;ive orders of discharge
or acquittances extend unto</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Exception of Receivers of Money privately for his Majesty's Supply, since 1648.</head>
			<para id="p40">Provided alsoe That noe thing herein contained shall extend to discharge any person or persons who have
beene by private order or instru&bholigct;ions imployed and intrusted or have undertaken the imployment to receive any
summe or summes of money for the Kings Majestyes Service or Supply since the yeare one thousand six hundred
forty and eight from making their accompts for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Exception of Persons in respe&bholigct; of Monies received upon Tax of Decimation.</head>
			<para id="p41">Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; shall not extend to pardon or discharge from account to the Kings Majesty any
person or persons for any summe or summes of money received for that Illegall Tax of Decimation, or upon the
accompt of any Militia setled or a&bholigct;ed in, since One thousand six hundred forty and eight, and not accompted
for, or paid over or discharged to, or by any that had authority or pretended authority to discharge the respe&bholigct;ive
Receivers of the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Exception of Persons that have had Dire&bholigct;ions from His Majesty, and have traiterously held Intelligence with Foreign States, &amp;c. or otherwise.</head>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">Limitation of Proceedings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">Provided alsoe that if any person or persons being his Majestyes Mesniall Servant or Servants, or haveing or
pretending to have received perticular Instru&bholigct;ions or Dire&bholigct;ions from his Majesty have dureing the time of such
his or their relation [un<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] to his Majesty, or whilst he or they were a&bholigct;ing or pretending to a&bholigct; for His Majestyes
Interest, in pursuance of the said Instru&bholigct;ions or Dire&bholigct;ions wilfully malitiously and traiterously held Intelligence
with any forraigne Prince or Princes State or States or with any person [or &bhopubr;sons<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] usurping Supreame authority in
this Kingdome or other his Majestyes Dominions or with their or either of their Ministers or Agents and without
his Majestyes license and to the intent to betray his Majestyes person or Councells, or have received any summe
or summes of money or pention for such Treachery, that then such person and persons as to the offence in
this provisoe mentioned shall be and is hereby [accepted<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] out of this A&bholigct;, Any thing herein contained to the contrary
notwithstanding soe as such person or persons be outlawed or [otherwise<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] legally convi&bholigct;ed of such offence or
offences within the space of two yeares from the five and twentyeth day of Aprill one thousand six hundred
and sixty.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Exception of Duties of Excise since 25th March 1658, and of Debts due to Excise since 25th March 1657.</head>
			<para id="p44">Provided that this A&bholigct; of Generall Pardon or any thing therin contained shall not extend to the pardoning or
discharging of any Debts or Summes of money due to, or for the Excise of any Good&bholngs; or Merchandize wherof
any Entryes have beene made in the Custome house which have growne due since the twenty fifth day of March
one thousand six hundred fifty and eight, or to the pardoning or discharging of any Debts or Summes of money
due to the Farmers, or pretended Farmers of Excise since the twenty fifth day of March one thousand six hundred
fifty and seven,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. Persons excepted by Name who were concerned in the Murder of King Charles I.</head>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">and of the two Persons who appeared disguised upon the Scaffold</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p46">Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; nor any thing therin contained shall extend to pardon discharge or give any
other benefit whatsoever unto [John Lisle William Say Sir Hardresse Waller, Valentine Wauton Thomas Harrison
Edward Whalley William Heveningham Isaac Penington Henry Martin John [Barstead<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] Gilbert Millington Edmond
Ludlow Sir Michael Livesey Robert Tichborne Owen Row Robert Lilburne Adrian Scroop John Okey John
Hewson William Goffe Cornelius Holland Thomas Challoner John Carew John Jones Miles Corbet Henry Smith
Gregory Clement Thomas Wogan Edmond Harvey Thomas Scot William Cawley John Downes Nicholas Love
Vincent Potter Augustine Garland John Dixwell George Fleetwood Simon Meyne James Temple Peter Temple
Daniel Blagrave Thomas Wait John Cooke Andrew Broughton Edward Dendy William Hewlet Hugh Peters
Francis Hacker Daniel Axtell<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] nor any of them, nor to those two persons [nor<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] either of them who being disguised
by Frocks and [Vizard&bholngs;<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] did appeare upon the Scaffeld ere&bholigct;ed before Whitehall upon the thirtyeth of January
one thousand six hundred forty[and<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] eight, All which persons for their execrable Treason in sentencing to death,
or signing the Instrument for the horrid Murder, or being instrumentall in taking away the pretious Life of our
late Soveraigne Lord Charles the first of glorious memory are left to be proceeded against as Traitors to his
late Majesty according to the Lawes of England and are out of this present A&bholigct; wholly excepted and foreprized,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. The Execution of certain Persons that appeared and rendered themselves suspended.</head>
			<para id="p47">[But in regard the said Owen Row Augustine Garland Edmond Harvey Henry Smith Henry Martin Sir Hardresse
Waller Robert Tichborne George Fleetwood James Temple Thomas Wait Simon Meyne William Heveningham
Isaac Penington Peter Temple Robert Lilburne Gilbert Millington Vincent Potter Thomas Wogan and John
Downes have personally appeared and rendered themselves (according to the Proclamation bearing Date the sixth
day of June one thousand six hundred and sixty to Summon the persons therin named who gave Judgement
and assisted in the said horrid and detestable murther of our said late Soveraigne to appeare and render themselves)
and doe pretend thereby to some favour upon some conceived doubtfull words in the said Proclamation; Be it
Ena&bholigct;ed by this present Parliament and [the<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] Authority of the same (upon the humble desires of the Lord&bholngs; and
Commons in Parliament assembled) That if the said Owen Row Augustine Garland Edmond Harvey Henry
Smith Henry Martin Sir Hardresse Waller Robert Tichborn George Fleetwood James Temple Thomas Wait Simon
Main William Heveningham Isaac Penington Peter Temple Robert Lilburn, Gilbert Millington Vincent Potter
Thomas Wogan and John Downes or any of them shall be legally attainted for the horrid Treason and Murther
aforesaid, that then neverthelesse the Execution of the said person and persons soe attainted shall be suspended
untill his Majesty by the advice and assent of the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in Parliament shall order the Execution by
A&bholigct; of Parliament to be passed for that purpose,<ref idref="n29">29</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Exception of Oliver Cromwell, &amp;c. deceased.</head>
			<para id="p48">Except alsoe out of this present A&bholigct; Oliver Cromwel deceased Henry Ireton deceased John Bradshaw deceased
and Thomas Pride deceased,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. Exception of the Land&bholngs; and Good&bholngs; of certain deceased Persons.</head>
			<para id="p49">Provided That noe thing in this A&bholigct; contained shall extend to discharge the Lands Tenements Goods
Chattels Rights Trusts and other the Hereditaments late of the said Oliver Cromwell Henry Ireton John
Bradshaw and Thomas Pride, or of Isaac Ewer deceased Sir John Danvers deceased Sir Thomas Maleverer Baronet
deceased, William Purefoy deceased John Blakiston deceased, Sir William Constable Baronet deceased Richard Dean
deceased Francis Alleyn deceased Peregrine Pelham deceased John Moore deceased John Aldred &bhoalias; Alured deceased
Humphrey Edward&bholngs; deceased Sir Gregory Norton Baronet deceased John Venn deceased Thomas Andrewes Alderman
deceased Anthony Staply deceased Thomas Horton deceased John Fry deceased Thomas Hamond deceased Sir John
Bourchier deceased of and from such paines penaltyes and forfeitures as by one other A&bholigct; of Parliament intended
to be hereafter passed for that purpose shall be expressed and declared,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. Exception of certain Persons as to Penalties not extending to Life.</head>
			<para id="p50">And alsoe except out of this present A&bholigct; William Lord Mounson James Challoner Sir Henry Mildmay Sir James
Harrington John Phelps and Robert Wallop All which persons did a&bholigct; and sitt in that traiterous Assembly which
in the moneth of January one thousand six hundred forty (<ref idref="n34">34</ref>) eight a&bholigct;ed and proceeded against the life of our late
Soveraigne King Charles the first of blessed Memory and are therefore reserved to such paines penalties and
forfeitures not extending to Life as by another A&bholigct; intended to be passed for that purpose shall be imposed on them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. The like Exception as to Sir Arthur Hasilrig.</head>
			<para id="p51">And alsoe except Sir Arthur Hasilrig for and in respe&bholigct; onely of such paines penaltyes and forfeitures not
extending to Life as [by<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] one A&bholigct; intended to be hereafter passed for that purpose shall be infli&bholigct;ed and imposed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. Certain Persons made incapable of any Offices. Penalty on Francis Lassels of one Year's Rent.</head>
			<para id="p52">Provided alwayes that John Hutchinson Esquire and Francis Lassels shall be and are hereby made for ever
incapable to execute any Place or Office of Trust Civill or Military within this Kingdome, And that the said Francis
Lassels shall pay unto our Soveraigne Lord the King one full yeares value of his Estate, Any thing herein before
contained to the contrary notwithstanding;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Exception of Sir Henry Vane and John Lambert.</head>
			<para id="p53">[Provided alwayes that this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained shall not extend to the pardoning or to give
any other benefit whatsoever unto Sir Henry Vane John Lambert or either of them, but that they and either of
them are and shalbe out of this present A&bholigct; wholly excepted and foreprized.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. Certain Persons accepting any Office.; Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p54">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p55">Provided that if William Lenthall William Burton Oliver S<emph type="p">t</emph> John, John Ireton Alderman Collonell William
Sidenham Collonell John Desbrow John Blackwel of Moreclak Christopher Packe Alderman Richard Keeble Charles
Fleetwood John Pyne Richard Deane Major Richard Creed Philip Nye Clerke John Goodwin Clerke, Sir Gilbert
Pickering [Colloner<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] Thomas Lister and Collonel Ralph Cobbet shall after the first day of September One thousand
six hundred and sixty accept or exercise any Office Ecclesiastical Civil or Military or any other publique imployment
within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede that then such person
or persons as doe soe accept or execute as aforesaid shall to all intents and purposes in Law stand as if he or they
had beene totally excepted by name in this A&bholigct;.<ref idref="n29">29</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>XLIII. Exception of Persons that gave Sentence upon any in the illegal High Courts of Justice Exception.</head>
			<para id="p56">[Provided likewise That all those who since the fifth of December one thousand six hundred forty eight did
give sentence of death upon any person or persons in any of the late Illegall and Tyrannicall High Courts of
Justice in England or Wales, or signed the Warrant for Execution of any person there condemned (except Collonel
[Richard<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] Ingolsby and Collonel Mathew Thomlinson) shal be and are hereby made incapable of bearing any Office
Ecclesiasticall Civill or Military within the Kingdome of England or Dominion of Wales, or [as<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] serving as a Member
in any Parliament after the first day of September one thousand six hundred and sixty,<ref idref="n38">38</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>XLIV. Persons intrusted by Ordinance 1649 concerning Tithes accountable.</head>
			<para id="p57">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Ministers and others for whose Benefit the said Ordinance was made</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p58">Provided alsoe and it is Ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the persons appointed Trustees in a late [pretend<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] A&bholigct; or
Ordinance made in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred forty nine for &amp; concerning Tithes appropriate,
Oblations, Obventions Pensions, Portions of Tithes appropriate Offerings Fee farme Rents issueing out of the Tithes
therin mentioned, First fruites and other things and ena&bholigct;ed or mentioned to be ena&bholigct;ed to be vested setled
adjudged or deemed to be in the a&bholigct;uall seizin or possession of such person and persons in the said pretended A&bholigct;
or Ordinance mentioned and their heires shall accompt for and be responsable for all Rents and Profits of the
premisses which came to their hands and have not beene by the said Trustees or their order disbursed disposed or
imployed for the maintenance of Ministers or other uses according to the said pretended A&bholigct; or Ordinance or some
other A&bholigct;s, Order or Ordinance made in the yeares [of our Lord<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] one thousand six hundred &amp; fifty, one thousand
six hundred fifty fower and one thousand six hundred fifty six by any assembly called or reputed a Parliament, or
assuming the power of Parliament according to the intention of such A&bholigct; A&bholigct;s or Ordinances, and the Agents and
Receivers under the order of the said Trustees and the occupiers and tenants of the premisses [who have taken the
&bhopcrl;misses<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] or proffits therof into their hand&bholngs; without agreement to pay Rent therefore, and have made noe accompt
or satisfa&bholigct;ion to the Trustees aforesaid, or to some other by their order, and alsoe the persons who have held the
same or taken the proffits therof under any agreement to pay rent or money for the same and have not paid the
same shall respe&bholigct;ively accompt pay and make satisfa&bholigct;ion for soe much of the premisses and profits of the premisses
as are unsatisfied or unaccompted for as aforesaid, and pay such arrearages of rents or money as by such agrement
remaineth unpaid by them, all which payments and accounts shall be made to such persons and in such manner as
in Parliament shall be dire&bholigct;ed, Neverthelesse it is not hereby intended that any Minister Schoolemaster or other
person for whose benefit or maintenance the said pretended A&bholigct;s or Ordinances were made shall be accomptable
or lyeable to make satisfa&bholigct;ion for any proffits rents or summes of money paid to, or taken by them respe&bholigct;ively
by vertue or colour of any order or appointment of the said Trustees or any of them, or otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>XLV. Exception of Bonds in His Majesty's Name before May 1642 for Securities of Receivers.</head>
			<para id="p59">
				<emph type="i">Order of House of Commons of 26th May 1641.; Farmers of the Customs paid &pound; 150,000 at the Desire of the said House.; Exception of Payments upon Proportions of &pound; 150,000 upon the Customs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p60">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; doe not extend to, pardon any Bond taken in his late Majestyes Name before the
moneth of May one thousand six hundred forty two for secureing the proper Debt of any Servant or Receiver of
the Revenew of his said late Majesty that hath not [been<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] paid to, or by order of some lawful or pretended authority,
And whereas by an order of the Six and twentyeth day of May in the yeare One thousand six hundred forty (<ref idref="n40">40</ref>) one
the then House of Commons in Parliament did accept the summe of One hundred and fifty thousand pound&bholngs; as a
composition from the Farmers of severall Customes voted to be illegally taken, and some of the said Farmers did
procure and pay the said whole summe of One hundred and fifty thousand pound&bholngs; at the desire of the said House
of Commons, and upon their Declaration that such of the said Farmers as did not pay their proportions should not
be pardoned but proceeded gainst, and out of their Fines satisfa&bholigct;ion should be made to those who had paid the
said One hundred and fifty thousand pound&bholngs;, and in pursuance therof did on the first of June then next following
resolve That the Estates of such persons living or dead as have by colour of any Patent received moneyes from the
Subje&bholigct; under pretence of such Customes or have beene Undersharers with the Patentees ought to be made lyeable
to restitution, It is therefore provided That this A&bholigct; shall not extend or bee construed to extend to pardon or
indempnifie any person or persons their heires executors administrators or assignes who have not paid their
proportions of the said One hundred and fifty thousand pounds, or ought to(<ref idref="n41">41</ref>) beene contributory therunto from
or against misdemeanours or offences relating to the said Customes, or from payment of their proportions But
that the Estates of the dead as well as the (<ref idref="n42">42</ref>) liveing of such who ought to have beene contributory [in whose
possession soever<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] (Purchasers bona fide and upon valuable considerations onely excepted) shall continue and be
charged and chargeable with the payment of their proportions to all intents and purposes as if this A&bholigct; had not
beene made, Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>XLVI. Exception of Arrears of Excise upon Beer and Ale since 24 June 1659</head>
			<para id="p61">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained shall not extend or be construed to pardon or
discharge any summe or summes of money due, and arreare for Excise of Beere Ale or other Native or Inland
Commoditye since the [twenty fowerth<ref idref="n43">43</ref>] day of June One thousand six hundred fifty [and<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] nine.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>XLVII. Exception of Monies due for Quarter since 2d July 1659.</head>
			<para id="p62">Provided alsoe That noe thing in this A&bholigct; contained shall extend to the pardoning or discharging of any
s&bhouov;me or summes of money due from any Officers or Souldiers to any of the Subje&bholigct;s of this Kingdome for free
quarter since the second day of July One thousand six hundred fifty [and<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] nine, or to discharge any moneys borrowed
by any Officers for preventing of free quarter,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>XLVIII. Proviso for Purchasers bon&acirc;fide of Lands, other than of the King or Church, to enjoy their Purchases;</head>
			<para id="p63">
				<emph type="i">and for Statutes, &amp;c. suffered, &amp;c.before 29th Sept. 1659; and for Conveyances, &amp;c. before 25th April 1660 in Trust</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p64">Provided alwayes And be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe Conveyance Assurance Grant Bargaine
Sale Charge Lease Assignement of Lease Grants and Surrenders by Copy of Court roll Estate Interest Trust or
Limitation of any Use or Uses of any Mannours Land&bholngs; Tenements or Hereditaments not being the Lands nor
Hereditaments of the late King, Queene Prince or of any Archbishops Bishops Deanes, Deanes or Chapters, nor
being Land&bholngs; or Hereditaments sold or given or appointed to be sold or given for the delinquency or pretended
delinquency of any person or persons whatsoever by vertue or pretext of any A&bholigct; order or ordinance, or reputed
A&bholigct; order or ordinance since the first day of January One thousand six hundred forty and one, Nor any Statute
Judgement or Recognizance had made acknowledged or suffered to any person or persons bodyes politique or corporate
before the nine and twentyeth day of September One thousand six hundred fifty and nine by any of the persons
before in this A&bholigct; by name excepted or their Heires, or by any other person or persons clayming by from or under
them or any of them other then the wife or wives child children heire and heires of such person and persons or
any of them for money bona fide to them or any of them, paid or lent, nor any conveyance assurance grant or
estate made before the five and twentyeth day of April One thousand six hundred and sixty by any person or
persons to any such person or persons excepted by Name as aforesaid, in trust and for the benefit of any other person or
persons Bodyes Politique or Corporate not excepted by name as aforesaid shall be impeached defeated made void or
frustrated hereby, or by the attainder or convi&bholigct;ion of any such excepted Person or persons but that the same shall
be held and enjoyed by the Purchasers Grantees Lessees Assignees Cestuy que use Cestuy que trust and every of
them their Heires Executors Administrators and Assignes respe&bholigct;ively as if this A&bholigct; had not beene made, and as if
the said person or persons had not beene excepted attainted or convi&bholigct;ed Any Law Statute Usage or Custome to
the contrary therof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>XLIX. Exception of Sacrilege, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p65">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall not extend to Indempnifie any person or
persons whatsoever who have entred into any Messuages Lands Tenements or Hereditaments called Fabrick Lands
or possest themselves of any Rent or Revenues given for the repaire of any Cathedrall or other Church, or who
have Sacreligiously enriched themselves by converting the Plate [and<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] Utensills and Materialls of or belonging
to such Churches to their owne private use and advantage for or in respe&bholigct; of the said Crimes onely.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">fower and twentieth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">ac&bhocotil;n <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Successor and Successors <emph type="i">O</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Fower and twentieth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Five and twentieth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Fower and twentieth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Marriage <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Revenew <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">against <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">be likewise <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">wherein <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">excepted <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">Barkstead <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">Vizors <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">Colonel <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39">&bhopcrl;tended <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41">have <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n42" number="42">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n43" number="43">fower and twentieth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n44" number="44">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n45" number="45">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


