<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47269" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXI. An Act for the speedy raising of Seaventy thousand pound&bholngs; for the present Supply of his Majestye. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p. 2. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Ordinance for an Assessment of &pound;70,000 recited</head>
		<para id="p1"><emph type="i">c. 2. ante recited; &pound;70,000 for One Month from 29th Sept. 1660 assessed under the same Commissioners (Exception) and by the same Rules, &amp;c. as by the said Ordinance; Commissioners to meet 5th Oct. 1660, and execute Authorities accordingly</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas in the absence of his Majestye an Ordinance of both Houses of Parliament was made entituled
An Ordinance of the Lords and Commons for an Assesment of seaventy thousand pound&bholngs; by the moneth
upon England for three moneths for the supply of the present occasions of the Kings Majesty and for and toward&bholngs;
the satisfa&bholigct;ion of the Armies and Navies to be continued for the defence of this kingdome, and for other the
urgent and necessary occasions therof, which said assesment was to continue for three moneths to be accompted
from the twenty fourth of June One thousand six hundred and sixty. And whereas it was afterward&bholngs; ena&bholigct;ed by
this present Parliament that all and every of the clauses powers and provisoes in the said Ordinance mentioned
should be put in [full<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] execution, We your Majestyes loyall and obedient Subje&bholigct;s the Commons in Parliament
assembled takeing notice of your Majestyes urgent occasions whilst your Majestyes Revenue stand&bholngs; unsetled, and
your just rights and prerogatives in point of tenures and the use of the Court of Ward&bholngs; are forborne and withall
acknowledging your Majesties great goodnes to us your subje&bholigct;s in the many gratious A&bholigct;s passed and other the
Messages received this present Parliament Doe pray your Most Excellent Majestye to accept this our present
grant of seaventy thousand pound&bholngs; to be raised and leavyed in the manner following, And that it may be ena&bholigct;ed
And be it ena&bholigct;ed by your most excellent Majestye by and with the advice and consent of the Lord&bholngs; and Commons
in Parliament assembled that the summe of threescore and ten thousand pound&bholngs; for one moneth onely begining
from the twenty nineth of September One thousand six hundred and sixty shall be assessed taxed colle&bholigct;ed leavyed
and paid in the severall Countyes Cittyes Burroughs Townes and places within England and Wales and towne of
Berwicke upon Tweede according to the severall rates rules and proportions and in such manner and forme and
by the same Commissioners (other then such as are disabled by the A&bholigct; of generall pardon indempnity and oblivion)
as in and by the same recited Ordinance are sett downe nominated limited and appointed Which Commissioners
shall meete on or before the fifth day of O&bholigct;ober One thousand six hundred and sixty, and are hereby enabled
to use and execute all and every the powers and authorityes as in and by the said Ordinance and A&bholigct; are
mentioned and expressed as fully and amply as if the same rates rules proportions powers and authorityes had
beene [&bhopubr;ticulerly<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] inserted in this present A&bholigct;.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The Monies to be paid into the Exchequer 1st Nov. 1660 by Receivers General.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to sign and seal Duplicate of Assessments, and certify into the Exchequer with the Names of Receivers General</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that all and every the summes of money charged by this
A&bholngs; upon the severall Countyes Cittyes Townes Burroughs and places aforesaid shall be leavyed and raised and
paid into his Majestyes receipt of the Exchequer upon or before the first day of November One thousand six
hundred and sixty by the severall Receivers Generall that shall be appointed by the said Commissioners, and the
said Commissioners or any two or more of them in their respe&bholngs;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughs Townes and
Places within England and Wales and the towne of Berwicke upon Tweede are hereby ordered [&amp; required<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to
signe and seale a duplicate of the said assesments and the same before the same first of November to certifie into
his Majestyes Court of Exchequer at Westminster together with the names of the respe&bholigct;ive Receivers Generall
who shall be appointed to receive the same.</para>
			<para id="p5">ITEM quedam peti&bhocotil;es privatas &bhopubr;sonas concernentes in se formam Actus continentes exhibita fuerunt &bhopcrl;dco D&ntilde;o
Regi in Parl[ia] &bhopubr;dct qua[rum] tituli subsequuntur viz</para>
			<para id="p6">PRIVATE ACTS</para>
			<para id="p7">1. An Act for naturalizing Peter De la Pierre &bhoalias; Peters and John De la Pierre alias Peters.</para>
			<para id="p8">2. An Act for the necessary maintenance of the Worke of draining the Great Level of the Fenns.</para>
			<para id="p9">3. An Act for restoreing unto Morough alias Morgan Earle of Inchequin all his Honours Mannours Land&bholngs;
and Tenements in Ireland whereof he was in possession [on<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the three and twentyeth of O&bholigct;ober One thousand
six hundred forty one, or at any time since.</para>
			<para id="p10">4. An Act for restoreing unto William Marquesse of Newcastle all his Honours Mannours Land&bholngs; and Tenements
in England whereof he was in possession on the twentyeth day of May One thousand six hundred forty two or
at any time since.</para>
			<para id="p11">5. An Act for the setling of the Priory of Watton and other Lands belonging to the Earle of Winchelsey
in the County of Yorke in the hand&bholngs; of Trustees for the payment of debts.</para>
			<para id="p12">6. An Act for restoreing of Sir George Lane Knight to the possession of the Manours of Rathclive and
Lisduff and other Land&bholngs; in Ireland.</para>
			<para id="p13">7. An Act for the regulating of the trade of Bay makeing in the Dutchy Bay Hall in Colchester. (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>)</para>
			<para id="p14">8. An Act for restoreing to Charles Lord Gerrard Baron of Brandon, all his Honours Mannours Land&bholngs; Tenements
and Heredi taments whereof he was in possession on the twentyeth day of May One thousand six hundred forty
two or at any time sithence.</para>
			<para id="p15">9. An Act for restoring of John Lord Culpeper sonne and heirc and sole executor to Thomas Lord Culpeper
Baron of Thorsway and Master of the Rolls, deceased, All the Honours Mannours Land&bholngs; and Tenements Leases
not determined and Hereditaments whatsoever whereof the said John Lord Culpeper was in possession on the
twentyeth day of May One thousand six hundred forty two, or at any time after, which have not beene since
sold, or aliened by the said John late Lord Culpeper by A&bholigct;s or Assurances to which himselfe was party and
consenting.</para>
			<para id="p16">10. An Act for restoring of the Marquesse of Hertford to the Dukedome of Somerset.</para>
			<para id="p17">11. An Act for enabling Augustine Skinner and William Skinner to make sale of some Land&bholngs; for payment
of debts.</para>
			<para id="p18">12. An Act for the incorporating of the Master and Wardens of the Company of Haberdashers London to
be Governors of the Free schoole and Alms Houses in Newport in the County of Salop, of the foundation of
William Adams, and for setling of Land&bholngs; and Possessions on them for maintenance thereof and other charitable uses.</para>
			<para id="p19">13. An Act for the naturalizing of Dorothea Helena Countesse of Derby Wife of the Right Honourable
Charles Earle of Derby, and Emilia called Countesse of Ossory, wife of the Right Honourable Thomas Butler called
Earle of Ossory sonne and heire apparent of the Right Honourable James Marquesse of Ormond and Earle of
Brecknocke, and Margaret Lady Culpeper Wife of the Right Honourable Thomas Lord Culpeper Baron of Thorsway,
and the Right Honourable Charles Kirkhoven Lord Wotton and Dame Emilia his sister, children of Katherine
Stanhop Countesse of Chesterfeild by John Kirkhoven Lord of Hemflett.</para>
			<para id="p20">14. An Act for enabling Sir George Booth Baronet to make Leases and Sales of part of his Estate.</para>
			<para id="p21">15. An Act for restoreing unto James Marquesse of Ormond all his Honours Mannours Land&bholngs; and Tenements
in Ireland whereof he was in possession on the 23<emph type="p">th</emph> of O&bholigct;ober 1641 or at any time since.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2 " number="2">This Act received the Royal Assent in the Form of a Private Act, viz<emph type="p">t</emph> "Soit fait come il est desire;" and is in the bundle
of Private Acts at the Parliament Office; but as it is inrolled on the Third Part of the Rolls of this Year, <emph type="i">nu</emph>. 1. and is printed
as Chapter XXII. in former editions, it is printed in this Collection in its usual place.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


