<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47262" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIV. An Act for a Perpetuall Anniversary Thanksgiveing on the nine and twentyeth day of May.[Rot.Parl.12 C.II.p. 2. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">His Majesty's Restoration on His Birth-day.; The 29th May to be annually celebrated</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">FORASMUCH as Almighty God the King of Kings and sole Disposer of all Earthly Crownes and Kingdomes
hath by his Alswaying Providence and Power miraculously demonstrated in the view of all the World his
transcendent Mercy Love and Gratiousnes toward&bholngs; His most Excellent Majesty Charles the Second by his especiall
Grace of England Scotland France and Ireland King Defender of the true Faith and all his Majestyes Loyall Subje&bholigct;s
of this his Kingdome of England and the Dominions therunto annexed by his Majestyes late most wonderfull glorious
peaceable and joyfull Restauration to the a&bholigct;uall possession and exercise of his undoubted hereditary Soveraigne
and Regall Authority over them, (after sundry yeares forced extermination into Forraigne parts by the most
Traiterous Conspiricies and armed power of usurping Tirants and execrable perfidious Traiters, and that without
the least opposition or effusion of blood through the unanimous cordiall loyall Votes of the Lord&bholngs; and Commons
in this present Parliament assembled and passionate desires of all other his Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s, which unexpressible
blessing (by God&bholngs; owne most wonderfull dispensation) was compleated on the twenty nineth day of May last past,
being the most memorable Birth day not onely of his Majesty both as a man and Prince but likewise as an a&bholigct;uall
King, and of this and other His Majesties Kingdomes all in a great measure new borne and raised from the
dead on this most joyfull day wherin many thousand&bholngs; of(<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Nobility [Citizens Gentry<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and other his Lieges of this
Realme condu&bholigct;ed His Majesty unto His Royall Cittyes of London and Westminster with all possible expressions
of their publique Joy and Loyall Affe&bholigct;ions in farr greater triumph then any of His [most<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Vi&bholigct;orious Predecessors
Kings of England returned thither from their Forraigne Conquests, and both His Majestyes Houses of Parliament
with all Dutyfull and Joyfull Demonstrations of their Allegiance publiquely received, and cordially congratulated
His Majestyes [most happy<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Arrivall and Investiture in His Royall Throne at His Pallace of Whitehall., Upon all
which considerations, this being the day which the Lord himselfe hath made and crowned with soe many publique
Blessings and signall Deliverances both of His Majestie and His People from all their late most deplorable Confusions
Divisions Warrs Devastations and Oppressions To the end that it may be kepte in perpetuall Remembrance in all
Ages to come, and that his Sacred Majesty(<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) with all His Subje&bholigct;s of this Realme and the Dominions thereof and
their Posterities after them might annually celebrate the perpetual memory therof by sacrificeing their unfaigned
hearty publique Thanks theron to Almighty God with one heart and voice in a most devout and Christian manner.
for all these publique benefits received and conferred on them upon this most joyfull day, Bee it therefore Ena&bholigct;ed
by the Kings most Excellent Majesty the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the
Authority of the same That all and singular Ministers of God&bholngs; Word and Sacraments in every Church Chappell
and other usuall place of divine service and publique prayer which now are or hereafter shall be within this Realme
of England and the respe&bholigct;ive Dominions therof and their Successors shall in all succeeding Ages annually celebrate
the twenty ninth day of May by rendering their hearty publique Praises and Thanksgivings unto Almighty God for
all the forementioned Extraordinary [Merces<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Blessings and Deliverances received, and mighty A&bholigct;s done thereon and
declare the same to all the People there [assemlled<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] and the Generations yet to come that soe they may for ever
praise the Lord for the same, whose Name alone is Excellent, and his Glory above the Earth and heavens,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. All Persons to resort to some public Place of Thanksgiving on that Day.</head>
			<para id="p3">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed That all and every person and persons inhabiting within this Kingdome and the
Dominions therunto belonging shall upon the said day annually resort with diligence and devotion to some usuall
Church Chappell or place where such publique thanksgivings and praises to God&bholngs; most Divine Majesty shall be
rendered, and there orderly and devoutly abide dureing the said publique Thanksgiveings Prayers Preaching Singing
of Psalmes and other service of God there to be used and ministered.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Notice of this A&bholigct; to be given the Lord's Day next before 29th May.</head>
			<para id="p4">And to the end that all persons may be put in minde of their duty theron, and be the better prepared to
discharge the same with that piety and devotion as becomes them Bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed That every Minister shall
give Notice to his Parishioners publiquely in the Church at morning prayer the Lord&bholngs; day next before every such
twenty ninth day of May for the due observation of the said day, And shall then likewise publiquely and distin&bholigct;ly
reade this present A&bholigct; to the people.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Gentry Citizens <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">will <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Mercies <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">assembled <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


