<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47264" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVI. An Act for inabling the Souldiers of the Army now to be disbanded to exercise Trades. [Rot. Parl. 12. C.II.p. 2.nu. II.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that there are divers Officers and Soldiers instrumental in His Majesties Restoration who used Trades</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">but who may be hindered by Bye Laws, &amp;c. and by 5 Eliz. c. 4.; Soldiers under General Monk 25th April 1660, &amp;c. may exercise Trades though not served their time as Apprentices, &amp;c.; Those who have been Apprentice to enjoy all Immunities as if they had served their Time.; And in case of A&bholigct;ion brought may plead the General Issue.; Double Costs.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS there are diverse Officers and Souldiers now in the Kings Majestyes Service under the Command
of his Excellency George Duke of Albemarle Captaine Generall of His Majestyes Armies who have beene
instrumentall by the blessing of Almighty God to the Happy Restitution and Restoration of his Sacred Majestye
unto His Kingdomes and People, and to His Just Right of Government in the Kingdome of England and the
Dominions and Territories thereunto belonging, Some of which are men that used Trades, others that were [Apprintices<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
to Trades who had not served out their times, and others who are apt and fitt for Trades, many of which the
Warrs being now ended would willingly imploy themselves in those Trades they were formerly accustomed unto,
or which they are apt and able to follow and make use of for the getting of their Liveing by their Labour and
Industry, but are or may be hindred from exerciseing those Trades in certaine Cittyes Corporations and other places
within this Kingdome, because of certaine By Lawes and Customes of those places, and of a Statute made in the
fifth yeare of the late Queene Elizabeth prohibiting the use of certaine Trades by any person that hath not served
as an [Apprintice<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to such Trades by the space of seaven yeares, For remedy wherof And to the end that those
persons who were in a&bholigct;uall Service under the c&bhooov;mand of the said Captaine Generall on the five and twentyeth
day of April in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and sixty and were instrumentall to the happy
restitution of the Kings Majesty unto his just right of Government as aforesaid, may not be deprived of a meanes
of livelyhood May it please your Majestye that it may be Ena&bholigct;ed And be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majestye and the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority therof That all
such Officers and Souldiers who were under the command of the said Captaine Generall on the said five and
twentyeth day of April in the said yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and sixty and have not since
deserted the Service, or refused to take the severall Oathes of Supremacy and Allegience unto the Kings Majestye
that now is, His Heires and Successors, and that have heretofore used or exercised any Trade before that time,
or that were [Apprintices<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to any Trade though they did not serve out the time of their [Apprintiship,<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] or any other
person imployed as aforesaid under the command of the said Captaine Generall at the time aforesaid that is apt
and able to pra&bholigct;ise any Trade may sett up and exercise such severall and respe&bholigct;ive Trades Misteries or Occupations
wherunto he or they have beene bound [Apprintise<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and served any part of his or their time or any Handycraft or
other Trade exercised about Manufa&bholigct;ures though he was never bound [Apprintise<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to the same in manner following
(that is to say Such of them as have beene [Apprintices<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] as aforesaid may sett up and exercise such severall and
respe&bholigct;ive Trades wherunto he or they have beene soe bound [Apprintices<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] as fully as if they had served out their
respe&bholigct;ive termes or times for which they have beene bound, and shall have and enjoy the same Immunityes as
they should have had and enjoyed if they had served out their said termes or times. And all others of the said
Officers and Souldiers may sett up and exercise such Trades [as<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] they are apt and able for in the severall Townes and
Places within the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes wherein they were borne without any suite lett or molestation
of any Person or Persons whatsoever for or by reason of the useing of such Trade. And if any such Officer or
Officers Souldier or Souldiers shall be sued impleaded or indi&bholigct;ed in any Court whatsoever within this Kingdome
for useing or exercising any such Trades as aforesaid, then the said Officer or Officers Souldier or Souldiers
makeing it appeare to the same Court where they are soe sued impleaded or indi&bholigct;ed that they have served the
Kings Majestye under the command of the said Captaine Generall as aforesaid, and that they have severally taken
the said Oathes of Supremacy and Allegiance and have not since deserted the said Service shall upon the Generall
Issue pleaded be found not guilty in any Plaint Bill Information or Indi&bholigct;ment exhibited against them and such
Persons who notwithstanding this A&bholigct; shall prosecute their said Suite by Bill Plaint Information or Indi&bholigct;sment, and
shall have a Verdi&bholigct; passe against them or become Non suite therein, or discontinue their said Suite such Person or
Persons shall pay unto such Officer or Officers Souldier or Souldiers double costs of Suite to be recovered as any
other costs at common Law may be recovered. And all Judges and Jurors before whom any such Suite Information
or Indi&bholigct;ment shall be brought, and all other persons whatsoever are to take notice of this present A&bholigct; and shall
conforme themselves thereunto, Any Statute Law Ordinance Custome or Provision to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. How an Officer or Soldier may prove his being in Service within this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided that noe Officer or Soldier shall have the benefit of this A&bholigct; that shall not prove his Service as aforesaid
either by a Certificate under the Hand and Seale of some Feild Officer and two Commission Officers of the Regiment
wherein he served, or some Generall Officer of the Army certifyeing his knowledge of the Service aforesaid, and
the said Certificate to be proved by one Witnesse at least to be a true Certificate, or for default of such Certificate
by the Oathes of two credible persons at least.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Producing false Certificates.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Imprisonment, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p5">Provided alsoe that if any person or persons pretending themselves to have been Officers or Soldiers within the
qualifications aforesaid shall produce a false Certificate to the intent to have the benefit of this A&bholigct;, and therof
be convi&bholigct;ed by confession of due proofe of Law shall suffer Imprisonment not exceeding six months, and to lose
the benefit of this A&bholigct;. Any thing therein contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV.Officers and Soldiers and other Tradesmen to bear Offices, &amp;c. in Corporations, and submit to Orders of Companies.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alsoe and be it ena&bholigct;ed that the said Officers and Soldiers in this A&bholigct; mentioned and all other persons
exercising or that shall exercise any Trade or Profession in any City or Corporation shall be lyeable to beare all
Offices in the said respe&bholigct;ive Cittyes and Corporations, when by the said Cittyes and Corporations they shall be
ele&bholigct;ed thereunto, and shall submit to such Orders of Corporations and Companyes for search of the well and true
makeing of their Manufa&bholigct;ure, as others free of the said Companies or Corporations are subje&bholigct; unto, Any Law
Usage or Custome to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Apprentices <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Apprentice <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Apprenticeship <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


