<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47266" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVIII. An Act for the Encourageing and increasing of Shipping and Navigation. [Rot. Parl. 12 C.II.p. 2. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">No Goods shall be imported to or exported from Asia, Africa, or America, but in English Ships, and Master and Three-fourths of Mariners English.; Penalty.; Admirals, &amp;c. empowered to seize and bring in as Prize all Ships offending.; Proceedings in case of Condemnation</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">FOR the increase of Shiping and incouragement of the Navigation of this Nation, wherin under the good
providence and prote&bholigct;ion of God the Wealth Safety and Strength of this Kingdome is soe much concerned
Bee it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty and by the Lord&bholngs; and C&bhooov;mons in this present Parliament,
assembled and the Authoritie therof That from and after the First day of December One thousand six hundred
and sixty and from thence forward noe Good&bholngs; or Commodities whatsoever shall be Imported into or Exported
out of any Land&bholngs; Islelands Plantations or Territories to his Majesty belonging or in his possession or which may
hereafter belong unto or be in the possession of His Majesty His Heires and Successors in Asia Africa or America
in any other Ship or Ships Vessell or Vessells whatsoever but in such Ships or Vessells as doe truely and without
fraude belong onely to the people of England or Ireland Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede,
or are of the built of, and belonging to any of the said Land&bholngs; Island&bholngs; Plantations or Territories as the Proprietors
and right Owners therof and wherof the Master and three fourthes of the Marriners at least are English under
the penalty of the Forfeiture and Losse of all the Good&bholngs; and Commodityes which shall be Imported into, or
Exported out of, any the aforesaid places in any other Ship or Vessell, as alsoe of the Ship or Vessell with all
its Guns Furniture Tackle Ammunition and Apparell, one third part thereof to his Majesty his Heires and
Successors, one third part to the Governour of such Land Plantation Island or Territory where such default shall
be commited in case the said Ship or Good&bholngs; be there seised, or otherwise that third part alsoe to his Majesty
his Heires and Successors, and the other third part to him or them who shall Seize Informe or sue for the
same in any Court of Record by Bill Information Plaint or other A&bholigct;ion wherin noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager
of Law shall be allowed, And all Admiralls and other Commanders at Sea of any the Ships of War or other
Ship haveing C&bhooov;mission from His Majesty or from his Heires or Successors are hereby authorized and stri&bholigct;ly
required to seize and bring in as prize all such Ships or Vessells as shall have offended contrary hereunto and
deliver them to the Court of Admiralty there to be proceeded against and in case of condemnation one moyety of
such Forfeitures shall be to the use of such Admiralls or Commanders and their Companies to be divided and
proportioned amongst them according to the Rules and Orders of the Sea in [cases<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of Ships taken prize, and
the other moyety to the use of his Majesty his Heires and Successors.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Aliens exercising the Occupation of Merchants or Fa&bholigct;ors in Plantations. Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Governors of Plantations to take Oath to perform the aforementioned Clauses.; Negle&bholigct;ing so to do, removed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it Ena&bholigct;ed that noe Alien or person not borne within the Allegiance of Our Soveraigne Lord the King
his Heires and Successors or Naturalized or made a free Denizen shall from and after the First day of February
which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty one exercise the Trade or Occupation
of a Merchant or Fa&bholigct;or in any the said places upon paine of the forfeiture and losse of all his Good&bholngs; and
Chattels, or which are in his possession, one third to his Majesty his Heires and Successors, one third to the
Governour of the Plantation where such person shall soe offend, and the other third to him or them that shall
informe or sue for the same in any of his Majestyes Courts in the Plantation where such offence shall be
committed, And all Governours of the said Land&bholngs; Island&bholngs; Plantations or Territories and every of them are hereby
stri&bholigct;ly required and commanded and all who hereafter shall be made Governours of any such Island&bholngs; Plantations
or Territories by his Majesty his Heires or Successors shall before their entrance into their Government take a
solemne Oath to doe their utmost that every the aforementioned clauses and all the matters and things therin
contained be pun&bholigct;ually and bona fide observed according to the true intent and meaning therof. And upon
complaint and proofe made before his Majesty his Heires or Successors, or such as shall be by him or them
therunto authorized and appointed that any the said Governours have beene willingly and wittingly negligent in doeing
their Duty accordingly, that the said Governour soe offending shall be removed from his Government.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Goods of Africa, Asia, or America not to be imported but in English Ships, and manned as aforesaid.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And it is further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that noe Good&bholngs; or Commodityes whatsoever of the growth
produ&bholigct;ion or manufa&bholigct;ure of Africa Asia or America or of any part therof, or which are discribed or laid downe
in the usuall Maps or Card&bholngs; of those places be Imported into England Ireland or Wales Island&bholngs; of Guernsey or
Jersey or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede in any other Ship or Ships Vessell or Vessels whatsoever, but in such
as doe truely and without fraude belong onely to the people of England or Ireland, Dominion of Wales or Towne
of Berwicke upon Tweede or of the Land&bholngs; Island&bholngs; Plantations or Territories in Asia Africa or America to his
Majesty belonging as the proprietors and right owners therof, and wherof the Master and three fourthes at least
of the Mariners are English under the penalty of the forfeiture of all such Good&bholngs; and Commodityes, and of the
Ship or Vessell in which they were Imported with all her Guns Tackle Furniture Ammunition and Apparell, one
moyety to his Majesty his Heires and Successors, and the other moyety to him or them whoe shall Seize Informe
or Sue for the same in any Court of Record by Bill Information Plaint or other A&bholigct;ion wherin noe Essoigne
Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager in Law shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Goods of foreign Growth or Manufa&bholigct;ure to be imported only from the Places of their said Growth, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">or from those Ports where they have been usually first shipped.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And it is further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that noe Good&bholngs; or Commodityes that are of forraigne
growth produ&bholigct;ion or manufa&bholigct;ure and which are to be brought into England Ireland, Wales, the Island&bholngs; of
Guernsey &amp; Jersey or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede in English built shiping, or other shiping belonging to
some of the aforesaid places, and navigated by English Mariners as abovesaid, shall be shiped or brought from
any other place or Places, Country or Countries but onely from those of their said Growth Produ&bholigct;ion or Manufa&bholigct;ure,
or from those Ports where the said Good&bholngs; and Commodityes can onely or are or usually have beene first shiped
for transportation and from none other Places or Countryes under the penalty of the forfeiture of all such of the
aforesaid Good&bholngs; as shall be Imported from any other place or Country contrary to the true intent and meaning
hereof, as alsoe of the ship in which they were imported with all her Guns Furniture Ammunition Tackle and
Apparel, one Moyety to His Majesty His Heires and Successors and the other Moyety to him or them that shall
seize informe or sue for the same in any Court of Record to be recovered as is before exprest,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. All Ling, Stock Fish, &amp;c. Oil, &amp;c. Whalefins, &amp;c. imported, not caught in Vessels of the Proprietors themselves, &amp;c. shall pay double Aliens Custom.</head>
			<para id="p9">And it is further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That any sort of Ling Stockefish Pilchard, or any other
kinde of dryed or salted fish usually fished for and caught by the people of England Ireland Wales or Towne of
Berwicke upon Tweede, or any sort of Codfish or Herring, or any Oyle or Blubber made or that shall be made
of any kinde of Fish whatsoever, or any Whale fines or Whale bones which shall be imported into England
Ireland Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede not haveing beene caught in Vessels truely and properly
belonging therunto as Proprietors and right Owners therof and the said Fish cured saved or dryed, and the Oyle
and Blubber aforesaid (which shall be accompted and pay as oyle) not made by the people thereof, and shall be
imported into England Ireland or Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede shall pay double Aliens custome.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. No Goods to be carried from one Port of England to another in the Vessel of any Alien.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Exception.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That from henceforth it shall not be lawfull to any person
or persons whatsoever to Load or cause to be Loaden and carryed in any Bottome or Bottomes Ship or Ships Vessell
or Vessels whatsoever wherof any Stranger or Strangers borne (unlesse such as [shall<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] bee Denizens or Naturalized)
be Owners part Owners or Master and wherof three Fourthes of the Mariners at least shall not be English any
Fish Vi&bholigct;uall Wares Good&bholngs; Commodityes or [Good&bholngs;<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] of what kinde or Nature soever the same shall be from one
Port or Creeke of England Ireland Wales Island&bholngs; of Guernsey or Jersey or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede to
another Port or Creeke of the same or of any of them under penalty for every one that shall offend contrary to
the true meaning of this branch of this present A&bholigct; to forfeit all such good&bholngs; as shall be loaden and carryed in any
such Ship or Vessell together with the Ship or Vessell and all her Guns Ammunition Tackle Furniture and Apparel,
one moyety to His Majesty His Heires and Successors and the other moyety to him or them that shall Informe
Seize or Sue for the same in any Court of Record to be recovered in manner aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Abatement, &amp;c. in the Book of Rates allowed only where the Master and Three Fourths of the Mariners be English.</head>
			<para id="p12">And it is further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That where any Ease Abatement or Priviledge is given in
the Booke of Rates to good&bholngs; or Commodityes imported or exported in English built Shiping that is to say shiping
built in England Ireland Wales Island&bholngs; of Guernsey or Jersey or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede, or in any
the Land&bholngs; Island&bholngs; Dominions or Territories to His Majesty in Africa Asia or America belonging or in his possession,
That [it<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] is alwayes to be understood and provided that the Master and three fourthes of the Mariners, of the said
Ships at least be alsoe English, And that where it is required that the Master and three Fourths, of the Mariners
be English that the true intent and meaning therof is that they should be such dureing the whole Voyage unlesse
in case of Sicknesse Death or being taken Prisoners in the Voyage to be proved by the Oath of the Master or
other cheife Officer of such Ships.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Goods of the Growth or Manufa&bholigct;ure of Muscovy or Russia, and of the Turkish Empire, and other Goods herein mentioned, to be imported in English Ships, and manned as aforesaid.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Exception.; Penalty</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p14">And it is further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe Good&bholngs; or Commodityes of the Growth
Produ&bholigct;ion or Manufa&bholigct;ure of Muscovy or of any the Countryes Dominions or Territories to the Great Duke or
Emporer of Muscovia or Russia belonging, As alsoe that noe sorts of Masts Timber or board&bholngs; noe forraigne Salt
Pitch Tar Rozin Hempe or Flax Raizins Figs Prunes Olive Oyles noe [sort<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] of Corne or Graine Sugar Pot-ashes
Wines Vinegar or Spirits called Aqua-vite or Brandy Wine shall from and after the First day of Aprill which
shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty one be imported into England Ireland Wales or
Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede in any Ship or Ships Vessel or Vessels whatsoever but in such as doe truely and
without fraude belong to the people therof or of some of them as the true Owners and proprietors therof, and
wherof the Master and Three Fourths of the Mariners at least are English, and that noe Currants, nor
Commodityes of the growth produ&bholigct;ion or Manufa&bholigct;ure of any the Countryes Island&bholngs; Dominions or Territories
to the Othoman or Turkish Empire belonging shall from and after the first day of September which shall be in
the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty one be imported into any the forementioned places in any
Ship or Vessel, but which is of English built and navigated as aforesaid and in noe other, except onely such
forraigne ships and vessels as are of the built of that Country or place of which the said Good&bholngs; are the growth
produ&bholigct;ion or Manufa&bholigct;ure respe&bholigct;ively, or of such Port where the said Good&bholngs; can onely be or most usually are first
shiped for transportation, and wherof the Master and three Fourths of the Mariners at least are of the said
Country [and<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] place under the penalty and forfeiture of Ship and Good&bholngs; to be disposed and recovered as in
the foregoeing Clause.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. What Goods deemed Aliens' Goods, and pay Aliens' Duties.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That for the prevention of the great
fraud&bholngs; dayly used in colouring and concealing of Aliens Good&bholngs; all Wines of the growth of France or Germany
which [from &amp;<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] after the twentyeth day of O&bholigct;ober One thousand six hundred sixty shall be Imported into any the
Ports or places aforesaid in any other Ship or Vessel then which doth truely and without fraude belong to England
Ireland Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede and navigated with the Marriners therof as aforesaid shall be
deemed Aliens good&bholngs; and pay all Strangers Customes and dutyes to His Majestye His Heires and Successors, as alsoe
to the Towne or Port into which they shall be imported, And that all sorts of Masts Timber or Board&bholngs;, as alsoe
all forraine Salt Pitch Tar Rozin Hempe Flax Raizins Figs Prunes Olive Oyles all sorts of Corne or Grane, Sugar
Pot-ashes Spirits commonly called Brandy Wine or Aqua vite Wines of the growth of Spaine the Island&bholngs; of the
Canaries or Portugall Madera or Westerne Island&bholngs; and all good&bholngs; of the growth Produ&bholigct;ion or Manufa&bholigct;ure of
Muscovia or Russia which from and after the first day of April which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred sixty one shall be imported into any of the aforesaid places in any other then such shiping,
and soe navigated and all Currants and Turky Commodityes which from and after the first day of September One
thousand six hundred sixty one shall be Imported into any the places aforesaid in any other then English built
shiping and Navigated as aforesaid shall be deemed Aliens Good&bholngs; and pay accordingly to his Majesty his Heires and
Successors and to the Towne or Port into which they shall be imported.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. In what Case and by what Means Foreign-built Ships shall be deemed English Ships.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Oath of Purchase of such Ship for a valuable Consideration, and other Particulars.; On Oath taken, Certificate under Hand and Seal of Officer.; Officer to keep Register of Certificates, and return Duplicates to Customs in London</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And for prevention of all Fraud&bholngs; which may be used in colouring or buying of Forraine Ships Be it Ena&bholigct;ed
by the Authority aforesaid And it is hereby Ena&bholigct;ed That from and after the first day of April which shal be in the
yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty one noe Foraine built ship or Vessell whatsoever shall be deemed
or passe as a ship to England Ireland Wales or Towne of Berwicke or any of them belonging or enjoy the benefit
or priviledge of such a Ship or Vessel, until such time that he or they claiming the said Ship or Yessel to be theirs
shal make appeare to the cheife Officer or Officers of the Customes in the Port next to the place of his or their
aboade that he or they are not Aliens, and shall have taken an Oath before such cheife Officer or Officers who
are hereby Authorised to administer the same, That such Ship or Vessel was bona fide and without fraude by him
or them bought for a valueable consideration expressing the summe as alsoe the time place and persons from
whom it was bought and who are his Partowners (if he have any) all which Partowners shall be lyeable to take
the said Oath before the cheife Officer or Officers of the Custome house of the Port next to the place of their
aboade, and that noe Forainer dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly hath any part interest or share therin, and that upon such
Oath he or they shall receive a Certificate under the Hand or Seale of the said cheife Officer or Officers of the
Port where such Person or Persons soe making Oath doe reside, wherby such Ship or Vessel may for the future
passe and be deemed as a Ship belonging to the said Port and enjoy the priviledge of such a Ship or Vessell,
And the said Officer or Officers shall keepe a Register of all such Certificates as he or they shall soe give and
returne a Duplicate therof to the cheife Officers of the Customes at London for such as shall be granted in
England Wales and Berwicke and to the cheife Officers of the Customes at Dublin for such as shall be given in
Ireland, together with the Names of the person or persons from whom such Ship was bought and the summe of
money which was paid for her as alsoe the Names of all such persons who are part owners of her if any such be.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Officers of the Customs allowing Privilege to any Foreign-built Ship until Certificate or Proof, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Governors of Plantations, &amp;c. suffering Foreign built Ships to load, &amp;c. without Certificate; Penalty</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p19">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any [Officers<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] of the Customes shall from and
after the (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) first day of April allow the priviledge of being a Ship or Vessel to England Ireland Wales or Towne
of Berwicke or any of them belonging to any Forraigne built Ship or Vessel, untill such Certificate be before them
produced, or such Proofe and Oath taken before them or if any Officer of the Customes shall allow the
priviledge of an English built ship or other Ship to any the aforesaid places belonging to any English or Forraine
built Ship comeing into any Port and makeing Entry of any Good&bholngs; untill Examination whether the Master and
three Fourths of the Mariners be English, or shall allow to any Foraigne built Ship bringing in the Commodities
of the Growth of the Country where it was built the priviledge by this A&bholigct; to such Ship given untill Examination
and Proofe whether it be a ship of the built of that Country, and that the Master and three Fourths of the
Mariners are of that Country, or if any Person who is or shall be made Governour of any Land&bholngs; Island&bholngs;
Plantations or Territories in Africa Asia or America by his Majesty His Heires or Successors shall suffer any Forraine
built Ship or Vessell to load or unload any Good&bholngs; or Commodityes within the Precin&bholigct;s of their Governments
untill such Certificate be produced before them, or such as shall be by them appointed to view the same, and
Examination whether the Master and three Fourthes of the Mariners at least be English, that for the first offence
such Officer of the Customes and Governours shall be put out of their places Offices or Governments.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Proviso for Goods of the Streights or Levant.</head>
			<para id="p20">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained extend not, or be meant to restraine and
prohibite the Importation of any the Commodityes of the Straights or Levant Seas loaden in English built shipping
&amp; whereof the Master &amp; three Fourths of the Mariners at least are English from the usuall Ports or Places for
lading of them heretofore within the said Straights or Levant Seas though the said Commodityes be not of the
very growth of the said places,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for Importation of East India Commodities as to Growth.</head>
			<para id="p21">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained extend not or be meant to restraine the Importing
of any East India Commodityes loaden in English built shipping, and wherof the Master and three Fourths of
the Mariners at least are English from the usuall place or places for lading of them in any part of those Seas
to the South-Ward and Eastward of Cabo bona Esperanza although the Ports be not the very places of their
growth.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Proviso for Goods imported from Spain, Portugal, Azores, Madeira, or Canary Islands.</head>
			<para id="p22">Provided alsoe That it shall and may bee lawful to and for any [of<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] the people of England Ireland Wales
Island&bholngs; of Guernsey or Jersey or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede in Vessels or Ships to them belonging, and
wherof the Master and three Fourths of the Mariners at least are English to load and bring in from any of the
Ports of Spaine or Portugall, or Westerne Island&bholngs; commonly called Azores or Madera or Canary Island&bholngs; all sorts
of Good&bholngs; or Commodityes of the Growth Produ&bholigct;ion or Manufa&bholigct;ure of the Plantations or Dominions of either
of them respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Proviso for Bullion, and Goods taken by way of Reprisal.</head>
			<para id="p23">Provided That this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained extend not to Bullion nor yet to any Good&bholngs; taken
or(<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) that shall be bona fide taken by way of Reprisall by any Ship or Ships belonging to England Ireland or
Wales Island&bholngs; of Guernsey or Jersey or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede and wherof the Master and three
Fourths of the Mariners at least are English haveing Commission from His Majestie his Heires [and<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Successors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Proviso concerning Corn, Salt, and Fish of Scotland;</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">and for Seal Oil of Russia</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct;, or any thing therin contained shall not extend or be construed to extend
to lay Aliens dutyes upon any Corne of the growth of Scotland, or to any Salt made in Scotland, nor to any
Fish caught saved and cured by the People of Scotland, and Imported dire&bholigct;ly from Scotland in Scotch built
Ships, and wherof the Master and three Fourths of the Mariners are of His Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s, nor to any Seale
Oyle of Russia Imported from thence into England Ireland Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede in shiping
bona fide to some of the said places belonging, and wherof the Master and three Fourths of the Mariners at
least are English.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. The Duty payable upon Goods in French Ships, and on their taking in and setting on Shore Passengers.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">How long to continue</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">Provided alsoe and it is hereby Ena&bholigct;ed That every Ship or Vessell belonging to any the Subje&bholigct;s of the
French King which from and after the twentyeth day of O&bholigct;ober in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred [&amp;<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] sixty shall come into any Port Creeke Harbour or Roade of England Ireland Wales or Towne of
Berwicke upon Tweede, and shall there [laid<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] or unlade any good&bholngs; or Commodityes, or take in or sett on
shore any Passengers shall pay to the Colle&bholigct;or of His Majesties Customes in such Port Creeke Harbour or Roade
for every Tun of which the said Ship or Vessell is of burthen to be computed by such Officer of the Customes
as shall be therunto appointed the summe of five shillings currant money of England, And that noe such Ship
or Vessell be suffered to depart out of such Port Creeke Harbour or Roade untill the said Duty be fully paid,
And that this Duty shall continue to be colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid for such time as a certaine Duty of Fifty
Solls per Tun lately imposed by the French King or any part therof shall continue to be Colle&bholigct;ed upon the
shiping of England lading in France and three moneths after and noe longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Sugars, Tobacco, &amp;c. of the Growth of America, Asia, or Africa, to be shipped only to English Dominions.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">And it is further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the first day of April which shall
be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty one noe Sugars Tobaccho Cotton Wool Indicoes
Ginger Fustick or other dyeing wood of the Growth Produ&bholigct;ion or Manufa&bholigct;ure of any English Plantations in
America Asia or Africa shall be shiped carryed conveyed or transported from any of the said English Plantations
to any Land Island Territory Dominion Port or place whatsoever other then to such (<ref idref="n15">15</ref>) English Plantations as doe
belong to His Majesty His Heires and Successors or to the Kingdome of England or Ireland or Principallity of
Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede there to be laid on shore under the penalty of the Forfeiture of
the said Good&bholngs; or the full value therof, as alsoe of the Ship with all her Guns Tackle Apparel Ammunition
and Furniture, the one moyety to the Kings Majesty His Heires and Successors, and the other moyety to him or
them that shal seize informe or sue for the same in any Court of Record by Bil Plaint or Information wherin
noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Ships sailing from England, Ireland, or Wales to English Plantations, bound.</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">according to Tonnage with Sureties, to bring Goods there loaded into England, &amp;c.; Ships coming from any other Port to the Plantations, Governors to take such Bond, or Certificate that such Bond has been given in England; Penalty.; Governors to return Bonds taken Twice yearly to Customs in London</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That for every Ship or Vessel which from and after
the [five and twentyeth<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] day of December in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and sixty shall set
saile out of, or from England Ireland Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede for any English Plantation in
America Asia[or<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Africa sufficient bond shall be given with one surety to the cheife Officers of the Custome house,
of such Port or place from whence the said Ship shall set saile to the value of one thousand pound&bholngs; if the ship
be of lesse burthen then one hundred Tuns, and of the s&bhouov;me of two thousand pound&bholngs; if the Ship [shal<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] be of
greater burthen, That in case the said Ship or Vessel shall loade any of the said C&bhooov;modityes at any of the said
English Plantations, that the same Commodityes shall be by the said ship brought to some Port of England Ireland
Wales, or to the Port or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede and shall there unload and put on shore the same,
the danger of the Seas onely excepted, And for all ships coming from any other Port or Place to any of the
aforesaid plantations who by this A&bholigct; are permited to trade there, that the Governour of such English plantation
shall before the said Ship or Vessel be permited to loade on board any of the said C&bhooov;modityes take Bond in
manner and to the value aforesaid for each respe&bholigct;ive Ship or Vessel, That such Ship or Vessell shall carry all
the aforesaid Good&bholngs; that shall be laden on board in the said ship to some other of His Majestyes English Plantations,
or to England Ireland Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede, And that every ship or vessel [that<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] shall loade
or take on board any of the aforesaid Good&bholngs; until such Bond given to the said Governour or Certificate produced
from the Officers of any Custome house of England Ireland Wales or of the Towne of Berwicke that such bond
have beene there duely given, shall be forfeited with all her Guns Tackle Apparel and Furniture to be imployed
and recovered in manner [as<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] aforesaid, And the said Governours and every of them shall twice in every yeare after
the first day of January One thousand six hundred [and<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] sixty returne true Copyes of all such Bond&bholngs; by him soe
taken to the cheife Officers of the Custome in London.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Case <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Things <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">sorts <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Officer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">lade <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">25th <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">which <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


