<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47276" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXVIII. An Act for further suplying and explaining certaine defe&bholigct;s in an A&bholigct; intituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy provision
of money for disbanding and paying off the forces of this kingdome both by land and sea. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p. 4. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Doubts, &amp;c. respe&bholigct;ing. c. 9. ante.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">c. 10. ante recited.; Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.; All Persons to pay the several Sums of Money appointed by the said Acts; also 40s. per Cent. on all their Estates Real and Personal.; Proviso for Estates under &pound;5 per Ann</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS through some doubts ariseing upon or by negligence in the execution of one A&bholigct; of this present
Parliament intituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy provision of money for the disbanding and paying off the
forces of this kingdome both by land and sea, and alsoe of one other A&bholigct; intituled An A&bholigct; for supplying and
explaining certaine defe&bholigct;s in the aforesaid A&bholigct;, the same A&bholigct;s doe not answere the end&bholngs; aforesaid in such measure
as was expe&bholigct;ed without some [further<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] explanation of the sence thereof and a review of the severall assessments
made thereby, soe that some persons may not escape without payment at all or goe away at very small proportions
whilest others pay their just and full due It is therefore ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Kings most excellent Majestie
by and with the consent and advice of the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in Parliament assembled and by the authoritie
of the same that all and every person and persons of the severall ranks degrees or qualifications in the said A&bholigct;
or A&bholigct;s mentioned shall contribute and pay the severall and respe&bholigct;ive summes of money therin appointed to be
paid (any pretence of exemption being the Kings Majestyes servants to the contrary notwithstanding) and alsoe that
(<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) every person and persons ecclesiasticall and temporall bodyes pollitique and corporate shall pay for their estates both
reall and personall the summe of forty shillings for one hundred pound&bholngs; per annum and soe proportionably for a
greater or lesser estate, and for every hundred pound&bholngs; personall estate after the rate of five pound&bholngs; per annum provided
it extend not to estates under five pound&bholngs; per annum,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The Commissioners named in c. 9. ante to appoint Persons to review the Rates that have been made,</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and thereupon to rate Estates to the full Value</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And to the intent the same may be equally and indifferently assessed and taxed Be it further ena&bholigct;ed and
declared by the authoritie aforesaid that the severall Commissioners in the said A&bholigct; named, or any three of them
within their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Limitts and precin&bholigct;s shall have power to nominate and appoint two
or more of the most able or discreet persons in every Parrish Village or Hamlet to review the severall rates and
assessments that have beene made in their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Parishes Villages and Hamlets, and where they
shall finde that by the negligence or default of any former Assessors any persons or estates have beene underrated
or ommitted to be rated, that then they shall rate and assesse all such persons and estates soe underrated or omitted
to the full value they are to be rated and assessed at either for their degrees persons or estates by this or the
former A&bholigct;s to that purpose made in this present Parliament, or shall by the appointment at the discretion of the
said Commissioners make new assessments or rates, and shall returne the same or their said additionall rates at such
places and times as the said Commissioners or any three of them shall appoint,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Sworn Clerks in the Exchequer 20 Nobles.</head>
			<para id="p5">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed [&amp; declared<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] by the authoritie aforesaid that every sworne Attourney or Clerke in the
Office of the Clerke of the Pipe in the Exchequer and every Attourney belonging to the Office of the Lord
Treasurers Remembrancer shall pay twenty nobles apeece,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Barristers at Law, and Persons written or writing themselves Esquire, to pay as Esquires.</head>
			<para id="p6">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that every Barrester at Law, and every other person or persons that hath
or have subscribed to any deed or writing wherein he or they have beene written or intituled Esquire, or that hath
or have a&bholigct;ed by vertue of any Commission or pretended Commission A&bholigct; or pretended A&bholigct;s of Parliament wherein
they have before the sitting of this Parliament beene written or entituled Esquire shall pay as reputed Esquiers
within the said A&bholigct;s,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Persons having paid, on Certificate of Commissioner to be discharged;</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">what such Certificate to express.; Proviso for Persons having paid for Estates in one or more Counties</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And to the intent that none that have or shall pay his or their due proportions that he or they ought to pay in
respe&bholigct; of his or their quality or degree may be doubly charged, every person that hath or shall pay his full proportion
for his or her degree and quality the same exceeding the proportion of his or her estate reall and personall shall by
certificate under the hand&bholngs; and seales of three or more of the Commissioners within the same County or precin&bholigct;s
where such summe hath or shall be paid be discharged from further payment for his or her estate soe that it be
perticularly expressed in every such certificate where such estate lyeth, and the severall and respe&bholigct;ive values thereof
soe that it may appeare that his or her proportion for his or her degree or quality doth exceed that of his or her
estate, And alsoe where any person or persons bodyes pollitique or corporate have paid or shall pay for his her or
their estate in one or more Countyes he or they shall by like certificate or certificates (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) for soe much and such values
specially mentioned to be paid in the said certificates and noe more,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Power to Commissioners on Oath to inquire and determine concerning Abuses by Assessors, &amp;c. and to fine.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Proviso that Fines do not exceed &pound;5 for one Offence.; Such Fines may be levied by Distress.; Fines employed as by the said former A&bholigct;s.; Where no Distress can be had, Commissioners may imprison Offender in the Common Gaol till Fine paid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And be it ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authoritie aforesaid that the said Commissioners or any three or more
of them within their severall precin&bholigct;s shall and may have power to inquire of heare and determine all abuses
negcle&bholigct;s and misdoeings of all and every the Assessors and Colle&bholigct;ors to be imployed by vertue of this, or the
said precedent A&bholigct;s, and shall have power to impose any fine or fines upon them or any of them whom they shall
be well informed (by the oath of two or more credible witnesses, which oath they or any two of them are hereby
impowered to administer) to offend from and after the twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred and
sixty in not performing their dutyes in their respe&bholigct;ive imployments, Provided that noe such fine shall exceed the
summe of five pound&bholngs; for one offence, and that such Commissioners who shall sett or impose such fine or fines
shall have full power by warrant under their hand&bholngs; and seales to command the severall Constables or Tithingmen
within the severall and respe&bholigct;ive places where such person or persons have their habitation or abode, upon
whom such fine or fines is or are imposed to levy the same by distresse upon the good&bholngs; of such person or
persons refuseing to pay the same and to returne the overplus thereof (if any be) dedu&bholigct;ing [alsoe<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] reasonable
charges for takeing such distresse to the Owner or Owners of such good&bholngs;, And every such fine shall be imployed
to the same purposes as the moneyes raised by the said former A&bholigct;s are appointed, And alsoe in case noe distresse
can be found or had for satisfieing such fine and in case noe distresse can be taken by the Colle&bholigct;ors or other
Officers appointed to distraine for the taxes or assessments by vertue of the said former A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s, that in
every such default upon complaint to the said C&bhooov;missioners or any three of them within their severall and
respe&bholigct;ive limitts the said Commissioners or any three of them shall have full power and authoritie to cause every
such person from whom noe distresse can be had to be committed to the next common goale there to remaine
untill he hath fully satisfied [&amp; paid<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] such summe or summes of money which ought to be charged upon him by
[vertue of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] this [or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] the said former A&bholigct;s without baile or mainprize,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Commissioners to make Account of Monies raised in Hundreds, &amp;c. only by former A&bholigct;s and this A&bholigct;, and return the same into the Exchequer before 2d March.</head>
			<para id="p11">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that the Commissioners of every County and place respe&bholigct;ively shall
make up a true accompt of the summes onely of every Hundred Lath Wapentake or Ward rated and assessed
by the said former A&bholigct;s together with the additionall summes that shall be rated by vertue of this present A&bholigct;
severally within their severall Countyes Limitts and Precin&bholigct;s without nameing the perticular persons or estates, and
shall shew what hath beene paid thereof and to what person and persons, and what hath beene discharged by such
certificates as are appointed by this A&bholigct;, and what is in arreare and unpaid, and shall returne the same into his
Majestyes Court of Exchequer before the second day of March next and in soe doeing they shall not be compelled
to make [or returne<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] any other accompt duplicate or certificate,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. The full yearly Value of Lands, &amp;c.; to be assessed.</head>
			<para id="p12">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that the true and full yearely value of all Land&bholngs; Tenements Rents Tythes
and other hereditaments shall be rated and assessed in manner aforesaid in the severall parishes villages or Hamlets
where the same are scituate lyeing or ariseing</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Sums paid under former A&bholigct;s dedu&bholigct;ed out of Charge by this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p13">And be it further declared that every summe charged upon and paid by any person by vertue of the said former
A&bholigct;s or either of them by reason of estate degree or quality shall be allowed and dedu&bholigct;ed out of such further
charge as shall be imposed upon him or her by vertue of this present A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Persons sued under this or former A&bholigct;s may plead General Issue.; Double Costs.</head>
			<para id="p14">Lastly it is ena&bholigct;ed and declared that whosoever is sued at law for any a&bholigct; done or to be done in the due
execution of this or either of the said former A&bholigct;s he may plead the generall issue and give the speciall matter
in evidence, and if the plaintiffe be non suite, or a verdi&bholigct; passe against any such plaintiffe or plaintiffes in any
such A&bholigct;ion the defendant shall and may recover his double costs,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Proviso for Peers.</head>
			<para id="p15">[Provided alwayes [&amp; be it ena&bholigct;ed<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to any Peere
of this Realme in point of assessment imprisonment distresse or otherwise provision being made in the said first
recited A&bholigct; for the assessing of the said Peeres by certaine Peeres who are therein named and appointed in that
behalfe,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Lord Chancellor, &amp;c. added to the Peers named in the said former A&bholigct;s for assessing Peers.</head>
			<para id="p16">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed that the Lord Chauncellour the Lord Treasurer, the Lord Steward of his Majesties
Household, Lord Chamberlaine of his Majestyes Household, the Earle of Northampton, Lord Howard of Charleton
the Lord Roberts the Lord Grey of Warke the Lord Craven the Lord Mohun and the Lord Hatton be added
to the Peeres named in the said first recited A&bholigct; for the assessing of the Peeres according to the said recited
A&bholigct;,<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] [which said Lord&bholngs; Commissioners or any five of them in this and the former A&bholigct; named shall have power to
assesse levy and colle&bholigct;, and shall assesse levy and colle&bholigct; all such summes of money as shall be assessed according
to the tenor of this and the former A&bholigct; upon such Peeres who have not paid proportionably to their estates.<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XII. Commissioners named.</head>
			<para id="p17">And be it declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that these persons hereafter named shall be added
Commissioners for their severall Countyes places and precin&bholigct;s respe&bholigct;ively and shall exercise the same power as if
they had beene named in the said former A&bholigct;s or either of them.</para>
			<para id="p18">Berks</para>
			<para id="p19">For the County of Berks Peregrine Hobby Richard Harrison Es&bhoqesq; John Fettiplace of Fernham Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p20">Burrough of New Windsor</para>
			<para id="p21">Andrew Plumton Gent. Richard Fishborne Gent..</para>
			<para id="p22">Bucks</para>
			<para id="p23">For the County of Bucks Sir Thomas Hampson Baronet Sir Philip Palmer Baronet Anthony Ratcliffe Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p24">Cambridge</para>
			<para id="p25">For the County of Cambridge Sir Thomas Dayrell John Bennet Es&bhoqesq; Sir Anthony Cage, Levinus Bennet.</para>
			<para id="p26">For the Isle of Ely</para>
			<para id="p27">For the Isle of Ely Roger Jennings Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p28">Chester</para>
			<para id="p29">For the County of Chester Sir George Warberton Baronet Edward Warren Es&bhoqesq; Jeffery Shakerly Esquire Henry
Lee Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p30">Citty of Chester</para>
			<para id="p31">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester The Maior for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p32">Cornewall</para>
			<para id="p33">For the County of Cornewall Robert Roberts Esquire Sir William Tredingham Joseph Tredingham Thomas
Penhallow The Knights and Burgesses that serve for the said County and James Eirsey Gent..</para>
			<para id="p34">Cumberland</para>
			<para id="p35">For the County of Cumberland Anthony Bouch Richard Uriall Thomas Croswhat Robert Webster</para>
			<para id="p36">Devon</para>
			<para id="p37">For the County of Devon Nicholas Dasies Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke William Jennins Gent. Edmond Tremaine (<ref idref="n7">7</ref>) William
Putt [Es&bhoqesq;s.<ref idref="n7">7</ref>
				<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] John Kellond (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) William Bogan (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) George Howard (<ref idref="n7">7</ref>) John Kelley (<ref idref="n7">7</ref>) William Kelley (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) James
Rodd [Es&bhoqesq;s.<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p38">Yorke</para>
			<para id="p39">For the West Riding in the County of Yorke Wellbury Norton Es&bhoqesq; Robert Wivell Es&bhoqesq; Richard Roundhill
Gent. William Hamond Es&bhoqesq; Walter Hawkesworth Es&bhoqesq; Cuthbert Wade John Preston Gent. Arthur Ingram Es&bhoqesq;
Edward Atkinson William Witham Gent. Samuell Sonderland Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Ward Gent. Sir William Ingram Knight.</para>
			<para id="p40">Yorke North Riding</para>
			<para id="p41">For the North Rideing in the County of Yorke Sir William Caley Arthur Caley Es&bhoqesq; William Wivell Es&bhoqesq; Sir
Thomas Gower Baronet Thomas Worsley Es&bhoqesq; Charles Tankred Sir William Frankland Baronet The Bailiffes of
Scarborough for the time being Tristram Fish Robert Belt Esquiers Thomas Robinson Thomas Scudamore Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p42">[Yorke</para>
			<para id="p43">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke, All the Aldermen of the Citty of Yorke.<ref idref="n10">10</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p44">For the Towne of Kingston upon Hull George Crowle.</para>
			<para id="p45">Essex</para>
			<para id="p46">For the County of Essex M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Glascock M<emph type="p">r</emph> Miles Hubbert M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Smart Captaine Hunter Deane Tindall
Es&bhoqesq; Isaac Wincoll Thomas Clapton Thomas Peeke Peter Johnson Thomas Manby Es&bhoqesq;s.</para>
			<para id="p47">Gloucester</para>
			<para id="p48">For the County of Gloucester Thomas Freame Thomas Floide Samuell Shepard Philip Shepard William Morgan
Richard Daston John Tooke [Es&bhoqesq;s<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Robert Lord Tracy.</para>
			<para id="p49">Hereford</para>
			<para id="p50">For the County of Hereford Sir Herbert Parret Knight, John Barnaby of Brookehampton Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Baskervile
of Collington Gent. John Booth of Hereford Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p51">Citty of Hereford</para>
			<para id="p52">For the Citty of Hereford Thomas Davies Es&bhoqesq; Maior James Lawrence Gent. Thomas Clerke Gent..</para>
			<para id="p53">Hertford</para>
			<para id="p54">For the County of Hertford Marmaduke Rawden James Willimot junior Gent. Arras Do&bholigct;or of Phisickt
Richard Combes Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p55">S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albans</para>
			<para id="p56">For the Burrough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albans William Foxwist [Esquires<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Recorder M<emph type="p">r</emph> John New M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Eames M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas
Cowley senior M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Marston Henry Conningsby Edmond Smith, Albon Cox Richard Combes Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p57">Kent</para>
			<para id="p58">For the County of Kent Sir William Mann Sir Edward Masters Thomas Peake Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Godfrey The
Maior of Maidston for the time being Sir William Merideth Baronet Sir Thomas Peirce Baronet M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Manley
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Manley.</para>
			<para id="p59">[Sandwich<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p60">For Sandwich John Verrier Peter Peake Gent.
			</para>
			<para id="p61">Lancaster</para>
			<para id="p62">For the County of Lancaster Henry Bannester Es&bhoqesq; Jeoffrey Rushton Gent. Richard Fleetwood Gent. John Mollineux
Es&bhoqesq; William Fife Es&bhoqesq; Sir George Midleton Knight and Baronet Mathew Richardson Es&bhoqesq; Robert Heywood Es&bhoqesq;
Roger Stoughton of the Citty of London Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p63">Lincolne</para>
			<para id="p64">For the parts of Linsey in the County of Lincolne Edward Turney (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) William Lister [Esquiers<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Sir Robert
Dallison Baronet, Sir Charles Dallison Knight.</para>
			<para id="p65">Great Grimsby</para>
			<para id="p66">For Great Grimsby William Draper Samuell Pro&bholigct;or.</para>
			<para id="p67">For the parts of Kestiven William Thompson, Humphrey Walcot.</para>
			<para id="p68">London</para>
			<para id="p69">For the Citty of London Nicholas Delves Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p70">Midlesex</para>
			<para id="p71">For the County of Midlesex Sir John Robinson Baronet Lieutenant of the Tower Sir Richard Browne Thomas
Bide Thomas Harrison of South Mims Sir William Bateman Leiutenant Collonell Powell Charles Pitfield Es&bhoqesq; Robert
Peyton John Jones John Limbrey Edward Chard Richard Shelton Esquiers William Page Es&bhoqesq; Roger Jennings
Es&bhoqesq; Richard Meney.</para>
			<para id="p72">Westminster</para>
			<para id="p73">For the Citty of Westminster and Liberties thereof Gabriel Becke Es&bhoqesq; M<emph type="p">r</emph> Graham Peter Maplesden George
Plunknet Thomas Kirke William Greene George Farewell Ralph Darnell.</para>
			<para id="p74">Northampton</para>
			<para id="p75">For the County of Northampton Edward Oneley, (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) John Thornton (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) John Willoughby [Esquiers<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p76">[Norffolke<ref idref="n13">13</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p77">For the County of [Norffolke<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] George Windham Robert Doughty of Hanworth (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) Robert Lagar [Esquiers<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]
Henry Scarborough Gent. M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Ripps M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Talbot M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Blackborne Gent..</para>
			<para id="p78">Burrough of Lyn Regis</para>
			<para id="p79">For the Burrough of Lyn Regis John Basset Maior Robert Steward Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Thomas Greene William
Wharton Henry Bell.</para>
			<para id="p80">Great Yarmouth</para>
			<para id="p81">For the Towne of Great Yarmouth Nicholas Cutting James Simond&bholngs; Bailiffes there, Sir John Potts Knight and
Baronet Sir William Doyley Knight Sir Thomas Meadow Knight Thomas Gooch George England John Carter
Nathaniell Ashby Thomas Lucas John Woodroft James Johnson Esquires George Tilyard Gentt..</para>
			<para id="p82">Thetford</para>
			<para id="p83">For the whole Burrough and Corporation of Thetford The Maior for the time being M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Kendall Gent.,
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Bourage Martin Maurice Shelton [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Keddington Gentt. M<emph type="p">r</emph> Nicholas Rookewood M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert
Wright of Kilveston.</para>
			<para id="p84">Newcastle upon Tine</para>
			<para id="p85">For the Towne and County of Newcastle upon Tine Sir John Marley</para>
			<para id="p86">Nottingham</para>
			<para id="p87">For the [Towne<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] of Nottingham Francis Sandis Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Bristow (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) William Newton [Gentlemen.<ref idref="n16">16</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p88">[East Retford<ref idref="n17">17</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p89">For the Burrough of East Retford The Bailiffes for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p90">Oxon</para>
			<para id="p91">For the County of Oxon William Glyn (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John West [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] John Coker Gent James Herbert Esquire,
Sir Thomas Tippin.</para>
			<para id="p92">University of Oxford</para>
			<para id="p93">M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Withers M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Master M<emph type="p">r</emph> David Thomas M<emph type="p">r</emph> Gregory Ballard, M<emph type="p">r</emph> Timothy Horton.</para>
			<para id="p94">The Citty of Oxford</para>
			<para id="p95">For the Citty of Oxford Francis Holloway William Cornish.</para>
			<para id="p96">Salop</para>
			<para id="p97">For the County of Salop Charles Baldwin (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Samuell Baldwin [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> Moore of Midleton M<emph type="p">r</emph> [Bishop<ref idref="n18">18</ref>]
of the Moore Benjamin Buckley.</para>
			<para id="p98">Stafford</para>
			<para id="p99">For the County of Stafford Thomas Ruddiard Esquire John Colclough (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Timothy Edge [Gentlemen.<ref idref="n16">16</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p100">Somerset</para>
			<para id="p101">For the County of Somerset William Orange Esquire William Bacon senior Gent. John Cridland Gent. Mawdley
Samborne (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Carew (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Roger Newborough (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) James Haise [Esquiers.<ref idref="n14">14</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p102">The Citty of Bristoll</para>
			<para id="p103">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll The Maior and Sheriffes for the time being John Knight the
elder, William Coulston John Bradway William Cole.</para>
			<para id="p104">For the Citty of Bath John Vane John Masters Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p105">Southampton</para>
			<para id="p106">For the County of Southampton with the Towne and County M<emph type="p">r</emph> Essex Powlet Richard Lucy (<ref idref="n18">18</ref>) Gabriel Whistler
[Esquiers.<ref idref="n18">18</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p107">Isle of Wight</para>
			<para id="p108">For the Isle of Wight Thomas Bowreman Es&bhoqesq; John Oglander of Newport Gentt.
			</para>
			<para id="p109">Suffolke</para>
			<para id="p110">For the County of Suffolke George Winiffe William Blumfield Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p111">Surrey</para>
			<para id="p112">For the County of Surrey Edward Evelin (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Yates (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Richard Knippe [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Parker Sir
Purbecke Temple Knight Earle of Ancram Henry Capell Dallmahey Es&bhoqesq; John Farewell Do&bholigct;or Windebank.</para>
			<para id="p113">For the Towne of Rye.</para>
			<para id="p114">Samuell Bembrigg James Welsh Thomas Osmonton.</para>
			<para id="p115">Coventry.</para>
			<para id="p116">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry Sir Arthur Caley Knight The Maior of Coventry for the
time being, Henry Smith Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p117">Warwicke</para>
			<para id="p118">For the Towne of Warwicke Sir Henry Puckering Baronet, Sir Clement Throckmorton Knight John Rouse (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>)
Nathaniell Stoughton (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) John Stanton [Esquiers.<ref idref="n19">19</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p119">Wilts</para>
			<para id="p120">For the County of Wilts Walter Buckland (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) Thomas Mompesson (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) William Caley [Esquiers<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Mathew Rayman
Gent. Thomas Hunt Gent. Robert Challoner (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Robert Nicholas of Almcamings William Broomewich Gent. Samuell
Eyre Gent. Simon Spatchurst Es&bhoqesq; Christopher Gardiner Gent..</para>
			<para id="p121">Sarum</para>
			<para id="p122">For the Citty of New Sarum Samuell Eyre Gent. Simon Spatchurst Es&bhoqesq; Christopher Gardiner Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p123">[Anglesey</para>
			<para id="p124">For the Isle of Anglesey Robert Lord Viscount Bulkley.<ref idref="n21">21</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p125">Cardigan</para>
			<para id="p126">For the County of Cardigan James Phillips (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) Morgan Herbert (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) Thomas Jenkins (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) Erasmus Lloyde (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>)
Thomas Evans (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) Henry Vaughan (<ref idref="n22">22</ref>) Thomas Price the elder [Esquiers<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Thomas Lloyde of Ymshim (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Maurice
Vaughan (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) John Price [Gentlemen.<ref idref="n20">20</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p127">Carnarvan</para>
			<para id="p128">For the County of Carnarvan Griffith Bodurda John Lloyde of Nangwunadle Robert Wynne of Conway William
Winne of Pengwoone William Thomas of Carnarvan Jonathan Lloyde Walter Lloyde Walter Mansell.</para>
			<para id="p129">Denbigh</para>
			<para id="p130">For the County of Denbigh Francis Weavely Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p131">Flint</para>
			<para id="p132">For the County of Flint Kenrick Eyton Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p133">Mountgomery</para>
			<para id="p134">For the County of Mountgomery</para>
			<para id="p135">Haverford West</para>
			<para id="p136">For the Towne and County of Haverford West Sir Herbert Perrot Knight, William Browne Alderman.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">all and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">bee discharged in other places <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">Northfolke <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Countie <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">Gent.
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">Bushop <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">Gent.
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


