<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47271" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIII. A Grant of certaine Impositions upon Beere Ale and other Liquors for the encrease of His Majestyes Revenue
dureing His Life. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p. 3. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Rates given to His Majesty for Life.</head>
			<para id="p1">THE Commons assembled in Parliament in gratitude for an humble acknowledgement of your Majestyes great
Grace and Favour to us Your Commons beyond Example of any Your Royall Progenitors expressed in many
publique A&bholigct;s and Declarations to the great rejoyceing and generall satisfa&bholigct;ion of all Your people which they
desire to answere with returnes suitable and exceeding the Examples of any of [there<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Auncesters for the encreasing
of Your Majestyes Revenue dureing Your Majestyes Raigne (which God long continue) Doe therefore give and
grant unto Your most Excellent Majestye the rates and dutyes Impositions Charges and summes of money herein
after following, And doe beseech your Majestye that it may be Ena&bholigct;ed And be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords and Commons in Parliament assembled that
from and after the twenty fifth day of December One thousand six hundred and sixty there shall be throughout
your Majestyes Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede raised levyed
colle&bholigct;ed and paid unto your Majestie dureing Your Life for Beere Ale Sider and other Liquors herein after
mentioned the severall Rates Impositions Dutyes and Charges herein after expressed and in manner and forme
following That is to say</para>
			<table id="t1">
				<tr>
					<td cols="2"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For every Barrell of Beere or Ale above six shillings the Barrell brewed by the Common Brewer or any
other Person or Persons who doth or shall sell or tap out Beere or Ale publiquely or privately to be paid
by the Common Brewer or by such other Person or Persons respe&bholigct;ively and soe proportionably for a
greater or lesser quantity One shilling three pence.</td>
					<td>[js. iijd. [<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For every Barrell of Six shillings Beere or Ale or under brewed by the Common Brewer or any other
Person or Persons who doth or shall sell or tap out such Beere or Ale publiquely or privately to be paid
by the [said<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Common Brewer or by such other Person or Persons respe&bholigct;ively as aforesaid, and soe
proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity three pence</td>
					<td>iij d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For all Sider and Perry made and sold by retaile upon every Hogshead to be paid by the Retayler
thereof, and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser measure One shilling three pence</td>
					<td> [js. iijd.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For all Metheglin or Meade sold whether by Retayle or otherwise to be paid by the maker therof
upon every Gallon One halfe penny</td>
					<td>ob.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For every barrell of Beere commonly called Vinegar beere brewed by any common Brewer in any
common Brew house six pence</td>
					<td> vjd.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For every Gallon of Strong water or Aqua vite made and sold to be paid by the maker thereof
One penny</td>
					<td> jd.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For every Barrell of Beere or Ale Imported from beyond the Seas Three shillings</td>
					<td> iij s.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For every Tun of Sider or Perry Imported from beyond the Seas, and soe proportionably for a greater
or lesser quantity Five shillings</td>
					<td> v s.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For every Gallon of Spirits made of any kinde of Wine or Sider Imported Two pence</td>
					<td> ij d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For every Gallon of Strong water perfe&bholigct;ly made Imported from beyond the Seas Foure pence</td>
					<td> iiij d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For every Gallon of Coffee made and sold to be paid by the maker Foure pence</td>
					<td> iiij d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For every Gallon of Chocolate Sherbet and Tea made and sold to be paid by the Maker thereof
Eight pence</td>
					<td> viij d.</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Duty upon Foreign Liquors imported to be paid by Importer in money upon Entry made before landing.</head>
			<para id="p2">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed and Ordained by the Authority aforesaid that the severall Rates Dutyes and Charges
of Excise or new Impost above mentioned hereby sett or imposed upon all and every the said Forraigne Liquors
which shall be Imported or brought into all or any the Ports of this Kingdome and Dominions thereof aforesaid
from and after the Five and twentyeth of December next shall be from time to time satisfied and paid by the
Merchant or Merchants Importer or Importers of the same in ready money upon his or their entry or entryes
made and before the landing thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Common Brewers to make Entry weekly, and other Retailers of Beer, Ale, &amp;c. monthly.</head>
			<para id="p3">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that all common Brewers of Beere and Ale shall once
in every weeke, and all Innkeepers Alehouse keepers Vi&bholigct;uallers and other Retailers of Beere Ale Sider Perry
Metheglin Strong water brewing makeing or retaileing the same shall once in every moneth make true and
perticular entries at the Office of Excise, within the limits of which the said Commodities and Manufactures are
made, of all Beere Ale Perry Sider Metheglin Strong water or other the Liquors aforesaid which they or any of
them shall brew make or retaile in that weeke and moneth respectively as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Brewers not making Entry, Penalty &pound;5. Innkeeper, Penalty &pound;5. Retailers, Penalty 20s.</head>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that all such common Brewers who doe not once a
weeke make due and perticular Entryes shall forfeit five pound&bholngs;, And that every such Inne-keeper who doth not
make true and perticular Entryes once a moneth shall forfeit five pound&bholngs;. And that every Alehouse keeper
Vi&bholigct;ualler or other retailer who doth not once a moneth make due and perticular Entryes shall forfeit twenty
shillings,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Brewers not clearing off, Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Retailers,; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that every common Brewer who shall not pay and
cleere off within a weeke after he made his entry or ought to have made his entry as aforesaid shall pay double
the value of the duty [And that every Inne keeper Alehouse keeper Vi&bholigct;ualer or other Retailer who shall not pay
&amp; cleere off within a moneth after he made his Entry or ought to have made his Entry (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) aforesaid shall pay double
the value of the duty the said respe&bholigct;ive forfeitures to be leavied upon theire<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Good&bholngs; and Chattells in such manner
and forme as hereafter in this A&bholigct; is ordained and dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. No Person compelled to go further to make Entries than next Market Town.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided that noe such person as aforesaid shall be compelled by the Commissioners or Sub-Commissioners of
Excise to travell for the makeing of the said Entryes or payment of the said Dutyes or other cause whatsoever
touching or concerning the same if he live in a market Towne out of the said Towne if he live out of a market
Towne then to noe other place then to the next market Towne to his habitation in the same County on the
market day.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Commissioners, &amp;c. for executing Act empowered to appoint Gaugers. Gaugers may enter Houses, &amp;c. to gauge;</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">and to make Return to Commissioners,; and leave Copy of Return with Brewer, &amp;c. which is to be a Charge on Brewer, &amp;c.; Brewer, &amp;c. refusing Gauger Admittance.; Proceedings; Brewer, &amp;c. in such Case selling, not having paid Duty, Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed and Ordained by the Authority aforesaid That the Commissioners who shall be
appointed by his Majestie for the puting this A&bholigct; in execution, and their Sub-Commissioners in their respe&bholigct;ive Circuits
and Divisions shall hereby have power to constitute under their Hand&bholngs; and Seales such and soc many Gagers as they
shall finde needfull, which Gagers and every of them shall at all times as well by night as by day, And if by
night then in the presence of a Constable or other lawfull Officer be permitted upon their request to enter the
House Brewhouse Distilling house and all other houses and places [whatsoever<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] belonging to or used by any Brewer
Inne-keeper Vi&bholigct;ualler or other Retayler of Beere brewing or makeing the same as aforesaid or by any Distiller of
Strong waters, or Retailer of other the Liquors aforesaid, and to gage all Coppers Fatts and Vessells in the same,
and to take an accompt of Beere Ale Worts Perry Sider Strong waters Aqua vite Metheglin or other the Liquors
aforesaid in the said houses places and vessells from time to time brewed or made &amp; distilled and therof to make
returne or report in writeing to the said Commissioners or Sub Commissioners of Excise under whose Office and
Limits such Brewer Retailer Distiller or maker of the Liquors aforesaid doth dwell and inhabit leaving a true
Copy of such Returne in writeing under his Hand with such Brewer Retailer Distiller or makers of the Liquors
aforesaid, And such Reports or Returnes of the said Gagers shall be a charge upon the said Brewers makers
and Retailers respe&bholigct;ively, And if any such common Brewer or Retailer shall refuse to permit any such Gager or
Gagers to enter his Brew house or any other place aforementioned, or to gage or take accompt of his brewing
vessells or of any such Beere Ale Worts Perry Sider Strong water Aqua-vite Metheglin or other the Liquors
aforesaid such Brewer Retailer [or<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Distiller shall be forthwith forbidden by the said Gager or Gagers to sell carry
out or deliver to any of his Customers any Beere Ale Strong water Aqua vite or other the Liquors aforesaid, And
if any such Brewer Retailer or Distiller of any the Liquors aforesaid after such warning given shall sell carry or
deliver out the same or any part therof not haveing paid and cleared the duty of Excise, such person and persons
shall besides the forfeiture of double the value forfeit and lose the summe of five pound&bholngs; as aforesaid for every
offence to be leavyed and recovered upon his [and<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] their Good&bholngs; and Chattels in manner and forme as hereafter
in this A&bholigct; is provided;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. What shall be reckoned a Barrel of Beer.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">What a Barrel of Ale</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And for the avoiding of all incertainty &amp; dispute touching the returnes made or to be made by the Gagers of
any Beere or Ale soe brewed as aforesaid Bee it Ena&bholigct;ed and Declared by the Authority aforesaid That every six
and thirty Gallons of Beare taken by the Gage according to the Standard of the Ale quart fower wherof shall
make the Gallon remaining in the custody of the Chamberlaines of his Majestyes Exchequer shall be reckoned
accounted and returned by the Gager for a barrell of Beare, And every two and thirty Gallons of Ale taken by
the Gage according to the same Standard shall be in like manner reckoned accounted and returned for a barrell
of Ale, and all other the Liquors aforesaid according to the Wine gallon,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Prices to be at the usual Rates.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Proviso</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">Provided alwayes and be it Ena&bholigct;ed and Ordained by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Brewers or Retailers of
Beere and Ale shall take any more in the price thereof upon sale of the same then according to the usuall rates
and prizes, saveing that every common Brewer shall and may take and receive of all and every person and persons
to whom he shall sell and deliver any [Beere or Ale<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] the Excise thereupon due as aforesaid over and above the
usuall rates and prizes,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Allowance for Waste and Leakage.</head>
			<para id="p14">And be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That for the better incouragement of all common brewers and
makers of Beere or Ale to make due entry and payment thereof according as by this A&bholigct; is appointed, the said
common brewer not selling the same by Retaile for and in consideration of waste by fillings and leakage of their
Beere and Ale shall have and be allowed out of the said returns made by the Gagers the severall allowances and
abatements hereafter mentioned (that is to say) upon every three and twenty barrells of Beere whether strong or
small returned by the said Gagers three barrells, and upon every two and twenty barrels of Ale whether strong or
small returned by the Gagers two barrels which said allowances and abatements the (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) Commissioners to be appointed
as aforesaid and their Sub-Commissioners are hereby authorized to allow and make accordingly,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. False Entries;</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">Provided alwayes that where any common Brewer shall wittingly or willingly make a false Entry and be
convi&bholigct;ed for the same before the Commissioners to be appointed as aforesaid or any two of them, or before such
other person or persons as are hereafter by this A&bholigct; appointed, in that case such Brewer or Brewers shall forfeit
and lose over and besides the penaltyes before mentioned the said allowance soe to be made for six moneths then
next ensueing,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. No Ale or Beer to be delivered by Brewer to Retailer before Duty paid. Proviso for Beer and Ale sold in Fairs.</head>
			<para id="p17">And bee it Ena&bholigct;ed and Ordained by the Authority aforesaid That noe Beere or Ale shall be delivered in by
such brewer or maker thereof to any Vi&bholigct;ualler or other Retailer thereof untill the rate which by such Vi&bholigct;ualler
or Retailer is to be paid over and above the price of the said Beere or Ale for or in respe&bholigct; of this duty be first
paid and satisfied by the said Vi&bholigct;ualler or Retailer to the brewer or maker thereof, Provided alwayes That if
any person or persons shall brew and sell by retaile any small quantities of Beere or Ale in any Faire within this
Realme or Dominions aforesaid who is not otherwise any common or usuall Brewer or Retailer thereof and shall
before any such selling and retailing thereof well and truely pay and satisfie the duty due for the same to the
Commissioners or Sub Commissioners within whose limitts or division the said Faire shall be held or to their
Officers thereunto appointed, then such person or persons soe brewing or retailing the same and for soe much and
noe more nor otherwise shall be freed and discharged from all penaltyes and forfeitures in and by this A&bholigct; before
mentioned and imposed Any thing therein contained to the contrary notwithstanding,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Commissioners may compound for Duty with Innkeeper, Retailer, or Vi&bholigct;ualler.</head>
			<para id="p18">Provided neverthelesse That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Commissioners and Sub Commissioners
respe&bholigct;ively to compound for this Duty with any Innekeeper Vi&bholigct;ualler Alehouse-keeper or Retayler of Beere Ale
and other the Liquors aforesaid within their respe&bholigct;ive divisions from time to time in such manner and forme as
may be most for the advantage and improvement of the receipts thereof, Any thing in this A&bholigct; before contained to
the contrary notwithstanding;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Rates may be farmed for Three Years.</head>
			<para id="p19">And it is further Ordained and Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Lord Treasurer or Commissioners
of the Treasury for the time being or such other person or persons as his Majestie shall appoint shall have power,
and are hereby authorized and impowered from time to time to treat contra&bholigct; conclude and agree with any person
or persons for or concerning the farming of all or any the Rates Dutyes and Charges in this A&bholigct; mentioned upon
Beere Ale Perry Sider or other the Liquors [aforesaid<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] in any the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes or Places of this
Realme or Dominions thereof as may be for the greatest benefit and advantage of the said receipt soe as the same
exceed not the terme of three yeares</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Such Contra&bholigct;s to be good in Law.</head>
			<para id="p20">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed that every such contra&bholigct; bargaine and agreement of the Lord Treasurer or Commissoners
of the Treasury or other persons aforesaid on behalfe of his Majestye on the one part, And the person or persons
farming on the other part shall be good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law to all intents and purposes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Treasury not to treat with Persons other than such as shall be nominated by Quarter Sessions; such Persons to have the First Refusal.</head>
			<para id="p21">Provided alwayes to the end the aforesaid duty may be paid with most ease to the people It is hereby further
Ena&bholigct;ed That the Lord Treasurer Commissioners of the Treasury or other persons aforesaid shall not within six
moneths after the commencement of this A&bholigct; treat conclude or agree with any person or persons touching the
Farming of this Duty upon Beere and Ale in any the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes or Places of this Realme or Dominions
thereof other then with such person or persons as by the Justices of Peace of the said Countyes or Places or the
major part of them at their publique Quarter Sessions shall be nominated and appointed in that behalfe, which
person or persons is to have the first refusall of any such Farme respe&bholigct;ively and may take the same, Any thing
in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding:</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Proviso as to Rate of farming.</head>
			<para id="p22">Provided that the said Duty shall not be lett to any other person or persons then to the person or persons
recommended by the Justices under the rate that it shall be tendered to and refused by such person or persons
soe recommended.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Forfeitures and Offences within the limits of London, where to be determined.</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">In any other County or Place, where to be determined.; Refusal of Justices to determine, then Sub-Commissioners.; Appeals by Parties aggrieved.; Proceedings by Commissioners for Appeals.; Who mayadminister an Oath, and issue Warrants for levying Penalties</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed and Ordained by the Authority aforesaid that all forfeitures and offences made and
committed against this A&bholigct; or any Clause or Article therein contained shall be heard adjudged and determined by
such person and persons and in such manner and forme as hereafter in and by this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed and appointed
that is to say all such forfeitures and offences made and committed [within the immediate limits of the cheife Office
in London shall be heard adjudged and determined by the said cheife Commissioners and Governours of Excise
(appointed by his Majestie) or the major part of them, or by the Commissioners for appeales and regulating of
this Duty or the major part of them in case of appeale and not otherwise, And all such forfeitures and offences
made and committed<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] within all or any other the Countyes Cittyes Towne or place within this Kingdome or
Dominions thereof shall be heard and determined by any two or more of the Justices of the Peace resideing neere
to the place where such forfeitures shall be made or offence committed, And in case of negcle&bholigct; or refusall of
such Justices of the Peace by the space of fowerteene dayes next after complaint made and notice therof given
to the offender, then the Sub Commissioners or the major part of them appointed for any such Citty County
Towne or Place shall and are hereby impowered to heare and determine the same, And if the party finde himselfe
aggreived by the Judgement given by the said Sub Commissioners he shall and may appeale to the Justices of
the Peace at the next Quarter Sessions who are hereby impowered and authorized to heare and determine the
same whose Judgement therin shall be finall, which said Commissioners for appeales and regulating of this Duty
and the cheife Commissioners for Excise and all Justices of Peace and Sub Commissioners aforesaid respe&bholigct;ively
are hereby authorized and stri&bholigct;ly enjoyned and required upon any complaint or information exhibited and brought
of any such forfeiture made or offence committed contrary to this A&bholigct; to summon the party accused, and upon
his appearance or contempt to proceed to the examination of the matter of Fa&bholigct; and upon due proofe made thereof
either by the voluntary confession of the party, or by the oath of one or more credible Witnesses (which oath
they or any two or more of them have hereby power to administer) to give Judgement or Sentence according
as in and by this A&bholigct; is before ordained and dire&bholigct;ed, And to award and issue out Warrants under their Hand&bholngs;</para>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Proceedings thereon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">for the leavying of such forefeitures penaltyes and fines as by this A&bholigct; is imposed for any such offence committed
upon the Good&bholngs; and Chattels of the offender, and to cause sale to be made of the said Good&bholngs; and Chattels if
they shall not be redeemed within fowerteene dayes rendering to the party the overplus if any be, and for want
of sufficient distresse to imprison the party offending till satisfa&bholigct;ion be made</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Fines and Forfeitures may be mitigated by Commissioners, &amp;c.; Such Mitigation a Discharge.</head>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">Proviso</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p28">Provided neverthelesse that it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said respe&bholigct;ive Justices of Peace
Commissioners for Excise or any two of them or their Sub Commissioners respe&bholigct;ively [from time to time.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] where
they shall see cause to mittigate compound or lessen such forfeiture penalty or fine as in their discretion they shall
thinke fitt, And that every such mitigation and payment thereupon accordingly made shall be a sufficient discharge
of the said penaltyes and forfeitures to the persons soe offending soe as by such mitigation the same be not made
lesse then double the value of the duty of Excise which should or ought to have beene paid besides the reasonable
costs and charges of such Officer or Officers or others as were imployed therein (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) to them allowed by the said Justices
Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. How the Fines and Forfeitures shall be employed.</head>
			<para id="p29">And it is hereby further Ena&bholigct;ed and Ordained that all Fines Forfeitures and Penalties mentioned in this A&bholigct;,
all necessary charges for the recovery thereof being first dedu&bholigct;ed shall be imployed three fourth parts thereof to
and for the use of the Kings Majestie, and the other fourth part to the Discoverer or Informer of the same,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI.</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Head Office ere&bholigct;ed in London to be managed by Officers appointed by the King, who are to be Commissioners and Governors for managing the Receipt of Excise</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">And for the better managing colle&bholigct;ing secureing leavying and recovering of all and every the said rates and
charges of Excise hereby imposed, and sett upon all or any the commodities before mentioned to the end the same
may be paid and disposed of according to the intent of this present A&bholigct;, Be it further Ena&bholigct;ed and Ordained by
the Authoritie aforesaid And it is hereby Ena&bholigct;ed That one principall Head Office shall be ere&bholigct;ed and continued in
the Citty of London or within ten miles thereof from time to time as long as his Majestie shall thinke fitt for this
duty, unto which all other Offices for the same within England and Wales and the Towne and Port of Berwicke
shall be subordinate and accomptable, Which said Office shall be managed by such Officers as shall be appointed
by the Kings Majestie as aforesaid who, or any two of them are hereby [appointed &amp;<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] constituted Commissioners
and Governours for the management of his Majestyes Receipt of the Excise, and to sitt in some convenient
place in the Citty of London or within ten miles therof [from time to time<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] as long as His Majestie shall thinke fitt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Officers of Excise to take the Oath of Allegiance and Supremacy, and the following Oath.</head>
			<para id="p32">And be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that noe person or persons shall be capeable of intermedling with
any Office or Imployment relating to the Excise untill he or they shall before two or more Justices of [the<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Peace
in the County where his or their Imployments shall be, or before one of the Barons of the Exchequer take the
Oathes of Alleigiance and Supremacy which Oathes they have hereby power to administer together with this Oath
following Mutatis mutandis</para>
			<para id="p33">YOU shall sweare to execute the Office of truely and faithfully without Favour or Affe&bholigct;ion, and
shall from time to time true Account make and deliver to such person or persons as his Majesty shall appoint
to receive the same and shall take noe Fee or Reward for the Execution of the said Office from any other person
then from his Majestie, or those whom his Majestie shall appoint in that behalfe,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Certificates of Oath taken to the next Quarter-Sessions.</head>
			<para id="p34">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that every such Justice of Peace shall certifie the takeing
of such Oath to the next Quarter Sessions there to be recorded.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. London, Westminister, Southwark, &amp;c.; to be under the Management of Head Office.</head>
			<para id="p35">
				<emph type="i">Officers in the Country to be appointed by His Majesty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p36">And it is further Ena&bholigct;ed that all parts of the Cittyes of London and Westminster with the Burrough of
Southwarke and the severall Suburbs thereof and Parishes within the weekely Bills of Mortallity shall be
under the immediate care inspe&bholigct;ion and management of the said Head Office and such and soe many subordinate
Commissioners and Sub Commissioners and other Officers and Ministers for the Execution of the Premisses shall
be from time to time nominated and appointed by his Majestie in all and every other [the<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Countyes Cittyes
Townes and places within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Port of Berwicke as from time
to time his Majestie shall thinke fitt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Hours at which Excise Office to be kept open.</head>
			<para id="p37">And it is hereby further Ena&bholigct;ed that the said Office of Excise in all places where it shall be appointed shall
be kept open from eight of the clocke in the morning till twelve of the clocke at noone, and from two of the
clocke in the afternoone till five of the clocke in the afternoone for the due execution and performance of all
and every the matters and things in this A&bholigct; appointed and required.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Commissioners to pay Monies colle&bholigct;ed into Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p38">And it is further hereby Ena&bholigct;ed that the said cheife Commissioners of Excise or the major part of them
shall from time to time issue forth and pay such summe and summes of money as shall from time to time be
received colle&bholigct;ed or leavyed by vertue of this A&bholigct; unto his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Persons sued may plead the General Issue.</head>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p40">Provided alwayes and bee it Ena&bholigct;ed That if any person or persons shall at any time be sued or prosecuted for
any thing by him or them done or executed in pursuance of this A&bholigct; he or they shall and may plead the generall
issue and give this A&bholigct; in evidence for his defence, and if upon the tryall a Verdi&bholigct; shall passe for the Defendant
or Defendants; or the Plaintiffe or Plaintiffes be non suited then such Defendent or Defendents shall have double
Costs to him or them awarded against such Plaintiffe or Plaintiffes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Certiorari.</head>
			<para id="p41">Provided alsoe and be it Ena&bholigct;ed that noe Writt or Writts of Certiorari shall supersede Execution or other
Proceedings upon any Order or Orders made by the Justices aforesaid in pursuance of this A&bholigct;, but that Execution
and other Proceeding shall and may be had and made thereupon, Any such Writt or Writts or allowance thereof
notwithstanding,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Proviso for E. Backwell, for Payment of &pound;28,450.</head>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">When and to whom, and for what Purposes, the same advanced</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">Provided alwayes and be it further Ena&bholigct;ed that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not be prejudiciall
to Edward Backwell Alderman of London as to the summe of twenty eight thousand fower hundred and fifty
pound&bholngs; (or any part thereof) by him advanced upon the credit of severall Orders of this present Parliament, and
by them charged on the receipt of the Grand Excise, that is to say the summe of five thousand pound&bholngs; payable
to his Majestyes Surveyour Generall for the repaire of his Majestyes houses charged by vertue of an Order of the
sixth of September One thousand six hundred and sixty with Interest for the same, the summe of ten thousand
pound&bholngs; advanced to her Highnesse the Princesse Royall being charged with Interest by an Order of the thirteenth
of September One thousand six hundred and sixty, the summe of ten thousand pound&bholngs; payable to her Majestie
the Queene of Bohemia being charged together with Interest by an Order of the thirteenth of September One
thousand six hundred and sixty, the summe of three thousand fower hundred and fifty pound&bholngs; payable for Provisions
for Dunkirke by Order of the twenty sixth of November One thousand six hundred and sixty, which summe of
twenty eight thousand fower hundred and fifty pound&bholngs; together with Interest for the same according to the tenor of
the said Orders after the rate of six per cent. shall be paid to the said Edward Backwell or his Assignes out of
the Grand Excise and the Arreares thereof in course as is by the said Orders appointed, and in case the same shall fall
short in payment by the twenty fifth of December One thousand six hundred and sixty that then the remainder shall
continue secured to him out of the whole Excise in course as aforesaid, and that noe other payments be made
out of the Excise but what is appointed by this present Parliament in course to precede the same untill the
said Debt due to the said Edward Backwell be satisfied, and that in case any part of the moneyes due to Alderman
Backwell be paid out of that part of the Excise which shall grow due to the Kings Majestie that then his Majestie
shall be reimbursed the same out of the first moneyes that shall come in of the Arreares of Excise that will be
due the said twenty fifth of December.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">their <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">xv d. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">as <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Ale or Beere <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">to be <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


