<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47277" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the raiseing of seaventy thousand pounds for the further supply of his Majestie.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Grant of &pound; 70,000,</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">to be assessed in the manner and by the Commissioners appointed by c. 21. ante.; Commissioners to meet 5th July 1661, and execute the like Powers, &amp;c. as in the said A&bholigct; are mentioned.; </emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">THE Commons assembled in Parliament doe give and grant unto your most excellent Majestie the summe of
seaventy thousand pounds to be raised and leavyed in manner following and doe pray your Majestie that
it may be ena&bholigct;ed And Be it ena&bholigct;ed by your most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the
Lord&bholngs; and Commons in Parliament assembled that the summe of threescore and ten thousand pound&bholngs; for one
moneth onely begining from the first day of July One thousand six hundred sixtie and one shall be assessed taxed
colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid in the severall countyes cittyes burroughes townes and places within England and Wales
and the towne of Berwicke upon Tweede according to the severall rates rules and proportions and in such manner
and forme and by the same Commissioners as in and by a certaine other A&bholigct; passed this parliament for raiseing the
like summe of seaventy thousand pound&bholngs; for one moneth onely begining from the twenty ninth of September One
thousand six hundred and sixty entituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy raiseing of seaventy thousand pound&bholngs; for the
present supply of his Majestie, are mentioned or referred unto and intended which Commissioners shall meete upon or before the fifth day of July One thousand six hundred sixtie and one, and are hereby enabled and required to
use and execute all and every the like powers and authorities as in and by the said A&bholigct; are mentioned, or referred
to and intended as fully and amply as if the same rates rules proportions powers and authorityes had beene
perticularly inserted in this present A&bholigct;,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Monies raised to be paid by Receivers General into the Exchequer 1st August 1661.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that all and every the summes of money charged by this
A&bholigct; upon the severall Countyes Cittyes Townes Burroughs and places aforesaid shall be raised levyed and paid
into his Majestyes receipt of the Exchequer upon or before the first day of August One thousand six hundred sixty
one by the severall Receivers Generall who shall be appointed by the said Commissioners.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Lands, &amp;c. in the Possession of the King or Queen, or of Ecclesiastical Persons, and formerly assessed.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes And it is hereby declared that noe Mannors Land&bholngs; Tenements and Hereditaments which were
formerly assessed and taxed for and toward&bholngs; former assessments and Land taxes and are now in the possession or
holding of his Majestie or of the Queenes Highnes or of any ecclesiasticall person or persons, or his [her<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] or their
farmers and tennants shall be exempted from the [pay&bhomsst; of y<emph type="p">e</emph>
				<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] severall summes of money in this Act comprised,
but that the said Mannours Land&bholngs; Tenements and Hereditaments shall be rated assessed, and taxed for and toward&bholngs;
the said severall summes of money in this Act comprized in such manner and forme as they were of late rated
taxed and assessed for and toward&bholngs; the said former land rates, Any law statute or custome to the contrary thereof
in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Peers.</head>
			<para id="p5">[Provided allwayes that neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall be drawne into example to the
prejudice of the auntient rights belonging to the Peeres of this Realme,<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Commissioners added for the several Counties, &amp;c. herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p6">And be it declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that these persons hereafter named shall be added
Commissioners for their severall Countyes places and precin&bholigct;s respe&bholigct;ively and shall exercise the same powers
as the other C&bhooov;missioners intended by this A&bholigct; are authorized and impowered to doe that is to say</para>
			<para id="p7">Berks</para>
			<para id="p8">For the County of Berks Peregrine Hobby Richard Harrison Esquiers, John Fettiplace of Ferneham Esquire and
Samuell Woodcox.</para>
			<para id="p9">Burrough of New Windsor</para>
			<para id="p10">For the Burrough of New Windsor Andrew Plumpton Richard Fishborne Gent.</para>
			<para id="p11">Bucks</para>
			<para id="p12">For the County of Bucks William Tirringham Esquire Sir Thomas Hampson Baronet Sir Phillip Palmer Baronet
Thomas Ratcliffe Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p13">Cambridge</para>
			<para id="p14">For the County of Cambridge Sir Thomas Dayrell John Bennet Esquire Sir Anthony Cage Levinus Bennet.</para>
			<para id="p15">Isle of Ely</para>
			<para id="p16">For the Isle of Ely Roger Jennings Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p17">Chester</para>
			<para id="p18">For the County of Chester Sir George Warburton Baronet Edward Warren (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) Jeffery Shakerley (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) Henry
Leigh [Esquiers.<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p19">Citty of Chester</para>
			<para id="p20">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester The Maior for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p21">Cornewall</para>
			<para id="p22">For the County of Cornewall Robert Roberts Es&bhoqesq; Sir William Tredingham Joseph Tredingham Thomas
Penhallow The Knights and Burgesses that serve for the said County and James Eirsey Gent. The Maior of Lostwithell
for the time being John Mollesworth Es&bhoqesq; William Williams of Trevithen.</para>
			<para id="p23">Cumberland</para>
			<para id="p24">For the County of Cumberland M<emph type="p">r</emph> Anthony Bouch M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Uriell M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Croswhat M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Webster.</para>
			<para id="p25">Devon</para>
			<para id="p26">For the County of Devon Nicholas Davies Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke William Jennens Gent. Edmond Tremaine (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) William
Putt (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) John Kellond (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) William Bogan (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) George Howard (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) John Kelley (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) James Rodd [Esquiers<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Walter
Jago Francis Drew Es&bhoqesq; William Walrond Esquire John Blagdon Gent. John Hamm Gent. Henry Newte</para>
			<para id="p27">Yorke</para>
			<para id="p28">For the West Riding in the County of Yorke Wellbury Norton (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) Robert Wivel [Esquiers<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Richard Roundhill
Gent. William Hamond (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) Walter Hawkesworth [Esquiers<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Cuthbert Wade John Preston Gent. Arthur Ingram
Esquire Edward Atkinson William Witham Gent. Samuell Sunderland Esquire Thomas Ward Gent. Sir William
Ingram Knight Sir John Goodricke Baronet Sir Thomas Wentworth (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) Sir Edward Rodes (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) Godfrey Copley of
Sprotsbrough John Claiton Josua Horton Thomas Stringer Esquiers The Alderman of Leedes for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p29">Yorke North Rideing</para>
			<para id="p30">For the North Rideing in the County of Yorke Sir William Caley Arthur Caley Es&bhoqesq; William Wivell Es&bhoqesq;
Sir Thomas Gower Baronet Thomas Worsley (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) Charles Tankred [Esquiers<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Sir William Franklin Baronet The
Bailiffes of Scarborough for the time being Tristram Fish Robert Belt Esquiers Thomas Robinson Thomas
Scudamore Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p31">Yorke Citty</para>
			<para id="p32">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke All the Aldermen of the Citty of Yorke.</para>
			<para id="p33">Kingston upon Hull</para>
			<para id="p34">For the Towne of Kingston upon Hull M<emph type="p">r</emph> George Crowle</para>
			<para id="p35">Essex</para>
			<para id="p36">For the County of Essex M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Glascock M<emph type="p">r</emph> Miles Hubbert M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Smart Captaine Hunter Deane
Tindell Es&bhoqesq; Isaac Wincall Thomas Clopton Thomas Peek Peter Johnson Thomas Manby Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p37">Glocester</para>
			<para id="p38">For the County of Glocester Thomas Freame Thomas [Floid<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Samuell Sheppard Phillip Sheppard William
Morgan Richard Daston John Tooke Esquiers Robert Lord Tracy Thomas Morgan Es&bhoqesq; Sir Nicholas Throckmorton
Knight William Bromage Gent. William Winter of Dimmock Gent. Richard Matchen Gent. John Winnyat Gent.
Thomas Aylway Gent..</para>
			<para id="p39">Hereford</para>
			<para id="p40">For the County of Hereford Sir Herbert Parret Knight, John Barnaby of Brookehampton Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Baskervile
of Collington Gent., John Booth of Hereford Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p41">Citty of Hereford</para>
			<para id="p42">For the Citty of Hereford Thomas Davies Es&bhoqesq; Maior, James Lawrence Gent. Thomas Clerke Gent..</para>
			<para id="p43">Hertford</para>
			<para id="p44">For the County of Hertford Marmaduke Rawden James Willimot junior Gent. Thomas Arras Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke
Richard Combes Es&bhoqesq; Sir Robert Joslin Knight Thomas Coppin Edward Briscoe John Halsie Esquiers M<emph type="p">r</emph> Fetherston
of Blakeswere Edward Brograve Ralph Gore Thomas Brograve Edward Cason Thomas Bonest Henry Becher
Henry Chauncey George Bromley Alexander Meade John Crouch James Willimot junior George Poyner Gent.
John Jesson Esquire Sir Edward Alston Knight.</para>
			<para id="p45">S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albanes</para>
			<para id="p46">For the Burrough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albanes William Foxwist Esquire Recorder M<emph type="p">r</emph> John New M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Eames M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas
Cowley senior M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Marston Sir Henry Conningsby Edmond Smith Alban Cox Richard Combes Es&bhoqesq;
Thomas Marston Gent..</para>
			<para id="p47">Kent</para>
			<para id="p48">For the County of Kent Sir William Mann Sir Edward Masters Thomas Peake Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Godfrey The
Maior of Maidston for the time being Sir William Merideth Baronet Sir Thomas Peirse Baronet M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Manley
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Manley.</para>
			<para id="p49">Sandwich</para>
			<para id="p50">For the Towne of Sandwich John Verrier, Peter Peke Gent..</para>
			<para id="p51">Lancaster</para>
			<para id="p52">For the County of Lancaster Henry Banister Es&bhoqesq; Jeofrey Rushton Gent. Richard Fleetwood Gent. John Mollineux Es&bhoqesq;
William Fife Es&bhoqesq; Sir George Midleton Knight and Baronet Mathew Richardson Es&bhoqesq; Robert Heywood Es&bhoqesq; Roger
Stowton of the Citty of London Thomas Butler Richard Farrington William Wall William Turner Henry Brabin
William [Hodgekenson<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Gent..</para>
			<para id="p53">Lincolne</para>
			<para id="p54">For the County of Lincolne and Citty and County of the same Edward Turney (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) William Lister [Esquiers<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]
Sir Robert Dallison Baronet Sir Charles Dallison Knight William Draper Samuell Pro&bholigct;or William Thompson
Humphrey Walcot Thomas Mills Michaell Dalton John Watson William Willoughby Henry Heron Marmaduke
Darrell John Ogle Anthony Treadway William Skipwith Thomas Browne of East Kirby John Almore M<emph type="p">r</emph> Skinner
of Thornton Colledge Thomas Harrington William Whichcot Charles Pelham junior Roger Pelham M<emph type="p">r</emph> John
Lockton M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Hobson junior M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Hall M<emph type="p">r</emph> Charles Bawdes M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Colthurst M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Bishop and
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Blaw Aldermen M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Perkins M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Mills M<emph type="p">r</emph> Peregrine Bucke M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Dowman
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Dickenson M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Thornton and Richard Wetherell Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p55">London</para>
			<para id="p56">For the Citty of London Nicholas Delves Es&bhoqesq; Benjamin Albin Richard Spencer.</para>
			<para id="p57">Midlesex</para>
			<para id="p58">For the County of Midlesex Sir John Robinson Baronet Leiutenant of the Tower Sir Richard Browne Thomas
Bide Thomas Harrison of South Mims Sir William Bateman Leiutenant Collonell Powell Charles Pittfield Es&bhoqesq;
Robert Peyton John Jones John Limbrey Edward Chard Richard Shelton [Esquiers<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] William Page Es&bhoqesq; Roger
Jennens Es&bhoqesq; Sir Heneage Finch Baronet his Majestyes Sollicitor Generall, Cheney of Hackney Es&bhoqesq;
Leiutenant Collonell Powell Charles Cheney of Chelsey Christopher Abdy Es&bhoqesq; Sir Allen Broadricke John
Barton Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p59">Westminster</para>
			<para id="p60">For the Citty of Westminster and Liberties thereof Gabriell Becke Es&bhoqesq; M<emph type="p">r</emph> Graham Peter Maplesden George
Plunknet Thomas Kirke William Greene George Farewell Ralph Darnell</para>
			<para id="p61">Monmouth</para>
			<para id="p62">For the County of Monmouth William Jones of Frowen Es&bhoqesq; James Proger Charles Proger.</para>
			<para id="p63">Northampton</para>
			<para id="p64">For the County of Northampton Edward Onely (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) John Thornton (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) John Willoughby [Esquiers.<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p65">Norffolke</para>
			<para id="p66">For the County of Norffolke George Windham Robert Doughty of Hanworth (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) Robert Legar [Esquiers<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Henry
Scarborough Gent. M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Repps M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Talbot M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Blackborne Gent..</para>
			<para id="p67">Burrough of Lyn Regis</para>
			<para id="p68">For the Burrough of Lyn Regis John Basset Maior Robert Steward Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Thomas Greene William
Wharton Henry Bell Robert Thorowgood Alderman Holley.</para>
			<para id="p69">Great Yarmouth</para>
			<para id="p70">For the Towne of Great Yarmouth Nicholas Cutting James Simond&bholngs; Bailiffes there Sir John Potts Knight and
Baronet Sir William Doyley Knight Sir Thomas Medow Knight Thomas Gooch George England John Carter
Nathaniell Ashby Thomas Lucas John Woodroffe James Johnson Esquiers George Tilyard Gent..</para>
			<para id="p71">Theftford</para>
			<para id="p72">For the whole Burrough and Corporation of Theftford The Maior for the time being M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Kendall Gent.
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Bourage Martin Maurice Shelton Esquire [M<emph type="p">r</emph>
				<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Robert Keddington Gent. M<emph type="p">r</emph> Nicholas Rookewood M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert
Wright of Kilveston.</para>
			<para id="p73">Newcastle upon Tine</para>
			<para id="p74">For the Towne and County of Newcastle upon Tine Sir John Marley Sir Nicholas Cole Knight and Baronet Sir
Francis Bows Knight Sir Francis Anderson Knight.</para>
			<para id="p75">Nottingham</para>
			<para id="p76">For the County of Nottingham Francis Sandis Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Bristow (<ref idref="n10">10</ref>) William Newton [Gentlemen.<ref idref="n10">10</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p77">East Retford</para>
			<para id="p78">For the Burrough of East Retford The Bailiffes for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p79">Oxon</para>
			<para id="p80">For the County of Oxon William Glin (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) John West [Esquiers<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] John Coker Gent. James Herbert Es&bhoqesq; Sir
Thomas Tippin.</para>
			<para id="p81">University of Oxford</para>
			<para id="p82">M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Withers M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Master M<emph type="p">r</emph> David Thomas M<emph type="p">r</emph> Gregory Ballard M<emph type="p">r</emph> Timothy Horton.</para>
			<para id="p83">The Citty of Oxford</para>
			<para id="p84">For the Citty of Oxford Francis Holloway William Cornish</para>
			<para id="p85">Salop</para>
			<para id="p86">For the County of Salop Charles Baldwin(<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) Samuel Baldwin [Esquiers<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> Moore of Midleton M<emph type="p">r</emph> [Bishop<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] of
the Moore Benjamin Buckley.</para>
			<para id="p87">Stafford</para>
			<para id="p88">For the County of Stafford Thomas Rudiard Es&bhoqesq; John Colclough (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Timothy Edge [Gentlemen.<ref idref="n13">13</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p89">Somerset</para>
			<para id="p90">For the County of Somerset William Orange Es&bhoqesq; William Bacon Senior Gent. John Cridland Gent. Mawdley
Samborne (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) John Carew (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) Roger Newborough (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) James Haise [Esquiers.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p91">For the Citty of Bristoll</para>
			<para id="p92">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll The Maior and Sheriffes for the time being John Knight the
elder William Coulston John Bradway William Coles.</para>
			<para id="p93">For the Citty of Bath</para>
			<para id="p94">For the Citty of Bath John Peirce John Masters Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p95">Southampton</para>
			<para id="p96">For the County of Southampton with the Towne and County M<emph type="p">r</emph> Essex Powlet Richard Lucy (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) Gabriel Whistler
[Esquiers.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p97">Isle of Wight</para>
			<para id="p98">For the Isle of Wight Thomas Bowreman Es&bhoqesq; John Oglander of Newport Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p99">Suffolke</para>
			<para id="p100">For the County of Suffolke George Winiffe William Blumfield Esquiers [Isaac Motham Es&bhoqesq; Gardiner Web
Gent.
				<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Brooke M<emph type="p">r</emph> Milton of Ipswich M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edmond Bedingfield M<emph type="p">r</emph> Francis Langley M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Read M<emph type="p">r</emph> Rabbit
of Bramfield.</para>
			<para id="p101">S<emph type="p">t</emph> Edmond&bholngs; Bury</para>
			<para id="p102">For S<emph type="p">t</emph> Edmonds Bury Francis Smith Robert Sharpe Samuell Hustler.</para>
			<para id="p103">Surrey</para>
			<para id="p104">For the County of Surrey Edward Evelin (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) John Yates (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) Richard [Knippe Esquiers<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Parker Sir
Purbecke Temple (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Sir Thomas Bludworth [Knights<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Thomas Rogers (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) Charles Good Harmon Atwood Esquiers
(<ref idref="n18">18</ref>) John Parker of Rigate.</para>
			<para id="p105">Rie in the County of Sussex</para>
			<para id="p106">For the Towne of Rie Samuell [Pembrig<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] James Welsh Thomas Osmonton.</para>
			<para id="p107">Worcester</para>
			<para id="p108">For the County of Worcester Sir John Packington Baronet Sir Rowland Berkley Knight Sir John Windford
Knight Samuell Sandis (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) Henry Townsend (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) John Bearecroft [Esquiers<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Sir Ralph Clare Knight of the Bath.</para>
			<para id="p109">Worcester Citty</para>
			<para id="p110">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester Edward Soley Alderman Samuell Smith (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Thomas Twitty
[Gentlemen<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Henry Townsend Es&bhoqesq; Sir William Moreton Knight Humphrey Tyrer (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Richard Heming (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Stephen
Richardson [Gentlemen<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Sir John Packington Sir Rowland Berkeley Sir Ralph Clare Sir John Winford Samuell
Sandis Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p111">Warwicke</para>
			<para id="p112">For the County of Warwicke Lister of Alveston Es&bhoqesq; Richard Bishop of Stratford Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p113">Coventry</para>
			<para id="p114">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry Sir Arthur Caley Knight The Maior of Coventry for the time
being Henry Smith Alderman Sir Richard Hopkins Knight William Jesson (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Thomas Norton [Esquiers<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas
Love (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Mathew Smith (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Samuell Snell (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) William Jelliffe (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Robert Beake (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) James Nailer [Aldermen.<ref idref="n21">21</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p115">Towne of Warwicke</para>
			<para id="p116">For the Towne of Warwicke Sir Henry Puckering Baronet Sir Clement Throckmorton Knight John Rouse (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>)
Nathaniell [Stounton<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] John Stanton [Esquiers<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Lister of Alveston Es&bhoqesq; Richard Bishop of Stratford.</para>
			<para id="p117">Wilts</para>
			<para id="p118">For the County of Wilts Walter Buckland (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Thomas Mompesson (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) William Caley [Esquiers<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Mathew Rayman
Gent. Thomas Hunt Gent. Robert Chaundler Robert Nicholas of Alcainings William Broomewich t. Samuell Eyre
Gent. Simon Spatchurst Esquire Christopher Gardiner Gent. M<emph type="p">r</emph> Francis Parry.</para>
			<para id="p119">Sarum</para>
			<para id="p120">For the Citty of New Sarum Samuell Eyre Gent. Simon Spatchurst Es&bhoqesq; Christopher Gardiner Gent.
			</para>
			<para id="p121">Anglesey</para>
			<para id="p122">For the Isle of Anglesey Robert Lord Viscount Bulkley.</para>
			<para id="p123">Cardigan</para>
			<para id="p124">For the County of Cardigan James Phillips (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Morgan Herbert (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Thomas Jenkins (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Erasmus Lloyde (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Thomas
Evans (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Henry Vaughan Thomas Price the Elder (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Thomas Lloyde of Yinshen (<ref idref="n23">23</ref>) Morrice Vaughon (<ref idref="n23">23</ref>) John Price
[Gentlemen<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Thomas Parry Reighnold Jenkins John Bowen Thomas Lewis He&bholigct;or Phillips Nicholas Lewis William
Jones Abell Griffin Esquiers Wa&bholigct;kin Lloyde (<ref idref="n23">23</ref>) John Griffith of Noyadd [Gentlemen<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] The Maior of Cardigan for
the time being Rees Guyn David Morgan Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p125">Carmarthen</para>
			<para id="p126">For the County of Carmarthen Jonathan Lloyde Walter Lloyde Walter Mansell.</para>
			<para id="p127">Carnarvon</para>
			<para id="p128">For the County of Carnarvon Griffith Bodurda John Lloyde of Nangwiniadale Robert Winn of Conway William
Wynn of Pengwoone William Thomas of Carnarvon Jonathan Lloyde Walter Lloyde Walter Mansell.</para>
			<para id="p129">Denbigh</para>
			<para id="p130">For the County of Denbigh Francis Manley Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p131">Flint</para>
			<para id="p132">For the County of Flint Kenricke Eaton Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p133">Glamorgan</para>
			<para id="p134">For the County of Glamorgan John Price of Courtcarne Morgan Morgan Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p135">Mountgomery</para>
			<para id="p136">For the County of Mountgomery William Oakely Edmond Wareing David Morrice Esquiers John Mathewes
Henry Pursall John Kiffin William Price of Lanligan John Lloyde of Conway.</para>
			<para id="p137">Haverford West</para>
			<para id="p138">For the Towne and County of Haverford West Sir Herbert Perrot Knight William Browne Alderman.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Es&bhoqesq;
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Es&bhoqesq;
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Lloyde <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Hodginson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Es&bhoqesq;
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Gent.
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Es&bhoqesq;
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">Bushop <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">Gent.
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Knipe Es&bhoqesq;
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">Knight <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">M<emph type="p">r</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">Bembrigg <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">Es&bhoqesq;
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">Alderman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">Stoughton Es&bhoqesq;
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">Gent.
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

