<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47274" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the levying of the Arreares of the twelve moneths Assessment commenceing the fower and twentyeth [day] of June One thousand six hundred fifty nine, and the six moneths Assessment commenceing the five and twentyeth [day] of December One thousand sixe hundred fifty nine.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that there are Arrears and Sums of Money upon the Assessment herein mentioned in the Hands of Collectors, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners for disbanding the Army to cause Arrears and Sums of Money in Collectors Hands to be levied and paid to the late Treasurers at War.; Proviso for certain Disbursements herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas there are severall great Summes of money yet uncolle&bholigct;ed and in arreare, and diverse Summes
of money in the hand&bholngs; of the Colle&bholigct;ors and not paid in; due upon the twelve monethes Assessment
commencing the twenty fourth of June One thousand six hundred fifty nine, and upon the six monethes
Assessment commencing the twenty fifth of December One thousand six hundred fifty nine for payment of the
Arreares of His Majestyes Army now disbanding and to be disbanded notwithstanding all former orders, and His
Majesties Proclamation for the speedy levying and colle&bholigct;ing thereof. Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
excellent Majestie and the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authoritie of the
same that the Commissioners nominated and appointed in the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes and Corporations of this
Kingdome, the Dominion of Wales and the Towne of Berwicke in an A&bholigct; made this present Parliament for the
speedy provision of money for disbanding and paying off the Forces of this Kingdome both by Land and Sea, doe
forthwith cause all the said Arreares to be leavyed and colle&bholigct;ed by such wayes and meanes as the same was formerly
appointed to be levyed and colle&bholigct;ed, and likewise all such summes of money as remaine in any Colle&bholigct;ors hand&bholngs;
to be speedily paid in to James Nelthorp and John Lawson Esquiers late Treasurers at Warr for and toward&bholngs; the
speedy disbanding and paying off the said Forces, Provided alwayes that the Summe of five hundred and twenty
pound&bholngs; and twelve shillings disbursed by Robert Quarum Receiver Generall of the County of Cornwall by the
desire and direction of the Commissioners of the Assessments and other gentlemen of the said County for the
publique Service of the Kingdome. And alsoe the Summe of seaventy pound&bholngs; disbursed by the Towne of Lyme
Regis in the County of Dorcet for the same Service shall be and are hereby discharged and allowed unto the said
Receiver and Towne of Lyme Regis as if the same had beene a&bholigct;ually paid into the Treasurers appointed to
receive the same. Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
	</section>
</report>

