<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47272" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>An Act takeing away the Court of Wards and Liveries and Tenures in Capite and by Knights Service and Purveyance, and for setling a Revenue upon his Majesty in Lieu thereof.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1"><head>The Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1"><emph type="i">The Court of Wards and Liveries, Primer-Seizin, &amp;c. taken away.; Fines for Alienation, &amp;c. taken away.; Tenures by Knights Service, and Tenures in Capite taken away.; Tenures herein mentioned turned into free and common Socage</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS it hath beene found by former experience that the Courts of Ward&bholngs; and Liveries and Tenures
by Knights service either of the King or others, or by Knights service in Capite or Soccage in Capite of
the King and the consequents upon the same have beene much more burthensome grievous and prejudiciall to
the Kingdome then they have beene beneficiall to the King, And whereas since the Intermission of the said Court
which hath beene from the fower and twentyeth day of February which was in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred forty and five many persons have by Will and otherwise made disposall of their Land&bholngs; held by Knight
service whereupon diverse Questions might possibly arise unlesse some seasonable remedy be taken to prevent the
same Bee it therefore Ena&bholigct;ed by the King our Soveraigne Lord with the assent of the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in
Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same And it is hereby Ena&bholigct;ed That the Court of Ward&bholngs; and
Liveries an`d all Wardships Liveries Primer-Seizins and Ouster-le-mains values and forfeitures of Marriages by reason
of any Tenure of the Kings Majesty or of any other by Knights service and all meane Rates and all other Gifts
Grants Charges incident or ariseing for or by reason of Wardships Liveries Primer Seizins or Ouster-le-main, be
taken away and discharged and are hereby Ena&bholigct;ed to be taken away and discharged from the said twenty fourth day
of February One thousand six hundred forty five, any Law, Statute Custome or Usage to the contrary hereof [in<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
any wise notwithstanding, And that all Fines for Alienation Seizures and Pardons for Alienations Tenure by Homage
and all Charges incident or ariseing for or by reason of Wardship Livery Primer-Seizin or Ouster-le-main or Tenure
by Knights service Escuage and also Aide pur file marrier et pur faier fitz Chivalier and all other Charges incident
therunto be likewise taken away and discharged from the said twenty fourth day of February One thousand six
hundred forty and five, Any Law Statute Custome or Usage to the contrary hereof [in<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] any wise notwithstanding,
And that all Tenures by Knights service of the King, or of any other person and by Knights service in Capite, and
by Soccage in Capite of the King and the fruits and consequents thereof happened or which shall or may hereafter
happen or arise thereupon or thereby be taken away and discharged Any Law Statute Custome or Usage to the
contrary hereof any wise notwithstanding, And all Tenures of any Honours Mannours Land&bholngs; Tenements or
Hereditaments of any Estate of Inheritance at the common Law held either of the King or of any other person or
persons Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate are hereby Ena&bholigct;ed to be turned into free and common Soccage to all
intents and purposes from the said [twenty fourth<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] day of February One thousand six hundred forty five, and shall be
soe construed adjudged and deemed to be from the said twenty fourth day of February One thousand six hundred
forty five, and for ever thereafter turned into free and common Soccage, Any Law Statute Custome or Usage to
the contrary hereof [any wise<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. And discharged of Homage, Escuage, Aide pur file marrier, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Conveyances expounded as if Manors, &amp;c. had been held in common Socage</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And that the same shall for ever hereafter stand and be discharged of all Tenure by Homage Escuage Voyages
Royall and charges for the same Wardships incident to Tenure by Knights service and values and forfeitures of
marriage and all other charges incident to tenure by Knights service And of and from Aide pur file marrier &amp; Aide
pur faier fitz Chivalier Any Law Statute Custome or Usage to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding. And that
all conveyances and devises of any Mannours Land&bholngs; Tenements and Hereditaments made since the said twenty
fourth of February shall be expounded to be of such effe&bholigct; as if the same Mannours Land&bholngs; Tenements and
Hereditaments had beene then held and continued to be holden in free and common Soccage onely Any Law
Statute Custome or usage to the contrary hereof any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. 32 H. VIII.c. 46. and 33 H. VIII. c. 22. repealed.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further Ordained and Enacted by Authority of this present Parliament that one A&bholigct; made in
the raigne of King Henry the Eight intituled An A&bholigct; for the establishment of the Court of the Kings Ward&bholngs;,
And alsoe one A&bholigct; of Parliament made in the three and thirtyeth yeare of the Raigne of the said King Henry the
Eighth concerning the Officers of the Court of Ward&bholngs; and Liveries and every Clause Article and matter in the
said A&bholigct;s contained shall from henceforth be repealed and utterly void.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. All Tenures to be created by the King hereafter to be in free and common Socage.</head>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that all tenures hereafter to be created by the Kings
Majestie his Heires or Successors upon any gifts or grants of any Mannours Land&bholngs; Tenements or Hereditaments of
any Estate of Inheritance at the common Law shall be in free and common Soccage, and shall be adjudged to be
in free and common Soccage onely, and not by Knight service or in Capite, and shall be discharged of all
Wardship value and forfeiture of Marriage Livery Primer-Seizin Ouster le main Aide pur faier fitz Chivalier &amp;
pur file marrier, Any Law Statute or reservation to the contrary thereof any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Rents certain, Heriots, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided neverthelesse and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; or any thing herein contayned shall not take away
nor be construed to take away any Rents certaine Herriots or Suites of Court belonging or incident to any former
Tenure now taken away or altered by vertue of this A&bholigct;s, or other Services incident or belonging to Tenure in
common Soccage due, or to grow due to the Kings Majestie or meane Lord&bholngs;s or other private person, or the
fealty and distresses incident thereunto, And that such releife shall be paid in respect of such Rents as is paid
in case of a death of a Tennant in common Soccage,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. For Fines for Alienation by Customs of Manors. Exception.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided alwayes and bee it Ena&bholigct;ed That any thing herein contayned shall not take away nor be construed
to take away any Fines for Alienation due by perticular customes of perticular Mannours and places other then
Fines for Alienations of Land&bholngs; or Tenements holden immediately of the King in Capite.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. For Tenures in Frank Almoigne.</head>
			<para id="p9"><emph type="i">Tenure by Copy of Court Roll; and for Honorary Services.; Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">Provided alsoe and be it further Ena&bholigct;ed that this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained shall not take away or
be construed to take away Tenures in Franke Almoigne or [to<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] subje&bholigct; them to any greater or other services then
they now are, nor to alter or change any Tenure by Copy of Court Roll or any services incident thereunto nor
to take away the honorary services of Grand Sergeantie other then of Wardship Marriage and value of Forfeiture
of Marriage Escuage Voyages Royall and other charges incident to Tenure by Knights Service and other then
Aide pur faier fitz Chivalier and Aide pur file marrier.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Fathers may dispose of the Custody of Children during their Minority.</head>
			<para id="p11"><emph type="i">Except Popish Recusants.; A&bholigct;ions of Ravishment of Ward for Guardians</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that where any person hath or shall have any Child
or Children under the age of twenty one yeares and not married at the time of his death that it shall and may be
lawfull to and for the Father of such child or children, [whether borne at the time of the decease of the Father
or at that time in ventre sa mere, or whether such Father be within the age<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] of twenty one yeares or of full age
by his deed executed in his life time, or by his last Will and Testament in writeing in the presence of two or more
credible witnesses in such manner and from time to time as he shall respe&bholigct;ively thinke fitt to dispose of the custody
and tuition of such child or children for and dureing such time as he or they shall respe&bholigct;ively remaine under the
age of twenty one yeares or any lesser time to any person or persons in possession or remainder other then Popish
Recusants, And that such disposition of the custodie of such childe or children made since the twenty fourth of
February One thousand six hundred forty five or hereafter to be made shall be good and effe&bholigct;uall against all and
every person or persons claiming the custody or tuition of such childe or children as Guardian in soccage or
otherwise; And that such person or persons to whom the custodie of such childe or children hath beene or shall
be soe disposed or devised as aforesaid shall and may maintaine an a&bholigct;ion of Ravishment of Ward or trespasse
against any person or persons which shall wrongfully take away or detaine such child or children for the Recovery
of such childe or children and shall and may recover damages for the same in the said A&bholigct;ion for the use and
benefit of such childe or children.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Custody of Lands and Personal Estate of Children, in Guardians, who may bring A&bholigct;ion, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p13"><emph type="i">Proviso for London and other Places as to Orphans; and for Apprentices</emph></para>
			<para id="p14">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That such Person or Persons to whom the custody of such Childe or Children hath
beene or shall be soe disposed or devised shall and may take into his or their custody to the use of such Childe
or Children the proffitts of all Land&bholngs; Tenements &amp; Hereditaments of such Childe or Children, and alsoe the custody
tuition and mannagment of the Good&bholngs; Chattells and personall Estate of such Childe or Children till their respe&bholigct;ive
Age of twenty one yeares or any lesser time according to such disposition aforesaid, and may bring such A&bholigct;ion
or A&bholigct;ions in relation thereunto as by Law a Guardian in common soccage might doe Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct;
or any thing therein contained shall not extend to alter or prejudice the Custome of the Citty of London, nor of
any other Citty or Towne Corporate, or of the Towne of Berwicke on Tweede concerning Orphans, nor to discharge
any [Apprintice<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] from his [Apprintiship<ref idref="n7">7</ref>].</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Proviso touching Titles of Honour, Feodal, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p15">[Provided alsoe That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall infringe or hurt any Title of Honour
Feodall or other by which any Person hath or may have right to sitt in the Lord&bholngs; of Parliament as to his
or their Title of Honour or sitting in Parliament, and the priviledge belonging to them as Peeres. This A&bholigct; or any
thing therein contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>.]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Recital that Laws had been passed to remedy the Mischiefs of Purveyance, but that divers Oppressions had still been continued.</head>
			<para id="p16"><emph type="i">Purveyances and Provisions for the King's Household taken away; Purveyances for the King, Queen, &amp;c. of Tumber, Carts, Carriages, &amp;c. taken away</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And whereas by like experience it hath beene found that though diverse good stri&bholigct; and wholesome Lawes have
beene made in the times of sundry His Majestyes most noble Progenitors some extending soe farr as to life for
Redresse of the grieviances and oppressions committed by the Persons imployed for makeing provisions for the
Kings Household Carriages and other purveyance for his Majestie and His occasions, Yet diverse oppressions have
beene still continued and severall Countyes have submitted themselves to sundry Rates and Taxes and Compositions
to redeeme themselves from such vexations and oppressions And for as much as the Lord&bholngs;Commons assembled
in Parliament doe finde that the said Remedies are not fully effe&bholigct;uall, and that noe other remedy will be soe
effe&bholigct;uall and just as to take away the occasion thereof especially if satisfa&bholigct;ion and recompence shall be therefore
made to His Majesty His Heires and Successors which is hereby provided to His Majestyes good likeing and content,
His Majestie is therefore gratiously pleased that it may be ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lord&bholngs;Commons in this present Parliament assembled That
from henceforth noe summe or summes of money or other thing shall be taken raised taxed rated imposed paid
or leavyed for or in regard of any provision Carriages or purveyance for His Majestie His Heires or Successors
And that henceforth noe person or persons by any Warrant Commission or Authoritie under the Great Seale or
otherwise by colour of buying or makeing provision or purveyance for His Majestie, or any Queene of England
for the time being [or of any the Children of any King or Queene of England for the time being<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] or that
shall be or for his their or any of their Household shall take any Timber Fewell Catle Corne Grain Mault
Hay Straw Victuall Cart Carriage or other thing whatsoever of any the Subje&bholigct;s of His Majestie His Heires
or Successors without the free and full consent of the Owner or Owners thereof had and obtained without
menace or enforcement, nor shall summon warne take use or require any [of<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] the said Subjects to furnish or
finde any Horses Oxen or other [ Cattell<ref idref="n8">8</ref> ] Carts Ploughs Waines or other carriages for the use of His Majestie His
Heires or Successors or of any Queene (<ref idref="n10">10</ref>) of any childe or children of any the Kings or Queenes of England for the
time being for the carrying the Good&bholngs;s Majestie His Heires or Successors or the said Queenes or Children
or any of them without such full and free consent as aforesaid Any Law Statute Custome or Usage to the contrary
notwithstanding,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. No Pre-emption to be allowed or claimed in behalf of the King, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p18"><emph type="i">Persons making Purveyance.; Imprisonment till next Session, and then Indi&bholigct;ment; A&bholigct;ion for Inhabitants, &amp;c.; No such A&bholigct;ion to be stayed but by Order of the Court where such A&bholigct;ion depends.; Premunire; 16 R. II c. 5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That noe preemption shall be allowed or claimed in the behalfe of His Majesty or of
any His Heires or Successors or of any the Queenes of England, or of any the children of the Royall Family for
the time being in Market or out of Market, but that it be for ever hereafter free to all and every of the Subje&bholigct;s
of His Majestie to sell dispose or imploy his said Good&bholngs; to any other person or persons as him listeth, Any pretence
of makeing provision or purveyance of Vi&bholigct;uall Carriages or other thing for His Majestie His Heires or Successors
or of the said Queenes, or Children, or any pretence of preemption in their or any of their behalfes notwithstanding;
And if any person or persons shall make provision or purveyance for His Majestie His Heires or Successors or
any the Queenes or Children aforesaid, or impresse or take any such Carriages or other things aforesaid on any
pretence or colour of any Warrant aforesaid under the Great Seale or otherwise contrary to the intent hereof It
shall be lawfull for the Justices of Peace or such two or one of them as dwell neere, and to the Constables of
such Parish or Village where such occasion shall happen at the request of the party grieved, And they are
hereby enjoyned to committ, or cause to be committed the party or partyes soe doeing and offending to Goale till
the next Sessions there to be indi&bholigct;ed and proceeded against for the same, and that the Officers and Inhabitants
of the Village or Parish where such offence shall happen shall be assistant therein, and moreover the party grieved
shall have his action or actions against such offender or offenders, and therein recover his treble damages and
treble costs, In which A&bholigct;ion noe Essoigne Wager of Law Aid Prior Priviledge Prote&bholigct;ion Imparlance Injun&bholigct;ion
or Order of Restraint shall be granted or allowed, And if any person or persons shall (after notice given that
the A&bholigct;ion [depending<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] is grounded upon this Statute) cause or procure any a&bholigct;ion at the Common Law grounded
on this Statute to be delayed or staid before Judgement by colour or meanes of any Order Power Warrant or
Authority save onely of the Court where such A&bholigct;ion shall be brought and depending, or after Judgement had
upon such A&bholigct;ion shall cause or procure Execution of such Judgement to be staid or delayed by colour or
meanes of any Order Warrant Power or Authority save onely by Writt of Error or Attaint, or Order of such
Court where such Writt of Error or Attaint shall be depending, That then the person soe offending shall incurr
the paines penaltyes and forfeitures ordained and provided by the Statute of Provision and Premunire made in the
sixteenth yeare of the Raigne of King Richard the second.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for the Stannaries</head>
			<para id="p20"><emph type="i">Butlerage, Prisage</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; extend not to prejudice any [of<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] His Majestyes Rights, Titles, or Dutyes of, in
or to, or out of any Tynn in the Stannaries of Devon and Cornwall, nor to prejudice the auntient Dutyes of
Butlerage and Prizage of Wines, but that the same shall be in the same plight that the same were in before the
makeing of this A&bholigct;, Any thing herein contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Recompence to His Majesty for the Court of Wards and Tenures, &amp;c. incident thereto.</head>
			<para id="p22"><emph type="i">Rates of the Excise</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And now to the intent and purpose that His Majesty His Heires and Successors may receive a full and ample
Recompence and Satisfa&bholigct;ion as well for the proffits of the said Court of Ward&bholngs; and the Tenures Wardships
Liveries Primer-Seizins Ouster le mains and other the Premises and Perquisits incident thereunto, and for all Arreares
any way due for the same as alsoe for all and all manner of Purveyance and Provisions herein before mentioned,
and intended to be taken away and abolished and all summes of money due or pretended to be due or payable
for, and in respe&bholigct; of any compositions for the same. Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That
there shall be paid unto the Kings Majestie His Heires and Successors for ever hereafter in recompence as aforesaid
the severall Rates Impositions Dutyes and Charge herein after expressed and in manner and forme following (that
is to say)</para>
			<para id="p24">For every Barrell of Beere or Ale above six shillings the Barrell brewed by the Common Brewer, or any
other Person or Persons who doth or shall sell, or tap out Beere or Ale publiquely or privately to be
paid by the C&bhooov;mon Brewer, or by such other Person or Persons respectively, and soe proportionably for
a greater or lesser quantity, One shilling three pence[js. iijd.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p25">For every Barrell of Six shillings Beere or Ale or under brewed by the C&bhooov;mon Brewer or other
Person or Persons who doth or shall sell or tap out such Beere or Ale publiquely or privately, to
be paid by the said C&bhooov;mon Brewer or by such other Person or Persons respe&bholigct;ively as aforesaid, and
soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity three pence[iij d.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p26">For all Sider and Perry made and sold by retaile upon every Hogshead to be paid by the Retailer
thereof and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser measure One shilling three pence[xv d.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p27">For all Metheglin or Meade sold whether by Retaile or otherwise to be paid by the maker thereof
upon every Gallon One halfe penny [vjd.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p28">For every barrell of Beere c&bhooov;monly called Vinegar beere brewed by any c&bhooov;mon Brewer [or<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] in any
c&bhooov;mon Brew house six pence [vj d.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p29">For every Gallon of Strong water or Aqua-vite made and sold to be paid by the maker therof One
penny [jd. <ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p30">For every Barrell of Beere or Ale Imported from beyond the Seas Three shillings [iijs. <ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p31">For every Tunn of Sider or Perry Imported from beyond the Seas, and soe proportionably for a greater
or lesser quantity Five shillings [vs. <ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p32">For every Gallon of Spirits made of any kinde of Wine or Sider imported Two pence [ij d. <ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p33">For every Gallon of Strong water perfe&bholigct;ly made imported from beyond the Seas Fower pence [iii j d. <ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p34">For every Gallon of Coffee made, and sold to be paid by the maker Fower pence [iv d.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p35">For every Gallon of Chocolate Sherbet and Tea made and sold, to be paid by the maker thereof
Eight pence [vii j d.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Duty upon Foreign Liquors imported to be paid by Importer in Money, upon Entry made, before Landing.</head>
			<para id="p36">And be it further Ena&bholigct;xed and Ordained by the Authoritie aforesaid That the severall Rates Dutyes and
Charges of Excise or New Impost above mentioned hereby sett or imposed upon all and every the said Forraigne
Liquors which shall be Imported or brought into all or any the Ports of this Kingdome and Dominions thereof
aforesaid from and after the five and twentyeth [Day<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] of December next shall be from time to time satisfied
and paid by the Merchant or Merchants Importer or Importers of the same in ready money upon his or their
[Entry or<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Entryes made and before the landing thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Entries to be made Weekly by Common Brewers, and Monthly by Innkeepers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p37">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all common Brewers of Beere and Ale shall once
in every weeke, And all Inne-keepers Alehouse keepers Vi&bholigct;uallers and other Retailers of Beere Ale Sider Perry
Metheglin or Strong water brewing makeing or retaileing the same shall once in every moneth make true and
perticular Entryes at the Office of Excise within the limitts of which the said Commodityes and Manufa&bholigct;ures are
made of all Beere Ale Perry Sider Metheglin Strong Water or other the Liquors aforesaid which they or any
of them shall brew make or retaile in that weeke and moneth respe&bholigct;ively as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Brewer not making Entries, Penalty &pound;10. Innkeeper, &pound;5. Retailers, 20s.</head>
			<para id="p38">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all such common Brewers who doe not once a
Weeke make due and perticular Entryes shall forfeit ten pounds. And that every such Innkeeper who doth not
make true and perticular Entryes once a moneth shall forfeit five pounds, And that every Alehouse keeper
Vi&bholigct;ualler or other Retailer who doth not once a moneth make true and perticular Entries shall forfeit twenty
shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Brewer not paying.</head>
			<para id="p39"><emph type="i">Penalty. Innkeeper, &amp;c.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p40">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every common Brewer who shall not pay and
cleare off within a weeke after he made his Entry or ought to have made his Entry as aforesaid shall pay double
the value of the duty, And that every Innekeeper Alehouse-keeper Vi&bholigct;ualer or other Retailer who shall not
pay and cleare off within a moneth after he made his Entry, or ought to have made his Entry as aforesaid shall
pay double the value of the Duty. The said respe&bholigct;ive forfeitures to be leavyed upon their Good&bholngs; and Chattells
in such manner and forme as hereafter in this A&bholigct; is ordained and dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. In what Places Entries to be made.</head>
			<para id="p41">Provided that noe such person as aforesaid shall be compelled by the Commissioners or Sub-Commissioners of
[the <ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Excise to travell for the makeing of the said Entryes or payment of the said Dutyes or other cause whatsoever
touching or concerning the same if he live in a Market Towne, out of the said Towne, if he live out of a
Market Towne then to noe other place then to the next Market Towne [to his habita&bhocotil;n<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] in the same County
on the Market day.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. The Powers of the Commissioners, and Sub-Commissioners to appoint Gaugers.</head>
			<para id="p42"><emph type="i">The Powers and Duty of Gaugers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43"><emph type="i">Entering Houses, &amp;c; Gauging Coppers, &amp;sc; Returning Gauge.; Return to be a Charge on Brewer, &amp;c.; Refusing to permit Gauger to enter;; forbidden by Gauger to sell, &amp;c.; Selling, &amp;c. not having cleared Duty.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p44">And bee it further, Ena&bholigct;ed [&amp; Ordained<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Commissioners who shall be
appointed by His Majestie for puting this A&bholigct; in execution and their Sub Commissioners in their respe&bholigct;ive circuits
and divisions shall hereby have power to constitute under their Hand&bholngs; and Seales such and soe many, Gagers as
they shall finde needfull, Which Gagers and every of them shall at all times aswell by Night as by Day, and
if by Night then in the presence of a Constable or other lawfull Officer be permitted upon their request to enter
the House Brewhouse Distilling house and all other Houses and Places whatsoever belonging to, or used by any
Brewer Inne keeper Vi&bholigct;ualler or other Retailer of Beere brewing or makeing the same as aforesaid or by any
Distiller of Strong Waters or Retailer of other the Liquors aforesaid, And to gage all Coppers Fats and Vessels
in the same, and to take an accompt of Beere Ale Worts Perry Sider Strong waters Aqua vite Metheglin or other
the Liquors aforesaid in the said Houses Places and Vessells from time to time brewed or made and distilled,
and thereof to make Returne or Report in Writeing to the said Commissioners or Sub Commissioners of Excise
under whose Office and Limitts such Brewer Retailer Distiller or Maker of the Liquors aforesaid doth dwell and
inhabit leaveing a true Copy of such Returne in writeing under his hand with such Brewer Retailer Distiller or
Makers of the Liquors aforesaid, And such Reports or Returnes of the said Gagers shall be a charge upon the
said Brewers Makers and Retailers respe&bholigct;ively, And if any such common Brewer Maker or Retailer shall refuse
to permit any such Gager or Gagers to enter his Brew house or any other places aforementioned, or to gage or
take accompt of his Brewing Vessells or of any such Beere Ale Worts Perry Sider Strong water Aqua vite
Metheglin or other the Liquors aforesaid, such Brewer Retailer or Distiller shall be forthwith forbidden by the
said Gager or Gagers to sell carry out or deliver to any of his Customers any Beere Ale Strongwater Aqua
vite or other the Liquors aforesaid, And if any such Brewer Retailer or Distiller of any the Liquors aforesaid
after such warning given shall sell carry or deliver out the same or any part thereof not haveing paid and cleared
the duty of Excise such person and persons shall besides the forfeiture of double the value forfeit and lose the
summe of ten pound&bholngs; as aforesaid for every offence to be leavyed and recovered upon his or their Good&bholngs; and
Chattels in manner and forme as hereafter in this A&bholigct; is provided,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Proportions to be observed in Returns of Gaugers of and for a Barrel of Beer or Ale.</head>
			<para id="p45">And for the avoiding of all incertainty and dispute touching the returnes made or to be made by the Gagers
of any Beere or Ale soe brewed as aforesaid Bee it ena&bholigct;ed and declared by [the<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Authority aforesaid That every
six and thirty Gallons of Beere taken by the Gage according to the Standard of the Ale quart fower wherof shall
make the Gallon remaining in the custody of the Chamberlains of his Majestyes Exchequer shall be reckoned
accounted and returned by the Gager for a Barrell of Beere, and every two and thirty Gallons of Ale taken by
the Gage according to the same Standard shall be in like manner reckoned accounted and returned for a Barrell
of Ale, And all other the Liquors aforesaid according to the Wine gallon.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Brewers and Retailers to observe the usual Rates and Prices</head>
			<para id="p46">Provided alwayes and bee it Ena&bholigct;ed and Ordained by Authoritie aforesaid That noe Brewers or Retailers
of Beere and Ale shall take any more in the price thereof upon sale of the same then according to the usuall Rates
and Prizes, saveing that every common Brewer shall and may take and receive of all and every person and persons
to whom he shall sell and deliver any Beere or Ale the Excise thereupon due as aforesaid over and above the
usuall Rates and Prizes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Allowance for Waste and Leakage.</head>
			<para id="p47">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That for the better encouragement of all common Brewers
or Makers of Beere or Ale to make due entry and payment thereof according as by this A&bholigct; is appointed, the said
common Brewer not selling the same by Retaile for and in consideration of waste by fillings and leakage of their
Beere and Ale shall have and be allowed out of the said Returnes made by the Gagers the severall allowances and
abatements hereafter mentioned (that is to say) upon every three and twenty Barrells of Beere whether strong or
small returned by the said Gagers three Barrells, And upon every two and twenty Barrells of Ale whether strong or
small returned by the Gagers two Barrells, which said allowances and abatements the said Commissioners to be
appointed as aforesaid and their Sub Commissioners are hereby authorized to allow and make accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Making false Entries.</head>
			<para id="p48"><emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p49">Provided alwayes That where any common brewer shall wittingly [and<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] willingly, make a false Entry and be
convi&bholigct;ed for the same before the Commissioners to be appointed as aforesaid or any two of them, or before such
other person or persons as are hereafter by this A&bholigct; appointed, in that case such Brewer or Brewers shall forfeit
and lose over and besides the penaltyes before mentioned, the said allowance soe to be made for six moneths then
next ensueing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. No Beer, &amp;c. to be delivered by Brewer until Duty be paid by the Retailer.; Proviso for Beer and Ale sold in Fairs</head>
			<para id="p50">And be it Ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by Authoritie aforesaid That noe Beere or Ale shall be delivered in by such
brewer or maker thereof to any Vi&bholigct;ualler or other Retailer thereof untill the rate which by such Victualler or
Retailer is to be paid over and above the price of the said Beere or Ale for or in respe&bholigct; of this duty be first
paid and satisfied by the said Vi&bholigct;ualler or Retailer to the brewer or maker thereof. Provided alwayes That if
any person or persons shall brew and sell by retaile any small quantityes of Beere or Ale in any Faier within this
Realme or Dominions aforesaid who is not otherwise any common or usuall brewer or Retailer thereof and shall
before any such selling and retailing thereof well and truely pay and satisfie the duty due for the same to the
Commissioners or Sub Commissioners within whose Limitts or Division the said Fair shall be held, or to their Officers
thereunto appointed, Then such person [or<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] persons soe brewing or retaileing the same, And for soe much and noe
more nor otherwise shall be freed and discharged from all Penaltyes and Forfeitures in and by this A&bholigct; before
mentioned and imposed, Any thing therein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Commissioners, &amp;c. may compound for Duty within their Divisions.</head>
			<para id="p51">Provided neverthelesse that it shall and may bee lawfull to and for the said Commissioners and Sub
Commissioners respe&bholigct;ively to compound for this Duty with any Inne-keeper Vi&bholigct;ualler Ale house keeper or Retayler
of Beere Ale and other the Liquors aforesaid within their respe&bholigct;ive Divisions from time to time &amp; in such manner
and forme as may be most for the advantage and improvement of the receipts thereof, Any thing in this A&bholigct;
before contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Power of Lord Treasurer, &amp;c. to contra&bholigct; for farming Duties.</head>
			<para id="p52">And it is further Ordained and Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Lord Treasurer or Commissioners
of the Treasury for the time being or such other person or persons as His Majesty His Heires and Successors shall
appoint shall have power, and are hereby authorized [and impoured<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] from time to time to treat contra&bholigct; conclude
and agree with any person or persons for or concerning the Farming of all or any the Rates Dutyes and Charges
in this A&bholigct; mentioned upon Beere Ale Perry Sider or other the Liquors aforesaid in any the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes
Cittyes or Places of this Realme or Dominions thereof as may be for the greatest benefit and advantage of the said
Receipt, soe as the same exceed not the terme of three yeares.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Such Contra&bholigct;s to be good.</head>
			<para id="p53">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That every such Contra&bholigct; Bargaine and Agreement of the Lord Treasurer or
Commissioners of the Treasury, or other persons aforesaid on behalfe of His Majestie on the one part, and the
person or persons farming on the other part shall be good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law to all intents and purposes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Treasury not to treat with Persons other than such as shall be approved by Quarter Sessions.</head>
			<para id="p54"><emph type="i">Such Persons to have the first refusal.; Proviso as to rate of letting</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p55">Provided alwayes to the end the aforesaid duty may be paid with most ease to the people It is hereby further
Ena&bholigct;ed That the Lord Treasurer Commissioners of the Treasury or other persons aforesaid shall not within six
moneths after the Commencement of this A&bholigct; treate conclude or agree with any person or persons touching the
Farming of this duty upon Beere and Ale in any the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes or places of this Realme or Dominions
therof other then with such person or persons as by the Justices of Peace of the said Countyes or places or the
major part of them at their publique Quarter Sessions shall be nominated and appointed in that behalfe, which
person or persons is to have the first refusall of any such Farme respe&bholigct;ively, and may take the same Any thing
in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding. Provided that the said duty shall not be let to any
other person or persons then to the person or persons recommended by the Justices under the rate that it shall be
tendred to, and refused by such person or persons soe recommended</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Forfeiture and Offences within this A&bholigct; how to be determined.</head>
			<para id="p56"><emph type="i">In London.; In all other Counties, Cities, &amp;c.; If Justices negle&bholigct;, then Sub-commissioners to determine.; Appeal to Quarter Sessions, final.; Commissioners of Appeal, &amp;c. to examine Witnesses on Oath;; and issue Warrants for levying the Penalties.; Proceedings thereon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p57">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed and Ordained by the Authoritie aforesaid That all forfeitures and offences made
[done<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] and committed against this A&bholigct;, or any Clause or Article therein contained shall be heard adjudged and
determined by such person and persons and in such manner and forme as hereafter in and by this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed
and appointed that is to say all such forfeitures and offences made and committed within the immediate limits of the
cheife Office in London shall be heard adjudged and determined by the said cheife Commissioners and Governours of
Excise (appointed by His Majestie) or the Major part of them, or by the Commissioners for Appeales and regulating
of this duty or the major part of them, in case of Appeale and not otherwise. And all such forfeitures and
offences made and committed within all or any other the Countyes Cittyes [Towne or Place<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] within this Kingdome or
Dominions thereof shall be heard and determined by any two or more of the Justices of the Peace residing neere
to the place where such forfeitures shall be made or offence committed, And in case of negcle&bholigct; or refusall of
such Justices of the Peace by the space of fowerteene dayes next after complaint made and notice thereof given
to the Offender, then the Sub Commissioners or the major part of them appointed for any such Citty County
Towne or place shall and are hereby impowered to heare and determine the same, And if the party finde himselfe
aggreived by the Judgement given by the said Sub Commissioners he shall and may appeale to the Justices of the
Peace at the next Quarter Sessions who are hereby impowered and authorized to heare and determine the same,
whose Judgement therein shall be finall, which said Commissioners for Appeales and regulating of this duty and
the cheife Commissioners for Excise and all Justices of [the<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Peace and Sub Commissioners aforesaid respectively are
hereby authorized and strictly enjoyned and required upon any complaint or information exhibited and brought of
any such forfeiture made or offence committed contrary to this A&bholigct; to summon the party accused, and upon his
appearance or contempt to proceeed to examination of the matter of fa&bholigct;, and upon due proofe made thereof either
by the voluntary confession of the party, or by the oath of one or more credible witnesses (which Oath they or
any two or more of them have hereby power to administer) to give Judgement or Sentence according as in and by
this Act is before ordained and directed, and to award and issue out Warrants under their hand&bholngs; for the levying
of such forfeitures penalties and fines as by this A&bholigct; is imposed for any such offence committed upon the Good&bholngs;
and Chattells of the Offender, and to cause sale to be made of the said Good&bholngs; and Chattells if they shall not
be redeemed within fowerteene dayes rendering to the party the overplus, if any be, and for want of sufficient
distresse to imprison the party offending till satisfa&bholigct;ion be made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Power to Justices and Commissioners of Excise to mitigate Penalties; but not to less than Amount of Double Duty.</head>
			<para id="p58"><emph type="i">Costs of Officer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p59">Provided neverthelesse That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said respe&bholigct;ive Justices of Peace
Commissioners for Excise or any two of them or their Sub Commissioners respe&bholigct;ively from time to time where
they shall see cause to mittigate compound or lessen such forfeiture penalty or fine as in their discretion they
shall thinke fitt, And that every such mitigation and payment thereupon accordingly made shall be a sufficient
discharge of the said penaltyes and forfeitures to the persons soe offending soe as by such mitigation the same be
not made lesse then double the value of the duty of Excise which should or ought to have beene paid, besides
the reasonable costs and charges of such Officer or Officers or others as were imployed therein, to be to them
allowed by the said Justices, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary in anywise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. How Penalties to be employed.</head>
			<para id="p60">And it is hereby further Ena&bholigct;ed and Ordained That all Fines Forfeitures and Penaltyes mentioned in this A&bholigct;
all necessary charges for the recovery thereof being first dedu&bholigct;ed shall be imployed three fourth parts thereof to
and for the use of the Kings Majestie, and one fourth part to the Discoverer or Informer of the same;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII.</head>
			<para id="p61"><emph type="i">One principal Office of Excise to be erected in London.; Officers appointed by the King</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p62">And for the better managing colle&bholigct;ing secureing leavying and recovering of all and every the said rates and
charges of Excise hereby imposed and sett upon all or any the Commodities before mentioned to the end the
same may be paid and disposed of according to the intent of this present A&bholigct;, Bee it further Enacted and
Ordained by Authority aforesaid, And it is hereby Ena&bholigct;ed That one principall Head Office shall be ere&bholigct;ed and
continued in the Citty of London or within ten miles thereof from time to time as long as his Majestie shall
thinke fitt for this duty, unto which all other Offices for the same within England and Wales and the Towne
and Port of Berwicke shall be subordinate and accomptable, Which said Office shall be managed by such Officers
as shall be appointed by the Kings Majestie as aforesaid, who, or any two of them are hereby appointed and
constituted Commissioners and Governours for the management of His Majestyes Receipt of [the <ref idref="n18">18</ref>] Excise, and to sitt
in some convenient place in the Citty of London, or within ten miles thereof from time to time as long as his
Majestie shall thinke fitt [for the ends aforesaid<ref idref="n19">19</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. Officers to take the Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy together with the Oath following.</head>
			<para id="p63">And be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe person or persons shall be capeable of intermedling
with any Office or Imployment relateing to the Excise untill he or they shall before two or more Justices of
Peace in the County where his or their imployments shall be, or before one of the Barons of the Exchequer
take the oaths of Alleigiance and Supremacie which oathes they have hereby power to Administer together with
this Oath following Mutatis Mutandis.</para>
			<para id="p64"><emph type="i">The Oath</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p65">YOU shall sweare to execute the Office of truely and faithfully without Favour or affe&bholigct;ion, and
shall from to time true Account make and deliver to such person or persons as his Majestie shall appoint
to receive the same, and shall take noe Fee or Reward for the Execution of the said Office from any other person
then from his Majestye or those whom his Majestie shall appoint in that behalfe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. To be certified to Quarter Sessions.</head>
			<para id="p66">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every such Justice of [the<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Peace shall certifie the
takeing of such Oath to the next Quarter Sessions there to be recorded</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. London. Westminster, &amp;c. under Management of Head Office.; Commissioners, &amp;c. to be nominated by His Majesty.</head>
			<para id="p67">And it is further Ena&bholigct;ed That all parts of the Cittyes of London and Westminster with the Borough of
Southwarke and [the<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] severall Suburbs thereof, and Parishes within the weekely Bills of Mortality shall be under
the immediate care inspe&bholigct;ion and mannagement of the said Head Office, and such and soe many subordinate
Commissioners and Sub-Commissioners and other Officers and Ministers for the execution of the Premisses shall
be from time to time nominated and appointed by his Majestie His Heires and Successors in all and every other
the Countyes Cittyes Townes and places within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Port of Berwicke
as from time to time His Majesty His Heires and Successors shall thinke fitt;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. Hours in which the Office to be kept open.</head>
			<para id="p68">And it is hereby further Ena&bholigct;ed That the said Office of Excise in all places where it shall be appointed shall
be kepte open from eight of the Clocke in the morning till twelve of the Clocke at noone, and from two of
the Clocke in the afternoone till five of the Clocke in the afternoone for the due execution and performance of
all and every the matters and things in this A&bholigct; appointed and required,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. Commissioners to pay into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p69">And it is further hereby Ena&bholigct;ed That the said cheife Commissioners of Excise or the major part of them shall
from time to time issue forth and pay such summe and summes of money as shall from time to time be received
colle&bholigct;ed or leavyed by vertue of this A&bholigct; into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. General Issue pleadable in any A&bholigct;ion upon this Statute.</head>
			<para id="p70"><emph type="i">Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p71">Provided allwayes and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That if any person or persons shall at any time be sued or prosecuted
for any thing by him or them done or executed in pursuance of this A&bholigct;, he or they shall and may plead the
generall issue, and give this A&bholigct; in evidence for his defence, and if upon the Tryall a Verdi&bholigct; shall passe for the
Deffendant or Defendants, or the Plaintiffe or Plaintiffes be nonsuite then such Defendant or Defendants shall have
double costs to him or them awarded against such Plaintiffe or Plaintiffes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. No Writs of Certiorari to supersede Proceedings.</head>
			<para id="p72">Provided alsoe and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That noe Writt or Writts of Certiorari shall supersede Execution or other
proceeding upon any Order or Orders made by the Justices aforesaid in pursuance of this A&bholigct; but that execution
and other proceeding shall and may be had and made thereupon, Any such Writt or Writts or allowance thereof
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Proviso as to A&bholigct; of General Pardon, c. 11. ante.</head>
			<para id="p73">Provided That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be construed to extend in any
manner to weaken or invalidate one A&bholigct; of this present Parliament Entituled An A&bholigct; of Free and General Pardon
Indempnity and Oblivion, but that every Clause Article Matter and thing therein mentioned &amp; comprized shall
notwithstanding this A&bholigct; or any matter or thing therein remaine good and valid, and be of the same force vertue
and effe&bholigct; as if this A&bholigct; had never beene made</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. Proviso concerning Edward Backwell as to &pound;28, 450 advanced by him on Credit of several Orders of this Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p74">Provided alwayes and be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not be
prejudiciall to Edward Backewell Alderman of London as to the summe of twenty eight thousand fower hundred
and fifty pound&bholngs; (or any part thereof) by him advanced upon the Credit of severall Orders of this present
Parliament, and by them charged on the Receipt of the Grand Excise that is to say the summe of Five thousand
pounds payable to His Majestyes Surveyour Generall for the repaire of his Majestyes Houses charged by vertue
of an Order of the sixth of September One thousand six hundred and sixty with Interest for the same, the summe
of tenn thousand pound&bholngs; advanced to her Highnesse the Princesse Royall being charged with Interest by an Order
of the thirteenth of September One thousand six hundred and sixty, the summe of ten thousand pound&bholngs; payable to
her Majestie the Queene of Bohemia being charged together with Interest by an Order of the thirteenth of September
One thousand six hundred and sixty the summe of three thousand foure hundred and fifty pound&bholngs; payable for
Provisions for Dunkirke by Order of the twenty sixth of November One thousand six hundred and sixty, which
summe of twenty eight thousand fower hundred and fifty pound&bholngs; together with Interest for the same according
to the tenor of the said Orders after the rate of six per cent. shall be paid to the said Edward Backewell or his
Assignes out of the Grand Excise and the Arreares thereof in course as is by the said Orders appointed, and in
case the same shall fall short in payment by the twenty fifth of December One thousand six hundred and sixty
that then the remainder shall continue secured to him out of the whole Excise in course as aforesaid, and that noe
other payments be made out of the Excise but what is appointed by this present Parliament in course to precede
the same untill the said Debt due to the said Edward Backewell be satisfied, and that in case any part of the
moneyes due to Alderman Backewell be paid out of that part of the Excise which shall grow due to the Kings
Majestie [that then his Majesty<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] shall be reimbursed the same out of the first moneyes that shall come in of
the Arreares of Excise that will be due the said twenty fifth of December.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">fowre and twentyeth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Apprentice <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Apprenticeshipp <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">of England or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">Townes or Places <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

