<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47282" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXIV. An Act for Prohibiting the Planting Setting or Sowing of Tobaccho in England and Ireland. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. 11 p. 4. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">No Person after the 1st Jan. 1660 shall set or plant any Tobacco.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">YOUR Majestyes Loyall and Obedient Subje&bholigct;s The Lord&bholngs; and Commons in this present Parliament assembled
considering of how great concern and importance it is That the Colonies and Plantations of this Kingdome
in America be defended prote&bholigct;ed maintained and kept up, and that all due and possible incouragement be given
unto them, and that not onely in regard great and considerable Dominions and Countryes have beene thereby
gained and added to the Imperiall Crowne of this Realme, But for that the strength and welfaire of this Kingdome
doe very much depend upon them in regard of the imployment of a very considerable part of its Shipping and
Seamen, and of the vent of very great quantities of its Native C&bhooov;modities and Manufa&bholigct;ures as alsoe of its supply
with severall considerable Commodities which it was wont formerly to have onely from Forraigners and at farr
dearer Rates And forasmuch as Tocaccho is one of the maine produ&bholigct;s of severall of those Plantations, and upon
which their Welfaire and Subsistance and the Navigation of this Kingdome and vent of its Commodities thither doe
much depend. And in regard it is found by experience that the Tobacchoes planted in these parts are not soe good
and wholsome for the takers thereof, and that by the planting thereof Your Majestie is deprived of a considerable
part of Your Revenue ariseing by Customs upon imported Tobaccho Doe most humbly pray that it may be Ena&bholigct;ed
by your Majesty, And it is hereby Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie and the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in
this present Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same that noe person or persons whatsoever shall or
doe from and after the first day of January in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and sixty sett,
plant, improve to grow make or cure any Tobaccho [either<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] in Seed Plant or otherwise in or upon any ground earth
field or place within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales Iseland&bholngs; of Guernsey or Jersey or Towne of
Berwicke upon Tweede or in the Kingdome of Ireland under the penalty of the forfeiture of all such Tobaccho or
the value thereof &amp; of the summe of forty shillings for every Rodd or Pole of Ground soe planted sett or sowne
as aforesaid and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity of Ground, one moyetie thereof to His Majestie
his Heires and Successors And the other moyety to him or them that shall sue for the same to be recovered by
Bill Plaint or Information in any Court of Record wherein noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion or wager in Law shall be allowed</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Sheriffs and other Officers may destroy Tobacco planted contrary to this A&bholigct;</head>
			<para id="p3">And it is hereby further Ena&bholigct;ed that all Sheriffes Justices of the Peace Maiors Bailiffes Constables and every of
them upon Information or Complaint made unto them or any of them by any the Officers of the Customes or by
any other person or persons whatsoever that there is any Tobaccho sett sowne planted or growing within their
Jurisdi&bholigct;ions or Precin&bholigct;s contrary to this A&bholigct; shall within ten dayes after such Information or Complaint cause to be
burnt plucked up consumed or utterly destroyed all such Tobaccho soe sett sowen planted or growing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Resisting Execution of A&bholigct;, Penalty &pound;5.; Distress.; If no Distress, Imprisonment.</head>
			<para id="p4">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed that in case any person or persons shall resist or make forceable Opposition
against any person or persons in the due and through execution of this A&bholigct; that every such person or persons
for every such Offence shall forfeit the summe of five pound&bholngs; to be divided and recovered in manner aforesaid.
And in case any person or persons shall not pay the summes of money by them to be paid by vertue of this
A&bholigct; that in every such case Distresse shall be made and Sale thereof returning the Overplus to the Owners and
in case noe Distresse be to be found that then every such party shall be committed to the common Goale in the
County where such Offence shall be committed there to remaine for the space of two monethes without baile or
maineprize.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Physic Gardens.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwayes and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed that this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained shall extend to the
hindering of the planting of Tobaccho in any Phisicke Garden of either University or in any other private Garden
for Phisicke or Surgery onely soe as the quantity soe planted exceed not one halfe of one Pole in any one place
or Garden.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


