<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47280" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXII. An Act for prohibiting the Exportation of Wooll Woolfells Fullers Earth or any kinde of Scouring Earth. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p. 4. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">No Person after 14th Jan. 1660 to export any Sheep, Wool, Woolfels, Mortlings, Shearlings, Yarn, Woolflocks, Fullers Earth, or Fulling Clay; nor carry, load, or board any such Sheep, Wool, &amp;c.;</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">FOR the better preventing and avoiding of such Losses and Inconveniencies as have happened and dayly doe and
may happen to the Kingdome of England and Dominion of Wales and to the Kingdome of Ireland by and
through the secret and subtile exportation and transportation, and by and through the secret and subtle carrying
and conveying [away<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of Wooll Woolfels Mortlings Sherlings Yarn made of Wooll Wooll flocks Fullers earth and
Fulling Clay out of and from the [Kingdome<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] &amp; Dominion aforesaid, and for the better setting on worke the poore
people and inhabitants of the Kingdomes and Dominion aforesaid, And to the intent that the full and best use and
benefit of the principall native Commodities of the same Kingdomes and Dominion may come redound and be unto
and amongst the Subje&bholigct;s and Inhabitants of the same, and not unto or amongst the Subje&bholigct;s and Inhabitants of
the Realme of Scotland, or of any Forraine Realmes or States as the same now of late in some great measure hath done and is further likely to doe if some severer punishment then heretofore be not speedily infli&bholigct;ed upon such
Offenders as shall be A&bholigct;ors or Assistants in and to such exportation and transportation, and in and to such carrying
and conveying away thereof as aforesaid Be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie the Lord&bholngs; and Commons
in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That noe person or persons whatsoever from
and after the fowerteenth day of January, One thousand six hundred and threescore shall dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly
export transport carry or convey or cause or procure to be exported transported carryed or conveyed out of or from
the Kingdome of England or Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede, or out of or from the Isles
of Jersey or Guernsey with Sarke and Alderney being under the Government of Guernsey aforesaid or out of or
from any of them, or out of or from the Kingdome of Ireland aforesaid into any parts or places out of the Kingdomes
Isles or Dominion aforesaid any Sheepe or Wooll whatsoever of the breed or growth of the [Kingdome<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] of England or
Ireland or Isles or Dominion aforesaid, or any Woollfells Mortlings or Shorlings or any Yarne made of Wooll or
any Woollflocks or any Fullers Earth or [any<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Fulling Clay whatseever, nor shall dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly packe or loade
or cause to be packed or loaden upon any Horse Cart or other Carriage or Loade or lay on board or cause to be
loaden or laid on board in any shipp or other vessell in any place or Port within the Kingdomes of England or
Ireland or Towne of Berwicke or Isles or Dominion aforesaid any such sheep wooll Woollfells Mortlings Shorlings Yarne
made of wooll or Wooll flocks or any Fullers Earth or Fullers Clay to the intent or purpose to export transport
carry or convey the same or to cause y<emph type="p">e</emph> same to be [exported<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] transported carried or conveyed out of y<emph type="p">e</emph> Kingdomes
of England or Ireland Towne of Berwick (<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) or Dominion afores[ai]d or with intent or purpose that any other &bhopubr;son
or &bhopubr;sons should so export transport carry or convey the same into parts or places out of the Kingdomes of
England and Ireland Towne of Berwicke Isles or Dominion aforesaid into the Kingdome of Scotland or any
forraigne parts,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. No Wool, Woolfels, &amp;c. after the 14th Jan. 1660, to be carried to Jersey, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe wooll Woollfells Mortlings Shorlings Yarne
made of wooll woolflocks or any Fullers earth or Fulling clay shall be from and after the fowerteenth day of
January in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and threescore exported transported carryed or conveyed
out of the Kingdome of England and Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke [and<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Kingdome of Ireland or out of
any Port or place of the said Kingdomes respe&bholigct;ively unto the Isles of Jersey or Guernsey or to Sarke or Alderney
except as in this A&bholigct; shall be hereafter limitted or appointed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Penalties by Exporters;</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">by Owners of Ships exporting</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid [That all and every the Offender and Offenders offence and
offences aforesaid shall be subje&bholigct; and lieable to the [respe&bholigct;ive<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] paines penaltyes and forfeitures hereafter following
That is to say The said sheepe [wools<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] woolfells Mortlings Shorlings Yarne made of wooll woolflocks Fullers earth
and fulling clay soe exported transported carryed conveyed packed or loaden contrary to the true intent of this A&bholigct;
shall be forfeited and that every offender and offenders therein shall forfeit twenty shillings for every such sheepe and
three shillings for every pound weight of such wooll woolfells Mortlings Shorlings Yarne made of wooll woolflocks
Fullers earth or Fulling Clay, And alsoe the owners of the said Shipps or Vessells knowing such offence shall forfeit
all their Interest in the said Shipps or Vessells with all their Apparell and Furniture to them and every of them
belonging, And that the Master and Marriners thereof knowing such offence and wittingly and willingly aiding and
assisting thereunto shall forfeite all their Good&bholngs; and Chattels and have imprisonment for the space of three moneths
without Baile or Maineprize, the one moyety of which said penaltyes and forfeitures shall be to the Kings Majestie
His Heires and Successors, and the other moyety to him that will sue for the same by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill
Plaint or Information in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record or before the Justices of Assize or in the Generall
Quarter Sessions of the Peace In which Suite noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion or wager of Law shall be allowed,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Merchant exporting Wools, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That if any Merchant or other person or persons shall after the said fowerteenth
day of January transport or cause to be transported any Sheepe [Wooll<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Woolfells Mortlings Shorlings Woollen
yarne Woolflocks Fullers earth or Fulling Clay contrary to the true intent of this A&bholigct; and be thereof lawfully
convi&bholigct;ed That then he shall be disabled to require any debt or accompt of any Fa&bholigct;or or others for or concerning
any Debt or Estate properly belonging to such offender</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. This A&bholigct; not to take away greater penalties.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alwayes and it is neverthelesse declared That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not be
construed to take away any greater paines or penaltyes infli&bholigct;ed or to be infli&bholigct;ed for any the offences aforesaid
by vertue of any former A&bholigct; of Parliament now in force.<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Offences against this A&bholigct; where to be tried.</head>
			<para id="p10">And be it [alsoe<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that every offence that shall be done or committed
contrary to this A&bholigct; shall and may be enquired of and heard examined tryed and determined in the County
where such Sheep Wooll Woolfells Mortlings Shorlings Yarne made of Wooll Woolflocks Fullers earth or Fulling
Clay respe&bholigct;ively shall be soe packed loaden or laid aboard as aforesaid contrary to this A&bholigct; or else in the County
where such offenders shall happen to be apprehended or arrested for such offence in such manner and forme
and to such effe&bholigct; to all intents and purposes as if the same offence had beene wholly and altogether done and
committed at and in such County,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Limitation of Prosecution.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwayes and be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe person or persons whatsoever shall
at any time hereafter be impeached for any offence aforesaid unlesse such person or persons shall be prosecuted
within the space of one yeare next ensueing such offence committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Any Person may seize Goods loaded contrary to this A&bholigct; with Intent to be exported, and to have the Moiety thereof.</head>
			<para id="p12">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any person
or persons to seize take and challenge to his or their owne use and behoofe, and to the use of the King His
Heires and Successors all and all manner such Sheep Wooll Woolfells [Mortlings Shorlings Yarn made of Wooll
Woolflocks<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Fullers earth and Fulling Clay as he or they shall happen to see finde know or discover to be laid
aboard in any Shipp or other Vessell or Boate or to be brought carryed or laid on shore at or neare the Sea
or any Navigable River or Water to the intent or purpose to be exported transported or conveyed out of the
Kingdomes of England or Ireland Towne of Berwicke Isles or Dominion aforesaid contrary to the true meaning
of this A&bholigct; or to be packed or loaden upon any Horse Cart or other Carriage to the intent or purpose to be
conveyed or carried into the Kingdome of Scotland aforesaid, and that such person or persons as shall happen soe
to seize take or challenge any such Sheepe [Wooll<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Woolfells Mortlings Shorlings Yarne made of Wooll Woolflocks
Fullers Earth or Fulling Clay as aforesaid shall have the full moyety thereof to all intents and purposes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Person seizing not to be Evidence against the Offender.</head>
			<para id="p13">Provided alwayes That such person or persons as shall make any such Seizure or challenge as aforesaid to
his or their owne use shall not be admitted or allowed to give in Evidence upon his or their Oath or Oathes
against any person or persons which shall happen to be indi&bholigct;ed accused or questioned by vertue of this A&bholigct; or
any thing therein contained</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Ships of Aliens or Persons not inhabiting in England, exporting Sheep, &amp;c. forfeited.</head>
			<para id="p14">And furthermore be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That all and every Ship Vessell Hulke Barge or
Boate of what kinde soever whereof any Alien borne or whereof any naturall borne Subje&bholigct;s not inhabiting within
the Realme of England shall be owner or part owner and wherein any Sheepe Wooll Woolfells Mortlings Shorlings
Yarne made of Wooll Woolflocks Fullers Earth or Fulling Clay shall happen to be shipped [put<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] or laid aboard
contrary to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; shall be forfeited to the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Proviso for drest Lambskins.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to any Lambe Skin ready drest and prepared fitt and usefull
for Furr or Lynings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Proviso for Pelts or Beds stuffed with Flocks used in Ships.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Wether Sheep, &amp;c. used in Ships</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; shall not in any wise extend to the transporting carrying or conveying away of
any such Woolfells or Pelts with such Wooll upon them or to any Bed&bholngs; stuffed with Flocks which shall be
carryed or imployed in any Ship or other vessell for necessary use onely of &amp; about the Ordnance or other thing
in or concerning such Ship or Vessell, or onely for the necessary use of any the Persons in such Ship or Vessell
passing or being and which shall not be sold or uttered in any forraigne parts out of the Kingdomes of England
or Ireland or Towne of Berwicke Isles or Dominion aforesaid, nor to the exporting transporting carrying or
conveying of any Weather sheep or of the Wooll growing upon any such Weather sheep to be carried alive in
any Shipp or other Vessell for and toward&bholngs; the onely necessary food or dyet of or for the Company or passengers
or other persons therein and for and toward&bholngs; none other purpose</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for Wool exported from Southampton to Jersey, Guernsey, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Exporter to deliver to Officer a Certificate from the Governor that he is authorized so to export.; Contents of such Certificate.; Quantity of Wool allowed to be so exported</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">Provided alwayes and be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to any
such wooll to be exported or transported out [of<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] or from the Port of Southampton onely [un<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] to the aforesaid
Isles of Jersey and Guernsey by or for the onely use or behoofe of any the Inhabitants of the said Isles of Jersey
&amp; Guernzey or either of them or to any such wooll to be shipped or loaden aboard in any shipp or other vessell
by or for the onely use or behoofe of any the Inhabitants of the said Isles of Jersey or Guernsey or either of
them in the Port aforesaid to be exported and transported into the said Isles of Jersey or Guernzey or either of
them soe as such person and persons that shall soe shipp or lay aboard such wooll into any ship or other vessell
doe before the shipping or laying aboard such wooll deliver unto the Customer Comptroller surveyour or searcher
of the Port of Southampton aforesaid (out of which the same wooll is to be exported) a writing under the Seale
or Seales of the respe&bholigct;ive Governours of the same Isles of Jersey and Guernsey unto which the said wooll is to
be transported, or of his or their Deputy or Deputyes respe&bholigct;ively, the which writing shall purport and expresse
that the party named in such writeing is authorized and appointed to export or to cause to be exported out of
the Port aforesaid soe much wooll expressing the number of the Tod&bholngs; to the same Isle to be used or manufa&bholigct;ured
in one of the same Isles or in some of the members or parts of the same, and that such party soe authorized and
appointed to export or cause to be exported that wooll hath before the makeing and sealing of that writeing
entered sufficient Bond to his Majestyes use for the landing of the said wooll in that Isle, And to the intent
that the quantity of wooll to be exported out of the Port of Southampton aforesaid into the said Isles or either
of them in any one yeare accompting the yeare to begin from the first day of January next ensueing, and soe
yearely from the first day of January may not exceed the quantity hereunder specified that is to say unto the Isle
of Jersey Two thousand Tod&bholngs; and noe more of unkeamed wool, and unto Guernzey one thousand Tod&bholngs; and noe
more of unkeamed wooll, and unto Alderney two hundred Tod&bholngs; and noe more of unkeamed wooll, and unto
Sarke one hundred Tod&bholngs; of unkeamed wooll and noe more every Tod not exceeding thirty two pound&bholngs;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Quantity of Wool for which Governor of Jersey to grant Certificate.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">The like Provision as to Guernsey.; Officer at the Port of Southampton to keep an Account of Wool laden there; Penalty.; Governors granting Licences for greater Quantities than before mentioned; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the Governour of the said Isle of Jersey or his Deputie
for whom he will answere shall not make to any person or persons any writeing or writeings such as is above
specified to authorize or appoint such person or persons as aforesaid to fetch export or transport out of the Port
of Southampton aforesaid unto the said Isle of Jersey in one yeare accompting the yeare from the first day of
January One thousand six hundred and sixty aforesaid, any greater quantity of wooll then two thousand Tod&bholngs; in
any one yeare, and that the Governour of the said Isle of Guernzey or his Deputy for whom he will answere
shall not make to any person or persons any writeing or writeings such as is above specified to authorize and appoint such person or persons as aforesaid to fetch export or transport out of the Port above specified unto the said
Isles of Guernzey with Alderny and Sarke in any one yeare accompting the yeare from the first day of January
aforesaid any greater quantity of Wooll then one thousand Tod&bholngs; for Guernzey, Two hundred Tod&bholngs; for Alderny
and One hundred Tod&bholngs; for Sarke in any one yeare, And that the Customer of the Port of Southampton aforesaid
shall keepe a true accompt of all the said quantity of Wooll soe by him permitted to be loaden by vertue of this
A&bholigct;, and shall not permitt any greater quantitye of Woolls to-be loaden then by this A&bholigct; is prescribed in any one
yeare to either of the said Island&bholngs; respe&bholigct;ively under any pretence whatsoever upon the penalty of the forfeiture of
his place, and of the summe of One hundred pound&bholngs; in money one moyetie whereof to the Kings Majestie his Heires
and Successors, and the other moyety to him or them that will sue for the same in any Court of Record wherein
noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion or wager of Law shall be allowed. And if any of the Governours aforesaid or any their or
either of their Deputy or Deputyes of the said Isles or [of<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] either of them shall give grant or make any Licence, or
Licences for exporting from Southampton aforesaid into the said Isles respe&bholigct;ively [of<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] any greater quantity of such
Wooll then is [before<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] by the true meaning of this A&bholigct; limited and appointed in that behalfe That then the respe&bholigct;ive
Governor or Governors of such of the said Isles shall forfeit and pay to the Kings Majesty his Heires or Successors
the summe of Twenty pound&bholngs; of lawfull money of England for every Todd of Wooll which shall be soe licensed
to be exported over and above the rate or proportion of Wooll in and by this A&bholigct;, or the true meaning thereof
limited or appointed,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Fee to Governors, &amp;c. for granting Licence.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Taking greater Fee, Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the respe&bholigct;ive Governours aforesaid or their respe&bholigct;ive
Deputyes, or any their Clerks Officers or Servants for the granting makeing or sealeing of every such writeing of
Licence as is abovesaid and for the entering a Remembrance of the same into some Booke which they shall have
and keepe for that purpose may have and take the summe of twelve pence and noe more upon paine of forfeiting to
the party grieved the summe of Five shillings for every penny which shall be taken over and above the said summe
of twelve pence in and by this A&bholigct; allowed to be taken, and soe after that proportion the said penalty or forfeiture
for the takeing above twelve pence as aforesaid to be recovered by Bill, Plaint, or Information in any Court of
Record at Westminster or elsewhere wherein noe Injun&bholigct;ion Prote&bholigct;ion Priviledge Essoyne or Wager of Law shall be
admitted or allowed.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Kingdomes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Kingdomes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Isles <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


