<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47287" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for the declaring vesting and setling of all such Moneys Goods and other things in His Majesty which were
received levied or colle&bholigct;ed in these late times and are remaining in the hands or possession of any Treasurers
Receivers Colle&bholigct;ors or others not pardoned by the A&bholigct; of Oblivion.[Rot. Parl. 13 C.II. p. I. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Doubts whether the Monies excepted to be accounted for, by 12 Car. II. c. II. are in the King.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Goods and Monies levied since the 30th Jan. 1642, and not pardoned, are vested in His Majesty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas divers Doubts have been made whether or no the Moneys Goods Chattels and other things
excepted to be accounted for in the A&bholigct; of Free and General Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion made and
passed in the Parliament begun at Westm[inster] the five and twentieth day of Aprill in the twelfth yeare of Your
Majesties Reign do belong unto and of right are in Your Majesty for that the same were not levied received
colle&bholigct;ed or taken by your Majesties Authority or to your Majesties use For remedy and clearing whereof We the
Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament humbly beseech your Majesty that it may be Ena&bholigct;ed And be it declared
ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the advice and consent of the Lords and
Commons assembled in Parliament and by the Authority [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] thereof That all and every sum and s&bhouov;ms of Money
Goods Plate Jewels Horses Armes Ammunition and other things whatsoever levied received or taken sithence the
thirtieth of January One thousand six hundred forty two by any of the late &bhopcrl;tended Authorities or by pretence or
colour of any Power or Authority derived or &bhopcrl;tended to be derived from them or any of them for any publique
use which are not pardoned by the said A&bholigct; which are not otherwise [invested<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and setled in the Kings Majesty and all
Bonds Obliga&bhocotil;ns and other Securities entred into for the same or any part thereof be and are hereby vested and
setled in the Kings Majestie His Heires and Successors and that His Sacred Majestie His Heires and Successors may
from time to time and att all times hereafter have demaund sue for and recover the same of all and every person and
persons theire Heires Executors and Administrators whoe are accountable for the same or in whose hands or possessions
soever the same were or are as if the same had beene leavyed received colle&bholigct;ed or taken in His Majesties Name by
Authority from His Majesty or to His Majesties use Any Lawe or Statute Usage or Custome to the contrary in
any wise notwithstanding</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Persons having received any of such Monies to account for the same;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and particularly those who have received the Revenues of Churches in Wales</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every person or persons which have received
any the aforesaid s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money from any Treasurer or Receiver for any publique use by way of Imprest
to bee accounted for which are not pardoned or discharged by the aforesaid A&bholigct; shall be liable to account and
called to account in such manner and forme as if they had received the same out of his Majesties Exchequer or
any other publique Treasury and particularly those persons that have received or colle&bholigct;ed the Revenues of any
Churches or Vicarages in Wales or in the County of Monmouth since the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred forty eight Provided they have all due allowances in theire accounts as all such persons whose accounts are
excepted in the A&bholigct; of Oblivion have or ought to have</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Commissions for Discovery of the same.</head>
			<para id="p5">And to the end His Majestie may be the better enabled to discover and sue for all such Moneys Goods and
other things invested in His Majesty by this A&bholigct; it is further ordained and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid
That His Majesty His Heires and Successors shall and may from time to time issue forth such and so many
C&bhooov;missions to such and soe many persons as his Majesty shall thinke fit either under the Great Seale of England
or the Seale of his Majesties Exchequer for the better discovering levying receiving and discharging the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Persons accountable enabled to sue for and levy all Arrears.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">None questioned but upon Prosecution begun before 24th June 1662.; To be prosecuted with Effe&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all persons accountable to His Majesty by this A&bholigct;
shall have full power and authority and are hereby enabled to sue for levy and recover from the parties from
whom the same was and is due and for which they are hereby accountable all s&bhouov;ms of Money and Arreares in
such manner and forme as they might have recovered and levied the same when they first grew due Provided
this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to call any person to account or to question any person
for Goods or other things remaining in his hands which shall not be called to account or some Informa&bhocotil;n against
him either in the Exchequer or Commissioners to be appointed as aforesaid before the foure and twentieth of June
which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand [One thousand<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] six hundred sixty two and that the said
Informa&bhocotil;n be prosecuted with effe&bholigct; within twelve moneths after the Exhibition thereof.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2"> vested <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


