<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47281" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXIII. An Act for Confirmation of Marriages. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. 11. p. 4. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Marriages since 1st May 1642 confirmed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS by vertue or colour of certaine Ordinances or certaine pretended A&bholigct;s or Ordinances diverse
marriages since the begining of the late troubles have beene had and solemnized in some other manner then
hath formerly beene used and accustomed, Now for the preventing and avoiding of all doubts and questions
touching the same It is Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie with the advice and assent of the Lords
and Commons in Parliament assembled and by [the<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Authority of the same That all marriages had or solemnized in
any of his Majestyes Dominions since the first day of May [in the yeare of our Lord<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] One thousand six hundred forty
and two before any Justice of Peace or reputed Justice of Peace of England or Wales or other his Majestyes
Dominions and by such Justice or reputed Justice soe pronounced or declared, And all marriages within any of his
Majesties Dominions since the same first day of May in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred forty two
had or solemnized according to the dire&bholigct;ion or true intent of any A&bholigct; or Ordinance or reputed A&bholigct; or Ordinance
of one or both Houses of Parliament, or of any Convention sitting at Westminster under the Name Stile or Title of
a Parliament or assumeing that Name Stile or Title shall be and shall be adjudged esteemed and taken to be, and to
have beene of the same and noe other force and effe&bholigct; as if such marriages had beene had and sollemnized according
to the Rites and Ceremonies established or used in the Church or Kingdome of England Any Law Custome or Usage
to the contrary thereof notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Issues upon Bastardy, or Lawfulness of Marriages, to be tried by Jury.</head>
			<para id="p3">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed That where in any Suite commenced or to be commenced in any of the Courts of
the common Law any issue hath beene joyned and not already tryed or determined, or shall be joyned upon the point
of Bastardy or lawfulnes of marriage for or concerning the marriages had and solemnized as aforesaid, the same Issues
shall be tryed by Jury of Twelve Men according to the course of Tryall of other Issues tryable by Jury at the
common Law and not otherwise Any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


