<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47288" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IV. An Act for a free and voluntary &bhopcrl;sent to his Majesty.[Rot. Parl 13 c. II. p. 1. nu. 4]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for this Grant.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The King may issue Commissions under the Great Seal for receiving Subscriptions; Acquittances by Receivers to be given without Fee. In what case Payment returned into Exchequer. Proviso as to Process</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee your Majesties most loyall and obedient subje&bholigct;s the Lords and Commons in Parliament assembled taking
into considera&bhocotil;n your Majesties great and important occasions for a speedy supply of moneys which can
no wayes be soe readily raised as by a free and voluntary present to your Majesty from those who are able and
willing to aide your Majesty in this suddain exigencie as a testimony of theire affe&bholigct;ions to your Majesty and in
ease of the poorer sort of your subje&bholigct;s doe therefore beseech your Majesty that it may be ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed
by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the advice and consent of the Lords and Commons in this &bhopcrl;sent
Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That your Majesty may issue out such and so many severall
Commissions under your Majesties Great Seale of England into the severall Counties Cities Towns corporate and
all other places in England and Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed dire&bholigct;ed to such persons as your
Majesty shall thinke fit for the receiving of such subscriptions as your Majesties good subje&bholigct;s shall voluntary offer
for supply of your Majesties pressing occasions and likewise to issue such other Commissions to such other persons
as your Majesty shall thinke fitt for colle&bholigct;ing and receiving the moneys so subscribed the acquittance of which
respe&bholigct;ive Receivers or of any one of them are immediately to be made and given without any fee upon payment
made and shall bee an absolute discharg for the s&bhouov;m soe subscribed And in case such subscriptions shall upon any
occasion be returned into the Court of Exchequer or any other place the payment thereof shall be likewise returned
together with the same Provided that no process shall issue out of the Exchequer against any person so subscribing
but within two yeares next after the passing of this A&bholigct;</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners to meet and may sever themselves.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to give Notice of Meetings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the better execution of the said service the said Commissioners of the Counties Cities Towns corporate
and all other places aforesaid respe&bholigct;ively shall and are hereby enjoyned withall convenient speed after the issuing
out and receipt of the said respe&bholigct;ive Commissions to meet togeather at the most usuall and common place of
meeting within each of the said Counties Cities Towns corporate and all other places and the said Commissioners
or soe many of them as shall be present at the said first generall meeting or the major part of them may by
theire consents and agreements sever themselves into Hundreds Rapes Wapentakes Wards and other places within
theire respe&bholigct;ive limits in such manner and form as to them shall seeme expedient And shall likewise from time
to time give notice of the respe&bholigct;ive times and places of theire meetings to the end that any persons bodies
politique or corporate may if they please resort to them and make such offers or present to your Majesty as theire
owne hearts shall prompt them to</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Limitation of Present from Peers and Commoners.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwaies that no person not being a Peer of this Realm shall in such Offer or present to your
Majesty exceed the sum of two hundred pounds nor any Peere of this Realm the s&bhouov;m of four hundred pounds</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. How long such Commissions to be effe&bholigct;ual.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alsoe That no Commissions to be issued out by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be of force or continue as
to the receiving of any moneys or subscriptions for moneys after the feast of S<emph type="p">t</emph> John the Baptist which shall be
in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and two.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Such Aids not to be without Authority of Parliament, nor to be drawn into Example.</head>
			<para id="p7">And be it hereby declared that no Commissions or Aids of this nature can be issued out or levied but by
Authority of Parliament And that this A&bholigct; and the supply hereby granted shall not be drawne into example for
the time to come.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


