<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47285" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for Safety and Preservation of His Majesties Person and Government against Treasonable and Seditious
practices and attempts [Rot. Parl. 13C.II. p. I. nu. I.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Seditious Sermons, Pamphlets, and Speeches.; 13 Eliz. c. 1.; What shall be adjudged.; To be proved by Two Witnesses.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p2">The Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament deeply weighing and considering the miseries and calamities
of well nigh twenty yeares before your Majesties happy Return and withall refle&bholigct;ing upon the causes &amp;
occasions of soe great and deplorable confusions do in all humility and thankfulnes acknowledge Your Majesties
incomparable Grace and Goodnes to Your People in Your Free and Generall Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion by
which Your Majestie hath beene pleased to deliver Your Subje&bholigct;s not only from the Punishment but alsoe from the
Reproach of their former miscarriages which unexampled Piety and Clemency of Your Majesty hath enflamed the
hearts of us Your Subje&bholigct;s with an ardent desire to expresse all possible zeal and duty in the care and preservation
of Your Majesties Person in whose Honour and Happines consists the good and welfare of Your People and in
preventing (as much as may be) all Treasonable and Seditious Pra&bholigct;ices and Attempts for the time to come And
because the growth and increase of the late troubles &amp; disorders did in a very great measure proceed from a
multitude of seditious Sermons Pamphlets and Speeches dayly preached printed and published with a transcendent
boldnes defaming the Perfon and Government of your Majestie and your Royall Father wherein men were to
much encouraged and (above all) from a wilfull mistake of the Supreame and lawfull Authoritie whilst men were
forward to cry up and maintaine those Orders and Ordinances Oathes and Covenants to be A&bholigct;s legall and
warrantable which in themselves had not the least colour of Law or Justice to support them from which kind of
distempers as the present Age is not yet wholly freed so Posterity may be apt to relapse into them if a timely remedy
be not provided Wee therefore the Lords and Commons in Parliament assembled having duly considered the &bhopcrl;misses
and remembring that in the Thirteenth yeare of the Reigne of Queene Elizabeth of ever blessed memory a right
good and profitable Law was made for preservation of Her Majesties Person Do most humbly beseech Your most
Excellent Majesty that it may be Ena&bholigct;ed And be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the
advice and consent of the Lords and Commons in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled and by Authoritie of the same
That if any person or persons whatsoever after the four and twentieth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred sixty and one during the naturall life of our most Gracious Soveraigne Lord the King (whom
Almighty God preserve and blesse with a long and prosperous Reigne) shall within the Realme or without compass
imagine invent devise or intend death or destruc&bhocotil;n or any bodily harm tending to death or destruc&bhocotil;n maim
or wounding imprisonment or restraint of the Person of the same our Soveraigne Lord the King or to deprive or depose him from the Stile Honour or Kingly Name of the Imperiall Crowne of this Realme or of any [other<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] His
&bhomtie; Dominions or Countreys or to levy war against His Majestie within this Realme or without or to move or
stirr any Foreiner or Strangers with force to invade this Realme or any other His Majesties Dominions or Countreys
being under His Majesties Obeysance And such Compassings Imaginations Inventions Devices or Intentions or any
of them shall ex&bhopcrl;ss utter or declare by any Printing Writing Preaching or Malicious and advised speaking being
legally convi&bholigct;ed thereof upon the Oaths of two lawfull and credible Witnesses upon triall or otherwise convi&bholigct;ed
or attainted by due course of Law then every such person and persons soe as aforesaid offending shall be deemed
declared and adjudged to be Traitors and shall suffer paines of death and alsoe loose and forfeit as in cases of
High Treason</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Certain Offences, during His Majesty's Life, to disable Persons to bear any Office.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Exception of Peerage.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any person or persons at any time after the four
and twentieth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and one during His &bhomtie; life
shall malitiously and advisedly publish or affirm the King to be an Heretick or a Papist or that he endeavours to
introduce Popery or shall maliciously and advisedly by writing printing preaching or other speaking expresse publish
utter or declare any Words Sentences or other thing or things to incite or stir up the people to hatred or dislike of
the Person of His Majestie or the established Government then every such person and persons being thereof legally
convi&bholigct;ed shall be disabled to have or enjoye and is hereby disabled and made incapable of having holding enjoying
or exercising any place Office or promotion Ecclesiasticall Civill or Military or any other Imployment in Church or
State other then that of his Peerage and shall likewise be liable to such further and other punishments as by the
Common Laws or Statutes of this Realm may be infli&bholigct;ed in such cases</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The Parliament begun 3d Nov. 1640 declared to be dissolved.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">No legislative Power in either or both Houses of Parliament without the King. Affirming that the said Parliament is not dissolved, or that there lies any Obligation upon any Person to endeavour a Change of Government, or that the Parliament has a legislative Power without the King.; Premunire.; 16 R. II. c.5.; The solemn League and Covenant unlawful.; Orders and Ordinances of both or either Houses of Parliament void.; Proviso for Indemnity by 12 Car. II. c. II</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And to the end that no man hereafter may be misled into any seditious or unquiet demeanour out of an
opinion that the Parliament begun and held att Westminster upon the third day of November in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred and forty is yet in being which is undoubtedly dissolved and determined and so is
hereby declared and adjudged to be fully dissolved and determined or out of an Opinion that there lies any
obligation upon him from any Oath Covenant or Engagement whatsoever to endeavour a change of Government
either in Church or State or out of an Opinion that both Houses of Parliament or either of them have a Legislative
Power without the King All which assertions have beene seditiously maintained in some Pamphlets lately printed
and are daily promoted by the a&bholigct;ive enemies of our Peace &amp; Happines Be it therefore further Ena&bholigct;ed by the
Authority aforesaid That if any person or persons at any time after the four and twentieth day of June in the yeare
of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and one shall maliciously and advisedly by Writing Printing Preaching
or other speaking express publish utter declare or affirm That the Parliament begun at Westminster upon the third
day of November in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and forty is not yet dissolved or is not
determined or that it ought to be in being or hath yet any continuance or existence or that there lies any
Obligation upon him or any other person from any Oath Covenant or Engagement whatsoever to endeavor a
change of Government either in Church or State or that both Houses of Parliament or either House of Parliament
have or hath a Legislative Power without the King or any other words to the same effe&bholigct; That then every such
person &amp; persons soe (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) aforesaid offending shall incurr the danger and penalty of a Premunire mentioned in a Statute
made in the sixteenth yeare of the Reigne of King Richard the Second And it is hereby alsoe declared That the Oath
usually called the Solemn League and Covenant was in it selfe an unlawfull Oath and imposed upon the Subje&bholigct;s
of this Realm against the Fundamentall Laws and Liberties of this Kingdome and that all Orders and Ordinances
or pretended Orders and Ordinances of both or either Houses of Parliament for imposing of Oathes Covenants or
Engagements Leavying of Taxes or Raising of Forces and Armes to which the Royall Assent either in Person or
by Commission was not expresly had or given were in theire first creation and making and still are and soe shall
be taken to be null and void to all intents and purposes whatsoever [Provided neverthelesse that all and every
person and persons Bodies Politique and Corporate who have beene or shall att any time hereafter be questioned
for any thing a&bholigct;ed or done by colour of any the Orders or Ordinances herein before men&bhocotil;ned and declared to be
null and void and are indempnified by an A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct;. of Free and Generall Pardon Indempnity and
Oblivion made in the twelfth yeare of His Majesties Reign that now is or shall be indempnified by any A&bholigct; of
Parliament shall and may make such use of the said Orders and Ordinances for theire Indempnity according to the
true intent and meaning of the said A&bholigct; and no other as he or they might have done if this A&bholigct; had not beene
made Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary notwithstanding<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. No Person to be prosecuted for any Offences in this A&bholigct; (other than Treason) unless by special Order from His Majesty. Limitation of Prosecution.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwaies That noe person be prosecuted for any of the offences in this A&bholigct; men&bhocotil;ned (other then
such as are made and declared to be high Treason) unlesse it be by Order of the Kings Majestie His Heires
or Successors under his or theire Signe Manual or by Order of the Councell Table of His Majesty His Heires
or Successors dire&bholigct;ed unto the Attorney Generall for the time being or some other of the Council learned to
His Majesty His Heires or Successors for the time being nor shall any person or persons by vertue of this
present A&bholigct; incur any of the penalties herein before men&bhocotil;ned unlesse he or they be prosecuted within six moneths
next after the Offence committed and indi&bholigct;ed thereupon within three moneths after such prosecu&bhocotil;n Any thing
herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Treasons and Offences within this A&bholigct; to be proved by Two Witnesses viva voce.</head>
			<para id="p8">[Provided always and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That no person or persons shall be indi&bholigct;ed arraigned condemned convi&bholigct;ed
or attainted for any of the Treasons or Offences aforesaid unlesse the same Offender or Offenders be thereof accused
by the Testimony and deposition of two lawfull and credible Witnesses upon Oath which Witnesses at the time of
the said Offender or Offenders arraignment shall be brought in person before him or them face to face and shall
openly avow and maintain upon Oath what they have to say against him or them concerning the Treason or
Offences contained in the said Indi&bholigct;ment unles the party or parties arraigned shall willingly without violence confess
the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Proviso for Privilege of Debate in Parliament;</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">and for Repeal or Alteration of Laws, or redressing public Grievances</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">Provided likewise and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to deprive
either of the Houses of Parliament or any of theire Members of theire just ancient Freedome and priviledge of
debating any matters or busines which shall be propounded or debated in either of the said Houses or att any
Conferences or Committees of both or either of the said Houses of Parliament or touching the repeal or altera&bhocotil;n
of any old or &bhopcrl;paring any new Lawes or the redressing (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) any publique grievance but that the said Members of either
of the said Houses and the Assistants of the House of Peers and every of them shall have the same freedome of
speech and all other Priviledges whatsoever as they had before the making of this A&bholigct; Any thing in this A&bholigct; to
the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Trial and Pardon of Peers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p11">[Provided alwaies and be it Ordained and Ena&bholigct;ed That no Peer of this Realm shall be tried for any offence
against this A&bholigct; but by his Peers and further That every Peer who shall be convi&bholigct;ed of any offence against this
A&bholigct; after such convi&bholigct;ion be disabled during his life to sit in Parliament unlesse His Majesty shall graciously be
pleased to pardon him And if His Majesty shall grant his pardon to any Peer of this Realm or Commoner
convi&bholigct;ed of any offence against this A&bholigct; after such Pardon granted the Peer or Commoner so pardoned shall be
restored to all intents and purposes as if he had never beene convi&bholigct;ed Any thing in this Law to the contrary
in any wise notwithstanding.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">as <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


