<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47284" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXVI. An Act impowering the Master of the Rolls for the time being to make Leases for yeares in order to new build
the old houses belonging to the Rolls. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) [Rot.Parl.12 C.II. p. 4. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that the House of the Rolls is out of Repair, by reason that the Master of the Rolls is not enabled to grant Leases.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Master of the Rolls enabled to grant Leases for 41 Years.; The Chapel and House of the Rolls, &amp;c. excepted.; Proviso as to Provision for new-building of Houses.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Mansion House Ground and Tenements with the appurtenances belonging to the Master of
the Rolls as Master of the Rolls are much out of repaire and not capeable of improvement in regard the
former Masters of the Rolls were not enabled to grant such leases, and for such termes as might incourage tennants
to build and to repaire Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings Most Excellent Majestie and the Lord&bholngs; and Commons
in this present Parliament assembled And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the Master of the
Rolls for the time being and his successors Masters of the Rolls shall have good right full power and lawfull
authority dureing the time he or they shall continue Master of the Rolls by writing indented under hand and seale
to grant and make leases for one and forty yeares or for any lesser terme to commence from the makeing of
any such leases of all and singular the premises or any part thereof the Chappell of the Rolls with a convenient
Mansion House Court Yard Garden Stable Coach house and other Outhouses and buildings fitt for the use and
habitation of the Master of the Rolls onely excepted, which lease and leases soe to be made shall be good and
effe&bholigct;uall in law to all intents and purposes as if such Master of the Rolls for the time being as shall soe make
the same had beene seized of the premisses of a good estate in fee simple. Provided that in leases where provision
is made for new building of houses or tenements that the yearely rent of twenty shillings at the least shall be
reserved upon every lease of such a quantity of the said premisses as shall be sett out and assigned by the Master
of the Rolls for the time being for any one house or tenement to be built upon, and that in leases where there is noe
provision for new building the like usuall rent that hath beene paid or reserved for the greater part of seaven
yeares now last past or more shall be yearely reserved. Provided alsoe that the Master of the Rolls for the time
being or any succeeding Master of the Rolls after the premises have been once letten according to the power
given as abovesaid shall not grant or make any new or concurrent lease untill within seaven yeares of the expiration
of the lease then in being, nor for any lesser rent then was reserved upon the former lease, nor for any longer
terme then for the terme of one and twenty yeares from the makeing of such new Lease.</para>
		<para id="p3">ITEM quedam peti&bhocotil;es privatas &bhopubr;sonas concernentes in se formam A&bholigct;us continentes exhibita fuerunt &bhopcrl;dco D&ntilde;o
Regi in Part &bhopcrl;d quar&umacr; tituli subscribuntur viz</para>
		<para id="p4">PRIVATE ACTS</para>
		<para id="p5">1. An Act for restoring of Henry Lord Arundell of Warder to the possession of his estate.</para>
		<para id="p6">2. An Act for restitution of Thomas Earle of Arundell, Surrey, and Norfolk to the dignity and title of Duke
of Norfolke.</para>
		<para id="p7">3. An Act to restore to Wentworth Earle of Roscomon of the Kingdome of Ireland all the Honours Castles
Lordships Land&bholngs; Tenements and Hereditaments in Ireland whereof James Earle of Roscomon his Great Grandfather
Robert Earle of Roscomon his grandfather, or James late Earle of Roscomon his father were in possession on the
three and twentieth of O&bholigct;ober One thousand six hundred forty one.</para>
		<para id="p8">4. An Act for enabling of John Newton the younger and William Oakeley to make sale of Land&bholngs; for payment
of debts and raising portions.</para>
		<para id="p9">5. An Act for restoreing Sir George Hamilton unto his Land&bholngs; and estate in Ireland.</para>
		<para id="p10">6. An Act for maintenance of the Viccar for the time being of the Viccaridge of Royston in the Counties of
Hertford and Cambridge and of his successors Viccars of the said Vicaridge.</para>
		<para id="p11">7. An Act for enabling Sir William Wray to sell Land&bholngs; for payment of his debts, and raising of portions for his
younger children.</para>
		<para id="p12">8. An Act for naturalizing of Gerrard Vantethusen Daniell Demetrius Theodore Cocke John Cravenburgh &amp;
others</para>
		<para id="p13">9. An Act for the levying of certaine moneys due upon the colle&bholigct;ion for the protestants of Piedmont.</para>
		<para id="p14">10. An Act for the naturalizing of John Boreel Es&bhoqesq; eldest sonne of Sir William Boreel Knight and Baronet.</para>
		<para id="p15">11. An Act for the naturalizing of Abraham Watchtor borne beyond the Seas.</para>
		<para id="p16">12. An Act for restoring of Sir Thomas Crimes Baronet to his estate.</para>
		<para id="p17">13. An Act enabling George Faunt of Foston in the County of Leicester Es&bhoqesq; to sell and convey part of his
Land&bholngs; for payment of severall debts and legacies charged upon his estate by Sir William Faunt Knight deceased and
for the raising of portions for his younger children and makeing his wife a joynture.</para>
		<para id="p18">14. An Act for naturalizing of [Frances<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Hyde and others.</para>
		<para id="p19">15. An Act to enable Joseph Micklethwaite an infant and his trustees to sell land for payment of his fathers
debts.</para>
		<para id="p20">16. An Act for raising portions and makeing provision for maintenance for the younger children of Sir Edward
Gostwicke Baronet.</para>
		<para id="p21">17. An Act for confirming the sale of the Manour of Hitcham sold to Charles Doe by Sir John Clarke Knight
and Baronet, and for setling and disposing other the Land&bholngs; of the said Sir John Clarke and Dame Philodelphia
his Wife.</para>
		<para id="p22">18. An Act for the setling of some of the Manours &amp; Land&bholngs; of the Earle of Cleavland in trustees to be sold
for the satisfieing of the debts of the said Earle and of Thomas Lord Wentworth his some.</para>
		<para id="p23">19. An Act for the disappropriating of the Re&bholigct;ory appropriate of Preston and uniting and consolidating of the
said Re&bholigct;ory and of the Vicaridge of the Church of Preston and for the assureing of the Advowson and right of
patronage of the same unto the Master Fellowes and Schollers of Emanuell Colledge in Cambridge and their
successors.</para>
		<para id="p24">20. An Act for makeing the precin&bholigct; of Covent Garden parochiall.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">This Act received the Royal Assent in the Form of a Private A&bholigct;, vizt "Soit fait come il est desire;" and is in the Bundle
of Private A&bholigct;s at the Parliament Office; but it is inrolled as a Public A&bholigct; on the Fourth Part of the Rolls of this Year, and
has usually been printed as Chapter XXXVI.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">On the Roll the Name is not intelligible, the Letter "e" remaining with a dot or tittle at the top as an "i", but in the Original
A&bholigct; it is "Frances."</note>
	</section>
</report>


