<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47290" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER VI. An Act declaring the sole Right of the Militia to be in (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) King and for the present ordering &amp; disposing the same.[Rot. Parl 13 C.II, p. 1. nu. 6;]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that the Command of the Militia, and of all Forces by Sea and Land, is the undoubted Right of His Majesty;</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">and that an A&bholigct; is under Consideration touching the Militia. Militia and Land Forces to be exercised as usual</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Foresmuch as within all His Majesties Realmes and Dominions the sole Supreme Government Command
and Disposition of the Militia and of all Forces by Sea and Land and of all Forts and Places of strength is
and by the Lawes of England ever was the undoubted Right of His Majesty and His Royall Predecessors Kings &amp;
Queenes of England and that both or either of the Houses of Parliament cannot nor ought to pretend to the same
nor can nor lawfully may raise or leavy any Warr Offensive or Defensive against His Majesty His Heires or lawfull
Successors and yet the contrary thereof hath of late yeares beene pra&bholigct;ised almost to the Ruine and Destru&bholigct;ion
of this Kingdome and during the late Usurped Governments many evill and rebellious Principles have beene distilled
into the minds of the People of this Kingdome which unlesse &bhopcrl;vented may breake forth to the disturbance of the
Peace and Quiet thereof And whereas an A&bholigct; is under considera&bhocotil;n for exercising the Militia with most safety and
ease to the King and His People which A&bholigct; cannot as yet be perfe&bholigct;ed Be it therefore Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords &amp; Commons assembled in Parliament That
the Militia and Land Forces of this Kingdome and of the Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweed
now under the power of Leiutennants or their Deputies shall be exercised ordered and managed untill the five &amp;
twentieth day of March next ensuing in such manner as the same now is a&bholigct;ually exercised ordered and managed
according to such Commissions and Instru&bholigct;ions as they formerly have or from time to time shall receive from His
Majesty</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Recital that Insurre&bholigct;ions have been.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Persons who have a&bholigct;ed by Commission of Lieutenancy indemnified.; Magistrates, &amp;c. indemnified in respe&bholigct; of Proceedings against Offenders, from 24th June 1660 to 20th July 1661</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And whereas since the twenty fourth of June One thousand six hundred and sixty there have beene [Inserre&bholigct;ions<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]
by occasion whereof diverse of His Majesties good Subje&bholigct;s have beene murdered and for the securing the Peace
of the Nation and preventing further disorders diverse persons suspe&bholigct;ed to be Fanaticks Se&bholigct;aries or Disturbers of
the Peace have beene assaulted arrested detained or imprisoned and diverse Armes have been seized and Houses
searched for Armes or suspe&bholigct;ed persons Bee it therefore further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and
every person and persons whoe have or shall have a&bholigct;ed or done any thing in execution of any Commission or
Commissions of Leiutenancy issued by the Kings Majesty that nowe is or by colour of them or any of them [or<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
touching or concerning the same or any of them or relating thereunto shalbe and are hereby saved harmelesse and
undempnified in this behalfe and alsoe all Magistrates Justices of the Peace Officers and Ministers of Justice and all
persons that have or shall have a&bholigct;ed by or under them or by theire or any of theire Commands since the said
twenty fourth day of June One thousand six hundred and sixty untill the twentieth day of July One thousand
six hundred sixty and one as to any assaulting arresting detaining or imprisoning any person suspe&bholigct;ed to be
Fanatick Se&bholigct;ary or Disturber of the Peace or seizing of Armes or searching of Houses for Armes or for suspe&bholigct;ed
persons shall be and are hereby saved harmelesse and indempnified in that behalfe</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Counties, &amp;c. overcharged.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall after the five and twentieth of March next
be prejudiciall to any County Citty or place within this Kingdome which are overcharged with Men and Armes
beyond theire ancient proportion</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso against compelling Subje&bholigct;s to go out of the Kingdom.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided That neither this A&bholigct; nor any matter or thing therein contained shall bee deemed construed or taken to
extend to the giving or declaring of any Power for the transporting of any the Subje&bholigct;s of this Realme or any way
compelling them to march out of this Kingdome otherwise then by the Lawes of England ought to be done</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Lieutenants, Deputy Lieutenants, Officers, &amp;c. to take the Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided That no person whatsoever shall be capable of a&bholigct;ing as Leiutenant [or Deputy Leiutenant<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] or other
Officer or Souldier by vertue of this A&bholigct; who hath not already taken the Oathes of Allegiance and Supremacy since
the return of His Majesty into England untill he shall take the same according to the Lawes and Statutes of this
Kingdome Which Oathes the Lords of His Privy Councell or any six of them are hereby impowred to administer
to any Peer of this Realm whoe shall be commissionated by vertue of this A&bholigct; and the Deputy Leiutenants or
any two of them in theire respe&bholigct;ive Counties to any Commoner.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Insurre&bholigct;ions <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


