<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47297" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER XIII. An Act for vesting the Arreares of the Excise and New Impost in His Majesty [Rot. Parl. 13 C. II. p. 1. nu. 13.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>All Monies owing upon Excise by any Laws or Ordinances vested in His Majesty,</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">who may recover the same from all Personsaccountable</emph>.; 33 H. VIII. c. 39. &sect;50.</para>
		<para id="p2">Bee it Declared and Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the
Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament and by the authority thereof That all and every sum and sums
of money any wayes due or owing from or by any person or persons whatsoever for or touching the Imposition or
Duty called the Excise heretofore imposed and made payable upon Beere Ale or any other Comodities by any Lawes
or pretended Lawes or Ordinances and all Debts therefore owing whether by Obligation or upon Accompt from
Farmers of Excise or any other person or persons whatsoever or any of theire Securities and not pardoned by His
Majesties most Gratious A&bholigct; of Pardon and Oblivion be and are hereby vested and setled in the Kings Majestie His
Heires and Successors And that his sacred Majesty his Heires and Successors [may<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] from time to time and att all times
hereafter have demand sue for and recover the same of all and every person and persons theire Heires Executors
and Administrators having assetts whoe are any way accountable for the same or any part thereof and from his and
theire respe&bholigct;ive Sureties and Secureties as if the same Duties of Excise or New Impost had beene lawfull assessed
imposed and colle&bholigct;ed and as if the severall pretended A&bholigct;s Orders and Ordinances assessing and imposing the
same had beene good true legall and effe&bholigct;uall A&bholigct;s of Parliament and had in expresse words given and granted
all and every the said Duties of Excise or new Impost unto His Majesty and as if the Obliga&bhocotil;ns and Recognizances
entred into by the respe&bholigct;ive Sureties &amp; Securities had att the time of entring into the same beene taken in. His
Majesties Name according to the forme prescribed in the Statute made in the three and thirtieth yeare of the
Reigne of King Henry the Eight</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Allowances.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">12 Car. II. c. 11</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwaies That all and every person and persons accomptable by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall have all such
due allowance in his or theire accompts as all such persons whose accompts are excepted in an A&bholigct; entituled An
A&bholigct; of Free and Generall Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion have or ought to have</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Limitation of Suit.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwaies That no person shall be questioned or molested for any of the Duties herein or hereby
vested in His Majesty unlesse he shall be sued or prosecuted with effe&bholigct; before the five and twentieth day of
December which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty two.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Persons accountable may levy and recover Arrears.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alsoe and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all persons accomptable to His Majesty by
this A&bholigct; shall have power and authority and are hereby enabled to sue for levy and recover from any person or
persons whoe doe stand indebted unto them in any sum of money for the Duty or Impost of Excise for which
they are hereby accomptable all s&bhouov;ms of money and Arreares unsatisfied in as full and ample manner and form
as they might have received and levied the same when they first grewe due.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


