<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47292" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for providing necessary Carriages for His Majestie in His Royall Progresse and Removalls. [Rot. Parl. 13 C. II. p. 1. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Recital of 12 Car. II. c. 24. &sect; 13.; and that the said Act may prove inconvenient to the King in His Royal Progresses through the Realm.; Clerk or Chief Officer of His Majesty's Carriages, by Warrant from the Green Cloth, to give Notice for providing Carts, &amp;c. for, His Majesty's Use.; Refusing to furnish His Majesty with necessary Carriages; On Proof by Oath of Officer or Two Witnesses,; Penalty 40s</head>
			<para id="p1">WHEREAS by an A&bholigct; made in Parliament in the Twelfth Yeare of His Majesties. Reign Entituled An A&bholigct;
for taking away the Court of Wards and Liveries and Tenures in capite and by Knight Service &amp;
Purveyance and for setling a Revenue upon His Majestie in lieu thereof It was (amongst other things) Ena&bholigct;ed for
the reasons and recompence therein expressed That from thenceforth no person or persons by any Warrant
Commission or Authority under the Great Seale or otherwise by colour of buying or making provison or purveyance
for His Majesty or any Queene of England [for the time being or of any the Children of any King or Queene
of England<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] that shall bee or for his theire or any of theire Houshold shall take any Cart Carriage or other thing
whatsoever of any of the Subje&bholigct;s of His Majesty His Heires or Successors without the free and full consent of
the Owner or Owners thereof had and obtained without Menace or enforcement nor shall summon warne take
use or require any the said Subjects to furnish or find any Horses Oxen or other Cattell Cart Ploughs Waynes
or other Carriages for the use of His Majesty His Heires or Successors or of any Queene of England or of any
Childe or Children of any the Kings or Queenes of England for the time being for the carrying the Goods of
His Majesty His Heires or Successors or the said Queenes or Children or any of them without such full and free
consent as aforesaid Any Lawe Statute Custome or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding Which A&bholigct; may prove
very prejudiciall and inconvenient to the Kings Majesty in His Royall Progresses upon His necessary occasions to
severall parts of this Realme in case any person or persons shall obstinately refuse voluntarily to provide sufficient
Carriages for Royall service att ordinary and usuall rates for such Carriages as are paid by others of His Subje&bholigct;s
in such places contrary to the true intent and meaning of the said A&bholigct; Be it therefore Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings
most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled That the Clarke or Cheife Officer of His Majesties Carriages shall three dayes att least before His
Majesties Arrivall by Warrant from the Greene Cloth give notice in writing to two or more of His Majesties
Justices of the Peace next adjoyning to provide such a number of Carts and Carriages from the places next
adjacent as His Majesty shall have present use of expressing the certainty of that number as alsoe the time and
place when and where the said Carts and Carriages are to attend which Carriages shall consist of foure able
Horses or six Oxen or foure Oxen and two Horses for each of which Cart or Carriage the respective Owners
shall receive six pence for each mile they shall goe laden And that in case any of His Majesties Subje&bholigct;s of this
Realme shall refuse to provide and furnish His Majesty that now is or His Queene that shall bee or His or Her
Houshold in theire [Progresse<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] or Removals with such sufficient and necessary Carriages for theire Wardrobe and
other necessaries for ready moneys tendred to them or shall without just and reasonable cause refuse to make
theire appearance with such sufficient Carts and Carriages as are before exprest that then upon due proofe and
convi&bholigct;ion of such negle&bholigct; and refusall by the Oath of the Constable or other Officer or twoe other credible
Witnesses before the said Justices of the Peace of the County or Maior or other Cheife Officer of the City or
Corporation where he or they inhabit (which Oath they shall have power to administer) the party soe refuseing
shall for such his refusall and negle&bholigct; forfeit the summe of Forty shillings to the Kings Majesties use to be forthwith
leavied by distresse and sale of his Goods and Chattels (rendring to the parties the overplus upon every such
sale if there shall be any) by Warrant from the said Justices of the Peace Maior or other Cheiffe Officer</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Horses, &amp;c. not to travel above a Day's Journey.</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">Ready Money. Officer taking Gift to spare Persons, &amp;c.; Penalty &pound;10.; Wrongful charging any Person.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwaies That no Horses Oxen Cart or Wayn shall be enforced to travell above one dayes journey
from the place where they receive theire Lading and that ready payment shall be made in hand for the said
Carriages att the place of Lading without delay according to the aforesaid Rates And in case any Justice of the
Peace Maior Cheife Officer or Constable shall take any Gift or Reward to spare any person or persons from
making such Carriage or shall injuriously charge or greive any person through envy hatred or evill will whoe
ought not to make such Carriage or shall Impresse more Carriages then he shall be dire&bholigct;ed from the Green
Cloth to do That then upon due proofe and convi&bholigct;ion thereof the party soe offending shall forfeit the sum of
Ten pounds to the party thereby greived or any other whoe shall sue for the same to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion
of Debt in any of His Majesties Courts of Record wherein no Prote&bholigct;ion Essoyn or Wager of Law shall be
allowed And in case any person or persons shall presume to take upon him or them to impresse any Horses
Oxen Cart Waine or Carriages for his Majesties service other then the person so impowered then he or they soe
offending shall upon due convi&bholigct;ion of the said offence incur and suffer the punishment contained in the first
recited A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Rates for Lodging for His Majesty's Servants.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Where Diet paid for, Lodging found</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And whereas of late in his Majesties Progresses excessive rates and prices have beene exa&bholigct;ed from his Majestyes
Servants for Lodging Horse meat Stable roome and other accommodations Be it therefore Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority
aforesaid That none of his Majesties said Servants shall be compelled to pay above One shilling by the night for every
Bed that they shall use for themselves nor above Six pence by the night for every Bed that they shall use for
theire Servants And that in all such Houses where any of his Majesties said servants shall pay for theire diett or
for hay and provender for theire Horses convenient lodging shall be provided for themselves and theire Servants
without paying any thing for the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Rates and Prices to be set by Two Justices of the Peace.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Rates to be proclaimed.; Taking higher Rates.; Penalty 40s.; Continuance of A&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that any twoe or more of the Justices of the Peace neere
adjoyning to the Roade through which his Majesty is to passe shall imediately after notice in writing from the said
Green Cloth and Avenor under theire hands and seales set downe and appoint such reasonable rates and prices to
bee paid during his Majesties abode there both for Hay and Oats and other accommodations for Horses as they in
theire discretion shall thinke meete which Rates one day att the least before his Majesties comeing to such place
the said Justices shall cause to be proclaimed in the Markett Towne next to such place and in such of the
Neighbouring Townes and Villages as to them shall seeme meete to the end that notice may bee taken of such rates
and prices And if any person shall take any other sum then what is or shall be soe limited either for Lodging
Horse meat Stable roome or other such accommodations and be [therefore<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] convi&bholigct;ed by confession of the party or by
the Oath of one credible Witnes before any one Justice of the Peace (which Oath the said Justice of the Peace is
hereby authorized to administer) That then in such case every person so offending shall forfeit and pay to the
party greived the sum of Forty shillings the same to bee levied by distresse by Warrant from the said Justice of the
Peace and sale thereof returning the overplus to the party (the charge of the distreining being first dedu&bholigct;ed)
This Act to have continuance till the end of the first Session of the next Parliament and no longer</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Progresses <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">thereof <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


