<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47294" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act to prevent the unlawfull Coursing Hurting or Killing of Deere. [Rot. Parl. 13 C. II. p. 1. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Unlawful Hunting or killing of Deer.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;20; Distress.; Want of Distress, Punishment.; Proviso against Double Punishment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">FOR the better preventing of the unlawfull coursing hurting takeing or killing of Deere by many idle loose
and disorderly Persons Be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie and by the advice and consent
of Lords and Commons in Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That if any person or persons
shall from and after the First day of August next unlawfully course kill hurt or take away any Red or Fallowe
Deere in any Forrest Chase Purliew Paddock Wood Park or other Ground where Deere are or have beene usually
kept within the Realm of England or Dominion of Wales without the consent of the Owner or person cheifly
intrusted with the custody thereof or shall be aiding or assisting therein and shall be convi&bholigct;ed thereof by the
confession of the party or by the Oath of one or more credible Witnesses before one or more Justices of the Peace
(whose are hereby impowered to administer an Oath to that purpose) such person being prosecuted for such Offence
within six monthes after such offence done that then every person soe offending shall forfeit for every such
offence the sum of Twenty pounds to be leavyed by way of Distresse upon the Goods and Chattells of every such
Offender by Warrant under the Justices hand before whom such convi&bholigct;ion shall be made the one moyetie of the
said Twenty pounds to be given to the Informer and the other moyety to the Owner of the Deere and for want
of sufficient Distresse the Offender shall be committed to the House of Corre&bholigct;ion for six monthes and there to
be put to hard labor or to the c&bhooov;mon Gaol for one whole yeare without Baile or Mainprize at the discretion of the
[Justices<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of Peace before whom such convi&bholigct;ion shall be (and not to be discharged from thence till he or they have
given sufficient Sureties for theire good behavior for one whole yeare next ensueing after his or theire inlargement)
Provided that where any Offender shall be punished by force of this A&bholigct; that he shall not be prosecuted nor
incur the Penalty of any other Law or Statute for the same Offence</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">Justice &amp; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


