<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47309" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An A&bholigct; for enlarging and repairing of Common High wayes; [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. I. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that former Laws are ineffe&bholigct;ual.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Choice of Surveyors of Highways regulated</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the former Lawes and Statutes for the mending and repairing of the Common and Publick
High wayes of this Realme have not beene found so effe&bholigct;uall as is desired by meanes whereof and the
extraordinary burthens carried upon Waggons and other Carriages diverse of the said High wayes are become very
dangerous and almost unpassable For remedy whereof bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by
and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same That the Church Wardens and Constables or Tything Men of every
Parish Town Village or Hamlett for the time being within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and
Town of Berwick upon Tweed shall upon Monday or Tuesday in the Easter weeke yearely (whereof notice shall
be publiquely given the Sunday foregoeing in the Church immediately after the end of Morning Prayer) with the
advice and consent of the major part of the Inhabitants which shall be then present choose twoe or more sufficient
and able persons residing and inhabiting within theire Parish Town Village or Hamlett to be Surveyors of theire
High Wayes for the yeare next ensueing and give notice thereof in writing to the persons chosen and for default
of such choice soe to be made as aforesaid the Church Wardens Constables or Tything Men and Inhabitants of
every such Parish Town Village or Hamlet shall forfeit and loose the sum of Five pounds</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Surveyors to view Highways, &amp;c.; Penalty &pound;5.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and to consider what Repairs wanting, and the Cost thereof; and, together with Householders, lay Assessment,; not exceeding 6d. in the Pound in one Year.; Assessments to be allowed and signed by Justice.; Persons not paying Assessment to pay Double.; Proviso.; Surveyors to see that Nuisances are reformed.; Surveyors to hire Labourers, &amp;c. yearly</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every Surveyor and Surveyors within Twenty Dayes
next after notice given unto him or them of his and theire Ele&bholigct;ion as aforesaid or of the Publication of this
A&bholigct; shall upon the penalty of five pounds view and survey all the C&bhooov;mon and Publique High Wayes and Bridges
within the Parish Town Village or Hamlett wherein he or they are respe&bholigct;ive Surveyor or Surveyors and all
Watercourses Causeys and Pavements therein which are to be repaired and amended at a Publique Charge of the
said Parish Town Village or Hamlett and shall consider what Reparations shall be needfull to bee made and what
Sum or S&bhouov;ms of money will be requisite to be raised for the amending repairing and enlargeing of the same
over and above what will be done by the other Lawes made for the amending of the said High wayes and thereupon
shall togeather with two or more substantiall Householders of the said Parish Town Village or Hamlet called by
the Surveyors to theire assistance within ten dayes after such Survey made lay one or more Assessment or
Assessments upon every Inhabitant rated to the poore and upon every Occupier of Lands Houses Tythes Impropriate
or Appropriate Portions of Tythes Coal Mines and other Mines saleable Underwoods Stock Goods or other
personal Estate not being Household stuffe within the said Parish Town Village or Hamlet for the repairing
amending and enlargeing of the said Publick and C&bhooov;mon High wayes as they the said Surveyors and other the
substantial Householders or the major part of them shall thinke fitt meet and necessary which said Assessment
or Assessments shall not exceed in the whole above the s&bhouov;m of Six pence in the pound in any one yeare
according to the reall value of the same and twenty pounds in Money Goods Stock or other personall Estate shall
be rated equally to twenty shillings a yeare in Lands And every such Assessment soe made shall within Six
dayes after be presented to some Justice of the Peace neare adjoyning to the Parish where it is made to bee seene
allowed and signed by him And after such allowance every person so assessed or taxed that shall not within
twenty dayes after demand made by the Surveyors or one of them pay such sum or s&bhouov;ms of money assessed on
him or her or them unto the Surveyors or one of them shall forfeit and pay double so much as he [she<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] or they
are assessed to pay unlesse (upon complaint made to the said Justice of wrong done to such person by that
Assessment) the said Justice shall thinke fitt to alter the same And in case where C&bhooov;mon Nusances are in High
wayes or where Ditches or Watercourses adjoyning unto High wayes are not scoured and dressed the said Surveyors
shall see the same reformed and the Offenders punished according to Law dedu&bholigct;ing out of the moneys soe to
be raised his reasonable charges for prosecution And for the more effe&bholigct;uall mending the High wayes and Parish
Bridges and Streets the Surveyors afore men&bhocotil;ned shall yearely att the most convenient and fitting time betweene
the first of May and (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) last of August hire Labourers Workemen Carts and Carriages for amending the High wayes
Streets Parish Bridges aforesaid and Water courses and shall cause them to be well and sufficiently mended</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Surveyors to dire&bholigct; Persons chargeable with Wain or Cart to come to labour or send their Carts, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">and to pay for the same according to the Rate of the Country for Overwork.; Questions respe&bholigct;ing the same to be settled by Justice.; Persons refusing, &amp;c.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And for the better effe&bholigct;ing thereof Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said Surveyors or any
of them within theire several Limits and Jurisdi&bholigct;ions may yearely as he shall see cause and need require dire&bholigct;
and appoint every person and persons who by the former Lawes &amp; Statutes of this Realme are chargeable
with Wayn or Cart to the amending of the High wayes and every other person and persons chargeable to come
to labour at the said Wayes to send his or her Cart or Wayn and Team so furnished as by the Lawes is
dire&bholigct;ed or to come and worke for the amending of the High wayes for so many dayes as by the Lawes are
appointed or for so many of them as the said Surveyors shall thinke needfull and appoint for which Teames
worke and labour the said Surveyors shall pay unto such Workemen and Owner of such Teames Carts and Waynes
according to the usuall rate of the Countrey for such worke as they shall doe over and above what by the other
Lawes made for the amending the High wayes they are appointed to doe And if any question shall arise about
the value or worth of such worke or labour for Man or Teames some Justice of the Peace neare adjoyning and
not living in the said Parish shall determine what is fitt to be allowed for such worke And in case any person
so charged to send his or her Team to worke as aforesaid shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to do so such person soe
refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing shall forfeit ten shillings for every day that he or shee shall make such default and every
Labourer Eighteene pence for such day that he negle&bholigct;s to worke as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. No Assessment both for Land and Stock.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided that no person or persons occupying any Lands shall be assessed and taxed both for the said Lands
and the Stock which he or they shall use or imploy upon the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Where Roads not of the Breadth of Eight Yards Surveyors to lay out Lands adjoining.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Writ of ad quod damnum first being issued; and Surveyors giving Satisfa&bholigct;ion to Owners of the Land.; Such new Ways to be repaired, &amp;c. as the former Ways</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said
Surveyors of the High wayes for the time being of every such Parish Town Village or Hamlet within theire several
Precin&bholigct;s from time to time by order from the Quarter Sessions and upon the view and by the allowance or
consent of twoe or more Justices of the Peace of the County authorized thereunto by the Sessions wherein such
Parish Town Village or Hamlet shall lie under theire Hands and Seales in writing where any c&bhooov;mon or publique
High way is not of the breadth of eight yards from the shoares and brincks of the Ditches on either side or
from the bancks and hedges where there are no Ditches to assign and lay out so much of any mans several
Lands next adjoyning to the said C&bhooov;mon and Publick High way where they shall thinke it needfull and it may
conveniently be done as shall enlarge the said way to be the full breadth of eight yards or so much broader
(toward the breadth of eight yards) then now it is as conveniently the place will beare from the said Shoares
Ditches Banks or Hedges by the consent of the Owner or Owners of the said Lands according to his or theire
respe&bholigct;ive Interests therein or otherwise by Order of the Justices of Peace at theire Quarter Sessions after a Writt
of Ad quod damnum first issued out and returned to assign and lay out a new and more comodious way in and
over the said Lands next or neare adjoyning to the said common and publick High wayes the said Surveyors first
giveing [such<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] satisfa&bholigct;ion for the said ground unto the respe&bholigct;ive Owners of the same according to theire severall
and respe&bholigct;ive Interest in the whole not exceeding twenty yeares purchase Provided alwaies That if any Common
or publick High way or wayes shall be so altered and changed as is aforesaid that then and in such case the same
new Way or Wayes as alsoe any new Way or Wayes altered or to be altered by a Writ of Ad quod damnum
shall from time to time be repaired and amended by such Parish or Parishes Town Hamlet or Village or by such
Person and Persons and in such manner and forme as the said old and [former<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] common or publick High way
or wayes was or were to be repaired and amended</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Where not sufficient Gravel, &amp;c. to repair, Surveyor may dig for the same in neighbouring Commons, &amp;c. without paying for the same;</head>
			<para id="p10">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That where there is not sufficient Gravell Chalk Sand
Cinders or Stones within any Parish Town Village or Hamlet to repaire theire Common and publick High wayes
it shall be lawfull for the Surveyor and Surveyors and such Person and Persons as he or they shall appoint upon the
allowance and approbation of any two Justices of Peace within the said County to dig take and carry away Gravel
Chalk Sand Cinders or Stones out of the Wast and C&bhooov;mon of any neighboring Parish Town Village or Hamlet
or upon the Seacoast without paying any thing for the same for [the<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] repairing and amending of the High wayes
aforesaid so as they fill up the place within One moneth next ensuing if required by the Owner of the soyle</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. And where not sufficient in Commons, &amp;c. Surveyors may enter and dig in Private Grounds;</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">except Orchards, &amp;c.; without paying,; (Exception); rendering Damages to the Owner, to be assessed by Justices;; but to fill up Holes, &amp;c. under Penalty of 5 Eliz. c. 13</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">Provided alwayes and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Authority aforesaid That where there is not sufficient Gravell
Chalke Stones Cinders and Sand or other Materials for to repaire the High wayes within the C&bhooov;mon or waste
Grounds of any Parish Township or Hamlett for to amend and repaire the High wayes therein it shall and may be
lawfull for the said Surveyor or Surveyors or such as they shall appoint to enter into the severall ground (not being
an House Orchard Garden Court yard Parke with Deere in it or Meadow) of any person or persons within the said
Parish Township or Hamlet neare adjoyning to the High wayes to be repaired where any such Materials are or may
be found and to dig take and carry away from time to time such [quanties<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] thereof as the said Surveyor or Surveyors
shall judge necessary for the said reparations without paying any thing for the said Materials (except only where they
have formerly been paid for by Custom or Composition and at such rates as heretofore were paid for the same)
rendring only such damages to the Occupier or Owner thereof as he shall sustaine by the digging and carriage
thereof to bee assessed by two Justices of Peace neare the said Parish in cases of difference about the same Provided
that the pitts and holes soe digged be filled up in such manner and under such penalties as are prescribed in the
Statute made in the Fifth yeare of Queene Elizabeth concerning the amending of High wayes</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Regulations as to Number of Horses and Oxen drawing Waggons, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Exception.; and as to Weight of Burthen; and as to Breadth of Wheels.; Penalty 40s.; To be levied by Distress.; Penalties not paid; Distress to be sold</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the [Authoroty<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] aforesaid That from and after the Nine and twentieth day of
September which shall bee in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and two no travelling Waggon
Wayn Cart or Carriage wherein any Burthens Goods or Wares are or shall be carried or drawn for hire (other then
such Carts and Carriages as are imployed in and about husbandry and manuring of Lands and in the carrying of
Hay Straw Corne unthreshed Coal Chalk Timber for Shipping Materials for building Stones of all sorts or such
Ammunition or Artillery as shall be for His Majesties Service) shall att any one time travel be drawn or go in any
Common or Publique High way or Road with above seaven Horse-beasts whereof six shall drawe in paires and not
with above eight Oxen or six Oxen and two Horse-beasts nor shall att any time carry above Twenty hundred
weight betweene the First day of O&bholigct;ober and the First [day<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] of May nor above Thirty hundred weight betweene the
First of May and the First of O&bholigct;ober (except such particulars as aforesaid) nor above five Quarters of Wheate
Meal Mesline Rye Pease Beanes and Tares nor above eight Quarters of Barley Malt or Oates and after that
proportion nor shall any Waggon Wayne Cart or Carriage for the uses aforesaid be imployed the Wheeles whereof
are lesse in breadth then foure Inches in the Tyre upon pain that every Owner of such Waggon Wayn Cart
Carriage Horse-beasts or Oxen shall forfeit for every of the said Offences the s&bhouov;m of Forty shillings to bee devided
into three equal parts One part thereof to the Surveyors of the High wayes of the Town Village or Hamlet where
any of the said Offences shall be committed to bee imployed in the Repaires of the said High wayes One other
part to the Overseers of the Poore of the Parish where any of the said Offences shall be committed for the releife of
the Poore of the said Parish and the other part thereof to him that shall discover and prosecute for any of the said
Offences the said penalty to be levied by Distresse of all or any of the said Horsebeasts or Oxen and to be distributed
as aforesaid by the Constable Surveyor or Surveyors of the said High wayes Overseer or Overseers of the Poore or
any of them And in case the said penalties shall not be paid within three dayes after such Distresse that then it shall
be lawfull to and for the said persons so distraining as aforesaid to sell the same and to restore the Overplus to
the Owner the Charges of keeping and selling first dedu&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Offences common Nuisances.</head>
			<para id="p15">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the said offences shall be and are hereby declared and adjudged to be
common Nusances.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Suit commenced against Persons executing A&bholigct;.; General Issue.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any Suit shall be commenced against any person for any thing done in pursuance
of this A&bholigct; that in every such case the A&bholigct;ion shall be laid in the proper County where the fa&bholigct; was done and not
elsewhere and the Defendant may plead the General Issue and give this A&bholigct; and the special matter in evidence at the
Tryal and if it shall [soe<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] appeare to be done or that it was not done in the County where the said Suit is commenced
that then the Jury shall find for the Defendant and in such case as alsoe if the Plaintiffe shall be non suit or discontinue
his A&bholigct;ion after the Defendant hath appeared or if upon Demurrer Judgement be given against the Plaintiffe or if
upon Tryal a Verdi&bholigct; passe for the Defendant the Defendant shall have his double Costs and the like Remedy for
the same as any Defendant hath in any other Case by Law.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Rates, charitable Gifts for repairing Roads, and Penalties, &amp;c.; (Exception)</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">how to be employed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all s&bhouov;ms of money so rated and assessed as aforesaid and
all charitable Guifts formerly given or to be given for the makeing amending and keeping in repaire of any common
and publick High wayes Pavements and Cawseys (except as hereafter is excepted) and all Fines Penalties Forfeitures
and other s&bhouov;ms of money arising by Assessment or otherwise by this A&bholigct; not otherwise by this A&bholigct; disposed of and
all Issues to be forfeited for not appeareing to any Information or Indi&bholigct;ment for not repairing any High wayes or
removing Nusances out of the same and all Fines and Amercements to be imposed upon any Parish Town Village
or Hamlet or upon any private person for not repairing of common [&amp; publick<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] High wayes which are not otherwise
disposed by this A&bholigct; shall bee imployed and bestowed by the said Surveyors within the respe&bholigct;ive Parishes Townes
Villages and Hamlets to which such charitable Gifts are given and bestowed and within which such Assessment
Fines Penalties Forfeitures Issues and Amercements are imposed happened or made in paying for Materials Workemens.
Wages and for such other employments as are hereby appointed to be done and performed and be levied colle&bholigct;ed
and gathered by the said Surveyors or any of them by Warrant under the Hands and Seals of any two Justices
of Peace within the County City Riding Town Corporate Liberty or Limit wherein the same lieth by distresse and
sale of the Goods as is aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Surveyors to account.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Method of Account; and to pay Balance to Successor.; Not accounting;; Imprisonment in Common Goal</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the [Authoroty<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] aforesaid That every person soe ele&bholigct;ed and taking upon him or
them the Office of Surveyor or Surveyors as aforesaid shall within One Moneth next after the expiration of the
yeare wherein [he<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] executed the said Office as Surveyor of the High wayes make and yeild up to the Inhabitants of
the Parish Town Village or Hamlet at some publick Meeting to bee appointed by the said Inhabitants a perfe&bholigct;.
Accompt in Writing under his and theire Hands of all the Moneys he or they received or paid within his or theire
yeare for or by reason of his or theire Office namely of whom and what received and to whom and what paid and
what Moneys are in arreare and unpaid either for Assessments Fines Forfeitures Penalties and charitable Gifts and
if any Overplus be in his or theire Hands he or they shall returne and pay the same to the next Surveyors or one
of them for the use of the Parish Town Village or Hamlett to bee disbursed in and about the High wayes in the
following yeare And if the said Surveyor or Surveyors shall not make such an Account and Payment as before any
two Justices of the Peace living neere to or in the said Parish shall and may upon complaint unto them made
examine the busines upon Oath and upon default found in the Surveyor or Surveyors shall and may commit him
or them to the Common Goal of that County City Riding Town Corporate Liberty or Limit there to remaine until
he hath made a true and perfe&bholigct; Account and Payment as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Justices of Assize, &amp;c. and of the Peace may determine respe&bholigct;ing charitable Gifts for repairing Highways. Exception.</head>
			<para id="p22">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every Justices of Assise Oyer and Terminer and Justices of the Peace
shall have Power and Authority and are hereby enabled and impowred to enquire after heare and determine all
matters concerning charitable Gifts for the makeing amending and keeping in repaire any Common High wayes
Pavements Streets and Cawseys within the limits of theire Commission and to make Orders therein for the due
imployment of such charitable Gifts according to the true intent and meaning of the Donors thereof except Gifts
to the aforesaid Uses made to any Colledge Hall Free School or Hospital which have Visitors of theire owne and
alsoe to heare and determine all Offences Defaults and Defe&bholigct;s in Surveyors or others concerning the Premisses.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Appeal to Chancery.</head>
			<para id="p23">Provided that if any person [shall<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] be agreived with such Order they shall have liberty to appeal to the Court
of Chancery as in the case of a Decree made upon the Statute of charitable Uses.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Certiorari not to be allowed on Information, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">unless Security for Costs, &pound;40</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the first day of May One thousand
six hundred sixty and two no Certiorari shall be allowed to remove any Information Indi&bholigct;ment Presentment
Order or other proceedings in the Quarter Sessions of for or concerning any matter or thing in this A&bholigct; unlesse
the party or parties against whom any such Information Indi&bholigct;ment Presentment Order or other proceedings shall
be had by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall before the allowance of such Certioraries become bound to the person or
persons prosecuting in the s&bhouov;m of forty pounds with such sufficient sureties as the Justices of Peace att theire said
Quarter Sessions of the Peace shall thinke fitt with condition to pay unto the said prosecutors within One moneth
after the Convi&bholigct;ion of such parties indi&bholigct;ed theire full costs and damages to be ascertained upon theire Oathes
and that in default thereof it shall be lawfull for the said Justices to proceed to triall of such Indi&bholigct;ments Any
such Writs of Certiorari to remove the same Indi&bholigct;ments notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Recital of Petition of certain Inhabitants of the Parish of Laycock in the County of Wilts, respe&bholigct;ing Foot Bridge and Rey Bridge.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">The said Parishioners indemnified against rebuilding Rey Bridge except for Horse and Pack</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">And whereas at a generall Quarter Sessions held for the County of Wilts it was at the humble Peti&bhocotil;n of the
Peti&bhocotil;ners of Laycock and other Inhabitants of the said County ordered that one ancient Bridge called Foot
Bridge leading thorough the said Parish between London Bath and Bristol being more comodious for all Carts
than one other Bridge in the said Parish called Rey Bridge should be repaired and made passable for all Carts
Waggons and Carriages (with the Materials of Rey Bridge) which was thereby ordered to be taken down which
Order was accordingly put in Execution in the said County and Parish Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority
aforesaid That the said Parishoners and all others imployed by them in the pulling downe the said Bridge called
Rey Bridge and imploying the Materials thereof as aforesaid shall be and are hereby indempnified from all suits
troubles and molestations whatsoever touching or concerning the same and that the said Parishoners of Laycock
and other the aforesaid Inhabitants shall not hereafter be compelled by Information or Indi&bholigct;ment or any other
way be made chargeable with the rebuilding of the said Bridge called Rey Bridge otherwise then for the maintaining
the said Bridge sufficient for Horse and Pack as it now stands Any Law or Statute to the contrary in any wise
nowithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Owners of Iron Works, and Persons within the Wilds of Surrey, Sussex, and Kent, not exempt.</head>
			<para id="p28">Provided likewise and be it ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to exempt any Owner Farmer or Lessee
of any Iron worke or other person within the Wildes of the Counties of Surrey Sussex or Kent for carrying so
many load of Cinder Gravel Stones and other Materials or contributing such s&bhouov;ms of money towards the amending
and repairing of the High wayes as they are obliged to by any former A&bholigct;s</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Cases in which no Assessment under this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p29">And be it further provided and ena&bholigct;ed That where the Justices of the Peace of any County at theire Generall
Quarter Sessions or any two of such Justices neare to any Parish Township or Hamlett shall be fully satisfied
that the High wayes and Bridges within the same may and will be sufficiently amended and repaired according
to former usage without the helpe of this A&bholigct; that then and in such Cases only there shall no Assessment be
made within the same for and towards theire reparations by vertue of this A&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Stratford Bridge in the Parish of Hillingdon in the County of Middlesex.</head>
			<para id="p30">Provided alwaies and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Justices of Peace of the
County of Middlesex in theire publick Sessions of the Peace shall have Power and Authority to make Orders for
ere&bholigct;ing or setting up a new Bridge of Brick or Stone fitting for the passage of Carts and Carriages in the
room and place of a Bridge now only passable for Foot and Horse called Stratford Bridge in the Parish of
Hillingdon in the said County or in some [other <ref idref="n11">11</ref>] more convenient place neare thereunto at the present charge of
the whole County for the ere&bholigct;ing of the same but to be upheld repaired and maintained after it be so ere&bholigct;ed at
the charge of the Lord of the Manour wherein the said Bridge now standeth proportionable to the charge he is
now at for maintaining the Horse Bridge and the residue of the charge to be borne by the Parishoners of the said
Parish for which purpose the said Justices of the Peace at theire said publick Sessions are hereby enabled to make
respe&bholigct;ive rates accordingly so as the s&bhouov;m to be assessed for the ere&bholigct;ing the said Bridge exceed not the s&bhouov;m of
One hundred pounds [And the said Justices are to take care that the said Bridge be finished by or before the first
day of August in the Yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty and three<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Surveyors to take care that Bridges have sufficient Walls, or Posts and Rails.</head>
			<para id="p31">[And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said Surveyors doe take care that all and every Bridge
or Bridges within theire respe&bholigct;ive limits shall before the Feast of S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Michael One thousand six hundred sixty [and<ref idref="n10">10</ref>]
two have sufficient walls or posts and railes of each side thereof four foot high at the least and that the said walls
or posts and railes be from time to time kept in sufficient repaire<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Surveyors for the Year 1662 ; and also where no Surveyors chosen for that Year.</head>
			<para id="p32">[Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Surveyors of the High ways named for
the yeare One thousand six hundred sixty and two shall within Twenty dayes after the Publication of this A&bholigct; proceede
to do and execute all things in this A&bholigct; for the said yeare One thousand six hundred sixty two And where there
are no Surveyors of the High wayes chosen for the said yeare One thousand six hundred sixty two they shall be
chosen within Twenty dayes after Publication of this A&bholigct; by such persons as by this A&bholigct; is appointed and being so
chosen they shall hereafter do and execute all things according to the tenure of this A&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Tenant of Lands to pay Assessment. Proviso for Agreements.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided alsoe and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That where any Lands are let the Tenant and
Occupier thereof shall pay the Assessment and bear all charges for the mending of the High wayes and not the
[Land<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] lord except where there is or shall be any Agreement betweene the said Landlord and the Tenant to the
contrary.<ref idref="n14">14</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p34">Provided alsoe and be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the power of raising and levying money by vertue of this A&bholigct;
shall continue in force for Three yeares only from the five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred
sixty and two and no longer but that all other Powers and Clauses in this A&bholigct; shall continue and stand in force
until the end of the First Session of the next Parliament and no longer.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">quantities <emph type="i">O</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Authority <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Authority <emph type="i">O.</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


