<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47302" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for granting unto the Kings Majestie twelve hundred and threescore thousand pounds to bee assessed and
levied by an assessment of threescore and ten thousand pounds by the moneth for eighteene moneths.[Rot. Parl. 13 C. II. p. 2. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Reasons for the present Grant.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">&pound;1,260,000. granted in the Manner following, but not to be drawn into Example</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">We your Majesties most dutifull and loyall subje&bholigct;s the Commons assembled in Parliament taking notice of
the present and important occasions for your Majesties supply and of your Majesties abundant grace and
bounty to your people in the late A&bholigct; of free and generall pardon indempnity and oblivion and withall considering
that the great and heavy taxations which your people have lately undergone were cheifely if not onely for the
paying off those publique debts to the Army and Navy which were contra&bholigct;ed in ill times and most of them for
ill purposes under the late tyranicall and usurping powers insomuch that wee are nowe to provide for all those
necessities your Majestie hath beene reduced to by the new setling [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] your Majesties household without any setled
revenue by the putting forth of severall Fleets and Navies to sea although your Majestie found the stores neere
exhausted by the provisions for the Garrison of Dunkirke and the establishment att Tangiers and alsoe att Jamaica
three great additions of honour att present and wee hope of plenty hereafter by securing our trade and commerce
besides the charges of those guards to your royall person which the implacable spirits of some men have for some
time made necessary and that noblest expence of all in bringing home your Royall Consort (whom Almighty
God preserve and blesse to the joy and comfort of your Majestie and to the happines of all future generations)
Nevertheles that your Majestie may see wee are no way discouraged by the charge or difficulty of the present
occasions and that your enemies may see and knowe our readines to assist your Majestie with the utmost hazards
both of our lives and estates Wee your said Commons doe hereby freely and cheerefully give and grant unto your
Most Excellent Majestie the sum of twelve hundred and threescore thousand pounds to be raised and levied in
manner following And although wee cannot but knowe that the ancient and usuall parliamentary course of raising
moneyes for the aid and supply of your Majesties extraordinary occasions is and hath beene by way of subsidies
which wee desire may bee observed in future times And that the course hereby taken may not bee drawne into
example for the time to come and considering that the way of subsidies hath for many yeares last past been
disused and that the regula&bhocotil;n of that method in raising moneys would require more time and occasion more
delay then your Majesties pressing and urgent affaires can well permit Wee therefore your Majesties faithfull and
obedient subje&bholigct;s the Commons assembled in Parliament beseech your Majestie that it may be ena&bholigct;ed [And be it
ena&bholigct;ed<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] by the Kings Most excellent Majestie by and with the consent and advice of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and of the Commons in this present Parliament assembled That the s&bhouov;me of threescore and ten thousand
pounds by the month for eighteene moneths begining from the five and twentieth day of December One thousand
six hundred sixty one shall bee assessed taxed colle&bholigct;ed levied and payed by six quarterly payment&bholngs; in the severall
Counties Cities Burroughs Townes &amp;places within England and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweed
according to the severall rules and propor&bhocotil;ns and in such manner as is hereafter expressed (that is to say) for
every moneth of the said [eighteen<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] moneths Upon</para>
			<para id="p3">The County of Bedford the s&bhouov;me of nine hundred thirty and three pounds six shillings and eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p4">The County of Berks the s&bhouov;me of one thousand fowerscore and eight pounds seaventeene shillings and ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p5">The County of Buckingham the sum of one thousand two hundred fourscore and three pounds six shillings and
eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p6">The County of Cambridge the s&bhouov;m of one thousand one hundred and two pounds ten shillings.</para>
			<para id="p7">The Isle of Ely the s&bhouov;m of three hundred threescore and seaven pounds ten shillings.</para>
			<para id="p8">The County of Chester the s&bhouov;m of seaven hundred threescore and ten pounds.</para>
			<para id="p9">The City and County of the City of Chester the s&bhouov;m of fourscore and five pounds eleaven shillings and
two pence.</para>
			<para id="p10">The County of Cornwall the s&bhouov;m of One thousand six hundred thirty three pounds six shillings [and<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p11">The County of Cumberland the s&bhouov;m of One hundred and eight pounds.</para>
			<para id="p12">The County of Derby the s&bhouov;m of nine hundred thirty and three pounds six shillings and eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p13">The County of Devon the s&bhouov;m of three thousand and three pounds fifteene shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p14">The City and County of the City of Exon the s&bhouov;m of [One<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] hundred and seaven pounds six shillings and eight
pence</para>
			<para id="p15">The County of Dorsett the s&bhouov;m of One thousand three hundred and eleaven pounds ten shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p16">The Towne and County of Poole the s&bhouov;m of Ten pounds and fourteene shillings.</para>
			<para id="p17">The County of Durham the s&bhouov;m of One hundred fifty three pounds fourteen shillings and four pence.</para>
			<para id="p18">The County of Yorke with the City and County of the City of York the s&bhouov;m of Three thousand forty three
pounds eight shillings and ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p19">The Towne and County of Kingston upon Hull the s&bhouov;m of Threescore and seaven pounds thirteene shillings
foure pence.</para>
			<para id="p20">The County of Essex the s&bhouov;m of Three thousand and five hundred pounds.</para>
			<para id="p21">The County of Gloucester the s&bhouov;m of One thousand six hundred twenty six pounds six shillings eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p22">The City and County of the City of Gloucester the s&bhouov;m of One hundred threescore and two pounds eleaven
shillings and two pence.</para>
			<para id="p23">The County of Hereford the s&bhouov;m of One thousand one hundred threescore and six pounds thirteene shillings and
foure pence.</para>
			<para id="p24">The County of Hertford the sum of One thousand and four hundred pounds.</para>
			<para id="p25">The County of Huntington the s&bhouov;m of Six hundred twenty two pounds foure shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p26">The County of Kent with the City and County of the City of Canterbury the s&bhouov;m of Three thousand six hundred
fifty five pounds eleaven shillings two pence.</para>
			<para id="p27">The County of Lancaster the s&bhouov;m [One<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] nine hundred thirty three pounds six shillings eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p28">The County of Leicester the s&bhouov;m of One thousand fourscore and eight pounds seaventeen shillings and eight
pence.</para>
			<para id="p29">The County of Lincoln with the City and County of the City of Lincoln the s&bhouov;m of Two thousand seaven
hundred twenty two pounds four shillings ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p30">The City of London the s&bhouov;m of Four thousand six hundred threescore and six pounds thirteene shillings and
foure pence.</para>
			<para id="p31">The County of Middlesex with the City and Liberties of Westminster the s&bhouov;m of One thousand seven hundred
fourscore and eight pounds seaventeene shillings and ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p32">The County of Monmouth the s&bhouov;m of Foure hundred threescore and six pounds thirteene shillings four pence.</para>
			<para id="p33">The County of Northampton the sum of One thousand and four hundred pounds.</para>
			<para id="p34">The County of Nottingham the s&bhouov;m of Nine hundred and three pounds four shillings and four pence.</para>
			<para id="p35">The Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham the sum of Thirty pounds two shillings four pence.</para>
			<para id="p36">The County of Norfolke the sum of Three thousand six hundred twenty four pounds eight shillings ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p37">The City and County of the City of Norwich the sum of One hundred fourscore and six pounds thirteene
shillings four pence.</para>
			<para id="p38">The County of Northumberland the sum [of<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] One hundred threescore and nineteene pounds nineteene shillings
ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p39">The Towne of Newcastle the s&bhouov;m of Thirty five pounds eleaven shillings eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p40">The County of Oxon the sum of One thousand one hundred twenty seaven pounds fifteene shillings six pence.</para>
			<para id="p41">The County of Rutland the sum of two hundred threescore and twelve pounds four shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p42">The County of Salop the sum of One thousand three hundred twenty two pounds four shillings and foure pence.</para>
			<para id="p43">The County of Stafford the s&bhouov;m of Nine hundred and nineteene pounds six shillings and eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p44">The City and County of the City of Lichfeild the sum of fourteen pounds.</para>
			<para id="p45">The County of Somersett the s&bhouov;m of two thousand seaven hundred twenty two pounds four shillings six pence.</para>
			<para id="p46">The City and County of the City of Bristoll the sum of One hundred threescore and eleaven pounds two
shillings and two pence.</para>
			<para id="p47">The County of Southampton with the Towne and County of Southampton the s&bhouov;m of Two thousand twenty
two pounds foure shillings and four pence.</para>
			<para id="p48">The County of Suffolke the sum of Three thousand six hundred fifty five pounds eleaven shillings and
two pence.</para>
			<para id="p49">The County of Surrey the sum of One thousand five hundred threescore and five pounds five shillings and
six pence.</para>
			<para id="p50">The Burrough of Southwarke the s&bhouov;m of [One<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] hundred fourscore and four pounds fourteen shillings and
six pence.</para>
			<para id="p51">The County of Sussex the sum of One thousand nine hundred and five pounds eleaven shillings and two pence.</para>
			<para id="p52">The County of Warwicke with the City and County of the City of Coventry the s&bhouov;m of One thousand two
hundred forty four pounds eight shillings and ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p53">The County of Worcester the s&bhouov;m of One thousand one hundred fourscore and two pounds four shillings and
four pence.</para>
			<para id="p54">The City and County of the City of Worcester the s&bhouov;m of threescore and two pounds four shillings and
six pence.</para>
			<para id="p55">The County of Wilts the s&bhouov;m of One thousand nine hundred forty foure pounds eight shillings and ten pence</para>
			<para id="p56">The County of Westmerland the sum of threescore and thirteene pounds nineteene shillings and four pence.</para>
			<para id="p57">The Isle of Anglesey the sum of One hundred thirty five pounds fourteen shillings four pence.</para>
			<para id="p58">The County of Brecknock the sum of Three hundred threescore and one pounds thirteen shillings four pence.</para>
			<para id="p59">The County of Cardigan the sum of Two hundred and thirteen pounds and ten shillings.</para>
			<para id="p60">The County of Carmarthen the s&bhouov;m of Three hundred fifty and two pounds six shillings and eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p61">The County of Carnarvan the sum of Two hundred and two pounds four shillings and four pence.</para>
			<para id="p62">The County of Denbigh the sum of Two hundred threescore and twelve pounds four shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p63">The County of Flint the sum of One hundred thirty five pounds fourteen shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p64">The County of Glamorgan the s&bhouov;m of Four hundred fifty and eight pounds seaventeen shillings and eight pence</para>
			<para id="p65">The County of Merioneth the s&bhouov;m of One hundred twenty four pounds eight shillings and ten pence</para>
			<para id="p66">The County of Mountgomery the s&bhouov;m of Two hundred fourscore and fifteen pounds and eleven shillings</para>
			<para id="p67">The County of Pembroke the s&bhouov;m of Four hundred and six pounds</para>
			<para id="p68">The County of Radnor the s&bhouov;m of Two hundred fifty four pounds six shillings and eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p69">The Town of Haveford West the s&bhouov;m of Fourteen pounds eleven shillings and eight pence</para>
			<para id="p70">And the Town of Berwick upon Tweed the s&bhouov;m of Five pounds sixteene shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>Commissioners named.</head>
			<para id="p71">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that all and every the persons hereafter named shall be
Commissioners of and for the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cityes Boroughs Townes and Places hereafter  
named that is to say.</para>
			<para id="p72">(<ref idref="n7">7</ref>)</para>
			<para id="p73">For the County of Bedford Francis Lord Russell Robert Lord Bruce Sir Beauchampe S[en]t John Sir Samuel Browne
Sir Loodwick Dyer Sir John Napier Sir Roger Burgoin Sir Thomas Alston Sir Humphrey Winch Sir Humphrey Monox
Sir S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Charnock Sir Henry Chester Knight of the Bath Sir Samuel Luke Sir William Palmer of Warden Sir
William Palmer of Hill Sir John Duncombe Sir James Beverley Sir William Beecher Sir Clement Armiger Sir George
Blundell Sir Henry Piggot John Keeling Serjeant att Law Stephen Anderson S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Tomson Oliver Luke John Osborne
Francis Dives William Boteler Francis Crawley Richard Tayler Richard Dyer Thomas Suagy William Geery James
Mountague Samuel Cotten John Neale John Harvey Walter Rolt John Vaux William Cheney of Sundon Thomas
Chaney of Bramingham John Huxley Robert Crompton Robert Audley William Spencer Walter Cary John Ventris
John Rotderam Francis Wingate Mathew Denton Gaius Squire John Mathewes Stanton Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p74">Towne of Bedford</para>
			<para id="p75">For the Towne of Bedford The Maior for the time being Robert Lord Bruce Sir Humphrey Winch Sir Henry
Chester Sir William Beecher Sir George Blundell William Boteler Es&bhoqesq; Richard Tayler Es&bhoqesq; John Keeling Serjeant
at Law William Spencer John Gardiner Robert Beverley John Beaumont Do&bholigct;or of Phisick John Barber Thomas
Christi William Foster William Riseley Simon Beckett Esquires John Hancock Crawley Robert
Fitzhugh Aldermen Lewis Harding Robert Little William Scot senior.</para>
			<para id="p76">Berks</para>
			<para id="p77">For the County of Berks George Fane Esquire John Lovelace Esquire Sir George Stonehouse Sir Thomas Draper
Sir Thomas Rich Sir Richard Powle Sir Edmund [Sawyer<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Sir Robert Pye Sir Richard Braham Sir Thomas Dolman
Sir Cesar [Colchough<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Sir Henry Winchcombe John Davis George Purefoy Peregrine Hobby Robert Packer Richard
Aldworth Richard Harrison Thomas Sanders William Backhouse John Elwaies John Southby Richard Nevill John
Allen John Whitfeild John Blagrave Henry Henn William Nelson William Trumball William Hyde William Barker
[Anthony Barker<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Francis Peacock Esquires M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Parr William James Thomas Southby M<emph type="p">r</emph> Dalby Paul Colton
Samuel Woodcock The Maiors of Reading Abingdon Windsor and Wallingford for the time being Richard Palmer
Peregrin Wilcock&bholigct; M<emph type="p">r</emph> Day M<emph type="p">r</emph> Piggott M<emph type="p">r</emph> [Coulton<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> Loder senior of Wallingford M<emph type="p">r</emph> Weston of Newberry James
Herne senior Do&bholigct;or Hungerford George Starke Es&bhoqesq; William Baker Esquire Robert Massey Es&bhoqesq; M<emph type="p">r</emph> Whisler of Alder
Humphrey Hyde senior Humphrey Hyde junior Edward Hobby Richard Broderick William Wilmot</para>
			<para id="p78">Buck&bholngs;</para>
			<para id="p79">For the County of Bucks Thomas Lord Wenman Sir Thomas Tirrell Justice of the C&bhooov;mon Pleas Sir Richard
Temple Baronett Sir Toby Tireill Sir John Burlace Sir Francis Henry Lea Sir Anthony Chester Sir Heneage Proby
Sir William Drake Sir Ralph Verney Sir William Smith Sir Richard Napier Sir William Bowyer Baronetts Sir William
Tirringham Knight of the Bath James Herbert Esquire Sir William Parsons Sir Henry Andrewes Baronets Sir Richard
Ingoldsby Knight of the Bath Sir Edmund Pye Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Longvile of [Molverton<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Baronet
Sir Robert Croke Charles Cheney Thomas Proby Richard Hampden Francis Ingoldsby John Dormer Richard
Greenvill Symon Bennet Thomas Saunders of Hadenham Thomas Stafford Robert Lovett Thomas Duncumbe of
Broughton Esquires Sir Purbecke Temple Knight Brett Norton Thomas Hacket Esquires Sir Thomas Lee Baronet
John Green Edmund Petty Alexander Croke Robert Croke William Fleetwood, William Burlace William Penn
Edmund Varney William Salter Edward Waller Edmund Waller of Esquires Thomas Berringer George
Tash Nicholas le Grice Thomas Farrer senior Thomas Farrer junior John Egglestone James Lowe Thomas Risley
Roger Price Francis Tirringham Knightley Purefoy Bernard Turney Duke Dorrell William Lane William Claver of
Weeden Esquires Captain Styles Sir Robert Geares Knight and Baronett Sir Thomas Hampson Baronet Sir Thomas
Clarges Knight Sir Richard Pickett Ralph Deane Peter Dayrell junior Edmund Dayrell Esquires Sir John Croke
Dudley Rewse Francis Duffeild Thomas Weedon Esquires Thomas Audley Richard Burton John Turner Gentlemen
William Hackwill Esquire James Perrot Gentleman Richard Winwood Thomas Waller Esquires The Bayliffe of
Buckingham for the time being The Maior of Wickham for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p80">Cambridge</para>
			<para id="p81">For the County of Cambridge The Lord Allington Sir William Compton Sir Dudley North Sir Francis Russell
Sir Thomas Hatten Sir John Cotten Sir Thomas Willis Sir John Cutts Sir Thomas Bennet Sir Thomas Dayrell Sir
Isaac Thornton Sir Thomas Wendy Thomas Chichley (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Levinus Bennet (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) John Bennet [Esquires<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Sir Anthony Cage
Samuel Thornton John Millisent Samuel Fortrey Thomas Story William Legat Thomas Ducket Robert Piggot
Jeoffry Nightingale John Wildbore William Layre Humphrey Gardiner Thomas Martin Roger Pepys Thomas Dodd
Esquires M<emph type="p">r</emph> Barnes.</para>
			<para id="p82">For the University and Towne of Cambridge</para>
			<para id="p83">For the University and Towne of Cambridge The Vice Chancellor of the University for the time being The
Maior of the Towne for the time being Sir Thomas Slater Baronet Richard Minsall Theophilus Dillington Do&bholigct;ors
of Divinity Andrew Owen Do&bholigct;or of Law Robert Eads Mathew Barlowe Henry Pamant James Jackson
Brady Do&bholigct;ors of Phisick Thomas Crowch Es&bhoqesq; Clement Nevile Do&bholigct;or Gostlyn Thomas Gearing Samms
Robert Crane Do&bholigct;or of Law Walter Catstrey John Peachel John Boord Roger Pepys Recorder of the Towne
Samuel Spalding Christopher Rose Chapman Thomas Tifford John Ewen John Jenkinson Rowland
Simpson John Tymms.</para>
			<para id="p84">Isle of Ely.</para>
			<para id="p85">For the Isle of Ely William Covell William Fisher Lawrence Oxburgh Thomas Marsh Thomas Steward Robert
Steward Robert Balaam William Balam Anthony Buckworth Anthony Fisher Mathew Tayler Humphrey Gardner
Robert Swaine John Swayne Thomas Edwards Robert Glapthorn Edmond Farrer Robert Twelve Michael Holman.</para>
			<para id="p86">Chester</para>
			<para id="p87">For the County of Chester Robert Lord Cholmley Sir William Stanley Sir Peter Leicester Sir Thomas Manwaring
Sir Richard Grosvenor Sir George Warburton Baronets Sir Philip Egerton Sir John Ardern Sir Fulke Lucy Sir
John Booth Knights Thomas Cholmondeley of Vel-Royall Richard Leigh Edward Warren Henry Brooke Thomas
Marbury Henry Legh John Crew of Utkinton Edward Legh (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Henry Bunbury (<ref idref="n15">15</ref>) Edward Hide Edward [<emph type="i">Legg</emph>
				<ref idref="n16">16</ref>]
Peter Dutton Richard Wathall [Roger Wilbraham of Nampwich<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Roger Wilbraham of Deerfold John Belot
William Lawton John Daniel William Liversage Peter Pindare Alexander Fitton Somerford Oldfeild Robert Tatton
Richard Masley Ralph Horton Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p88">City of Chester.</para>
			<para id="p89">For the City and County of the City of Chester Thomas Thrope Maior of the said City Sir Thomas Smith
Baronet John Ratcliffe Esquire Recorder Charles Walley Robert Harvey Thomas Cooper William Ince Edward
Bradshawe William Crompton John Johnson William Bennet Robert Bird William Wright Peter Leigh Richard
Minshull Gerrard Jones Arthur Walley The Maior for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p90">Cornwall</para>
			<para id="p91">For the County of Cornwall Robert Roberts Esquire Sir Chichester Wrey Knight and Baronett Sir John Trelawney
Knight and Baronett Sir John Carew Sir Richard Vivian Baronets Sir William Godolphin Knight and Baronet
Sir Richard Edgecombe Knight of the Bath Sir Francis Godolphin Knight of the Bath Sir Nicholas Slaning Knight
of the Bath Sir John Arundell Sir Peter Courtney Sir Peter Killigrew Sir Samuel Coswarth Sir Richard Prideaux
Sir James Smith Sir William Tredinham Knight&bholngs; Charles Grills Peircy Edgecombe Jonathan Trelawney John
Coryton Hender Roberts Richard Arundell Bernard Greenvil Hugh Biscawen Jonathan Rashley Charles Trevanion
Charles Roscarrock Francis Buller Walter Langdon William Pendarvis John Elliot John Buller John Arundell
Nicholas Arrundel William Scawn Edward Boscawn William Cotten John Harris Samuel Trelawney John Trelawney
John Penrose John Speccot Renatus Billet Humphrey Noy Esquires John Tanner James Prade Thomas Robinson
Edward Nosworthy Arthur Spry Thomas Hearl John Rashley Richard Rouse William Godolphin Richard Erisie
junior John Polewheel Digory Polewheel Walter Kendal Walter Moyl Nicholas Burlace Edmond Prideaux Oliver
Sawle Thomas Trefry John Moulsworth John Nicholls of Trewane John Carnsew Francis Jones Ezekiel Arrundel
Richard Pendarvis Anthony Chinoweth William Painter Hannibal Buggins George Hele Samuel Ennis John
[Bonthen<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] of Carclew Hugh Trevanion Nathaniel Trevanion Colan Blewet Hugh Pomeroy Christopher Cooke
Hugh Courtney Thomas Wills Thomas Castle Michael Hill Nathaniel Mohun Esquires Thomas Hoblin of
S<emph type="p">t</emph> Stephens Gent. John Accland George Potter Merchants Isaac Maudite senior.
ephens Gent. William Trevisa John Bligh Richard Porter Henry Spur Henry Spur junior Leor Tremain
Esquires Francis Robinson Gent. Hugh Piper James Bond Digory Tremain Chamond Greenvil John Peirce John
Billing Christopher Billet Joseph Sawle Esquires Hugh Trevanion Marke Silly William Spry Richard Hawke
William Courtney of Sde; William Trevisa John Bligh Richard Porter Henry Spur Henry Spur junior Leor Tremain
Esquires Francis Robinson Gent.Hugh Piper James Bond Digory Tremain Chamond Greenvil John Peirce John
Billing Christopher Billet Joseph Sawle Esquires Hugh Trevanion Marke Silly William Spry Richard Hawke
William Courtney of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Erme John Mathews Humphrey Arscot Thomas Hoblin of Goran Samuel Gully Thomas
Hick&bholngs; John Verman John Williams Richard Williams John Burgesse Edmund Phillips Andrew Cory Francis
Burgis William Williams Charles Grills Bernard Kendall William Mohun William Webber David Moyl Nicholas
Sawle Robert Soyle John Edwards Francis Hearle James Crocker Stephen Polewheel Nathaniel Lugger Gentlemen
Reynald Hawkey Thomas Pyker Richard Erisie John Vivian Thomas Wadden Peter Jenkin Edward Hearle James
Erisie Edward Elliott Charles Biscawen John Ceely Esquires Edward Hender Gentleman John Thomas William
Hender Richard Carter Esquires John Conock Mathew Vivian.</para>
			<para id="p92">Cumberland</para>
			<para id="p93">For the County of Cumberland Sir Philip Musgrave Knight &amp;Baronett Sir Patricius Curwen Baronet Sir William
Dalstone Knight and Baronett Sir George Fletcher Sir John Lowther [Sir John Lowther<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Sir Edward
Musgrave Baronets Sir Thomas Dacre Sir William Huddlestone Sir William Carleton Sir Philip Howard Sir Wilfrid
Lawson Sir Francis Salkeld Knights Christopher Musgrave John Lamplugh Christopher Blencow William Musgrave
Daniel Fleming Richard Skelton William Musgrave William Layton George Denton Richard Tolson John Barwis
William Briscoe John Eglanby Jonathan Atkins Christopher Potter Christopher Richmond Thomas Denton Anthony
Bouch John Senhouse Edward Stanley John Warwick Esquires The Maior of Carlisle for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p94">Derby.</para>
			<para id="p95">For the County of Derby Henry Viscount Mansfeild William Lord Cavendish Anchitel Gray Esquire George
Pierpoint Esquire Sir Thomas Gresley Sir Francis Burdet Sir John Harper Baronets Sir John Curson Knight and
Baronett Sir Edward Coke Sir Henry Every Sir William Boothby Baronets Sir John Harper Sir Samuel Sleigh
Knights John Fretchvile German Pole John Ferrers John Mundey George Vernon Richard Coke John Milward Walter
Horton Charles Agard Gilbert Thacker William Fitzherbert Charles Cotton Henry Gilbert Nicholas Willimot
Robert Eyre James Abney Godfrey Clarke William Bullocke George Sitwell Simon Degg Esquires Roger Alestry
John Dalton William Woolly Maior of Derby for the time being Thomas Sleigh John Donage Aldermen George
Tayler William Wright Rowland Eyre of Bradway Francis Barker Gent..</para>
			<para id="p96">Devon.</para>
			<para id="p97">For the County of Devon Sir William Morrice Principall Secretary of State Sir Peter Prideaux High Sheriffe Sir
Edward Seymour Sir George Chudley Sir Francis Drake Sir Thomas Hele Sir Hugh Pollard Sir Courtney Poole Sir
Copplestone Bampfeild Sir John Northcot Sir John Chichester Sir William Courtney Sir John Davye Sir Edmund
Fowell Sir William Morrice Sir Thomas Carew Sir John Drake Baronets Sir Edward Wise Sir John Roll Sir Nicholas
Slanning Knights of the Bath Sir John Chichester Sir Henry Carew Sir John Young Sir Thomas Stewkley Sir Robert
Cary Sir Richard Prideaux Sir Peter Ball Sir James Smith Sir William Stroud Sir Edmund Fortescue Sir John Skelton
Knights Edward Seymore Peter Prideaux Arthur Bassett William Jennings Arthur Northcoat John Fowell Thomas
Clifford Robert Fortescue Thomas Hele Walter Young John Giffard Edmond Tremain Thomas Southcoat Edmond
Parker Richard Cabal John Courtney John Bury John Arscote George Yeo Thomas Carew Edward Pyne John
Speccot John Tanner Amos Pollard John Pollard Nicholas Dennys Robert Walker John Tuckfeild George Potter
Samuel Trelawney George Howard John Kelland William Bogan Jonathan Sparke James Clifford Nicholas Duck
Thomas Reynel Mathew Halls Thomas Carew of Bowhill Thomas Stafford John Stowell John Jacob John Harris
of Hotham Thomas Wood William Williams Balthazar Bear Thomas Berry of Northam John Harris of Radford John
Kelley Henry Norleygh Josias Calmady Ambrose Roope Thomas Gibbons Edmond Fowell John Martin Arthur
Champernone [Philip Champernone<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Mathewe Heale John Wise John Hawkins Thomas Prestwood John Trelawney
Edward Walrond Francis Drewe John Fry [Benjamin Colme John Willoughby Thomas Beare John Fry<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] William
Walrond William Putt (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Richard Duke Thomas Southcote Gideon Haydon John Bragg Philip Shapcote James [Huich<ref idref="n21">21</ref>]
Ellis Bartlett Henry Ford Samuel Tanner William Martin Henry Stevens Henry Newte Esquires The Maiors of
Totnes Plimouth Tiverton Dartmouth and Barnstaple for the time being Christopher Clobery Peter Fortescue
Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p98">City of Exon.</para>
			<para id="p99">For the City and County of the City of Exon Sir Thomas Mallet Knight one of his Majesties Justices of the
Kings Bench The Maior for the time being Sir Peter Ball Recorder Sir James Smith Knight Robert Walker John
Were Esquires John Bidgood Do&bholigct;or of Phisick Nicholas Isaac Sheriff John Marten Merchant Henry Walker Gent.
Thomas Shapcote Gent. John Accland George Potter Merchants Isaac Maudite senior.</para>
			<para id="p100">Durham.</para>
			<para id="p101">For the County of Durham Sir Thomas Widdrington Knight Sir John Conyers Sir Thomas Lyddell Sir Gilbert
Gerrard Baronets Sir George Vane Sir Francis Bowes Sir Francis Lyddell Sir William Darcy Sir Nicholas Cole
Sir Joseph Craddock Knights Thomas Burwell Do&bholigct;or of Lawes John Hilton Esquire Thomas Delaval James
Clavering Cuthbert Carr Anthony Byarly Nicholas Frevill Christopher Conyers Ralph Cole George Darcy Ralph
Davison Thomas Shadforth Anthony Dodsworth John Tempest Thomas Fetherstonhaugh Cuthbert Pepper Es&bhoqesq;s
Timothy Whittingham Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p102">Newcastle upon Tyne</para>
			<para id="p103">For the Towne and County of Newcastle upon Tyne Sir John Marley Knight present Maior Sir Nicholas Cole
Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Anderson Knight Sir Francis Bowes Knight M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Shafto Recorder M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert
Shafto M<emph type="p">r</emph> Marke Milbanks M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Emerson Aldermen M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Jenison Sheriff M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Madison M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas
Davison M<emph type="p">r</emph> Ralph Grey junior M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Wetherell M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Dobson junior M<emph type="p">r</emph> Ralph Tayler.</para>
			<para id="p104">Dorset.</para>
			<para id="p105">For the County of Dorset John Lord Digby Sir Francis Hollis Sir Gerrard Napier Sir Hugh Windham Baronets
Sir Francis Fulford Sir John Strangewaies Sir Walter Earle Sir Ralph Banks Sir John Fitz James Sir John Lowe
Knights Giles Strangewayes John Strode Humphrey Wilde John Morton John Strangwaies John Tregonwell of
Anderston Henry Henly George Pit Robert Culliford Winston Churchill Henry Whitaker James Gould John
Churchill Bullen Reymes Humphrey Bishop Thomas Freake Nathaniel Naper John Tregonwell of Milton Edward
Hooper Robert Coker John Rogers Thomas Trenchard Thomas Fownes Thomas Moore George Fulford John
Turbervel Robert Lawrence Robert Naper Maximilian Mohun Michael Harvey George Hussey Thomas Baynard
Esquires John Browne William Constantine William Thomas George Grey Henry Butler William Floyer Robert
Tyderleigh John Ryves of Damare John Gould John Abington Arthur Radford William Okeden Edmond Uvedall
George Savage of Deane John Michel John Jeffreys Dillaline Hussey John Hardey Wolle Miller William Ellesdon
George Strangwaies William Caldecote Mathew Davis John Still Arthur Fooks Gregory Gibbs George Strenchard
John Dolling John S<emph type="p">t</emph> Lowe John Hoskins John Ironside William Fautleroy Esquires George Style Henry Herbin
Gentlemen Thomas Chaff Peter Hoskins John Hurden George Browne James Smith Robert Freak Robert Seymour
Robert Williams of Heringstone Richard Newman Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p106">Pool.</para>
			<para id="p107">For the Towne and County of Pool Sir John Fitz James John Morton Es&bhoqesq; Colonel William Skut Robert
Cleeves Richard Dolberry Moses Durrell Aaron Durrel.</para>
			<para id="p108">Essex.</para>
			<para id="p109">For the County of Essex Sir Edward Turner Speaker of the House of Comons Sir Harbottle Grimstone Master
of the Rolls Sir John Barrington Knight and Baronet Edward Russell Esquire Sir Henry Appleton Sir Benjamin
Ailoffe Sir William Hick&bholngs; Sir William Wiseman of [Cawfeild<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] Sir Andrewe Jenner Sir Capell Luckin Sir Martin
Lumbley Sir Thomas Abdy Sir Samuel Tryan Sir Robert Abdy Sir William Wiseman Sir Henry Wright Sir
Thomas Smith Baronets Sir John Brampstone Sir James Altham Knights of the Bath Sir Humphrey Mildmay
Sir John Tyrell Sir Robert Kempe Sir Thomas Bowes Sir Richard Wiseman Sir Anthony Browne Sir Thomas
Fanshawe Sir Edmond Peirce Sir Thomas Gardiner Sir Mundeforde Brampstone Sir William Glascock Sir John
Shawe Sir Cranmer Herris Knights Thomas King John Bendish Charles Fitz Gamaliel Capel Richard Sames
Charles Maynard senior Thomas S<emph type="p">t</emph> George Oliver Raymond Thomas Meade Peter Solme Thomas Argoll John
Atward Tristram Conyers Henry Wollistone Henry Pert John Eldred senior Salter Herris John Eldred junior
George Walton John Godbold John Paschall Robert Joselin Thomas Midleton Gulston William Glascock
Thomas Luther Thomas Cambell William Umfreven James Silverlock Thomas Roberts John Aylet William Hicks
John James Francis Nicholson William Houlcrat Thomas Bland Haynes Barley William Appleton Charles Maynard
junior Richard Cooper Lancelot Slamby John Tyrel Daniel Andrewes John Berners Esquires John Lowen Do&bholigct;or
of Lawes John Turner John Berriff Esquires The Maior of Colchester for the time being Thomas Talcost John
Radams Thomas Peake Thomas Renolds Andrew Fromanteel Henry Lambe Robert Legg Thomas Raynald junior
Peter Johnson Bailiffs of Malden for the time being Rubin Robinson Do&bholigct;or of Phisick John Stynnens Samuel
Plumbe Bartholomew Brickwood Francis Gurney Joseph Hall The Maior of Harwich for the time being Daniel
Smith George Coleman Richard Fuller Anthony Wollward Humphrey Jaggard Henry Wright Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p110">Gloucester</para>
			<para id="p111">Henry Lord Herbert Robert Viscount Tracy Sir Henry Capell Knight Sir William Ducy Baronet Sir Henry
Frederick Thynne Baronet Sir Edward Bathurst Sir Richard Ashfeild Sir John How Baronets Sir Robert Pointz
Sir Robert Atkins Knights of the Bath Sir William Catchmay Sir Nicholas Throckmorton Sir Baynham Throckmorton
Sir Edmund Bray Sir Gabriell Lowe Sir John Newton Sir Thomas How Knights William Cooke Thomas Masters
William Dutton Francis Norwood John Winter William Try William Stratford Sir Baynham Throckmorton
Baronet Sir Edward Massey Knight John How Esquire Evan Seys Es&bhoqesq; Serjeant at Law John George Es&bhoqesq; Richard
Dowdeswell Es&bhoqesq; Sir Hugh Middleton Baronet Fleetwood Dormer Esquire Lord Cheife Baron Hales George
Mountague Es&bhoqesq; Philip Sherrard William Selwin Sir Thomas Stephens Sir Thomas Overbury Knights Sir Christopher
Gyse Knight William Cope Es&bhoqesq; Philip Sheppard Richard Whitmore Nicholas Veale John Stephens Thomas
Chester Richard Atkins John Fettiplace John Coddrington Thomas Seymour John Chamberlain Richard Sackvile
William Bourcher John Barrow Duncumb Colchester Henry Paul John Smith Charles Cox John Rich Andrewe
Barker Richard Cox senior Esquires M<emph type="p">r</emph>. David Williams M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Driver M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Morgan M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Jones
M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Morgan M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Aylway Edward Rich Thomas Horton Robert Pleydell Thomas Thynne Esquires
Richard Baugh Esquire The Bayliffs of Tewkesbury for the time being M<emph type="p">r</emph>. William Wilson M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Jenings
M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Hancock M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Carver M<emph type="p">r</emph>. John Dobbins M<emph type="p">r</emph> Conway Whitterne M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Dowdeswell M<emph type="p">r</emph>. Henry
Browne M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Freame M<emph type="p">r</emph>. William Dobbins Thorpe Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p112">Gloucester.</para>
			<para id="p113">For the Citty and County of the City of Gloucester The Maior of Gloucester for the time being Edward Lord
Herbert Sir Robert Atkins Knight of the Bath Sir Edward Massey Knight Evan Seys Serjeant att Law Sir Christopher
Gyse Knight John Grubhamhow Esquire William Cooke Richard Atkins Silvanus Wood William Selwin Esquires
William Singleton William Capel Thomas Pury Dennis Wise Luke Nourse Lawrence Singleton Henry Cugley
James Stephens Toby Jordan Robert Pain Thomas Pyers Thomas Lugg Aldermen John Dorney Esquire John
Powell Thomas Yate Thomas Price Gentlemen Edward Nourse Esquire Henry Nourse Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p114">Hereford.</para>
			<para id="p115">For the County of Hereford Henry Lord Herbert John Lord Viscount Scudamore James Scudamore Wallop
Brabazon Esquires Sir James, Bridges Sir John Kirle Sir John Scudamore Sir William Powel Baronets Sir Edward
Harley Sir Henry Lingen Knights of the Bath Sir Edward Hopton Sir Herbert Perrot Knights [Fitzwilliams<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Coningsby
Thomas Whitney Thomas Tomkins John Prise Thomas Prise Herbert Aubrey senior Walter Pye John Scudamore
senior Roger Vaughan Humphrey Cornwall Herbert Awbrey junior Herbert Westfaileing Esquires Job Charleton
Serjeant at Law James Pit Thomas Cornwall John Scudamore junior Thomas Cockes Edward Cornwall John
Skipp Reynold Grayham Richard Hopton Bennet Hoskins Giles Bridges John Barnaby Thomas Geeres Thomas
Carpender Humphrey Howorth William Gregorie Francis Unet John Hanford Humphrey Baskervile John Birch
John Vaughan John Booth of Hereford Thomas Harley Ambrose Elton Richard Wigmore John Nurse Rudhale
Guillym Nicholas Wallwin Thomas Rodd John Booth of [Broynton<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] Thomas French Thomas Wigmore Robert
Rodd Richard Reed Thomas Whittington Thomas Veynal Timothy Cowles Herbert Masters William Bridges
John Barnaby of Brockhampton John Dansey William Dansey Esquires John Guyllin of Willington Gent. Humphrey
Tayler of Withington John Kidley of Bromley Thomas Gomond of Kilpeck Arthur Winwood senior John Carver
Gentlemen The Bayliff for the Burrough of Leominster for the time being Edward Rodd Gent. Richard Rodd of
Rodd Esquire Thomas Blaney Priamus Davies Edward Freeman</para>
			<para id="p116">City of Hereford.</para>
			<para id="p117">For the City of Hereford The Maior for the time being Sir Henry Lingen Knight Herbert Westfailing John
Booth of Hereford Thomas French Esquires Charles Booth Richard Philpots David Bowen William Phillips Walter
Wall Jerom Addis Thomas Homes Robert Symonds William Edwin John Rawlins Thomas Paynard Thomas
Davids Gentlemen Edward Aldern Do&bholigct;or of Lawes James Smith Nicholas Philpots Thomas Bond Hugh Rodd
Thomas Clarke Gentlemen John Hill John Barnes.</para>
			<para id="p118">Hertford.</para>
			<para id="p119">For the County of Hertford Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the House of Commons Lord Fanshaw
Sir Thomas Fanshaw [Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] of the Honourable Order of the Bath Sir Thomas Leventhorpe Sir Edward Atkins
one of the Barons of his Majesties Exchequer Sir Richard Atkins Sir Richard Francklin Sir Harbottle Grimstone
Sir Ralph Baesh Sir Thomas Hewet Sir Thomas Dacres Sir Fetherston Sir Phillip Butler Sir Henry C&aelig;sar
Sir John Gore Sir Rowland Litton Sir Henry Coningsby. Sir Broket Spencer Sir Richard Combes [Sir<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] Thomas
Dacres M<emph type="p">r</emph>: Poulter M<emph type="p">r</emph>. William Willoughby M<emph type="p">r</emph>. Graveley Norton M<emph type="p">r</emph> Needham M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Glascock
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Coppin M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Cotton M<emph type="p">r</emph> Ralph Gore M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Brograve M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Cason M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Beecher M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas
Stanley M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Dockwray M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Heydon M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Austin M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Hales M<emph type="p">r</emph> Arthur Sparks M<emph type="p">r</emph> John
Fetherley M<emph type="p">r</emph> Maurice Rawden M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Jesson M<emph type="p">r</emph> James Wilmot Do&bholigct;or Harris M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Atkins M<emph type="p">r</emph> Ralph
Freeman junior M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Cecill M<emph type="p">r</emph> Algernon Cecil M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Jennings M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Feild M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Smith
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Sadler M<emph type="p">r</emph> Erasmus Harby Sir John Wats Sir Francis Butler M<emph type="p">r</emph> Ralph Freeman senior Sir John Hales
Sir Henry Blount M<emph type="p">r</emph> George Blombley M<emph type="p">r</emph> Saunders Mead M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Briscoe</para>
			<para id="p120">Burrough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albans</para>
			<para id="p121">For the Burrough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albans Sir Harbottle Grimstone Sir Henry Coningsby Sir Richard Combes, The Maior of
the Towne for the time being M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Haynes M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Cawley M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Marstone M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edmond Smith
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Dockwray M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Sadler M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Jennings Do&bholigct;or Arris M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Oxton M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Jesson
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Alban Cox M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Briscoe M<emph type="p">r</emph> Charles Chamberlaine M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Eames M<emph type="p">r</emph> Algernon Cecil M<emph type="p">r</emph> Joshua Lomox.</para>
			<para id="p122">Huntington.</para>
			<para id="p123">For the County of Huntington Robert Viscount Mandevile Edward Mountague Francis Compton Esquires Sir
Thomas Cotten Sir John Hewet Baronets Sir Robert Bernard Knight John Cotton John Stone Henry Williams
Robert Appreece John Bernard Richard Elmes Nicholas Pedley Lawrence Throckington Lionel Walden John Heron
Jasper Trice William Bradley Robert Payne Anthony South John Farrer Esquires M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Nayler M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas
Colstone.</para>
			<para id="p124">Town of Huntington</para>
			<para id="p125">For the Towne of Huntington Sir Robert Bernard Nicholas Pedley Lionel Walden Lawrence Throckington Esquires
Richard Weaver Thomas Ashton Thomas Judson Aldermen Richard Astrey Gent.</para>
			<para id="p126">Kent.</para>
			<para id="p127">For the County of Kent Lord Buckhurst Lord Stranghford Sir Thomas Twisden one of the Justices of the Kings
Bench David Pothel Esquire High Sheriff Sir Thomas Peyton Sir Roger Twisden Sir Edward Hales Sir Edward
Monins Sir Henry Palmer Baronets Sir John Tufton Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Styles Sir Edward Deering Sir
Oliver Botler Sir Richard Hardress Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir Norton Knatchbull Baronets Sir John Reyney
Sir Thomas Peirce Sir William Wilde Sir John Rivers Sir Francis Vincent Sir Stephen Lemard, Sir Robert Austin
Sir John Seliard Sir Humphrey Millar Sir John Wroth Sir William Leech Baronets Sir George Sands Knight of the
Bath Sir John Mennes Sir Anthony Aucher Sir William Man Sir Walter Vane Sir John Darell Sir John Boys
Sir Edward Felmer Sir William Batten Sir Thomas Culpeper senior Sir Francis Clarke Sir Arnold Braems Sir
Theophilus Biddulph Sir John Marsham Sir Edward Master Sir William Hugeson Sir William Boreman Sir Richard
Sandys Sir Thomas Godfrey Sir William Meredith Sir Bernard Hyde Sir William Swan Sir Edmund Peirce Sir Anthony
Bateman Knights Walter Franklin Esquire John Heath Attorney of the Dutchy of Lancaster Robert Barneham
Herbert Kendal John Scot Thomas Lambert Philip Packer George Bournham George Polehill John Evelyn Henry
Gilborne Robert Heath Francis Heath John Seyl[i<ref idref="n25">25</ref>]ard John Hyde John Culpeper Norton Curtis William Leonard
William Swan of Southfleete Henry Washington Thomas Crispe Maximilian Dallison Francis Lovelace Recorder of
the City of Canterbury William Boys Samuel Boys William Buggins Richard Amhurst Richard Head Thomas
Culpeper of Bedgbury George Newman Richard Duke Thomas Fludd John Munn Edward Finch, Thomas Hinman
Thomas Lake John Horsmanden Maurice Diggs James Brockman John Best Thomas Hardres John Boys of Fretvel
Thomas Peake Richard Masters Anthony Foule Richard Hulse Richard Marsh William Rooke Thomas Broadnax
Nicholas Toke senior Robert Lewkenor Henry Thornehill Zouch Brockman John Boys of Hoad Alablaster Flud
Thomas Knatchbull Ralph Buskin John Smith Esquires George Curtis William Maddox Do&bholigct;or Mason Master of
Requests John Trouts Peter Heyman Francis Twisden Richard Manley Francis Barrel Thomas Brewer George May
Thomas Manley Christopher Allanson Peter Pett George Woodyer Robert Oliver Edward Wyat John Knatchbull
Francis Barrel James Newman Robert. Davell of Quekes Henry Petit John Cason John Austin James Fortree Stephen
Alwise Robert Fowler Esquires Herbert Randall.</para>
			<para id="p128">Canterbury.</para>
			<para id="p129">For the City of Canterbury The Maior for the time being Francis Lovelace Recorder Sir William Man Sir Edward
Master Thomas Peake Esquire William Stanly and Henry Twiman Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p130">Dover.</para>
			<para id="p131">For the Town and Port of Dover The Maior for the time being, Captain Jacob Michael Eaton Captain West
Mr Matson.</para>
			<para id="p132">Sandwich</para>
			<para id="p133">For the Town and Port of Sandwich The Maior for the time being Tobias Cleer John Verier Jeoffry Wells
Jeoffry Sackett James Thurbane</para>
			<para id="p134">Rumney.</para>
			<para id="p135">For the Towne and Port of Rumney The Maior for the time being Robert Wivell Jeremy Standford Stephen
Bret Thomas Chalcroft.</para>
			<para id="p136">Hith.</para>
			<para id="p137">For the Towne and Port of Hith The Maior for the time being Mr Finch James Pashley.</para>
			<para id="p138">Feversham.</para>
			<para id="p139">For the Towne and Port of Feversham The Maior for the time being John Trouts John Upton Robert Watson.</para>
			<para id="p140">Maidstone.</para>
			<para id="p141">For the Towne of Maidstone The Maior for the time being The Maior of Gravesend for the time being The Maior
of Queenburrough for the time being The Maior of Tenterdon for the time being The Bailiff for the Towne of Lid for
for the time being Richard Allen Recorder of Rochester Captaine Cox Thomas Brett Godfrey Martin.</para>
			<para id="p142">Lancaster.</para>
			<para id="p143">For the County of Lancaster Charles Earle of Ancram Edward Stanley William Stanley William Spencer Esquires
Sir Richard Hoghton Sir George Midleton Sir Robert Bindlos Sir Edward Moseley Baronets Sir Roger Bradshaigh
Knight John Molineux Richard Kirekby Roger Nowell Edward Fleetwood Henry Banister William Farrington
Edward Rigby Hugh Dickenson William Radley Esquires Sir Ralph Ashton of Whaley Baronett Robert Holt of
Castleton Lawrence Rawstorne Nicholas Townley of Royle Thomas Preston Nathaniel West John Girlington Robert
Rawlinson Jeoffery Rishton Do&bholigct;or of Phisick John Parker of Extwisle Nicholas Banister Alexander Osbaldeston
Thomas Holt Sir Ralph Ashton Baronet Richard Standish Alexander Rigby of Middleton Richard Pennington Thomas
Norres Richard Leigh John Lightbowne Alexander Rigby of Layton Richard Fleetwood of Russal Thomas Butler of
Kirkeland Sir Gilbert Ireland Knight Thomas Bradal Esquire John Townley of Hurstwood Gent. Christopher Barker
Esquire John Halsteed of Bankhouse Gent. Nicholas Moseley John Byrom Robert Heywood James Duckenfeild Peers
Leigh John Entwisley Cuthbert Ogle John Risley Bartholomew Hesketh Sir Henry Slayter Knight Henry Hoghton
William Banks junior Esquires Nicholas Fezakirly Gent. Captain Byrom Captain Ashton of Peicketh Henry Porter
George Hutton William Fyffe Thomas Carus Thomas Greenhalgh Esquires Roger Kenyon James Hodgkinson William
Turner Gentlemen The Maior of Lancaster for the time being Richard Fleetwood John Aynsworth of Plesington
William Wall William Hodgkinson Gentlemen Captain Brabine Seth [Backhurst<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] Gent. Captaine Longworth Robert
Heywood Esquire Nicholas Pennington Gent. The Maior of Leverpoole for the time being Alexander Woodward Gent.
Luke Hodgkinson</para>
			<para id="p144">Leicester</para>
			<para id="p145">For the County and Town of Leicester Lord Beaumont Lord [Gerrard<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] John Lord Roos Beamont Dixy Esquire
George Faunt Esquire Sir George Villiers Baronet Sir Charles Sudley Baronet Sir Woolstan Dixy Baronet Sir Thomas
Smith Sir John Pettyman Sir Henry Hudson Sir Edward Smith Baronets Sir Erasmus De la Fountaine Sir John Cave
junior Sir William Hartop Knight&bholngs; Thomas Merry Richard Lister William Whaley Mathew Babington John De la
Fountaine Esquires Sir John Hartop Baronet James Winstanley Esquire Sir Clement Clarke Baronet Philip Sherard
William Street John Orton John Cave William Boothby Theophilus Cave John Morton junior George Pochin Thomas
Brudnell William [Sheffington<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] Richard Roberts John Turvil Thomas Bradgate Everard Goodman Thomas Caldecote
William Robert&bholngs; Edward Arnold Henry Bigland Thomas Staveley John Chamberlain John Mitton William Bent
John Danvers John Needham Walter Bracy Hood Needham Christopher Bradgate Samuel
Gervase Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p146">Leicester Towne</para>
			<para id="p147">For the Towne of Leicester Henry Hungate Esquire Daniel Deacon Thomas Overing Gent. Edward Browne
William Major Thomas Browne George Resin Gent. Walter Rydings Esquire John Clerke Gent. Edmond
Sutton Gent.</para>
			<para id="p148">Lincoln</para>
			<para id="p149">For the County of Lincolne and City and County of the same George Viscount Castleton John Lord Ross
Robert Lord Willoughby Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath William Peirpoint Esquire Sir Philip Tirwhit Sir
John Mounson Sir Thomas Hussey Sir Thomas Williamson Sir Michael Armin Sir Robert Bowles Sir John Brownlowe
Sir William Brownlow [Sir William Tirill Sir<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] Richard Earle Sir William Hickman Sir Robert Markham Sir William
Trollop Sir William Wray Sir Charles Hussey Sir Thomas Ellis Sir Robert Dallison Sir John Buck Sir Edward
Barker Sir Anthony Oldfeild Sir John Anderson Sir Richard Rothwell Sir Humphrey Winch Sir Edward LakeSouthcoate Baronets Sir John Mounson junior Sir Adrian Scroope Sir Henry Heron Knights of the Bath
Sir Anthony Irby Sir Martin Lister Sir John Wallpool Sir Edward Rosseter Sir Sutten Cony Sir Edward Aiscue
Sir Charles Dallison Sir Thomas Meers Sir Edward Dymock Sir Christopher Clapham Knight&bholngs; Philip Tirwhit
Robert Car Richard Brownlow John Bowles John Newton William Whitchcot William Skipwith Charles Pelham
senior Charles Pelham junior Charles Hall Cecil Tirwit Edward Maddison William Marwood Marmaduke Darrell
Francis Goodrick William Bard Jervas Holles Master of Request&bholngs; Robert Christopher George Sherwood Anthony
Thorold John Sherrard Thomas Hatcher Robert Peirpoint George Mountague William Mountague William Stafford
Christopher Nevil Erasmus de Ligne Thomas Ellis John Hatcher Redman Burrel Edward King William Blith Charles
Dymock John White Mollineux Disney John Teigh Francis Wingfeild William Hyde Charles Halford John Saunders
Francis Hatcher William Savil Edward Skipwith Thomas Welby Thomas Rands Charles Bawdy William Welby
Richard Sherrard John Jay Adam Claypool John Booth George Booth Thomas Ogle Atland Welby Thomas Hall
Richard Coney Lewis Palmer John Hobson John Empson Mathew Woolmer Thomas Roulton Anthony Oldfeild
John Lockton Henry Burwell Esquires Anthony Hall Thomas Thory Henry Stone Thomas Petchell Thomas Key
John Palmer George Caborn Thomas Browne Matthias Brown Toller George Slee William Yorke
Charles Radley Heely William Lister John Elmore Richard Williams Anthony Tredway William
Broxholm Thomas Harrington Anthony Weberley Stephen Rothwell M<emph type="p">r</emph> Long of Kirkby William Perkins
Do&bholigct;or Denham Do&bholigct;or Edward Stourton M<emph type="p">r</emph> Miller Marmaduke Darel junior Samuel Jackson Eastoft  
Charles Bishop Esquire Thomas Welcome William Fitzwilliams John Wilson John Dymock John Farmery John
Tilson Austin Coldorn Robert Coldorn William Rivet William Thornton Edward Rothwel James Ashton Thomas
Audley Robert Snouton Anthony Gibbon John Luddington Henry Fynes Esquire Lionell Hollingworth The Maiors of
Lincoln Boston and Grimsby for the time being The Aldermen of Grantham and Stamford for the time being Henry
Morley [<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] of Sutton William Bishop Edward Blow M<emph type="p">r</emph> Keyte M<emph type="p">r</emph> Rosse Alderman William Hall William   
Woolley Joseph Whitinge Richard Butcher Luke Blythe Daniel Thorowgood John Balgay George Hill John Palmer John
Mason M<emph type="p">r</emph> (<ref idref="n32">32</ref>) Robinson Richard Walley Henry Gedney Leonard Town William Town William Garnon Robert
Humphrey Poplewell Robert Meldley Robert Bisle Richard Balder Thomas Milles Thomas Grant Andrew Pool
Symon Dagg Esquire William Darwin Esquire Samuel Ludding</para>
			<para id="p150">Middlesex.</para>
			<para id="p151">For the County of Middlesex Sir Edward Turner Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons Henry Viscount
Cornebury Sir Edward Nicholas Principal Secretary of State Sir Harbottle Grimstone Baronet Master of the Rolls
Edward Russell George Mountague James Sheiffeild Edward Noell William Pagett Esquires John Ashburnham
Esquire Daniel Oneale Sileus Titus of his Majesties Bedchamber William Ashburnham Cofferer of his Majesties
Household Sir John Glynn Sir John Maynard his Majesties Serjeant&bholngs; at Lawe Sir Heneage Finch Baronet His
Majesties Solliciter General Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir Thomas Fisher Sir Richard Browne Sir Jeremy Whitchcot
Sir John Robinson Leiutennant of the Tower Sir Richard Francklin Knight and Baronet Sir William Robert&bholngs; the
younger Sir Joseph Ash Baronet&bholngs; Sir Thomas Draper Baronet Sir Charles Cornwalles Sir John Nicholas Sir Robert
Atkins Sir John Bennet Knight&bholngs; of the Honorable Order of the Bath Sir Henry Bennet Sir Henry Herbert Sir
Thomas Ingram Sir Thomas Reynell Sir Thomas Allen Sir Edmond [Bower<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] Sir Thomas Rowe Sir William Waller
Sir Christopher Abdy Sir Nicholas Crispe Sir George Benion Sir Henry Wroth Sir William Bateman Sir Francis
Gerrard Sir Philip Warwicke Sir Allen Broderick Sir Gilbert Gerard Sir Thomas Bide Humphrey Weld
M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Sandys John Cary Charles Chaney Henry Mildmay Thomas Allen John Maynard Christopher Abdy
Ralph Hawtrey Nicholas Rawton George Pitt Henry Rowe Francis Philips Richard Peacock Richard Pro&bholigct;or John
Hutchinson John Hawtrey Edwin Rich Edward Rich Giles Hungerford Joseph Ayliffe of Grayes Inne Francis
Crawley Edward Chard John Jones John Wentworth William Megg Robert Peyton John Page Richard Powell
senior John Goldsmith Michael Holeman John May Daniel Pro&bholigct;er John Smith Charles Pitfeild John May
Esquires Sir Thomas Player junior Thoma&bholngs; Henshawe Robert Page William Page Francis Blower Thomas Collett
John Greene Ralph Hatsell William Goldesbrough James Norfolk Esquires John Wilford William Bowler John
Rives Nathaniel Snape Thoma&bholngs; Beverley Thomas Lane John Browne Richard Cheyney James Hawley William
Geery Benjamin Baron Robert Bladwell Thomas Bayles Edward Shelton Esquires Sir Lancelot Lake Knight
Thomas Lake of Cannons Esquire Henry Haughton Esquire Sir Thomas Littleton Richard Adams William Glascock
Edward Smith Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p152">London.</para>
			<para id="p153">For the City of London Sir John Frederick Lord Maior Sir Thomas Adams Sir Richard Browne Sir Thomas
Allen Knight&bholngs; &amp;Baronets and Aldermen of the said City Sir John Robinson Knight and Baronet Leiutenant of the
Tower of London Alderman, Alderman Fowke Alderman Chiverton Sir John Laurence Alderman Sir Anthony
Bateman Alderman Alderman Warner Alderman Peake Sir Richard Ford Alderman Alderman Chard Alderman
Fisher Alderman Culling Alderman Bathurst Alderman Meynell Alderman Sterling Sheriff&bholngs; Alderman Bolton Deputy
Nodes Sir William Tomson Sir Theophilus Bidolph Sir John Cutler Knight and Baronet Sir William Wale Sir
Thomas Chamberlaine Sir Thomas Bludworth Sir George Smith Sir Lawrence Bromfeild Sir Abraham Cullin Sir
Nicholas Crispe Sir William Bateman Sir Andrew King Sir John Shaw Sir William Gardiner Knights John Jolliff
Thomas Turgis John Jones Henry Dunster Thomas Gower John Saunders Colonel Trussell Thomas King Esquires
Richard Mills Treasurer of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Bartholomews Hospital John Pory Esquire Thomas Cannam Colonel Nevil Colonel
Claget Collonel Allot Deputy Thomas Minn Deputy Robert Hanson Deputy Humphrey Cliff Robert Bidolph
Thomas Tite Thomas Pearle Nicholas Penning Peter Mills Lawrence Blomley Henry Hanson Deputy Thomas
Clowes Deputy Ailmer Richard Spencer Benjamin Albin John Sharpe Abraham Johnson Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p154">Westminster.</para>
			<para id="p155">For the City and Liberties of Westminster and St Martins le Grand Sir George Cartwright Vice Chamberlaine
to his Majestie Sir Charles Berkley Comptroller of his Majesties Household Sir John Nicholas Knight of the Bath
Sir Robert Howard Sir John Denham Knight of the Bath Sir William Throckmorton Knight Marshall Sir William
Playters Knight and Baronett Sir Gilbert Gerard of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Martins in the Feilds Knight Sir Philip Warwick Sir Richard  
Everard Sir Edmond Pye Knights Sir Thomas Littleton Sir John Pettus Baronet Sir Robert Bowles Sir Edward
Ford Sir Hugh Cartwright Sir Anthony Irby Sir Edward Broughton Sir Thomas Clarges Knight&bholngs; Colonel William
Howard George Mountague John Ashburnham William Ashburnham John Cotton Alexander Popham Thomas
Morton William Legg Reynold Graham John Harvey Es&bhoqesq; Simon Smith Charles Whitaker William Glascock
Edward Penrudduck Richard Atkins Thomas Coppin Thomas Fisher Richard Newman William Hoare Doctor of
Phisick John Clarke Do&bholigct;or of Phisick George Farewell Walter Bridal Richard Adams William Bell Esquires
Samuel Argal Do&bholigct;or of Phisick Brian Barnaby George Plucknet Thomas Stevens Thomas Edwards William
Dolben Francis Dorington Robert Mawer Rice Hamond William Gape Thomas Morris George Cooper Walter
Lapp Robert Bradbury John Porey William Newington John Hammond Philip Hanbury Richard Stanlake Edmund
Bury Godfrey George Merrifeild Job Williams George Greens Sir Edward Wingfeild William Sandys John Fox
Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p156">Monmouth.</para>
			<para id="p157">For the County of Monmouth Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland William Lord Herbert of Cardaffe Sir Edward
Morgan Sir Trever Williams Sir Thomas Morgan Baronets Sir George Probert Sir Baynham Throckmorton Knights
Thomas Morgan of Tredegar William Morgan of the same William Jones of Treowen Edmond Morgan Harry
Proberts Thomas Lewis of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Peen William Morgan of Pencrick Thomas Hughes Thomas Morgan of Lanfore
Charles Hughes Charles Van of Coldrey Charles Proger Herbert William Herbert William Jones Edmond Jones
Lewis Morgan Henry Morgan of Penlloyne Searth Roger Oates Edward Kemis of Bertholey Roger Williams Henry
Chambers William Jones of Tregirong Philip Cicill John Parry James Prichard of Campson Esquires George
Morgan of Pullhead Gentleman Christopher Perkins Thomas Williams of Carlion Esquire Walter Morgan of
Landilo Walter Rumsey Esquire Hugh Lewis Esquire The Maior of the Towne of Monmouth for the time being
John Rumsey Gent. William William Gent. John Walter Esquire Roger Audey Gent.</para>
			<para id="p158">Norfolke</para>
			<para id="p159">For the County of Norfolk Sir Edward Turner Speaker of the House of Commons Thomas Lord Richardson
Sir John Tracy Sir Charles Cornwalles Sir Edmond Bacon Sir Philip Woodhouse Sir Charles Mordant Sir John
Hobart Sir Richard Berney Sir Edward Barkham Sir Nicholas le Estrange Sir John Holland Sir William Paston
Sir John Palgrave Sir Ralph Hare Sir John Pott&bholngs; Sir Robert Kempe Sir Jacob Ashley Sir Edward Ward Sir
Thomas Deareham Baronet&bholngs; Sir John Knivet Sir Edward Walpoole Sir Christopher Calthorpe Knight&bholngs; of the Bath
Sir Charles Herbert Sir William Doyley Sir Thomas Guibon Sir Robert Paston Sir William Hovel Sir Thomas
Rant Sir Thomas Meadowe Sir John Creamer Sir William Hewit Sir Joseph Paine Sir Justinian Lewin Sir Allen
Apseley Knight&bholngs; John Cooke John Spelman James de Gray Robert Gawsell Thomas le Crosse John Windham
Edward Barkham Augustine Palgrave John Potts William Doyly William Gibbon Roger Spelman Erasmus Earle
Serjeant at Lawe William Gaudy Philip Harbord Maurice Shelton Peter Glean But&bholngs; Bacon Robert Buxton
Thomas Gaudy Thomas Berney William Crane Robert Yallop William Cooke Thomas Barker Henry Repps
Oliver Neave Phillip Beddingfeild Robert Suckling Humphrey Beddingfeild [[Thomas Bacon<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] Francis Bacon<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] Robert 
Long Robert Balddock Robert Steward Edward Pepys Nevil Catline John Earle Francis Cory Suckling Gay
Leonard Mapes Thomas Cory Christopher Jay John Kendall John Shadwel Lawrence Oxburgh Robert Canny
Richard Godfrey John Anguish William Barnes Anthony Frestone William Brampton Edward Barber Nicholas
Rookewood Nicholas Stileman Thomas Talbot Jacob Preston Robert Haughton Anthony Drury Robert Drury Thomas
Drury Bassingborn Gaudy Charles Gaudy William Davis of Ellingham Edmond Skipwith James Long Nathaniel
Knivet Edmond Brittiff Simon Brittiff Edward Denny William Rant John Lovel Edward Chamberlaine William Nixon
Thomas Write of Kilverston Thomas Write of Opington Edmond de Gray Thomas Townshend William Cooke
senior Robert London John Bladwel le Estrange Calthorpe Thomas Dey Robert [Keldington<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] Robert Tirrell of
Wilton Francis Thirsby Thomas Lilly Samuel Smith Samuel Harsenet Leonard Gooch M<emph type="p">r</emph> Scarborough Thomas
Browne of Elsing.</para>
			<para id="p160">Burrough of Kings Linn</para>
			<para id="p161">For the Burrough of Kings Linn The Maior for the time being Robert Steward Recorder Walter Kirby John
Basset Thomas Greene John Bird Benjamin Holly Henry Bell William Wharton Robert Thorowgood Thomas
Robinson Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p162">Burrough of Great Yarmouth</para>
			<para id="p163">For the Burrough of Great Yarmouth The Bailiff&bholngs; for the time being Jeoffry Ward Abraham Castle Sir Thomas
Meadow Nicholas Cutting James Symonds Thomas Cooch George England John Woodroff Nathaniel Ashby James
Johnson Thomas Lucas M<emph type="p">r</emph> Rowe.</para>
			<para id="p164">Burrough of Thetford.</para>
			<para id="p165">For the Burrough of Thetford The Maior for the time being Sir Allen Apseley Knight William Gaudy Morris
Shelton Esq[uires] Burrage Martin Osmond Clarke John Kendal Robert Tyrrel Edmond Hunt.</para>
			<para id="p166">City of Norwich.</para>
			<para id="p167">For the City and County of the City of Norwich The Maior for the time being Sir Joseph Paine Knight Francis
Cory Esquire Recorder William Wat&bholngs; Esquire Steward Henry Wat&bholngs; Edmond Boreman John Bayley Bernard Church
William Barnham John Man Thoma&bholngs; Toft John Salter Christopher Jay John Hobart John Osborn Francis Bacon
Thomas Bacon John Earle Esquire The Sheriff for the time being Thomas Cory Esquire Edward Chamberlain John
Norris Esquire John Crosshold Matthias Sutterton Richard Wenman Robert Homes William Hayward Augustine
Briggs Thomas Wisse Robert Bendish Richard Cowldham Francis Norris Aldermen Edmond Cock John Richers
John Manser Henry Woods William Trundel Henry Herne.</para>
			<para id="p168">Northampton.</para>
			<para id="p169">For the County of Northampton Obrian Lord Cullen Charles Lord de le Spencer George Mountague Henry
Howard Robert Spencer William Mountague Esquires Sir Thomas Crew Knight Edward Mountague Esquire Sir
Justinian Isham Sir Thomas Cave Sir Roger Norwich Sir Henry Yelverton Sir Samuel Danvers Sir William Dudley
Sir George Buswel Sir Oliver S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Sir John Robinson Baronet&bholngs; Sir Edward Griffin Sir John Egerton Sir Samuel 
Jones Sir John Bernard Knight&bholngs; Richard Rainsford Serjeant at Law Lewis Palmer William Stafford George Clarke
Richard Samwel Henry Robinson Francis Lane Maurice Tressham Edward Palmer Philip Holman William Downhall
Humphrey Orme George Tressam Edward Onely William Adams Richard Kinsman Miles Fleetwood Godward
Pemberton Thomas Chubnal John Syers William Tate Francis Crane Robert Clarke Bryan Janson John Willoby
John Rye William Lisle Samuel Trist George Ashby John Browne Nicholas Steward Thomas Elmes John Lyn
Walter Kirkham Christopher Thursby Thomas Dove Thomas Blincoe Robert Pargiter Edward Death John Delaval
Esquires Francis Kirkham Esquire The Maior of Northampton for the time being Thomas Thornton Jonathan Whishton
Edward Colles Hatton Farmer.</para>
			<para id="p170">Northumberland</para>
			<para id="p171">For the County of Northumberland Henry Lord Viscount Mansfeild Thomas Grey of Chillingham Ralph Grey of
Chevington Esquires Sir William Fenwick Baronet Edward Widdrington of Felton Esquire Sir Ralph de Laval Baronet
Sir Thomas Widdrington Sir Robert Collingwood Sir William Forster Sir Francis Liddel Sir Henry Widdrington of
Blacke Heddon Knight&bholngs; Edward Gray of Heaton Robert de Laval Cuthbert Hearon James Ogle Ralph Gray of
Bradford Hugh Potter Thomas Forster of Ederston William Struther of Kirk Newton Mark Milbank Sheriff William
Widdrington Ralph Hebron Gilbert Swino John Salkeild William Fenwick of Bywel Robert Shafto of Benwel John
Clarke Robert Widrington of Auxley Ralph Jenison of Elswick Richard Stots of Gesmond John Roddum Thomas
Benwick of Closehouse Ralph Anderson of Ovingun Ralph Batt&bholngs; of Hollawel Esquires John Ridley of Hardrideing
Nicholas Whitehead of Flatworth William Warren of Chillingham Gentlemen The Bailiffes of the Burrough of
Morpeth for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p172">Berwick.</para>
			<para id="p173">For the Town of Berwick upon Tweed Benjamin Clarke Es&bhoqesq; Maior Sir Thomas Widdrington Colonel Edward
Grey John Sleigh Thomas Watson Ralph Hebburn Andrew Moor Esquires Mark Scot James Scot Mark Armorer
Barrow Morton (<ref idref="n37">37</ref>) Caterel George Harrison senior Robert Scot William Anderson James Ord Gent.</para>
			<para id="p174">Nottingham.</para>
			<para id="p175">For the County of Nottingham Henry Lord Viscount Mansfeild Gilbert Lord Houghton Patrick Lord Chaworth
William Peirpoint Arthur Stanhope William Willoughby Anshatell Grey Esquires Sir Gervas Clifton Sir George
Savell Sir Francis Mullineux Sir Thomas Williamson Sir William Hickman Sir Hardolph Wastneys Baronet&bholngs; Clifford
Clifton Robert Peirpoint Anthony Eyre Henry Sacheveril William Willoughby Esquires Sir John Digby Knight Cicill
Cooper. Francis Leeke William Stanhope Philip Leacock William Clarkson Robert Butler Thomas Charlton William
Cartwright John Moseley Esquires Sir Ralph Knight [Kn <emph type="p">t</emph>
				<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] Rowland Dand Rutland Mullineux Francis Stringer Francis
Sandys John Grubham How Esquires William Herbert Esquire John Rainer William Skevington Peneston Whalley
A&bholigct;on Burnell Thomas Wawen Robert Mellish William Savil Rayson Mellish William Childers James Lane William
Leeke William Braisford John Crosse George Camm William Sampson Thomas Smith John Hickman John Cartwright
William Booth George Booth George Coles Henry Halfehead John Darrell Mathew Jenison The Bailiff&bholngs; of East
Retford for the time being The Maior of Newarke for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p176">Oxford</para>
			<para id="p177">For the County of Oxford Henry Lord Viscount Falkland Thomas Earl of Down Thomas Lord Viscount Wenman
Sir Anthony Cope Sir Thomas Spencer Sir Francis Henry Lea Sir Thomas Peniston Sir Thomas Chamberlain Sir
William Walter Sir William Fleetwood S<emph type="p">t</emph>. William Morton Sir Timothy Tyrril Sir Thomas Hord Sir Francis Norris
Sir Henry Jones Sir Edmond Bray Sir John Robinson Sir John Clarke Sir Thomas Tipping Sir Francis Wenman Sir
Robert Jenkinson Sir Compton Read Sir George Croke Sir John Fettiplace Sir Thomas Clayton James Fienns
Broom Whorwood Robert Dormer David Walter Rowland Lacy William Dormer Edmond Lenthall William Cope
Thomas Hord George Bury William Knollis William Cartwright William Draper John Clarke William Barber John
Taverner Thomas Cobb William Ganock John Osbaldeston George Chamberlain Littleton Osbaldeston Charles
Holloway Serjeant at Law John Doyly Vincent Barrie William Sheppard Richard Croke Anthony Libb William Wheat
Thomas Saunders Robert Parrot Esquires John Wickham William Wright John Machen Gentlemen Sir Philip Harcourt.</para>
			<para id="p178">City of Oxford.</para>
			<para id="p179">For the City of Oxford The Maior for the time being The Lord Viscount Falkland Sir Anthony Cope Baronet Sir
Thomas Clayton Knight Broon Whorwood Esquire Richard Croke Esquire Recorder James Huxley George Lowe
Esquires Francis Harris Martin Wright John Nixon Thomas Dennis William Wright Aldermen Sir Sampson White
Knight Leonard Bowman Gentleman Henry Silvester Walter Cave Mathew Langley Richard Miller John Lamb
William Baily Roger Griffin Robert Whorwood John White.</para>
			<para id="p180">Rutland</para>
			<para id="p181">For the County of Rutland Bennett Lord Sherard Edward [Noe<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] Philip Sherard Esquires Sir Thomas Mackworth
Baronet Sir Edward Heath Knight of the Bath Sir Richard Wingfeild Sir Edward Wingfeild Sir Francis Mackworth
Sir Eusebeus Pelsunt Knight&bholngs; Alexander Noel Christopher Browne Samuel Browne Abel Barker Edward Falkener
Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p182">Salop</para>
			<para id="p183">For the County of Salop William Peirpoint Andrew Newport Esquires Sir Thomas Harris Sir Thomas Woolrich
Sir William Whitmore Sir Francis Lawley Sir Walter Acton Sir Henry Frederick Thinn Sir Vincent Corbet Sir
Thomas Littleton Sir Henry Vernon Baronets Sir Thomas Whitmore Knight of the Bath Sir William Owen Sir
Richard Prince Sir John Weld Sir Richard Otley Sir Clement Throckmorton Sir William Child Knight&bholngs; Job
Charlton Timothy Littleton Serjeants at Law William Fowler Timothy Tourneur Philip Eaton Richard Scriven
Francis Thorne James Lacon Robert Sandford Roger Kynaston [Thomas Baldwin Robert Lighton Philip Prince Richard
Lister Edward Kynaston<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] Samuel Wringfeild Thomas Whitmore George Weld Robert Berry George Ludlow Thomas
Rock Charles Baldwin Edward Baldwin Thomas Jones Samuel Baldwin Robert Charlton Henry Barnard Thomas
Powis Thomas Kettleby William Jones Robert Corbett of Hall Hussey Thomas Holland John Cotes William Oakely
Edmund Waring of Ouldbury Sommerset Fox Richard Fowler John Walcot Thomas Walcot Adam Otley Robert
Cresset Thomas [Crimpe<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] John Cole Francis Charlton Thomas Higgons Robert Owen Edward Powell Edward Loyd
of Lanvarda Thomas Loyd Thomas Lockyer Thomas Smalman John Lacon Thomas Lochard John Kynaston
Wil: Owen of Perkington John Newton Thomas Kinersley of Badger William Cotton Richard Mitton Rowland
Hill Vincent Edwards Thomas A&bholigct;on Goodricke of Plash Thomas Harris of Cruckton The Maior of the
Town of Shrewsbury for the time being The Bailiffs of Bridgnorth Ludlow Wenlock and Bishops Castle for the
time being Andrew Hill Francis Smith Richard Walker John Whitaker Thomas Hayes Richard Clarke Andrew Vivers
Robert Forster Richard Tayler John Harding Arthur Hincks John Baugh Edward Woolaston Alexander. Middleton
Samuel Loyd Edward Richards Richard Davis of Ludlow Roger Gough Benjamin Buckley Somerset Hall Robert
Betton Thomas Jones of Sheet Richard Charlton William Bowdler Richard Hosier Francis Hinck&bholngs; Captain Philip
Jennings Henry Sprot Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p184">Somersett.</para>
			<para id="p185">For the County of Somersett Lord Hawley Francis Pawlett Sir Thomas Mallet one of the Justices of the Kings
Bench Sir William Portman Sir John Sidenham Sir Maurice Berkley Sir Hugh Smith Baronet&bholngs; Sir John Stowell Sir
John Coventrey [Knight<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] of the Bath Sir Henry Berkley Sir Thomas Bridges Sir John War Sir George Norton Sir
George Farmer Sir William Basset Sir Hugh Windham Knight&bholngs; Sir Edward Hungerford Knight of the Bath
Sir William Windham Baronet Alexander Popham Edward Phelips Edmond Windham George Speake Francis
Luterell John Mallet Henry Rogers Peregrine Palmer Samuel Gorges William Hellier of Cother Francis Windham
William Prynne William Waldron Edward Berkley William Ball Thomas War John Hippesley Thomas Piggot
John Buckland Francis Roll Charles Pim Edward Court John Churchhill John Harrington Thomas White William
Doble Henry Bull William Carrant George Trevillian Francis Baber Richard Jones William Lacy George Stawell
John Tynt Warwick Bamfeild George Sydenham Robert Hunt Michael Mallet Robert Hawley Anthony Pawlet
Roger Bourne Henry Light John Harbin Edward Bampfeild John Moor Angell Grey John St. Albans Hugh Tynt
Hugh Norris William Speake Henry Walrond John Winter William Bacon John Cridland William Harbord John
Hall Roger Newborough Maudley Samborne Thomas Mallett Thomas Trevillian Francis Vaughan John Hody Edward
Philips junior Esquires And for the City of Wells and the Towns of Bridgewater Chard and Taunton the respe&bholigct;ive
Maiors for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p186">Bristoll</para>
			<para id="p187">For the City and County of the City of Bristoll The Maior of the City for the time being Thomas Earle of
Ossory Sir Humphrey Hooke Knight Nathaniel Cale John Lock Alexander James John Gunning Richard Balmam
Henry Creswick William Colston William Fitzherbert Walter Sandy John Knight the elder Esquires The Sheriffes
of the said City for the time being Thomas Stevens John Hicks Richard Grigson Robert Cann John Pope John
Lawford Robert Vickris John Knight the Younger Thomas Langton John Bradway Robert Yeomans Richard Streamer
William Cole Henry Gough John Floyd John Fitzherbert.</para>
			<para id="p188">Bath</para>
			<para id="p189">For the City of Bath The Maior Recorder and the two ancientest Aldermen of the said City for the time being
John Pearce John Chapman John [Brish<ref idref="n43">43</ref>] John Fisher.</para>
			<para id="p190">Southampton.</para>
			<para id="p191">For the County of Southampton Charles Lord St. John of Basing Henry Lord Pawlet Sir Robert Howard Sir Henry
Worsley Sir John Mills Sir John Norton Sir William Lewis Sir Hugh Stewkley Sir William Meux Sir Richard
Lucy Sir Nicholas Steward Sir Andrew Henley Sir Thomas Bad Sir John Trot Sir Robert Dillington Baronets
Sir Humphrey Bennet Sir John Leigh Sir Richard Uvedal Sir Richard Kingsmil Sir Robert Mason Knights Richard
Norton Richard Goddard of Winton Lawrence Hide Richard Whitehead Henry Wallop John Button John Bulkeley
Thomas Knollis William Oglander Robert Dillington John Collins Thomas Jervoyse John Richards Henry Whitehead
Edward Trussell George Pit Thomas Brook Leonard Bilson Francis Rolle John Hooke Thomas Cole Edward Goddard
Philip Leigh James May Richard Compton Benjamin Ruddiard Giles Hungerford Francis Rivet Roger Gallop Francis
Tilney John Lloyd Henry Bromfeild William Pitt Arthur Bold William Collins Edward Norton Daniel Norton John
Wolveridge' Edward Exton William Stanley Robert Richbill William Wither John Worsley senior Edward Worsley
Edward Hooper of Chilworth Edward Hooper of Pairtree Edward Fleming Francis Dickins Francis Leigh John
Stewkley Bartholomew Price Nicholas Bowell Henry [Tulfe<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] William [Tulfe<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] Thomas Edmonds Robert Oxenbridge
Robert Goffe Richard Love Essex Paulet Thomas Feilder Gabriel Whistler Anthony Yalden Thomas Newnham
Esquires John Dean John Oglander William Wall John Dingley Thomas Mason Richard Ailliff Thomas Higgons
Edward Hide Bartholomew Smith John Smith Esquires Peter Clungeon William Horn Thomas Cornelius James
Clungeon Joseph De la Moat Nicholas Clement Gentlemen The Maior of Winton The Maior of Southampton
The Maior of Portsmouth The Maior of Newport The Maior of Basingstoake The Bailiff of Andover for the time
being Edward Downs Thomas Brooke Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p192">Stafford</para>
			<para id="p193">For the County of Stafford Sir Thomas Leigh Knight Sir Thomas Wilbraham Sir Edward Bagot Sir Edward
Littleton Sir Charles Wolseley Sir Francis Lawley Sir Walter Wrotesley Sir Cesar Colclough Baronets Sir John
Bowyer Knight and Baronet Sir Brian Broughton Knight and Baronett Sir John Broomfeild Baronet Sir Charles
Egerton Sir John Wyrley Sir Theophilus Biddolph Sir Thomas Whitgrave Knights Henry Gray William Sneyd
John Skrimsher [or<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] Norbury Gerard Skrimsher of Aquilat Randal Egerton Walter Chetwind junior George Digby
Edward Mainwaring John Lane Broom Whorwood Robert Levingston Robert Milward William Chetwind Charles
Cotton Rowland Cotton Henry Archbold John Shilton Amos Walrond John Whitehall John Peirsehouse Henry
Vernon Anthony Dyott Rowland Okeover Jonathan Cope Thomas Kinnersley George Parker William Orm John
Swinfem Edward Broughton Walter Grosvenor Walter Fowler junior Thomas Villars and Daniel Watson Esquires
Samuel Terrick John Colclough Timothy Edge Thomas Palmer and Thomas Bagnal Gentlemen Walter Littleton
Do&bholigct;or of the Lawes Samuel Hinton Do&bholigct;or of the Lawes Francis Whitwick Edward Morton senior Richard
Congrave Jonathan Woodnanth Edward Arablaster Thomas Whitby Esquires William Farmer Richard Braccgirdle
Thomas Rugeley John Gough Gentlemen William Whitby Esquire Thomas Scot Leicester Barbour Gentlemen The
Bayliffs of Tamworth for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p194">Lichfeild</para>
			<para id="p195">For the City and County of the City of Litchfeild The Bailiffs for the time being Michael Biddulph Anthony
Dyct John Hill Henry Archbold Esquires Thomas Caterbank Gentleman Jeoffry Glasier Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p196">Suffolk.</para>
			<para id="p197">For the County of Suffolke Sir Dudley North Sir Charles Cornwallis Sir Nicholas Bacon Sir John Knivet Knights
of the Bath Walter Devereux Esquire Sir Edmund Bacon Sir Lionel Tolmache Sir Henry Felton Sir John Barker
Sir Robert Kempe Sir John Castleton Sir William Spring Sir Henry Bacon Sir Henry North Sir Gervas Elwyes
Sir Thomas Darcy Sir Robert [Cardal<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] Sir John Rous Sir John Warner Sir John Crofts Sir Charles Gawdy Sir
Edward Duke Sir Robert Brooke Sir Philip Parker Baronets Sir Henry Crofts Sir (<ref idref="n47">47</ref>) William Pooley Sir Edmond
Pooly Sir John Duncombe Sir William Doyley Sir Philip Parker Sir Thomas Barnardistone Sir George Reve Sir
Robert Brooke Sir Thomas Hervey Sir John Pettus Sir Thomas Smith Knights John Hervey Isaac Appleton
Thomas Walgrave Thomas Holland Thomas Cullum Maurice Barrow John Poley Richard Cooke John Sicklemore
William Bloys senior Henry Warner Thomas Stewart John Garnish Henry Parker Joseph Brand Thomas Edgar
Hamond Claxton Clement Heigham William Gipps Edmond Harvey Wiseman Bokenham Henry Stebbin John
Thurston Robert Stile Fitznonne Lambe Henry Coppinger Philip Haward William Dawtry Thomas Arris Do&bholigct;or
of Phisick, Peregrine Doyley George Weneve Framlingham Gawdy John Duke Jeoffrey Burwell Isaac Botham
Thomas Vesey Robert Appleton Joseph Beaumont Borowdale Millisent Edward Spencer Thomas Bacon Humphrey
Moseley Thomas Dade Thomas Scrivenor Nevil Catlin William Blomfeild Thomas Leman William Bloys junior
Robert Buts [Thomas Day junior Thomas But&bholngs; <ref idref="n48">48</ref>] Robert Brownrig Francis Cheney Robert Marriot William Goodwin
Thomas Edgar of Glemhan Robert Nanton Gardner Webb Thomas Wright Barnaby Gibson Thomas Read John
Bence Robert King Do&bholigct;or of the Civill Law Henry North of Lackfeild Miles Edgar Edward North Edward
Man Thomas Man Edward Brampton John Rivett Thomas Tirrel Francis Theobald Edmond Firnely John Southby
Thomas Ogle Robert Gasnold Robert Penning Lionel Playters [Edward Spencer John Playters<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] John Braham
of Ash junior The Maior of Sudbury for the time being William Byat Joseph Man John Warner Esquires
John Cole Esquire Robert Maltiward Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p198">Burrough of Ipswich.</para>
			<para id="p199">For the Burrough of Ipswich The Bailiffs for the time being Sir Emanuel Sorrel John Sicklemore Recorder John
Smithier Nicholas Philips Robert Sparrow Robert Clerke Gilbert Windfeild</para>
			<para id="p200">Burrough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Edmonds Bury.</para>
			<para id="p201">For the Burrough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Edmonds Bury The Alderman for the time being John Southley Recorder Sir Edmond
Poley Sir John Duncombe James Cob Esquires Stephen Coke Samuel Hustler Edward Bourne Robert Sharpe
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p202">Burrough of Alburrough</para>
			<para id="p203">For the Burrough of Alburrough The Bailiffs for the time being Sir Robert Brooke Francis Bacon Recorder
William Shipman Thomas Elliot Richard Browne John Burwood Alexander Blowers Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p204">Burrough of Orford.</para>
			<para id="p205">For the Burrough of Orford The Maior for the time being Walter Devereux Thomas Cock Joseph Hastings
Edward Johnson Esquires John Copping [James Copping<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] Richard Copping Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p206">Surrey.</para>
			<para id="p207">For the County of Surrey [Rober<ref idref="n49">49</ref>] Duncombe High Sheriff of the County Charles Earle of Ancram Francis Lord
Aungier Benjamin Weston Esquire Sir Henry Capel Knight of the Bath Sir Francis Vincent Knight and Baronet
Sir Walter S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Johns Baronet Sir Adam Browne Baronet Sir Thomas Trevor Knight and Baronet and Knight of the
Bath Sir William Moore Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir John Evelin junior Sir Richard Stidolfe Sir Abraham Cullen
Sir George Ascough Sir John Brumfeild Baronets Sir Ralph Freeman Knight one of the Masters of the Requests
Sir Richard Onslow Sir John Lenthal Sir Edmond Bowyer Sir Charles Howard Sir John Evelin Sir William
Haward Sir Thomas Bludworth Sir Daniel Harvey Sir John Maynard Sir Robert [Parkehurst<ref idref="n50">50</ref>] Sir Richard Hatton
Sir Lawrence Smith Sir Allen Broderick Sir Nicholas Carew Sir Purbeck Temple Sir Edward Bish Knights Colonel
Robert Phillips one of the Groomes of his Majesties Bedchamber Edmond Hoskins Serjea[n<ref idref="n48">48</ref>]t att Law Henry Hilliard
Arthur Onslow George Chute Roger James John Scot Christopher Buckle Edward Evelin Anthony Bowyer
Thomas Foster George Evelin George Smith John Holmden Richard Evelin Esquires Thomas Turner 0Do&bholigct;or of
Law Edward Thurland Anthony Thomas William Hoskins Dixey Long George Moore John Thynne William
Owfeild William Wimondsold Mathew Carlton William Muschampe Henry Weston Thomas Turgis Erasmus
Gainsford Robert Holman Charles Bickerstaffe George Browne John Westbrooke George Vernon George Duncombe
Samuel Rowse James Gresham John Parker Edward Leventhorpe George Woodroffe Thomas Rogers William
Elliot John Loyd John Jones Lawrence Marsh Peter Hussey Richard West James Austin George Garth Dawes
Wimondsold Thomas Dalmahoy Vincent Randhill Doctor Windibanck Richard Heath William Boothby John
Wight William Street Anthony Covert Peter Quennel senior Es&bhoqesq;s</para>
			<para id="p208">The Burrough of Southwark</para>
			<para id="p209">For the Burrough of Southwark Sir John Brumfeild Baronet Sir John Lenthal Sir Edmond Bowyer Sir Thomas
Bludworth Knights George Chute John Scot George Moore Anthony Thomas Anthony Bowyer James Austin
Thomas Lee Robert Backhouse Giles Warcup John Thorpe Esquires Thomas Swinfeild Samuel Hyland Edward
Cooke George Mayot Peter De-la-noy Edward Ball William Lock Hugh Currer John Neale John Luntley James
Burton Richard Lewin William Whitworth Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p210">Sussex.</para>
			<para id="p211">For the County of Sussex Lord Peircy John Ashburnham Esquire Thomas Leonard Esquire Sir John Pelham
Sir Henry Goring Sir Charles Shelley Sir William Culpeper Sir John Covert Sir Herbert Springet Sir John Stapeley
Sir William Thomas Sir Denney Ashburnham Sir John Fag Sir William Wilson Baronets Sir John Lewkenor Sir
William Morley Knights of the Bath Sir John Morley Sir Thomas Dyke Sir Thomas Woodcock Sir Thomas Nut
Sir George Courthop Knights George Parker George Nevil Thomas Sackvil Henry Goring Esquires William
Garraway Henry Peckham John Steward Hugh Potter Esquires John May John Heward Thomas Gray Robert
Anderson John Farrington Allen Carr Brewen Bickley Thomas Palmer Thomas Peckham Esquires The Maior of
Chichester for the time being John Bine Thomas Middleton Henry Chowne Bray Chowne Edward Eresfeild Nizel
Rivers Samuel Got Walter Burrel Anthony Shirley John de-la-Chambri Richard Bridger Walter Duble William
Spencer Stephen French William Lane Ambrose Trayton John Oliver Henry Goring of Cobden John Shelley
Anthony Eversfeild William Screice John Bagshall John Gratwicke William Gratwick of Jervis Henry Onslow
Thomas Bettesworth Thomas Gray Harbert Morley Edward Blaker Thomas Board Peter Courthop Henry Bill
Richard Mills Robert Palmer Thomas Barnard Percy Goring Christopher Coles Thomas Pain George Edmonds
William Gratwick of Torton Thomas Collings Walter Everden Robert Fowle Edward Polhil Roger Shewswell Walter
Roberts John Dunk Richard Alchorne John Dine Robert Edsam Richard Sheppard Thomas Brumfeild William
Dyke of [Haunt<ref idref="n51">51</ref>] John Baker of Stoneland Thomas Luxford Edward May Anthony May Nicholas Gildridge Edward
Paine Richard Linsey Sackvil Graves John Fuller of Waldron John Hay of Glinborn Edward Michelburn Edward
Chowne Esquires Henry Shelley Peter Farneden Joseph Newington William Dyke junior Charles Bret Simon Smith
Robert Rochester John Harford William Markwick Thomas Delves William Parker Gentlemen The Maior of Hasting
The Maior of Rye The Maior of Winchelsea The Bailiff of Seaford The Bailiff of Pevensey George Easeman
Edward Peake Thomas Harrison Peter Guard Stephen Elphick Mr Grinfeild of Rye James French junior Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p212">Warwick.</para>
			<para id="p213">For the County of Warwick Sir William Compton Knight George Fane Charles Leigh Esquires Sir Robert Holt
Sir Richard Temple Sir Henry Puckering alias Newton Sir Edward Boughton Sir Roger Burgoigne Sir John
Knightley Sir Thomas Norton Sir Clement Fisher Sir Thomas Rouse Baronets Sir William Bromly Sir Stephen
Hailes Knights of the Bath Sir Simon Archer, Sir George Devereux Sir Francis Willoughby Sir Charles Adderley
Sir John Repington Sir Charles Lee Sir William Palmer Sir Arthur Cailey. Sir William Underhill Sir Combe
Wagstaffe Sir Richard Hopkins Sir Clement Throckmorton Knights Sir Herbert Price Baronet Amos Walrond Walter
Chetwind senior William Booth of Witton John Bridgman John Ferrers Richard Lucy Thomas Archer Clement
Throckmorton William Somervil Francis Willoughby Thomas Gibbs Seabright Repington William Dilks John Lisle
William Purefoy Harvey Bagot Richard Newdigate Serjeant at Law Thomas Temple Bazil Feilding Thomas
Boughton Boughton of Causton John Rous Thomas Flint Henry Beaufoy John Clopton Henry Ferrers William
Colmore Charles Newsham Lister of Alveston Richard Verney of Compton Verney Richard Verney of
Kingston Charles Bentley Giles Palmer Edward Underhill Thomas Marriot Robert Dod Humphrey Jennings Thomas
Corbin John Fetherston Mathew Holbeck Ambrose Holbeck John Stanton James Prescot John Wagstaff Thomas
Rawlins of Stratford Bishop Serjeant at Armes John Main Richard Willoughby Samuel Eborall George
Feilding Greswold of Cubington Nathaniel Stoughton Draper Esquires John Westley Adolphus
Wooton Richard Woodward Henry Smith Thomas Dighton Walduce Willington [Thomas Willington<ref idref="n52">52</ref>] of Whateley
Gentlemen The Bailiff of Warwick for the time being The Bailiff of Stratford for the time being The Bailiffs of
Tamworth for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p214">[For the City and County of Coventrey.</para>
			<para id="p215">M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Pigeon the present Maior Sir Thomas Morton Baronet Sir Richard Hopkins Knight Sir Arthur Caley
Thomas Hales Edmund Palmer Isaac Walden Robert Beak Alderman James Naylor John Wooldridge Julius Billiars
Henry Smith Mathew Smith Samuel Snel Joseph Chambers Aldermen Abraham [Gibbows<ref idref="n53">53</ref>] Gentleman.<ref idref="n54">54</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p216">Westmorland</para>
			<para id="p217">For the County of Westmorland Sir Philip Musgrave Sir William Dalston Sir George Fletcher Sir Richard
Sandford Sir John Lowther junior Sir John Lowther of Lowther Baronets Sir Thomas Strickland Knight Richard
Musgrave John Lowther Allin Bellingham Daniel Fleming Walter Strickland James Ducket John Dalston Richard
Crackinthorpe Richard Braithwait of Warcop Richard Braithwait of Burinside Robert Hilton Edward Nevison
Thomas Braithwayt John Otway Nicholas Fisher Thomas Sandford Lancelot Machel Thomas Gabelas Esquires The
Maior of Appleby for the time being. The Maior of Kendell for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p218">Wilts</para>
			<para id="p219">For the County of Wilts Henry Lord Herbert John Lord Seymour William Lord Herbert Henry Viscount
Cornbury Sir Edward Nicholas Knight one of his Majesties Principal Secretaries of State James Mountague Edward
Howard Charles Seymour Esquires Sir Walter S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Sir Seymour Pile Sir George Grobham How Sir Walter Erule
Sir George Hungerford Baronets Sir Edward Hungerford Sir John Nicholas Sir John Coventrey Sir Edward Baynton
Knights of the Bath Sir Robert Hide one of his Majesties Justices of the C&bhooov;mon Pleas Sir Wadham Windham one
of the Justices of the Kings Bench Sir James Thinne Sir John Evelin Sir Thomas Hall Sir John Talbot Sir (<ref idref="n55">55</ref>) Edward
Poole Sir Thomas Escourt Sir John Lowe Sir Thomas [Joy<ref idref="n56">56</ref>] Sir Henry Coker Sir William Calley Knights Alexander
Popham Edward Seymour Richard Grobham How Richard Lewis Edward Nicholas Lawrence Washington Henry
Clerke John Pleydell William Glanvil William Jordan Robert Philips John Erule George Ayliffe William Pawlett
Edward Hungerford Edward Tooker Ralph Freke (<ref idref="n57">57</ref>) Thomas Mompesson of Corton William Duckett Edward Hide
Edward Goddard of Standen William Brounker Henry Hungerford Walter Bokeland Gilbert Raleigh Duke Stonehouse
Joseph Stockman John Warnford Henry Baynton John Nordell Thomas Gore Jeffery Daniel Thomas Wancklin
George Lowe William Yorke John Kent John Long Henry Trenchard Henry Long Thomas Lambert William
Willoughby Thomas Grub John Foyle John Collins Edward Manning Giles Eyre William Kent Thomas Hawlis
Edward Topp James Ash Rowland Plot John Bowles Thomas Bennet of Pithouse Richard Southby John Danvers
Benjamin Gifford Nevil Maskline William Broomwich Richard Escourt George Joy John Hawkins Thomas Stewkley
William Fisher Edward Goddard of Ogborne John Eyre Samuel Ire Simon Spatchurst John Davenant Edward Not
Thomas Hungerford Henry Wallis John Curl Richard Long Samuel Ash John Awbry Michael Erule William
Swanton Seymour Bowman Walter Parker Edmond Web Isaac Burges John Mompesson John Fitzherbert William
Sadler Richard Bowle Thomas Chafin Esquires John Elliot Edward Yerbury Mathew Raymond Edmond Pike
Richard Green Richard Callow Robert Challoner Robert Chandler Paul Methwin Ferrers Greisley Charles Yorke
Peter Keblewhite Richard Crowch Ephraim Westley Jeffery Pinnel Christopher Gardiner Gentlemen John Holt
Richard Davy The Maior of New Sarum for the time being Stephen Fox Esquire William Joyce Alderman Edward
Edmonds Thomas [Oriat<ref idref="n58">58</ref>] Thomas Ray Maurice Greene Nicholas Johnson Sir John Denham Knight of the Bath John
Birkenhead Doctor of the Laws Thomas Gardiner John Glanvil Thomas Sadler The Maior of Wilton The Maior of
the Devizes for the time being Walter Sharpe.</para>
			<para id="p220">New Sarum.</para>
			<para id="p221">For the City of New Sarum Sir Walter Erule Baronet Sir John Low Knight Edward Tooker Thomas Hawles
William Swanton John Holt Thomas Darrel Esquires Thomas Ray Thomas [Oriat<ref idref="n59">59</ref>] Gentlemen M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Davy
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Mumpesson.</para>
			<para id="p222">Worcester.</para>
			<para id="p223">For the County of Worcester Sir John Pakington Baronet Colonel Sandys Sir William Russel Sir Henry
Littleton Baronets Sir Ralph Clare Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Herbert Sir Rowland Berkley Sir John Winford
Sir John Talbot Knights Thomas Savage of Elmely Edward Pits William Sandys Henry Bromley of Holt Henry
Bromley of Upton Henry Jefferies of Horncastle Henry Townshend Joseph Walsh Edward Cary Edward Bushel
William Sheldon of Broadway William Mucklow Walter Savage Edward Pennel Thomas Jollife George Symonds
Thomas Wilde Richard Dowdswel John Bearcroft Thomas Foley William Kite Thomas [Walson<ref idref="n60">60</ref>] William Sheldon
of Finstal Edward Vernon Francis Sheldon of Aberton John Nanfan Philip Parsons Philip Brace Edward Dingley of
Charleton Anthony Crump William Baldwin Theophilus Andrewes Francis Finch Samuel Sandys junior Thomas
Childe William Washborne William Hancock John Charlet Thomas Street Somerset Draper Esquires The Bailiffs of
the Burrough of Droytwich for the time being The Bayliff of Bewdley for the time being The Maior of Evesham
for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p224">City of Worcester.</para>
			<para id="p225">For the City and County of the City of Worcester The Maior Aldermen and Sheriffes for the time being
Sir Rowland Barkley Sir William Moreton Knights Richard Carwardin Richard Henning Robert Sollars John Higgens
John Bearcroft Thomas Street junior Humphrey Tyrer Gentlemen Thomas Hall Thomas Street Esquires Robert
Wild Thomas Harrison Thomas Twitty Edward Cooksey Edward Warring Francis Hughs Gent..</para>
			<para id="p226">Yorke</para>
			<para id="p227">For the Westriding in the County of Yorke Sir Thomas Osborne High Sheriff of the County George Viscount
Castleton Henry Viscount Earwin Thomas Lord Fairfax Conyers Darcy Esquire Sir George Savil Baronet Sir Francis
Wortley Baronet Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath Sir John Goodrick Knight and Baronet Sir John Kay Sir
Thomas Slingsby Sir Francis Bland Sir Solomon Swaile Sir Metcalfe Robinson Sir John Armitage Sir Richard
[Mallever Baronet<ref idref="n61">61</ref>] Sir Richard Tankard (<ref idref="n62">62</ref>) Sir William Rookbey Sir William Ingoldby Sir John Reasby Baronets Sir  
Jordan Crosland Sir Thomas Wentworth Knights Sir Godfrey Copley Baronet Walter Hawesworth Thomas Robinson
Robert Wivel Thomas Stringer Esquires Sir Miles Stapleton Sir Edmond Jenninges Knights Thomas Danby Francis
Nevil William Adams Esquires Sir John Dawney Francis Goodrick William Lowther Do&bholigct;or Burrel John Richard
Welbery Norton Richard Hutton Francis White Charles Tankerd of Whixley Henry Atkinson Ambrose Pudsey
Hugh Potter William Drake Esquires Sir William Ingram Knight William Stockdel Parker of
Bronsam Esquires Sir Christopher Clapham Knight Inglebert Leeds Thomas Yarbrugh Esquires Cuthbert Wade John
Preston The Maior of Pontefra&bholigct; for the time being Edward Atkinson John Stanhope Robert Branlin John Beelby
William Witham Esquires The Maior of Doncaster for the time being Roger Portington Esquire Sir George Wynn
Baronet.</para>
			<para id="p228">For the Northriding in the said County of Yorke Lord Bruce Conyers Darcy Esquire Sir Christopher Wyvel
Baronet Sir John Goodrick Knight and Baronet Sir John Lowther Sir Thomas Gower Sir John Hotham Sir Metcalfe
Robinson Sir Solomon Swaile Baronets James Darcy Esquire Sir Henry Stapleton Baronet Henry Darcy Esquire Sir
Roger Langley Baronet Sir Robert Strickland Sir Thomas Strickland Sir Jordan Crosland Knights Henry Chater Esquire
Sir William Dalton Sir John Yorke Knights Sir William Cholmley Sir James Pennyman Knight Sir David Fowles
Baronet Sir Thomas Ingram Knight James Medcalfe Esquire William Weddal Walter Strickland Mathew Hutton
Esquires Sir Thomas Heblethwait John Turner Esquire John Beverley Humphrey Wharton Thomas Robinson
Reynold Grayham Richard Grayham Esquires Sir Henry Cholmley Knight Major Norton Esquire Sir Henry Franklin
Knight Sir William Franklin Baronet Thomas Norton Thomas Jackson Thomas Rookby William Robinson Robert
Layton Roger Talbot Henry Marwood Edward Croft Charles Tankard of Arden Esquires Sir Joseph Craddock Knight
John Calverly George Norton Esquires Thomas Waite Gentleman The Alderman of Richmond for the time being
William Trueman Timothy Maleverer John Dodsworth William Thompson William Hickham Christopher Wandesford
Esquire Edward Trotter Anthony Lowther Roger Colvel Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p229">For the Eastriding in the said County Sir John Hotham Sir Francis Boynton Sir Watkinson Paylour Sir Robert
Hilliard Baronets Sir Mathew Appleyard Sir Francis Cobb Knights Tobias Jenkins Stephen Thompson Esquires Sir
John Ledyard Baronet Michael Wharton Esquire Sir Thomas Rudston Baronet Sir Thomas Remington Knight
Sir Philip Mountain Knight Thomas Grantham Durand Hotham John Constable Henry Holmes Christopher Hilliard
Hugh Lister Esquires Sir Hugh Bethel Knight Sir Hugh Bethel of Rize Knight George Mountain John Vavosour
John Headlam William Osbaston William Grimston Esquires Sir William Cobb Knight Robert Sotheby John
Hearn Thomas Crompton Samford Nevil William Gee Richard Leadgeard Tobias Hodgson Esquires Richard
Thompson.</para>
			<para id="p230">City of Yorke</para>
			<para id="p231">For the City and County of the City of Yorke James Brook Lord Maior Sir Medcalfe Robinson Baronet John
Scot Esquire George Manklings George Lamplough Aldermen M<emph type="p">r</emph> Cressey Burnet M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Thompson junior
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Speman M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Kilvington M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Elwick M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Loftus M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Tayler M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Calvert
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Philip Herbert M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Richardson M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Scot M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Coltman M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Setterthayht M<emph type="p">r</emph> Francis
Chadderton M<emph type="p">r</emph> Francis Brice M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Basford M<emph type="p">r</emph> James Breary Sir Thomas Slingsby Sir Miles Stapilton William
Fairfax Henry Fairfax James Moyser Thomas Robinson Lewis D'Arcy Richard Rowndall Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p232">Kingston upon Hull.</para>
			<para id="p233">For the Town and County of Kingston upon Hull M<emph type="p">r</emph> George Crowle now Maior Colonel Anthony Gilby William
Lister Esquire M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Rakes M<emph type="p">r</emph> William [Dadson<ref idref="n63">63</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Ripley M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Maister M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Berrier
M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Foxley M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Ramsden M<emph type="p">r</emph> Christopher Richardson M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Robinson M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Wilson
M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Raikes M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Vevers Hugh Lister Esquire Andrew Marvel Esquire M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edmund Popple M<emph type="p">r</emph> Anthony
Lambert senior M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Thompson M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Horner.</para>
			<para id="p234">Beverley.</para>
			<para id="p235">For the Town of Beverley The Maior for the time being Thomas Johnson Edward Grey senior William Wade
William Forge William Colson William Dunn Timothy Grey Robert Fotherby William Newcomb Edward Grey
junior John Todd William Nelson William Garthwait Abraham Burnet Thomas Gossip George Davies William
Hunter Robert Richardson.</para>
			<para id="p236">Anglesey</para>
			<para id="p237">For the County of Anglesey Robert Lord Viscount Bulkley Thomas Bulkley Esquire Nicholas Bagenal Esquire
Rouland Bulkley Esquire of Porthomwel John Robinson Esquire Peirce Lloyd senior Peirce Lloyd junior Richard
Owen Theodore Esquires Sir Hugh Owen Knight and Baronet John Bodvel Rowland White William Bould
Thomas Wood Hugh Hughes John Griffith Esquires John Owens John Owens Penrose Gentlemen Conisby
Williams Gent&bholngs; Henry Lloyd Esquire Henry Jones Gent&bholngs; David Lloyd Esquire William Lewis Gent&bholngs; John [Wine<ref idref="n64">64</ref>]
of Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p238">Brecon.</para>
			<para id="p239">For the County of Brecon Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland Sir William Lewis Sir Herbert Price Sir Henry
Williams Baronets John Herbert Esquire High Sheriff George Gwin Milburn Williams John Jefferies Lewis Morgan
Walter Vaugham Edmond Jones John Stedman Thomas Williams of Abercamlayes William Morgan of Newton
Thomas Lewis Hugh Powel Meredith Lewis James Watkins John Gwin Esquires William Vaughan of Lanihangel
Nantbrain William Lloyd of Wernos Rees Prise Lewis Gunter James Williams Henry Stedman Gentlemen The
Bailiff of Brecon for the time being Thomas Bowen Esquire Edward Games Esquire Henry Williams of Languttock
John Morgan of Wenalt William Lloyd of Llangamarch Jeoffrey Jeffreys of Liwel William Bowen junior Howel
Powel Gentt Henry Rumsey.</para>
			<para id="p240">Cardigan.</para>
			<para id="p241">For the County of Cardigan Sir Richard Price Baronet Sir Francis Lloyd Knight James Lewis senior John
Vaughan Jonathan Lloyd Henry Vaughan James Lewis junior Edward Vaughan Erasmus Lloyd Morgan Herbert
Reignald Jenkins David Lloyd Thomas Jenkins Richard Herbert Thomas Perry John Lewis Thomas Lloyd of
Rhue Arthen John Jones Esquires David Evans Thomas Lloyd of Ynis Gentlemen</para>
			<para id="p242">Carmarthen.</para>
			<para id="p243">For the County of Carmarthen Francis Lord Vaughan Sir John Vaughan Knight of the Bath Sir Edward Mansel
Sir William Russel Baronets Sir Edward Rice Knight John Vaughan of Lanelthy William Gwyn of Telliaris Henry
Vaughan of Derwith Henry Middleton John Vaughan of Dertlis Nicholas Williams Thomas Lloyd of Dengralt
John Lloyd of the Forrest James Jones of Talicothy Penry Vaughan John Vaughan of Place Gwyn Evan Thomas
Morgan Jones Thomas Lloyd of Bertlandoet Walter Vaughan John Lewis of Lisimeth Esquires John Powel junior
Gentlemen Owen Bristoc Walter Jones Charles Gwin of Gwempe Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p244">Burrough of Carmarthen.</para>
			<para id="p245">For the Burrough of Carmarthen The present Maior Anthony Jones David Goffe Griffith Burion Thomas Jones
Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p246">Carnarvan.</para>
			<para id="p247">For the County of Carnarvan Robert Lord Viscount Bulkley Thomas Bulkley Esquire Sir Richard Wynne
Baronet Sir Roger Mostin Sir Griffith Williams Baronets Sir John Owen Sir Richard Lloyd Knights Nicholas
Bagnal Griffith Jones John Bodvel William Griffith William Vaughan Thomas Winne Owen Winne Richard
Thomas John Bodurda Thomas Vaughan John Williams William Hookes Richard Cuffin Maurice Winne of
Crogen Esquires Hugh Bodurda William Williams Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p248">Denbigh</para>
			<para id="p249">For the County of Denbigh Sir Thomas Middleton Knight Sir Richard Winne Sir John Salisbury Sir Thomas
Powel Sir William Meredith Sir Thomas Middleton Baronets Sir Thomas Trevor Knight &amp;Baronet Sir Evan Lloyd
Baronet Sir Richard Lloyd Sir Edward Broughton Sir Robert Agbrow Knights William Owen of Landur Simon
Thelwal John Robinson John Winne of Watstay Mutton Davis Bevis Lloyd Thomas Jones Hugh Winne Kenrick
Eyton John Wynne of Melay Robert Wynne of Voylay John Thelwal John Edisbury William Wynne of Grath
kuman Fouk Middleton Edward Bruerton John Jefferies Richard Middleton of Lansylin Charles Middleton William
Parry Robert Price of Geeler Watkin Kiffin David Maurice John Thelwal Owen Thelwal Hugh Roberts George
Bostock Francis Manley Esquires Humphrey Lloyd Gentleman Robert Wynne of Garthwynne Howel Lloyd
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p250">Flint.</para>
			<para id="p251">For the County of Flint Roger Puleston High Sheriff of the County Sir Thomas Hanmer Sir Henry Conway
Sir Roger Mostin Baronets Sir John Hanmer Knight William Hanmer Robert Davies Thomas Ravenscroft Thomas
Lloyd Roger Whitley John Parry Peter Griffith Thomas Salisbury Robert Whitley David Pennant Mutton Davies
Richard Young John Broughton William Mostin Robert Mostin Evan Edwards Edward Lloyd Owen Barton
Hugh Pennant Thomas Cratchley Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p252">Glamorgan.</para>
			<para id="p253">For the County of Glamorgan Henry Lord Herbert William Lord Herbert of Cardiffe Sir Richard Lloyd Knight
Arthur Trevor Esquire Sir Edward Mansil Sir Edward Thomas Sir John Awbry Baronets Sir Thomas Lewis Sir
Richard Basset Sir William Lewis Knights Thomas Lewis William Basset Bussey Mansel William Herbert Edmond
Thomas David Mathew Thomas Mathew Thomas Carne David Jenkins William Thomas Herbert Evans Esquires
Evan Seyes Serjeant at Law Humphrey Windham Thomas Stradling senior Thomas Stradling junior John Windham
William Morgan Thomas Awbry John Carne Esquires Do&bholigct;or William Basset Thomas Thomas Walter Thomas
Myles Button Gabriel Lewis Richard Longer Edmond Gamage Esquires Doctor Crofts Edward Mathew John
Van Miles Mathew of the Ulstrid Richard Seyes Edward Mansel Charles Bowen Henry Basset Henry Hill Roger
Williams Esquires M<emph type="p">r</emph>. ThomasBasset M<emph type="p">r</emph>. William Jones M<emph type="p">r</emph>. Richard Jenkins of Pantenowall M<emph type="p">r</emph>. Edward Jenkins of
Cowbridge M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Corrock M<emph type="p">r</emph>. Reece Hopkins M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Deere M<emph type="p">r</emph> David Evan of Lantwit Verdra Mr George
Williams of Baylan M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Prichard M<emph type="p">r</emph> George Gibbons M<emph type="p">r</emph> Morgan Miles M<emph type="p">r</emph> Stephen Edwards M<emph type="p">r</emph> David Richards
M<emph type="p">r</emph> George Lucas M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Thomas of Peterston super Montem M<emph type="p">r</emph> Watkin Jones M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Morgan M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas
Powel M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Jenkins.</para>
			<para id="p254">Merioneth.</para>
			<para id="p255">For the County of Merioneth William Salisbury Esquire High Sheriff of the County of Merioneth Sir Richard
Wynne Sir Thomas Middleton Baronets Sir John Owen Sir Richard Lloyd Knights William Price William Vaughan
William Winne of Barthginan Maurice Winne of [Rogen<ref idref="n65">65</ref>] Lewis Lloyd Howel Vaughan of Glin-yllyn John Lloyd
John Pugh Roger Mostin John Winne of Rihwgoch Robert Winne Griffith Lloyd Lewis Owen William Vaughan
of [Cothle<ref idref="n66">66</ref>] John Nanney of Llanventheged Edmond Merick Humfry Hughes John Vaughan Rowland Vaughan Maurice
Williams Richard Anwill Ellis Edwards John Morgans Henry Winne Esquires. William Tudir Lewis Gwyn Thomas
Lloyd Richard Lloyd of Carrog John Lloyd of Ddualt John Owen of Havod Dowilth. John Foults Evan Lloyd of
Goppa Richard Winne Gentlemen</para>
			<para id="p256">Mountgomery.</para>
			<para id="p257">For the County of Mountgomery Andrew Newport Esquire Sir Mathew Price Baronet Sir Edward Lloyd Knight
John Purcel John Blayney John Pugh Richard Herbert Francis Buller Edmond Waring William Okely Richard
Owen John Price of Parks Mathew Morgan William Penchin Roger Mostin Thomas Maurice Edward Glynn of
of Glyn Edward Evans of Rhydy Carrow John Whittingham David Powel Thomas Inks Edward Edwards of
Coltfrin John Blodwell Thomas Wind Thomas Corbet Esquires Samuel Bigs Michael Middleton Gentlemen
Robert Lee Esquire Henry Purcel Evan Vaughan John Kiffin Humfry Nicholas Gent. Francis Fitz herbert Esquire
Edward Whittingham Gent. Robert Leighton Esquire Charles Salisbury Robert Griffiths Esquires John Okely
James Penrhyn Evan Evans of Coome-yr-Annel Gent.</para>
			<para id="p258">Pembroke</para>
			<para id="p259">For the County of Pembroke Sir Erasmus Phillips Sir John Stepney Baronets Sir Hugh Owen Knight and
Baronet Sir Herbert Perrot Knight Essex Meyrick Rowland Langharn Roger Lort Arthur Owen Henry White
Thomas Warren Lewis Barlow Hugh Bowen George Barlow William Scowrefeild William Phillips James Bowen
Thomas Owen Thomas Parry George Haward James Lloyd Isaac Lloyd Arnold Thomas Thomas Lloyd of [Marvile<ref idref="n67">67</ref>]
David Morgan Thomas Wogan of Langstinan John Lort Walter Cuny Nicholas Adams William Mordant Thomas
Cozens John Mathias Esquires The Maior of Pembroke for the time being Richard Browne Mathew Bowen
Aldermen The Maior of Tenby for the time being Richard Wyat John Protherough Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p260">Haverford West.</para>
			<para id="p261">For the Town and County of Haverford West Sir Erasmus Phillips Sir John Stepney Baronets Sir Hugh Owen
Knight and Baronet Sir Herbert Perrot Knight Rowland Langharne Arthur Owen [Rogert<ref idref="n68">68</ref>] Lort Henry White Isaac
Lloyd George Barlow Thomas Lloyd Arnold Thomas Esquires William Meyler William Williams Henry Bowen
Thomas Davies Philip Wall Richard Bateman William Walter Aldermen John Thomas Thomas Bowen William
Howel Baltazer Walford George Knethel Daniel Freeman Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p262">Radnor.</para>
			<para id="p263">For the County of Radnor Sir Richard Lloyd Knight Arthur Trevor Esquire Sir Edward Harley Knight of the
Bath Sir Robert Harley Knight George Gwin Richard Fowler James Price Thomas Corbet Henry Williams Lewis.
Morgan John Walcot Thomas Harley Samuel Powel Nicholas Taylor Evan Davies Andrew Phillips Charles Lewis
Henry Probert Herbert Weston Griffith Jones Hugh Powel Richard Meredith Thomas Eckleston Robert Cutler
Francis Richards John [Richards<ref idref="n69">69</ref>] Rowland Higgens Esquires The Bailiff of New Radnor for the time being</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Commissioners to meet to execute Act on or before 20th Jan. next, and to divide themselves.</head>
			<para id="p264">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that the several Commissioners aforesaid shall meet togeather at the
most usual and comon place of meeting within each of the said Counties Cities Burroughs Towns and places
respe&bholigct;ively on or before the twentieth day of January now next ensueing and the said Commissioners or so many
of them as shal be present at the said first General Meeting or the major part of them are hereby authorized and
required to put this present A&bholigct;in execution according to the best of theire judgements and discretions and shal then
subdivide and distribute themselves so into lesser numbers as two or more of the said Commissioners may be appointed
for the service of each hundred or other division and as may best conduce to the carrying on of his Majesties
service hereby required</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. And to set down in Writing what Number shall act in each Division.</head>
			<para id="p265">And for the more effe&bholigct;ual performance thereof Be it ena&bholigct;ed and declared that the Commissioners att the
aforesaid first General Meeting or the major part of them shall agree and sett downe in writing who and what
number of the said C&bhooov;missioners shall a&bholigct; in each of the said divisions or hundreds to the end that there be no
failure in any part of the due execution of the service by this A&bholigct; required</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Commissioners to cause Assessment to be equally made, and to appoint Assessors,</head>
			<para id="p266">
				<emph type="i">who are to assess by a Pound Rate</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p267">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid that the Commissioners within the several divisions or
hundreds or any two or more of them are hereby authorized and required to cause the said several propor&bhocotil;ns
charged on the respe&bholigct;ive divisions and on every parish and place therein for the said eighteen moneths assessment
to be equally assessed and taxed and to appoint two or more assessors in each parish or place for the perfe&bholigct;ing
thereof who are hereby required withal care and diligence to assess the same equally by a pound rate as formerly
upon all Lands Tenements Hereditaments Annuities Rents Park&bholngs; Warrens Goods Chattels Stocke Merchandize Offices
usually rated Tolls Profit&bholngs; and all other Estates both real and personal within the limits circuites and bounds of theire
respe&bholigct;ive parishes and places.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. &pound;210,000, the first quarterly Payment, to be paid to Receiver General, and by him into the Exchequer on or before 25th March 1662.</head>
			<para id="p268">
				<emph type="i">Second Payment 24th June.; Third Payment 29th September.; Fourth Payment 25th December.; Fifth Payment 25th March 1663.; Last Payment 24th June</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p269">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the s&bhouov;m of two hundred and ten thousand pounds
being the first of the said six quarterly payment&bholngs; hereby imposed shal bee assessed colle&bholigct;ed levied and paid into
the Receivors-General of the said several Counties who shall be appointed by his Majesty and who are hereby
required to transmit or cause the same to be paid into his Majesties Receipt of his Exchequer on or before the
five and twentieth day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty two and the sum of two
hundred and ten thousand pounds being the second of the said quarterly payments on or before the twenty fourth
day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty two and the s&bhouov;m of two hundred and ten
thousand pounds being the third of the said quarterly payments on or before the twenty ninth day of September
in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty two and the s&bhouov;m of twoe hundred and ten thousand
pounds being the fourth of the said quarterly payments on or before the twenty fifth day of December in the
yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty two and the s&bhouov;m of two hundred and ten thousand pounds
being the fifth of the said quarterly payments on or before the twenty fifth day of March in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred sixty three and the s&bhouov;m of two hundred and ten thousand pounds being the last
of the said quarterly payments on or before the twenty fourth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred sixty three.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Assessors to deliver Copy of Assessment to Commissioners, who are to sign and seal two Duplicates and deliver one to Sub-colle&bholigct;or, whom they are to appoint, together with a Warrant to colle&bholigct; the Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p270">
				<emph type="i">Monies to be paid to Head Colle&bholigct;ors, and by them to Receivers General, and by them into the Exchequer.; The other Duplicate to Lord High Treasurer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p271">And for the compleating [of<ref idref="n70">70</ref>] the whole s&bhouov;ms charged upon the same and to the end the aforesaid s&bhouov;ms charged
upon the several and respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cities Burroughes Towns and places may be equally and indifferently
assessed according to the true intent of this A&bholigct; and the money duly colle&bholigct;ed and true accompt thereof made the
said Assessors are hereby required to deliver one Copy of theire respe&bholigct;ive assessments fairely written and
subscribed by them unto the said Commissioners And the said Commissioners or any twoe or more of them are
hereby ordered and required to signe and seale two Duplicates of the said Assessments and the one of them to
deliver or cause to be delivered to one or more honest and responsible person or persons to be Subcolle&bholigct;or or
Subcolle&bholigct;ors which the said Commissioners are hereby authorized to nominate and appoint for each parish or
place with warrant to the said Subcolle&bholigct;or or Subcolle&bholigct;ors to colle&bholigct; the said eighteen monthes assessment payable
as aforesaid so as the said several s&bhouov;ms may be paid in to the head Colle&bholigct;ors to be nominated and appointed by
the said Commissioners to receive the same so timely as they may by them be paid in to the said Receivers
Generall and by them into the receipt of his Majesties Exchequer at the respe&bholigct;ive times aforesaid And the said
Commissioners are hereby required to deliver or cause to be delivered the other of the said Duplicates of each
parish or place to the Receiver General of each County City Town or place respe&bholigct;ively to be by him the said
Receiver General transmitted to the Lord High Treasurer of England which the said Receiver General is required
to perform accordingly</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Commissioners to appoint Head Colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
			<para id="p272">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that the said Commissioners in theire respe&bholigct;ive divisions or hundreds or
any two or more of them shal and are hereby impowered to nominate and appoint under theire hands and
seales an honest able and responsible person to be head Colle&bholigct;or unto whom the moneys received by the
Subcolle&bholigct;ors within the division or hundred shall from time to time be duly paid And the said head Colle&bholigct;or
is hereby required upon the receipt thereof to pay the same forthwith to the Receiver General of each county
respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Collectors to pay to Receivers General, who are to pay into Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p273">
				<emph type="i">Salary to Receiver General of 1d. in the Pound</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p274">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that the particular Colle&bholigct;ors and sub colle&bholigct;ors are hereby required to
pay in all and every the s&bhouov;ms so received by them to the said Receivers-Gen[er]all aforesaid who are hereby required
forthwith to transmit or cause to be paid the moneys by them received into the Receipt of his Maj&bhomties; Exchequer
And the said Lord Treasurer is hereby authorized to allow the said Receiver Generall of each County City and
Town respe&bholigct;ively in case he hath returned up to him a duplicate of the Assessment of each parish or place in
county city or Town for which he is appointed Receiver General a Salary for his paines not exceeding one penny
in the pound upon the cleareing of his accompt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Salary to Sub-Colle&bholigct;ors of id. in the Pound.</head>
			<para id="p275">
				<emph type="i">Allowance to Head Colle&bholigct;ors of id. in the Pound.; Allowance to Commissioners Clerks of 1d. in the Pound</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p276">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the Sub Colle&bholigct;ors of each parish or place which shall bee
appointed by vertue of this A&bholigct;shall upon the colle&bholigct;ion of the whole s&bhouov;m appointed to bee colle&bholigct;ed by them
and payment thereof as is hereby and before appointed have and receive for theire paines in colle&bholigct;ing and paying
the moneys one penny in the pound which the said several head collectors are hereby authorized to pay unto
them and the several head Colle&bholigct;ors which shall bee appointed by vertue of this A&bholigct;shall upon the payment
of the whole s&bhouov;m due from theire Hundred or Division to the Receiver-Generall of each County have and
receive for theire paines in receiving and paying the said moneys one penny in the pound which each ReceiverGenerall is hereby authorized to pay and allow unto them accordingly And alsoe upon the Receipt of the whole
assessment of the County City or Town for which he is appointed Receiver General in case he hath received the
severall Duplicates of each parish or place therein and not otherwise to allow and pay according to such Warrant
as shall bee in that behalfe given by the said Commissioners or any three of them one penny in the pound for
the Comissioners Clerkes for theire paines in faire writing the Assessments Duplicates and Copies Provided that
no head Colle&bholigct;or shall be appointed for any City or Town which is by this A&bholigct; particularly charged with
the payment of any s&bhouov;m towards the assessment hereby to be levied and for which a Receiver General is to
be appointed excepting within the City of London</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Persons rated refusing to pay. Distress.</head>
			<para id="p277">
				<emph type="i">Colle&bholigct;ors may break open Houses, Chests, &amp;c. calling to their Assistance Constables, &amp;c.; Questions upon Distresses to be determined by Commissioners. Conveying Goods away so that no Levy can be had. Imprisonment. Except Peers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p278">And be it ena&bholigct;ed &amp;declared That if any person shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to pay any s&bhouov;m of money whereat
he shall be rated or assessed that then it shall and may bee lawfull to and for the said Colle&bholigct;ors Sub Colle&bholigct;ors
or any of them who are hereby authorized and required thereunto to levie the s&bhouov;m assessed by distresse and sale
of the goods of such persons so refusing or negle&bholigct;ing to pay dedu&bholigct;ing the s&bhouov;m assessed and reasonable charges
of distraining and restore the overplus to the owner thereof and to breake open in the day time any house and upon
warrant under the hands and seals of two or more of the said Commissioners any Chest Trunk or Box or other
thing where any such goods are and to call to theire assistance the Constables Tythingman and Headborough within
the Counties Cities Towns or places where any refusall negle&bholigct;or resistance shall be made which said Officers and
Forces are hereby required to bee aiding and assisting in the premisses as they will answer the contrary att theire
perills And if any question or difference happen upon takeing of such distresses betweene the parties distressed or
distrained the same shall be ended and determined by the said Commissioners or any two or more of them And if
any person or persons shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to pay his or theire assessment and convey his or theire goods or
other personall estate whereby the s&bhouov;m of money so assessed cannot be levied according to this A&bholigct; then the respe&bholigct;ive
Commissioners or any twoe or more of them are hereby authorized to imprison the person (except a Peere or
Peers of this Realm) and him and them in prison to detain and keepe untill the money so assessed and the charges
for the bringing in the same be paid and satisfied and no longer</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Tenants to pay Rate on Land and dedu&bholigct; out of Rent.</head>
			<para id="p279">
				<emph type="i">Landlords to allow such Deduction</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p280">And the severall and respe&bholigct;ive tennants or tennant of all Houses and Land which shall be rated by vertue of
this A&bholigct; are hereby required and authorized to pay such s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money as shall be rated upon such house
or lands and to dedu&bholigct; out of the rent so much of the said rates as in respe&bholigct;of the said Rents of every such
house and lands the Landlord should or ought to [pay &amp;<ref idref="n71">71</ref>] beare And the said Landlords both mediate and immediate
according to theire respe&bholigct;ive Interests are hereby required to allow such dedu&bholigct;ions and payments upon the receipt
of the residue of theire Rent&bholngs;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Tenant so paying acquitted for Amount of Payment.</head>
			<para id="p281">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may settle Differences between Landlords and Tenants.; Persons aggrieved by Assessment may complain to Commissioners, who may relieve</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p282">And it is ena&bholigct;ed and declared that every tenant paying the said Assessment shall be acquitted and discharged
[for<ref idref="n71">71</ref>] so much money as the said Assessment shall amount unto as if the same had bee a&bholigct;ually paid unto such
person and persons unto whom his rents should have been due and payable And if any difference shall arise
betweene Landlord and Tennant or any other concerning the said Rates the said severall Commissioners or any two
or more of them in theire several divisions shall and have hereby power to settle the same as they shall thinke fitt
And if any person or persons shall find him or themselves [agreived<ref idref="n71">71</ref>] in that the Assessors have over rated him or
them and shall within six dayes after demand made of the s&bhouov;m of money assessed on him or them complain to the
Commissioners who signed and allowed his or theire assessment the said Commissioners or any two or more of
them who signed or allowed such assessment shall have and have hereby power within the said six dayes after the
demand of the assessment as aforesaid to releive such person or persons and to charge the same on such other
person or persons as they shall see cause</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. If Assessment be not fully paid, Commissioners, &amp;c. may re-assess;</head>
			<para id="p283">
				<emph type="i">and the new Assessment to be paid accordingly</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p284">And in case the proportions set by this A&bholigct;upon all and every the respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cities Towns and Places
shall not be full assessed levied and paid according to the true meaning thereof or that if any of the said assessments
shall be rated and imposed upon any person not being of ability to pay the same or upon any empty or void house
or land where the same cannot be colle&bholigct;ed or levied or that through any wilfulnes negligence mistake or accident
the said assessment charged upon each County City Town or Place by vertue of this A&bholigct; happens not to be paid
to the receipt of his Majesties Exchequer as in this A&bholigct;is dire&bholigct;ed that then in all and every such cases the several
and respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners Assessors and Colle&bholigct;ors aforesaid and every of them respe&bholigct;ively are hereby authorized
and required to assesse or re assesse or cause to bee assessed or re assessed levied and paid [and<ref idref="n72">72</ref>] all and every such
s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money upon the respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cities Towns and Places or upon any of the Divisions Hundreds
and Parishes therein as to the said Commissioners or such number of them as by this A&bholigct; are authorized to cause
the first assessment hereby required to be made shall seeme most agreeable to equity and justice the said new
assessment to be made colle&bholigct;ed and paid in such manner and by such meanes as in this A&bholigct; for this Assessment
is declared and dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Persons refusing to execute A&bholigct;;</head>
			<para id="p285">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may fine them, not exceeding &pound;20.; Fines to whom paid; </emph>.</para>
			<para id="p286">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid that if any person or persons shall wilfully
negle&bholigct;or refuse to performe his or theire duty in the due and speedy execution of this present A&bholigct; the said
respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any three or more of them have hereby power to impose on such person or persons
so refusing or negle&bholigct;ing theire duties such fine or fines as to them shall be thought fitt and to cause the same
to bee levied by distresse and sale of his and theire Goods Provided that no fine to be imposed by any of
the said Commissioners shall for any one Offence exceed the s&bhouov;m of twenty pounds And that all fines that shall
be imposed by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be paid to the respe&bholigct;ive Receivers General and by them to the Receipt
of his Majesties Exchequer</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Receivers General, Colle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. not paying or detaining Monies received by them, Commissioners may imprison them, and seize their Estates Real and Personal.</head>
			<para id="p287">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that if any Receiver General Colle&bholigct;or or Sub Colle&bholigct;or that shall by
vertue of this A&bholigct; be appointed for the receipt of any s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money thereby to bee assessed shall
neglect or refuse to pay any su[m]m or su[m]ms of money which shall [be<ref idref="n71">71</ref>] by him so received as aforesaid and
not pay the same as in and by this Act is directed [&amp; shall detaine in his or theire hands any money received
by them or any of them &amp; not pay the same as by this Act is directed<ref idref="n71">71</ref>] the Commissioners of each County
City or Town respectively or any two or more of them in theire respective divisions are hereby authorized and
impowred to imprison the person and seize and secure the estate both real and personal of such Receiver-General
Colle&bholigct;or or Sub Colle&bholigct;or theire heires executors or administrators where ever the same can be discovered and
found And the said Commissioners who shall so seize and secure the Estate of any Receiver General Colle&bholigct;or
or Sub Colle&bholigct;or shall be and are hereby impowred to appoint a time for the general meeting of the Commissioners
of such County City or Town and there to cause pubique notice to bee given at the place where such meeting
shall be appointed ten dayes att least before such general meeting And the Commissioners present at such general
meeting or the major part of them in case the moneys detained by Receivers General Colle&bholigct;ors or Sub Colle&bholigct;ors
be not paid and satisfied as it ought to bee according to the directions of this A&bholigct;shall and are hereby impowred
to sell and dispose of all such estates which shall be for the causes aforesaid seized and secured and satisfie and
pay such County and Place the s&bhouov;ms that shall be soe detained in the hands of such Receiver-General Collector
or Sub Colle&bholigct;or and return the Overplus to such Receiver-General Colle&bholigct;or or Sub Colle&bholigct;or their heires
executors and administrators.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. At the Expiration of Times for quarterly Payments, Commissioners to call Colle&bholigct;ors before them, and assure themselves of Payments of Monies charged.</head>
			<para id="p288">
				<emph type="i">In case of Failure, Commissioners to levy the same</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p289">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that at the expira&bhocotil;n of the respe&bholigct;ive times in this A&bholigct;prescribed
for the full payment of the said quarterly Assessments the several and respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any two of
them within the division and hundred shall and are hereby required to call before them the cheife Colle&bholigct;ors
and Sub Colle&bholigct;ors within each respe&bholigct;ive Division and Hundred to examine and assure themselves of the full and
whole payment of the particular s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money charged upon the said Division Hundred and every
parish and place therein and of the due return of the same into the hands of the Receiver-General of the
said County City Town and Place respe&bholigct;ively And by such Receiver General to the Receipt of his Majesties
Exchequer to the end there may bee no failure in the payment of any part of the assessment by vertue of this
A&bholigct; to be assessed and paid nor any arreares remaine chargeable upon any of the said Counties Cities Towns or
places respe&bholigct;ively And in case of any failure in the &bhopcrl;misses the said Commissioners or any two of them are
hereby to cause the same to bee forthwith levied and paid according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. If Controversies arise in which Commissioners interested, such Commissioners to withdraw.</head>
			<para id="p290">And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared that in case any controversies arise concerning the said assessments or the
dividing apportioning or payment thereof which concern any of the Commissioners by this A&bholigct; appointed that the
Commissioners so concerned in the said controversies shall have no voice but shall withdrawe at the time of the
debate of any such controversie untill it be determined by the rest of the Commissioners.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Privileged Places, Fee Farm Rents, &amp;c. liable.</head>
			<para id="p291">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Tenants thereof paying</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p292">And be it hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared that no priviledged place or person body politick or corporate within
the Counties Cities and Townes aforesaid shall be exempted from the said Assessment&bholngs; and taxes but that they
and every of them and alsoe all Fee Farme Rents and all other manner of Rent&bholngs; Payments and s&bhouov;ms of moneys
and Annuities issuing out of [any<ref idref="n74">74</ref>] Lands within City or County shall be lyable towards the payment of every s&bhouov;m
by this A&bholigct; to be taxed and levied and all the tennant&bholngs; of any Fee Farme Rent other rent s&bhouov;ms of money or
Annuities aforesaid are hereby dire&bholigct;ed and authorized to pay them proportionably according to the Rates and
Assessments by this Act appointed and dire&bholigct;ed And all such Tennant&bholngs;shall be hereby saved and kept harmelesse
by authority of this A&bholigct; from any further payment of such portion of any such Rent Rents s&bhouov;ms or Annuities
either to the Exchequer or to any other person or persons to whom any such Rent Rents s&bhouov;ms of moneys or
a&bhonov;uities as aforesaid should or ought to bee paid to all intents or purposes whatsoever as fully and as amply as if
they had paid the same into the Exchequer or to any other person or persons to whom the same is reserved or
become due.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Proviso for the Universities, and the Colleges of Winchester, Eaton, Westminster, Free Schools, Hospitals, &amp;c. and for Lands, &amp;c. of St. Bartholomew, Bridewell, St. Thomas, and Bethlem Hospitals.</head>
			<para id="p293">Provided that nothing contained in this A&bholigct; shall be extended to charge any Master Fellow or Scholar of any
Colledge in either of the Universities or in the Colledge of Winchester Eaton or Westminster or in any other
Free Schooles or any Reader Officer or Minister of the said Universities Colledges or Schooles or of any Hospitals
or Almes-houses for or in respe&bholigct; of any Stipend Wages or profit whatsoever ariseing or growing due to them in
respe&bholigct; of the said several places and imployments in the said Universities Colledges Schools Hospitals or Almeshouses nor to charge any of the houses or lands belonging to Christs Hospital S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Bartholomew Bridewel S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Thomas
and Bethelem Hospitals in the City of London and Burrough of Southwarke or any of them for or in respe&bholigct; of
any Rents or Revenues payable to the said Hospitals being to bee received and disbursed for the immediate use
and releife of the poore in the said Hospitals.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. But Tenants under Lease from said Hospitals, to pay.</head>
			<para id="p294">Provided that no Tenants that hold or enjoy any Lands or Houses by lease or any other grant from any of
the said Hospitals do claime and enjoy any freedome exemption or advantage by this A&bholigct; But that all the houses
and Lands which they so hold shall be rated [&amp;<ref idref="n74">74</ref>] assessed for soe much as they are yearely worth over and
above the rents reserved and payable to the said Hospitals</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Person dwelling in London in one Parish, &amp;c. and having Goods in other Parishes, &amp;c. charged where he dwells.</head>
			<para id="p295">Provided alsoe That where any person inhabiting within the City of London hath his dwelling house in one of
the parishes or ward&bholngs; therein and hath any Office goods wares or merchandizes in one or more of the other parishes
or wards within the same that then such person shall be charged taxed and assessed for such his Office Goods or
Merchandize in the parish or ward where he dwelleth and not elsewhere in the said City.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. The like as to Persons dwelling out of London and having Office within.</head>
			<para id="p296">Provided alsoe That where any person inhabiting without the City of London and hath any Office within the
said City that then such person shall be taxed and assessed for such his Office in the place or parish where he
dwelleth and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. No Clause in this A&bholigct; to lessen Payment.</head>
			<para id="p297">Provided nevertheles That no Clause or Proviso in this A&bholigct; shall extend to the lessening or abatement of
the full s&bhouov;m by this A&bholigct; appointed to be taxed levied and paid but that the same be fully assessed taxed levied
colle&bholigct;ed and paid in the several and respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cities and Towns aforesaid in such manner and form
and to such uses as is herein before men&bhocotil;ned and declared</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Commissioners to account to Lord Treasurer, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p298">And that the several and respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners and every of them shall from time to time give a true and
perfe&bholigct; accompt of all theire doings and proceedings in the execution of this A&bholigct;to the said Lord Treasurer or to
other such persons as his Majesty shall appoint</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. If Pound Rate be found prejudicial, Commissioners may assess in the manner usual in respect&bholigct;ive Counties, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p299">Provided alwaies And bee it hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared that in case the way or manner of assessing by a
pound rate shall prove any way prejudicial or obstru&bholigct;ive to the said speedy bringing in of the assessment or any
part thereof appointed by this A&bholigct; That then and in all such cases the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any twoe of
them are hereby authorized to order and dire&bholigct; the respe&bholigct;ive Assessors who are hereby required to proceed
accordingly to assesse the respe&bholigct;ive sums charged on the respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cities &amp;Burroughs Townes and
Places mentioned in this A&bholigct; according to the most just and usuall way of rates held and pra&bholigct;ised in such
Counties Cities Burroughs Towns and Places respe&bholigct;ively, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof contained
in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. This Assessment not to be drawn into Example.</head>
			<para id="p300">Provided alwaies That the apportionment of the assessment according to the Rates and [&bhopubrc;portions<ref idref="n74">74</ref>] of this A&bholigct;
upon the several Counties Cities and Burroughs assessed shall not be drawne into president or used for any example
for the future.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Proviso for the Bishops, Peers, and Clergy, Universities, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p301">Provided alsoe That nothing herein contained shall be drawn into example to the prejudice of the ancient
rights belonging unto the Lords Spiritual and Temporal or Clergy of this Realm or unto either of the Universities
or unto any Colledges Schools Almes houses or Hospitals.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Proviso for Agreements as to Taxes between Landlord and Tenant.</head>
			<para id="p302">Provided alwaies that nothing in this A&bholigct; contained shall be construed to alter change determine or make void
any Contra&bholigct;s Covenants Agreements or Usages whatsoever between the Landlord and Tenant touching the payment
of taxes or assessments Any thing herein before mentioned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Places to be assessed in such Hundreds, &amp;c. as heretofore.</head>
			<para id="p303">Provided alwaies And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid that for the avoiding of all
obstru&bholigct;ions and delayes in colle&bholigct;ing the s&bhouov;ms by this A&bholigct; to be raised and assessed all Places Constable wicks
Divisions &amp;Allotments shall pay and be assessed in such hundred rape and wapentake as the same hath heretofore
usually beene assessed in and not elsewhere</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. In A&bholigct;ions brought for executing A&bholigct; General Issue may be pleaded.</head>
			<para id="p304">
				<emph type="i">Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p305">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that if any a&bholigct;ion plaint suit or information shall bee
c&bhooov;menced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall do in pursuance or in execution
of this A&bholigct; such person or persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall or may plead the generall issue not
guilty And upon any issue joyned may give this A&bholigct;and the speciall matter in evidence And if the Plaintiff or
Prosecutor shall become nonsuit or forbeare further prosecution or suffer [a<ref idref="n75">75</ref>] discontinuance or if a verdi&bholigct;
passe against him the defendant shall recover theire treble Costs for which they shall have the like remedy as in
any case where costs by the law are given to defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. No future monthly Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p306">Provided alsoe And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed That no future aid or supply of money to the King by Parliament in
charge of the people shall at any time hereafter be granted or levied by way of monethly assessment.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Fee to Officers of Exchequer in respe&bholigct; of Fee Farm Rents to the King or Queen Dowager.</head>
			<para id="p307">Provided that no Auditor of his Mat.ies Exchequer or other Officer shall upon allowance to bee made to any
person or persons assessed within this A&bholigct; for any fee farme rent due to his Majesty or the Queen-Dowager take
or receive any other fee for the same then the s&bhouov;m of four pence for any debt upon such Allowance</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Bedford <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Sayer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Colclough <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Caulton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">Wolverton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Es&bhoqesq;s <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">Glegg Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">Bonithon <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">Huishe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">Canfeild <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">Fitz William <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">Braynton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">M<emph type="p">r</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">Blackhurst <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">Sherard <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">Skeffington <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">The Roll is illegible here, but it is "Baulder" in the Original A&bholigct;.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">Blank in Original.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">Bowyer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">Francis Bacon Thomas Bacon <emph type="i">O</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">Kedington.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">Blank in Original.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39">Noell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41">Crumpe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n42" number="42">Knights <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n43" number="43">Bish <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n44" number="44">Tulse <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n45" number="45">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n46" number="46">Cordall <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n47" number="47">Sr <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n48" number="48">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n49" number="49">Roger <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n50" number="50">Parkhurst <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n51" number="51">Faunt <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n52" number="52">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n53" number="53">Gibbons <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n54" number="54">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n55" number="55">S<emph type="p">r</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n56" number="56">Ivy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n57" number="57">Thomas Mompesson of Battington <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n58" number="58">Ovyatt <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n59" number="59">Ovyatt <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n60" number="60">Watson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n61" number="61">Maleverer Baronetts <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n62" number="62">K<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n63" number="63">Dobson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n64" number="64">Wynne <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n65" number="65">Crogen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n66" number="66">Cathle <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n67" number="67">Morvile <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n68" number="68">Roger <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n69" number="69">Rickards <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n70" number="70">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n71" number="71">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n72" number="72">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n73" number="73">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n74" number="74">proportion<emph type="i">O</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n75" number="75">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


