<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47319" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVI. An Act for the more speedy and effe&bholigct;ual bringing those persons to accompt whose Accompts are excepted in the A&bholigct; of Oblivion. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 3. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Accountant not pardoned by 12 car.II.c. II.not perfecting their Accounts befor the End of Trinity Term 1662. </head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Charge against them taken as a Debt, under 33 H. VIII. c. 39. Other Accountants who have Notice of a Charge in the Exchequer against them, before Sept. 29, 1662, and shall not perfe&bholigct; their Accounts before the 1st Day of Easter Term then next, taken in like manner to be Debtors to the Crown</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">BE it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual
and Temporal and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That
all and every person and persons who are accomptable to the Kings Majestie and theire Accompts are not pardoned
but excepted by the late A&bholigct; of Free and General Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion and against whom there is any
charge now remaining in His Majesties Exchequer and shall through theire default not perfe&bholigct; his or theire Accompt
before the end of Trinity Terme in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and two That then the
Charge against all and every such person or persons shall be taken as a Debt by Writing Obligatory or Recognizance
taken or acknowledged to the Kings Majesty according to the Statute of 33 H. 8. Chap. 39 And that all and every
other person or persons whose Accounts are excepted in the said A&bholigct; of Oblivion and have or shall have a Charge
or Information against them in His Majesties Exchequer before the Foure and twentieth of June One thousand six
hundred sixty and two and have or shall have notice thereof by Processe out of the Court of Exchequer or otherwise
served upon his person or left att his house or last knowne place of Habitation before the Nine and twentieth of
September One thousand six hundred sixty and two and shall not before the First day of Easter Terme then
next ensuing perfe&bholigct; theire Accompts touching the said Charge that then the Charge against all and every such
person or persons shall be taken as a Debt by Writing Obligatory or Recognizance taken and acknowledged to the
Kings Majesty according to the Statute aforesaid and that in both the said Cases Proces shall be awarded as is used
for recovery of Debts due to His Majesty according to the Statute [as<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] aforesaid against him or them and against all and
every theire Sureties not pardoned or discharged by the said A&bholigct; of Oblivion and his and theire respe&bholigct;ive Lands
Tenements Goods and Chattells and Debts and the said Charge to continue in force onely untill the Accompts
shall be perfe&bholigct;ed and the Accomptants discharge them thereof in due manner in the said Court of Exchequer with
such allowances as are given by the said A&bholigct; of Oblivion and untill payment made unto His Majestie of all such
s&bhouov;ms of Money as shall be found due upon the determina&bhocotil;n of his or theire Accompts.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>


