<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47310" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act to restrain the Exportation of Leather and Raw Hides out of the Realme of England.[Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 1. nu, 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that by reason of Exportation of Leather the Price is unduly raised.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Persons not to export Skins, &amp;c. otherwise than as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas notwithstanding the many good Lawes before this time made and still in force prohibiting the
Exportation of Leather out of this Realm and the penaltie by those A&bholigct;s imposed by the cunning and
subtilty of some persons and the negle&bholigct; of others who ought to take care thereof there are such quantities of
Leather daily exported to forreign parts that the price of Leather is grown to those excessive rates that many
Artificers working Leather cannot furnish themselves with sufficient store thereof for the carrying on of theire Trades
and the poore sort of people are not able to buy those things made of Leather which of necessity they must
make use of: For redresse of which greifs be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the
Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled
That from and after the first day of May now next ensuing no person or persons whatsoever shall carry or
transport or cause to bee carried or transported out of England into Scotland Ireland or into any of the Isles
belonging to this Kingdome or to any parts beyond the Seas the Skins or Hides tanned or untanned of any Ox
Steer Bull Cow or Calfe otherwise or in any other manner then is by this present a&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ed</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Skins taken from Beasts in any Island except Ireland to be exported to England only. Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That none of the Skins or Hides aforesaid which shall
happen to be taken from any of the Beasts aforesaid within any Island whatsoever belonging to the Kingdome of
England (except Ireland) shall be transported out of that Island to any other place but into the Kingdome of
England upon pain of forfeiting for every such offence double the value of Skins or Hides so to be transported
out of the said Island or any of them to any other place then into the Kingdome of England the same forfeiture
to bee sued for and disposed as hereafter in this a&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Red Tanned Leather to be brought into Common Fairs and Markets only. Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">contra&bholigct;void.; Such Leather to be searched and sealed, and Sale registered.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And for the better preventing of such mischeifs as are intended to be remedied by this a&bholigct; bee it ena&bholigct;ed by
the Authority aforesaid That all Red tanned Leather made of the Hides or Skins of any of the Beasts aforesaid of
what kind or nature soever shall be bought onely in the open and common Fair or Market used for the putting
of Leather to sale and not in any House Tanners Yard Shop or other place whatsoever on pain that such person
or persons that shall not accordingly doe the same shall for every such offence forfeit the same Leather or the
value thereof and the contra&bholigct; for the sale thereof shall be void And all such Leather shall be searched and sealed
by the Searchers and Sealers thereunto appointed before the same be put to sale and upon such sale shall be
registred and a true Entry thereof made both by the Buyer and Seller who are both to be present at such
Registring thereof and both theire names and places of abode entred into the booke of the said Register on pain
that every such Buyer or Seller that shall not accordingly do the same shall for every such offence forfeit the same
Leather or the value thereof and the forfeiture shall be recovered and imployed in such manner as hereafter in this
a&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Unduly exporting Leather, &amp;c.; (Exception.)</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Disabled to trade, and Penalty &pound;500</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any person or persons shall be found guilty of
the Transportation of any Leather or Raw Hides of any of the Beasts aforesaid excepting such Calve-Skins and
Sheep-Skins dressed without the Wool as by Law may be transported) contrary to the provision of this a&bholigct; he
shall from thenceforth be disabled to trade or deal in Leather for the future and shall for every such offence forfeit
the s&bhouov;m of five hundred pounds to be sued for and disposed as hereafter in this a&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Exportation of Leather made into Boots, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided neverthelesse That this a&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to the prohibiting the
Transportation of any Leather made into Bootes Shoos or Slippers but that the same may be transported Any
thing in this a&bholigct; contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. The Companies of Cordwainers, Saddlers, &amp;c. and also Mayors, &amp;c. may search and seize Leather intended to be exported.</head>
			<para id="p9">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the respe&bholigct;ive
Masters and Wardens of the Cordweyners Sadlers Girdlers and Curriers of the City of London and theire Deputies
and all Customers Comptrollers Farmers of Customes Supervisors Searchers and other Officers belonging to the
Customes and to and for all Justices of the Peace Maiors and cheife Officers of Corporations within this Realm
Dominion of Wales or Town of Berwick upon Tweed from time to time as well by Land as Water to search for
and seise any Leather or Raw Hides wrought or unwrought cut or uncut packed up or unpacked intended or
purposed to be transported by any person or persons into any the parts beyond the Seas or into Scotland other
then Calve Skins and Sheep Skins as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. </head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Tanners unduly shaving Hides, Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And whereas diverse Tanners do shave cut and rake theire upper leather Hides all over and the necks of their
backs and butts to the great impairing thereof and the extream prejudice of the Kingdome Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by
the Authority aforesaid That every Tanner who after the Nine and twentieth day of September in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and two shall commit any such offence as aforesaid shall forfeit all the said
Leather Backs Buts or Calve skins so shaved cut or raked or the value thereof and it shall be lawfull for the Searchers
and Sealers of Leather to seise the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. When Leadenhall Market to be kept.</head>
			<para id="p12">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Market for Leather in Leaden hall [in London<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] shall be kept on the Tuesday
as now it is Any Law usage or custome to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Penalties how to be recovered.</head>
			<para id="p13">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all the penalties and forfeitures and every sum and s&bhouov;ms
of money for any offence or offences herein before mentioned shall be recovered by a&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint Information
to be brought for the same in any Court or Courts at Westminster or in any Court or Courts of Record in the City
Town County or place where the said offence shall be committed wherein no Wager of Law Prote&bholigct;ion or Essoign
shall be admitted neither shall the same be removed out of the said County City or Town Corporate the one halfe
of the said forfeitures to be to the [use of the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Kings Majesty his Heires and Successors and the other halfe thereof to the
use of the Informer or Informers that shall sue for the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Undue Exportation a common Nuisance.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided alsoe and be it ena&bholigct;ed That all such Exportation or Transportation of any Hides or Leather contrary to
this a&bholigct; is hereby adjudged and declared to be a common and publick Nusance</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Proviso for Hides, &amp;c. carried for the Use of Ships on Voyages.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided neverthelesse that this a&bholigct; shall not extend or be construed to prohibite the carrying or conveying [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
any such Hides or Leather which shall be used or imployed for the necessary use or provision of any Shipp or Vessell
in any Voyage beyond the Seas and which shall not be sold in any forreigne parts so as the number doe not exceed
Six Raw Hides and Three Tanned Hides</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Persons buying Red Tanned Leather to give Notice to any of Curriers Company carrying on Business in London, and within Three Miles thereof.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for certain Leather used for Soles.; 1 Jac. I. c. 22. Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">Provided alwaies neverthelesse and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every Artificer
dealing in cutting of Leather or other person or persons whatsoever which shall hereafter buy any Red tanned Leather
within the City of London or three miles thereof shall before the next Market day within the said place for sale of
Leather give notice thereof to one or more of the Company of Curryers then exercising and using the Art and Mistery
of a Curryer within the said City [of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] London and three miles thereof and within three weekes after such notice shall
deliver or cause to be delivered the said Leather so bought except such part thereof as shall be used for Soales without
being curried tallowed or dressed unto the said Currier or Curriers to whom such notice was given to the intent that the
same may [b<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] curried tallowed or otherwise dressed as is dire&bholigct;ed and appointed by one a&bholigct; made in the First yeare
of King James Chapter twenty second touching the duty of Tanners Curriers Shoemakers and others upon penalty of
the forfeiture of Six shillings eight pence for every Back But Hide or Calves skin so bought and not delivered as
aforesaid for the uses and to be recovered as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Recital of 1 Jac. 1. c. 22.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Master and Wardens of Curriers Company may in the Day- time enter Shops, &amp;c. in London, or within Three Miles thereof, belonging to Artificers in cutting Leather, and search and seize.; Such Persons opposing Search, &amp;c.; Penalty &pound;20.; or refusing to be present at Search, Penalty &pound;10</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And whereas it is ena&bholigct;ed amongst other things by the said a&bholigct; made in the First yeare of King James that no
person or persons shall by any meanes occupy or put in any made wares within the City of London or three miles
of the same City any Curryed Leather before the same shall be searched and allowed by the Wardens of the Curryers
of London for the time being or such persons as they shall thereto assign and be sealed with a Seale therefore to be
prepared upon pain that every Shoemaker and other Artificer Cutter of Leather offending against that Article should
forfeit for every Hide or Skin otherwise curryed or imployed as is aforesaid Six shillings eight pence and the value
of every such Hide or Skin Be it therefore further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Master and Wardens of
the Company of Curriers for the time being or such persons as they shall thereto assign shall from time to time and
att all seasonable times in the day time enter into any Ware House Shopp Celler or other place within the said City
of London or three miles of the same City belonging unto any (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) the said Cordwainers Sadlers Girdlers or other person
or persons being Artificers dealing in cutting Leather and in the presence of any two or more of them to search for
and seize all such Leather intended to bee prohibited to be used by the said Clause Branch or Article as aforesaid
as alsoe for all Wares made of such Leather and if any such person or persons Artificers or Dealers as aforesaid shall
oppose or refuse to permit the said Master and Wardens of the Company of Curriers or such persons as they shall
thereto assign to make any such search or seisure as aforesaid hee or they shall forfeit for every such offence the
s&bhouov;m of Twenty pounds for the uses and to be recovered as aforesaid And if any of the said Artificers and Dealers
in cutting of Leather do refuse to be present with the said Searchers whensoever the same shall be desired by the
said Master and Wardens of the Company of the Curriers or such persons thereto assigned by them as aforesaid
then for every such default the persons so refusing shall forfeit the s&bhouov;m of Ten pounds for the uses and to bee
recovered as aforesaid.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">bee <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


