<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47316" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>An Act prohibiting the Importacion of Forreign Bonelace Cutt worke Imbroidery Fringe Band-strings Buttons and Needle worke.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Rectial; that many of the inhabitans of this kingdom are employed in making of Bone Lace, &amp; and have there by maintaine themselve and Families, &amp;c</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that such Persons have heretofore procured great Quantities of Silk, &amp;c. to be imported, to the Benefit of the Revenue; but that of late great Quantities of foreign Bone Lace, &amp;c. have been imported and that great Mischiefs had resulted therefrom; contrary to I R. III. c. 10. 3 E. IV. cc. 3, 4. 19 H. VII. c. 21. 5 Eliz. c. 7. and a Proclamation, dated Nov. 20 last.; Reasons for passing this Act.; No Person to sell or offer to sale or export any foreign Bone Lace after June 24, 1662; or import the same after May 1, 1662.;
Selling or offering to sale,; Penalty &pound;50. and Forfeiture of the Goods. Importing, Penalty &pound;100. and Forfeiture of the Goods imported. Forfeitures, how to be disposed of</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas great numbers of the Inhabitants of this Kingdome are imployed in the making of Bonelace
Bandstrings Buttons Needle worke Fringe and Imbroideries who by theire industry and labour have attained
and gained so great skill and dexterity in the making thereof that they make as good of all sorts thereof as is
made in any forreign parts by reason whereof they have beene heretofore able to releive their poor Neighbors and
maintained theire Families and alsoe enabled to sett on worke many poore Children and other persons who have
very small meanes or maintenance of living other then by theire labours and endeavors in the said Art And
whereas the persons so imployed in the said Mystery have heretofore served most parts of this Kingdome with
Bonelace Bandstrings Buttons Needle-worke and Imbroidery And for the carrying on and managing of the said
Trade they have procured great quantities, of Thread and Silke to be brought into the Kingdome from forreign
parts whereby his Majesties Customes and Revenues have beene much advanced until of late that great quantities
of Forreigne Bonelace Bandstrings Needle worke Cut worke Fringe Silke Bonelace Buttons and Imbroidery were
brought into this Kingdome by Forreigners and Inhabitants of this Kingdome and sold to Shop keepers &amp; others
Dealers in the said C&bhooov;modity as well by Whole sale as Retail without ever entring of the same in any of His
Majesties Custom-houses or paying any Duty or Custome for the same by meanes whereof the said Trade and
Calling is of late very much decayed those imployed in the said Calling very much impoverished the manufa&bholigct;ure
much decreased and great quantities thereof already made left on theire hands that make it His Majesty defrauded
and deceived in His Customes and many thousand poore people formerly kept on worke in the said Art like to
perish for want of imployment there being dayly great s&bhouov;ms of money exported out of this Kingdome for the
buying and fetching in of the said C&bhooov;modity to the great impoverishment of the Nation by the consumption of the
Bullion and Treasure thereof and contrary to several Statutes made in the First of King Richard the Third in
the Third of King Edward the Fourth in the Nineteenth of King Henry the Seventh and the Fifth of Queene
Elizabeth and to a late Proclamation made by His Majesty that now is dated the Twentieth day of November last
for the putting the said Lawes in Execution For redresse whereof and prevention of the like mischeifs for the
future and the better releife comfort and subsistence of those imployed in the said Art and manufa&bholigct;ure And for
the quickning reviving explaining amending and more effectual execution of the said Statutes Be it ena&bholigct;ed by
the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and
Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by Authority of the same That no person or persons whatsoever
shall from and after the Twenty fourth day of June One thousand six hundred sixty two sell or cause to be
sold or offer to sale within the Kingdome of England or Dominion of Wales or export any Forreign Bonelace
Cut worke Imbroidery Fringe Bandstrings Buttons or Needle worke made of Thread Silke or any or either [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
any of them in parts beyond the Seas or import bring in send or convey or cause to be brought in sent or
conveyed into the Kingdome of England or Dominion of Wales any such Forreigne Bonelace Cut worke Fringe
Imbroidery Bandstrings Buttons or Needle worke made of Thread Silke or any or either of them beyond the
Seas after the First day of May which shall be in the [said<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty
and two upon pain that all and every person or persons who shall sell or cause to be sold or offer to sale any
such Forreigne Bonelace Cutt worke Imbroidery Fringe Bandstrings Buttons or Needle worke shall forfeit and lose
for every offense by him committed contrary to this A&bholigct; the s&bhouov;m of fifty pounds and the whole Bonelace Cutt
worke Imbroidery Fringe Bandstrings Buttons or Needle-worke so sold or [cause<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to be sold or offered to sale And
upon further pain that all and every person or persons who shall import bring in send or convey or cause to be
brought in sent or conveyed into this Kingdome of England or Dominion of Wales any such Bonelace Cut worke
Imbroidery Fringe Bandstrings Buttons or Needle worke shall forfeite and lose for every offence by him committed
contrary to this A&bholigct; the s&bhouov;m of One hundred pounds and the whole Bonelace Cut worke Imbroidery Fringe
Bandstrings Buttons or Needle worke so imported brought in sent or conveyed or caused to be imported brought
in sent or conveyed contrary to the forme and effe&bholigct; of this present A&bholigct; as abovesaid the Moyeties of all which
Forfeitures to be to the use of our Soveraigne Lord the Kings Majesty His Heires and Successors and the other
Moyety to him or them that shall sue for the same in any of the Kings Courts of Record by Bill Plaint A&bholigct;ion
of Debt Information or other wise wherein no Essoign Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed at every
time and as often as any person shall be found to offend in selling importing conveying or bringing in as
aforesaid</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Justices upon Information may issue Search Warrants.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That for the preventing of the importing of the said
manufa&bholigct;ures as aforesaid upon Complaint &amp; Information given to the Justices of the Peace or any or either of
them within theire respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cities and Towns Corporate at times reasonable he or they are hereby
authorized and required to issue forth his or theire Warrants to the Constables of theire respective Counties Cities
and Towns Corporate to enter and search for such manufa&bholigct;ures in the Shops being open or Warehouses and
Dwelling houses of such person or persons as shall be suspected to have any such Forreign Bonelaces Imbroidery
Cutt worke Fringe Bandstrings Buttons or Needle-work within theire respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cities and Towns-Corporate
and to seise the same. Any A&bholigct; Statute or Ordinance to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Limitation of Informations, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwaies and be it hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That all Informations A&bholigct;ions and Suites that shall be
commenced for any offence committed against this Law shall be brought and commenced within Twelve Moneths
after the discovery of such offence Any former A&bholigct; or Law to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">caused <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

