<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47324" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXI. An Act for preventing the unnecessary charge of Sheriffes and for ease in passing theire Accompts. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 3. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that by reason of Charges at Assises, &#x0026;c. the Office of Sheriff hath of late become very burthensome.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Regulation respecting Tables to be kept by Sheriffs during the Assises.; Sheriffs not to make Presents to the Judges for their Provison, nor to their Servants. Number of Sheriff's Servants.Penalty &pound;200</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS the Office of Sheriff as well by reason of the great and unnecessary charges in the time of
Assises and other publique meetings as by the tedious attendance and charge of Sheriffes in passing of
theire accompts in the Exchequer hath of late yeares been very burthensom to the Gentry of this Your Realm
who in the late times of Tyranny and Oppression have been great Sufferers and thereby much impoverished in
theire Estates and Fortunes For remedy wherein Your Majesties most Loyal Subje&bholigct;s the Knights Citizens and
Burgesses assembled in Parliament do most humbly beseech Your Most Excellent Majesty that it may be declared
and ena&bholigct;ed And be it declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the advice and
consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the
Authority of the same That no person or persons being duely sworne into the Office of Sheriff for any County
or Shire within this Your Majesties Realm shall from and after the First day of February next ensuing in the
time of the Assises held for the said County or Shire during his or theire Sherifalty keepe or maintaine or cause
to be kept or maintained one or more Table or Tables for Receipt or Entertainment of any person or persons
resorting to the said Assises other then those that shall bee of his owne Family or Retinue nor shall make
or send in any Present to any Judge or Judges of Assise for his or theire provision nor give any gratuity to his
or theire Officers or Servants or any of them. And alsoe that no Sheriffe shall after the [said<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] First day of February
have more then Forty Men servants with Liveries attending upon him in the time of the said Assises nor under
the number of Twenty Men servants in any County whatsoever within the Kingdom of England nor under the
number of Twelve Men servants in any County within the Dominion of Wales upon pain that every Sheriffe
offending in any of the &bhopcrl;misses contrary to the true meaning hereof shall forfeit for every default the s&bhouov;m of
two hundred pounds</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Sheriffs of London, Westmorland, and of Cities and Towns.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided that nothing before in this A&bholigct; contained shall in any wise extend unto or any wayes concern the
Sheriffs of the Citty of London and Middlesex and the Sheriff of Westmerland or either of them or any of the
Sheriffs of or belonging to any Citty and County or Town and County within this Realm but that the same
Sheriff or Sheriffs shall or may [doe<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] as heretofore hath been used or accustomed within the said County of
Middlesex and Cities of London and Westminster and such other Cities and Counties or Towns and Counties
aforesaid Any thing herein before contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Recital of Causes of Hardships on Sheriffs in passing their Accounts.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Seizures concerning Lands, &#x0026;c. remaining charged in Foreign Accounts for the Year ending at Michaelmas 1660 charged in the great Roll in the Exchequer. Remembrancers to make Copies of other Seizures, to be delivered to the Engrosser of the great Roll. Seizures already returned to be delivered before 1st Feb. next; other Seizures before the 1st Day of the next Term after received by Remembrancer. Fee to Remembrancer, Deputy, and Clerks. No Sheriff to be charged forilleviable Seizure, &#x0026;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And to the end that Sheriffs may for the time future be eased of the great charge and trouble which they
heretofore have been put to in passing theire Accounts in the Exchequer occasioned partly in regard that divers
s&bhouov;ms of money have stood charged upon them in grosse without expressing from what persons for what cause or
out of what lands or tenements the same are to be particularly levied or out of what particulars the said s&bhouov;ms
in grosse doe arise (whereby it cometh to passe that the said Sheriffs doe still stand charged in grosse with divers
s&bhooov;mes of money which were heretofore payable by Abbotts Priors persons attainted and such other persons whose
Estates have since come to the Crowne or are otherwise discharged or illeviable) and partly by the Accompt of
Seizures or Forreign Accompt and by the exa&bholigct;ion of undue Fees of Sheriffs upon theire apposal concerning the
same For the &bhopcrl;venting whereof and for the future ease of Sheriffs in passing theire Accompts Be it ena&bholigct;ed and
declared That from hence forth every Seizure for or concerning any Lands Tenements and Hereditaments now
remaining charged in the forreign accompt of any Sheriff or Sheriffs within the Kingdome of England for the
yeare ended att Michaelmas One thousand six hundred and sixty shall be from the said foreign accompt charged
particularly in the Great Roll of the Exchequer And that the several Remembrancers of the said Court or theire
respective Deputies doe in theire respe&bholigct;ive Offices forthwith and soe from time to time for the future write and
make true and perfe&bholigct; Copies of all and every such other Seizure and Inquisi&bhocotil;n as already are or hereafter shall be
certified into theire respe&bholigct;ive Offices without certifying the Copy of the Writ or Commission att large upon which
such Seizure or Inquisition is or shall be so taken or returned mentioning only in breife the Date of the said
Writt or Commission and shall deliver the same Copies well and truly examined and attested under his or theire
Hands to the Engrosser of the said Great Roll And that all such of the said Seizures and Inquisitions as now are
returned into any of theire respe&bholigct;ive Offices shall be delivered before the First day of February next coming And
that all such other Seizures as shall hereafter be returned or certified into theire respe&bholigct;ive Offices shall be delivered
so examined and attested as aforesaid to the said Engrosser before the first day of the next Terme after the said
Remembrancers shall have received the same so as the same may be charged in the Great Roll to the end that the
Processe of the Court may from thence issue for levying the Issues and Proffits thereof to the use of the Crowne unto
which said Remembrancers or theire Deputies shall be from time to time paid for every Sheet which they or theire
respe&bholigct;ive Clerks shall so write and deliver the s&bhouov;m of eight pence the same to be paid unto them by the aforesaid
respe&bholigct;ive Sheriffes who shall bee allowed the same by the Barons upon theire respe&bholigct;ive Accompts out of the Issues
and Proffits arising out of the &bhopubr;misses so seized and no Sheriff or Sheriffs for this present Yeare One thousand
six hundred sixty and one nor any Sheriff or Sheriffs to be hereafter made or appointed within this Kingdome of
England shall be charged in accompt to answeare any illeviable Seizure Farm Rent or Debt or other Seizure
Farme Rent Debt Matter or Thing whatsoever which was not writ in Processe to him or them to be levied wherein
the persons of whom or the Lands or Tenements out of which togeather with the cause for which the same shall
be soe levied shall be plainly and particularly expressed but shall be thereof wholly discharged without Peti&bhocotil;n Plea
or other trouble or charge whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Seizures made before Jac. I. and Seizures pardoned discharged.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">No Process to issue in respe&bholigct; thereof. All other dead Farms, &#x0026;c. to be removed out of the annual into the exannual Roll</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That all Seizures heretofore made before the First Yeare of the
Reigne of the late King James of every blessed memory now remaining in the Accompts of Sheriffs and all Seizures
and Debts which are pardoned shall be and are hereby fully discharged And that the same and every of them
shall hereafter be left out of Sheriffs Accompts without further Order Plea Peti&bhocotil;n or other Charge to any Sheriff
or Sheriffs whatsoever And that no Process shall from hence forth be written forth to any Sheriff for the levying
of the same or any of them nor for any other Rent or Farm which cannot be explained by setting forth the
particulars thereof or which hath been unanswered by the space of forty yeares last past And that all other dead
Farmes and Seizures and all desperate illeviable and [un<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] intelligible Debts shall be removed out of the Annual
Roll and Sheriffs charge into the Exanual Roll there to remaine untill by Commission they shall be revived and
made answerable</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Remembrancers to eurol and certify to the Engrosser of the Great Roll Debts charged on Sheriffs, Fines, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Such as are now returned to be delivered before 1st Feb. next; those to be hereafter returned the first Day of the next Term after Return made.; Penalty &pound;40.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">And to the end that all new Debts arising and coming into the Exchequer for the future may be sent forth
in Process within convenient time Be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the aforesaid several Remembrancers do
forthwith inroll and certifie to the said Ingrosser of the Great Roll all such Debts as any Sheriff or Sheriffs of this
Realm are or hereafter shall be charged withall either by vertue of theire respe&bholigct;ive Returns made &#x0149;o the Barons
of the said Exchequer upon His Ma[jes]ties Writs of Fieri facias Levari facias Capias or other Processe and alsoe of
all Fines and Amerciaments which are or shall be sett and imposed by the Court of Exchequer upon any Sheriff
or Sheriffs for his or their - contempts or negle&bholigct;s (that is to say) That all and every such Debts Fines and
Amerciaments as now are returned set or imposed in any of the said Offices shall be delivered as aforesaid before
the First day of February next ensuing And all such Debts Fines and Amerciaments as shall hereafter be returned
set or imposed in any of the respe&bholigct;ive Offices shall be alsoe delivered by the First day of the next Term after
such Retorns made of such Fines or Amerciaments so set or imposed that so they may be all charged in the
Sheriffs Accompts respe&bholigct;ively and comprehended within his or theire Quietus est upon pain that every Officer or
Officers in the said Exchequer who shall in any thing offend contrary to this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; shall forfeit the s&bhouov;m of
Forty pounds for every such offence whereof (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) one moyety shall be to the King His Heires and Successors and the
other moyety to the party or parties who shall be thereby agreived to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill
Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties Courts at Westminster wherein no Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion Priviledge or
Wager of Law shall be allowed or admitted</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Qualification of Sheriff.</head>
			<para id="p10">And it is hereby further provided and ordained That no person shall be assigned to be Sheriff of any County
within this Realm except such as have Lands within the same County sufficient to answer the King and
his People</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. 21 Jac. I. c. 5. &sect; 1.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Recital that Sheriffs have been troubled after their Quietus est. Limitation of Time for calling on Sheriff after Quietus est. Officers suffering Process to the contrary. Penalty as by 21 Jac. I. c. 5.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p12">And whereas by an A&bholigct; made in the One and twentieth yeare of the Reigne of our late Soveraigne Lord King
James over England it was provided that whensoever any Sheriff upon passing his Accompts should have his
Quietus est that he should be thereby absolutely discharged of all s&bhouov;ms of Money by him levied and received
and pretended not to be accompted for within the said Accompt whereupon he had his Quietus est unlesse such
Sheriff should be called in question for such s&bhouov;ms of Money so &bhopcrl;tended to be levied and not accompted for
within Four yeares after the time of such Accompt and Quietus est Which A&bholigct; notwithstanding divers Sheriffs and
theire Heires upon such &bhopcrl;tences have beene molested and troubled many yeares after theire Accompts and Quietus
est and have had Process sent out against them contrary to the true intent and meaning of the said A&bholigct; It is
hereby further provided and ena&bholigct;ed That when any Sheriff or Sheriffs within the Kingdom of England or Dominion
of Wales upon passing their Accompts shall have theire Quietus est that then such Sheriff and Sheriffs their
Heires Executors and Administrators Lands Tenements Goods and Chattells shall be thereby absolutely discharged
of all manner of sum or s&bhouov;ms of Money whatsoever by them levied and received notwithstanding any such pretence
that the same were not accompted for or other pretence whatsoever unless such Sheriff or Sheriffs shall be called
in question and that Judgment shall be given against him or them for the same within Four yeares next after
such Accompt or Quietus est and that every Officer or Minister by whom or by whose default any Writt or
Process contrary to this A&bholigct; shall be sent out shall incur the like Forfeitures and Penalties to be recovered and
infli&bholigct;ed by such persons and in such manner as by the aforesaid A&bholigct; is provided</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for Counties Palatine.</head>
			<para id="p13">Provided alwaies That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to the Counties of Chester
Lancaster Durham or the Counties in Wales being County Palatines as to theire manner of accompting but that
the Sheriffes therein shall accompt as formerly before the respe&bholigct;ive Auditors onely and not elsewhere</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Proviso as to what Inquisitions, Seizures, &#x0026;c. are to be transcribed and delivered by Remembrancers to the Engrossers of the Great Roll; and for Process on Debtors to the Crown;</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">and for the Pleadings heretofore used in the said Office. A&bholigct; not to stay, compound, &#x0026;c. Process for Debts charged by the Great Roll, except by Order, &#x0026;c. If Debt, &#x0026;c. not levied upon Process of Summons of the Pipe, Clerk of the Pipe, &#x0026;c. to certify into the Remembrancer's Office. Proviso for Remembrancer's Fees</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">Provided That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to enjoyn His Majesties Remembrancer
or the Lord Treasurers Remembrancer to transcribe and deliver to the Ingrosser of the Great Roll any Inquisitions
or Seisures but such as have beene formerly charged in the Foreign Accompts of the Sheriffs but for all Inquisitions
upon Attainders or other Forfeitures to the Crown the same shall be put in charge as heretofore they have been
according to the constant Usage and Decree of the Court of Exchequer nor shall this A&bholigct; or any thing therein
contained extend to exclude His Majesties said Remembrancer of or from the writing forth Processe for or upon
any His Majesties Debts Duties Outlawries or other charge whatsoever or Process of Levari facias att the prosecution
of any person or persons to levy the Issues or Proffits of any Lands or Tenements seised or to be seised into the
Kings hands or Process of Venditioni exponas for Goods seised or to be seised upon any Debt to His Majesty His
Heires or Successors or upon any Outlawry or to alter or change the Pleadings or other Proceedings heretofore
used and accustomed in the said Office upon any Pleadings touching the said Debts Duties and Seizures or any of
them whatsoever And that no Debt Duty Fine Amerciament or Seisure whatsoever which shall be charged in the
said Great Roll of the Pipe upon any person whatsoever by or from any Record Process or Proceeding had made
filed or recorded in the Office of His Majesties Remembrancer of His Exchequer nor any Process or Proceeding
thereupon to be had or made by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be respited stayed mitigated extenuated compounded or
otherwise discharged but by Order Warrant or Judgment made filed or entered in the said Office of His Majesties
Remembrancer where the original of such Debt Duty or Charge as aforesaid is and remaineth And that in case
any Processe of Summons of the Pipe have beene or shall be awarded for or upon any such Debt Duty Fine
Amerciament or Seisure whatsoever and the same Debt Duty Fine Amerciament or Seisure shall not upon such
Summons of the Pipe be levied or answered unto His Majesty that then the Clerke of the Pipe or Engrosser of
the Great Roll shall the next Terme after the return of such Summons certifie the same in a Schedule into the
Office of His Majesties Remembrancer aforesaid to the end that further Process may be from thence written forth
for the levying and answering thereof And that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend unto
nor be construed to be prejudicial to His Majesties Remembrancer in His Exchequer in any just ancient and lawfull
Fees by him claimed or belonging or incident to his Office and usually had and received by him or his Predecessors
Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p16">This A&bholigct; to continue to the end of the first Session of the next Parliament and no longer.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


