<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47325" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXII. An Act for preventing of Theft and Rapine upon the Northern Borders of England [Rot. Parl. 14. C. II. p. 3. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Moss Troopers have for many Years past frequented the Northern Borders, and escape from one Kingdom into the other to avoid Justice;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">that the Inhabitants of the Counties of Northumberland and Cumberland have been obliged to maintain Parties of Horse for their Defence; and that the Inhabitants remote from the Borders have been unwilling to contribute thereto. From Michaelmas 1662, for 5 Years, Justices in Sessions may make Order for charging the Inhabitants for the Safeguard of the said Counties</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS a great number of lewd disorderly and lawlesse persons being Theives and Robbers who are
comonly called Moss Troopers have successively for many and sundry yeares last past been bred resided
in and frequented the borders of the two respe&bholigct;ive Counties of Northumberland and Cumberland and the next
adjacent parts of Scotland and they taking the opportunity of the large Waste Grounds Heaths &amp; Mosses and the
many intricate and dangerous Ways and By paths in those parts do usually after the most notorious crimes committed
by them escape over from the one Kingdome [into<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the other respe&bholigct;ively and so avoid the hand of Justice in regard
the Offences done and perpetrated in the one Kingdome cannot be punished in the other. And whereas since the time
of the late unhappy distra&bholigct;ions such Offences and Offenders as aforesaid have exceedingly more increased and
abounded and the several Inhabitants of the said respe&bholigct;ive Counties have been for divers years last past necessitated
att theire owne free and voluntary charge to maintain several Parties of Horse for the necessary defence of theire
Persons Families and Goods and to the end the aforesaid evill and pernitious members might be apprehended and
brought to Judgement And whereas the most part of the Inhabitants of the said Counties being more remote from
the borders then other parts and consequently not soe much exposed to imminent [dangers<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] as others are therefore
unwilling to contribute theire proportionable parts of the aforesaid Charge and yet notwithstanding it cannot probably
or possibly be avoided but that those Inhabitants of the respe&bholigct;ive Counties who hold themselves most secure must
certainly sustain much damage and detriment in theire Goods and Estates in case the aforesaid Mosse Troopers be
not timely suppressed but suffered to growe numerous strong and potent which they must needs doe in case there
be no restraint upon them Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advise and consent
of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by Authority thereof
that from and after the Feast of S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Michael the Archangell which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred sixty and two for and during the terme of Five yeares next ensuing the date of this present A&bholigct; it shall
and may be lawfull for the respe&bholigct;ive Justices of Peace of the said respe&bholigct;ive Counties or the major part of them
at any General Sessions of the Peace to be holden for the said Counties respe&bholigct;ively on the behalfe of the said
Counties or either of them from time to time as they shall see occasion to make an Order in open Court of Sessions
for charging according to theire several &bhopubrc;portions all and every the several Inhabitants of the said respe&bholigct;ive Counties
for the safeguard and securing of the said several Counties and Inhabitants thereof from all injury violence spoil
and rapine of the Mosse troopers aforesaid</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The Amount above which the said Counties are not to be charged. Quarter Sessions may appoint Persons to have the Command of a certain Number of Men;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and may issue Warrants for levying Money for the Safeguard of the said Counties; may be levied by Distress. Justices may hear Complaints against Persons refusing to obey this A&bholigct;; and may bind over such Persons.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided That the said County of Northumberland be not by force of this A&bholigct; at any time charged above the
s&bhouov;m of Five hundred pounds in the yeare nor the said County of Cumberland charged above the s&bhouov;m of Two
hundred pounds in the yeare And for this end and purpose the said several Justices of Peace of the respe&bholigct;ive
Counties aforesaid are hereby impowered and authorized at any theire General Quarter Sessions aforesaid to appoint
and imploy from time to time if occasion require any person or persons to have the Condu&bholigct; and Command of a
certaine number of men not exceeding the number of Thirty men in the County of Northumberland and Twelve
in the County of Cumberland whereby the Malefa&bholigct;ors aforesaid may be searched out discovered pursued apprehended
and brought to tryal of the Law And all and every the said Justices of Peace of the respe&bholigct;ive Counties aforesaid
or the major part of them at any General Sessions of the Peace to be holden for the said Counties [of<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] either of them
respe&bholigct;ively are hereby further impowered and authorized by force of this present A&bholigct; to make and issue forth
theire respe&bholigct;ive Warrants under theire hands for the levying and colle&bholigct;ing any s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money ordered
to be paid for and towards the Safeguard and securing of the said Counties respe&bholigct;ively as aforesaid and to give
full power to the several Constables and other Officers to raise levy and colle&bholigct; the said money and all and every
the Inhabitants of the said several Counties according to theire respe&bholigct;ive proportionable Estates in Lands or
Goods by Distresse and Sale of Goods rendring the overplus if there be any to the respe&bholigct;ive owner or owners And
the said Justices of [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Peace in the said several Counties or any one of them respe&bholigct;ively are hereby alsoe
authorized to examine any Complaint made against the Colle&bholigct;ors and Constables or any other Officers or Ministers
of Justice whatsoever or any of them or any other refra&bholigct;ory person or persons whatsoever that at any time hereafter
shall refuse negle&bholigct; or fail to give obedience to this A&bholigct; or shall doe any a&bholigct; or a&bholigct;s in disturbance or obstru&bholigct;ion
thereof and to bind over such person or persons to the next Quarter Sessions according to the knowne Laws of
the Land to the end such person or persons may be proceeded withall according to Justice</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Justices may appoint Treasurers, to receive such Monies; and may agree with Persons to be employed in the said Service.</head>
			<para id="p5">And the said respe&bholigct;ive Justices of Peace as aforesaid are hereby further impowered and authorized on behalfe
of the said several Counties respe&bholigct;ively to appoint a Treasurer to receive from the said Colle&bholigct;ors the moneys by
them colle&bholigct;ed and to pay over the same according to the Orders they shall receive from the said Justices at the
General Sessions of the Peace to be holden for the said respe&bholigct;ive Counties And the said Justices are alsoe impowered
to agree and article with such person or persons yearely as they shall thinke fitt to imploy in the said Service and
to take sufficient Security of them for the faithfull and most effe&bholigct;ual performance thereof for the best safeguard
advantage and benefit of the people according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Persons employed in the Border. Service corruptly forbearing to discover or apprehend Offenders; Disability. Imprisonment.</head>
			<para id="p6">And in case any person or persons shall in pursuance of this A&bholigct; be imployed in the Border Service and shall
att any time hereafter wilfully and corruptly or for any sinister respe&bholigct; whatsoever negle&bholigct; or forbeare to discover
or apprehend or to bring to tryall any of the said persons called Moss Troopers as aforesaid and shall be convi&bholigct;ed
thereof according to Law he or they shall from thenceforth be disabled and made uncapable for ever after to manage
or take upon him or them the said Imployment and to suffer such Fine and Imprisonment according to the qualityof his or theire offence as the Justices of Peace att theire General Sessions shall thinke fitt to infliof his or theire offence as the Justices of Peace att theire General Sessions shall thinke fitt to infli&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Justices may moderate Charge.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided neverthelesse and be it hereby declared That it shall be lawfull for the Justices of Peace of eith&#x0103;r of
the said Counties as aforesaid respe&bholigct;ively at any time hereafter to moderate or lessen the said Charge if they
see cause</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided that this A&bholigct; shall continue and be in force for Five yeares and no longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. 4 Jac. I. c. 1. 7 Jac. I. c. 1. revived.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alwaies and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by Authority aforesaid That for better suppression and punishment
of the said Moss Troopers flying out of England into Scotland or out of Scotland into England the Statutes made
in the several Sessions of Parlia&bhomsst; in the Fourth and Seventh yeares of King James shall be revived and put in
execution according to theire true intent.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">danger <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


