<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47326" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chatper XXIII. An Addi&bhocotil;nal A&bholigct; concerning matters of Assurance used amongst Merchants. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 3. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 43 Eliz. c. 12. &sect; 1</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">&sect;2. &sect;3. Recital that there cannot be a Court without Five Commissioners, and that no Proceedings can be without a Court. Recital of 43 Eliz. c. 12. &sect; 4. whereby Delay arises; and that Commissioners have no Power to make Order against Ship or Goods. Lord Chancellor, &amp;c. may, when requisite, issue out a Standing Commission. Commissioners' Power; may summon Parties and Witnesses;
and punish such as refuse Obedience. Commissioners to take Oath before Lord Mayor of London.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS by an A&bholigct; of Parliament made in the Three and fortieth yeare of the Reigne of Queen Elizabeth
of happy memory entituled An A&bholigct; concerning matters of Assurances used amongst Merchants The
Parliament then taking into Consideration by all good meanes to comfort and encourage the Merchants of this
Kingdome thereby to advance and increase the Wealth of this Realme her Majesties Customes and the strength of
Shipping and for preventing of diverse mischeifs in the said A&bholigct; mentioned It was ena&bholigct; ed That it should and might
be lawfull for the Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the time being to award forth
under the Great Seale of England one generall or standing Commission to be renewed yearely at the least and
otherwise so often as unto the Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper should seem meet for the hearing and [determing<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
of Causes arising on Policies of Assurance such as then were or then after should be entred within the Office of
Assurance of the City of London which Commissions should be [ere&bholigct; ed<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to the Judge of the Admiralty for the
time being the Recorder of London for the time being Two Do&bholigct; ors of the Civil Law Two Common Lawyers and
eight grave or discreet Merchants or any five of them which Commissioners or the greater part of them which
should sit and meet should have full Power and Authority to heare examine order and decree all and every such
Cause and Causes in a breife and s&bhouov;mary course without formalities of pleadings or proceedings with power to warn
parties to come before them and to examine upon Oath any Witnesses that should be produced and to commit to
Prison any person that should wilfully disobey theire final Orders and Decrees And the Commission[er]s to sit once
weekely upon the Execution of the said Commission with a liberty in the said A&bholigct; for any person greived by any
such Sentence or Decree to exhibite his Bill in Chancery for the reexamination of such Sentence or Decree As by
the said A&bholigct; relation being thereunto had more at large may appeare But forasmuch as by the said recited A&bholigct;
without five C&bhooov;missioners there cannot be a Court and without there be a Court they cannot proceed in the
Execution of theire Commission so much as to summon Parties or Witnesses to appeare And in case of negle&bholigct; or
refusal of any Party or Witnesse to appeare they have no power to punish the delay or contempt with Costs or
otherwise And it is provided by the said A&bholigct; that not any Commissioner other then the Judge of the Admiralty
or the Recorder of London shall proceed in the Execution of such Commission before hee hath taken his Oath
before the Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen to proceed uprightly and indifferently betweene party and party
which upon the renewing of the said Commissions often proves a great delay there being so many Commissioners
to be sworn and the Court of Aldermen not sitting at some times in the yeare when the said Commissions have
hapened to be renewed And although the said Commissioners upon theire final Sentence have power to commit to
Prison any person that shall wilfully disobey theire said Sentences or Decrees yet they have no power to make any
Order against the Ship or Goods which comonly are the things assured by which Omissions or want of Power
given by the said A&bholigct; the benefits intended by the said A&bholigct; of Parliament are much retarded and the mischeifs by
the A&bholigct; endeavored to be prevented much increased For remedy whereof Be it ena&bholigct;ed and ordained [&amp; it is hereby
ena&bholigct;ed and ordained<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] by the Kings most Excellent Majesty and by and with the advice and consent of the Lords
Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled That from and after the foure and
twentieth day of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and two it shall
and may be lawfull to and for the Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the time
being to issue out yearely (or oftner if need require) one standing Commission under the Great Seale of England
thereby impowering and authorizing the said Commissioners or any three of them (whereof a Do&bholigct;or of the Civil
Law or a Barrister at Law of Five yeares standing at the least to be alwaies one) to meet and sit and make a Court
and proceed in all things in the Execution of the said Commission as before by the said A&bholigct; any Five might have
done And that the said Commissioners or any such three of them as aforesaid be and hereby are impowered to
summon Parties and Witnesses to appeare and in Case of Contempt or wilfull delay in the Witnesses upon the
first Summons and tender of reasonable Charges and in the Parties upon theire second Summons to punish the
Offenders by Imprisonment or Costs for such time and in such manner as shall be reasonable and according to the
nature and quality of theire Offences And that it shall and may be lawfull to and for every such Commissioner
to proceed in the Execution of the said Commission having first taken an Oath before the Lord Maior of the City
of London for the time being only to proceed uprightly and indifferently betweene party and party And the said
Lord Maior is hereby authorized to give such Oath Any thing in the said A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding
And that no person shall proceed in Execution of the said Commission before he be first sworne before the Lord
Mayor of London for the time being to proceed uprightly and indifferently betweene party and party as formerly
he should have been before the Lord Mayor and Court of Aldermen</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissions may be issued out of Admiralty Court for Examination of Witnesses abroad.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may pass final Sentence against Body and Goods, Executors and Administrators, and assess Costs.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">Bee it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That in case the said Commissioners or any such three of them
as aforesaid shall find cause to examine Witnesses beyond the Seas or any remote parts of his Majesties Dominions
for the clearing [of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] any doubt or matter before them depending that in such case by dire&bholigct;ion of the said
Commissioners or any such three of them like Commissions or Processe shall issue out of the Court of Admiralty
as have formerly been for the purposes aforesaid returnable before the said Commissioners And that the said
Commissioners or any such three of them shall have alsoe power to give and passe theire final Sentence Decree
and Executions as well against the body of the party evi&bholigct;ed or his goods as alsoe against the Executors and
Administrators of such party so evi&bholigct;ed And to assesse Costs of Suit upon such person or persons as shall be
condemned by the Decree of the said Court as to them shall seem just</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Power to Commissioners to swear Witnesses going abroad.</head>
			<para id="p5">And forasmuch as many Witnesses (as Seamen and others) come [and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] speedily go again to Sea before a Court
can be summoned by which meanes the assured and assurers are many times much damnified For the preventing
of which mischeif Be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that it shall and may be lawfull to and for
any one of the said Commissioners to administer an Oath to any Witnesse legally summoned to give testimony
(timely notice [being<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] thereof given to the adverse party and sett up in the Office before such examination) to the
end such Witnesse or Witnesses may be crosse examined</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proceedings not to be against Body and Goods for the same Debt.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Appeal to Chancery.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwaies That the said Commissioners shall in no case proceed both against person and goods for one
and the same debt And provided also that any thing in this A&bholigct; contained shall not in any wise extend to
prejudice the appeal to the High Court of Chancery given or allowed in the said former A&bholigct; of Parliament.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">determining <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">directed <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


