<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47328" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXV. An Act for [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] restoring [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] all such Advowsons Re&bholigct;ories Impropriate Gleeb Lands &amp; Tithes to His Majesties
Loyal Subje&bholigct;s as were taken from them and making void certain charges imposed on them upon theire Compositions
for Delinquency by the late usurped Powers. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 3. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that many loyal Subje&bholigct;s had been constrained by the Long Parliament to pay large Sums of Money, and to settle Advowsons, Rents, &amp;c. without a valuable Consideration, as Compositions for pretended Delinquency.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Such Grants, &amp;c. void in Law. Proviso for Rights accrued (Exception) before May 19, 1662.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS many Loyal Subje&bholigct;s of our late Soveraigne Lord King Charles the First and of the Kings
Majesty that now is were upon pretence of Delinquency for adhering unto and faithfully serving theire
said Majesties according to theire Duty and Allegiance enforced and constrained by the pretended power of
the Long Parliament not onely to part with great s&bhouov;ms of money in satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said supposed Delinquency
but likewise to setle all or part of such Advowsons Re&bholigct;ories Gleeb Lands and Tithes Estates and Termes as they
or any in trust for them were then seised or possessed of and to make grants &amp; assurances of Rents and Annuities
to and upon such Trustees as were appointed by the said Long Parliament as well for the augmentation of certain
Vicarages as for the use and maintenance of Preaching Ministers and Le&bholigct;urers without any valuable considera&bhocotil;n
given for the same other then some abatement of those excessive Fines imposed upon them for theire pretended
Delinquency and exa&bholigct;ed from them by those arbitrary powers to the impoverishing and undoing of many of the
Kings most Loyal Subje&bholigct;s Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the advice
and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by
Authority of the same That all Grants Feoffments Bargaines and Sales Releases Confirmations and other Conveyances
and Assurances in the Law of any higher or lower nature whatsoever had or made by any such pretended
Delinquents theire Heires Executors or Administrators or by any person having any Estate or Interest in Law
or Equity in Trust for them or by any other person or persons having any Estate or Interest joyntly or in Common
with them or in Reversion or Remainder after them to any person or persons Bodies Politick or Corporate of
any such Advowsons Re&bholigct;ories Impropriate Gleeb Lands Tithes Estates Termes Annuities and Rents as aforesaid
to or for the uses aforesaid as part or in full of theire Compositions for such &bhopcrl;tended Delinquency as aforesaid
and all Securities touching or concerning the same only be and are hereby adjudged from henceforth null and
void in Law to all intents and purposes whatsoever Saving to all persons other then the said Trustees and theire
Heires and all claiming under them all right to the said Re&bholigct;ories and &bhopcrl;misses as hath accrued unto them before
the Nineteenth day of May One thousand six hundred sixty and two</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Tenants, of such Advowsons, &amp;c. to pay their Rents to Persons entitled before such Grants, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all Tennants Lessees and Occupiers of all such
Advousons Re&bholigct;ories Impropriate Gleeb Lands Tithes and Premisses so granted or setled to or upon such Trustees
as aforesaid for the uses or purposes aforesaid shall pay all such Rents as shall hereafter growe due and
payable to such persons onely unto whom the right and interest of and in the same Advowsons Re&bholigct;ories Gleeb
Lands Tithes and &bhopcrl;misses before the said Conveyances or Assurances (intended to be annulled and made voide by
this present A&bholigct;) did or should of right belong or appertain</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Recital that Redemises of some of the Premises comprised in such Grants, &amp;c. were executed at certain Rents for Augmentation of Vicarages and Maintenance of Ministers.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Purchasers to pay and former Owners to hold the said Rents, with Remedies by Distress, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And whereas the said Conveyances and Assurances in and by this A&bholigct; intended to be made void were some
of them of Estates in Fee Simple and some of them long Termes for yeares made to Trustees who redemised
the same at and under such yearely Rents and S&bhouov;ms of Money as were then appointed to be the Augmentation
of certain Vicarages or maintenance for Preaching Ministers since which time many of the Re&bholigct;ories and Lands so
conveyed and leased have been absolutely sold and the Redemises thereof granted and assigned by the Owners
thereof for the benefit of such purchasers Be it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by this present Parliament and by
the Authority of the same that the said Purchasers theire Heires and Assigns shall pay and the said former
Owners of the said Lands and Re&bholigct;ories theire Executors Administrators and Assignes shall have hold and enjoye
the said Rents and S&bhouov;ms of Money so reserved for the Augmentation of the said Vicarages &amp; maintenance for
Preaching Ministers upon the said several Redemises and shall have the same and the like remedies by Distresse
or by a&bholigct;ion of Debt for the recovery thereof as the said Trustees who redemised the same should or might
have had if this A&bholigct; had not been made</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


