<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47337" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) An Act for repairing the Highwayes within the Countyes of Hertford Cambridge and Huntington; [O. nu. 28.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Recital of the bad State of the Roads in the Counties of Hertford, Cambridge, and Huntington; </head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">and the ordinary Course appointed by the Laws is not sufficient for the effe&bholigct;ual repairing of the same.; Four Justices for each of the said Counties may appoint Nine Surveyors.; Justices or Surveyors to a&bholigct; in their several Counties only.; Notice to Surveyors of being chosen, and Surveyors to meet within one Week after such Notice,; for the Purpose of viewing and considering of Repairs.; Surveyors to appoint Colle&bholigct;or and other Officers.; Allowance to such Officers to be approved and removed by Two or more Justices</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas the auntient Highway and Poast Roade leading from London to Yorke, and soe into Scotland, and
likewise from London into Lincolnshire lyeth for many miles in the Countyes of Hertford, Cambridge and
Huntington, in many of which places, the Roade, by reason of the great and many Loades, which are weekly drawne
in Waggons through the said places, aswell by reason of the great Trade of Barley and Mault, that cometh to Ware,
and so is conveyed by water to the City of London, as other Carriages, both from the North parts, as also from the
City of Norwich, Saint Edmunds Bury, and the Towne of Cambridge to London, is very ruinous, and become almost
impassible, insomuch, that it is become very dangerous to all His Majesties Leige people that passe that way, And for
that the ordinary course appointed by the Lawes and Statutes of this Realme is not sufficient for the effe&bholigct;ual repairing
and amending of the same, neither are the Inhabitants through which the said Road doth lye of ability to repaire
the same, without some other provision of moneys to be raised, towards the putting the same into good and sufficient
Repayre, For remedy whereof and to the intent the said Highwayes, at or in the Countyes aforesaid, may bee
forthwith effe&bholigct;ually repaired and amended, and from time to time hereafter kept in good repayres, May it please
your Majesty that it may bee ena&bholigct;ed, And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty, by and with the
Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall, and the Co&bhooov;mons in this present Parliament assembled, and
by the Authority of the same, That for the surveying, ordering, repairing, and keeping in Repaire of the said
Highway in the Countyes aforesaid, Foure Justices of the Peace for each of the said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes,
dwelling next to the said Highwayes respe&bholigct;ively, or any two of them, for the yeare, One thousand six hundred sixty
three, and untill the Quarter Sessions then next ensueing, and from thenceforth the Justices of the Peace at the
Sessions, to bee holden next after [Easter<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] every yeare, for the said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, from time to time, shall,
and are hereby impowered, to nominate and appoint Nine sufficient and able persons, residing and inhabiting, within
the said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, to bee Surveyors of the severall places, in the said Highway for the yeare,
from thence next ensueing, The Justices of the Peace for the County of Hertford, to appoint Surveyors for the
Highway lying in the said severall Townes and Parishes of the said County, and the Justices of the Peace in the
County of Cambridge to appoint Surveyors for the severall Townes and Parishes, within their said County of
Cambridge, And the Justices of Peace for the County of Huntington, to appoint Surveyors for the severall Townes and
Parishes of the said County, And that the said Justices or Surveyors aforesaid, shall not a&bholigct; or doe any thing,
towards the Repaires of the said Highwayes, but in their owne severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, And that the said
Justices in their severall Countyes, shall cause notice to bee given to the severall Surveyors soe chosen in writeing
of their said choice, which said Surveyors and every of them having no lawfull impediment, to bee allowed by the
said Justices, by whom they shalbee chosen, in manner as aforesaid, within one weeke next after such notice to
them given of their Ele&bholigct;ion, shall and are hereby required to meet and assemble themselves together, (that is to
say) the Surveyors for the County of Hertford, in some convenient place within the County of Hertford, and the
Surveyors chosen for the County of Cambridge in some convenient place within their County, and the surveyors
chosen for the County of Huntington, in some convenient place within their said County, to bee appointed by the
severall Justices of the said Countyes, at their severall Quarter Sessions, to the intent to veiw and Survey the said
Highway and places aforesaid, and shall consider what Reparations shalbee needfull, for repairing of the severall
Highwayes and places aforesaid And the said severall Surveyors, in their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, shall provide Stones,
Gravell, and other materialls and necessaryes, to bee used for and towards the repairing and amending the said
Highway, at the places aforesaid, And the said Surveyors, or three or more of them, in their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes,
being so mett and assembled, are hereby authorized to appoint a Receiver or Colle&bholigct;or of Toll, and such other
Officer and Officers as they shall finde necessary in their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes for carrying on the said Worke (with
such moderate allowance, as shalbee thought fitt) to bee approved of by any two or more Justices of the Peace for
the said respe&bholigct;ive County, for which such Officer is chosen, living neere to the said Highway or places aforesaid,
or otherwise to bee removed, and other fitt person or persons, to bee chosen in his or their places, by the said
Justices, in the said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Surveyors to require Persons chargeable to come with Wains, Carts, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Surveyors to pay Labourers and Owners of Wains, Carts, &amp;c.; Such Persons negle&bholigct;ing, &amp;c.; Penalty on Owners.; Penalty on Labourers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the better effe&bholigct;ing thereof Bee it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said Surveyors, or any
three or more of them, in their severall Countyes, shall from time to time, as they shall see cause, appoint and
require, all and every person and persons, inhabiting within three miles of the places aforesaid, being within their
severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, who by any Law or Statute of this Realme now in force, is, or are chargeable,
to finde any Wayne, or Cart, for the amending of the Highwayes and every other person and persons chargeable,
to labour in the Highwayes, upon reasonable notice, to send his or their Cart or Wayne and Teame, or to come to
labour in the said Highway at any the places aforesaid, within their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, so furnished, as by the
Lawes and Statutes of this Realme is dire&bholigct;ed, for the amending of other Highwayes when and soe often, as the
said Surveyors for their said severall Countyes, or any three or more of them, shall thinke needfull and appoint,
for which the said Surveyors, shall pay unto such Labourers, and to the Owners of such Teames Carts and Waynes,
according to the usuall rate of the Countrey And in case any person soe charged, to send his or their Teame to
worke as aforesaid; shall refuse or negle&bholigct; soe to doe, such person so refusing or negle&bholigct;ing, shall forfeit Ten
shillings for every day, that hee or they shall make such default, and every Labourer Eighteen pence, for every
day, hee shall negle&bholigct; or refuse to worke as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Distance at which Persons may be compelled to come with their Wains, Carts, &amp;c. or to labour.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Justices of Peace to determine Questions concerning Hire, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">Provided That no person or persons, by virtue of this A&bholigct;, bee compelled or compellable to labour, or to send
his or their Teame Cart or Waggon, for the mending of the said Highway, to any of the said places, being above
Three miles distant from his Dwelling house, or not in the same County, nor to labour, or send his or their Teame,
Cart or Waggon, for amending of the said Highway, above Three dayes in any one weeke, nor at any time [in<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
Seed time Hay or Corne harvest And in case that any question shall happen to arise, touching the hire to bee given
by the said Surveyors, for such Teame Cart, or Waggon, or concerning the wages of such Labourers, imployed
in mending the said Highwayes, That then the said Justices of the Peace, in the County, where such difference
ariseth, or any two or more of them, shall and may determine and set downe, what hire for such Teame Cart
or Waggon, and also what wages to such Labourer, shall bee paid or allowed by the said Surveyors, and such
Order in that behalfe to bee made shall conclude all parties</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Where not sufficient Gravel, &amp;c. in any Parish, Surveyors may carry away Gravel, &amp;c. out of neighbouring Parishes, &amp;c. without paying for the same.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Where not sufficient Materials in Commons, &amp;c. then to dig for the same in Private Grounds (Exception) without paying, but to make Satisfa&bholigct;ion to Owners.; Quarter Sessions to determine the same.; Pits, &amp;c. to be filled up or secured.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid, That where there is not sufficient Gravell, Chaulke,
Sand, or Stones, within any Parish, Towne Village or Hamlett, wherein the said Highway or places aforesaid, or
any of them doe lye to repaire the said Highway, at any of the places aforesaid, It shall and may bee lawfull,
for the said Surveyors, in their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, or any three or more of them, and such person
and persons, as they shall appoint, to digg, take, and carry away, Gravell, Chaulke Sand or Stones, out of the
Wast or Co&bhooov;mon of any neighbouring Parish, Towne, Village, or Hamlett (without paying any thing for the same)
for the repairing or amending of the said Highway, at any the places aforesaid, or where there is not sufficient of
such materialls, in any Co&bhooov;mon or Wast Ground thereunto neere adjoyning, to digg in the severall grounds of any
person or persons, not being an House Garden Orchard, Yard, or Parke stored with Deere, being within any
Parish chargeable towards the repaires of the said Highway and places, soe to bee repaired where any such
materialls are or may bee found, And from time to time to carry away such, and soe much thereof, as the said
Surveyors, or any three or more of them, in their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, shall adjudge necessary for the said
Reparations, without paying any thing for such materialls, saving only such reasonable satisfa&bholigct;ion, to the Owner or
Occupyer of the Ground, where the same shall bee soe digged and carryed away, as for the damage hee or they
shall thereby susteyne to bee assessed and adjudged, by the said Justices of the County, where the same is digged,
at the next or any other Quarter Sessions for the said County, in case of difference concerning the same, And that
the Pitts and places, where and from whence such materialls, shall bee dugg and carryed away for the Reparations
aforesaid, shall with all convenient speed, (to bee adjudged by the [said <ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Justices of Peace as aforesaid) bee
filled up and levelled with earth or other materialls, or else rayled about, soe as that the same may not bee
deemed dangerous or prejudiciall to man or beast,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Surveyors, with the Approbation of Justices, to appoint Toll Gatherers.</head>
			<para id="p9">And for the defraying of the charge of such Reparations, to bee done in the places aforesaid Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed,
That from and after the choice of the Surveyors aforesaid, it shall and may bee lawfull to and for the said
Surveyors for the time being, with such consent and approbation as is aforesaid of the said Justices of the severall
Countyes, within their owne Countyes, and not elsewhere, to choose and appoint one or more fitt person or persons,
to receive or take such su&bhouov;me or su&bhouov;mes of money in the name of Toll or Custome, to bee paid for all such
Horses, Carts, Coaches, Waggons, Droves, and Gangs of Cattell, as in time to come shall passe, bee ledd, or
droven, in or through the said waye or places aforesaid, as are hereafter by this Act limited and appointed (that
is to say),</para>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Rates appointed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">For every Horse one penny, for every Coach six pence, for every Waggon one shilling, for every Cart eight
pence, for every score of Sheepe or Lambes one [halfe<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] penny, and so proportionably for greater numbers,</para>
			<para id="p12">For every score of Oxen or Neat Cattell five pence, and so for every greater or lesser number proportionably,</para>
			<para id="p13">For every score of Hoggs two pence, and so for every greater or lesser number proportionably, not being
under five,</para>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">In colle&bholigct;ing of Toll Places appointed.; Persons refusing to pay Toll,; Horse, &amp;c. may be-detained; and Expence thereof made good; Receivers of Toll to account.; Monies to be laid out in Repairs of Roads, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p15">And that from and after the passing this A&bholigct; all and every person or persons, who shall travell with Horse,
Coach, Cart, or Waggon, or shall leade or drive any Oxen, Sheepe, Horses, or other Cattell afore, mentioned, in
and through the Highway and places aforesaid, shall and are hereby required to pay unto the respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;ors
and Receivers of Toll, in the severall Countyes aforesaid, in that behalfe to bee appointed, after the rates aforesaid,
The places for colle&bholigct;ing of the said Toll to bee, for the County of Hertford at Wades-Mill, and for the County
of Cambridge at Caxton, within the said County of Cambridge, and for the County of Huntington, at Stilton in
the said County of Huntington, and at no other place or places within the said Countyes And in case any person
or persons, upon demaund made of Toll aforesaid, by the Colle&bholigct;ctor or Receiver in that behalfe, to be appointed
shall negle&bholigct;ct or refuse to pay the same, that then it shall and may bee lawfull, to and for the said Colle&bholigct;or or
Receiver appointed for [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Receipt of the said Toll, upon such refusall to distreyne and deteyne such Horse,
Cart, Coach Waggon Oxen or other Cattell aforementioned, or any of them, untill the said Toll shalbee satisfied
and paid, according to the teno<emph type="p">r</emph> of this present A&bholigct;ct, together with such d&bhoaovm;mages, as the party soe distreyning,
shall susteyne, by keeping of such Distresse, of all which money soe to bee received the said Colle&bholigct;or or Receivor
of Toll soe to bee appointed in the severall Countyes, shall from time to time render true Accounts, and shall
pay the money soe by them received, unto the said Surveyors of their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, or to
any three or more of them, or unto such Treasurers as they shall appoint, when and as often, as they shalbee
thereunto required, by the said Surveyors or any three or more of them, by them to bee laid out and expended,
for and towards the necessary Repaires and amending of the severall places beforementioned and not elsewhere,
within their said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Surveyors to account to Quarter Sessions.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Colle&bholigct;ors to pay Monies remaining in Hand to Surveyors, &amp;c.; Justices to make Allowance to Surveyors.; Colle&bholigct;or not duly paying to Surveyor, &amp;c.; or Surveyors not accounting or paying; Quarter Sessions may proceed; and may imprison until Account rendered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid, That the Surveyors and every of them, in their severall
and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, at the Quarter Sessions of the Peace, for the said County, to bee holden next after
Easter [in<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] every yeare, shall make and yeild up, unto the Justices of the Peace, there to bee assembled a
perfe&bholigct; Accompt in writeing, under their hands, of all the money which they or any of them, shall have received
from the said Colle&bholigct;or, or Receivor of Toll, in their said County, and likewise of all their disbursements, in and
about the said Highway or otherwise, by reason of their Offices, And in case of any overplus of money soe
received, remaining in their hands, shall pay the same to the Surveyors to bee chosen for the yeare ensueing, or
to the Treasurer or Receivor, by them to bee appointed, to bee disbursed and laid out in the severall places
aforesaid, within such County, wherein the overplus doth remaine, and not elsewhere in the yeare ensueing, which
said Justices to whom such Account shall bee given, shall out of the benefitt of the [said<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Toll, make such
allowance unto the said Surveyors, for and in consideration of their care and paines, taken in the execution of
their said Offices, as to them shall seeme good, And in case the Colle&bholigct;or or Receivor of the aforesaid Toll, for
the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, soe to bee paid as aforesaid, shall not upon request duely pay the same unto the said
Surveyors of the said County for the time being or the Treasurer or Receivor by them appointed, or in case the
said Surveyors, or any of them, shall not make such Account and payment as aforesaid, that then the said Justices,
for the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, at any Quarter Sessions of the Peace, to bee holden for the said County,
in case of such default of Account or Payment, shall and may make enquiry concerning such default, aswell by
the confession of the partyes themselves, as by testimony of two or more credible Witnesses upon Oath, and in
case of such default, to bee found and adjudged by the said Justices, in their said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, either in
their said Receivor or Colle&bholigct;or of the said Toll, or in their said Surveyors, or any of them, the said Justices,
upon such their convi&bholigct;ion, shall co&bhooov;mitt the party or partyes, soe convi&bholigct; to the co&bhooov;mon Goale for the said County,
there to remaine without Bayle or Maineprize, untill hee or they shall have made a true and perfe&bholigct; account and
payment as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Recital that Monies so to be colle&bholigct;ed will not raise a sufficient Stock.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Power to Surveyors, with Consent of Justices, to mort-gage the Tolls.; If Money cannot be so borrowed, Quarter Sessions may make a Rate.; Rates to be paid to Surveyors.; Persons refusing to pay Rates; Surveyors may distrain.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p19">And forasmuch as the moneys soe to bee colle&bholigct;ed by such receipt of the said Toll, will not at present, raise
such a Stocke or Su&bhouov;me of Money, as may bee sufficient for the speedy repairing of the Premisses, in the said severall
Countyes of Hertford Cambridge and Huntington, It is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed, and the said Surveyors are hereby
enabled, by and with the like consent of the said Justices, for their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, without further
license severally to engage, the profitts arising of the said Toll, in their severall Countyes, for such su&bhouov;me or su&bhouov;mes
of money, by them to bee borrowed for that purpose, and by Indenture, under the hands and seales of the
said respe&bholigct;ive Surveyors, for the time being to transferr the said profitts of the said Toll, and to grant and
convey the same for any time or tearme, not exceeding nine yeares, unto any person or persons, that shall or
will upon that Security, advance any present su&bhouov;me or su&bhouov;mes of money, for and towards the present repairing
and amending of the said Highway, in the respe&bholigct;ive places and Countyes aforesaid, for the repayment of such
principall su&bhouov;me or su&bhouov;mes of money soe lent with Interest for the same, or in case such su&bhouov;me or su&bhouov;mes of money
cannot bee borrowed upon the Security aforesaid, for the repaire of the said Wayes, that then it shall and may
bee lawfull to and for the said Justices, in their said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, at their severall Quarter
Sessions, when they shall see cause, to make a Rate, not to extend to any other County but their owne, nor to
repaire any other then the places aforesaid, in that particular County, where such rate is made, whereby they
shall have power for their severall Countyes, to raise upon the Parishes, that lye in or neere the said Roade (and
soe will have a benefitt therefrom) such su&bhouov;me or su&bhouov;mes of money, as they shall see fitt and convenient for the speedy
effe&bholigct;ing of the said Repaires before mentioned which said su&bhouov;me and su&bhouov;mes, soe to bee rated as aforesaid, shall bee
paid to the Surveyors, for the respe&bholigct;ive County, where such Rate is made, or to their Receivor or Colle&bholigct;or, to
bee imployed for the repairing of the said Wayes and Places aforementioned and not otherwise, And in case any
person, shall refuse to pay such rate soe to bee made, that it shall and may bee lawfull for the said Surveyors, or
their said Receivors, and Colle&bholigct;ors, to distreyne for such su&bhouov;me or su&bhouov;mes of money, and the distresse to sell,
rendring the overplus to the Owners</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Monies advanced by Towns to be repaid with Interest.</head>
			<para id="p20">Provided alwayes and it is ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said money soe advanced by the said
severall Townes, in the said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, shall againe bee repaid, with Interest, by the severall Surveyors,
for the severall Countyes, as it doth arise out of the said Toll, every County paying for what is soe borrowed
within its owne County, and no further.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Persons refusing to a&bholigct; as Surveyors without lawful Excuse</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Justices may fine, not exceeding &pound;10.; may be levied by Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid, That if any person or persons, not having, any lawfull
cause, to bee allowed as aforesaid, shall negle&bholigct; or refuse, to take upon him or them the said Office of Surveyor,
being thereunto nominated and chosen according as by this A&bholigct; is appointed, or to doe or performe his or their
duty, in the due and speedy execution of this [present<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] A&bholigct;, the said Justices of the Peace for the severall and
respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, where such Surveyor or Surveyors dwell, at their Quarter Sessions, shall and may hereby have
power to impose, on such person or persons, soe refusing or negle&bholigct;ing, such Fine or Fines, (not exceeding Ten
pounds, upon each person soe refusing or negle&bholigct;ing,) as to them shall seeme meet, and to cause the same to
bee leavyed by distresse and sale of his or their Goods, rendring to the party so distreyned, the overplus, if any
shall bee</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Fines paid to Surveyors for repairing the Roads.</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Surveyors dying, &amp;c.; Two or more Justices may appoint others.; Such Persons refusing to a&bholigct;; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by Authority aforesaid That all Fines or Forfeitures, to bee imposed or incurred by
virtue of this A&bholigct;, shall bee paid to the Surveyors for the time being, or any three of them, or the Treasurers
of the said Surveyors for the said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, for and towards the repairing of the said Highwayes and
places aforesaid And in case of refusall, or if any person or persons soe chosen to take upon him or them the
said Office, shall happen to dye, or shall for any lawfull impediment bee discharged from the said Office, that
then some other fitt person or persons within that County, shall bee appointed by two or more Justices in the
said County, living neere the said Highway and places aforesaid, in the place of him or them, that shall soe refuse,
dye or bee discharged, and the person or persons soe chosen, shall, and are hereby required upon notice thereof
to him or them given, under the hands and seales of the said Justices, by whom hee or they shall bee so chosen,
to take upon him or them the said Office of Surveyor, and to execute the same in such manner and under such
and the like penalties, as if hee or they had been chosen by the Justices at their Sessions of the Peace, in manner
as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. In A&bholigct;lions for executing A&bholigct;,</head>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">General Issue may be pleaded.; Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid, That if any Suite shall bee co&bhooov;menced against any person
for any thing done, in pursuance of this present A&bholigct;, That in every such case, the A&bholigct;ion shall bee layd in the
said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, where the Cause doth arise and not elsewhere, and the Defendant in such A&bholigct;ions so to
bee brought, may plead the generall Issue, and give this A&bholigct; and the speciall matter in evidence, at any Tryall to
bee had thereupon, and that the same was done in pursueance, and by Authority of the said A&bholigct;, And if it shall
so appeare to bee done, and that such A&bholigct;ion shalbee brought in any other County, That then the Jury shall finde
for the Defendant, and upon such Verdi&bholigct;, or if the Plaintiffe shall bee nonsuited or discontinue his A&bholigct;ion after
the Defendant shall have appeared, or if upon Demurrer Judgment shall bee given against the Plaintiffe, the said
Defendant shall have and recover his double Costs, and have the like remedy for the same, as any Defendant hath
in any other case by Law</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. No Double Toll.</head>
			<para id="p27">Provided alwayes, That no person or persons, having occasion to passe any place where the Toll is taken, and
returne the same day with the same Horse Coach Waggon, or other Carriage or with Cattell, shall bee compelled
in the same day, to pay the said Toll a second time, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Persons now chargeable still to remain so.</head>
			<para id="p28">Provided also, That all and every person and persons, who by Law are chargeable towards the repairing of the
said Highwayes and places aforesaid, shall still remaine soe chargeable, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof
in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p29">Provided also That neither this A&bholigct;, nor any thing therein conteyned, shall extend to any further time, or bee
of force any longer than the tearme of Eleaven yeares, to bee accounted from the passing of this A&bholigct; Any thing
in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Proviso for Persons passing through Places appointed for receiving Tolls carrying Stones, Gravel, Hay, Straw, Corn, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p30">Provided alwayes That all and every person and persons, passing through the respe&bholigct;ive places appointed for
the receiving of Toll as aforesaid (viz.<emph type="i">t</emph>) at Wades-Mill for the County of Hertford at Caxton for the County of
Cambridge and at Stilton for the County of Huntington, and coming imediatly and primarily to and from the
severall Parishes of Standen Thundridge, Ware, and Bengeo, adjacent to Wades-Mill in the said County of Hertford,
and Stowe, Great Papworth, Litle Papworth, Borne, and Elsley, adjacent to Caxton in the said County of Cambridge;
and Yaxley, Washingley, Glatton, Cunnington, Waddon, and Stibbington, adjacent to Stilton, in the said County of
Huntington, shall have a liberty to carry any quantity or quantityes of Stones, Sand, Lyme, or Gravell, Dung,
Mould, and Compost of any nature or kinde whatsoever, Bricke Chalke or Wood, And that they, and all Carts,
with Hay or Corne in the Strawe, at Hay time or Harvest, Plowes, Harrowes, and other Implements of Husbandry,
and all other things whatsoever, imployed in the Husbanding [Stocking<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] and Manureing of their severall and
respe&bholigct;ive Lands, in the said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Parishes, shall passe to and fro, through the said respe&bholigct;ive
places, where such Toll is to bee received as aforesaid without paying any thing for their respe&bholigct;ive passing through
the same, Any thing in this present A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. If Receivers, Colle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. at the Expiration of 11 Years, have Money in Hand, they are to account for and pay the same to Justices.</head>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">Penalty,; recovered by Distress.; Quarter Sessions may dispose of such Monies and Penalties.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p32">Provided also, and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That if it shall happen, that at the end and expiration of the terme of the
Eleaven yeares aforesaid, that the Receivor or Receivors Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors, then in being, or any of them,
of the aforesaid Tolls, or any part thereof, in all and every of the said Countyes, made and to bee made, shall
upon their or any of their accounts, made and to bee made, for the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Receipts of the Tolls
aforesaid, have any su&bhouov;me or sumes of money in [their or<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] any of their hands, more then they or any of them
have expended as aforesaid, That then such Receivor and Receivors, Colle&bholigct;or and Colle&bholigct;ors, and every of them,
shall bring in all and every su&bhouov;me and su&bhouov;mes of money so remaining in their or any of their hands, unto the
Justices of the Peace of the said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, where such Receivor or Receivors, Colle&bholigct;or or
Colle&bholigct;ors shall live, or have received the said severall su&bhouov;me or su&bhouov;mes, at the next Generall Quarter Sessions for
the Peace, which shall happen to bee after their said severall Accounts, so to bee made as aforesaid, upon paine
of forfeiting double the su&bhouov;me, which shall bee in their or any of their hands upon the said Account, which said
su&bhouov;me and penalties shalbee recovered by distresse and sale of the parties Goods, so refusing to doe the same, by
Warrant under the hands and seales of any two Justices of the Peace of the said severall Countyes, And that the
said Justices of the Peace, at their said severall Quarter Sessions in their severall Countyes, are hereby impowered
and enabled, to dispose of the said severall su&bhouov;me and su&bhouov;mes of money, and all the said Penalties, into the hands
of such person and persons, and upon such Securityes as they shall approve of, to and for a Stocke for the
repairing [of <ref idref="n6">6</ref>] the said severall Highwayes, according, to the intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;, and not otherwise</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Power to Justices for Huntingdon to name any Place other than Stilton for receiving the Toll.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided also and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if the Justices of the Peace for the County
of Huntington, or any foure of them, dwelling next to the said High Road, shall adjudge some other place, more
convenient then Stilton, for receiving the Toll for the said County That then it shall and may bee lawfull for the
said Justices of Peace as aforesaid, to appoint some other place, upon the High Road, within their said County, to
receive the aforesaid Toll, instead of Stilton, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Proviso for Soldiers and Persons riding Post.</head>
			<para id="p34">And that it shall and may bee lawfull for all and every Soldier and Soldiers, upon their March and all persons
riding Post to passe through any the places in this A&bholigct; mentioned, without paying any Toll</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. If before the Ex-piration of II Years Roads sufficiently amended, Tolls to cease in that County.</head>
			<para id="p35">Provided also, That if at any time before the expiration of the Eleaven yeares aforesaid the said Highwayes.
shalbee well and sufficiently amended and repaired, and so adjudged by the Justices of the Peace, at the Quarter
Sessions, for their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes aforesaid That then from and after such Adjudication made and
Repayment of such moneys as shall have been borrowed, the aforesaid Toll [in the said County<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] shall cease and
determine, Any thing aforesaid, to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This A&bholigct; is not entered on the Roll as a Public A&bholigct;, but the Title is entered amongst the Private A&bholigct;s. It is here inserted
from the Original A&bholigct;, and is entered in the Long Calendar N&deg; 28. at the Parliament Office.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


