<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47333" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXX. An Act for the importing of Madder pure and unmixed. [Rot. Parl. 14. C. II. p.3. nu. 14.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Madder is useful in the Art of Dying, and that the same has been mixed with Sand, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Importing or exposing to sale Madder mixed with Sand, &amp;c.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS the use of Madder for the laying and grounding of most colours is most usefull and necessary
in the Art of Dying within this Kingdom which is imported from Holland and other Forreign parts in great
quantities but so deceitfully and abundantly mixed with sand and other materials before it is imported that one
pound of good and pure Madder will make more perfe&bholigct; worke then three of that which is usually imported by
reason of which deceit and &bhopcrl;judice the colours therewith laid and grounded are very imperfe&bholigct; and fading which
occasioneth the Transportation of great quantities of Woollen Clothes and other Woollen Manufa&bholigct;ures undyed
and undressed beyond the Seas to be there wrought and put in colours to the great &bhopcrl;judice and impoverishing
of many thousands of His Majesties leige people. For the preventing of which deceits and mischeifs and for the
better incouragement of all planters of Madder within this Kingdome Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majesty with the Advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same That if any person or persons shall from and after the Foure and
twentieth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and two import into this Realm
of England or any part thereof any Madder whatsoever or expose the same to sale being mixed with sand or
other materials over and above two pound weight in every hundred weight of Madder which hundred weight shall
containe One hundred and twelve pound that then every person and persons so offending as aforesaid shall forfeit
and lose all and every such parcell of Madder so mixed with sand or other materials as aforesaid the one moyetie
of the said forfeiture to be to the use of His Majesty His Heires and Successors and the other moyety to such
person or persons as shall discover the same to be recovered by him by A&bholigct;ion or Bill of Debt in any of His
Majesties Courts of Westminster wherein no Essoign Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed.</para>
	</section>
</report>


