<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47334" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXI. An Act to prevent the Inconvenience arising by melting the Silver Coyn of this Realm. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 3. nu. 15.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 9 E. III. st. 2. c. 3.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">17 Ric. II. c. 1. and that the said Statutes are eluded.; Melting the Current Silver Money of the Realm; Penalty.; and if Offender be a Freeman of any Corporation, to be disfranchised; and if not a Freeman, then Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS by an A&bholigct; made in the Ninth yeare of King Edward the Third It is ena&bholigct;ed that no sterling
Halfe penny or Farthing shall be moulten to make Vessel or any other thing by Goldsmiths or any other
upon pain of forfeiture of the moneys so molten Whereas by one other Statute made in the Seaventeenth yeare
of King Richard the Second It was further ena&bholigct;ed that no Groats or Halfe groats shall be moulten by any man to
make Vessel or other thing thereof upon the same pain And whereas divers persons do elude the said Statutes as
wel Goldsmiths as others by melting Silver Coyns of this Realm above the value of Groats to the great diminishing
of the Silver Coyn of this Realm and the hindrance of the commerce of the same Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the
Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual &amp; Temporal and the
Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by Authority of the same That no person or persons whatsoever
shall after the Twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred sixty two wilfully melt or cause to be melted
any of the Curent Silver money of this Realm upon pain not onely of forfeiture of the same but alsoe of the
double value of any such Coyn so melted the one halfe to His Majestie His Heires and Successors the other
halfe to the Informers whoe shal sue for the same upon A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of His
Majesties Courts at Westminster in which no Essoign Wager of Law or prote&bholigct;ion shall be allowed And moreover
that the said person or persons offending contrary to the Tenor of this A&bholigct; (if hee or they be a Freeman or
Freemen or priviledged person or persons of any City or Corporation within this Kingdome of England) shall upon
legal convi&bholigct;ion for the same be forthwith disfranchised and made uncapable of exerciseing the Trade of a Goldsmith
or any other Mistery by vertue of the Priviledges of the City or Corpora&bhocotil;n of which he or they are members
And if the said person or persons offending and convi&bholigct; as aforesaid shall not bee a Freeman or Freemen or priviledged
person or persons of any City or Corporation as aforesaid then hee or they shall suffer imprisonment without
bail or mainprize for the space of six moneths next ensueing his or theire convi&bholigct;ion as aforesaid.</para>
	</section>
</report>


