<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47332" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIX. An Act for the reversing the Earle of Strafford his Attainder (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) [O. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>The Reasons and Grounds of repealing the Attainder.</head>
		<para id="p1">WHEREAS Thomas late Earle of Strafford was impeached of High Treason upon pretence of endeavoring to
subvert the fundamentall Lawes and called to a publique and solemne Arraignment and Tryall before the
Peeres in Parliament where hee made a particular defence to every article obje&bholigct;ed against him in so much that the
turbulent Partie then seeinge noe hopes to effe&bholigct; their unjust designes by any ordinary way and method of proceedings
did att last resolve to attempt the destru&bhocotil;n and attainder of the said Earle by an A&bholigct; of Parliament to bee
therefore purposely made to condemne him upon accumulative Treason none of the pretended Crimes being Treason
apart and soe could not bee in the whole if they had beene proved as they were not and alsoe adjudged him guilty
of constru&bholigct;ive Treason (that is) of levying Warr against the King though it was only the c&bhooov;manding an Order
of the Councell Board in Ireland to be executed, by a Serjant att Armes and three or foure Souldiers which
was the constant Pra&bholigct;ice of the Deputies there for a long tyme; to which end they haveing first presented a Bill
for this intent to the House of C&bhooov;mons and finding there more opposition then they expe&bholigct;ed, they caused a multitude
of tumultuous Persons to come downe to Westminster, armed with Swords and Staves and to fill both the Pallace
Yards, and all the approches to both Houses of Parliament with fury and clamo<emph type="p">r</emph> and to require justice speedy justice
against the Earle of Strafford. And haveing by these and other undue pra&bholigct;ises obtayned that Bill to passe in the
House of C&bhooov;mons, they caused the names of those resolute Gentlemen who in a case of inocent Bloud, had freely
discharged their consciences, being nine and fiftie to bee posted up in severall places about the Cities of London
and Westminster, and stiled them Straffordians and Enemies to their Country, hoping thereby to deliver them up
to the fury of the people, whom they had endevoured to incense against them, and then procured the said Bill
to bee sent up to the House of Peeres where it haveing sometyme rested under great delibera&bhocotil;n, att last in a tyme
when a greate parte of the Peeres were absent by reason of the tumults, and many of those who were present
protested against it, the said Bill passed in the House of Peeres, And at length his late Majestie Kinge Charles the
First of Glorious Memory granted a C&bhooov;mission for giveing his Royall Assent thereunto which neverthelesse was done
by his said Majestie with exceeding greate sorrowe then, and ever remembred by him with unexpressable Greife of
Hart, and out of his Majesties greate Piety hee did publiquely expresse it when his owne Sacred Life was taken
away by the most detestable Traytors that ever were; For all which causes bee it declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the
Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
C&bhooov;mons in this present Parliament assembled, That the A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for the Attainder of Thomas Earle
of Strafford of High Treason, and all and every Clause Article and Thing therein conteyned being obteyned as
aforesaid, is now hereby repealed revoked and reversed.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.</head>
			<para id="p2">And to the end that right bee done to the memory of the deceased Earle of Strafford aforesaid bee it further
ena&bholigct;ed That all Records and Proceedings of Parlyament relateing to the said Attainder bee wholly cancelled and taken
of the Fyle, or otherwayes defaced and obliterated, to the intent the same may not bee visible in after ages, or
brought into example to the prejudice of any Person whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to the future Questioning of any Person or Persons however concerned
in this Busines, or who had any Hand in the Tumults or disorderly procuring the A&bholigct; aforesaid, any thinge herein
conteyned to the contrary thereof notwithstandinge.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">from the Original A&bholigct; in the Parliament Office.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


