<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47339" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act to explaine and supply a former A&bholigct; for destribution of Threescore thousand Pounds amongst the truely loyall and indigent Commission. Officers and for assessing of Offices and destributing the moneyes thereby raised for their further supply.[Rot. Parl. 15 C.II.p. 2. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 14.(13 &amp; 14) Car. II. c. 8</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.; Rules by which the Commissioners under the said A&bholigct; are to proceed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas His Majestie hath beene gratiously pleased (in and by an A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for destribution
of Threescore thousand pounds amongst the truely loyall and indigent Commission Officers and for assessing
of Offices and destributeing the moneyes thereby raised for their further supply) to ena&bholigct; and appoint the said
summe of Threescore thousand pounds together with the Proceed of the said Assessment of Offices to be destributed
as hereinafter is expressed that is to say amongst such truely loyall and indigent Officers who have had a reall
Command of Soldiers according to their severall Co&bhooov;missions and who have never deserted His Majestie nor His
blessed Fathers Service dureing the late times of Rebellion and Usurpation and who have not a sufficient Livelihood
of their owne, nor have since His Majesties returne obtained any Reward Office or Imployment sufficient for a
livelyhood, For the better clearing and preventing of doubts and avoiding frauds in the execution of the said A&bholigct;.
it is thought fitt to prescribe certaine Dire&bholigct;ions whereby to proceed Be it therefore declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the
Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the
Commons in this present Parliament assembled That the Commissioners appointed by and in the said A&bholigct; shall
proceede and a&bholigct; according to the Rules hereafter following.</para>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Description of Officers allowed to have a real Command</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">First The Officers allowed by the said A&bholigct; to have a reall Command of Soldiers are these following and noe
other viz Collonels Adjutant Generalls Quarter Master Generalls Scout Master Generalls Commissary Generalls
Leiutenant Collonells Majors Captaines Leiutenants Cornets Ensignes Quarter Masters,</para>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">Number of Men under each Officer</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">Secondly Each Colonel of Horse if he had a Regiment of Horse consisting of the number of One hundred
and fifty each Captaine of Horse if he had a Troope of Horse consisting of the number of Thirty, each Colonel
of Foote if he had a Regiment of Foote consisting of the number of Three hundred, each Captaine of Foote if he
had a Company of Foote consisting of the number of Fortie, each Colonel of Dragoons if he had a Regiment
of Dragoons consisting of the number of Two hundred, each Captaine of Dragoons if he had a Company of
Dragoons consisting of the number of Thirtie,</para>
		<para id="p7">
			<emph type="i">What Officers shall be accounted truly loyal</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p8">Thirdly Those Officers shall be accounted truely Loyall and not to have deserted who have faithfully served
His late Majestie of blessed Memory and continued Loyall to the King that now is, and did not withdraw themselves
from the said Service without sufficient cause to be allowed by the said Commissioners,</para>
		<para id="p9">
			<emph type="i">What persons deemed indigent</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p10">Fourthly Noe person shall be deemed Indigent who hath either of his owne or by His Majesties gift or otherwise
such an Estate or Income as the said Commissioners shall adjudge to be a sufficient Livelyhood,</para>
		<para id="p11">
			<emph type="i">Proceedings when Certificates lost or invalid</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p12">Fifthly If upon examination by the said Commissioners it shall be found that any Certificates have beene lost
or that any of the said Certificates are invalid because not signed at a Publique meeting That then and in such
Cases it shall be lawfull for the Commissioners aforesaid or any Nine or more of them then sitting in the StarChamber by vertue of the said A&bholigct; to give releife to the parties concerned, And the said Commissioners shall be
likewise hereby impowered to meete and adjourne de die in diem, any thing in the A&bholigct; before mentioned to the
contrary hereof notwithstanding,</para>
		<para id="p13">
			<emph type="i">Proceedings in respe&bholigct; of suspe&bholigct;ed Certificates, and Exceptions to Certificates.; Commissioners of Counties may examine upon Oath</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p14">Sixthly If the said Commissioners sitting in the Star-Chamber as aforesaid or any Nine or more of them or the
Commissioners of the respe&bholigct;ive Counties and places or any Three or more of them shall reasonably suspe&bholigct;
that any Certificates have beene unduely procured or that they are otherwise insufficient The said respe&bholigct;ive
Commissioners shall have power to examine Witnesses upon Oath (which said Oath they are hereby authorized to
administer) And the said Commissioners of the Star-Chamber shall transmitt the Exceptions there taken against
such Certificates together with the names of the persons excepting thereunto unto the Commissioners of the respe&bholigct;ive
Counties and places or to any Three or more of them to be by them joyntly reveiwed and examined either by
depositions taken before them upon Oath (which Oath they are hereby impowered to administer) or otherwise and
their Opinions thereupon, As alsoe upon any of their former Certificates which shall be excepted against before
them to be forthwith returned to the said Commissioners sitting in the Star-Chamber, and the same to be
conclusive.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Limitation of Exceptions to Certificates.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Returns to be in Writing under Hand and Seal</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">Provided alsoe And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe exception shall be taken or
admitted to any Certificate from and after the first day of O&bholigct;ober next ensueing, And alsoe that all returnes of
Reviewes and Opinions thereupon shall be made in writeing under the hands and Seales of the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners
before the first day of November next ensueing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Time within which Monies under the said A&bholigct; are to be distributed.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Colonel Roscarrock and other Officers and their Certificates</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And it is hereby further declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all moneyes to be paid and
destributed by this or the said recited A&bholigct; shall be paid and destributed to the respe&bholigct;ive persons quallified to
receive the same before the fower and twentyeth day of December next ensueing. Provided alwaies That noe
thing either in the A&bholigct; before mentioned or in this present A&bholigct; contained shall extend or be construed to extend
to the harme or prejudice of Edward Roscarrock Collonel of Horse Guy Molesworth Colonel of Horse Edward
Molesworth Colonel of Foote John Low Leiutenant Colonel of Horse to Colonel John Stuart Captaine John Forsyth
Captaine of Horse Mathew Carew Captaine of Foote in the Regiment of Sir Mathew Carew Walter Braems Captaine
of Horse in the Regiment of Colonel Robert Hatton Thomas Gleadstone Captaine of Foote in the Regiment of
Colonel John Scroope to deprive them or any of them of the benefit of the A&bholigct; aforesaid by reason that their or
any of their Certificates were not entred within the time appointed by the said A&bholigct;, but that all and every of the
said persons herein before mentioned who shall at any time hereafter before the Sixteenth day of August next
deliver in their respe&bholigct;ive Certificates attested under the Hands and Seales of Five Commissioners to the Register
appointed by the said Commissioners sitting in [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Star-Chamber for receiveing of the same are hereby declared
and shall be deemed and taken to have as good right to the benefit of the said A&bholigct; as if their such Certificates
had beene respe&bholigct;ively entred and admitted within the time limitted as aforesaid, Any thing in the said A&bholigct; to the
contrary hereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">0</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


