<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47330" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXVII. An Act for repairing of Dover Harbour. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 3. nu. 12.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Dover Harbour hath been much broken and decayed;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that His Majesty had bestowed a great Sum of Money in Repairs, but that further Money was wanted. For keeping the same in Repair according to 1 Jac. 1. c. 32. A Tonnage Duty on certain Ships herein mentioned. Exception of Colliers and certain other Vessels. Duty on Coals, Grindstones, &amp;c. to be paid to the Officer of the Port from or at which the Vessel shall sail or arrive before Goods are loaded or unloaded.;
Entry not allowed without Information on Oath of Burthen and Payment; to be allowed by Merchant to Master, &amp;c. Officer to pay Monies received to Treasurer of the Harbour. Officer unduly making Entries; or not colle&bholigct;ing the Duties, or not paying the same to the said Treasurer; Penalty &pound;10</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS it is found by long experience that Dover Harbour is and hath beene of very great use and
benefit to the Merchants of this Realm and others passing through the Narrow Seas whereunto they
have and do enter to avoid imminent danger of Tempests Pirates or the Common Enemy in time of Warr
And whereas the said Harbour of late by Tempests and the violence of the Sea hath been much broken ruined
and decayed and in great danger of being lost unlesse timely prevented by repairing thereof which cannot be
without great charges and expences as well in the present repaire as in the future maintenance of the same Whereof
His Majesty being informed and minding the good and safety of Merchants and Sea-faring men hath of late of
his Majesties goodnes and liberality bestowed a great s&bhouov;m of money in and about the repairing of the said Harbour
which yet is not sufficient to carry on that worke and to secure it for the future And to the end that the same
may be from time to time maintained and kept in good repaire for the use and benefit of Merchants and Seafaring
men And that such provision for the maintainance thereof may now be made as by an A&bholigct; of Parliament made
in the First yeare of His Majesties Grand father King James of ever blessed memory hath been formerly done and
provided for Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the
Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Commons in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the
same That from and after the Foure and twentieth day of June next ensueing dureing the space of Seven yeares
thence next following there shall be paid by the Master or Owner of every Shipp Vessel or Crayer whereof any
of His Majesties Subje&bholigct;s of England shall be Owners or Part owners of the burthen of Twenty Tuns or upwards
and not exceeding the burthen of Two hundred and fifty Tun for every Voyage loading or discharging within
this Realme or to or from any Foreign Country beyond the Seas and passing to or from London or for from
to or by Dover or coming into the Harbour there not having a Cocquet testifying his payment before for that
Voyage towards the repaire of Dover Harbour the s&bhouov;m of Three pence for every Tun of the burthen of every
such Ship Vessel or Crayer (except Vessels loaden with Seacoales or Grindstones or Purbeck or Portland stone)
and for every Chaldron of Seacoles or Tun of Grindstones Penny halfe penny the same to be paid to the Customer
or Colle&bholigct;or of Customes or Subsidies or theire Deputies within this Realme in such Port from whence such Ship
Vessel or Crayer shall set forth or where such Shipp Vessel or Crayer shall arrive before they load or unload
the Goods therein the Accompt of the number of the said Tuns to be made according to the Entry of Goods
in every such Shipp Vessel or Crayer in the Custome house and no Entry thereof to be allowed in any Office
of Customes or Subsidies without true Information before made by Oath of the Master Owners or Shipper of
such Shipp Vessel or Crayer concerning the burthen thereof and payment by him made of the s&bhouov;ms aforesaid of
which payment the Master Owner or Shipper paying the same shall have allowance of the Merchants according
to the rate of the Goods in the same Ship Vessell or Crayer by way of Average And the Customer or Colle&bholigct;or
or his Deputy receiving the sums aforesaid or any of them shall disburse and pay the same from time to time
to the Treasurer of the said Harbour for the time being or such person or persons as he shall assign to receive
the same to be expended in and about the repaire of the said Harbour And every Customer or Comptroller or
theire Deputies that shall make any Entries of Customes or Subsidies of any Goods in the said Ships Vessels or
Crayers before such Information as aforesaid concerning the burthen thereof shall be made or before payment
made of the s&bhouov;ms before limited to be paid by this A&bholigct; or shall make any wilfull default in not colle&bholigct;ing the
said s&bhouov;ms or any of them or not paying the same over from time to time to the Treasurer of the said Harbour
for the time being or such person or persons as he shall assign to receive the same as aforesaid shall forfeit to
the use of the reparations of the said Harbour Ten pounds for every such default to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of
Debt in any Court of Record by the Warden and Assistants of the said Harbour for the time being in which
Suite no Essoign Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Trinity House of London may inspect Repairs and Works; and may yearly require Accounts from Colle&bholigct;ors and Treasurer.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Colle&bholigct;ors and Treasurer not giving Accounts, or if Monies not duly disbursed, or Harbour sufficiently repaired; Proceedings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the
Master and Wardens of the Trinity house of London for the time being to appoint such person or persons as they
shall thinke fitt to inspe&bholigct; and oversee the repaires and workes to be made for the security of the said Harbour
And that they may once every yeare during the terme of Seven yeares aforesaid require an Accompt of the respe&bholigct;ive
Colle&bholigct;ors of the Duties aforesaid and the Treasurer for the said Harbour for the time being of the monies by them
respe&bholigct;ively received by vertue of this A&bholigct; and of the disbursements thereof And if the said Colle&bholigct;ors and Treasurer
shall not within six weeks next after demaund of such Accompt give in the same accordingly or if thereupon it
shall appeare that the said money shall not be duly disbursed in and about the said repair and the works for the
securing and maintenance of the said Harbour according to the intent of this A&bholigct; or if the said Harbour shall
within the time aforesaid be sufficiently repaired and secured that then the said Master and Wardens shall inform
the Lords of His Majesties Privy Councel thereof who shall and may thereupon and to that purpose are hereby
impowered to suspend or cause all and every further payments by vertue of this A&bholigct; to cease and determine if
they shall see cause</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Ships of Weymouth, Melcombe Regis, and Lime Regis, on Certificate brought.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all Ships and Vessells belonging to the
Ports of Weymouth and Melcombe Regis and Lime Regis in the County of Dorset having a Peire and Cob of
theire owne (which by reason of theire poverty at present they are not able to maintain) shall be exempt from
contributing or paying any thing to the Harbour of Dover mentioned in this A&bholigct; Any thing herein contained to
the contrary notwithstanding so as they shall bring Certificate made upon Oath before the Mayor and under the
Common Seale of the said respe&bholigct;ive Corporations that the said Shipps and Vessels do properly belong thereunto
And that the Inhabitants of the said respe&bholigct;ive Corporations are Owners of the major part of the said Vessels</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Not more than &pound;22,000 to be raised.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alwaies and be it hereby ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; or any thing herein contained shall not extend to
authorize the Colle&bholigct;ion of more then the sum of Twenty two thousand pounds in the whole And then the said
Colle&bholigct;ion to cease.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


