<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47343" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An A&bholigct; for the Encouragement of Trade [Rot. Parl. 15 C. II. p. 2. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Prices at which Corn may be exported; paying Rates for the same as under 12 Car. II. c. 4</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Forasmuch as the encourageing of Tillage ought to be in an especiall manner regaurded and endeavoured
and the surest and effe&bholigct;ualest meanes of promoting and advanceing any Trade Occupation or Mistery being
by rendring it proffitable to the users thereof, And great quantities of Land within this Kingdome for the present
lyeing in a manner waste and yeilding litle which might thereby be improved to considerable Proffitt and Advantage
(if sufficient incouragement were given for the laying out of cost and labour on the same) and thereby much
more Corne produced, greater numbers of People Horses and Catle imployed and other Land alsoe rendred more
valueable Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie thereof, And it is
hereby ena&bholigct;ed That from and after the First day of September in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
sixty and three and from thenceforward when the prices of Corne and Graine Winchester measure doe not
exceed the rates hereafter following at the Havens or Places where the same shall be shipped or loaden (viz)
The Quarter of Wheate Eight and forty Shillings, the Quarter of Barly or Malt Eight and twenty Shillings,
The Quarter of Bucke wheate Eight and twenty shillings, The Quarter of Oates Thirteene Shillings and fower
pence, The Quarter of Rye Two and Thirty Shillings The Quarter of Pease or Beanes Two and Thirty Shillings
currant English Money That then it shall be lawfull for all and every person and persons to shipp load carry
and transport any of the said Corns or Graines from the Havens or Places where they shall be of such Prices unto
any parts beyond the Seas as Merchandice, Any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding paying
such Rates for the same and none other as are to be paid when the same might have beene transported by one
A&bholigct; passed this present Parliament entituled A Subsidy granted to the King of Tonnage and Poundage,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Certain Prices at which Custom and Poundage to be paid.</head>
			<para id="p3">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That when the prices of the aforesaid Cornes and
Graines doe not exceede the Rates above mentioned respe&bholigct;ively Winchester Measure at the Haven or Place into
which any of them shall be imported from any [parts<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] beyond the Seas there shall be paid for the Custome and
Poundage of every Quarter of Wheate five shillings and fower pence, and for every Quarter of Rye fower shillings,
and for every Quarter of Barley or Malt two shillings and eight pence, and for every Quarter of Bucke wheate
two shillings, and for every Quarter of Oates one shilling fower pence, and for every Quarter of Pease or Beanes
fower shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Prices at which Corn may be bought and laid up in Granaries, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p4">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That when the prices of Corne or Graine Winchester
Measure doe not exceede the Rates following at the Markets Havens or Places where the same shall be bought
(viz) The Quarter of Wheate Eight and forty shillings, the Quarter of Rye Two and thirty shillings, the Quarter
of Barley or Malt Eight and twenty shillings, the Quarter of Bucke Wheate Eight and twenty shillings, the Quarter of
Oates thirteene shillings (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) fower pence, the Quarter of Pease or Beanes Two and thirty shillings That then it shall be
lawfull for all and every person and persons (not forestalling nor selling the same in the [same<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Market within three
Moneths after the buying thereof) to buy in open Market, and to lay up and keepe in his [and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] their Graineries
or Houses, and to sell againe such Corne or Graine of the kinds aforesaid as without fraude and coven shall
have beene bought at or under the prices before expressed without incurring any penaltie; Any Law Statute or
Usage to the contrary notwithstanding,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. For maintaining a greater Correspondence and Kindness between this Kingdom and the Plantations,</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">no Manufa&bholigct;ure of Europe to be imported into any Plantation (Tangier excepted), but what shall be shipped in Englandin English built Shipping, pursuant to 14 (13 &amp; 14) Car. II. c. 11.; and English manned, and carried dire&bholigct;ly to the said Plantations; Penalty; how to be disposed of</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And in reguard His Majesties Plantations beyond the Seas are inhabited and peopled by His Subje&bholigct;s of this His
Kingdome of England, For the maintaining a greater correspondence and kindnesse betweene them and keepeing
them in a firmer dependance upon it, and rendring them yet more beneficiall and advantagious unto it in the
farther Imployment and Encrease of English Shipping and Seamen, vent of English Woollen and other Manufa&bholigct;ures
and Commodities rendring the Navigation to and from the same more safe and cheape, and makeing this Kingdome a
Staple not onely of the Commodities of those Plantations but alsoe of the Commodities of other Countryes and Places
for the supplying of them, and it being the usage of other Nations to keepe their [Plantations<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Trade to themselves,
Be it ena&bholigct;ed and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ted That from and after the Five and twentyeth day of March One thousand
six hundred sixtie fower noe Commoditie of the Growth Produ&bholigct;ion or Manufa&bholigct;ure of Europe shall be imported
into any Land Island Plantation Colony Territory or Place to His Majestie belonging, or which shall [belong hereafter<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]
unto, or be in the Possession of His Majestie His Heircs and Successors in Asia Africa or America (Tangier onely
excepted) but what shall be bona fide and without fraude laden and shipped in England Wales [and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the Towne of
Berwicke upon Tweede and in English built Shipping, or which were bona fide bought before the first day of
O&bholigct;ober One thousand six hundred sixtie and two and had such Certificate thereof as is dire&bholigct;ed in one A&bholigct; passed
the last Sessions of this present Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; for preventing Frauds and regulating Abuses in His
Majesties Customes, and whereof the Master and three Fourthes of the Marriners at least are English, and which
shall be carryed dire&bholigct;ly thence to the said Lands Islands Plantations Colonyes Territories or Places, and from noe
other place or places whatsoever Any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding, under the Penaltie
of the losse of all such Commodities of the Growth Produ&bholigct;ion or Manufa&bholigct;ure of Europe as shall be imported into
any of them from any other Place whatsoever by Land or Water, and if by Water, of the Ship, or Vessell alsoe
in which they were imported with all her Guns Tackle Furniture Ammunition and Apparell, one third parte to
His Majestie His Heires and Successors, one third part to the Governour of such Land Island Plantation Colony



Territory or Place into which such Goods were imported if the said Shipp, Vessell or Goods be there seised, or
informed against and sued for, or otherwise that Third part alsoe to His Majestie His Heires and Successors, and
the other Third parte to him or them who shall seise informe or sue for the same in any of His Majesties Courts
in such of the said Lands Islands Colonies Plantations Territories or Places where the Offence was committed, or in
any Court of Record in England by Bill, Information Plaint or other A&bholigct;ion wherein noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion or
Wager in Law shall be allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for shipping Salt for the Fisheries, Madeira Wines, Wines of the Western Isles, Servantsand Horses and Vi&bholigct;uals of Scotland and Ireland.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwayes and be it hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to shipp
and lade in such Shipps, and soe navigated as in the foregoeing Clause is sett downe and expressed in any part of
Europe Salt for the Fisheries of New England and New found land, and to shipp and lade in the Medera's Wines
of the Growth thereof, and to shipp and lade in the Westerne Islands or Azores Wines of the Growth of the said
Islands, and to shipp [or<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] take in Servants or Horses in Scotland or Ireland, and to shipp or lade in Scotland all
sorts of Vi&bholigct;uall of the Growth or Produ&bholigct;ion of Scotland; and to shipp or lade in Ireland all sortes of Vi&bholigct;uall of
the Growth or Produ&bholigct;ion of Ireland, and the same to transport into any of the said Lands Islands Plantations
Colonyes Territories or Places, Any thing in the foregoeing Clause in the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Persons importing into the Plantations to deliver to the Governor an Account of their Names and of the Goods imported.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">No Ship to unlade till the Master has produced a Certificate of Name and Built of Ship, and the Name of the Commander, &amp;c.; and delivered an Inventory of the Lading and the Place of Growth; Penalty.; Governors of Plantations, (Tangier excepted) before their Entrance upon Office, to take an Oath to observe this A&bholigct;; Penalty. Offending after Oath taken turned out; Incapacity; Penalty &pound;1,000</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And for the better prevention of Fraudes Be it ena&bholigct;ed and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed That from and after the Five
and twentyeth day of March One thousand six hundred sixty and fower every person or persons importing by land any
Goods or Commodities whatsoever into any the said Lands Islands Plantations Colonies Territories or Places shall
deliver to the Governour of such Land Island Plantation Colony Territory or Place, or to such Person or Officer as
shall be by him thereunto authorized and appointed within fower and twenty hours after such Importation his and
their Names and Surnames and a true Inventory and Particular of all such Goods or Commodities, And noe Shipp
or Vessell comeing to any such Land Island Plantation Colony Territory or Place shall lade or unlade any Goods
or Commodities whatsoever untill the Master or Commander of such Shipp or Vessell shall first have made knowne
to the Governour of such Land Isleland Plantation Colony Territory or Place or such other Person or Officer as
shall be by him thereunto authorized and appointed the arrivall of the said Shipp or Vessell with her name, and
the name and surname of her Master or Commander, and have shewen to him that she is an English built Shipp,
or made good by produceing such Certificate as abovesaid that she is a Shipp or Vessell bona fide belonging to
England Wales or the Towne of Berwicke and navigated with an English Master and three fourth parts of the
Marriners at least Englishmen and have delivered to such Governour or other Person or Officer a true and perfe&bholigct;
Inventory or Invoice of her Ladeing together with the place or places in which the said Goods were laden or
taken into the said Shipp or Vessell under the paine of the losse of the Shipp or Vessell with all her Guns
A&bhomov;munition Tackle Furniture and Apparell and of all such Goods of the Growth Produ&bholigct;ion or Manufa&bholigct;ure of
Europe as were not bona fide laden and taken in, in England Wales or the Towne of Berwicke to be recovered
and divided in manner aforesaid, And all such as are Governours or Comanders of any the said Lands Islands
Plantations Colonyes Territoryes or Places (Tangier onely excepted) shall before the Five and twentyeth day of
March One thousand six hundred sixtie and fower and all such as shall hereafter be made Governours or
Commanders of any of them shall before their entrance upon the execution of such trust or charge take a Solemne
Oath before such person or persons as shall be authorized by His Majestie His Heires and Successors to administer
the same to doe their utmost within their respe&bholigct;ive Governments or Commands to cause to be well and truely
observed what is in this A&bholigct; ena&bholigct;ed in relation to the Trade of such Lands Islands Plantations Colonyes Territoryes
and Places under the penaltie of being removed out of their respe&bholigct;ive Governments and Commands. And if any
of them shall be found after the takeing of such Oath to have wittingly and willingly offended contrary to what
is by this A&bholigct; required of them, that they shall for such Offence be turned out of their Governments, and be
incapeable of the Government of any other Land Island Plantation or Colony, and moreover forfeite the summe
of One thousand pounds lawfull money. of England, the one moyety to His Majestie His Heires and Successors
and the other moyetie to him or them that shall informe or sue for the same in any of His Majesties Courts in
any of the said Plantations or in any Court of Record in England wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager in
Law shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Officer of the Customs in England giving Warrant or suffering Plantation Goods herein mentioned to be carried to any other Country, without having first been landed in England;</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Forfeiture of Place, and Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That if any Officer of the Customes in England Wales or Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede shall give any Warrant for or suffer any Sugar, Tobaccho, Ginger, Cotton, Wooll, Indico Speckle
Wood or Jamaica Wood Fusticke or other Dying Wood of the growth of any of the said Lands Islands Colonyes
Plantations Territories or Places to be carryed into any other Country or Place whatsoever untill they have beene
first unladen bona fide and putt on shore in some Port or Haven in England or Wales or in the Towne of
Berwicke, that every such Officer for such Offence shall forfeite his place and the value of such of the said
Goods as he shall give Warrant for or suffer to passe into any other Country or Place the one moyety to His
Majestie His Heires and Successors and the other moyety to him or them that shall informe or sue for the same
in any Court of Record in England or Wales wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager in Law shall be allowed,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for lading Sea-coals on Payment of Duty, and being navigated according to A&bholigct;, and giving Security for landing.</head>
			<para id="p12">And for the better encouragement of the said Plantations and the increase of the Shipping and Navigation of
this Kingdome Be it ena&bholigct;ed and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That from and after the Five
and twentyeth day of March One thousand six hundred sixtie and fower it shall and may be lawfull out of any
Port of England or Wales or out of the Towne of Berwicke to shipp and lade Sea coales for any part of them
paying for the Chalder Newcastle measure one shilling eight pence, and for the Chalder London measure one


shilling and noe more in full of all Custome and Poundage for the same, Any Law Statute or Prohibition to the
contrary in any wise notwithstanding. Provided that such Sea-coales be shipped in such Shipping and soe navigated
as abovesaid, And that good security be given to the Officers of the Customes in such Port in which they are
shipped for the landing them in the said Plantations and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. For the Purpose of keeping in and increasing the Current Coin of this Kingdom, Foreign Coin or Bullion may be exported.</head>
			<para id="p13">And forasmuch as severall considerable and advantagious [Trades<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] cannot be conveniently driven and carryed on
without the Species of Money or Bullion, and that it is found by experience that they are carryed in greatest
abundance (as to a Common Market) to such places as give free liberty for exporting the same and the better to
keepe in and encrease the current Coynes of this Kingdome Be it ena&bholigct;ed and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed That from and
after the First day of August One thousand six hundred sixtie and three it shall and may be lawfull to and for
any person or persons whatsoever to export out of any Port of England or Wales in which there is a Customer
or Colle&bholigct;or or out of the Towne of Berwicke all sortes of Forreigne Coyne or Bullion of Gold or Silver first
makeing entry thereof in such Custome house respe&bholigct;ively without paying any Duty Custome Poundage or Fee for
the same Any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Recital that by bringing fatted Cattle the Rents of Lands have fallen.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">For every Head of great Cattle, except of Scotland, imported after the 1st July and before 20th December; and of great Cattle of Scotland imported after 24th August and before 20th Dec. 20s. to the King, 10s. to Informer, 10s. to the Poor</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">And lastly whereas a very great part of the richest and best Land of this Kingdome is, and cannot soe well
be otherwise imployed and made use of as in the Feeding and Fattening of Catle, And that by the comeing in
of late of vast numbers of Catle already fatted such lands are in many places much fallen and like dayly to fall
more in their Rents and Values and in consequence other Lands alsoe to the great prejudice detriment and
impoverishment of this Kingdome Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed That
for every head of great Catle (excepte such as are of the breed of Scotland) that shall be imported or brought
into England Wales or the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede after the First day of July and before the Twentyeth
day of December in any yeare, And for every head of great Catle of the breed of Scotland that shall be
imported (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) into England Wales or the Towne of Berwicke after the Fower and twentyeth day of August and before
the Twentyeth day of December in any yeare there shall be paid to His Majestie His Heires and Successors the
summe of twenty shillings, And the summe of ten shillings to him or them that shall informe or seise the same,
And the summe of tenn shillings to the Poore of the Parish where such Seisure or Information shall be made
to be recovered and leavyed by Bill Plaint or other A&bholigct;ion wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager in Law
shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. And for every Sheep imported, to the King 10s.</head>
			<para id="p16">And moreover That there shall be paid to His Majestie His Heires and Successors for every Sheepe which shall
be imported into England Wales or the Towne of Berwicke aforesaid after the First day of August and before the
Twentyeth day of December in any yeare the summe of Ten shillings of lawfull money of England to be recovered
and leavyed in manner aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Commencement of A&bholigct; as to such Importations.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; in soe far as it relates to great Catle or Sheepe shall not take place till the
First day of July One thousand six hundred sixtie and fower, nor continue longer then the end of the First Session
of the next Parliament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Regulation as to Importation of Fresh Herring, Fresh Cod, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And for the Encouragement of the Herring and North Sea [Island<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] and Westmony Fisheryes Be it ena&bholigct;ed and it
is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That from and after the First day of August which shall be in the
yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixtie and fower noe Fresh Herring Fresh Codd or Haddock Coal
fish or Gull fish shall be imported into England Wales or the Towne of Berwicke but in English built Shipps or
Vessells, or in Shipps or Vessells bona fide belonging to England Wales or the Towne of Berwicke and haveing
such Certificate thereof as is abovesaid, And whereof the Master and three Fourthes at (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) least of the Mariners are
English, and which hath beene fished caught and taken in such Shipps or Vessells and soe navigated, and not being
bought or had of any Strangers borne or out of any Strangers Bottomes under the paine of the forfeiture of all
such Herring Codd Haddock Coal fish or Gull fish imported contrary to the true intent and meaning hereof, and
of the Shipp or Vessell in which it was imported, one moiety of which forfeitures shall be to His Majestie His
Heires and Successors and the other moyetie to him or them that shall informe seise or sue for the same to be
recovered by Bill Plaint or other A&bholigct;ion wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager in Law shall be allowed,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Duties on certain Sorts of salted and dried Fish imported.</head>
			<para id="p20">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed, and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That for the following sortes or
kinds of salted or dryed Fish which from and after the [said<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] First day of August shall be imported into England
Wales or the Towne of Berwicke in any other Shipp or Vessell then what is English built or belonging to England
Wales or Towne of Berwicke and haveing such Certificate thereof as abovesaid and whereof the Master and three
Fourthes of the Marriners at least are English and not haveing beene fished and caught in such Shipps or Vessells
and soe navigated there shall be paid by way of Custome and Impost the severall summes of money herein after
perticularly mentioned (that is to say)</para>
			<para id="p21">For Cod-fish the Barrell five shillings</para>
			<para id="p22">For Cod fish, the Last containing twelve Barrell Three pounds,</para>
			<para id="p23">For Cod fish the hundred containing sixscore Ten shillings</para>
			<para id="p24">For Coale fish the hundred containing sixscore five shillings,</para>
			<para id="p25">For Lings the hundred containing sixscore One pound,</para>
			<para id="p26">For White Herrings the Last containing twelve Barrells One pound sixteene shillings,</para>
			<para id="p27">For Haddocks the Barrell Two shillings,</para>
			<para id="p28">For Gull fish the Barrell Two shillings,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Recital that the growing and making of Tobacco in England increases, notwithstanding 12 Car. II. c.34.in consequence of the smallness of the Penalties.</head>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">Sowing Tobacco, further Penalty; how to be disposed of</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p30">And forasmuch as planting and makeing Tobaccho within this Kingdome of England doth continue and increase
to the apparent losse of His said Majestie in His Customes the discouragement of the English Plantations in the
parts beyond the Seas and prejudice of this Kingdome in generall notwithstanding an A&bholigct; of Parliament made in the
Twelfth yeare of His said Majesties Raigne for prevention thereof entituled An A&bholigct; for prohibiting, the planting
setting or sowing of Tobacco in England and Ireland, And forasmuch as it is found by experience that the reason
why the said planting and makeing of Tobaccho doth continue is That the penalties prescribed and appointed by
that Law are soe litle as have neither power or effe&bholigct; over the transgressors thereof For remedy therefore of soe
great an evill Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every the person and persons whatsoever
that doe, or shall at any time hereafter sett plant or sow any Tobaccho in Seed, Plant or otherwise in or upon
any Ground Field Earth or place within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales Islands of Guernsie and
Jersie or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede or Kingdome of Ireland shall over and above the Penaltie of the said
A&bholigct; for that purpose ordained for every such offence forfeite and pay the summe of Ten pounds for every Rod or
Pole of Ground that he or they shall soe plant sett or sow with Tobaccho and soe proportionably for a greater
or lesser quantity of ground one third part thereof to the Kings Majestie, one other third part thereof to the
use of the Poore of such respe&bholigct;ive Parish or Parishes wherein such Tobaccho shall be soe planted sett or sowed
and the other third part thereof to him or them that shall sue for the same to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt
Bill Plaint or Information in any of His said Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne
Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Resisting Execution of A&bholigct;,</head>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">Imprisonment, over and above the former Penalties</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p32">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That in case any person or persons shall resist or make forceable opposition
against any person or persons in the due and through Execution of the said A&bholigct; of the Twelfth of His said
Majesties Raigne that he she or they soe resisting and makeing forceable opposition shall over and above the
Penalties therein mentioned for such Offences be committed to the common Goale of the County where such
Offence shall be committed there to remaine without Baile or Maineprize untill he she or they have entred into a
Recognizance to His Majestie His Heires and Successors with two sufficient Sureties of Ten pounds penaltie not to
doe or committ the like offence againe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Proviso for Physic Gardens of the Universities, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend to the hindrance or prejudice of
planting Tobaccho in any Phisicke Garden of either of the Universities or any other private Garden for Surgery
soe as the quantity soe planted exceede not the halfe of one Pole in any one place or Garden,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Proviso for Importation of Cattle and Corn from the Isle of Man.</head>
			<para id="p34">Provided alsoe and be it ena&bholigct;ed That it shall and may be lawfull to import Catle of the breed of the Isle
of Man not exceeding six hundred in any one yeare And Corne of the growth of that Island out of that Island
into England soe as the said Catle be landed at Chester Liverpoole or Wirewater, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the
contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Part <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Plantation <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">hereafter belong <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">or brought <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Iseland <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


