<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47345" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IX. An Act for granting Fower intire Subsidies to His Majestie by the Temporaltie. [Rot. Parl. 15 C. II. p. I. nu. I.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Four entire Subsidies presented, at Two several Payments.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Guilds, &amp;c. Corporate and not Corporate, to pay.; Proviso for Apparel, &amp;c.; Two Shillings and Eight-pence of every Pound.; Aliens and Popish Recusants Convi&bholigct;,; Five Shillings and Four-pence of every Pound. Aliens Seven Years old. Popish Recusants Convi&bholigct;,; 17 Years old, or 21 Years old, not having received the Sacrament. Eight-pence Poll</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">MOST Gratious Soveraigne Wee your Majesties most dutyfull and Loyall Subje&bholigct;s the Commons assembled in
Parliament haveing entred into a due and serious consideration of those difficulties and dangers which have
soe long threatened the Peace and exhausted the Treasure of this Kingdome, and well knowing those weighty and
important occasions which doe still presse your Majestie, and with all humble thankfulnesse acknowledging the
many blessings we enjoy through the Justice and the Peace, the Wisedome and [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Pietie of your Majesties Royall
Government doe chearefully and unanimously and with hearts fully and intirely devoted to your Majesties Service
humbly present your Majestie with the free Guift of Fower intire Subsidies which wee humbly beseech your
Majestie gratiously to accept of as a testimony of the most dutyfull Affe&bholigct;ions of us your Subje&bholigct;s, And that your
Majestie would be pleased that it may be ena&bholigct;ed, And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie the
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by Authoritie of the same
That our said Soveraigne Lord the Kings Majestie His Heires and Successors shall have receive and enjoy Fower
intire Subsidies to be rated taxed levyed and paid at Two severall Payments of every person Spirituall and Temporall
of what Estate or Degree he or they be of according to the tenour of this A&bholigct; in manner and forme following
that is to say That as well every person borne within this Realme of England Wales Towne of Berwicke upon
Tweede or other the Kings Dominions as all and every Fraternity Guild Corporation Misterie Brotherhood and
Commonaltie Corporate and not Corporate within this Realme of England Wales or other the Kings Dominions
being worth Three pounds aswell in Coyne, And the value of every pound that every such Person Fraternitie Guild
Corporation Misterie Brotherhood and Commonaltie Corporate or not Corporate hath of his or their owne, or any
other hath to his or their use, As alsoe in Plate Stocke of Merchandice, all manner of Corne and Graine Householdstuffe,
and of all other Goods moveable aswell within this Realme as without, And of all such summes of money as to
him or them is or shall be oweing whereof he or they trust in his or their conscience surely to be paid (except
and out of the premisses dedu&bholigct;ed such summes of money as he or they doe owe and in his or their consciences
intend truely to pay, and except alsoe the apparell of every such persons their Wives and Children belonging to
their owne Bodyes saveing Jewels Gold Silver Stone and Pearle) shall pay to and for every of the said Subsidyes
Two shillings eight pence of every pound, And alsoe every Alien and Stranger borne out of the Kings obeisance
aswell Denizens as others inhabiting within this Realme, And alsoe every Popish Recusant Convi&bholigct;, or which before
the time of the Assessment of the severall Subsidies by this present A&bholigct; granted shall be Popish Recusant, Convi&bholigct;,
or which are, or shall be indi&bholigct;ed for Popish Recusancy, And their Indi&bholigct;ments either are or shall be removed by
Certiorari, or being not removed shall not by Apparance and Traverse legally discharge their said Indi&bholigct;ments at
the next Assizes or within two Generall Sessions of the Peace where the said persons shall be indi&bholigct;ed respe&bholigct;ively,
of every pound that he or they shall have in Coyne, and the value of every pound in Plate Corne Graine
Merchandize Householdstuffe or other Goods Jewells Chattells Moveables and unmovables as is aforesaid aswell
within this Realme as without, And of all summes of money to him or them oweing, whereof he or they trust
in his or their consciences to be paid (except and out of the premisses dedu&bholigct;ed every such Summe and Summes
of money which he or they doe owe, and in his or their conscience or consciences intend truely to pay) shall
pay to and for every of the said Subsidyes Five shillings and fower pence for every pound, And alsoe that every
Alien and Stranger borne out of the Kings Dominions being Denizen or not Denizen not being contributary to
any the Rates aforesaid, and being of the age of seaven yeares or above, And every Popish Recusant Convi&bholigct;,
or which before the time of the Assessment of the severall Subsidies by this present A&bholigct; granted shall be a Popish
Recusant Convi&bholigct;, and being of the age of seaventeene yeares, or which being of the age of one and twenty
yeares hath not received the Holy Co&bhooov;munion within one yeare then last past shall pay to and for every of the
said severall Subsidyes eight pence for every Poll, And the Master or he or she with whom the said Alien is,
or shall be abideing at the time of the Taxation or Taxations thereof to be charged with the same for lacke of
payment thereof.</para></section>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II Persons, Corporations, &amp;c. having Lands, &amp;c. of Twenty Shillings yearly Value.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Four Shillings in every Pound; Aliens, &amp;c. Eight Shillings in the Pound.; Proviso for Land chargeable to Tithes and Servants Wages.; Plate, &amp;c. held for Corporations, to be rated.; Land, Corrodies, Fees, &amp;c. Proviso for Ornaments, &amp;c. of the Church</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every person borne under the Kings Obeisance and
every Corporation Fraternitie Guild Misterie Brotherhood and Commonaltie Corporate or not Corporate for every
pound that every of the said persons and every Corporation Fraternity Guild Mistery Brotherhood and Commonaltie
Corporate or not Corporate or any other to his or their use both in Fee simple Fee taile for terme of life, terme of
yeares by Execution or by Copy of Court Roll of and in any Honours Castles Mannours Lands Tenements Rents
Services Hereditaments Annuityes Fees Corrodyes or other yearely Proffitts of the yearely value of Twenty shillings
aswell within Auntient Demeasne and other places priviledged as elsewhere, and soe upward shall pay to and for
every of the said Fower Subsidies Fower shillings of and for every pound. And every Alien Denizen or not Denizen
borne out of the Kings Obeizance, and every Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; of what Estate or Degree soever they be
of, or which before the time of the Assessment of the severall Subsidyes by this present A&bholigct; granted shall be a
Popish Recusant convi&bholigct;, or which shall be indited for Popish Recusancy, and their Indi&bholigct;ments are or shall be
removed by (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Certiorari, or being not removed shall not by Apparance and Traverse legally discharge their said
Indi&bholigct;ments at the next Assizes, or within two Generall Sessions of the Peace, where the said persons shall be
indi&bholigct;ed respe&bholigct;ively in such case to pay to and for every of the said Fower severall Subsidies Eight shillings for
every pound, And that all summes to be presented and chargeable by this A&bholigct; either for Goods and Debts or
either of them or for Lands Tenements and other the premisses as is in this A&bholigct; contained shall be at every of the
said Payments sett and taxed after the rate and proportion according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; Lands and
Tenements chargeable to the Disms of the Clergy and yearely Wages due to Servants for their yearely Service
(other then the Kings Servants, takeing yearely Wages of Five pounds or above) onely excepted and foreprized,
And that all Plate Coyne Jewells Goods Debts and Chattells personall and all Lands Tenements and other the
premisses as aforesaid being in the rule and custodie of any person or persons to the use of any Corporation
Fraternity Guild Mistery Brotherhood or any Commonaltie being Corporate or not Corporate be and shall be rated
sett and charged by reason of this A&bholigct; at the value certifyed by the Presenters in their Certificate for every pound in
Goods and Debts as is aforesaid, And for every pound in Lands Tenements Annuityes Fees Corodyes and other
yearely Proffitts as is aforesaid, And the summes that are above rehearsed sett and taxed to be levyed and taken
of them that shall have such Goods in custody, or otherwise charged for Lands as is before rehearsed, And the
same persons and persons and bodyes Corporate by authoritie of this A&bholigct; shall be discharged against him or them
that shall or ought to have the same at the time of the payment or delivery thereof, or at his otherwise departure
from the custodie or possession of the same, except and alwayes foreprized from the charge and Assessment of
the said Subsidyes all Goods Chattells Jewells and Ornaments of Churches and Chappells which have beene ordained
and used in Churches and Chappells for the honour and service of Almighty God.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. First Two Subsidies how to be rated.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Last Two Subsidies how to be rated.; Sums, Names of Persons charged, and Names of Colle&bholigct;ors to be certified to Exchequer.; Payments into the Exchequer in one entire Sum.; Payments in Liberties, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And the first two of the said Fower Subsidyes shall be by Authority aforesaid taxed sessed and rated according
to this A&bholigct; in every Shire Rydeing Lath Wapentake Rape Citty Burrough Towne and every other place within
this Realme of England Wales Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede and other the Kings Dominions before the First
day of O&bholigct;ober now next comeing, And the last two of the said Fower Subsidyes shall be by Authoritie aforesaid
taxed assessed and rated according to this A&bholigct; in every Shire Rideing Lath Wapentake Rape Citty Burrough Towne
and every other place within this Realme of England Wales Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede and other the
Kings Dominions before the First day of March which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
sixty and three, And the perticular summes of every Shire Riding Burrough Towne and other place aforesaid with
the particular names of such as are or shall be chargeable to and for the payment of the two first of the said
Fower Subsidyes to be taxed and sett by the Commissioners for the same to be limitted, or two of them at the
least with the names of the High Colle&bholigct;ors, and in the same forme, shall be certifyed into the Kings Exchequer
before the fowerteenth day of O&bholigct;ober next ensueing, And the two latter before the Fowerteenth day of Aprill
then next ensueing And the same summes in forme aforesaid to be taxed to and for the payment of the [said<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] two
first of the said fower Subsidyes shall be paid in one intire summe into the Kings Receipte of the Exchequer aforesaid,
to the use of our said Soveraigne Lord His Heires and Successors at or before the First day of November now
next comeing And the said summes in manner and forme aforesaid to be taxed for the payment of the two last
of the said fower Subsidyes shall be paid in one intire summe into the Kings Receipt of the Exchequer aforesaid
to the use of our said Soveraigne Lord at or before the First day of May then next following, And the summes
abovesaid of and for the said Subsidyes shall be taxed sett asked and demanded taken gathered levyed and paid
to the use of our said Soveraigne Lord His Heires and Successors in forme aforesaid aswell within [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Liberties
Franchises San&bholigct;uaryes, Auntient Demesnes and other whatsoever places exempt or not exempt as without (except
such Shires Places and Persons as shall be foreprized in and by this present A&bholigct;) Any Grant Charter Prescription
Use or Liberty by reason of any Letters Patents or other Priviledge Prescription Allowance for the same or
whatsoever other matter or discharge heretofore to the contrary made granted used or obtained notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Absentees, whether Natives or Aliens, to be charged by Certificate of Inhabitants of Place.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Rule by which they are to be charged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by Authority of this present Parliament That every such persons aswell such as be
borne under the Kings Obeysance, as every other person stranger borne Denizen or not Denizen inhabiting within
this Realme or within Wales, Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede or other the Kings Dominions which at the time
of the said Assessings or Taxations or any or every of them to be had or made shall be out of this Realme or out
of Wales and have Goods Chattells Lands or Tenements Fees or Annuityes or other Proffitts within this Realme
or in Wales shall be charged and chargeable for the same by the Certificate of the Inhabitants of the place where
such Goods Chattells Lands Tenements or other the Premisses then shall be, or in such place where such person
or persons or his or their Fa&bholigct;or Deputy or Attourney shall have his or their most resorte unto within this Realme
or in Wales in like manner as if the said person were or had beene at the time of the said assessing within this
Realme; And that every person abideing or dwelling within or without this Realme shall be charged and chargeable
to the said severall Subsidyes granted by this A&bholigct; according and after the rate of such yearely substance or value
of Lands or Tenements Goods Chattells and other the Premisses as every person soe to be charged shall be sett
att, at the time of the said Assessing or Taxation upon him to be made and noe otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Commissioners for assessing the King's Household to be appointed by Lord Chancellor, Lord Treasurer, and other great Officers.</head>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That for the assessing and ordering of the said Subsidyes
to be duely had the Lord Chauncellour of England or the Lord Keeper of the Great Seale, the Lord Treasurer
of England, the Lord President of the Kings Councell, the Lord Privy Seale the Lord Admirall of England, the
Lord Steward of the Kings Householde and the Lord Chamberlaine of the Kings most honourable Household for
the time being or two of them at the least (whereof the Lord Chauncellour or Lord Keeper of the Great Seale, or
the Lord Treasurer for the time being to be one) shall and may name and appoint such and soe many persons as
they in their discretions shall thinke fitt to be Co&bhooov;missioners for the rateing and taxeing of the Honourable Household
of the Kings Majestie, in what Shire or other place the said Household shall happen then to be, And the said
Chauncellour of England, or Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the time being shall make and dire&bholigct; out
of the Court of Chauncery under [the Great Seale one or more Commissions for the [assessing<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] and levying of
the said severall Subsidyes according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; in manner and forme hereafter expressed for
His Majestyes Household unto the persons in manner aforesaid to be nominated.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Commissioners for Counties, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p10">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every the persons hereafter named shall by
vertue of this A&bholigct;, and without any further Authority or Commission be Commissioners of and for the severall
and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places hereafter named That is to say</para>
		
		<section id="s7">
			<head>For the County of Bedford</head>
			<para id="p11">Robert Lord Bruce Sir Humphrey Winch Baronet Richard Tayler William Russell Esquiers Sir Henry Chester
Knight of the Bath Sir Humphry Monox Sir Thomas Alston Sir Lodowicke Dyer Sir John Napier Baronets Sir
Roger Burgoyn Knight and Baronet, Sir William Beecher Sir George Blundell Knights, Sir Samuell Browne one of
the Justices of His Majestyes Court of Common Pleas Sir John Keeling one of [His Majestyes<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Justices of [the<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]
Court of Kings Bench Sir William Palmer of Warden streete Sir William Palmer of Hill Knights John Keeling
S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Thompson William Boteler Thomas Snag John Vaux John Osborne Francis Crawley William Spencer Francis
Wingate Stephen Anderson Esquiers Sir Clement Armiger Sir John Duncombe Knights Francis Dive James Mountague
William Geery Samuell Cotton John Neal John Ventris Robert Audley Robert Crompton Walter Cary Mathew Denton
and John Mathewes Es&bhoqesq;s Pawlet St John Es&bhoqesq;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>For the Towne of Bedford</head>
			<para id="p12">Robert Lord Bruce William Russell Es&bhoqesq; Sir Humphry Winch Baronet Richard Tayler Paulet St John John
Gardiner Esquiers The Maior for the time being William Risley William Foster Symon Becket William Scott senior
Thomas Christie Robert Beverley and Lewis Harding Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>For the County of Bucks</head>
			<para id="p13">Charles Earle of Ancram Thomas Lord Wainman Sir Thomas Tyrrell one of the Justices of the Common Pleas
Sir Richard Temple Sir Toby Tyrrell Sir John Burlace Sir Anthony Chester Sir Thomas Proby Sir William Bowyer
Sir William Smith Sir Ralph Varney Sir William Drake Sir Thomas Hampson Baronets Sir William Tirringham
Knight of the Bath Sir Edmond Pye Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Napper Sir William Parsons Knights Sir Richard
Pigott Sir Henry Harbert Sir John Dormer Knights William Fleetwood [Edmond Waller senior Charles Cheney<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Edmond
Waller junior William Penn William Salter Francis Duffield Bret Norton Thomas Duncombe Thomas Hacket William
Lane John Egleston Thomas Farrers Cesar Cranmore Thomas Risley Roger Price Peter Dorrell Francis Ingoldsby
Edmond Dorrell Thomas Saunders James Herbert Esquiers Sir Thomas Clayton Knight Thomas Wedon Richard
Winwood Richard Greenvile and Robert Scawen Esquires Sir John Croke. Baronet Sir Richard Ingoldsby Sir Robert
Gears Knights of the Bath Sir Robert Croke Sir Thomas Clargies Knights Robert Croke Richard Hampden William
Burlace William Hill Thomas Farrer junior James Low Thomas Stafford Robert Lovet Bernard Turny Thomas Egleton
Robert Dormer Francis Tyrryngham George Wyan William Cleaver William Abraham James Perrot John Green
Henry Alnut Esquiers The Bayliffe of Buckingham for the time being, and The Maior of Wickham for the
time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>For the Towne of Buckingham</head>
			<para id="p14">The Bailyffe for the time being Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir William Smith Baronet
Thomas Risley Roger Price Esquiers John Smith Edmond Dayrell John Risley and John Turner Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>For the County of Berks</head>
			<para id="p15">Charles Earle of Ancram John Lovelace Es&bhoqesq; Sir Richard Powle Knight of the Bath Sir George Stonehouse
Sir George Pratt, Sir Richard Braham Sir Thomas Draper Sir Thomas Rich Sir Anthony Craven Sir Henry
Winchcombe Sir William Backehouse Sir John Fettyplace Sir William Armorer Baronets Sir Edmond Sawyer
Sir Robert Pye Sir Thomas Dolman Sir John Davis Knights Richard Nevill Humphry Hyde senior Humphry Hyde
junior Thomas Fettiplace George Fettiplace Richard Harrison Robert Packer Richard Aldworth John Blagrave George
Blagrave Peregrine Hoby William Barker Anthony Barker William Tayler Humphry Hyde of Hurst. William Barker of
Hurst John Elwes Thomas Garret Francis Piget John Southby John Allan William James Nicholas Hyde William
Nelson Thomas Saunders Edward Hoby Edward Keat Richard Jones John Hersey Robert Leigh Robert Coston
Edward Dalby Henry Pro&bholigct;or Thomas Southby Richard Palmer James Heron Philip Weston Henry Barker Esquiers
William Offley Do&bholigct;or in Law Francis Hungerford Do&bholigct;or [in <ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Phisicke John Powney Roger Knight Richard Lovelace
Roger Draper William Hussey William Baker Hargel Baron George Starkey Esquiers Walter Knight Thomas
Seex William Braxton Gabriel Cox John Mundy Thomas Porter Gentlemen, The Maior of Reading for the time
being, The Maior of Newbery for the time being, The Maior of Abingdon for the time being, The Maior of Windsor
for the time being, and The Maior of Wallingford for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>For the County of Cornwall</head>
			<para id="p16">Robert Roberts Hender Roberts Esquiers Sir Chichester Wray Sir John Trelawney Sir Richard Vivian Knights
and Baronets Sir John Carew Sir John Coryton Sir William Godolphin Baronets Sir Francis Godolphin Sir Richard
Edgecombe Sir Nicholas Slanning Knights of the Bath Sir Peter Courtney Sir John Arundell Sir William Godolphin
Sir Peter Killigrew Sir James Smith Sir Samuell Cosworth Knights Bernard Greenvile Jonathan Trelawney Richard
Arundell Peirce Edgecombe Charles Trevanian William Godolphin, Vinel Vivion John Vivion Hugh Boscowen
Francis Buller junior Charles Roscarrock Michaell Vivion Nicholas Arundell William Pendarvis Arthur Spry Thomas
Robinson John Tanner John Elliot John Buller John Kendall Thomas Craddon John Cotton Degorie Tremaine
Walter Langdon senior Walter Langdon junior John [Nicholas<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] of Trewayne John [Nicholas<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] of Litlewood William
Spry George Spry Richard Rous Thomas Achim Charles Grill of Court Thomas Hawkes Joseph Nichols Samuell
Trelawney John Trelawney John Polewheele Degory Polewheele [John<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Rashleigh [Jonathan<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Rashleigh William
Scawne William Trevisa Hugh Piper John Blegh James Praed John St Aubin Richard Penwarden Walter Kendall
Nicholas Glyn Henry Spoore senior Henry Spoore junior Richard Ensley Colon Blewet Thomas Piper Francis
Luterel John Connock John Bellin Nathaniel Trevanion Christopher Cooke Francis Gregor Ezekiel Arundel James
Erisey John Thomas Edward Elliot Thomas Hearle Thomas [Burle<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Edmond Prideaux [Esquiers.<ref idref="n14">14</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>For the County of Cumberland</head>
			<para id="p17">Sir Philip Musgrave Sir Partricius Curwen Sir William Dalston Sir George Fletcher Sir John Lowther senior
Sir John Lowther junior Sir Edward Musgrave Baronets Sir Thomas Dacres Sir Wilfrid Lawson Sir William
Hudlestone Sir William Carleton Sir Philip Howard Sir Francis Salkeld Knights John Dalston Daniel Fleming
John Lamplugh Robert Scawen Christopher Musgrave Richard Skelton William Musgrave William Layton George
Denton John Eglonby George Tory Robert Highmore William Musgrave of [Croockdake<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] Richard Tolson Anthony
Latus William Pennington Edward Stanley John Senhouse senior John Senhouse junior Andrew Hudlestone junior
John Senhouse of Seascale Joseph Patrickson Thomas Wibergh [John<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Irton John Punsonby Leonard Dikes Lancelot
Fletcher Richard Lamplugh Esquiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>For the Citty of Carlisle</head>
			<para id="p18">The Maior of Carlisle for the time being Sir Philip Howard Knight Christopher Musgrave John Eglonby Esquiers
John Tomlinson Mathew Wilkinson William Wilson and Thomas Jackson Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>For the County of Cambridge and Isle of Ely</head>
			<para id="p19">William Lord Allington Sir Dudley North Knight of the Bath Sir William Compton Knight Thomas Chichley
Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Wendy Knight of the Bath Sir John Cotton Sir Thomas Willis Sir Thomas Hatton Sir John
Cuts Sir George Downing Baronets Sir Thomas Darrell Sir Isaac Thornton Knights Levinus Bennet Roger Pepys
John Millicent Humphry Gardner Thomas Story William Lagar William Leggat Jeoffrey Nightingale and Samuel
Fortrey Esquiers Mathew Wren William Colvile Thomas Marsh Charles Wren Michael Holman William Fisher
Anthony Balam Robert Balam Edward Partrich and Thomas Castle Esquiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>For the Towne of Cambridge</head>
			<para id="p20">The Maior for the time being Sir Thomas Slater Baronet Robert Eade Stoyte Do&bholigct;ors of Phisicke
Samuel Spalding and Christopher Rose Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>For the County of Chester</head>
			<para id="p21">William Lord Brereton Robert Lord Viscount [Chalmondeley<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Sir Thomas Smith Sir Richard Grosvenor Sir
George Warburton Sir Peter Leicester Sir William Stanley Sir Peter Pindar Sir John Bellor Baronets Sir Philip
Egerton Sir John Ardern Sir Robert Cotton Sir Foulke Lucy Sir Jeoffrey Shakerley Knights Sir Thomas Wilbraham
Baronet Peter Venables Colonel Robinson Henry Leigh Richard Leigh Thomas Leigh Thomas Cholmondeley
William Lawton John Crew of Crew Henry Bunbury Edward Warren William Leversage Esquiers and John
Ward Gentleman.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>For the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester</head>
			<para id="p22">The Maior for the time being Richard Leving Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Charles Walley Robert Harvey Thomas Thropp
Thomas Cooper William Ince Robert Bird Richard Minshul Arthur Walley Aldermen, and the Sheriffes of the
Citty for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>For the County of Derby</head>
			<para id="p23">Henry Viscount Mansfeild William Lord Cavendish Anchitel Gray George Pierpoint Esquiers Sir Thomas
Greisley Sir John Curson Sir Francis Burdet Sir John Harper Sir Henry Evory Sir Edward Coke Sir William
Boothby Baronets Sir John Harpur Knight John Fretchville German Pale John Ferrers George Vernon John
Shalcrosse John Mundy Richard Coke John Milward William Fitzherbert Walter Horton Charles Agard Charles
Cotton Gilbert Thacker Henry Gilbert Godfrey Clarke Nicholas Willimott Robert Eyre William Bullocke Edward
Vernon John Low George Sitwell Francis Meynell Symon Degg Roger Allestrey John Dalton Esquiers The Maior
of Derby for the time being The Maior of Chesterfeild for the time being Thomas Milward George Taylor William
Wright Rowland Eyre of Bradway Edmond Browne and Francis Barker Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>For the Burrough of Derby</head>
			<para id="p24">The Maior for the time being Simon Degg Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Roger Allestry John Dalton and Hugh Bateman
Esquiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>For the County of Devon</head>
			<para id="p25">Arthur Earle of Donegall in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Hugh Pollard Comptroller of His Majestyes Household
Sir William Morrice Principall Secretary of State, Sir John Drake High Sheriffe of the County of Devon Sir Edward
Seamour Sir George Chudley Sir Peter Prideaux Sir Thomas Hale Sir Courtney Poole Sir Coplestone Bampfield
Sir John Northcot Sir John Chichester of Rawleigh Sir William Courtney Sir Edmond Fowell Sir William Morice
Sir Thomas Carew Sir Chichester Wray Baronets Sir Edward Wise Sir John Roll Sir Edward Hungerford Knights
of the Bath Sir John Chichester of Hall Sir Henry Carew Sir Richard Prideaux Sir James Smith Sir Thomas
Stuckley Sir Robert Carew Sir William Stroud Sir Edmond Fortescue Sir John Davis Baronet Sir Thomas Higgons
[Knight<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] Edward Seamour Peter Prideaux John Fowell Arthur Basset Walter Young Francis Drew Robert Fortescue
Thomas Clifford Arthur Champernowne Edmond Tremaine John Gifford of Brightley George Yeo Thomas [Scutcote<ref idref="n19">19</ref>]
Thomas Carew of Bowhill John Bury John Pollard Richard Cabell John Arscot Nicholas Ducke George Howard
Jonathan Sparke Samuell Trelawney George Reynolds Nicholas Dennis Henry Northleigh Josias Calmady Henry.
Ford William Walrond Thomas Bere Samuel St Hill Edmond Walrond Henry Stephens Edward Hungerford
Henry Nute John Willoughby James Clifford Peter Fortescue of Wood John Tanner Peirce Edgecombe Christopher
Clobery Chilston Calmady Richard Coffin and Edmond Fowell Esquiers The Maior of Totnes for the time being
The Maior of Plimouth for the time being, The Maior of Barnestable for the time being, The Maior of Dartmouth
for the time being, and the Maior of Tiverton for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>For the Citty and County of the Citty of Exon</head>
			<para id="p26">The Maior for the time being Sir Peter Ball Recorder Sir James Smith Knight Robert Walker John Martin
William Bruton Es?rs John Bidgood Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Christopher Lethbridge Henry Gaudy Anthony Salter John
Butler Allen Penny Aldermen, Thomas Shapcot Henry Walker Samuel Isaac Isaac Maudit senior Gentlemen
Nicholas Isaac and John Acland Merchants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>For the County of Dorset</head>
			<para id="p27">Wolley Miller Es&bhoqesq; High Sheriffe of the County John Lord Digby Sir Edward Nicholas Knight one of His
Majestyes Privy Councell Sir John Morton Sir Francis Hollis Sir Gerrard Napper Baronets Sir Francis Fulford
Sir John Strangwayes Sir Walter Earle Sir Ralph Bancks Sir John Fitz-James Sir John Low Sir John Strode Sir
Nathaniel Napper Sir John Rogers Knights Giles Strangwayes Thomas Freake Humphry Weld Francis Windham
John Strangwayes George Pite John Tregonwell of Anderston James Gould John Churchill Humphry Bishop Henry
Whittaker Robert Gulleford Bullen Reymes John Rives Councellour at Law Thomas Fownes John Rives of [Darnare<ref idref="n20">20</ref>]
Robert Coker Henry Henley John Tregonwell of Milton Thomas Trenchard Robert Lawrence Maximilian Mohun
Robert Napper George Hussey Mathew Davies George Strangewayes George Fulford William Thomas Henry
Butler George Grey William Okeden Robert Seamour Robert Tiderleigh John Ironside Arthur Fowkes George
Trenchard Thomas Hussey of Edmondisham Peter Hoskins John Abington Esquiers. The Maior and Bayliffes of
Dorchester for the time being, The Maior and Bayliffes of Weymouth and Melcombe Regis for the time being,
The Maior of Shaston for the time being, The Maior of [Lynn<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] for the time being, and the Bayliffes of Bridport
for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Poole</head>
			<para id="p28">The Maior for the time being Anthony Etricke Es&bhoqesq; Recorder William Scutt Es&bhoqesq; Robert Lewen Samuel
Bramble Gentlemen and Robert Cleaves Merchant.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>For the Bishoprick of Durham</head>
			<para id="p29">Sir Thomas Davison High Sheriffe Sir John Conyers Sir Thomas Gore Sir Nicholas Cole Sir Gilbert Gerrard Knights
and Baronets Sir James Pavering Baronet Sir Thomas Widrington Sir William Blackstone of Newton Sir Francis
Anderson Sir Francis Bowes Knights Thomas Shadford Nicholas Frevill William Blackstone of Piddington Esquiers
Colonel John Tempest Roger Talbot Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Burwell Do&bholigct;or of the Lawes Ralph Davison [Samuel Davison<ref idref="n22">22</ref>]
Charles Gerard Esquiers The Maior of Durham Thomas Swinborne John Swinborne Esquiers Colonel John Byerly
Henry Lamton Cutbard Care Es&bhoqesq; Baron John Hilton Mr Gabriel Jackson Captaine Edward Gower Major
Charles Belleses Captaine Barnes Mr Morland of Durham and James Moore Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>For the West Rideing of the County of Yorke.</head>
			<para id="p30">Henry Viscount Irwin George Viscount Castleton Thomas Lord Fairefax Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath
Conyers Darcey Es&bhoqesq; Sir Francis Worthley Sir George Savill Sir Thomas Osborne Baronets Sir Richard Maleverer
Sir John Goodrick Knights and Baronets Sir John Reasby Sir John Key Sir Francis Bland Sir John Armatage Sir William
Ingleby Sir William Rokeby Sir Solomon Swale Sir Godfrey Copley Sir George Wynn Sir John Jackson Sir Thomas
Slingsby Sir George Cooke Sir Thomas Yarborough Baronets Sir John Lewis Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Wharton
Sir Francis Fane junior Knights of the Bath Sir Richard Tanckred Sir Jordan Crosland Sir Thomas Wentworth Sir John
Dawney Sir Miles Stapleton Sir Edmond Jennings Sir Thomas Widrington Sir William Lowther Sir Francis Goodrick
Sir William Ingram Sir Christopher Clapham Sir Ralph Knight Knights Walter Hawkesworth Robert Wivel Thomas
Danby Francis Nevill Esquiers Thomas Burwell Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Thomas Stringer John Vincent John Rickard Welbury
Norton Richard Hutton Henry Arthington John Beibbie Walter Strickland William Markington Francis Rockley
Richard Mounteny Walter Calverley Henry Atkinson Charles Tanckred Ambrose Pudsey William Stockdale William
Hammond William Drake Edward Parker of Bowson Inglebert Leeds Cuthbert Wade James Moseley John Stahhop
Nicholas Stable Robert [Branding<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Roger Portington John Thornhill William Wombell Francis White Esquiers
Michael Fawkes Jonathan Jennings Henry Redshaw John Preston William Witham Henry Tompson John Doddesworth
Benjamin Wade James Moseley Gentlemen, The Maior of Rippon for the time being The Maior of Doncaster for
the time being The Maior of Pontefra&bholigct; for the time being, and The Maior of Leeds for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>For the North Rideing of the County of Yorke</head>
			<para id="p31">Sir Thomas Gower Knight and Baronet High Sheriffe of the County Charles Lord St John Robert. Lord Bruce
Conyers Darcy [Charles<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] Darcy James Darcy Esquiers Sir Christopher Wivell Sir William Chomley Baronets Sir John
Goodrick Knight and Baronet Sir John Hotham Sir Metealfe Robinson Sir Solomon Swale Sir Henry Stapleton Sir
David Fowles Sir John Lowther Sir Roger Langley Sir William Caley Sir Christopher [Windeford<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] Sir George Marwood
Sir Richard Graham Sir William Franckland Baronets Sir Robert Strickland Sir Richard Tanckred Sir Jordan Crosland
Sir William Dalton Sir James Pennyman Sir Thomas Ingram Sir Henry Cholmley Sir Thomas Heblethwaite Sir Henry
Franckland Sir Joseph Craddocke Knights Henry Chater Edward Gower James Medcalfe William Wedle Walter
Strickland Mathew Hutton Thomas Danby John Turner John Beverley Humphry Wharton Charles Bellassis. Reynold
Graham Major Norton William Fielding William Robinson Robert Layton Roger Talbot Edward Croft Charles
Tankard Robert Belt John Calverley Timothy Malevorer John Dodsworth William Tompson William Wickham
Edward Trotter Anthony Lowther Thomas Norton Roger Colvel William Medcalfe Henry Blackstone Walter Lister
John Gibson Thomas Worsley Esquiers Major Edward Gower Major William Gower James Moore Francis Driffield
Thomas Langdale John Smith Christopher Keld Henry Crosland Lampley William Trueman Gentlemen,
The Alderman of Richmond for the time being, and the Bayliffes of Scarborough for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>For the East Rideing of the County of Yorke</head>
			<para id="p32">Sir John Hotham Sir Francis Boynton Sir Watkinson Paler Sir Robert Hilliard Sir Thomas Rudston Sir Hugh
Bethel Sir John Leadyard Baronets Sir Thomas Northcliffe Sir Philip Monckton Sir Mathew Appleyard Sir Francis
Kobb Sir Thomas Remington Sir Thomas Heblethwait Knights Tobias Jenkins Stephen Tompson Michaell Warton
Thomas Grantham Durand Hotham Hugh Lister John Constable John Lister Henry Holmes Christopher Hilyard
Walter Bethell George Mountague John Vavasour John Headlum William Osbaldston William Grimston Robert
Sotheby Thomas Crumpton Samford Nevill William Gee Richard Ledgeard Tobias Hodgson Richard Tompson
Henry Hilyard Francis Wright Edward Barnard Thomas Hesket Gregory Creyke William Harpham Thomas Anlaby
Alexander Rookesby Esquiers Thomas Swan Leonard Robinson William Blunt Lewins Edward Gray junior
William Dobson William Thompson Gentlemen, The Maior of Hedon for the time being, and The Maior of Beverley
for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>For the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke.</head>
			<para id="p33">The Lord Maior for the time being Thomas Lord Fairefax Sir Medcalfe Robinson Sir Thomas Slingsby Baronets
Sir John Goodrick Knight and Baronet Sir Miles Stapleton Knight John Scot Es&bhoqesq; James Brooke Christopher Topham
George Lamplough George Mancklins Edward Elwick Cressey Burnet Henry Tyreman Christopher Breary John Tayler
John Kilvington James Bawtrey Richard Hewet Aldermen Tobias Jenkins Thomas Robinson Lewis Darcy William
Fairefax Henry Fairefax Richard Hutton Thomas Hesketh James Moysyer, Es&bhoqesq; George Aslaby Gentleman Mr William
Richardson Mr Richard Rawlinson Mr Francis Brice Mr John Lotus Mr Philip Herbert Mr John Thompson
Mr Francis Chadderton Mr George Mangie and Mr James Moseley Citizens.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Kingston upon Hull.</head>
			<para id="p34">The Maior for the time being Richard Wilson William Dobson Robert Ripley William Maister Robert Berier
William Foxley William Ramsden Christopher Richardson George Crowle Richard Robinson Robert Bloome and
William Skinner Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>For the County of Essex</head>
			<para id="p35">Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the House of Co&bhooov;mons Charles Lord Rich Sir Harbotle Grimston Master of
the Rolls Edward Russell Banestree Mainard Esquiers Sir John Barington Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Appleton Sir
William Ayloffe Sir William Hicks Sir Thomas Nightingale Sir William Wiseman of Canfeild Sir Andrew [Gennour<ref idref="n26">26</ref>]
Sir Richard Everard Baronets Sir Capell Luckin Knight and Baronet Sir Martin Lumley Baronet Sheriffe of the County
Sir Samuell Tryan Sir Henry Wright Sir Thomas Smith Sir Thomas Cambell Baronets Sir Thomas Abdy Sir Robert
Abdy Sir William Wiseman of Rivenhall Knights and Baronets Sir James Altham Sir John Brampstone Knights of
the Bath Sir Humphrey Mildmay Sir John Tyrell Sir Richard Wiseman Sir Gobert Barington Sir Richard Everard
Sir Anthony Browne Sir Thomas Bowes Sir Thomas Fanshaw Sir Henry Wroth Sir Edmond Pierce Sir Thomas Gardner
Sir Henry Clarke Sir Robert Brookes Sir Mundeford Brampstone Sir John Shaw Sir Cranmer Herris Sir William Batten
Knights John Archer Sergeant at Law John Bendish Charles Fitch George Scot Gamaliel Capel Richard Samms
Charles Mainard Thomas St George Anthony Luther Thomas Meade Robert Clarke Peter [Soame<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] Anthony Maxie
Thomas Argall James Milburne Tristram Conyers Henry Peert John Eldred senior Oliver Reymond Salter Herris John
Godbold Robert Joselin John Eldred junior Thomas Midleton William Wright of Stanstead Mount Fitchet William
Glascock of Farmham Thomas Luther Thomas Roberts John James Richard Cooper John Turner John Atwood
John Joselin Giles Dent John Tyrell Stephen Smith William Appleton James Silverlock Henry Ayloffe John Simons
John Berners Henry Woolleston Robert Mildmay of Tarting Thomas Bland Henry Wight Edward Glascocke William
Holecroft Edward Shelton Thomas Manby and Thomas Lucy Esquiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>For the Towne of Colchester</head>
			<para id="p36">The Maior of Colchester for the time being Sir John Shaw Knight Recorder John Eldred junior Es&bhoqesq; Thomas
Reynolds (<ref idref="n28">28</ref>) Andrew Fromantell Henry Lambe John Brasier Aldermen Thomas Talcot Es&bhoqesq; Edmond Thurston and
George Sandford Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>For the Towne of Malden</head>
			<para id="p37">Rubin Robinson John Hart Bayliffes Francis Brampstone Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Plumbe Francis Gurney and
James Sterling Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>For the Towne of Harwich</head>
			<para id="p38">The Maior for the time being Thomas King Gentleman John Eldred junior Recorder Daniel Smith Arthur Hawkes
Thomas Keyes Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>For the Liberty of Havering</head>
			<para id="p39">Robert Cheeke Carew Harvey alias Mildmay Francis Brampstone Esquires John Thorowgood and Thomas Legatt
Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>For the County of Gloucester</head>
			<para id="p40">Henry Lord Herbert James Earle of Newburgh John Viscount Tracy Sir Henry Capell Knight of the Bath Sir
Baynham Throckmorton Sir Henry Fredericke Thynne Sir Richard Ashfeild Sir Edward Batthurst Sir John Howe
Sir William Ducy Sir William. Kite Sir Richard Cox Sir Francis Henry Lea Baronets Sir Robert Pointz Sir
Robert Atkins Knights of the Bath Sir William Catchmay Sir Nicholas Throckmorton Sir Baynham Throckmorton
Knights Sir Christopher Gyse Baronet Sir William Morton Knight one of His Ma&bhojties;ties Sergeants at Law Sir John
Fettiplace Sir Gabriell Low Sir Edward Fusse Sir Thomas Howe Sir Thomas Stephens Sir Humphrey Hooke Sir
Edmond Wray Sir John Seymour Sir Thomas Overbury Sir John Newton Knights George Mountague John Grubham
Howe William Dutton William Berkley William Coope Philip Shepherd Henry Sims Richard Atkins Thomas Chester
John Smith Thomas Majsters Thomas Seamour Thomas Escourt Henry Poole William Bourchier John Chamberlin
John Winter William Try John Cotherington William Straford William Cope Robert Oldesworth John George
Richard Dowdeswell Duncombe Colchester William Leigh Francis Norwood Richard Baugh John Stephens John
Barum Henry Guyse Richard Daston Esquiers Evan Seyes Sergeant at Law Richard Stephens Edward Rich Silvanus
Wood Thomas Horton Fleetwood Dormer Richard Whitmore Samuel Cothrington [...] Rutter Esquiers Thomas
Trye William Batson Henry Browne Conway Whitterne Edward Chamberlin Thomas Ayleway Gentlemen and The
Bayliffes of Tewksbury for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>For the Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester.</head>
			<para id="p41">William Russell the present Maior and the Maior of the said Citty for the time being James Earle of Newburgh
Sir William Morton Knight one of His Majestyes Sergeants at Law Recorder of the said Citty Sir Edward Massey
Knight Evan Seyes Sergeant at Law Robert Fielding Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Henry Cugley James Stephens Aldermen
Thomas Williams Es&bhoqesq; John Powell Thomas Yates [Thomas Price<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] John Woodward Anthony Arnold Henry Ockold
John-Wagstaffe and Henry Fowler Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>For the County of Huntington</head>
			<para id="p42">Lord Mandevill George Mountague John Barnard Richard Elmes Esquiers Sir Francis Compton Knight Sir John
Cotton Sir John Hewet Baronets Sir Robert Bernard Knight and Baronet Robert Appreece John Ferrer Henry Williams
Nicholas Pedley Lyonell Walden Robert Payne John Heron and Richard Nayler Esquiers</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>For the Towne of Huntington</head>
			<para id="p43">Lord Mandeville Sir John Cotton Baronet Henry Williams Lyonel Walden Lawrence Thockington Esquiers The
Maior for the time being Richard Weaver Thomas Ashton Thomas Judson and James Faireside Gentleman.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>For the County of Hertford</head>
			<para id="p44">Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the House of Commons Thomas Lord Fanshaw Sir Thomas Fanshaw
Knight of the Honourable Order of the Bath William Willoughby William Cecill Algernoone Cecil Esquiers Sir
Thomas Leventhorpe Bart Sir Harbotle Grimston Baronet Master of the Rolls Sir Heneage Fetherstone Sir Brocket
Spencer Sir Erasmus [Harvey<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] Baronets Sir Richard Atkins Sir Richard Francklin Knights and Baronets Sir Philip
Boteler Sir Ralph Baesh Knights of the Bath Sir Edward Atkins one of the Barons of His Majestyes Court of
Exchequer Edward Gardner Edward Cason James Willimot Richard Goulston Thomas Dacres Arthur Pulter George
Nedha? Thomas Coppin Ralph Gore Henry Beecher Thomas Stanley Thomas Dockwray John Heyden Robert
Austin William Hale Arthur Sparkes John Fortherley Marmaduke Royden John Jesson Edward Atkins Esquiers Sir
Thomas Dacres Sir Henry Cesar Sir Rowland Litton Sir John Gore Sir Harry Conisby Sir John Watts Sir Francis
Boteler Sir Henry Blunt Sir Humphrey Gore Sir John Hale Sir William Glascock Knights Ralph Freeman junior
Richard Jennings Edmond Feild Edmond Smith Robert Sadler Edward Briscoe William Minoes Richard Gamon
Esquiers Thomas Arris  Dean Do&bholigct;ors of Phisicke Henry Chauncey Ralph Freeman senior Esquiers George
Bramley John Ellis Gentlemen Humphrey Shalcrosse senior  Shalcrosse Gentlemen, and The Maior of Hertford
for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>For the Burrough of St. Albanes</head>
			<para id="p45">Algernoone Cecill Es&bhoqesq; Sir Harbotle Grimston [Baronet<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] Master of the Rolls Sir Harry Conisby Sir Richard Comes
Knights, The Maior of the Towne for the time being John Simpson Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Edmond Smith Thomas Dockwray
Robert Sadler Richard Jennings William Cotton Es&bhoqesq;s Edward Haynes Thomas Cowley [junior<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] William Marston
Gentlemen Thomas Arris Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Thomas Oxton John Briscoe Charles Chamberlaine Edward Fames and
John Jesson Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>For the County of Hereford</head>
			<para id="p46">John Lord Viscount Scudamore James Scudamore Walter Brabason Esquiers Sir John Scudamore Sir Edward
Harley Knights of the Bath Sir James Bridges Sir John Kirle Sir William Powell Baronets Sir Edward Hopkins
Sir Thomas Tomkins Sir Herbert Perrot Knights Sir Job Charleton Knight Sergeant at Law and Cheife Justice of
Chester Roger Vaughan Thomas Whitney John Price Fitz-William Coningsby John Scudamore senior Thomas
Price Herbert Aubrey senior Thomas Harley Herbert Westfailing Humphrey Cornwall John Scudamore junior
John Barnaby of Cannon-pion James Pitts John Birch Francis Unitt Richard Hopton Thomas Cocks John Hanford
High Sheriffe John Booth of Hereford Thomas Cornwall Herbert Awbrey junior John Vaughan John Skipp
William Dansey Thomas Rodd Richard Rodd Humphrey Baskervill of Pentreloes Edward Cornwell Thomas
Wigmore Rudhale Guyllim Bennet Hoskins William Lambe Nicholas Walwin Timothy Colles John Vaughan of
Hergast William Gregory Edmond Greene Esquiers Edward Alderne Do&bholigct;or of Law Thomas Geers Humphrey
Tayler of Withrington Herbert Maisters William Whittington John Booth of Breynton John Gwillim of Wellingson
John Karvars of Upton Edward Rodd Gentlemen And the Bayliffe of Leominster for the time being</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>For the Citty of Hereford</head>
			<para id="p47">The Maior for the time being John Lord Viscount Scudamore High Steward Roger Vaughan Herbert Westfailing
Pridstock Harford junior Thomas Price Esquiers Richard Philpots William Gregory William Philips James Lawrence
Aldermen Robert Symonds Nicholas Philpots Thomas Paynard and Jerome Addis Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>For the County of Kent</head>
			<para id="p48">Sir Thomas [Peyston<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] Sir Roger Twisden Sir Edward Hale Sir Edward Monnis Sir John Sidley Sir Edward Deereing
Sir John Rivers Sir Thomas Stile Sir Oliver Boteler Sir Norton Knatchbull Sir John Tufton Sir Richard Hardresse
Sir Robert Austin Baronets Sir William Wilde Baronet one of His Majesties Sergeants at Law Sir Theophilus
Biddolph Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir William Meredeth Baronets Sir George Sands Knight of the Bath Sir Stephen
Leonard Sir Phillip Warwicke Sir John Darell Sir Edward Filmer Sir Anthony Aucher Sir Francis Clarke Sir
William Swan Sir William Hugeson Sir William Boreman Sir John Marsham Sir John Maynee Sir Richard Sandys
Sir Nicholas Crispe Sir John Shaw Sir Edward Maisters Knights Sir Thomas Twisden one of the Justices of His
Majestyes Court of Kings Bench Nicholas Toke High Sheriffe John Heath Attourney of the Dutchy Robert Barnham
John Knatchbull John Boyes of Fretchvill George Newman James Brockman Thomas Lambert George Pollhill
Thomas Culpeper of Bedgebury Francis Lovelace Recorder of Canterbury Edward Finch Richard Amhurst Richard
Allen Recorder of Rochester Thomas Flood Maurice Diggs William Cage Thomas Harlakenden Philip [Parker<ref idref="n33">33</ref>]
Anthony Fowle Henry Gilburne Richard Hulse John Horsemanden Edward Hales Edmond Tooke Samuell Boys
William. Dike Thomas Hardresse George. Boreman Thomas Pecke John Scott of Langley and Stephen Alcock
senior Esquiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>For the Citty and County of Canterbury</head>
			<para id="p49">The Maior for the time being Sir William Man Sir Edward Maister Knights Francis Lovelace Esquire Recorder
of the said Citty Thomas Hardresse John [West<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] Esquiers William Stanley and Henry Twiman Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>For the Citty of Rochester</head>
			<para id="p50">The Maior of Rochester for the time being Sir Francis Clarke Knight Richard Allen Es&bhoqesq; Recorder George
Newman Fardinando Marsham Stephen Alcock senior Esquiers Richard Head and Robert Fowler Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p51">For the Towne of Maidstone The Maior for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p52">For Gravesend and Milton The Maior for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p53">For Quinborough The Maior for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>For the parts of Lindsey in the County of Lincolne.</head>
			<para id="p54">George Viscount Castleton Robert Lord Willoughby of Earsby William Willoughby Es&bhoqesq; Sir Philip Tyrwhitt
Sir Robert Bowles Sir William Hickman Sir William Wray Sir Edward Barkham Sir John Anderson Sir George
Wynne Baronets Sir John Mounson Knight of the Bath and [Baronets<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] Sir Adrian Scroope Knight of the Bath Sir
Martin Lister Sir Charles Dallison Sir Edward Rosseter Sir Edward Ascough Sir Thomas Meeres Sir Francis
Goodrick Knights Sir John Mounson the younger Michaell Warton Philip Tyrwitt Charles Pelham junior William
Oldfeild Jervas Holles Marmaduke Dorrell William Broxholme Charles Pelham senior William Fitzwilliams Edward
Turney William Marwood George Heley Anthony Weberley James Moseley Cecill Tyrwhitt William Bard William
Anderson John Boles (<ref idref="n35">35</ref>) Esquiers and the Maior of Grimsby for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>For the Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne.</head>
			<para id="p55">Mr. Robert Rosse Maior of the said Citty Sir Robert Bolle Baronet Sir Thomas Meeres Knight John Bolle
Es&bhoqesq; William Bishop Edward Blow Richard Wetherell Henry Morley Richard Kyte John Kent Aldermen Mr Wilson
of Sheepwash Mr Robinson of Bramston and Mr John Johnson.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>For the Parts of Holland</head>
			<para id="p56">Sir Anthony Oldfeild Baronet Sir Henry Heron Knight of the Bath Sir Anthony Irby Knight Thomas Browne
Thomas Hall Mathew Woolmer Anthony Oldfeild John Empson Thomas Thory John Jay John Lockton Henry
Burrell Esquiers Joseph Whiteing Daniell Rhodes Samuell Jackson Anthony Hall Charles Rushworth Gentlemen
and the Maior of Boston for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s50">
			<head>For the Parts of Kestaven</head>
			<para id="p57">Sir William Thorold Knight and Baronet William Mountague Es&bhoqesq; the Queenes Majestyes Attourney Generall
Sir Thomas Hussey Sir Michaell Armine Sir John Brownelowe Sir Robert Markham Sir Thomas Williamson Sir
William Trollop Sir John Newton Sir Charles Hussey Sir Richard Rothwell Baronets Sir Francis Fane Knight
of the Bath Sir John Walpoole Knight George Sherard Richard Brownlow Anthony Thorold Lewis Palmer Erasmus
Deligne Christopher Nevill Charles Dymocke John White William Savill John Hatcher Henry Hall Redmaine
Burrell John Saunders Charles Baudes William Blith William Welby Edward King Henry Stone William Revit
Adam Claypoole Thomas Willoughby Stephen Rothwell Edward Skipwith William Stafford Francis Wingfeild
Thomas Skipwith Anthony Tredway And the Aldermen of Grantham and Stamford for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s51">
			<head>For the County of Leicester</head>
			<para id="p58">Thomas Armstone Es&bhoqesq; High Sheriffe John Lord Roos Thomas Lord Beaumont Viscount Swords Bennet Lord
Sherrard John Gray Es&bhoqesq; Sir George Villiers Sir Thomas Halford Sir John Bale Sir Wollaston Dixie Sir Thomas
Smith Sir John Prettyman Sir Verney Noell Sir Henry Hudson Baronets Sir William Hartoppe Knight George
Fawnt Henry Nevill Thomas Merry William Halford Mathew Babington William Skeffington Richard Lister
William Boothby William Whaley Richard Verney Richard Brudenall William Streete William Allicock Walter
Rudeing William Cole Roger Roe William Roberts Samuell Jervis Richard Orton Richard Halford Thomas
Bradgate Richard Bradgate of Litle Peatlin William Belgrave John Mitton George Ashby Thomas Staveley John
Danvers John Chamberlaine John Nedham William Quarles John Hacket John Cave Thomas Hood John Morton
William Bent William Watts John Barwell Wiseman neere Loughborrough Wilson John Nedham
Francis Chamberlaine William Leeke William Gilbert and Henry Gibbon Esquiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s52">
			<head>For the Burrough of Leicester</head>
			<para id="p59">Daniell Deacon [Malter<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] Rudeings Henry Hungate Robert Tyrringham Richard Mason Robert Harding Esquires
Thomas Overing Thomas Browne George Reasons William Major John Clarke William Stubbins and Daniell
Coates Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s53">
			<head>For the County Palatine of Lancaster</head>
			<para id="p60">Charles Earle of Ancram Richard Lord Gorge Edward Stanley William Stanley William Spencer Esquires Sir
Robert [Bindles<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] Sir George Midleton Sir Ralph Ashton of Midleton Sir Edward Moseley Baronets Sir Gilbert
Ireland Sir Roger Bradsheigh Sir Henry Slater Sir Jeoffrey Shakerley and Sir John Harrison Knights John Heath
Es&bhoqesq; Attourney of the Dutchy of Lancaster Robert Holt Thomas Greenhalth Lawrence Rawstone Richard Kirkby
Thomas Norris John Molineux Nicholas Moseley Richard Fleetwood of Roshall Ambrose Pudsey Richard Legh
Edward Rigby Leonard Egerton Es?s Jeoffrey Rishton Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke William Farrington Thomas Preston
John Girlington Thomas Carus Roger Nowell Edward Fleetwood Thomas Bradell John Lightboune John Entwisle
Henry Banister Hugh Dickenson Alexander Rigby of Layton Robert Rawlinson Mathew Richardson Alexander
Osbaldeston Nicholas Towneley of Royle John Parker of Extwisle William Radley Thomas Ashton William Bankes
junior John Birch Esquiers Thomas Hawarden Nicholas Fasakerley Gentlemen The Maior of the Towne of Lancaster
for the time being, and the Maior of the Towne of Preston for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s54">
			<head>For the Burrough of Wigan</head>
			<para id="p61">The Maior for the time being and Richard Penington Esquire Recorder.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s55">
			<head>For the Burrough of Liverpoole</head>
			<para id="p62">The Maior for the Time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s56">
			<head>For the Burrough of Clitherowe</head>
			<para id="p63">The In-Bayliffe for the time being</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s57">
			<head>For the County of Midlesex</head>
			<para id="p64">Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons Edward Russell George Mountague
Christopher Hatton James Sheffeild Thomas Coventry Esquiers Sir Henry Bennet Principall Secretary of State John
Ashburnham Es&bholigct; one of His Majestyes Bedchamber Edward Progers Esq[uire] one of His Majestyes Bedchamber Sir
Harbotle Grimston Baronet and Master of the Rolls Sir Heneage Finch Baronet His Majestyes Solliciter Generall
Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir Thomas Fisher Sir Henry Wood Sir Thomas Adams Sir John Robinson Sir Richard
Browne Sir Richard Francklin Sir Joseph Ash Sir Reginald Forster Sir William Roberts Baronets Sir John
Brampston Sir Robert Atkins Sir John Nicholas Sir John Bennet Knights of the Bath Sir Christopher Abdy Sir
Henry Herbert Sir Thomas Allen Sir Nicholas Crispe Sir Thomas Rowe Sir William Bateman Sir Lancelot Lake
Sir Henry Wroth Sir Thomas Ingram Sir Francis Gerrard Sir Thomas Clergies Sir Thomas Player junior Sir
Thomas Byde Sir William Ryder Sir Clifford Clifton Sir Gilbert Gerard Knights Sir Thomas Trevor Baronet Sir
Thomas Ingram Sir Philip Warwicke Knights Sir Jeremy Whitchcot Baronet John Heath Es&bhoqesq; Attourney of the
Dutchy John Trever Charles Cornwallis Humphry Weld William Ashburnham Francis Crawley George Pitt John
Carey Thomas Allen Thomas Lake Henry Barker John Browne Edwin Rich Francis Bloomer Joseph Ayliffe
Thomas Bales Thomas Swallow Richard Peacock Charles Cheney Francis Phillips William Hill George Day George
Marsh Nicholas Bacon John Page Christopher Eyres Thomas Lucy William Meggs Thomas Collett Ralph Hawtry
Henry Murrey William Waters John Hawtry Thomas Povey Richard Dunton James Hawley Erasmus Moyse
Charles Pitfield Thomas Harrison Thomas Wharton Michaell Holman John Smith William Gouldesborough Richard
Abell John Wilford Giles Hungerford John Jones Samuell Reeve John Wandeford Richard Cheney Richard
Proctor and James Norfolke Es?.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s58">
			<head>[For the Liberty of the Dutchy of Lancaster</head>
			<para id="p65">Sir Thomas Trevor Baronet Sir Thomas Ingram Sir Philip Warwicke Sir Gilbert Gerrard junior Knights John
Heath Attourney of the Dutchy John Trevor Es&bhoqesq;.<ref idref="n39">39</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s59">
			<head>For the Citty of Westminster</head>
			<para id="p66">Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the House of Commons Sir William Morrice Knight Sir Henry Bennet
Knight Principall Secretaryes of State Thomas Elliot Es&bhoqesq; one of His Majestyes Bedchamber Sir William Playter
Sir John Rous Baronets Sir Edmond Pye Knight and Baronet Sir John Nicholas Sir John Denham Knights of the
Bath Sir Lancelot Lake Sir Henry Herbert Knights George Mountague Daniell Oneale Esquiers Sir Philip Warwicke
Sir Richard Everard Sir Thomas Meeres Sir Edward Philmer Sir Thomas Ingram Sir John Talbot Sir Charles
Cotterell Sir Edward Ford Sir Thomas Higgons Sir Robert Pye Sir Edward Broughton Sir Hugh Cartwright Sir
Thomas Litleton Sir Clement Fisher Sir William Poultney Sir John [Baker<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] Sir John Birkenhead Sir Charles Harboard
Sir Robert Long Sir Edmond Pye and Sir William Armorer Knights John Harvey John Trevor Charles Whitaker
Reighnall Graham Thomas Povey Esquiers Edward Greaves Doctor of Phisicke Phisition in Ordinary to His
Majestie Thomas Coppin William Glascocke Bullen Reymes Edmond-Bury Godfrey [Thomas<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] Lucie Thomas Morris
Robert Philmer Maurice Kingwell Ralph Halsell Thomas Russell John Browne Richard Atkins William Dallen
Thomas Bates William Leg William Hardopp Thomas Windham Edmond Warcupp Stephen Fox Esquiers William
[Waterman<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] Phisition in Ordinary to His Majestie Richard Mason Henry Pecke George Farewell James Norfolke
Esquiers James Maisters Do&bholigct;or of the Civill Law William Hoare Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke The two High Burgesses of
Westminster for the time being Humphry Wortly Bryan Barnaby Francis Dorrington William Gape Walter Lapp
and John Throckmorton Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s60">
			<head>For the Citty of London</head>
			<para id="p67">Sir John Robinson Knight and Baronet Lord Maior and the Maior for the time being Sir Thomas Adams Sir
Richard Browne Sir Thomas Allen Knights and Baronets Sir John Fredericke Knight and Richard Cheverton
Aldermen Sir William Wilde Knight and Baronet one of His Majestyes Sergeants at Law and Recorder of the said
Citty Sir Abraham Cullen Baronet Sir William Tompson Sir John Lawrence Sir Anthony Bateman Sir Thomas
Chamberlaine Sir George Binion Sir Theophilus Biddolph Sir George Smith Sir Thomas Bludworth Sir William
Turner and Sir Andrew King Sir Richard Ford Knights Sir William Wale Sir William Bateman Knights John
Jones Es&bhoqesq; Francis Meynell John Saunders William Bolton Aldermen George Noeds Deputy Alderman Thomas
Gore Henry Dunster John Jolliffe Thomas Turgis Robert Lant Edward Clagget Thomas Bromfeild Esquiers Richard
Mills Es&bhoqesq; Treasurer of St Bartholimewes Hospitall Robert Bidolph Nicholas Penning Benjamine Albin Richard
Spencer Edward Arris Thomas Canham Esquiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s61">
			<head>For the County of Monmouth</head>
			<para id="p68">Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland William Lord Herbert of Cardiffe Sir Edward Morgan Sir Trever Williams Sir
Thomas Morgan Baronets Sir George Probert Sir Bainham Throckmorton Knights Thomas Morgan of Tredegar
William Morgan of the same William Jones of Treowen Edward Progers Charles Proger-Herbert Henry Baker Edmond
Morgan Harry Probarts Thomas Lewis of St Peere William Morgan of Pencreeke Thomas Hughes Thomas Morgan
of Penrose Charles Hughes Charles Van of Coldrey William Herbert William Jones Lewis Morgan Henry Morgan
of Penlloyn-search Roger Oates Edward Kemys of Bertholey Roger Williams Henry Chambers Philip Cecill George
Gwyn John Parry James Prichard of Campson Thomas Williams of Carlion Walter Morgan of Landilo Walter Rumsey
John Walter Esquiers George Morgan of Pulhead Christopher Perkins John Rumsey William Williams Roger Aldy
Gentlemen and the Maior of the Towne of Monmouth for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s62">
			<head>For the County of Northampton</head>
			<para id="p69">Robert Viscount Mandevill Obrian Viscount Cullen Charles Lord [de le<ref idref="n43">43</ref>] Spencer George Mountague Edward
Mountague Christopher Hatton Esquiers Sir Thomas Crew Robert Spencer Es&bhoqesq; Sir Jeoffrey Palmer His Majestyes
Attourney Generall William Mountague Esq[uire] the Queenes Attourney Generall Sir Justinian Isham Sir Thomas Cave
Sir Samuell Danvers Sir Roger Norris Sir William Dudley Sir George Boswell Baronets Sir Edward Griffin Sir William
Fleetwood Sir Samuell Jones Sir John Bernard of Abingdon Sir James Langham Knights Sir Richard Rainsford Knight
Sergeant at Law Lewis Palmer William Stafford George Clarke Humphrey Orme Francis Lane Maurice Tresham
Ferdinando Marsham George Tresham Philip Holman John Cartwright William Coe William Bugby William Tate
Charles Proger Herbert William Downhall Richard Kinsman Miles Fleetwood Edward Onely John Syers William
Washborne Edward Palmer Edmond Sawyer Robert Clarke Thomas Cole George Wake John Browne Henry Edmonds
William Haslewood Robert Pergiter junior Bryan[Johnson<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] Christopher Pickering Tanfeild Mulsho Francis Crane
Edward Harby junior Walter Kirkham John Ward Richard Nailer Thomas Roan Alexander Ekins Christopher
Thursby John Lynne Francis Kirkham Goddard Pemberton John Ekins John Delavall Henry Robinson of Caster
Esquiers William Langham Thomas Wright Do&bholigct;ors in Phisicke And the Maior of Higham Ferrers for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s63">
			<head>For the Towne of Northampton</head>
			<para id="p70">The Maior for the time being Thomas Thornton Edward Collis Jonathan Whiston Aldermen Salathiell Lovell
James Coles Esquiers Mr William Kimbole Mr John Bromfeild and Mr William Vaughan.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s64">
			<head>For the County of Nottingham</head>
			<para id="p71">Henry Lord Mansfeild Gilbert Lord Haughton Anchetill Gray Es&bhoqesq; William Pierrepoint Es&bhoqesq; Partricius Lord Chaworth
Sir Jervis Clifton Knight and Baronet Sir George Savill Sir William Hickman Baronets Arthur Stanhop William Byron
Esquiers Sir Clifford Clifton Knight Sir Thomas Williamson Sir William Willoughby Sir Francis Mullenaux Baronets
Sir John Digby Knight Anthony Eyre Francis Leeke Robert Pierrepoint William Stanhop John Grubham How William
Palmer Cecill Cooper Isham Perkins William Harboard Anthony Gilby Francis Sandis Francis Stringer Penniston
Whalley William Sacheverell Thomas Women Thomas Charlton James Moseley William Clarkson William Cartwright
Acton Burnell William Sandys Rowland Dan William Willoughby and Thomas Roffell Esquiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s65">
			<head>For the Towne of Nottingham</head>
			<para id="p72">The Maior for the time being Arthur Stanhop Es&bhoqesq; Sir Jervas Cliffton Knight and Baronet Robert Pierrepoint Es&bhoqesq;
Sir Clifford Clifton Knight Charles Hutchinson Anthony Eyre William [Sheffington<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] Esquiers George Gregory Samuell
Staples John Parker Gentlemen Francis Toplady John Toplady William Greaves and Ralph Edge Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s66">
			<head>For the Towne of Newarke upon Trent</head>
			<para id="p73">The Maior for the time Anthony Eyre Francis Leake Edward Bigland Es s Rcert Atkinson Christopher Hassome
Leviret Jennison and Richard Mason Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s67">
			<head>For the County of Norfolke</head>
			<para id="p74">Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the House of Commons Thomas Lord Richardson Sir John Tracy Knight
Sir Edmond Bacon Sir John Hobard Sir [William<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] Woodhouse Sir Charles Mordant Sir Richard Berney Sir Henry
Jernegan Sir Edward Barkham Sir Nicholas L'Strange Sir John Holland Sir Robert Paston Sir Ralph Hare Sir John
Potts Sir John Palgrave Sir Thomas Pettus Sir Robert Kempe Sir Francis Bickley Sir Jacob Ashley Sir Thomas
Deerham Sir William Gaudy Baronets Sir Miles Hobart Sir John Knivett Sir Christopher Calthrope Sir Edward
Walpoole Knights of the Bath Sir Charles Harbord Sir William Doyley Sir Thomas Guybon Sir William Hovell
Sir Allen Apsley Sir Thomas Rant Sir Joseph Payne Sir Thomas Meddows Sir William Hewet Sir Justinian Lewin
Sir Nevil Catlin Knights Erasmus Earle Sergeant at Law John Cooke James de Gray John Hobart Robert Gawsell
William Adams Thomas Le Grosse John Windham Edward Barkham Augustine Palgrave John Potts Thomas Holland
William Doyley Maurice Skelton William Guybon Roger Spelman Philip Harbord Peter Gleane Thomas Gawdy of
Claxton Thomas Barney William Crane Robert Yallop Anthony Freeston Leonard Mapps William Cooke senior William
Cooke junior Robert Sucklin William Barker Thomas Adams Edward Pepis Oliver Neave Phillip Beddingfeild Francis
Bacon Thomas Bacon L'Strange Calthorpe Robert Long Robert Baldock Robert Steward John Earle Francis Cory
Christopher Jay Sucklin Jay Thomas Cory Robert Haughton John Kendall John Repps Robert Kerrington. Henry
Repps Lawrence Oxburgh Richard Godfrey John Anguish William Brampton William Branthwaite Nicholas Rockewood
Edward Barber Nicholas Stileman Thomas Talbot Jacob Preston Anthony Drury John Flowerdew Robert Drury Thomas
Drury Charles Gawdy Bassingborne Gaudy William Davy James Long Nathaniell Knivet William Rant Edmond
Brittiffe Charles [Stotterton<ref idref="n47">47</ref>] Edward Denny Edward Chamberlin William Nickson Robert London John Baspoole John
Bladwell William Bladwell Simon Brittiffe Thomas Wright George Townesend Thomas Townesend Edmond de Gray
Robert Haughton Francis Butler Thomas Dye Humphrey Beddingfeild Francis Thoresby Samuell Smith Samuell
Harsenet Robert Coney Leonard Gooch Thomas Browne of Elsmy Robert Doughty of Hamworth Robert Tyrell of
Wilton Esquiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s68">
			<head>For the Towne of Thetford</head>
			<para id="p75">The Maior for the time being Sir William Gaudy Baronet Sir Allen Apsley Knight Maurice Shelton Es&bhoqesq; Bourage
Martin Osmond Clarke Robert Tirrell John Kendall Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s69">
			<head>For the Citty of Norwich</head>
			<para id="p76">The Maior for the time being Sir Joseph Paine Knight Francis Cory Recorder William Watts Steward Richard
Wenman John Rawling Bernard Chruch John Man John Salter Christopher Jay John Osborne John Croshold Esquiers
The two Sheriffes for the time being William Heyward Augustine Briggs Thomas Wisse Robert Bendish John Lawrence
Richard Cowldham Francis Norris James Long Henry Herne William Tooke Henry Woods Henry Watts junior John
Mansee Mathew Markon Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s70">
			<head>For the Towne of Lynne Regis</head>
			<para id="p77">The Maior for the time being Robert Steward Es&bhoqesq; John Bird Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Greene John Basse Benjamine Holly
Walter Kirby William Wharton Thomas Robinson Lawrence Withers Henry Bell Goodwin
Abbot Mathias Twelves Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s71">
			<head>For the Towne of Yarmouth</head>
			<para id="p78">The Bayliffes for the time being Sir Thomas Meadow Robert Baldocke Esq[uire] Recorder Arthur Bacon Thomas Gouch
Abraham Castle John Rowe John Woodruffe Nathaniell Ashby George England Richard Huntington Edmond Thaxter
Thomas Greenwood John Hall Thomas Puppett Thomas Greenwood William Bateman.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s72">
			<head>For the County of Northumberland</head>
			<para id="p79">Henry Lord Viscount Mansfeild Sir William Fenwicke of Wellington Baronet Edward Widrington of Felton Es&bhoqesq;
Sir Ralph Delavall of Seaton Delavall Sir Cuthbert Heron of Chipchase Baronets Sir Thomas Widdrington Sir Robert
Collingwood of Brampton Sir William Foster of Bambrough Sir Henry Widdrington of Backhadin Knights Robert
Delivall of Dissington Thomas Forster of Edderston James Ogle of Cawsey Parke William Strother of Grimden Rigg
William Widdrington of Bolton John Roddan of Litle Haughton William Fenwick of Bywell Ralph Heborne of
Heborne William Delavall of Bewick Thomas Lawren of Kirdeherle Ralph Jennison of Elswicke Robert Widdrington
of Auxley John Ridley of Willemonswike Ralph Gray of Bradford William Carr of Eshott Nicholas Whitehead of
Burston John Salkeild senior of Rocke Esq[uire]s Michaell Widdrington of Morpeth Gentleman The Bayliffes of the
Burrough of Morpeth for the time being Daniel Collingwood Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s73">
			<head>For the Towne of Newcastle upon Tyne</head>
			<para id="p80">The Maior of the said Towne for the time being Sir Francis Anderson Knight the present Maior Sir John
[Morley<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] Knight Sir James Clavering Baronet Robert Shaftoe Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Robert Shaftoe Marke Milbankes John
Emerson Henry Maddison Aldermen Henry Brabent Sheriffe Richard Scot Esquiers Mr Robert Marbay Towne Clarke
Mr Ralph Carr Sir Nicholas Cole Baronet.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s74">
			<head>For the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede</head>
			<para id="p81">The Maior for the time being Andrew Moore Es&bhoqesq; the present Maior Sir Thomas Widdrington Knight Coll
Edward Gray Sir William Forster Knight Benjamine Clarke Ralph Hebburne Es?s Thomas Watson Alderman, The
Bayliffes for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s75">
			<head>For the County of Oxford</head>
			<para id="p82">Henry Viscount Cornbury Thomas Earle of Down Thomas Viscount [Wainman<ref idref="n49">49</ref>] David Walter Es&bhoqesq; one of the
Groomes of His Majesties Bedchamber Sir Anthony Cope Sir Thomas Chamberline Sir Francis Henry Lea Sir Thomas
Penniston Sir William Walter Baronets Sir Francis Norris Knight Sir John Clarke Knight and Baronet Sir Edward
Norris Knight Sir Francis [Waynman<ref idref="n49">49</ref>] Knight and Baronet Sir John Fettiplace Sir Compton Reade Baronets Sir William
Moreton Knight Sergeant at Law Sir Thomas Spencer Baronet Sir William Fleetwood Sir Timothy Tyrrell Sir
Thomas Typping Knights William Knollis Broome [Horwood<ref idref="n50">50</ref>] Richard Croope Thomas Saunders Anthony Libb Henry
Alnut John Stone Francis Martin Edmond Lenthall John Clarke William Dormer Vincent Barrey Esquiers Sir George
Crooke Knight Sir William Glyn Sir Philip Harcourt Baronets John Cartwright George Chamberlaine William
Cartwright William Sheppeard Thomas Wheate Robert Dormer Rowland Lacey Samuel Sandys junior Litleton
Osbaldiston Regnold Bray William Baley Thomas Hoord John Doyley Charles Holloway Sergeant at Law Richard
Hallaway William Weight Thomas Coventry John Harris William Tayler John Wickham William Hamersby William
Oakeley Esquiers The Maior of Woodstocke The Maior of Banbury The Warden of Henley, The Bayliffes of Chipping
Norton and Burford and The Cheife Magistrate of any other Corporation within the said County to a&bholigct; within
their severall and respective [Towne<ref idref="n51">51</ref>] and Corporations onely.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s76">
			<head>For the Citty of Oxford</head>
			<para id="p83">The Maior for the time being Sir Anthony Cope Baronet William Knollis Esquire Sir Thomas Clayton Sir Sampson
White Knights Broome Whorwood Es&bhoqesq; John Fell Doctor in Divinity Richard Croke Recorder George Low Esquiers
Francis Harris Martin Wright Leonard Bowman William Wright Roger Griffin Aldermen William Bayley Francis
Heyward John White Francis Grenoway John Townesend John Harris Robert Worwood Richard Pratt Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s77">
			<head>For the County of Rutland</head>
			<para id="p84">Bennet Lord Sherrard Edward Noell Henry Noell Philip Sherard Esquiers Sir Edward Heath Sir Richard Wingfeild
Sir Eusebius Pelsant Alexander Noell Abell Barker Samuell Browne Edward Palcker Esquiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s78">
			<head>For the County of Surrey</head>
			<para id="p85">Charles Earle of Ancram Sir Robert Foster Cheife Justice of His Majesties Court of Kings Bench Sir Henry Capell
[Knight<ref idref="n52">52</ref>] of the Bath Sir Adam Browne Sir Francis Vincent Sir Thomas Trevor Sir Walter St Johns Baronets Sir
William Tyrringham Knight of the Bath Sir William Moore Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir Abraham Cullen Baronets
Sir Richard Onslow Sir Edmond Bowyer Sir Charles Howard Sir John Evelin Sir William Haward Sir Daniell Harvey
Sir Robert Parkhurst Sir John Mainard Sir Nicholas Carew Sir Richard Hatton Sir Edward Bish Sir Ralph Freeman
Sir Edmond Hoskins Sir John Lloyd Sir William Throckmorton Sir Thomas Thinne Sir Purbecke Temple Knights
William Turner Do&bholigct;or of the Law Robert Phillips Arthur Onslow Edward Thurland Roger James John Scott
George Chute Christopher Buckle Thomas Foster Henry Hilliard William Elliot Anthony Bowyer George Evelin
Anthony Thomas Edward Evelin Richard Evelin William Oldfeild William Hoskins George Browne Henry Weston
William Muschampe John Thynne Thomas Turgis Roger Duncombe George Duncombe George Vernon Esquiers
Do&bholigct;or Windebanke George Smith George Duke Mathew Carleton Thomas Lee Es&bhoqesq; Peter Hussey Lawrence Marsh
Thomas Rogers Samuell Rowse Roger Clarke William Wymondsall Roger [Pelliwood<ref idref="n53">53</ref>] George [Woodfroste<ref idref="n54">54</ref>] John
Heather Richard Ward Robert Holman John Parker John Jones Gentlemen</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s79">
			<head>For the Burrough of Southwarke</head>
			<para id="p86">Sir John Bromfeild Sir John Lenthall Sir Edmond Bowyer Sir Thomas Bludworth Sir James Austin George Moore
Edward Smith Esquiers Edmond Warcup Es&bhoqesq; Mr John Neale Mr John Luntley Mr William Lock Mr Edward Ball
Mr William Whitworth Mr George Maggot Mr William Burton Mr Jonathan Buck.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s80">
			<head>For the County of Stafford</head>
			<para id="p87">Sir John Bowyer Knight and Baronet High Sheriffe Sir Edward Litleton Baronet Randolph Egerton Es&bhoqesq; Sir
Thomas Wilbraham Sir Edward Bagget Sir Walter Wrotesley Sir Francis Lawley Sir Bryan Broughton Baronets
Sir John Wyrley [Knight<ref idref="n52">52</ref>] William Snead Henry Gray Walter Chetwind senior John Lane Walter Chetwind junior
George Digby Broome Whorwood Esquires Sir Walter Litleton Sir Theophilus Biddolph Sir Thomas Whitgrave
Knights Rowland Oakeover Edward Manwairing Charles Cotton John Skrimshire Gerard Skrimshire Richard
Congreeve Robert Milward William Chetwin Thomas Kinnersly John Pearsehouse Jonathan Woodnorth Jonathan
Cope John Swinfin Robert Levison Rowland Cotton Henry Archbold George Parker Henry Vernon John Whitehall
Francis Wightwick Mathew Moreton Ferrers Fowke Edward Arablaster William Orme Edward Birch John Shelton
Esquiers Samuell Hinton Doctor of the Lawes Thomas Pudsey of [Charley<ref idref="n55">55</ref>] William Farmer Richard Bracegirdle
John Gough John Woollaston William Smallwood John Birch John Colclough Timothy Edge Gentlemen, The
Maior of Stafford for the time being, The Maior of Newcastle for the time being, The Bayliffes of Tamworth for
the time being, The Maior of Walshall for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s81">
			<head>For the Citty and County of the Citty of Litchfeild.</head>
			<para id="p88">The Bayliffes and Sheriffe for the time being Sir Walter Litleton Knight Michael Biddolph Richard Dyott Henry
Archbold John Hill Esquiers Thomas Caterbanke Henry Boylstone William Jesson Gen&bhotcrl; Samuell Hinton Do&bholigct;or
of the Law Anthony Hewet Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke William Whitby Es&bhoqesq;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s82">
			<head>For the County of Salop</head>
			<para id="p89">Andrew Newport Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Woolrich Sir William Whitmore Sir Henry Vernon Sir Francis Lawley Sir
Walter Acton Baronets Sir Richard Prince Sir John Weld Sir Richard Oately Sir Clement Throckmorton Sir
William Childe Sir Job Charleton Sergeant at Law and Cheife Justice of Chester Knights Timothy Litleton Sergeant
at Law Sir Vincent Corbet William Fowler Timothy Turner Philip E&bholigct;on Richard Screven Richard Fowler Francis
Thornes James Lacon Francis Charleton Robert Sandford Robert Leighton Phillip Prince Robert Charleton John
Lacon Henry Goodrick Samuell Winkefeild Thomas Whitmore George Ludlow Edward Latwich Edward Baldwin
Charles Baldwin Henry Bernard Thomas Powis Thomas Holland John Coates William Oakeley [Edward<ref idref="n56">56</ref>] Wareing of
Oldbury Thomas Lloyd Esquiers Captaine Philip Jenings John Corbet Richard Ridley Somerset Fox John Walcost
Thomas Crumpe William Owen of Perkington Robert Owen Thomas Lockier John Newton Vincent Edwards Esquiers
Roger Gough John Bawdwin of Midlehope Gen&bhotcrl; Thomas Walcolt Rowland Hill Charles Mainwairing William
Cotton Andrew Hill Francis Smith Francis Forrester junior Robert Cresset Richard Lister Esquiers Daniell Wicherley
Humphrey Grove Henry Griffiths Richard Baggott Francis Walker Alexander Midleton John Baugh Richard
Walker Gen&bhotcrl; The Bayliffes of Bridgenorth for the time-being The Bayliffe of the Franchise of Wenlocke for
the time being, The Bayliffes of Bishops Castle for the time being, The Bayliffes for Ludlow for the time being
Richard Davis Thomas Jones of Sheete and William Bowdler Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s83">
			<head>For the Towne of Shrewsbury</head>
			<para id="p90">The Maior for the time being Timothy Tourner Recorder Thomas Rocke Robert Leighton Jonathan Langley
Adam Oateley Thomas Bawdewin Thomas Jones Robert Corbert of the Hall of Hussey Samuell Wingfeild Richard
Tayler John Harding Arthur Hinks Richard Clarke Samuell Lloyd Andrew Vivers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s84">
			<head>For the County of Southampton</head>
			<para id="p91">Charles Lord St John of Basing Henry Lord Pawlet Sir Robert Howard Knight Sir Henry Worseley Sir John
Mill Sir John Norton Sir Hugh Stewkley Sir William Lewis Sir Thomas Badd Sir Nicholas Stuart Sir Andrew
Henley Sir John Trott Baronets Sir Humphrey Bennet Sir Robert Mason Sir Philip Honywood Sir Thomas Higgons
Knights Richard Norton Henry Wallop Lawrence Hyde James May Leonard Bilson Arthur Bold Thomas Cole
Bartholimew Price John Stewkley Richard Goddard of Winton Edward Hooper of Chilworth Edward Fleming
Thomas Knowlett Francis Roules John Woldrich Thomas Jarvoys William Wither High Sheriffe Humphrey Weld
Richard Compton Thomas Knollis Philip Lee Edward Hooper of Hurne Court Henry Tulse Roger Gallop Henry
Whitehead Thomas Brookes Giles Hungerford Benjamine Ruddiard Robert Oxenbridge Richard Lucy Edward
Norton Robert Warcupp Thomas Neale George Pitt Nicholas Bowell John Deane Daniell Kingsmill John Kingsmill
Nicholas Venables Gabriell Whistler Esquiers Samuell Holmes John Duke John Rivers Gentlemen, The Maior of
Portsmouth for the time being, The Maior of Basing Stooke for the time being, The Bayliffe of Andover for the
time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s85">
			<head>For the Isle of Wight</head>
			<para id="p92">Sir Henry Worsley Sir Robert Dillington Sir William Meux Baronets Sir John Leigh Knight Sir John Barington
Robert Dillington John Richards William Oglander John Worseley senior Edward Worsley Francis Leigh Richard
Lucy Es?s.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s86">
			<head>For the Citty of Winchester</head>
			<para id="p93">The Maior for the time being Nicholas Purdue James Guy John Mondy Richard Dennet John Fifeild Gen&bhotcrl;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s87">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Southampton</head>
			<para id="p94">Robert Richkell Maior Roger Gallop Esq&bholigct; Edward Exton Peter Clungeon Henry Pitt William Stanley Joseph
Delamot Thomas Cornellis William Horne James Clungeon Gen&bhotcrl;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s88">
			<head>For the County of Suffolke</head>
			<para id="p95">Sir Edward Turner Speaker of the House of Commons Sir Dudley North Knight of the Bath Walter Devereux
Esq[uire] Sir Edmond Bacon Sir Lyonell Tolemache Sir Henry Felton Sir John Holland Sir John Barker Sir Robert
Kempe Sir John Castleton Sir William Spring Sir Henry Bacon Sir Henry North Sir Thomas Darcy Sir Robert
Cordell Sir Jervas Elwis Sir John Rous Sir John Warner Sir John Crofts Sir Robert Brooke Sir Philip Parker Sir
Samuell Bernardiston Sir William Gawdy Baronets Sir William Playters Sir Henry Wood Sir Charles Gaudy Sir
Edward Duke Sir George Reve Sir Thomas Bernadiston Knights and Baronets Sir John Knivett Sir Nicholas Bacon
Knights of the Bath Sir Henry Crofts Sir William Poley Sir Philip Parker Sir [Edward<ref idref="n57">57</ref>] Poley Sir William Doyley Sir
John Duncombe Sir Robert Brooke Sir John Pettus Sir Thomas Smith Sir Thomas Harvey Sir Thomas Ogle Sir
William Bloys Sir Jeoffrey [Butwell<ref idref="n57">57</ref>] Sir George Weneve Sir Nevil [Charling<ref idref="n59">59</ref>] Sir Algernon May Knights Robert
Wright John Harvey Thomas Holland Thomas Cullum Thomas Walgrave Maurice Barrow John Duke John Poley of
Stowmarket John Poley of Boxsted Wiseman Bockenham Charles [Sentivill<ref idref="n60">60</ref>] Richard Coke Benjamin Cutler of the
Chauntry Fitz-non Lambe William Bloyes Henry Warner John Sicklemore Francis Burwell Thomas Stewart Henry
Parker Arthur Jenny John Sotheby Charles Cornewallis Joseph Brand Thomas Edgar Edmond Harvey Thomas Tirrell
William Dawtree Thomas Dade of Tannington Thomas Scrivener Edward Feilder William Blomfeild Robert Marriot
Henry Coppenger Gardner Web Hamond Claxton Clement Heigham Philip Howard Robert Butts Thomas Butts
Francis Cheney Robert Nanton Edmond Clench the younger Michaell Grigg John Barker John Bedingfeild Henry
Bedingfeild William Gooche William Brewse James With Thomas Wood Samuell Alston John Lambe Henry North
of Laxfeild Edward North Framingham Gaudy Peregrine Doyley Thomas Vesey James Cob Thomas Wright John
Cole Robert [Malliwood<ref idref="n61">61</ref>] Robert King Doctor of Law Thomas Arris Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Borrowdale Millecent Joseph
Beaumont John Bence [Roswid<ref idref="n62">62</ref>] John Playters Robert Pembrig John Brame of Ash junior John Rivet Edward
Brampton Edward Spencer Francis Theobald Edmond Farneley William Gibbs. Thomas Day Henry Stecking John
Thuston Robert Stile Thomas Bacon Thomas Leman William Goodwin Miles Edgar Erward Man the younger
Thomas Man Barnaby Gibson Thomas Read Robert Brownrig William Jermy Richard Kirby Esquiers The Maior of
Sudbury for the time being, The Maior of Hadley for the time being, The Maior of Orford for the time being
The Bayliffes of Dunwich for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s89">
			<head>For the Towne of Ipswich</head>
			<para id="p96">The Bayliffes for the time being Sir Henry Felton Baronet Sir Manuell Sorrell Knight William Bloyes Es&bhoqesq;
John Sicklemore. Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Nicholas Philips John Robinson Robert Sparrow John Wright Gilbert Lyndfeild
Robert Clarge Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s90">
			<head>For the Burrough of St Edmonds Bury</head>
			<para id="p97">The Alderman for the time being Robert Sharpe Gen&bhotcrl; Sir Edmond Poley Sir John Duncombe Knights John
Sothesby Es&bhoqesq; Recorder James Kobbs Stephen Cooke Francis Browne Samuell Huftler Gen&bhotcrl;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s91">
			<head>For the Towne of Aldborough</head>
			<para id="p98">Sir John Holland Baronet Sir Robert Brooke Knight The Bayliffes for the time being [William<ref idref="n63">63</ref>] Shipman Mr Elliot,
Mr Barwood Mr Wall junior.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s92">
			<head>For the County of Somerset</head>
			<para id="p99">Sir John Warre Knight High Sheriffe Francis Lord Hawley Sir Charles Berkley Knight Treasurer of His Majestyes
Household Sir Thomas Mallet Knight one of the Justices of the Kings Bench John Pawlet Francis Pawlet (<ref idref="n64">64</ref>) Amos
Pawlet [Esquiers<ref idref="n65">65</ref>] Sir William Portman Sir Maurice Berkley Sir Hugh Smith Sir William Wyndham Knights and
Baronets Sir John Sidenham Sir George Trevilliam Baronets Sir John Coventry Sir Edward Hungerford Knights
of the Bath Sir Henry Berkley Sir Thomas Bridges Sir Hugh Windham Sir George Norton Sir George Horner
Sir William Basset Sir Edward Wingfeild Sir Thomas Gore Knights John Merefeild Sergeant at Law Alexander
Popham George Stawell Edward Phillips Edmond Windham William Prynne George Speake Francis Lutrell
Peregrine Palmer Henry Rogers Francis Windham Edward Berkley Maurice Berkley Samuell Gorges John Tint
John Mallet Edward Phelips junior William Heliar Angell Gray Ralph Stawell Robert Hawley George Sidenham
John Buckland Thomas Warr William Bull Robert Hunt Michaell Mallet John Churchell Warwicke Bampfeild
Anthony Pawlet William Harboard Kingsmill Lucy William Lucy Henry Waldron Thomas Windham of Wicham
Francis Vaughan William Clarke Edward Clarke Thomas Harwell Henry Bull of Mid-summer-Norton Esquiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s93">
			<head>For the Citty of Bath</head>
			<para id="p100">The Maior for the time being William Prynne Es&bhoqesq; John Masters Alderman Henry Parker Robert Penny Edward
White John Reade Walter Gibbs Alderman John Chapman Henry Chapman Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s94">
			<head>For the Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll.</head>
			<para id="p101">The Maior for the time being Sir Robert Cann Knight and Baronet Sir Robert Atkins Knight of the Bath
Recorder John Locke Richard Balman Henry Creswicke William Colson Nathaniel Cale Walter Sandy John
Knight Aldermen The Sheriffes for the time being John Pope John Lawford John Wright Robert Yeomans
Christopher Griffith John Bradway John Willoughby Thomas Langton Thomas Stevens John Hicks Sir Humphrey
Hooke John Knight junior.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s95">
			<head>For the County of Sussex</head>
			<para id="p102">Thomas Leonard John Ashburnham Esquiers Sir Thomas Pelham Sir John Stapeley Sir John Covet Sir Walter
Hendley Sir Denny Ashburnham Sir William Thomas Sir John Fagg Sir Cecill Bishop Baronets Sir John Lewkner
Sir William Morley Knights of the Bath Sir Thomas Dike Sir Thomas Woodcocke Sir Thomas Nutt Sir George
Courtop Sir John Morley Sir Henry Peckham Knights Henry Goreing Percy Goreing William Garway John Steward
George Nevill Thomas Sackvile Herbert Morley Edward Blaker Henry Chawne Thomas Palmer Robert Anderson
Nisel Rivers George Parker Richard Lindsey Sackvile Graves Edward May John May Walter Evernden William
Gratwicke Thomas Gray John Farrington Thomas Bestworth Bruin Bickley Richard Cooper Ralph Mill Thomas Midleton
Symon Smith John Jones Charles Brett Richard Bridgar Walter Burrell Henry West Edward Keeling William Spence
Edward Polhill [Thomas Luxford Robert Fowle<ref idref="n66">66</ref>] John De-la-Chambre John Baker of Stonelud Nicholas Gildridge
Richard Sheppard John Paine Allan Carr Anthony Sherley Esquiers John Gratwick of Eatons William Scace John
Bagshall Christopher Coles Thomas Barnard William Markewricke William Palmer Richard Mills Gent The Maior
of Arundell for the time being Robert Palmer Nicholas Cooke Thomas Hudson Mathew Young William Westbrooke
Richard Nash John Eversfeild senior William Gratwick of Jervas Gen&bhotcrl; Bray Showne Es&bhoqesq; Joseph Newington Allan
Carr Edward Mitchell Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s96">
			<head>For the Citty of Chichester</head>
			<para id="p103">Marke Miller Es&bhoqesq; Maior of Chichester Thomas Leonard Es&bhoqesq; Sir Henry Peckham Knight William Garway Robert
Anderson John Farrington Esquiers Richard Young Nicholas Exton Aldermen Allan Carr Gentleman.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s97">
			<head>For the County of Westmerland</head>
			<para id="p104">Sir Philip Musgrave Sir John Lowther Sir John Lowther Sir Thomas Strickland John Lowther Daniell Fleming
Allan Bellingham Richard Braithwaite John Dalston Christopher Crakenthrope James Ducket Robert Hilton [Christopher
Musgrave Richard Musgrave<ref idref="n67">67</ref>] Richard Braithwaite Thomas Samford Lancelot Machell Nicholas Fisher Thomas Gebetas
Edward Nephinson Thomas Braithwaite John Otway Henry Wilson Edward Wilson William Midleton Esquiers Richard
Duckat Gen&bhotcrl; The Maior of Apleby for the time being; The Maior of Kendall for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s98">
			<head>For the County of Wilts.</head>
			<para id="p105">Henry Lord Herbert John Lord Seymour William Lord Herbert Henry Viscount Cornebury Sir Edward Nicholas
one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councell Edward Howard James Mountague Charles Seymour Esquiers
Sir Robert Hyde one of the Justices of the Co&bhouov;mon Pleas Sir Wadham Windham one of the Justices of the Kings
Bench Sir Walter St John Sir Seymour Pile Sir George Grubham-Howe Sir Walter [Earlue<ref idref="n68">68</ref>] Baronets Sir John Coventry
Sir John Nicholas Sir Edward Hungerford Sir [John<ref idref="n69">69</ref>] Baynton Knights of the Bath Sir James Thynne Sir [James<ref idref="n70">70</ref>] Evelin
Sir John Talbot Sir Edward Poole Sir George Hungerford Sir John Low Sir Thomas Escourt Sir Henry Coker Sir
Thomas Ivy Sir William Cally Sir Thomas Mompesson Knights Alexander Popham Edward Seymour Robert Phillips
Richard Grubham Howe Richard Lewis Francis Wroughton John Erule senior William Glanvile Henry Clerke John
Pleydell William Jordan John [Earlue<ref idref="n68">68</ref>] junior Edward Nicholas Thomas Bennet George Ayliffe Edward Hungerford
Walter Long William Pawlet Ralph Freke Edward Hyde Edward Tooker William Ducket William Brounker Henry
Hungerford Henry Baynton Walter Brockeland George Bond Edmond Warneford Thomas Mompesson Gilbert Rawley
Edward Goddard of Standon Alexander Thistlewaite junior William Yorke Jeoffrey Daniell Thomas [Wincklin<ref idref="n71">71</ref>] John
Kent John Collins Thomas Gore James Ash John Foyle John Norden Henry Long Richard Harrison Richard
Aldworth Edward Topp Thomas Hawles Joseph Stockman Giles Eyre William Willoughby John Long John Eyre
Samuell Eyre John Bowles Rowland Platt Richard Escourt George Ivy William Swanton Robert Chaundler Thomas
Hungerford Thomas Lambert Thomas Pile Richard Southby Nevill Maskeline Edward Goddard of Ogborne John
Danvers Seymour Bowman Henry Wallis Edmond Webb Walter Parker Benjamine Gifford Isaac Burges William
Sadler Richard Greene John Mompesson John Fitz-herbert Robert Chaloner Esquiers The Maior of the Devises for
the time being, The Maior of Marleborough for the time being, the Maior of Wilton for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s99">
			<head>For the Citty of New Sarum</head>
			<para id="p106">The Maior for the time being Sir Robert Hyde one of the Justices of the Common Pleas Sir Wadham Windham
one of the Justices of the Kings Bench Mr Seymour Bowman Mr Maurice Greene Mr William Slaune Sir Thomas
Mompesson Edward Tooker William Swanton Richard Davy John Holt Symon Spatchurst Esq[uire]s Mr William Joyce
Mr Thomas Oviat Mr James Harward Stephen Fox Thomas Chaffin Thomas Hawles Richard Coleman Esquiers
Thomas Gardner Gen&bhotcrl;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s100">
			<head>For the County of Worcester</head>
			<para id="p107">Sir John Packington Sir Henry Litleton Sir William Russell Sir Edward Seabright Sir William Kite Baronets Sir
Ralph Clare Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Herbert Sir Rowland Berkley Sir John Winfrid Sir John Talbot Knights
William Sandys Samuell Sandys senior Samuell Sandys junior Edward Pitt Sherrington Talbot Henry Bromely of Holt
Thomas Savage of Elmby Castle Francis Finch Thomas Child Henry Bromley of Upton John Minfun Henry Jefferyes
Joseph Walsh of Aberley Philip Bruce William Washburne Richard Dowdeswell Thomas Wild Edward Vernon, John
Bearecroft Edward Pemmell Thomas Streete George Symonds Theophilus Andrewes Edward Carew of Litleton
Thomas Hall Thomas Vernon Francis Sheldon of Aberton Phillip Parsons Edward Bushell Walter Savage of Broadway
William Sheldon of Broadway Henry Spiller Edward Dingley Parrot of Bell-Broughton junior Henry Litleton
of Newton William Cookes Gerrard Dunnet Henry Townesend Henry Evett Esquiers The Bayliffes of Wich for the
time being The Maior of Evesham for the time being, The Bayliffe of Bewdley for the time being William Mucklow
Francis Winington William Hancock Esq[uire]s.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s101">
			<head>For the Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester.</head>
			<para id="p108">The Maior, Aldermen and Sheriffe for the time being Sir Rowland Berkeley Sir William Moreton Knights one of
His Majestyes Sergeants at Law Thomas Hall Thomas Streete Thomas Vernon Esquiers Robert Wilde Humphrey
Wildey Richard Bedors Francis Hughes Humphrey Tyrer, John Bearecroft.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s102">
			<head>For the Burrough of Evesham</head>
			<para id="p109">The Maior for the time being Sir Abraham Cullen Baronet William Sandys Theophilus [Andres<ref idref="n72">72</ref>] Recorder
John Lunn William Watson Richard Bartley William Mathewes Aldermen and Capitall Burgesses</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s103">
			<head>For the County of Warwicke</head>
			<para id="p110">Charles Leigh Es&bhoqesq; Sir Robert Holt Sir Richard Temple Sir Henry Puckering alias Newton Sir Clement Fisher Sir
Roger Burgoyne Sir Edward Broughton Sir John Knightley Sir Thomas Norton Baronets Sir William Bromley Sir Stephen
Hales Knights of the Bath Sir George Devereux Sir Francis Willoughby Sir Charley Adderley Sir Charles Lee Sir Arthur
Caley Sir William Underhill Sir Combe Wagstaffe Sir Richard Hopkins Sir Richard Bishop Sir John Clopton Knights
Richard Lucy John Bridgeman Walter Chetwin senior Thomas Archer Clement Throckmorton William Somerville
Sebright Repington Francis Ficher William Dilkes John Lisle William Purefoy Stephen Bolton Thomas Gibbs
Thomas Fisher John Rigley George Pudsey senior Harvey Bagott Richard Newdigate Sergeant at Law Thomas Temple
Basill Feilding Thomas Boughton John Rous Thomas Flint Charles Bentley Charles Newsham Richard Verney of
Kingston Giles Palmer Thomas Marriot John Fetherston Humphrey Jennings Mathew Holbich Thomas Rawlins
Nathaniell Brookes William Booth James Prescot Es?s Samuell [Dykes<ref idref="n73">73</ref>] John Mayne George Feilding Gen&bhotcrl; The
Bayliffe of Warwicke for the time being The Bayliffe of Stratford for the time being, The Bayliffes of Tamworth
for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s104">
			<head>For the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry.</head>
			<para id="p111">The Maior for the time being Sir Thomas Norton Baronet Sir Arthur Caley Sir Richard Hopkins Knights Edmond
Palmer Es&bhoqesq; Henry Smith Thomas Love Mathew Smith Samuell Snell Joseph Chambers James Nayler Julius Billiars
Thomas Pidgeon Humphrey Burton Aldermen William Jolliffe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s105">
			<head>For the County of Anglesey</head>
			<para id="p112">Robert Lord Viscount Bulkley Marke Lord Viscount Duncannon Thomas Bulkley Sir Hugh Owen Knight and
Baronet Nicholas Bagenall Thomas Wood Peirce Lloyd senior [Peirce Lloyd junior<ref idref="n74">74</ref>] Rowland Bulkley William Bold
John Robinson Griffith Jones of Trevarthin Hugh Owen Richard Meirick John Lloyd of Landeguin John Griffith of
Llunvaithly John [Wynore<ref idref="n75">75</ref>] of Bodewryde William Bulkley of Bronddu Henry Lloyd John Pritherch of Llysdelas
Rowland White Richard Owen Esquiers Hugh Hughes John Owens Llanvathley John Owens Penrhose Conisby
Williams Henry Jones Henry Davies William Williams Trearther Will Lewis Griffith Lloyd of Treaseph Edward Price
of Bodawir Edward Price of Trevadog Howell Lewis Owen Lloyd of Henblas John Williams of Bodurdin Owen
Owen of Trevillir Richard Wynne of Penheskine, The Maior of Beaumorice for the time being William Wynne of
Llangoed Owen Hughes William Hampton Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s106">
			<head>For the County of Brecon</head>
			<para id="p113">Henry Williams Es&bhoqesq; High Sheriffe Sir Herbert Price Sir William Lewis Sir Henry [William Lewes Sir Henry<ref idref="n76">76</ref>]
Williams Baronets Sir John Herbert Knight Edward Progers Es&bhoqesq; one of the Groomes of His Majestyes Bedchamber
William Morgan of Dderw George Gwyne Milburne Williams Lewis Morgan Thomas Lewis John Stedman Hugh
Powell William Morgan of Newton Walter Vaughan Thomas Williams Edward Powell James Watkins Henry Stedman
Meredith Lewes Lewis Gunter William Lloyd William Saunders Daniell Winter Edward Herbert Edward Proger of
Guernenald John Morgan Es?s, The Bayliffe of Brecon for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s107">
			<head>For the County of Cardigan</head>
			<para id="p114">Sir Richard Price Baronet Sir Francis Lloyd Knight James Lewes senior John Vaughan Henry Vaughan Morgan
Herbert Erasmus Lloyd James Stedman Edward Vaughan James Lewis junior Richard Herbert Reynold Jenkins
Thomas Jenkins John Jones John Lewes Thomas Evans David Lloyd Thomas Lloyd Esquiers The Maior of Cardigan
for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s108">
			<head>For the County of Carmarthen</head>
			<para id="p115">Francis Lord Vaughan Sir William Moreton Knight one of His Majestyes Sergeants at Law Symon Dege Sir John
Vaughan Knight of the Bath Sir Edward Mansell Sir William Russell Sir John Lloyd Baronets Sir Edward Rice Sir
Henry Vaughan Knights John Vaughan of Llannelly William Gwynne of Talliaris Nicholas Williams John Vaughan of
Court Derlis Richard Walter Henry Midleton James Jones of Tallacothy Penry Vaughan John Vaughan of Place
Gwynne junior Morgan Jones Philip Vaughan Thomas Lloyd of Berlandowell Thomas [Lloyd<ref idref="n77">77</ref>] of Cunguilly Thomas
Lloyd of Deveratt Owen Bruckstocke Thomas Lloyd of Lan Lowlocke John Powell of Lanarder junior Es?s.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s109">
			<head>For the Burrough of Carmarthen</head>
			<para id="p116">The Maior for the time being Francis Lord Vaughan Sir John Vaughan Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Vaughan
Knight John Vaughan of Llannelly John Vaughan of Court Derttis Es?s John Okely Anthony Jones Thomas Jones
Lewis Jones Gen&bhotcrl;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s110">
			<head>For the County of Carnarvan</head>
			<para id="p117">Robert Lord Viscount Bulckley Richard Cuffin High Sheriffe Robert Roberts of Bodvell Thomas Bulkley of Dinas
Esquiers Sir Richard Wynne of Gwidder Sir Griffith Williams of Vaynell Sir Roger Mostin of Mostin Sir Griffith
Williams of Penthrin Baronet Sir John Owen Sir Richard Lloyd Knights Griffith Jones Maurice Wynne William
Griffith of Lynne Hugh Wynne John Bodurda Thomas Vaughan William Hookes Robert Coytmore Robert Wynne
of Connoway Owen Griffith Owen Wynne of Glascord Hugh Williams William Wynne of Camunda William Williams
John Williams William Bulckley of Coytmore Robert Wynne of Sesselgy Farch Hugh Bodurda Griffith Bodurda
Richard Anwill of Hafodwryd Richard Griffith Richard Ellis Edmond Gwynne of Bryn-y Gwdion John Jones Trevan
William Spicer William Arthur Jeoffrew Williams John Wynne Pennarch Gent William Thomas Alderman of
Carnarvan Herbert Griffith Gen&bhotcrl;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s111">
			<head>For the County of Denbigh</head>
			<para id="p118">Sir Thomas Midleton Knight Sir Richard Wynne Sir John Salisbury Sir Thomas Powell Sir William Meredith
Baronets Sir Thomas Trevor Knight and Baronet Sir John Trevor Knight Sir Thomas Midleton Sir Evan Lloyd
Baronets Sir Richard Lloyd Sir Edward Broughton Sir Robert Towneshend Sir John Wynne Knights Roger Puleston
of Emeroll John Trevor of Trevalin William Owen William Price Hugh Wynne Mutton Davyes Robert Wynne of
Voylas Kenricke Eyton Charles Salisbury John Wynne John Robinson Bevis Lloyd John Thelwall senior John Edisbury
Charles Midleton Eubell Thelwall John Jefferyes Richard Midleton of Llansilin Robert Price John Thelwall junior
Edward Brereton Watkin Cuffin Owen Thelwall David Morris John Langford William Wynne of Gartigan William
Perry John Puleston Hugh Roberts George Bostocke Francis Manley Fowlke Midleton Hugh Lloyd of Foxhall
Gabriell Goodman Es?s Thomas Price of Geeler Edward Griffith of Henllam William Jones of Careghono John
Salisbury of Lliwesog Humphrey Lloyd of Berse Robert Wynne of Garthwynne Howell Lloyd Gent The two
Aldermen of Denbigh John Hughes Thomas Mathewes John Jones Robert Salisbury Gent.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s112">
			<head>For the County of Flint</head>
			<para id="p119">Sir Thomas Hanmer Knight and Baronet Sir John Salisbury Sir Henry Conway Baronets Sir Roger Mostin Knight
and Baronet Sir John Hanmer Knight Robert Davies Thomas Ravenscroft John Trevor Roger Puleston William
Hanmer Thomas Mostin Thomas Lloyd Mutton Davies Robert Whitley Peter Griffith Robert Mostin David Pennant
John Parry John Brougton William Griffith Evan Edwards John Lloyd Edward Lloyd Robert Wynne Richard Young
Thomas Cratchley Thomas Salisbury John Salisbury Charles Jones Owen Barton Es?s.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s113">
			<head>For the County of Glamorgan</head>
			<para id="p120">Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland William Lord Herbert of Cardiffe Sir Richard Lloyd Knight Arthur Trevor Es&bhoqesq;
Sir Edward Mansell Sir Edward Stradling Sir Edward Thomas Baronets Sir John Awbry Knight and Baronet Sir
William Lewis Sir Thomas Lewis Sir Richard Basset Knights Evan Seyes Sergeant at Law William Basset Doctor of
Lawes Robert Thomas Miles Button Thomas Lewis William Bassett of Bewpree William Herbert of Swansey Edmond
Thomas Bussey Mansell Herbert Evans Thomas Mathew Humphrey Windham David Jenkins Gabriell Lewis William
Thomas Thomas Stading Thomas Carue John Avan John Gibbs Thomas Thomas David Mathew Lamerock Stradling
Thomas Evans Edmond Gammage Richard Longher William Herbert of Killy Bebell John Carue Henry Basset
Edward Herbert of Cogan David Evans John Llewellin Es?s.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s114">
			<head>For the County of Merioneth</head>
			<para id="p121">Roger Mostin Es&bhoqesq; High Sheriffe Sir Richard Wynne Baronet Sir John Owen Sir Richard Lloyd Knights William
Salisbury Henry Wynne William Price William Vaughan William Wynne Lewis Lloyd Howell Vaughan John Pugh
Vincent Corbet Maurice Wynne John Lloyd Es?s Sir John Wynne Knight Robert Wynne Richard Wynne [Lewis
Owen Griffith Lloyd<ref idref="n78">78</ref>] William Vaughan of Kaithly John Nanny of Llanvantheged Edmond Meirick Humphry Hughes
John Vaughan Rowland Vaughan Richard Anwill Ellis Edwards Maurice Williams William Tudar Lewis Wynne Es?s
John Owen of Havoddowilch Richard Jones John Lloyd of Ddialt Anthony Poole Griffith John Lewis Richard Lloyd
of Carrog Evan Lloyd of Goppa Gen&bhotcrl;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s115">
			<head>For the County of Montgomery</head>
			<para id="p122">Sir Mathew Price Sir Thomas Middleton Sir Richard Corbet Sir Edward Lloyd Henry Herbert Andrew Newport
John Purcell John Blaney John Pugh Richard Herbert Richard Owen Francis Buller Robert Leighton Charles
Salisbury John Price of Parke Mathew Morgan Roger Mostyn John Blodwell Robert Lee Thomas Wind Henry
Purcell John Newton Edmond Wareing John Mathews the elder John Mathewes the younger of Treffnany Thomas
[Tanner<ref idref="n79">79</ref>] Vincent Perce Thomas Corbet Thomas [Norris<ref idref="n80">80</ref>] Brockwell Griffiths Robert Griffithes Thomas Jones
Francis Fitzherbert John Whittingham David Powell Thomas Jukes Arthur Weaver William Browne Edward
Glynne of Glynne Es?s Edward Herbert John Kiffin John Oakeley Samuell Biggs Edward Edwards of Colfryn
John Lloyd of Cowney Evan Vaughan Edward Whittingham Gen?.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s116">
			<head>For the County of Pembrooke</head>
			<para id="p123">Sir Erasmus Phillips Sir John Stepney Baronets Sir Hugh Owen Sir John Lort Knights and Baronets Sir Herbert
Perrot Knight William Scourefeild Essex Meiricke Rowland Langharne John Barlow Arthur Owen Henry White
Lewis Barloe Hugh Bowen James Bowen Thomas Warren William Phillips Thomas Parry George Haward James
Lloyd John Lort Thomas Lloyd Isaac Lloyd Thomas Wogan of Llantinane William Mordant John Mathias Esquiers
The Maior of Pembrooke for the time being William Hinton Mathew Bowen Francis Rogers Aldermen The Maior
of Tenby for the time being Thomas Wyat Rice Barrow David Palmer Aldermen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s117">
			<head>For the Towne and County of Haverford West</head>
			<para id="p124">Lewis Baron Maior Sir William Moreton Knight one of His Majestyes Sergeants at Law Sir John Stepney Sir
Hugh Owen Baronets Rowland Langherne William Phillips Richard Walter George Haward Es?s (<ref idref="n81">81</ref>) Henry Bowen
Aldermen John Barlowe John Williams Mathew Prinne Thomas Cozens Gabrell Wade John Lloyd Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s118">
			<head>For the County of Radnor</head>
			<para id="p125">Sir Edward Harley Knight of the Bath Richard Fowler George Gwyne Henry Williams James Price Samuell
Powell Herbert Weston Andrew Phillips Thomas Lewis of Harpton Nicholas Tayler Charles Lewis Evan Davies
Griffith Jones Henry Probert Thomas Lewis of [Nanaughty<ref idref="n82">82</ref>] Thomas Ecleston Nicholas Meredith Robert Cutler
Esq[uire]s The Bayliffe of New [Radnar<ref idref="n83">83</ref>] Francis Rickards Gent.</para>
			<para id="p126">The which said Commissioners or any three or more of them are hereby authorized to putt in Execution the
Powers of this A&bholigct; within their respective Divisions, And that by Authority of this A&bholigct; the said C&bhooov;missioners
may by their Assents and Agreements sever themselves for the Execution of this A&bholigct; in Hundreds Lathes Wards
Rapes Wapentakes Townes Parishes and other places within their respective Limitts in such forme as to them
shall seeme expedient to be ordered and betweene them to be agreed according to the tenour and effect of
this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section></section>
		<section id="s119">
			<head>VII. Commissioners to execute Act according to the Tenor thereof.</head>
			<para id="p127">And be it alsoe enacted by [the<ref idref="n84">84</ref>] Authoritie of this present Parliament That the Commissioners and every of them
which are herein named limitted and appointed according to this A&bholigct; to be Commissioners in every such Shire
Rideing Lath Wapentake Rape Citty Towne Burrough Isle or any other place And that shall be nominated in any
Commission [that shall<ref idref="n85">85</ref>] be dire&bholigct;ed from His Majesty for assessing of His Majestyes Honourable Household and
none other shall truely effe&bholigct;ually and diligently for their parts execute the effe&bholigct; of this present A&bholigct; according to
the tenoure thereof in every behalfe and noe otherwise by any meanes without ommission favour dread mallice or
any other thing to be [attempted or<ref idref="n86">86</ref>] done by them or any of them to the contrary thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s120">
			<head>VIII. Commissioners to dire&bholigct; Precepts to certain Number of Inhabitants in Hundreds, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p128">
				<emph type="i">who are to shew such Precepts; Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p129">And the said Commissioners shall for the Taxation of the said two first of the said Fower Subsidies before the
tenth day of September next comeing, And for the Taxation of the two last of the said Fower Subsidyes shall
before the tenth day of February next ensueing dire&bholigct; their severall or joynt Precept or Precepts unto eight seaven
six five fower three or two as for the number of Inhabitants shall be requisite of the most substantiall discreete
and honest persons Inhabitants of and in Hundreds Lathes Rapes Wapentakes Wards Parishes Townes and other
places aswell within Liberties Franchices [and<ref idref="n87">87</ref>] Auntient Demeasne Places exempted and San&bholigct;uaryes as without within
the Limitts of the Shires Rideings Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Cittyes Townes Burroughes and Isle aforesaid and
other places within their respe&bholigct;ive limitts, And to the Constables Sub Constables Bayliffes and other like Officers
and Ministers of every of the said Hundreds Townes Wards Lathes Wapentakes Parishes and other places aforesaid
as to the said Commissioners and every number of them or to three or two of them by their discretion in division
shall seeme expedient, and as by the manner and use of these parts shall be requisite, straitely by the said Precept
chargeing and commanding the said Inhabitants Constables and other Officers aforesaid to whom such Precept shall
be soe dire&bholigct;ed to appeare in their proper persons before the said Commissioners or such number of them as they
shall divide themselves according to this A&bholigct; at certaine dayes and places by the said Commissioners or any such
number of them as is aforesaid within Cittyes Burroughes or Townes Corporate or without in any other places
as is aforesaid by their discretion to be limitted thereunto to doe and accomplish all that to them on the part
of the Kings Majestie shall be enjoyned touching this A&bholigct;, commanding further by the same Precept that he to 
whose hands such Precepts shall come shall shew and deliver the same to the other Inhabitants or Officers named
in the same Precept, And that none of them faile to accomplish the same upon paine of Forty shillings to be
forfeited to the Kings Majestie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s121">
			<head>IX. Persons named in Precept to appear before Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p130">
				<emph type="i">Such Persons making Default or refusing to serve.; Penalty 40s.; Penalty 40s.; Enquiry into the Substance of Persons to be charged, but such Enquiry not to be taken on Oath, and to certify before Commissioners.; Penalty.; Commissioners to read the Rates openly.; Afterwards another Day to be appointed by Commissioners for such Persons to appear.; Not appearing, Penalty 40s.; or refusing to make Certificate; Penalty 40s.; Commissioners to examine Presenters of Certificate.; Further Proceedings on Assessments by Precept to Constables, &amp;c. to warn Persons named therein to appear; Oath not allowed on Inquiry into the Substance of Persons charged.; Persons named in the said Precept called upon, not appearing; Penalty, Double Rate.; On Inquiry into the Substance of Persons charged, Commissioners may increase Taxation.; Spiritual Persons how to be rated for Temporal Possessions</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p131">And it is further ordained by the Authoritie of this present Parliament That at the said day and place prefixed
and limitted in the said Precept, every of the said Co[m]missioners then being in the Shire and not haveing sufficient
excuse for his absence at the day and place [prefixed<ref idref="n88">88</ref>] for that part whereunto he was limitted shall appeare in
his owne proper person, And there the same Co[m]missioners being present or as many of them as shall be appointed
by vertue of this Act shall call or cause to be called before them the said Inhabitants and Officers to whom they
have directed their said Precept, And if any person soe warned [doe<ref idref="n89">89</ref>] make defaulte unlesse he then be letted by
sicknes or lawfull excuse, and that Lett be then witnessed by the Oathes of two credible persons or if any
appeareing refuse to serve in forme following then every such person soe makeing default or refuseing to serve
shall forfeite to the Kings Majesty Forty shillings and soe at every time appointed by the said Commissioners for
the said severall Taxations untill such time the number of every such persons have appeared and certifyed in forme
underwritten every of them soe makeing defaulte or refuseing to serve shall forfeit to the Kings Majestye Forty
shillings And upon the same appearance had they shall be charged before the Commissioners by all convenient
wayes and meanes (other then by Corporall Oath) to inquire of the value of the substance after the usuall
manner of every person dwelling and abiding within the limitts of the places that they shall be charged with,
and of other which shall have his or their most resorte unto any of the said places and chargeable with any summe
of money by this Act of the said Subsidyes and of all other things requisite touching the said Act and according
to the intent of the same and thereupon as neere as it may be, or shall come to their knowledge without respect
of any former Taxation heretofore had but these hereafter mentioned truely to present and certifie before the said
Commissioners the Names and Sirnames and the Substance and Values of every of them after the usuall manner
as aforesaid aswell of Lands Tenements and other Hereditaments Possessions and Proffitts as of Goods Chattells
Debts and other things chargeable by the same Act without any concealment love favour affection dread or
mallice upon paine of [forfeiting<ref idref="n90">90</ref>] any summe not exceeding five pounds to be taxed estreated and levyed in forme
as hereafter in this present Act shall be limitted or appointed. And thereupon the said Commissers shall openly there
reade or cause to be read unto them the said Rates in this Act mentioned and openly declare the effect of their
charge unto them in what manner and forme they ought and should make their Certificates according to the Rates
and Summes thereof abovesaid and of all manner of persons aswell Aliens and Strangers Denizens or not Denizens
inhabiting within this Realme as of such Popish Recusants and others persons as be borne under the Kings obeisance
chargeable to this Act, and of the Possessions Goods and Chattells of Fraternityes Guilds Corporations Brotherhoods
Misteries Commonalties and other as is abovesaid, and of persons being in the parts beyond the Seas haveing
Goods and Chattells Lands or Tenements within this Realme as is aforesaid, and of all Goods being in the
custody of any person or persons to the use of any other as is aforesaid, by the which information and shewing
the said persons may have such plaine knowledge of the true intent of this present Act and of the manner of
their Certificate that the same persons shall have noe reasonable cause to excuse them by ignorance, And after
such Charge and the Statute of the said Subsidyes and the manner of the said Certificate to be made in writeing
containing the Names and Sirnames of every person and whether he be borne without the Kings Dominions or
within and the value of every person in every degree as well of the yearely value of Lands and Tenements and
of such like Possessions and Proffitts as of the value of Goods and Chattells Debts and every thing to their
Certificate requisite and necessary to them declared, the said Commissioners there being shall by their Discretions limitt
and appoint unto the said persons another day and place to appeare before the said Commissioners and chargeing
the said persons that they shall in the meane time make diligent enquiry by all wayes and meanes of the premisses,
And then and there every of them upon paine of forfeiture of Forty Shillings to the Kings Majestie, to appeare
at the said next prefixed day and place there to certifie unto the said Commissioners in writeing according to
their said Charge, and according to the true intent of the said Grant of Subsidy and as to them in manner aforesaid
hath beene declared and shewed by the Commissers, at which day and place soe to them prefixed if any of the
said persons make defaulte, or appeare and refuse to make the said Certificate, then every of them soe offending
[shall<ref idref="n91">91</ref>] forfeite to the Kings Majestie Forty Shillings, (except there be a reasonable excuse of his default by reason
of his sicknes, or otherwise by the Oathes of two credible persons there witnessed) And of such as appeare ready
to make Certificate as is aforesaid, the said Commissioners there being shall take and receive the same Certificate
and every part thereof and the Names Values and Substance of every person soe certified, And if the said Commissers
see cause reasonable they shall examine the said Presenters thereof, and thereupon the said Commissioners at the
said dayes and places by their agreement amongst themselves shall from time to time there openly prefix a day at
a certaine place or places within their respective limitts by their Discretion for their further proceeding to the said
assessing of the same Subsidyes, and thereupon at the said day of the said Certificate as is aforesaid taken, the same
Commissioners shall make their Precept or Precepts to the Constables Sub-Constables Bayliffes or other Officers of
such Hundreds Wapentakes Townes or other places aforesaid as the same Co[m]missers shall be of comprising and
containing in the said Precepts the Names and Sirnames of all persons presented before them in the said Certificate,
of whom if the said Commissioners or as many of them as are thereunto appointed by vertue of this Act shall then
have vehement suspect to be of more greater Value or Substance of Lands Goods Chattells or Summes of money
oweing unto them, or other Substance aforesaid then is upon such person and persons soe certifyed and specified
as aforesaid the same Co[m]missers shall make their Precept or Precepts directed to the Constables Bayliffes or other Officers commanding them to whom such Precept shall be dire&bholigct;ed to warne such persons whose names shall be
comprized in the said Precepts at their Mansions or to their persons that the same persons named in such Precepts
and every of them shall personally appeare before the said Commissioners at the said new prefixed day and place
(<ref idref="n92">92</ref>) by all wayes and meanes (other then by Corporall Oath) by the said Commissioners of their Substance and Value in
manner as is aforesaid, and of all and every summes of money oweing to them and other whatsoever matter
concerning the premisses or any of them according to this A&bholigct;, at which day and place soe prefixed the said
Commissers then and there being, or as many of them as are, or shall be thereunto appointed by vertue of this
A&bholigct; shall cause to be called the said persons whose Names shall be comprized in the said Precept as is aforesaid
for their examination, And if any of those persons which shall be warned as aforesaid to be examined (which
at any time after the warning and before the day prefixed shall be within such place as he may have knowledge
of his said appearance to be made) shall make defaulte and appeare not, unlesse a reasonable cause or excuse by
the Oathes of two credible persons before the said C&bhooov;missers be truely alledged for his discharge that then every
of them soe makeing defaulte to be taxed and charged to the Kings Majestie with and at the double summe of
the Rate that he should or ought to have beene sett at for and after the value aforesaid of his Lands or substance
upon him certifyed if he had appeared by the discretion of the Co[m]missers there being, which C&bholigct;missers shall travell
with every of the other persons soe then and there appearing whose names shall be expressed in the said Precept
or Precepts, and to whom any vehement suspe&bholigct; was or shall be had in forme aforesaid by all wayes and meanes
they can (other then by Corporall Oath) for the better knowledge of their value as aforesaid, either in Hereditaments
or Possessions or else in Goods or Debts. And thereupon shall have power and Authority by vertue of this A&bholigct;
according to their discretions to enlarge and encrease the Taxation of such Persons as they shall soe finde by due
examination to be of greater value or Substance in Lands or Goods then they were presented at, And that every
Spirituall Person at every of the said Taxations of the (<ref idref="n93">93</ref>) Subsidyes shall be rated and sett according to the Rate
abovesaid of and for every pound that the same Spirituall Person or any other to his use hath by Descent Bargaine
or Purchase in Fee Simple or Fee Tayle terme of Life, terme of yeares by Execution, or Copy of Court Roll in
any Mannours Lands Tenements Rents Services Offices Fees Corodyes Annuityes and Hereditaments after the true
just and yearely value thereof, And according as other the Kings Majestyes subjects borne within this Realme be
charged in forme above remembred, soe that it extend to the yearely value of Twenty shillings or above in the
Subsidy Booke,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s122">
			<head>X. Assessors misbehaving, Commissioners may set a Fine upon them.</head>
			<para id="p132">
				<emph type="i">To be estreated into the Exchequer.; Remedy for Persons aggrieved by the Assessment.; Commissioners may abate or increase Assessment.; False Oath of Value of Lands, &amp;c.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p133">And it is further enacted That if the said Taxors or Assessors shall not duely behave themselves in their enquiry
taxation assessment or Certificate but shall affe&bholigct;ionately corruptly or partially demeane themselves in (<ref idref="n94">94</ref>) that behalfe,
in such wise that the C&bhooov;missers shall by their Considerations deeme them Offenders worthy of punishment for not
doeing their dutyes therein, That then fower or more of the C&bhooov;missers in that County for the said Subsidy shall
have power and authority by their discretions either to charge the said Assessors upon their Corporall Oathes for the
better service aforesaid in that behalfe, or else by their Discretions to tax and sett upon the said Assessors for their
misdemeanours in that behalfe such Fine or paine as they shall thinke good soe that it exceed not the Summe of
ten pounds, And the same Fine [and<ref idref="n95">95</ref>] paine at their Discrestions to estreate into the Court of Exchequer, every which
Fine soe taxed and sett by Fower of the said C&bhooov;missers or more, and being estreated with the Schedule [&amp; Books<ref idref="n96">96</ref>]
of that Limitt shall be levyed and answered to the Kings use in like manner and forme to all intents and purposes
as any other Summes that shall be taxed and become due by vertue of this Statute and Act of Subsidy and not in
any other wise or manner, And if any person certifyed or rated by vertue of this Act, whether he be a Commissioner
or other to any manner of value doth finde himselfe greived with the same presentment sessing or rateing, and
thereupon complaine to the C&bhooov;missers before whom he shall be called sessed or taxed or before Two of them,
before the same taxation be certifyed in the Court of Exchequer, that then the said Commissioners or Two of
them shall by all wayes and meanes examine perticularly and distinctly the person soe complaining upon his Oath,
and other his Neighbours by their discretions of every his Lands and Tenements above specified and of every
his Goods Chattells and Debts above-mentioned, And after due examination and perfect knowledge thereof had and
perceived by the said Co[m]missers or Two of them which shall have power by [the<ref idref="n97">97</ref>] Authoritie aforesaid, the said
C&bhooov;missers or any Two of them to whom such complaint shall be made by their discretions upon the Oath of the
said persons soe complaining may abate defalk increase or inlarge the said assessments according as it shall appeare
unto them just upon the same examination, And the same Summe soe abated defalked increased or enlarged shall
be by them estreated in forme as is hereafter specifyed, And if it be proved by witnesses or by the partyes owne
confession or other lawfull wayes or meanes within a yeare after any such Oath made that the same person soe
rated and sworne was of any better or greater value in Lands Goods or other things above specifyed at the time
of his said Oath then the same person soe sworne did declare upon his Oath, That then every such person soe
offending shall loose and forfeite to the Kings Majestye soe much lawfull money of England as he the same person
soe sworne was sett at, or taxed to pay</para>
</section>
<section id="s123">
	<head>XI. Commissioners to be rated at such Place where they shall be Commissioners</head>
			<para id="p134">
				<emph type="i">other Persons where they have resided for the most Part of the Year preceding; Absentees to be assessed where last abiding.; Rate to be according to the Substance of Persons liable.; Remedy for Commissioners and other Persons taxed in other Place than where they are Commissioners, or where resiant for most Part of the preceding Year.; Fee for Allowance</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p135">And alsoe it is enacted by the same Authority That every person to be rated and taxed as is aforesaid shall
be rated and sett, and the summe on him sett to be levyed at such place where he and his family were resident
for the most part of the yeare next before the same Presentment and the Taxation made and noe where else,
And that noe Commissioner for his Subsidy shall be rated or taxed for his Goods or Lands but in the Shire or
other place where he shall be Commissioner, And that if any Person chargeable by this A&bholigct; at the time of the
said Assessings happen to be out of this Realme and out of Wales or farr from the place where he shall be
knowne then he to be sett where he was last abideing within this Realme or in Wales and after the substance
value or other proffitts of every Person to be knowne by Examination Certificate or other manner of way as is
aforesaid, And that the said resp&bholigct;ive Commissioners or as many of them as are or shall be appointed shall
according to the respe&bholigct;ive powers given them and after the Rate and Rates aforesaid cause every person soe to
be sett rated and taxed according to the [Rate of the<ref idref="n98">98</ref>] substance and value of his Lands Goods Chattells and other
proffitts chargeable by this A&bholigct; whereby the greatest or best summe or summes according to his substance as
aforesaid by reason of this A&bholigct; might or may be sett or taxed, And that every person taxed in any County or
place other then where he or his family were resiant for the most part of the yeare then next before, or in any
County or place other then where he is a Commissioner for the Subsidy if he be a Commissioner upon Certificate
made to the said Court of Exchequer under the hands and Seales of two Commissioners for the same Subsidy
in the same County or place where such person and his family were resiant for the most part of the yeare
then next before, or where he is a C&bhooov;miss[ion]er for the Taxation and payment of the same Subsidy, testifying his
non resiance haveing a family or being a C&bhooov;miss[ion]er shall be a sufficient discharge for the Taxation of that person
in any other places, and of and for all other summes of Money upon such persons soe sett and taxed save onely
the Taxations made in that County or place from which such Certificate shall be made as [is<ref idref="n98">98</ref>] aforesaid and for the
summe of Money upon such person there assessed or taxed, And that such Certificate without any Plea or other
circumstance shall be a sufficient Warrant aswell to the Barons and Auditor and Auditors of the said Court of
Exchequer as to all and every other Officers to whom the allowance thereof shall appertaine paying for such
discharge and allowance onely six pence and noe more.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s124">
			<head>XII. Double Charges not to be allowed.</head>
			<para id="p136">
				<emph type="i">Remedy in respect of Double Charges</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p137">Provided alwayes That every such person that shall be rated or taxed according to the true meaning of this
A&bholigct; for paying of and to these Subsidyes for and after the yearely value of his Lands Tenements or other reall
Possessions or Proffitts at any of the said Taxations shall not after be sett and rated for his Goods and Chattells or
other moveable substance at the same Taxation, And that he that shall be sett charged or taxed for the same
Subsidies for his Goods Chattells and other Moveables at any of the Taxations according to the true meaning of
this A&bholigct; shall not after be taxed, charged or chargeable for his Lands or other Reall Possessions or Proffitts
aforesaid at the same Taxations or any of them; Nor that any person by any Taxation be doubly charged for the
said Subsidyes nor sett or rated at severall places by reason of this A&bholigct;, But if any person happen to be double
sett taxed or charged either in one place or at severall places, then he to be discharged of the one Taxation
and charged with the other according to the meaning and intent of this A&bholigct;. Any thing contained in this present
Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s125">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for Persons having Two Mansions, or being Household Servants or Waiting Servants to the King or others.</head>
			<para id="p138">
				<emph type="i">Persons unduly escaping Taxation; on Proof thereof before Commissioners or Barons of the Exchequer; to be taxed at Double Value</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p139">And be it ordained and enacted by the Authority of this present Parliament That noe person haveing two
Mansions or two places to resorte unto, or calling himselfe Household servant or Waiteing servant to the Kings
Majestye or other Lord or Lady Master or Mistrisse be excused upon his saying from the Taxes of the said
Subsidyes in neither of the said places where he may be sett or taxed unlesse he bring a Certificate in writeing
from the C&bhooov;missers where he is soe sett or taxed indeed at one place, And if any person that ought to be sett
and taxed to these present Subsidyes by reason of his removeing or resorting to two Places, or by reason of his
saying that he was elsewhere taxed by reason of any Priviledge of his dwelling or abideing in any place not being
foreprized in this A&bholigct; or otherwise by his covin, or craft, or by any words or sayings, or otherwise, Or if any
that is Commisser or Assessor of others happen to escape from the said Taxations for the payment of these
Subsidyes or any of them, and be not sett and taxed according to the true intent of this A&bholigct; and that proved by
Presentment [Information Examination<ref idref="n99">99</ref>] or otherwise before the said C&bhooov;missers or two of them or before the Barons
of the Kings Majestyes Exchequer or two Justices of Peace of that County where such person dwelleth, Then every
such person that by such meanes or otherwise willingly by covin or without just cause shall happen to escape
from the said Taxations or payments aforesaid or any of them and shall not be rated taxed and sett shall be
charged upon the knowledge and proofe thereof with and at the same double value of soe much as he should might
or ought to have beene sett or taxed at by vertue of this Act; And the same double value to be leavyed gathered
and paid of his Goods and Chattells Lands and Tenements towards the said Subsidyes, And further to be punished
according to the discretions of the said Barons Justices or C&bhooov;missers before whom he shall be convicted for his
offence and deceite in that busines,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s126">
			<head>XIV. The Power of Commissioners to tax other Commissioners, and also Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p140">
				<emph type="i">Barons and Persons of higher Estate taxed by the Lord Chancellor, Lord; Treasurer, and other Persons herein named.; Rate to be estreated and certified</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p141">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the C&bhooov;missers appointed by this Act and all other
C&bhooov;missers appointed by his Majestie which shall be or inhabit in any County or place within their respe&bholigct;ive
Limitts or Commission or the more part of them, shall have full power and Authority by this A&bholigct; to sett taxe
and sesse every other C&bhooov;misser joyned with them, And the said C&bhooov;miss[ion]ers within their Division shall alsoe assesse
every Assessor within their Division for his or their Goods Lands and other the Premisses as is abovesaid shall
indifferently sett taxe and sesse themselves and the said Assessors, And that aswell the summes upon every of the
said C&bhooov;miss[ion]ers and Assessors soe assessed rated and taxed as the summes made and presented by the Presenters
as is abovesaid shall be written certifyed sett and estreated and the estreates thereof to be made with other the
Inhabitants of that part, and within their respe&bholigct;ive Limitts and Division soe to be gathered and levyed in like
manner as it ought and should have beene if the said C&bhooov;missers had not beene nominated C&bhooov;miss[ion]ers, And that
all persons of the Estate of a Baron or Baronesse and every Estate above shall be charged with their freehold
and value as is aforesaid [by Edward Earle of Clarendon Lord Chauncellour of England Thomas Earle of Southampton Lord High Treasurer of England John Lord Roberts Lord Privy Seale Charles Duke of Richmond George Duke
of Albemarle John Marquesse of Winchester, Mountague Earle of Lyndsey Lord Great Chamberlaine of England,
Edward Earle of Manchester Lord Chamberlaine of His Majestyes Household William Earle of Bedford Richard
Earle of Dorsett John Earle of Bridgewater James Earle of Northampton John Earle of Clare Thomas Earle of
Cleaveland Thomas Earle Rivers Mountjoy Earle of Newport John Earle of Thannet Francis Viscount Mountague
Charles Lord [Delaway<ref idref="n100">100</ref>] George Lord Berkley of Berkeley George Lord Eure Philip Lord Wharton Henry Lord
Arundell Charles Lord Howard of Charleton William Lord Craven Francis Lord Newport Christopher Lord Hatton
Richard Lord Vaughan Thomas Lord Colpeper John Lord Lucas Robert Lord Lexington John Lord Berkley of
Stratton Charles Lord Cornwallis and Anthony Lord Ashley or any seaven or more of them<ref idref="n101">101</ref>] for the said severall
payments of the said Subsidyes after the forme of the said Grant according to the Taxation aforesaid, And the
Summes of and upon them to be taxed and sett with the names of the Collectors, [which Collectors shall be
appointed by the Lord Chauncellour or Lord Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the time being<ref idref="n101">101</ref>] for gathering
and paying of them to be estreated delivered and certifyed at the dayes and places above specified [by the said
Edward Earle of Clarendon Lord Chauncellour of England Thomas Earle of Southampton Lord High Treasurer
of England John Lord Roberts Lord Privy Seale Charles Duke of Richmond George Duke of Albemarle John
Marquesse of Winchester Mountague Earle of Lindsey Lord Great Chamberlaine of England Edward Earle of
Manchester Lord Chamberlaine of His Majestyes Household William Earle of Bedford Richard Earle of Dorset
John Earle of Bridgewater James Earle of Northampton John Earle of Clare Thomas Earle of Cleaveland Thomas
Earle Rivers Mountjoy Earle of Newport John Earle of Thannet Francis Viscount Mountague Charles Lord Delawar
George Lord Berkley of Berkley George Lord Eure Philip Lord Wharton Henry Lord Arundell Charles Lord
Howard of Charleton William Lord Craven Francis Lord Newport Christopher Lord Hatton Richard Lord Vaughan
Thomas Lord Culpeper John Lord Lucas Robert Lord Lexington John Lord Berkley of Stratton Charles Lord
Cornewallis and Anthony Lord Ashley or any seaven or more of them.<ref idref="n101">101</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s127">
			<head>XV. Rates to be estreated under the Seal and Sign Manual of the Commissioners, and Estreat delivered to sufficient Inhabitants, &amp;c. of Hundreds, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p142">
				<emph type="i">By virtue of Estreat Officers, &amp;c. to levy Rate.; Distress.; If Rate not paid in Eight Days, then Distress to be appraised and sold.; Officers, &amp;c. to answer for the Portion limited to them only.; Allowance to Officers on Rate received</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p143">And be it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That after the Taxes and Assesses of the said S&bhouov;mmes upon
and by the said Assessing and Certificate as is aforesaid made the said respective Co[m]miss[ion]ers or as many of them
as shall be thereunto by this A&bholigct; appointed, or have Authority by the Kings Majestyes Commission shall with all
speede and without delay by their writeing estreate the said Taxes thereof under the Seales and Signes Manuall
of the said C&bhooov;missers, or as many of them as shall be appointed at the least, And the same shall deliver unto
sufficient and substantiall Inhabitants Constables Sub-Constables Bayliffes and other Officers joyntly of Hundreds
Townes Parishes and other places aforesaid within their Limitts, And to other sufficient persons Inhabitants of
the same onely by the Discretion of the said C&bhooov;missers with the assent of the High Collectors and as the places
and partyes shall require aswell the perticular names and surnames as the Remembrance of all summes of Money
taxed and sett of and upon every person aswell Man as Woman chargeable by (<ref idref="n102">102</ref>) this Act Householders and all
other Inhabitants and Dwellers within the said Parishes Townes and Places contributory to this Act of Subsidyes.
By Authority of which Writeing and Estreate soe delivered the said Officers and other persons soe named and
deputed severally shall have full power and authority by vertue of this A&bholigct; immediately after the delivery of the
said Writeing or Estreate to demand leavy and gather of every person therein specified the s&bhouov;mme and s&bhouov;mmes in
the [said<ref idref="n103">103</ref>] Writeing or Estreate comprised, and for non-payment thereof to destraine the same person or persons soe
being behind by their Goods and Chattells, and the Distresse soe taken to keepe by the space of Eight dayes at
the costs and charges of the Owner thereof, And if the said Owner doe not pay such summe of money as shall
be taxed upon him or her by Authority of this A&bholigct; within the same eight dayes, then the same Distresse to be
appraised by Fower Three or Two of the Inhabitants where such Distresse is taken, and alsoe then to be sold
by the Constables or other Colle&bholigct;ors for the payment of the said money and the overplus comeing by the sale
(if any be) over and besides the charge of keepeing the said Distresse to be im&bhomov;ediately restored to the owner
thereof which said Officers and other persons soe deputed to aske take gather and leavy the said Summes shall
answere and be charged for the portion onely to them assigned and limitted to be gathered leavyed and comprized
in the said Writeing or Estreate soe to them as aforesaid delivered to the use of our Soveraigne Lord the Kings
Majestie and His Heires and Successors, and the said Summe in that Writeing or Estreate to be comprized to
pay unto the High Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors of that place in manner and forme underwritten thereunto to be named
and deputed, and the same Inhabitants and Officers soe gathering the same perticular summes for [the<ref idref="n104">104</ref>] Collection
thereof shall retaine for every Twenty shillings soe by them received and paid Two pence and that to be allowed
at the payment of their Collection by them to be made to the High Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s128">
			<head>XVI. Commissioners may appoint Persons; to be High Collectors.</head>
			<para id="p144">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to deliver Estreats under their Seals and Sign Manual to Collectors.; Collectors to answer the Sums comprized in Estreat</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p145">And further be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That such of the said C&bhooov;missers or the greater part of
them [that<ref idref="n105">105</ref>] shall take upon them the execution of this Act shall for every of the said payments of the said Subsidyes
name such sufficient and able persons which then shall have and possesse Lands or other Hereditaments in their
owne right of the cleare yearely value of Forty pounds, or Goods to the value of Fower hundred pounds at
the least as he shall be taxed in the Subsidy Booke (if any such be in the said Limitts) and for want of such
soe assessed then those to be appointed Colle&bholigct;ors that then shall be sufficient and rated and taxed in the Subsidy
Bookes in Lands and Goods neerest to the values aforesaid as by their Discretions shall be thought good in Shires
Rideings Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Cittyes Townes Corporate and other whatsoever places aswell within places
priviledged as without not being foreprized in this A&bholigct; to be high Colle&bholigct;or And to have the Colle&bholigct;ion and
Receipt of the said Summes sett and levyable within the Precin&bholigct;s Limitts and Bounds where they shall be soe limitted and appointed to be High-Colle&bholigct;ors, And to every of the said Colle&bholigct;ors soe severally named the said
C&bhooov;miss[ion]ers or two of them at the least with all speede and without delay after the said whole Summe of any
payment of the said Subsidies be sett by all their respe&bholigct;ive Limitts, or in such Limitts as the high Colle&bholigct;or shall
be soe severally assigned shall under their Seales and Signes Manuall deliver one Estreate indented in Parchment
compriseing in it the names of all such persons as were assigned to leavy the said perticular summes and the
summes of every Hundred Wapentake Towne or other Place aforesaid with the names and surnames of the persons
soe chargeable according to the Estreate soe thereof first made and delivered as is aforesaid, And the Colle&bholigct;ors
to be assigned shall be charged to answere the whole Summe comprized in the said Estreats limitted to his Colle&bholigct;ion
as is aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s129">
			<head>XVII. Commissioners to take Recognizances of Collectors.</head>
			<para id="p146">
				<emph type="i">Condition of Recognizance for Two first Subsidies.; Condition of Recognizance of Two last Subsidies.; Commissioners to certify Recognizances, &amp;c. into the Exchequer.; Penalty &pound;10. Collector not making Recognizance, Penalty &pound;20. Exchequer to cancel Recognizances on Payment of Collection into Exchequer without Fee. Collector may appoint Days and Places for Payment of Collection. Assessor, &amp;c. not paying Collection to High Collectors, with Allowance of 2d. in the Pound of Collection.; Distress.; Proceedings thereon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p147">Provided alwayes and bee it enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That the said C&bhooov;missioners haveing Authority by
this Act to name and nominate the said High Collectors of every the said Subsidyes shall immediately upon their
nomination and election take by Authority of this present Parliament sufficient Recognizances or Obligations without
any Fee or Reward to be paid therefore of every person soe by them to be named to be High Colle&bholigct;ors to be
bound to the Kings Majesty in the double Summe of the Summe of his Collection, And to be endorsed and
made upon such Condition (that is to say) for the Colle&bholigct;ion of the payment of the said Two first of the said
Fower Subsidies that if the said Colle&bholigct;or his Heires or Executors doe truely content and pay to the use of the
Kings Majestie his Heires [and<ref idref="n106">106</ref>] Successors in the Receipt of the said Exchequer at or before the First day of
November now next comeing soe much of the said Summe of money allotted and appointed to his Colle&bholigct;ion as he
shall colle&bholigct; and gather and content and pay the Residue of his Colle&bholigct;ion and Charge within one Moneth [next<ref idref="n107">107</ref>]
after such time as he hath colle&bholigct;ed and gathered the same Residue, that then the said Recognizance or Obligation
to be void or else to stand in full strength and vertue. And for the collection of the said Two last of the said
Fower Subsidyes upon Condition that if the said Colle&bholigct;or his Heires or Executors doe truely content and pay to
the use of the Kings Majestie His Heires or Successors in His Receipt of Exchequer at or before the First day of
May then next following soe much of the said Summe of money allotted and appointed to his Colle&bholigct;ion as he
shall collect and gather and content and pay the Residue of his Colle&bholigct;ion and Charge within one Moneth next
after such time as he hath colle&bholigct;ed and gathered the same Residue that then the [same<ref idref="n108">108</ref>] Recognizances or Obligations
to be void or else to stand in full strength and vertue; Which said severall Recognizances or Obligations soe
taken the said C&bhooov;missioners shall severally certifie and deliver into the Kings Majestyes Exchequer with the severall
Certificates of the said Taxations and Rates of the payments of the said Subsidyes at and by the times to them
prescribed and appointed by this A&bholigct; for the Certificate of the said severall Taxations of the said Subsidy upon paine
of forfeiture of Ten pounds to the Kings Majestie for every Recognizance or Obligation not soe certified, And
that every Collector soe elected named and chosen upon request to him made shall knowledge and make the said
Recognizance or Obligation upon paine of forfeiture of Twenty pounds to the Kings Majestie for refusall thereof,
And that the Treasurer and Barons of the Exchequer for the time being upon payment of the said severall
Colle&bholigct;ions of the Subsidyes at the dayes and times herein limited for the payment thereof, shall cancell and deliver
the Recognizances or Obligations for the payment thereof to the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors without any other Warrant
and without any Fee or Reward to be paid for the same to any person, And every Colle&bholigct;or soe deputed haveing
the said Estreate in Parchment as is aforesaid shall have Authoritie by this A&bholigct; to appoint dayes and places within
the circuit of his Collection for the payment of the said Subsidyes to him to be made, And thereof to give warning
by Proclamation or otherwise to all the Constables or other Persons or Inhabitants haveing the charge of the
perticular Colle&bholigct;ion within the Hundreds Parishes Townes or other places by him or them limitted to make
payment of the said perticular Collection of every Summe as to them shall appertaine, And if at the same day
and place soe limitted and prefixed by the said High Collector, the said Constable Officers or (<ref idref="n109">109</ref>) other Persons or
Inhabitants as is aforesaid for the said perticular Collection assigned and appointed within such Hundred Citty Towne
or other place due and comprised in the said Estreate thereof to them delivered by the said C&bhooov;missioners or some of
them as is aforesaid or soe much thereof as they have by any meanes received two pence for every pound for
the said perticular Collection as is aforesaid alwayes thereof to be allowed, excepted and abated that then it shall
be lawfull to the said High Collectors and every of them and to their Assignes to destraine every of the said
Constables Officers and other Inhabitants for their severall and perticular Colle&bholigct;ion of the said Summe comprised
in the said Estreate and Writeing thereof to them and every of them as is before expressed delivered, or for soe
much of the same Summe as soe then shall happen to be gathered and levyed and behind and unpaid by the
Goods and Chattells of every of them soe being behinde, And the Distresse soe taken to be kepte and appraised
and sold as is aforesaid, And thereof to take and leavy the Summes soe then being behinde and unpaid, And
the overplus comeing of the Sale of the said Distresse (if any be) to be restored and delivered to the owner in
forme above remembred</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s130">
			<head>XVIII. Persons having been Colle&bholigct;ors of First Subsidy not to be appointed Colle&bholigct;ors of Second Subsidy unless they shew Quietus est.</head>
			<para id="p148">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p149">Provided alwayes and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That noe person or persons shall be nominated
or appointed to be High Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors for the two last of the said Fower Subsidyes granted by this A&bholigct;
which before that time hath beene a Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors [of<ref idref="n110">110</ref>] the two first of the said Fower Subsidyes or either
of them unlesse such person or persons soe to be nominated or appointed High Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors for the
said two first of the said Fower Subsidyes doe first shew forth before him or them by whom [they<ref idref="n111">111</ref>] shall be
nominated and appointed his Quietus est for his discharge of his Colle&bholigct;ion before appointed to his discharge upon
paine of One hundred pounds to be paid and forfeited by him or them that shall soe nominate and appoint any
such Colle&bholigct;or contrary to this present A&bholigct;,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s131">
			<head>XIX. Persons living in Cities, &amp;c. not to be Colle&bholigct;ors or Assessors out of them.</head>
			<para id="p150">Provided alwayes That noe person inhabiting in any Citty Burrough or Towne Corporate shall be compelled
to be any Assessor or Colle&bholigct;or of or for any part of the said Subsidyes in any place or places out of the said
Citty Burrough or Towne Corporate where he dweleth</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s132">
			<head>XX. Persons after being charged with Receipt of Assessment, dying or removing or concealing their Goods; or when Monies comprized in Estreat cannot be levied by Distress; or where Distress cannot be sold.</head>
			<para id="p151">
				<emph type="i">Process out of the Exchequer and the Commissioners may direct Precepts to Officer to levy such Money.; Who may distrain.; Distress to be appraised and sold.; If Distress taken out of Limit assigned, Allowance.; Persons charged to be discharged by Distrees</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p152">And it is alsoe by the said Authoritie enacted That if any Inhabitants or Officers or whatsoever person or persons
charged to and for the Colle&bholigct;ion and Receipt of any part or portion of the said Subsidyes by any manner of
meanes according to this A&bholigct; or any person or persons for themselves or as Keeper Guardian, Deputie, Factor or
Attourney of or for any other person or persons for any Goods or Chattells of the Owner thereof at the time of
the assessing to be paid being out of this Realme or in any other parts not knowne, or of and for the Goods
and Chattells of any other person or persons of any Corporation Fraternity Mistery or other whatsoever Comonaltie
being Corporate or not Corporate and all persons haveing in their Rule Governance and Custody any Goods or
Chattells at the time of the said Assessing or any of them to be made or which for any cause for and by
Colle&bholigct;ion or for himselfe or for any other, or by reason that he hath the Rule Governance [and<ref idref="n112">112</ref>] Custodie of any
Goods or Chattells of any other person or persons Corporations Comonaltie Fraternitie Guild or Misterie or any
such other like or as Factor Deputy or Attourney of or for any person shall be taxed valued rated and sett to
any Summe and Summes by reason of this Act, And after the Taxation and assessing upon any such person or
persons as shall be charged with the receipt of the same happen to dye, or depart from the place where he was
taxed and sett, or his Goods or Chattells; to be soe eloyned or in such privy or covert manner kept as the same
person or persons charged with the same by Estreates or [or<ref idref="n113">113</ref>] other Writeings from the said C&bhooov;missioners or as many
of them as shall be thereunto appointed by the said C&bhooov;mission as is aforesaid can nor may leavy the same Summe
and Summes comprised within the same Estreates by the said Distresse within the limitts of their Colle&bholigct;ion as is aforesaid,
or cannot sell such Distresse or Distresses as be taken for any the said Payments before the time limitted to the
High Colle&bholigct;or for his payment to be made in the Kings Majestyes Receipt then upon relation thereof with due
examination by the Oath, or examination of such person or persons as shall be charged with and for the Receipt
and Colle&bholigct;ion of the same before the said C&bhooov;missioners, or as many of them as by the said C&bhooov;mission shall be
thereunto appointed where such person or persons or other (as is aforesaid) their Goods and Chattells were sett
and taxed, and upon plaine Certificate thereof made unto the Kings Majestyes Exchequer by the same C&bhooov;missioners
aswell of the Dwelling place Names and Summes of the said persons of whom the same Summes cannot be levyed
and had as is aforesaid, then aswell the Constable and other Inhabitants, appointed for the same perticular Colle&bholigct;ion
against the High Colle&bholigct;or as the High Colle&bholigct;or, upon his Account and Oath in the said Exchequer to be
discharged thereof, and Processe to be made for the Kings Majestie out of the same Exchequer by the discretion
of the Barons of the same Exchequer against such person his Heires or Executors soe being behind with his
payment, And alsoe that the same C&bhooov;missers to whom any such Declaration of the Premisses shall be made in
forme aforesaid from time to time shall have full power and authority to direct their Precept or Precepts to the
said person or persons charged with any summe of for and upon, any such person and persons or other as is
aforesaid, or to any Sheriffe Steward Bayliffe or other whatsoever Officer Minister person or persons of such place
or places or any such person or persons soe oweing any such summe or summes shall have Lands or Tenements
and other Hereditaments or reall Possessions Goods and Chattells whereby any such person or persons soe indebted
his Heires Executors or Assignes or other haveing the Custodie Governance or Disposition of any Goods or
Chattells Lands Tenements or other Hereditaments which ought or may by this A&bholigct; be lawfully distrained or taken
for the same hath and shall have Goods Chattells Lands Tenements or other Possessions, whereof such summe
and summes which by any such person or persons may or ought to be levyed, be it within the limitts of such
C&bhooov;mission where such person or persons was or were taxed or without in any place within this Realme of England
Wales [or<ref idref="n115">115</ref>] other the Kings Majestyes Dominions [Marshes<ref idref="n115">115</ref>] or Territoryes by which Precept aswell such person or
persons shall be charged to leavy such money as the Officer of the place or places where such Distresse may be
taken shall have full power and authoritie to destraine every such person indebted charged or chargeable by this
A&bholigct; or his Executors or Administrators of his Goods and Chattells his Guardians Factors Deputyes Lessees
Farmers and Assignes, and all other persons by whose hands or out of whose Lands any such person should
have Fee Rent Annuity or other Proffitt, or which at the time of the said Assessing shall have Goods or Chattells
or any other thing moveable of any such person or persons being indebted or owing such summe, and the
Distresses soe taken cause to be kepte appraised and sold in like manner and forme as is aforesaid for the Distresse
to be taken upon such persons to be taxed to the said Subsidyes and be insufficient to destraine within the Limitts
of the Colle&bholigct;ors Inhabitants or other Officers charged with or for the said Summes soe upon them to be taxed,
And if any such Distresse for non payment happen to be taken out of the [Limitts<ref idref="n116">116</ref>] of the said persons charged
and assigned to leavy the said persons soe charged for the leavying of any such summes by distresse shall perceive
and take of the same Distresse for the labour of every person goeing for the execution of every Mile that every
person soe laboureth for the same Two pence, And every Farmer Guardian Tennant Factor or other whatsoever
person being destrained or other person charged for payment of any such summe or summes or any other
summe by reason of this A&bholigct; shall be of such summe or summes of him or them soe levyed and taken
discharged and acquitted at his next day of payment for the same or at the delivery of such Goods and
Chattells as he that is soe destrained had in his custodie or governance against him or them that shall be
soe taxed and sett Any Grant or Writeing Obligatory or other whatsoever matter to the contrary made heretofore
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s133">
			<head>XXI. Persons distrained having no Lands, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p153">
				<emph type="i">Proceedings.; Imprisonment until Sums due, and also Fee for Arrest, paid.; Officer not executing Process; Penalty 20s.; Gaoler suffering Escape;; Penalty 40s. and Double Value of Rate and Fees.; Like Process for Subsidies due by any Person charged for another unpaid.; In default of Payment, Imprisonment.; Certificate by Commissioners.; Persons suspected to be not indifferently taxed refusing to appear or be examined.; Penalty 40s. or under, at Discretion of Commissioners.; Commissioners may punish by Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p154">And if any such person that should be soe destrained have noe Lands or Tenements sufficient whereby he or
his Tennants and Farmers may be destrained or have aliened eloyned or hid his Goods and Chattells whereby he
should or might be destrained in such manner that such Goods or Chattells should not be knowne or found soe
that the summe of or by him to be paid in the said forme shall not nor can be conveniently leavyed then upon
relation thereof to the C&bhooov;missers or soe many of them as by this A&bholigct; or the said C&bhooov;mission shall be thereunto
appointed where such person or persons was taxed and sett by the Oathes of him or them that shall be charged
with the leavying and payment of that summe or summes the said Co[m]missers shall make a Precept in such manner
as is aforesaid for to attach take and arreast the body of such person or persons that ought to pay the said
summes, And by this Act shall be charged with and for the said summe and summes and them soe taken safely
to keepe in Prison within the Shire or other place where any such person or persons shall be taken and attached
there to remaine without baile or mainprize untill they have paid the said summe or summes that such person
for himselfe or for any other by this A&bholigct; shall be chargeable or ought to be charged withall, And alsoe for the
Fees of every such Arreast to him or them that shall execute such Precept twenty pence, And that every Officer
unto whom such Precept shall be directed doe his true diligence and execute the same upon every person soe
being indebted upon paine to forfeite to the Kings Majestie for every defaulte in that behalfe Twenty shillings,
And that noe Keeper of any Goale from his Goale suffer any [such<ref idref="n117">117</ref>] person or persons to goe at large by letting
to baile or otherwise to depart out of his Prison before he have beene paid his said debt and the said Twenty
pence for his arreast upon paine to forfeite to the Kings Majestie Forty shillings, And the said Gaoler to pay to
the Kings Majestic the double value aswell of the Rate which the said [person soe imprisoned<ref idref="n117">117</ref>] was taxed at as
of the said Twenty pence for the Fees, And like Processe and Remedy in like forme shall be granted by the
said C&bhooov;missers or as many of them as by this A&bholigct; or the said Commission shall be thereunto appointed at like
information of every person or persons being charged with any summe of money for any other person or persons
by reason of the said Subsidyes and not thereof paid but wilfully withdrawen, nor the same leavyable within the
Limitts where such persons were thereunto taxed, And if the summe or summes being behinde unpaid by any
person or persons as is aforesaid be leavyed and gathered by force of the said Processe to be made by the said
C&bhooov;missers, or if in defaulte, or for lacke of payment thereof the person or persons soe oweing the said summe
and summes of money by Processe of the same C&bhooov;missers to be made as is aforesaid be c&bhooov;mitted to Prison in
forme abovesaid That then the said Comissers which shall award such Processe shall make Certificate thereof in
the said Exchequer of that shall be done in the Premisses in the Terme next following after such summe or summes
of money soe being behind shall be leavyed and gathered, or such person or persons for non-payment of the
same committed to Prison, And if it happen any of the said Collectors to be assigned or any Maiors Sheriffes
Stewards Constables the Headborough Burseholder Bayliffe or any other Officer or Minister or other whatsoever
person or persons to disobey the said C&bhooov;missers or any of them in the reasonable request to them made by the
said C&bhooov;missers for the execution of the said C&bhooov;mission, or if any of the Officers or other persons doe refuse
that to them shall appertaine and belong to doe by reason of any Precept to him or them to be directed or any
reasonable Commandment Instance or Request touching the premisses, or other defaulte in any Appearance or
Collection to make, or if any person [be<ref idref="n118">118</ref>] suspected not to be indifferently taxed as is aforesaid doe refuse to be
examined according to the tenour of this Act before the said C&bhooov;missers or as many of them as shall be thereunto
assigned as is aforesaid or will not appeare before the said C&bhooov;missers upon warning to him made or else make
resistance or rescues upon any Distresse upon him to be taken for any parcell of the said Subsidyes, or committ
any misdemeanour in any manner or wise contrary to this A&bholigct;, or committ any wilfull omission, or other whatsoever
wilfull doeing or misdoeing contrary to the tenour of this A&bholigct; or Grant, The same C&bhooov;missers and every number of
them above remembred or two of them at the least upon certaine knowledge of any such misdemeanours had,
by Information or Examination shall and may sett upon every such Offender for every such Offence in the name
of a Fine by the same Offender to be forfeited Forty shillings or under by discretion of the same C&bhooov;missers, And
further the said C&bhooov;missers and every number of them or two of them at the least shall have Authority by this
present Act to punish every such Offender by Impisonment there to remaine and to be delivered by their discretion
as shall seeme to them convenient, the said Fines if any such be to be certifyed by the said C&bhooov;missers that soe
assessed the same into the Kings Majestyes Exchequer there to be levyed and paid by the Collectors of that part
for the said Subsidyes returned into the said Exchequer to be therewith charged with the payment of the said
Subsidyes in such manner as if the said Fines had beene sett and taxed upon the said Offenders for the said
Subsidyes;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s134">
			<head>XXII. Allowance to High Collectors upon their Accounts.</head>
			<para id="p155">
				<emph type="i">Allowance to be paid by Collectors to Commissioners for Expences and Labour of their Clerks; Remedy for the same for Commissioners against Collectors; Commissioners, &amp;c. not compellable to make Presentments other than to Exchequer.; Head Collectors of Two first Subsidies not compellable to be Collectors of Two last.; Taking Fees of Accountants.; Penalty.; Imprisonment.; Commissioners at Meetings to shew Certificates and Presentments to the other Commissioners.; Indenture of Collectors Names, and of Sums written to Collectors, Fines, &amp;c. to be certified by Commissioners into the Exchequer.; Collectors answerable for their own Collection only.; Commissioners, if they cannot agree, &amp;c. may make several Indentures.; Collectors not chargeable for other Collectors.; Commissioners or Collectors, or Persons taxed, dying before discharged, Heirs and Executors chargeable as such Persons would have been if alive; Commissioners not thinking fit to join in one Certificate, Proceedings; Commissioners making default of Certificate, Process out of Exchequer against them</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p156">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by the said Authority of this present Parliament That every of the said High Collectors
which shall account for any part of the said Subsidies in the said Exchequer upon their severall Accounts to be
yeilded, shall be allowed at every of the said payments of the said Subsidyes for every pound limitted to his
Collection whereof any such Collector shall be charged and yeild Account Six pence as parcell of their charge
that is to say of every pound thereof for such person as then have had the perticular Collection of the Townes
and other places as is aforesaid specified in his Collection Two. pence, And other Two pence of every pound
thereof every of the said cheife Collectors or their Accomptants to retaine to their owne use for their labour and
charge in and about the premisses, And two pence of every pound residue to be delivered allowed and paid by
the said Collector soe being thereof allowed to such of the C&bhooov;missers as shall take upon them the busines and
labour for and about the premisses that is to say every Collector to pay that C&bhooov;missers or Comissers which had
the ordering of the Writeings of and for every of the said Subsidyes where the said Collector or Collectors had 
their Colle&bholigct;ion for the expences of the said C&bhooov;missers soe takeing upon them the said busines and labour of the
Clerks writeing the said Precepts and Extra&bholigct;s of the said Collections the said last Two pence of every pound to
be divided amongst the said C&bhooov;missers haveing regard to their labour and busines taken by them and their said
Clerks in and about the premisses, for which part soe to the said C&bhooov;missers appertaining, the said C&bhooov;missers Six
Five Fower Three or Two or as many of them as shall be thereunto appointed by this Act, or the Kings Majestyes
C&bhooov;mission, and every of them joyntly and severally for his and their said part may have his remedy against the
Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors which thereof have beene or might have beene allowed by Action of Debt, in which the
Defendant shall not wage his Law, neither Protection nor Injunction [nor<ref idref="n119">119</ref>] Essoigne shall be allowed, And that noe
person now being of the number of the Company of this present Parliament nor any C&bhooov;misser shall be named
or assigned to be any Colle&bholigct;or or Subcollector or Presenter of the said Subsidyes or any part thereof, nor any
C&bhooov;missers shall be compelled to make any Presentment or Certificate other then into the Kings Majestyes [said<ref idref="n120">120</ref>]
Exchequer of for or concerning the said Subsidyes or any part or parcell thereof, And likewise that noe other
person that shall be named and assigned to be C&bhooov;missers in any place to and for the execution of this Act of
Subsidyes be or shall be assigned or named Head Collector of any of the Payments of the said Subsidyes neither
of any part thereof, And that every such person and persons which shall be named and appointed as is aforesaid
to be Head Colle&bholigct;or of and for the payment of the said Two first Subsidyes or of any part thereof shall not
be compelled to be Colle&bholigct;or for the payment of the said two last Subsidyes nor any part thereof, And the said
Colle&bholigct;ors which shall be assigned for the Collection of the said Fower Subsidyes or of any part thereof and
every of them [be and<ref idref="n120">120</ref>] shall be acquitted and discharged of all manner of Fees and Rewards and of every other
charge in the Kings Majestyes Exchequer or concerning the same to be asked, And that if any person receive or
take any Fees Rewards or Pleasures of any such Accomptants or use any unnecessary delay in their Account that
then he shall forfeite to the Kings Majestie for every penny or value of every pennyworth Five shillings and Five
pounds to the party greived for every such delay and suffer Imprisonment at the Kings Majestyes pleasure And
after every taxeing and assessing of the said severall Subsidies as is aforesaid had or made and the said Extracts
thereof in Parchment unto the Colle&bholigct;or in manner and forme before rehearsed, delivered the said C&bhooov;missers which
shall take upon them the execution of this A&bholigct; within theire respective Limitts by their agreement shall have meeteings
together, at which meeteing every of the said C&bhooov;missers which then shall have taken upon them the execution of
any part of this Act shall by himselfe or his sufficient Deputie truely certifie and bring forth unto the said C&bhooov;missers
named by this Act or in the said C&bhooov;mission the Certificate and Presentment made before him and such other
C&bhooov;missers as were limitted with him in one Limitt, soe as the same Certificate may be accounted and cast with the
other Certificates within their respe&bholigct;ive Limitts, And then the said C&bhooov;missers and every number of them unto two
at the least as is aforesaid if any be in life, or their Executors or Administrators of their goods (if they then be
dead) shall joyntly and severally as they were divided within their Limitts under their Seales by their Discretions
make one or severall writeings indented containing in it aswell the names of the said Colle&bholigct;ors by the C&bhooov;missers
for such Colle&bholigct;ions and Accounts in the Exchequer and payments in the said receipt deputed and assigned as the
grosse and severall summes written unto every such Colle&bholigct;ors to receive the said Subsidyes And alsoe all Fines
Amerciaments and other Forfeitures if any such by reason of this A&bholigct; happen to be within their respective Limitts
and Precin&bholigct;s to be certified into the Kings Majestyes said Exchequer by the said C&bhooov;missers, in which writeing or
writeings indented soe to be certified shall be plainely declared and expressed the whole matter and entire s&bhouov;me or
s&bhouov;mes of the said Subsidyes severally limitted to the Collection of the said Collectors severally deputed and assigned
to the said summes soe as none of the said Collectors soe certifyed into the Exchequer shall be compelled there
to accompt or be charged but onely to and for the summes limitted to his Colle&bholigct;ion, and not to or for any
summe limitted to the Colle&bholigct;ion of his Fellowes, But every of them shall be severally charged for their part limitted
to their Collection, And if the said respe&bholigct;ive C&bhooov;missers amongst themselves in that matter cannot agree, or if any
of them be not ready or refuse to make Certificate with the other of the same C&bhooov;missers that then the said
C&bhooov;missers may make severall Indentures in forme aforesaid of their severall Limitts or Seperations of Colle&bholigct;ors
within their respe&bholigct;ive Limitts upon and in the Hundreds Wards Wapentakes Lathes Rapes or such other like
Divisions within their respe&bholigct;ive Limitts as the places there shall require to be severed and divided and as to the
same C&bhooov;missers shall seeme good, to make Divisions or other Limits or Colle&bholigct;ions for the severall charges of the
same Colle&bholigct;ors, soe that alwayes one Colle&bholigct;or shall be charged and accompt for his part to him to be limitted
onely by himselfe and not for any summe limitted to the part of any of his Fellowes, And the charges of every
of the Colle&bholigct;ors to be sett and certified severally upon them, And every such Colle&bholigct;or upon his accompt and
payment of the summe of money limitted within his Colle&bholigct;ion to be severally by himselfe acquitted and discharged
in the said Exchequer without paying any manner of Fees or Rewards to any person or persons for the same
upon paine and penalty last above mentioned and not to be charged for any portion of any other Collector, And
if any C&bhooov;misser after he hath taken Certificate of them, that as is aforesaid shall be before any C&bhooov;missers examined
and the Sumes rated and sett and the Bookes and Writeings thereof being in his hands, or if any Collector
or other person charged with any Receipt of any part of the said Subsidyes or any other person taxed or
otherwise by this A&bholigct; charged with or for any parcell of the said Subsidyes or with any other Summe Fine
Amerciament Penalty or other Forfeiture happen to dye before the C&bhooov;missers Colle&bholigct;ors or other whatsoever
person or persons have executed accomplished satisfyed or sufficiently discharged that which to every such person
shall appertaine or belong to doe according to this A&bholigct;, then the Executors and Heires of every such person and
all [others<ref idref="n121">121</ref>] seised of any Lands and Tenements that any such person being charged by this A&bholigct;, and disceasing before he be discharged thereof, or any other to his use onely had of an estate of Inheritance at the time that any
such person was named C&bhooov;misser, Collector or otherwise charged with or for any manner of thing to be done
satisfyed or paid by reason of this A&bholigct;, And all those that have in their possession or hands any Goods Chattells
Leases or other things that were to any such person or persons at the time of his death or any Lands or
Tenements that were the same persons at the time that he was as is aforesaid charged by this A&bholigct; shall be by the
same compelled and charged to doe and accomplish in every case as the same person soe being charged should
have done or might have beene compelled to doe if he had beene in plaine life after such Rate of the Lands and
Goods of the said Comisser and Colle&bholigct;or as the party shall have in his hands, And if the said C&bhooov;missers for
causes reasonable them moveing shall thinke it not fitt to joyne in one Certificate as is aforesaid, then the said
person or persons that shall first joyne together or he that shall first certifie the said Writeing indented as
is aforesaid shall certifie all the names of the C&bhooov;missers of that respe&bholigct;ive Division, Whereupon such Writeing
shall be there then to be certifyed with division of the Hundreds Wapentakes Wards Tythings and other places
to and among such C&bhooov;missers of the same Division with the names of the said C&bhooov;missers where such Seperations
and Divisions shall be, with the grosse Summes of money aswell of and for the said Subsidyes, and taxed or sett
of or within the said Hundreds Wards Wapentakes or other places to him or them divided or assigned that shall
soe certifie the said first Writeings, as of the Fines Amerciaments Penaltyes and other Forfeitures if any happen
to be within the same limitts whereof the same Writeings shall be certifyed And after such Writeings indented
which as is aforesaid shall be certifyed and not containe in it the whole and full summes sett and taxed within
the respe&bholigct;ive Limitts of the said C&bhooov;missers, the other C&bhooov;missers before the day of payment of the said Subsidy
shall certifie into the said Exchequer by their Writeing or Writeings indented to be made as is aforesaid the grosse
and severall summes sett and taxed within the places to them limitted for every of the said Subsidyes and other
Fines Amerciaments Penaltyes and Forfeitures with the names of the Hundreds Wards Wapentakes and other
places to them assigned or else by their said Writeings indented to certifie at the same place before the same
day of payment such reasonable causes for their excuses why they may not make such Certificate of and for
the said Subsidyes Fines Amerciaments and other Forfeitures growing or sett by reason of the causes of their
letts or for their not certifying as is aforesaid or else in defaulte thereof Processe to be made out of the Kings
Majestyes said Exchequer against the said C&bhooov;missers and every of them not makeing Certificate as is aforesaid
by the dire&bholigct;ion of the Treasurer and Barons of the said Exchequer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s135">
			<head>XXIII. Proviso for Stamford Baron.</head>
			<para id="p157">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Inhabitants of the Parish of
St Martins called Stamford Baron in the Suburbs of the Burrough and Towne of Stamford in the South part
of the Waters there called Wellands which hereafter shall be contributary to the payment of these present Subsidyes
granted to the Kings Majestie His Heires and Successors shall be assessed rated and taxed for the same by such
C&bhooov;missers which shall be appointed for the taxing rateing and assessing of the same Subsidyes within the County
of Lincolne, and shall be for the same contributary and pay the said Subsidyes to the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors which
shall be assigned and appointed for the leavying and gathering of the same with the Aldermen and Burgesses of
the same Burrough and Towne of Stamford,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s136">
			<head>XXIV. Persons having Spiritual and Temporal Possessions, and also Personal Property, not to be doubly charged.</head>
			<para id="p158">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every person and persons haveing
Mannours Lands Tenements and other Hereditaments chargeable to the payment of the said Subsidyes granted to
the Kings Majestie by this A&bholigct;, And alsoe haveing Spirituall Possessions charged to His Majestie by any Grant made
or to be made by the Clergy of this Realme in their Convocation, and over this haveing Substance in Goods
and Chattells chargeable by the said A&bholigct; That then if any of the said person or persons be hereafter charged
assessed and taxed for the said Mannours Lands and Tenements and Spirituall Possessions, and alsoe charged
assessed and taxed for his and their Goods and Chattells That then he or they shall be onely charged by vertue
of this A&bholigct; for his and their said Mannours Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Spirituall Possessions, or onely
for his said Goods and Chattells, the best thereof to be taken for the Kings Majestie and not to be charged for
both, or doubly charged for any of them, Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s137">
			<head>XXV. Exception for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey, and Guernsey.</head>
			<para id="p159">Provided alwayes That this grant of Subsidyes nor any thing therein contained in any wise extend not to
charge the Inhabitants of Scotland Ireland Jersey and Guernsey or any of them or for or concerning any Mannours
Lands Tenements or other Possessions Goods Chattells and other moveable Substance which the said Inhabitants
or Dwellers or any others to their use have within Scotland Ireland Jersey and Garnsey or in any of them, or of
for or concerning any Fees or Wages which any of the said Inhabitants or Dwellers have of the Kings Majesty
for their attendance and doeing service to our Soveraigne Lord the Kings Majestye in Scotland Ireland Jersey and
Garnsey or any of them, Any thing in this present Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s138">
			<head>XXVI. Proviso for Patents of Liberties, &amp;c. to Cities, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p160">Provided alsoe That all Letters Patents granted by the Kings Majestie or any of His Noble Progenitors to any
Cittyes Burroughes or Townes within this Realme of any manner of Liberties Priviledges or Exemptions from the
burthen and charge of any such Grants of Subsidyes which be at this present time in force and availeable shall
remaine good and effe&bholigct;uall to the said Cittyes Burroughes and Townes hereafter according to the purports thereof
Although the Inhabitants of the same and alsoe the said Corporations shall upon the great and weighty Considerations
of the Grant aforesaid be for this Grant charged and contributary in like manner forme and sorte as other Cittyes
Burroughes and Townes which be not in any wise priviledged but by this A&bholigct; charged</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s139">
			<head>XXVII. Orphans and Infants' not chargeable to Subsidies.</head>
			<para id="p161">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe Orphan or Infant within the age of
One and twenty yeares borne within any of the Kings Majestyes Dominions shall be charged to any payment of
these Subsidyes for his or their Goods or Chattells to him or her left or bequeathed Any thing in this A&bholigct;
contained to the contrary not withstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s140">
			<head>XXVIII. Universities of Oxford and Cambridge, Winchester College and Eaton College, the Poor Knights of Windsor, Free Schools and Reader, &amp;c. in the Universities of Oxford and Cambridege, and Hospitals, &amp;c. not chargeable.</head>
			<para id="p162">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; nor any thing, therein contained shall extend to the Lands or Goods of any
Colledge Hall or Hostell within the Universityes of Oxford and Cambridge or either of them, or to the Goods
or Lands of the Colledge of Winton founded by Bishop Wickham, or to the Goods or Lands of the Colledge of
Eaton next Windsor, or to the Lands Tenements or Revenues onely assigned and appointed for the sustentation
and liveing of the poore Knights founded in the Castle, or Colledge of Windsor by our late Soveraigne Lord King
Henry the Eighth or to any the Goods or Chattells of the same Knights or any of them or to the Goods or
Lands of any Common Free Grammer Schoole within the Realme of England and Wales or the Goods of any
Reader Schoole master or Schollar or any Graduate Resiant or remaining for Study without Fraude or Covin within
any the said Universityes and Colledges of Oxford and Cambridge or to any of them, or to any of their servants
tending dayly upon any of them, or to the Goods and Lands of any Hospitall Meason dieu or Spitle House
prepared and used for the sustentation and releife of poore people Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary
in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s141">
			<head>XXIX. Alien or Denizen assigning his Lands, &amp;c. to his Child, with Intent to defraud the Subsidy, such Child chargeable as an Alien.</head>
			<para id="p163">Provided neverthelesse and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid. That if any Alien or Stranger borne
Denizen or not Denizen and dwelling and inhabiting within this Realme of England shall assigne and convey over
unto his or their Childe or Children borne within the said Realme of England any his or their Lands Tenements
Goods or Chattells to the intent thereby to defraud the Kings Majestie of the said Subsidyes of or for the same,
that then all and every such Childe and Children soe being seised of any such Lands and Tenements and possessed
of any such Goods or Chattells shall be charged and chargeable to and with the payment of double the said
Subsidyes for the same Lands Tenements Goods and Chattells at the said Rates and Values as Aliens and Strangers
Denizens or not Denizens are before limitted and appointed to pay,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s142">
			<head>XXX. Inhabitants of Cinque Ports for the most Part of the Year before the Grant not chargeable during Resiance.</head>
			<para id="p164">Provided alsoe and be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the said Grant of Subsidyes or any thing therein contained doe
not in any wise extend or be prejudiciall or hurtfull to any of the Inhabitants or, Resiants haveing dwelt for the
most part of the yeare next before the taxeing and assessing of the Subsidyes aforesaid within the Five Ports Corporate
or to any their Members incorporated or united to the said Five Ports, or to any of the said Five Ports, But that
such the Inhabitants or Resiants as aforesaid in the said Five Ports Corporate and their Members be and shall be
of and from the said Grant and Payment of every of the said Subsidyes and every part thereof and onely dureing
their Resiance as aforesaid and noe longer, clearely acquitted and discharged, Any matter or whatsoever thing in
this present A&bholigct; had or made to the contrary notwithstanding;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s143">
			<head>XXXI. Inhabitants of Rumney Marsh in like manner not chargeable.</head>
			<para id="p165">Provided alsoe That the said Grant of Subsidyes doe not in any wise extend to be prejudiciall or hurtfull to
the English Inhabitants or Resiants at this present time within the Libertyes of Rumney Marsh of or for any part
of the said Summes granted in this present Parliament of the said English Inhabitants now there Resiants or any
of them, to be taxed sett asked levyed or paid, But that the English Inhabitants and now Resiants of Rumney
Marsh aforesaid and every of them be and shall be of and from the Grant [&amp; Payment<ref idref="n122">122</ref>] of the said Subsidyes
dureing their Resiance there and noe longer acquitted and discharged, Any matter and whatsoever thing in this
present A&bholigct; made to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s144">
			<head>XXXII. Regard to be had to Debts and former Subsidies</head>
			<para id="p166">Provided and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authoritie aforesaid That for the better Dire&bholigct;ions of
the said Comissers in the due execution of this A&bholigct; there shall be a restri&bholigct;ion as to the reall Value of Lands and
Goods by haveing regard to Debts and other necessary Expences, And with relation to former Presidents of
Subsidyes in the Raignes of King James and King Charles the first in the manner of taxing and levying thereof.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">by <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">sessing <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">His Majesties <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Charles Cheyney, Edmond Waller senior <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Nicholls <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Jonathan <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">John <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">Burrell Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Croodake <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">Johon <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">Cholmondeley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">Kn'&bholngs; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">Soutcote <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">Damare <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">Line <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">Brandling <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">Henry <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">Wandsford <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">Jennour <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">Soames <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">Thomas Reynolds <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">Hamby <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">Peyton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">Packer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">Best <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">Bar<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">John Bolles <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">Mayor, Walter <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">Binlos <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">Baber <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41">Francis <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n42" number="42">Quatremain <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n43" number="43">Le de <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n44" number="44">Janson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n45" number="45">Skeffington <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n46" number="46">Phillip <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n47" number="47">Sotterton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n48" number="48">Marlay <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n49" number="49">Wenman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n50" number="50">Whorwood <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n51" number="51">Townes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n52" number="52">Kn[ight]s <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n53" number="53">Pelliward <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n54" number="54">Woodroffe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n55" number="55">Chartley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n56" number="56">Edmond <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n57" number="57">Edmond <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n58" number="58">Burwell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n59" number="59">Catling <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n60" number="60">Stutevill <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n61" number="61">Mallyward <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n62" number="62">Robert Goswild <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n63" number="63">M<emph type="p">r </emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n64" number="64">Esquiers <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n65" number="65">Esq[uire] <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n66" number="66">Robert Fowle Thomas Luxford <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n67" number="67">Richard Musgrave Christopher Musgrave <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n68" number="68">Erule <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n69" number="69">Edward <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n70" number="70">John <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n71" number="71">Wancklyn <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n72" number="72">Andros <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n73" number="73">Dylkes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n74" number="74">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n75" number="75">Wynne <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n76" number="76">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n77" number="77">Vaughan <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n78" number="78">Griffith Lloyd Lewis Owen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n79" number="79">Tannatt <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n80" number="80">Morris <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n81" number="81">William Williams <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n82" number="82">Manaughty <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n83" number="83">Radnor <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n84" number="84">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.omits.</note>
			<note id="n85" number="85">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n86" number="86">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n87" number="87">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.omits.</note>
			<note id="n88" number="88">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n89" number="89">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n90" number="90">forfeiture of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n91" number="91">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n92" number="92">there to bee examined <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n93" number="93">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n94" number="94">in <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n95" number="95">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n96" number="96">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n97" number="97">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n98" number="98">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n99" number="99">Examinac[i]on Inform&bhocotil;ation <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n100" number="100">Delawar <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n101" number="101">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n102" number="102">by <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n103" number="103">same <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n104" number="104">their <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n105" number="105">as <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n106" number="106">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n107" number="107">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n108" number="108">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n109" number="109">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n110" number="110">for <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n111" number="111">hee <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n112" number="112">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n113" number="113">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n114" number="114">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n115" number="115">Marches <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n116" number="116">Limitt <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n117" number="117">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n118" number="118">being <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n119" number="119">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n120" number="120">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n121" number="121">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n122" number="122">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	
</report>


