<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47342" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act for Releife of such Persons as by Sicknes or other Impediment were disabled from subscribeing the Declaration in the A&bholigct; of Uniformity and Explanation of part of the said A&bholigct;. [Rot. Parl. 15 C. II. p. 2. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 14 (13 &amp; 14) C. II. c. 4.; &sect; 8</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas by an A&bholigct; of this present Parliament (entituled An A&bholigct; for Uniformitie of Publique Prayer and
Administration of the Sacraments and other Rites and Ceremonies and for establishing the Forme of
makeing ordaining and consecrating Bishops Priests and Deacons in the Church of England) it was ena&bholigct;ed That
every Deane Canon and Prebendary of every Cathedrall or Collegiate Church and all Masters and Fellowes of any
Colledge, Hall, House of Learning or Hospitall and every Parson Vicar Curate and every other person in Holy
Orders who upon the First day of May which should be in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred
sixtie and two or at any time thereafter should be Incumbent or have possession of any Deanary Canonry Prebend
Mastership Fellowship Parsonage Vicaridge or any other Ecclesiasticall Dignitie or Promotion should before the
Feast day of Saint Bartholimew which should be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixtie and
two subscribe the Declaration or Acknowledgement in the said A&bholigct; mentioned and expressed before their respe&bholigct;ive
Archbishops Bishops Ordinaries or Vice Chauncellors of the respe&bholigct;ive Universities upon paine that all and every
of the persons aforesaid faileing in such Subscription should loose and forfeite such respe&bholigct;ive Deanry Canonry
Prebend Mastership Fellowship Parsonage Vicaradge Ecclesiasticall Dignitie or Promotion and should be utterly
disabled and ipso fa&bholigct;o deprived of the same, And that every such respe&bholigct;ive Deanry Canonry Prebend Mastership
Fellowship Parsonage Vicaridge Ecclesiasticall Dignity or Promotion should be void as if such person soe faileing
were naturally dead, And that after such Subscription made every such Parson Vicar Curate and Le&bholigct;urer should
procure a Certificate under the Hand and Seale of the respe&bholigct;ive Archbishop Bishop or Ordinary of the Diocesse
and should publiquely and openly reade the same together with the Declaration or Acknowledgement aforesaid upon
some Lords day within three moneths then next following in his Parish Church where he was to officiate in the
presence of the Congregation there assembled in the time of Divine Service upon paine that every person failing
therein should lose such Parsonage Vicaridge or Benefice respe&bholigct;ively and should be utterly disabled and ipso
fa&bholigct;o deprived of the same, And that the said Parsonage Vicarage or Benefice should be void as if he were
naturally dead.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Recital that divers Persons of eminent Loyalty and known Affe&bholigct;ion to the Church of England were out of the Realm at the passing of the said A&bholigct;, and had no Notice thereof until after the Feast of St. Bartholomew, and others by reason of Sickness, &amp;c. had not complied with the said A&bholigct;; whereby such Persons were disabled and deprived of their Benefices; all such Persons declared to be restored;</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">And may hold their Benefices</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">And whereas diverse persons of eminent Loyaltie to His Majestie and of knowne affe&bholigct;ion to the Liturgie of the
Church of England who by the said A&bholigct; were required to subscribe the said Declaration or Acknowledgement at
the time of the passeing of the said A&bholigct; were out of this Realme in Ireland or other parts beyond the Seas upon
lawfull and justifyable Occasions and had noe knowledge or notice thereof untill their returne into England being
after the said Feast of Saint Bartholomew, And diverse other of the said Loyall and well affe&bholigct;ed persons by reason
of sicknes imprisonment disabilitie of body or otherwise could not, or did not resorte unto their respe&bholigct;ive Archbishops
Bishops or Ordinaries or Vice Chauncellours of the respe&bholigct;ive Universities before whom such Subscription was
appointed by the said A&bholigct; to be made All which said persons are by force of the said A&bholigct; utterly disabled and
ipso fa&bholigct;o deprived of their respe&bholigct;ive Deanries Canonries Prebendryes Mastershipps Fellowshipps Parsonages
Vicarages or other Ecclesiasticall Benefices or Promotions by reason of such their ommission, For remedy whereof
and for the releife of such persons Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice
and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by
Authoritie of the same That all Deanes Canons Prebendaries Masters and Fellowes of any Colledges Halls or other
Houses of Learning and all Parsons Vicars and other Ecclesiasticall persons aforesaid who at the time of the passeing
of the said A&bholigct; being in Ireland or any the parts beyond the Seas did not returne into this Kingdome before the said
Feast of Saint Bartholimew One thousand six hundred sixtie and two, or who being in England by Imprisonment
Sicknes Disabilitie of Body or otherwise did not resorte unto their respe&bholigct;ive Archbishop Bishop Ordinary or Vice
Chauncellour of the said respe&bholigct;ive Universities to subscribe the said Declaration and Acknowledgement before the
said Feast in the yeare of our Lord aforesaid shall be and are hereby declared to be restored unto and preserved in
their respe&bholigct;ive Deanryes Canonryes Prebends Masterships Fellowships Parsonages Vicarages and other Ecclesiasticall
Benefices and Promotions whereunto noe other person or persons before the first day of August in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred sixtie and three were or shall be lawfully instituted indu&bholigct;ed collated or placed,
And shall and may hold and enjoy the same according to his and their former right, The aforesaid A&bholigct; or any thing
therein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso that such Persons, if in England before the Nativity of our Lord, or if beyond Sea within 40 Days after return to England, subscribe the Declaration</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">and procure a Certificate; and publicly read the same, together with the said Declaration, within the time herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">Provided That every such Deane Canon Prebendary Master and Fellow of any Colledge, Hall or House of
Learning and all Parsons Vicars and Curates and other Ecclesiasticall persons who are, or shall by vertue of this
A&bholigct; be restored to, or preserved in their said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Promotions shall before the Feast of the
Nativitie of our Lord next ensueing if he be in England or if beyond the Seas within Forty dayes after his returne
into England subscribe the said Declaration or Acknowledgement before the respe&bholigct;ive Archbishop Bishop or
Ordinary of the Diocesse, or Vice Chauncellour aforesaid respe&bholigct;ively, And that every such Parson Vicar Curate
or Le&bholigct;urer shall procure a Certificate under the Hand and Seale of the respe&bholigct;ive Arch-bishop Bishop or Ordinary
of the Diocesse (who are hereby required and enjoyned upon demand to make and deliver such Certificate) And
shall publiquely and openly reade the same together with the Declaration or Acknowledgement aforesaid upon
some Lords day within three monethes [then<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] next following such Subscription in his Parish Church where he is
to officiate in the presence of the Congregation then assembled in the time of Divine Service.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Subscriptions made before Vicar General, Chancellor to Archbishop, &amp;c. or Commissary to Archbishop of Canterbury.</head>
			<para id="p6">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authoritie aforesaid That every Subscription already made or
hereafter to be made before any Vicar Generall or Chauncellour to any Archbishop or Bishop or Commissary to
the Archbishop of Canterbury or any other Bishop is and shall be as effe&bholigct;uall and beneficiall in Law to all intents
and purposes to every person and persons which have or shall make such Subscription as aforesaid as if the same
had beene made before the Archbishop or Bishop of the Province or Diocese respe&bholigct;ively, Any thing in the aforesaid
A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Persons having the Benefit of this A&bholigct; to make Allowance for serving Cure since Aug. 24, 1662.</head>
			<para id="p7">[Provided alsoe That every person who shall have benefit by this A&bholigct; shall make such Allowance for serveing
the Cure since the fower and twentyeth day of August One thousand six hundred sixtie two as shall be judged
fitt by the Ordinary of the place and shall pay and discharge all Tenthes Pensions and other Charges wherewith
the Benefice to which he is by this A&bholigct; restored hath beene or might be legally charged since the day aforesaid,<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Persons disabled to preach to be liable to the same Penalties as Persons prohibited.</head>
			<para id="p8">And whereas some Doubt hath arisen whether persons prohibited to preach by the said A&bholigct; are in the same
plight as to punishment with persons disabled by the said A&bholigct; to preach Be it declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie
aforesaid that the Penalties by the said A&bholigct; to be infli&bholigct;ed upon any person disabled by the said A&bholigct; to preach
for any offence against the said A&bholigct;, shall in like manner be infli&bholigct;ed upon every person soe offending that is prohibited
by the said A&bholigct; to preach, Any thing doubt or ambiguity in the said A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


