<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47341" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for regulating Select Vestryes.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Vestrymen in Parishes, &amp;c. where Sele&bholigct; Vestries are used on or before Sept. 29 next, and all Persons hereafter ele&bholigct;ed within One Month after Ele&bholigct;ion, before Ordinary, &amp;c. to make and subscribe the Declaration of 14(13 &amp; 14) C. II. c. 4.</head>
		<para id="p1">For prevention of the evills which may arise from Vestry men not conforming to the Government and Discipline
of the Church of England as it now is by Law established Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestic
by the Advice and with the Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Commons in. this present
Parliament assembled That all and every person who now is a Vestry man or member of any Vestry within any
Parish in the Cittyes of London and Westminster Borough of Southwarke and weekely Bills of Mortality and in
all other Cittyes Boroughes and Townes Corporate where Sele&bholigct; Vestryes are used in the Kingdome of England on
or before the Nine and twentyeth day of September next, And all and every person who at any time hereafter shall
be ele&bholigct;ed to be a Vestry man or member of any Vestry within any Parish in any the places aforesaid within one,
moneth after such his Ele&bholigct;ion shall before the respe&bholigct;ive Archbishop Bishop or Ordinary Viccar Generall or
Chauncellour of the Diocesse make and subscribe the Declaration and Acknowledgement enjoyned in the late
wholsome good A&bholigct; Entituled (An A&bholigct; for the Uniformity of Publique Prayers and Administration of Sacraments
and other Rites and Ceremonies and for establishing the Forme of makeing ordaining and consecrating Bishops
Preists and Deacons in the Church of England). in these words following</para>
		<para id="p2">I A B doe declare That it is not lawfull upon any pretence whatsoever to take Armes against the King and that
I doe abhor that Trayterous Position of takeing Armes by His Authoritie against His Person or against those that
are commissioned by Him, And that I will conforme to the Liturgy of the Church of England as it is now by
Law established, And I doe declare That I doe hold there lyes noe Obligation upon me or on any other person
from the Oath commonly called The Solemne League and Covenant to endeavour any change or alteration of
Government either in Church or State And that the same was in itselfe an unlawfull Oath and imposed upon the
Subje&bholigct;s of this Realme against the knowne Lawes and Liberties of this Kingdome,</para>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Negle&bholigct;ing, &amp;c. Deprived; and Persons having Right of Ele&bholigct;ion to proceed to a new Ele&bholigct;ion; Persons thereupon ele&bholigct;ed negle&bholigct;ing or refusing to make and subscribe the said Declaration, or such new Ele&bholigct;ion not being had within one Month, Ordinary may nominate Vestryman</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">And that all and every such person who shall negcle&bholigct; or refuse to doe the same within the respe&bholigct;ive times aforesaid
shall (ipso fa&bholigct;o) be deprived of such his place of Vestry man and of being a Member of such Vestry to all intents
and purposes and such place shall be a&bholigct;ually void as if such person were naturally dead, Any Usage or Custome
to the contrary notwithstanding, And that from and after such negcle&bholigct; or refusall it shall be lawfull for all
persons who shall have right of Ele&bholigct;ion or nomination of such Vestry man or member of such Vestry to proceede
to ele&bholigct;ion or nomination of some other discreete person of the respe&bholigct;ive Parish in the roome of such person soe
negcle&bholigct;ing or refuseing as aforesaid, And if such person soe to be ele&bholigct;ed in the roome of such person soe
negcle&bholigct;ing or refuseing as aforesaid shall alsoe negcle&bholigct; or refuse to make and subscribe the said Declaration and
Acknowledgement in manner and time aforesaid whereby such place shall againe become void, or if such persons
who shall have right of Ele&bholigct;ion or nomination as aforesaid shall not proceed to Ele&bholigct;ion within one moneth after
such Vacancy then it shall be lawfull to and for the respe&bholigct;ive Archbishop Bishop or Ordinary of the Diocesse
under his Hand and Seale to ele&bholigct; and nominate a discreete person of the respe&bholigct;ive Parish in such vacant roome,
which person soe to be ele&bholigct;ed and nominated after his makeing and subscription in manner and time aforesaid
shall be, and shall to all intents and purposes be reputed deemed and taken to be a Vestry man or member of
such Vestry in like manner as if he had beene chosen by the respe&bholigct;ive Ele&bholigct;ors Any Law Custome or Usage
to the contrary notwithstanding,</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Ordinary to grant Certificate of Subscription.</head>
		<para id="p5">And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the respe&bholigct;ive Archbishop Bishop or Ordinary Vicar-Generall
or Chauncellour of the Diocesse shall upon request to him made by any Vestry man soe makeing and subscribeing
the said Declaration and Acknowledgement aforesaid deliver a Certificate of his soe doeing for which noe Fee shall
be paid</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. A&bholigct; not to give new Power or confirm any usurped Power of Vestrymen.</head>
		<para id="p6">Provided alwayes That noething in this A&bholigct; shall be construed to give any new Power to any Sele&bholigct; Vestry man
or to confirme any usurped Power heretofore exercised by any Sele&bholigct; Vestry man which before the makeing of
this A&bholigct; is not warranted by the Law of the Land.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p7">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; shall continue in force to the end of the first Session of the next Parliament
and noe longer.</para>
	</section>
</report>

