<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47347" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XI. An Additionall A&bholigct; for the better ordering and colle&bholigct;ing the Duty of Excise and preventing the Abuses therein. [Rot. Parl. 15 C.II. p. 2. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Brewers, &amp;c. to give Notice to Officer of setting up, altering, or enlarging Tuns, Fats, &amp;c.; Not to keep or use private or concealed Storehouses, Cellars, &amp;c. Penalty.; Penalty on Persons occupying House, &amp;c. where such concealed Tuns, &amp;c. are.; Such concealed Tun, &amp;c and all the Beer, &amp;c. may be seized and sold for the Poor</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the preventing of the Fraudes and Deceites of Brewers and other persons who make Beere and Ale and
other Exciseable Liquors to sell, and of the abuses committed by the Officers Colle&bholigct;ors and Managers of
the Excise to the great decay of His Majesties Revenue of Excise and obstru&bholigct;ion of the due and orderly collecting
of the same and for supply and amendment of certaine defe&bholigct;s in the Lawes and Statutes relateing to the Duty
of Excise aswell for the support and advance of the said Revenue as for the ease of the people Be it ena&bholigct;ed
by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the
Commons in this Parliament assembled and by Authoritie of the same That noe common Brewer Innkeeper
Victualler or other Retailer of Beere or Ale shall at any time after the First day of September One thousand
six hundred sixtie three without first giveing notice thereof at the next Office of Excise or to the Commissioners
Farmers or Sub Commissioners of Excise or one of them within the Limitts and Jurisdi&bholigct;ion of whose Office he
or they doe or shall inhabite ere&bholigct; sett up alter or enlarge any Tun Fatt, Backe Cooler or Copper and shall
make use of any of them for the brewing or makeing any Beere or Ale or Worts, or shall make use of or keepe
any private and concealed Storehouse Celler or other place for the laying of any Beere or Ale or Worts in Caske
other then such as are already openly sett up, erected and made use of in his common and usuall Brewhouse
and now openly discovered and knowne upon paine to forfeite the summe of Fifty pounds for every Tun, Fatt,
Backe, Copper and Cooler sett up and made use of without such notice given [thereof<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] as aforesaid and contrary
to the true intent and meaneing hereof, And that all and every other person or persons in whose occupation any
House Messuage Outhouse or other place whatsoever is or shall be where any such private and concealed Tun,
Back, Cooler or Storehouse shall be found and discovered shall alsoe forfeite and lose the summe of Fifty pounds
to be leavyed and recovered in manner and forme as in and by this present A&bholigct; is hereafter directed and ordained,
And moreover every such private and concealed Tun, Fatt, Backe, Copper or Cooler soe discovered and found as
aforesaid or altered or enlarged together with all Beere Ale or Worts therein being shall and may be taken up,
seized carryed away and delivered to the Overseers for the Poore to be sold for the use of the Poore or distributed
amongst them.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners under 12 Car. II. cc. 23, 24. not to farm this Revenue.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">No Farmer capable of being nominated a Commissioners of Excise.; Penalty.; All Acts done by such Persons void.; Persons troubled by them may have their Action and recover Damages.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by Authoritie aforesaid That from and after the Eighth day of November in the
yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixtie and five noe person or persons whatsoever nominated by His
Majestie to be in Commission for the regulateing of His Majesties Revenue of Excise or for the Exercise of any
the Powers or Authorities mentioned in an A&bholigct; Entituled A Grant of certaine Impositions upon Beere Ale and other
Liquors for the encrease of His Majesties Revenue dureing His life or one other Act Entituled An A&bholigct; for takeing
away the Court of Wards and Liveries and Tenures in Capite by Knights Service and Purveyance and for setleing
a Revenue upon His Majestie in lieu thereof or in this present, A&bholigct; shall presume to farme the said Revenue of
His Majestie either dire&bholigct;ly or indirectly by obtaining Letters Patents to him or themselves thereof; or any person
or persons whatsoever intrusted for him or them or to or for his or their use benefitt or behoofe, Nor that any
person or persons whatsoever being a Farmer of the said Revenue shall be any way capeable to be nominated
Commissioner for the regulating His Majesties said Revenue of Excise or exerciseing any Powers or Authorities
concerning the same, But if any person or persons who stands thus disabled as aforesaid to be nominated a
Commissioner shall become a Farmer and shall in either of the said cases neverthelesse presume directly or indirectly
to a&bholigct; as a Commissioner Farmer or Sub Commissioner to execute the Powers and Authorities aforesaid either alone
or joyntly with other persons that are Farmers, or else with any [others<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] who are not Farmers shall from and after
such his a&bholigct;ing lose the benefitt of his said Farme, and be thenceforth totally for ever disabled to be either Farmer
of the said Revenue or Commissioner for the regulating thereof and exercising the Powers aforesaid, And that all
and every, a&bholigct; and a&bholigct;s done by any Commissioner or Commissioners or Sub Commissioners being Farmer or Farmers
by him or themselves or joyntly with others who are not Farmers shall be void in Law and of none effe&bholigct;t, And
that all and every person or persons any way molested or troubled by the command and authoritie of such Commissioner
or Commissioners a&bholigct;ing by him or themselves or together with others who are not Farmers or Commissioners may
bring his A&bholigct;ion at Law for the same in any of His Majesties Courts at Westminster and thereby recover his
Damages against any such Commissioner or Commissioners Any Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. All Letters Patent for the above Purpose void.</head>
			<para id="p5">And that all and every Letters patents to be made from and after the Tenth day of Aprill in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred sixtie and three inableing any Farmer or Farmers of the Excise to be Commissioner
or Commissioners or Sub Commissioners shall be utterly void and of none effect, Any thing in any of the said
A&bholigct;s to the contrary, notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Commissioners, Sub-commissioners, and Farmers giving false or corrupt Judgment; Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Persons unjuftly complaining of the Judgment of the Commissioners; Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">And that if any Commissioner or Sub Commissioner Commissioners or Sub Commissioners who by colour or
vertue of any Letters Patents are now both Commissioners or Sub Commissioners for regulating the said Revenue
and likewise Farmers of the said Revenue shall give any false and corrupt Judgement in advancement of the benefit
of his or their said Farme to the Brewers damage contrary to Law, he or they shall forfeite for every such Judgement
soe falsely and corruptly given double Costs to the partie soe injured by the said corrupt and false Judgement,
And in case any person shall unjustly complaine of (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) any Judgement of the Commissioners or Sub Commissioners as
aforesaid, and soe shall be found upon his Appeale the said partie shall forfeite double Costs to the said Commissioners
for such unjust vexations to be recovered by Information Bill or Plaint in any Court of Record.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Gaugers to deliver to Brewer, after Entry made, a true Copy of his Return.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 40s.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">And be it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That from and after the First day of September in the
yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixtie and three all and every Gager or Gagers of the Excise who
shall take an accompt of any Beere or Ale brewed or made by any common Brewer shall weekely after such
common Brewer hath made or ought to have made his Entry at the Office of Excise and not otherwise make
and deliver to such common Brewer at his house, or to some of his Servants in his behalfe a true Copy under
his or their hand of such Returne or Reporte as he or they have made thereof to the Commissioners or Sub
Commissioners of Excise respe&bholigct;ively upon paine to forfeit for every negcle&bholigct; or refusall the summe of Forty
shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Brewer not liable to Prosecution if he discharge himself within one Week from delivery.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided neverthelesse That noe such common Brewer or Brewers shall be sued or prosecuted for any penaltie
or forfeiture by him or them incurred for or by reason of any misentry or short Entry if he or they shall within
the space of One weeke after the delivery of such Copy as aforesaid rectifie his or their Entry according to the said
Returne or otherwise discharge himselfe</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Two Artists to be appointed, one by the Commissioners and one by the Brewer, to compute Gauge, &amp;c. on Oath;</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">who are to give a Copy of Contents to Commissioners and Brewer.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p12">Be it ena&bholigct;ed That from and after the said First day of September One thousand six hundred sixtie three and
as often as there shall be occasion Two able Artists shall be appointed one of them by His Majesties Commissioners
Farmers or Sub Commissioners for Excise and the other by the Brewers of any Citty or place, which said Artists
shall take an Oath, which Oath any one Justice hath hereby power to administer, to take and compute the just
Contents and Gage of all Coppers, Fatts, Tunns, Backes and Coolers and all other Brewing Vessells of that
nature belonging to all or any Brewer or Brewers of Beere or Ale to sell and to deliver and give under their
hands one Copy of the perticular Contents of all such Vessells to the aforesaid Commissioners Farmers and Sub
Commissioners and another true Copy thereof to each and every such respe&bholigct;ive Brewer, which Computation by
the Artists aforesaid shall answere and be according to the measures and proportions exprest in the said former
A&bholigct;s for Excise,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Commissioners, Farmers, Brewers, &amp;c. not to act as Justices of Peace touching the Excise.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Such Acts of such Persons void.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p14">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That noe Commissioner Farmer or Sub Commissioner for the Excise or common
Brewer of Ale or Beere to sell or Inn keeper whatsoever shall from and after the said First day of September
have power to act in or execute as a Justice of the Peace any of the Powers Clauses or things contained in any
of the Lawes made for and concerning the Excise or in this present A&bholigct;, And if any of the said persons shall
presume to a&bholigct; or execute any thing contrary hereunto It is hereby further declared That all such things soe a&bholigct;ed
or executed by any of them are and shall be utterly void and null to all intents and purposes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Recital of 12 C.II. c.23. &sect;18. 12 C.II. c 24. &sect; 32.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">and that Commissioners do not keep Officers in Towns where Entries may be made, and yet exact the Penalties of the said Acts.; Commissioners.; &amp;c. to appoint Persons in Market Towns to receive Entries.; Office to be published. Hours at which such Officer to attend.; Penalty.; Persons coming to such Market Town, and tendering Entry and Payment, not liable to Penalties.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p16">And whereas by the faid recited A&bholigct;s it is ena&bholigct;ed That noe person shall be compelled by the Commissioners
or Sub Commissioners of Excise to travell for the makeing of his Entryes or Payment of the Dutyes of Excise or
other [Clause<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] whatsoever touching or concerning the same if he live in a Market Towne out of the said Towne,
and if he live out of a Market Towne then to noe other place then to the next Market Towne to his habitation
in the same County on the Market day, and neverthelesse the Commissioners and Sub Commissioners or their
Officers have not accordingly kepte Officers in the Market Townes in many Countyes within England and Wales
whereby such Entryes and Payments for the Dutyes of Excise might be had and made and yet doe take and levy
the Penaltyes and Forfeitures in the said Acts mentioned for non Entry and Payment of the Duty and doe otherwise
thereupon grieve and vexe His Majesties Subje&bholigct;s contrary to the true intent and meaning of the said Acts, Be it
therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That from and after the said First day of September in the yeare of
our Lord One thousand six hundred sixtie and three the Commissioners Farmers or Sub Commissioners in each
County within England and Wales shall constitute and appoint or depute under their hands and seales such person
or persons as they shall thinke needfull in each respe&bholigct;ive Market Towne to be there upon every Market day in
some knowne and publique place for the receiveing of the said Entryes and Dutyes of Excise and for performing
all other matters and things touching the said Duty according to the said A&bholigct;s and this present A&bholigct;, which said
person and persons soe, constituted or deputed (and the place where they intend to hold or keepe such Office,
being on the next Market day after such Constitution or Deputation published in full and open Market) shall
attend at such Office on every Market day in such Market Towne and shall keepe the said Office open from Nine
of the Clocke in the morning untill Twelve of the Clocke at Noone, and from Two of the Clocke in the Afternoone
untill Five of the Clocke in the Afternoone, And in case such Office shall not be soe kepte and attended in each
Market Towne respe&bholigct;ively the Commissioners Farmers Sub Commissioners or other person or persons so negcle&bholigct;ing
or refuseing to doe the same shall for every Market day forfeite Ten pounds, the one halfe to the Kings Majestie
His Heires and Successors and the other halfe to him or them that will informe and sue for the same in any
of His Majesties Courts of Record by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information wherein noe Essoigne Protection
or Wager of Law shall be admitted or allowed, And such person as shall come to such Market Towne to make
such Entry or Payment of the Dutyes and shall tender the same according to the said A&bholigct;s and be able to prove
such Tender by the Oath of one or more sufficient Witnesse shall not be lyeable to any Penaltie or Forfeiture
imposed by the said Acts for such weekely or monethly Entryes or Payments as should have beene made or paid
on such Market day, Any Article Clause or Thing in any or either of the said A&bholigct;s or this present A&bholigct; to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Hours at which, on Notice, Brewer may sell and deliver Beer,; &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p18">And be it further enacted by [the<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Authoritie aforesaid That from and after the said First Day of September Noe
common Brewer of Beare or Ale shall sell deliver or carry out any Beere or Ale to any his Customers either in
whole Caske or by the Gallon in any Citty Towne Corporate or Market Towne before notice given to an Officer
of Excise but betweene the houres of the day hereafter mentioned (That is to say) From the Twenty fifth day of
March to the Twenty nineth day of September yearely betweene the houres of Three of the Clocke in the morning
and Nine of the Clocke in the evening, and from the Nine and twentyeth day of September to the Five and
twentyeth day of March yearely betweene the houres of Five of the clocke in the morning and Seaven of the
clocke in the evening upon paine that every Brewer doeing contrary hereunto shall for every such Offence forfeite
and loose the summe of Twenty shillings for every Barrell of Beere or Ale that shall be soe carryed out contrary
to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; to be leavyed and recovered as in and by this present A&bholigct; is hereafter ena&bholigct;ed
and appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Brewer, after Account taken by Gauger, converting Small Beer or Worts into Strong, or selling the same without Notice to Gauger, or concealing Beer, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p20">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by Authoritie aforesaid That if any common Brewer Innkeeper Vi&bholigct;ualler or other
Retailer of Beere or Ale shall at any time after the First day of September after an Accompt hath beene taken
by the said Gager or Gagers of the quantity and quality of the Beere Ale or Worts found in his Tun and other
Brewing Vessells convert, any part of his small Beere or small Worts soe taken account of into Strong Beere or
Ale by mingling letting downe or strikeing over any such Strong Ale or Strong Worts [into<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] which, or amongst any
such small Beere or small Worts, and shall sell, deliver out, or retaile the same or any part thereof without giveing
notice to the same Gager or Gagers of the quantity soe mingled and converted as aforesaid, or if any such Brewer
or Retailer as aforesaid shall after the said time hide conceale or convey any Beere Ale or Worts not gaged from
the sight or view of the Gager or Gagers appointed to take accompt of the same whereby the Kings Majestie or
his Commissioners or Farmers shall or may be defrauded in any manner of wise of the Dutyes due for the same
or any part thereof every such common Brewer Victualler and Retailer for every Barrell of Beere or Ale by him
or them soe mingled, converted, sold, delivered, hid, concealed or conveyed away contrary to the true intent and
meaning hereof, shall forfeite and loose the summe of Twenty shillings to be levyed and recovered in manner and
forme as in and by this present A&bholigct; is hereafter ordained and appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Brewing Vessels and Utensils liable to Duties and Penalties in whatsoever Hands they may be.</head>
			<para id="p21">And be it further declared and ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the Brewing Vessells and Utensills for Brewing
into whose hands soever the same shall come, and by what Conveyance or Title soever the same be claimed shall
be lyeable and subje&bholigct; unto, and are hereby charged with all and fingular the Debts and Dutyes of Excise in
arreare and oweing by any person or persons for [any<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Beare or Ale made within the said Brew house, and shall
alsoe be subject to all Penalties and Forfeitures incurred by such person or persons soe useing the said Brew house
for any offence against the Lawes and Statutes for Excise, And that it shall be lawfull in all cases to leavy Debts
and Penalties and use such Proceedings against the Utensills therein contained as it may be lawfull to doe in case
the Debter or Offender useing the said Utensills had beene truely and really Owner and Proprietor of the same,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Brewer compounding for Duties not to brew for any other Brewer without giving Notice to Commissioners, &amp;c. of the District.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And be it further enacted by Authority aforesaid That after the First day of September noe common Brewer of
Beere or Ale nor any other person whatsoever who hath or shall compound for the Dutyes of Excise for Beere
or Ale by him brewed or to be brewed shall dureing the terme of such Composition brew or make or suffer or
permitt any Beere or Ale to be brewed or made within his Brewhouse for any other common Brewer whatsoever
without first giveing notice as well of every perticular brewing as of the quantity and quality of the Beere and
Ale at every such brewing intended to be brewed and made unto the respective Commissioners Farmers or
Sub Commissioners of Excise within the Districts of whose Office such common Brewer doth or shall inhabite and
forthwith paying downe unto the said respective Commissioners Farmers or Sub Commissioners the full Excise of
all the said Beere and Ale, upon paine that aswell the Brewer who shall brew the same, as the Brewer for whom
the said Beere or Ale shall be brewed shall forfeite and loose for every Barrell the summe of Five Pounds, the
one moyety to the Kings Majestie, and the other moyetie to the Informer that shall sue for the same in any Court
of Record,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. No Person to sell or retail Coffee, Chocolate, &amp;c. without License, and giving Security for Payment of Duties.</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">Fee for Licence and Security.; Selling, &amp;c. without License.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And be it further enacted by Authoritic aforesaid That from and after the said First day of September noe person
or persons shall be permitted to sell, or retaile any Coffee, Chocolate Sherbett or Tea without Licence first obtained
and had by Order of the Generall Sessions of the Peace in the [severall and respective Countyes Certificate being first
shewed that they have given good Security for the (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) payment of their dues to the King,<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] or the Cheife Magistrate
of the place in whose Jurisdiction he or they doe or shall inhabite or dwell for the selling or retailing of the
same, nor shall any Licence be granted to any Retailer untill Securitie first given by Recognizance or otherwise,
For which License, Recognizance and Securitie Twelve pence shall be given and noe more for the payment of the
Excise, And every person or persons selling or retailing any of the said Liquors without License had and Security
given as aforesaid shall forfeite and loose the summe of Five pounds for every moneth he or they shall continue
selling or retailing the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Brewers, &amp;c. bribing Officers;</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound; 10.; Officer receiving Bribe; Penalty &pound;10.; How such Offences to be proved.; Penalties may be levied by Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">And be it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That from and after the said First day of September noe
Brewer or other person whatsoever shall bribe or corrupt, or give any Money Fee or other Reward whatsoever to
any Gager or Gagers or other Officer whatsoever to make any false Returne or Reporte into the office of Excise
of any Beere Ale or other Liquors exciseable made or brewed or to be made or brewed within his or their Charge
Division or Walke, or to forbeare or omit the doeing or executeing of his or their Places or Imployments upon
penalty of Ten pounds for every such Offence, And that noe Sworne Gager or Gagers or other Officer whatsoever
shall directly or indirectly take and receive any Bribe Money Fee Gift or other Reward of any Brewer or other
person whatsoever for any cause or matter relateing to the Excise upon Penaltie that every such Sworne Gager or
other Officer soe offending shall for every such Offence forfeite and loose the summe of Ten pounds, all and every
of which said respective offences shall be proved by the Oathes of Two lawfull and credible Witnesses before Two
Justices of the Peace or Cheife Magistrate of the place where such offence shall be committed which said Justices
or Magistrates respectively have hereby power to administer the said Oathes and alsoe to examine adjudge and
determine the same, and to cause such penalties by Warrant under their Hands and Seales to be leavyed by Distresse
and Sale of the Offenders Goods, rendring to the party the overplus and for want of such Distresse to committ
every such Offender to the common Gaole of such County [or Place<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] there to remaine by the space of Three
Moneths without Baile or Maineprize,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Foreign or imported Liquors not to be landed before Entry or Duty paid.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Warrant for landing to be signed by Officer.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">[And for the better leavying and collecting the Dutyes of Excise upon all forreigne or imported Liquors, Be it
enacted by Authority aforesaid That noe such forreigne or imported Liquors shall be landed or putt on shore out
of any Shipp or Vessell from beyond the Seas before due Entry he first made thereof with the Officer or Collector
appointed for the Excise in the Port or Place where the same shall be imported, or before the Duty of Excise
due and payable for the same be fully satisfyed and paid And that every Warrant for the landing or delivering
of any fuch Forreigne Liquors shall be signed by the hand of the said Officer or Collector of the Excise in the
said Port or Place respectively upon paine that all such Forreigne Liquors as shall be landed, putt on shore, or
delivered contrary to the true intent and meaneing hereof, or without the presence of an Officer or Waiter for
the Excise or the value thereof shall be forfeited and lost, the one moyetie to the Kings Majestie and the other
moyetie to him or them who shall or will seise informe or sue for the same to be recovered of the Importer or
Proprietor thereof,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Liquors coasted (Exception) not to be landed before Entry.</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">And that noe person or persons whatsoever bringing any Exciseable Liquors (except Beere Aile Sider Perry
and Metheglin) into any part or place of this Realme by Coast Cocquet Transire or Certificate, nor any person
or persons to whom the same or any of them shall be consigned shall land, or cause any such Exciseable Liquors
(except before excepted) to be landed or putt on shore without makeing or causeing due Entry to be made of
the same with the Officer or Officers of the Excise for the time being appointed to receive and take such Entryes
within the Port or Place where the same shall be landed upon paine in every such case as aforesaid to forfeite
double the value of the said Liquors landed or put on shore contrary to the true intent and meaning hereof,<ref idref="n9">9</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. On Appeal, Deposit of Single Duty to be made, and Security to Commissioners of Appeal.</head>
			<para id="p32">
				<emph type="i">If upon Appeal Original Judgment reversed, Deposit, or a fit Part thereof, to be restored to Appellant; and double Costs.; If Judgment affirmed, Appellant to pay the like Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p33">Provided alsoe and be it further enacted and ordained by Authoritie aforesaid That noe Appeale in any Cause
of Excise whatsoever shall be admitted untill the Partie Appellant shall have first deposited and laid downe the
single Duty of Excise in the hands of the Commissioners Farmers or Sub Commissioners of Excise within whose
Jurisdiction or Division the said Cause was originally heard and determined, and have given Securitie to the
Commissioners of Appeale or Justice of the Peace respectively where such Cause is to be finally adjudged for all
such Fine Forfeiture and Penaltie as upon such heareing and determination was adjudged against him, And that
if upon the heareing and determineing of any such Appeale the said Originall Judgement shall happen to be reversed
and made null, then and in every such case the said Commissioners Farmers or Sub Commissioners of Excise in
whose hands the said single Duty of Excise was deposited shall restore and deliver backe the same or as much
thereof as shall be adjudged by the Commissioners of Appeales or Justices of the Peace respectively to the said
Appellant, and the partie originally prosecuteing shall pay him double Costs, But in case the first Judgement shall
be affirmed the partie appealing shall pay the like Costs unto the Commissioner or Commissioners complained of
Any thing in this Act or in any other Act or Statute whatsoever to the contrary thereof contained in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Duty to be paid by Persons making Vinegar Beer.</head>
			<para id="p34">And be it further enacted by Authoritie aforesaid That all and every person or persons whatsoever brewing or
makeing any Beere whether in a common Brew house or otherwise for sale, or to convert into Vinegar for sale
shall pay for every Barrell of such Vinegar Beere soe made and brewed the severall and respective summes already
imposed and sett by any the Acts of Excise above mentioned upon Vinegar Beere brewed by any common Brewer
in any common Brew house, Any thing in the said Acts or either of them to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Proviso for Colleges, &amp;c. brewing their own Beer.</head>
			<para id="p35">It is hereby further declared That every Colledge and Hall in either of the Universities which before the Duty
of Excise was imposed did brew their owne Beere and Ale within their owne Precincts and size it out to their
respective Members within their owne Precincts onely are not lyeable to the payment of any Duty of Excise for
the same either by this or any the forementioned Acts.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Appeals to be heard in the proper County.</head>
			<para id="p36">Provided alsoe and be it enacted That all Differences Appeales and Complaints that shall happen and, arise
betweene partie and partie in order to the payment of the Duty of Excise shall be heard and determined in the
proper Countie or in the severall Rideings and Divisions of Yorkeshire and Lincolneshire where they shall arise
and not elsewhere</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Commissioners, &amp;c. taking Fees or Reward for taking Bonds, &amp;c. Penalty 10s.</head>
			<para id="p37">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That noe Farmer Commissioner Sub Commissioner or other
Officer of Excise shall directly or indirectly take or receive any Money Fee or Reward for or concerning the
takeing of any Bond, or giveing any Receipt or Note in Writeing relateing to the Excise to or from any person
or persons whatsoever upon paine that every such person soe offending shall for every such offence forfeite the
summe of Ten shillings</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Justices of Peace, &amp;c. to meet to determine Offences.</head>
			<para id="p38">And be it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Justices of the Peace or any two or more of
them or Cheife Magistrates in the severall Countyes Cittyes Divisions and Places within England and Wales respectively
shall meete once in every Moneth in their respective Divisions or oftener if there shall be occasion to heare determine
and to adjudge all matters and offences against this or the aforesaid Acts</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. How Penalties to be disposed of;</head>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">and recovered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p40">And be it further enacted by the Authoritie aforesaid That one third part of all Fines Penalties and Forfeitures
not herein otherwise disposed shall be to the Kings Majestie His Heires and Successors and one other third part
to the Poore of the Parish where the Offence shall be committed, and the other third part to him that shall
informe and sue for the same And that all Fines Penalties and Forfeitures for which noe remedy is ordained for
recovery thereof by this Act shall be recovered by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Informations in any Court of
Record within such County Citty or Corporation where the Offence shall be committed or by such other wayes
and meanes and in such manner as by the said former Act is directed and appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Limitation of Appeals in London;</head>
			<para id="p41">
				<emph type="i">in the Country</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p42">Provided alwayes That after the said Third Day of September noe Appeale in any Matter or Cause of Excise
within the immediate Limitts of the Cheife Office of London, nor within the Limits of the present Farme of
London dureing the continuance of such Farme shall be admitted unlesse the same be brought within Two Monethes
next after the first Judgement and notice thereof given or left at the Dwelling house of the party or partyes
concerned therein, nor shall any Appeale in any Matter or Cause of Excise in any other County Citty Towne or
Place be admitted unlesse the same be brought within Fower Moneths after the first Judgement and notice given
as aforesaid, Any thing in this Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Commissioner, Farmers, &amp;c. to take the Oath of 12 Car. II. c.23.</head>
			<para id="p43">Provided neverthelesse and it is hereby enacted That noe Commissioner Farmer Sub Commissioner or other
person imployed or to be imployed in the farmeing collecting or takeing Accompts for the Duty of Excise doe
after the First day of September next take upon him or them any such Office, or proceed in execution of any
such Imployment untill he or they have first taken the Oathes appointed to be taken by the Act of Parliament
Entituled A Grant of certaine Impositions on Beere Ale and other Liquors for the encrease of His Majesties Revenue
dureing His life before the respective persons appointed in the said Act of Parliament, and have entred his
Certificate for takeing the said Oathes with the Auditor for Excise under the Penaltie of Fifty pounds for every
Moneth he or they shall soe negclect to take the same</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph> omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Cause <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">due <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


