<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47344" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act to prevent the selling of live fatt Catle by Butchers. [Rot. Parl. 15 C.II. p. 2. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 3 &amp; 4 Ed. VI. c. 19. &sect; 3.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.; Butchers not to sell fat Cattle alive.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; made in the Third and Fourth yeares of the Raigne of King Edward the Sixth it
is ena&bholigct;ed That noe person useing the Craft or Mistery of a Butcher should buy any fatt Oxen Steeres
Runts Kine Heifers Calves or Sheepe and sell the same againe alive upon paine of forfeiture of the Catle soe
sold which Law hath not wrought such effe&bholigct;uall reformation as was intended by reason of the difficultie in the
proofe of such buying and selling being for the most, part at places far distant if not in severall Countyes, by
meanes whereof the parties soe offending have escaped unpunished Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in
this present Parliament assembled and by Authoritie of the same That noe person useing the Trade of a Butcher
shall at any time from and after the Feast of Saint Michaell the Arch Angell next ensueing sell offer or expose
to sale in any Market or elsewhere either by himselfe or any Servant or Agent whatsoever any Fatt Oxen [Strees,<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
Runts, Kine, Heifers Calves Sheepe or Lambes alive upon paine to forfeite the double Value of the Catle soe
sold, or offered or exposed to sale as aforesaid, the one moyetie of which Forfeiture shall be to the Kings Majestie
H,s Heires and Successors and the other moyety to him or them that will sue for the same in any of His Majesties
Courts of Record by Bill Plaint A&bholigct;ion of Debt or Information wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law
shall be allowed</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">Steeres <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


