<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47354" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for the assembling and holding of Parliaments once in Three yeares at the least, And for the repeale
of an A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for the preventing of Inconveniencies happening by the long Intermission of
Parliaments.[Rot. Parl. 16 C. II. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that 16 Car. I. c. 1. is in Derogation of the Crown. </head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The said A&bholigct; repealed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the A&bholigct; made in the Parliament begun at Westminster the Third day of November in the Sixteenth
Yeare of the Raigne of our late Soveraigne Lord King Charles of blessed Memory entituled An A&bholigct; for
the preventing of Inconveniencies happening by the long Intermission of Parliaments is in Derogation of His
Majestyes just Rights and Prerogative inherent to the Imperiall Crowne of this Realme for the calling and
assembling of Parliaments, And may be an occasion of manifold mischeifes and inconveniences, and much endanger
the Peace and Safety of His Majestie, and all His Leidge People of this Realme, Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the
Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
the C&bhooov;mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the said A&bholigct; entituled
An A&bholigct; for the preventing of Inconveniencies happening by the long Intermission of Parliaments And all and every
the Articles Clauses and Things therein contained is, shall be and are hereby wholly repealed annulled and utterly
made void, And are hereby declared to be null and void to all intents and purposes whatsoever as if the said
A&bholigct; had never beene had or made, Any thing in the said A&bholigct; contained to the contrary (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. No longer Intermission of Parliaments than Three Years.</head>
			<para id="p3">And because by the auntient Lawes and Statutes of this Realme made in the Raigne of King Edward the Third
Parliaments are to be held very often Your Majesties humble and loyall Subje&bholigct;s the Lords Spirituall and Temporall
and the C&bhooov;mons in this present Parliament assembled most humbly doe beseech Your most Excellent Majestie,
That it may be declared and ena&bholigct;ed And bee it declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That hereafter
the sitting and holding of Parliaments shall not be intermitted or discontinued above three yeares at the most,
but that within three yeares from and after the determination of this present Parliament and soe from time to
time within three yeares after the determination of any other Parliament or Parliaments, or if there be occasion
more often, Your Majestie Your Heires and Successors doe issue out Your Writts for calling, assembling and
holding of another Parliament to the end there may be a frequent calling assembling and holding of Parliaments
once in Three yeares at the least.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">in any wise <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


