<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47355" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act for preventing of Abatements of Writts of Error upon Judgements in the Exchequer.[Rot. Parl. 16 C. II. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 31 Eliz. c. 1. &sect;1.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.; The not coming of the Lord Chancellor or Lord Treasurer shall not abate Writs of Error if either of the Chief Justices are in the Exchequer Chamber.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by a Statute made in the One and thirtyeth yeare of the Raigne of the late Queene Elizabeth
It is ena&bholigct;ed That the not comeing of the Lord Chauncellour and Lord Treasurer or either of them at
the day of Adjournment in any Suite of Error depending by vertue of the Statute of the One and thirtyeth yeare
of the Raigne of King Edward the Third therein mentioned concerning Error made in the Exchequer shall not be
any Discontinuance of any such Writt of Error, But if both the Cheife Justices of either Bench, or any one of
the said great Officers the Lord Chauncellour or Lord Treasurer shall come to the Exchequer Chamber and there
be present at the day of Adjournment in such Suite of Error, It shall be noe Discontinuance but the Suite shall
proceede in Law to all intents and purposes as if both the Lord Chauncellour and Lord Treasurer had comen,
and beene present at the day and place of Adjournment, Which Statute doth not provide a Remedy in case the
said Lord Chauncellour and Lord Treasurer or either of them shall not be present at the dayes and times of the
Returnes of such Writts of Error although it be within the same mischeife Justice being delayed, And the partyes
in such Cases being putt to begin new Suites to their great Charges and Prejudice by reason of the absence and
not comeing of the said great Officers Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with
the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in Parliament assembled and by
Authoritie of the same That the not comeing of the Lord Chauncellour and Lord Treasurer or either of them at
the day of Returne of any Writt of Error to be sued forth by vertue of the said Statute made in the said One
and thirtyeth yeare of the Raigne of the said King Edward the Third shall not cause any Abatement or Discontinuance
of any such Writt of Error, But if both the Cheife Justices of either Bench or either of them or any one of the
said great Officers the Lord Chauncellour or Lord Treasurer shall come to the Exchequer Chamber and there be
present at the day of Returne of any such Writt of Error it shall be noe Abatement or Discontinuance, But the
Suite shall proceede in Law to all intents and purposes as if both the Lord Chauncellour and Lord Treasurer had
commen and beene present at the day and place of [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] returne of such Writt.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. But no Judgment given unless Lord Chancellor and Treasurer be present.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes That noe Judgement shall be given in any such Suite or Writt of Error, unlesse both the
Lord Chauncellour and the Lord Treasurer shall be present thereat.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


