<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47367" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664 &amp; 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An A&bholigct; for repealing of part of an A&bholigct; of Parlyament intituled An A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ing the prosecution of such as are
accomptable for Prize Goods.[Rot. Parl. 16 &amp; 17 C. II. nu. 5]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 14 (13 &amp; 14) C. II. C. 14. &sect; 2.; and that divers Officers and Mariners have been or may be sued contrary to St. 12 C. II. c. II. and to His Majesty's Proclamation of the 14th July 1662.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.; The said A&bholigct; repealed as to Admirals, &amp;c. Mariners and Seamen. ; All Process against them to cease.; And none of the said Officers or Mariners to be arrested, &amp;c.; but shall henceforth stand acquitted from all Suits, &amp;c.; This A&bholigct; to be expounded most beneficially for the said Officers and Mariners, &amp;c.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; made in this p&bhopcrl;sent Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; [for<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] dire&bholigct;ing the prosecution of such
as are accomptable for Prize Goods It is amongst other things ena&bholigct;ed That all and every Admiralls ViceAdmiralls Captaines of Shipps Officers and Marriners that did surprize or receive to or for the publique use or
by pretence thereof any Shipps, Plate, Jewells, Bullion, Money, Silver, Gold, Armes, Ammunition, Wares, Merchandices
or any manner of Goods whatsoever seized or taken for Prize betwixt the Thirtyeth of January One thousand six
hundred forty two, and the nine and twentyeth of May One thousand six hundred sixty, And that had not at
the makeing of the said A&bholigct; truely accompted for and paid in the same or the just Provenues thereof should be
chargeable to His Majestie for the said premisses and convened and sued for in His Majesties Court of Admiralty,
and called to accompt, or otherwise by such Suite &amp; in such manner as should be most availeable to His Majestie,
And in case of defe&bholigct; of Jurisdi&bholigct;ion in the said Court of Admiralty, then upon Certificate thereof from the said
Court of Admiraltie made into His Majestyes Court of Exchequer speedy proceedings were to be had in the said
Court of Exchequer for the recovering and levying of the Prizes Goods matters and things as by the said A&bholigct;
relation being thereunto had more plainely fully and at large appeares, Whereupon diverse Captaines and Officers
of His Majestyes Fleetes and severall others the Commanders Officers and Mariners imployed in the Sea service
have beene sued or may possibly be sued concerning [the<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] severall Prizes and Prize-goods by them heretofore
seized and taken at Sea, or in Ports since the Moneth of January One thousand six hundred forty two, and before
the Twenty ninth of May One thousand six hundred sixty contrary to the grace and favour extended towards
them not onely in and by His Majestyes most gracious A&bholigct; of Free and Generall Pardon Indempnitie and Oblivion,
but alsoe by a Proclamation since made by His Majestie beareing date the Fowerteenth day of July One thousand
six hundred sixty two in the Fowerteenth yeare of His Majestyes Raigne declareing His Majestyes grace and favour
towards all Commanders and Seamen in relation to Prizes and Prize goods seised and, taken since the Moneth of
January One thousand six hundred forty two untill the nine and twentyeth of May One thousand six hundred sixty
His Majestie thereupon willing that His Grace and Favour towards all Admiralls Vice-Admiralls Commanders Sea-men
and Marriners should take its full effe&bholigct; And being fully satisfied of their dutyfull affe&bholigct;ions unto His Majestyes
Royall Person and Government and for their future incouragement to persevere loyally in His Majestyes Service
is most graciously pleased that it may be ena&bholigct;ed, And bee it ena&bholigct;ed [by the Kings most Excellent Majesty<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] by
and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Co&bhooov;mons in this present Parlyament
assembled and by(<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) Authority of the same That the said A&bholigct; intituled An A&bholigct; for dire&bholigct;ing the prosecution of such
as are accomptable for Prize Goods and all and every Branches Clauses Powers and Articles and every matter and
thing therein contained for soe much onely, and as for and concerning all and every Admiralls Vice-Admiralls
Captaines of Shipps Officers of Shipps or Vessells Sea-men and Mariners and every of them shall be and is hereby
from henceforth repealed annulled and made void, and of noe effe&bholigct; to all intents and purposes whatsoever And
that all and singular Processe and Proceedings whatsoever which before this time have beene, now are, or may be
at any time hereafter had sued forth and prosecuted in any of His Majestyes Courts at Westminster or in the
High Court of Admiralty of England or elsewhere within any His Majestyes Dominions against any Admiralls
Vice-Admiralls Captaines of Shipps Officers, of Shipps or Vessells Seamen and Marriners or any of them by force 
and vertue of the said A&bholigct;, or any Article or Clause therein contained be forthwith and for ever hereafter superseded
surseased stayed and discharged, And that none of the said Admiralls Vice-Admiralls Captaines or Officers of Shipps
or Vessells Sea men or Mariners shall from henceforth by vertue force or colour of any Processe or Proceedings
whatsoever in any of His Majestyes said Courts or elsewhere be in any wise arreasted disquieted questioned or
troubled either in their Persons Lands or Goods for or by reason of the said A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained,
But that all and every the said Admiralls Vice-Admiralls Captaines and Officers of Shipps or Vessells and all
Seamen and Marriners and every of them shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; stand and be for ever discharged and acquitted
in all Courts and Places, and of and from all Suites and Proceedings whatsoever sued of begun, or to be sued
or begun against them or any of them for any manner of Prizes Shipps or Goods whatsoever by them or any
of them seised surprized or any [wayes<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] taken betwixt the said Thirtyeth of January One thousand six hundred
forty&deg; two and the Nine and twentyeth of May One thousand six hundred sixty and of and from all Accompts
[Troubles<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Articles and Suites whatsoever concerning the same; And that this A&bholigct; shall be taken and expounded
in the most large and beneficiall manner for the said Admiralls Vice-Admiralls Commanders Captaines and Officers
of Shipps and Vessells and Sea-men and Marriners and every of them, and for their best advantage for the finall
free and absolute :acquitting and dischargeing of them and every of them of and from all the said Prizes and
every part. thereof, and all Shipps and Vessells and Goods whatsoever, or of what nature or kinde soever by them
or any of them seised surprized or in any sort taken betwixt the said Thirtyeth of January One thousand six
hundred forty two, and the said Nine and twentyeth of May One thousand six hundred sixty.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. No other Persons, who have not accounted, discharged.; except those who are discharged by 12 Car. II. c. II.; but such other Persons shall remain chargeable.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed. That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be
construed to extend to discharge any other persons whatsoever but onely the said Admiralls Vice-Admiralls Commanders
Captaines of Shipps and Officers of Shipps or Vessells and Sea men and Marriners but that all and every Colle&bholigct;ors
and Treasurers Subcolle&bholigct;ors and Undertreasurers of Prize-Goods Co&bhooov;mis?ers and Sub Co&bhooov;mis?ers of Prize-Goods and
all and every their Casheers Deputyes Officers and Receivers other then such person or persons who are discharged
by the A&bholigct; of Free and Generall Pardon Indempnitie and Oblivion that have not yet truely accompted or paid in
the Provenues of the Prizes or Moneyes ariseing thereout seized or taken betwixt the said Thirtyeth of January
One thousand six hundred forty two and the said Nine and twentyeth of May One thousand six hundred, sixtie
and all and every other person and persons by whom or to whom, or to or for whose use any Prizes or Prize
Shipps Plate Jewells Armes Ammunition Wares Merchandices or any manner of Goods whatsoever seised or, taken
for Prize betwixt the said Thirtyeth of January One thousand, six hundred forty two, and the said Nine and
twentyeth of May, One thousand six hundred sixty were disposed or sold or, to whose hands they came, and who
had and enjoyed the same or any part thereof, and are still behinde and have not paid in the moneyes contra&bholigct;ed
for, and ariseing or due upon, such Sales or Dispositions or any of them, and all Securityes by them and every of
them given for, or touching the premisses or any thing concerning the said Prizes or any of them shall be chargeable
to Your Majestie for the said premisses and all the Dependences thereof respe&bholigct;ively in the said Court of Admiralty
or Exchequer, and shall be proceeded upon in the said Court of Admiralty or Exchequer in Your Majestyes Name
and to and for Your Majestyes use according to the said A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ing the prosecution of such as are accomptable
for Prize Goods and as fully and entirely as if this A&bholigct; had never beene, Any thing, in this present A&bholigct;
notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">wise <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


