<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47363" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664 &amp; 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An A&bholigct; for regulateing the Measures and Prices of Coales.[Rot. Parl. 16 &amp; 17 C. II. nu. I.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Sea Coal to be sold by the Chaldron.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Contents of a Chaldron.; Other Coal sold by Weight.; Penalty.; Before whom Complaints may be made.; Penalties how to be levied.; Who shall set the Prices of Coals sold by Retail.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">For avoiding the [manifold deceits exa&bholigct;ions and abuses used in the Measures and [Seales<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of Coales, and for
preventing the like and the better regulation thereof for the time to come Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in
this present Parlyament assembled and by Authoritie of the same That from and after the Sixth day of March
in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty fower all sorts of Coale commonly called Sea Coales
brought into the River of Thames and sold shall be sold by the Chaldron containing Thirty six Bushells heaped
up, and according to the Bushell sealed for that purpose at Guildhall in London and soe for a greater or lesser
quantity, And that all other sorts of Coales comeing from Scotland and other places commonly sold by Weight
and not by Measure shall be sold by Weight after the proportion of a hundred and twelve pound to the hundred
of Avoirdupois weight without any fallacy or deceit upon paine of forfeiture of all the Coales which shall be
otherwise sold or exposed to sale by any Woodmonger or Retailer of Coales, and the double value thereof to be
recovered by any person or persons that will prosecute for the same in any Court of Record, or by way of
complaint made unto the Lord Maior of London for the time being, and Justices of Peace within the Citty of
London and Libertyes thereof, or to any two of them, or to the Justices of Peace of the severall and respe&bholigct;ive
Countyes and Places where such Coales shall be exposed to sale or any of them who are hereby impowered and
required to call the Partyes before them and to heare and examine such complaint upon Oath which by vertue of
this A&bholigct; is to be administred by them or any Two of them, and upon due proofe thereof made to their satisfa&bholigct;ion
to convi&bholigct; the Offenders, and to give Warrant under their Hands and Seales for levying the Forfeitures accordingly,
the one halfe thereof to be to and for the use of the person or persons soe Prosecuteing or complaining, and the
other halfe to and for the use of the Poore, or repairing of the Highwayes within the same Parish or any other
adjoyning Parish or Parishes to be appointed and apportioned by the dire&bholigct;ion of the said Lord Maior and Justices
by such their Warrant as aforesaid, And the said Lord Maior of London and the Court of Aldermen for the
time, being, and the Justices of Peace of the severall Countyes respe&bholigct;ively or any three or more of them, whereof
one to be of the Quorum are hereby impowered to sett the Rates and Prices of all such Coales as shall be sold
by Retaile as they from time to time shall judge reasonable allowing a competent proffitt to the said Retailer
beyond the price paid by him to the Importer and the ordinary charges thereupon accrueing.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Refusing to sell at those Rates; Officer may enter upon Wharf, &amp;c. and sell.</head>
			<para id="p3">And that if any Ingrosser or Retailer of such Coales shall refuse to sell as aforesaid That then the said Lord
Maior and Aldermen, and Justices of Peace respe&bholigct;ively are hereby authorized to appoint and impower such Officer
or Officers or other persons as they shall thinke fitt to enter into any Wharfe or other place where such Coales
are stored up, And in case of refusall takeing a Constable to force entrance, and the said Coales to sell, or cause
to be sold at such Rates as the said Lord Maior and Aldermen and Justices respe&bholigct;ively shall judge reasonable
rendring to such Ingrosser or Retailer the money for which the said Coales shall be soe sold necessary charges
being dedu&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided That this A&bholigct; shall continue for three yeares next ensueing, and thenceforth to the end of the next
Session of Parlyament and noe longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. No Offender to be punished by any other A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">In A&bholigct;ions for executing A&bholigct; General Issue may be pleaded.; Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">Provided alsoe That noe person or persons that shall be sued by vertue of this A&bholigct; for not observeing thereof
shall be sued upon any other A&bholigct; or Law now in force for the same offence, And if any A&bholigct;ion shall be commenced
against any Justice of Peace Constable or other Officer or Person for any thing done by colour of this A&bholigct; the
Defendant in every such A&bholigct;ion may pleade the Generall Issue and give the speciall matter in Evidence, And if
the Verdi&bholigct; be found for him, or [if<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] the Plaintiffe become nonsuited shall recover and have his Damages and
double Costs of suite for his unjust Vexation in that behalfe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Coal-seller to set Prices.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwayes That noe person haveing any Interest in any Wharfe used for the receiving or uttering of
Coales, or that doth or shall trade by himselfe or others in his owne or any other name in the sale of any Coales,
or the engrossing the same in order to sell the same and not for his owne private use onely shall a&bholigct; or otherwise
intermedle in the setting the Price of Coales, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Sales <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


