<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47370" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664 &amp; 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IX. An A&bholigct; to impower the Chauncellour of the Dutchy to grant Commissions for takeing Affidavits within the
Dutchy Liberty.[Rot. Parl. 16 &amp; 17 C. II. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Chancellor of the Dutchy may empower Persons to receive Affidavits concerning Matters depending in the Dutchy Court.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">For the greater east and benefit of the Inhabitants within the County Palatine of Lancaster and other places
within severall other Countyes of this Kingdome within the Survey of the Court of Dutchy Chamber at
Westminster in the takeing of Affidavits in the Countrey to be made use of, and read in Causes depending and
to be depending within the said Court, Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the
advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall, and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and
by the Authoritie of the same That the Chauncellour of the said Dutchy and County Palatine of Lancaster for
the time being shall and may by one or more Commission or Commissions from time to time as need shall require
impower what and as many persons as he shall thinke fitt and necessary within the said County Palatine and other
Dutchy Libertyes to take and receive all and every such Affidavit or Affidavits as any person or persons shall be
willing and desireous to make before any of the persons soe impowered in, or concerning any cause matter or
thing depending or hereafter to be depending in the said Court of Dutchy Chamber as Masters of Chauncery in
Extraordinary doe use to doe, which said Affidavits shall be field in the Office of the Clerke of the Court of the
Dutchy, and then be read and made use of in the said Court to all intents and purposes as other Affidavits taken
in the said Court now are.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners Fee.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided That for the takeing of every such Affidavit the person or persons soe impowered and takeing the
same shall for soe doeing receive onely the Summe or Fee of Twelve pence and noe more.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


