<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47375" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1665</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for restraining Non-Conformists from inhabiting in Corporations.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that divers Persons in Holy Orders had not declared their Assent to the Matters required by 14 (13 &amp; 14) Car. II. c. 4.; and that they and divers other Persons not duly ordained had settled in Corporations.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Such Persons to take the Oath following.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas diverse Parsons Vicars Curates Le&bholigct;urers and other persons in Holy Orders have not declared
their unfaigned assent and consent to the use of all things contained and prescribed in the Booke of
Common Prayer and Administration of the Sacraments and other Rites and Ceremonies of the Church according
to the use of the Church of England, or have not subscribed the Declaration or Acknowledgement contained in
a certaine A&bholigct; of Parlyament made in the Fowerteenth yeare of His Majestyes Raigne and Intituled An A&bholigct; for
the Uniformity of Publique Prayers and Administration of Sacraments and other Rites and Ceremonies and for the
establishing the forme of makeing ordaining and consecrating of Bishops Priests and Deacons in the Church of
England according to the said A&bholigct; or any other subsequent A&bholigct;. And whereas they or some of them and diverse
other person &amp; persons not ordained according to the Forme of the Church of England, and as have since the
A&bholigct; of Oblivion taken upon them to preach in unlawfull Assemblyes Conventicles or Meeteings under colour or
pretence of Exercise of Religion contrary to the Lawes and Statutes of this Kingdome have setled themselves in
diverse Corporations in England sometimes Three or more of them in a place thereby takeing an oportunity to
distill the poysonous Principles of Schisme and Rebellion into the hearts of His Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s to the great
danger of [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Church and Kingdome. Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with
the Advice and Consent of the Lord's Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament
assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the said Parsons Viccars Curates Le&bholigct;urers and other persons
in holy Orders, or pretended holy Orders, or pretending to holy Orders, and all Stipendaryes and other persons
who have beene possessed of any Ecclesiasticall or Spirituall Promotion and every of them who have not declared
their unfaigned assent and consent as aforesaid and subscribed the Declaration aforesaid and shall not take and
subscribe the Oath following.</para>
		<para id="p3">I A B doe sweare That it is not lawfull upon any pretence whatsoever to take Armes against the King And
that I doe abhorr that Traiterous Position of takeing Armes by His Authoritie against His Person or against
those that are co&bhooov;missionated by Him in pursuance of such Co&bhooov;missions And that I will not at any time endeavour
any Alteration of Goverment either in Church or State.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Persons preaching in Conventicles not to come within Five Miles of any Corporation sending Members to Parliament,; (Exception); before they have taken the said Oath.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;40.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p5">And all such person and persons as shall take upon them to preach in any unlawfull Assembly Conventicle or
Meeting under colour or pretence of any Exercise of Religion contrary to the Lawes and Statutes of this Kingdome
shall not at any time from and after the Fower and twentyeth day of March which shall be in this present yeare
of our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty and five unlesse onely in passeing upon the Road come or
be within Five miles of any Citty or Towne Corporate or Burrough that sends Burgesses to the Parlyament within
His Majesties Kingdome of England Principallitie of Wales or of the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede or within
Five miles of any Parish Towne or Place wherein he or they have since the A&bholigct; of Oblivion beene Parson Viccar
Curate Stipendary or Le&bholigct;urer or taken upon them to preach in any unlawfull Assembly Conventicle or Meeting
under colour or pretence of any Exercise of Religion contrary to the Lawes and Statutes of this Kingdome before
he or they have taken and subscribed the Oath aforesaid before the Justices of Peace at their Quarter Sessions
to be holden for the County Rideing or Division next unto the said Corporation Citty or Burrough Parish Place
or Towne in open Court (which said Oath the said Justices are hereby impowered there to administer) upon
forfeiture of every such offence the summe of Forty pounds of lawfull English money, the one Third part thereof
to His Majestie and His Successors, the other Third part to the use of the poore of the Parish where the offence
shall be committed and the other Third part thereof to such person or persons as shall or will sue for the same
by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Plaint Bill or Information in any Court of Record at Westminster or before any Justices of
Assize Oyer and Terminer or Goale delivery or before any Justices of the Countyes Pallatine of Chester Lancaster
or Durham or the Justices of the Great Sessions in Wales or before any Justices of Peace in their Quarter Sessions
wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Such Persons, or those not frequenting the Established Church, not to teach in any public or private School, &amp;c. </head>
			<para id="p6">Penalty &pound;40.</para>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That it shall not be lawfull for any
person or persons restrained from comeing to any Citty Towne Corporate Burrough Parish Towne or Place as
aforesaid or for any other person or persons as shall not first take and subscribe the said Oath and as shall not
frequent Divine Service established by the Lawes of this Kingdome and carry him or herselfe reverently decently
and orderly there [to teach any Publick or Private School<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] or take any Boarders or Tablers that are taught or
instru&bholigct;ed by him or herselfe or any other upon paine for every such offence to [forfeit the sum of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Forty pounds
to be recovered and distributed as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Two Justices may commit Offenders charged on Oath, unless they make and subscribe Oath and Declaration.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided alsoe and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That it shall be lawfull for any two
Justices of the Peace of the respe&bholigct;ive County upon Oath to them of any offence against this A&bholigct; which Oath
they are hereby impowered to administer to committ the Offender for Six Monethes without Baile or Maineprize,
unlesse upon or before such Commitment he shall before the said Justices of the Peace sweare and subscribe the
aforesaid Oath and Declaration.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Persons served with Process.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alwayes That if any person intended to be restrained by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall without fraude or covin
be served with any Writt Subpena Warrant or other Processe whereby his personall appearance is required, his
obedience to such Writt Subpena or Processe shall not be construed an offence against this A&bholigct;.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

