<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47377" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1665</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for continuance of a former Act for regulateing the Presse.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>14 (13 &amp; 14) C. 11. c. 33. continued.</head>
		<para id="p1">Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestye by and with the advice and Consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled That an A&bholigct; made in the
fowerteenth yeare of the Raigne of Our Soveraigne Lord the King that now is entituled An A&bholigct; for preventing
Abuses in printing seditious treasonable and unlicensed Bookes and Pamphletts and for regulating of Printing and
Printing Presses shall be continued with the Alterations and Additions made in and by this A&bholigct; and shall remaine
in force untill the [end of the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] First Session of the next Parlyament.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>III. Every Printer, except the Two Universities, to reserve Three Copies, and deliver them to the Master of the Stationer's Company, one for the King, and one for each of the Universities.</head>
			<para id="p2">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That from and after the Six and twentyeth day of December One thousand six
hundred sixty five Every Printer within the Citty of London or in any other place except the Two Universityes
shall reserve Three printed Copies of the best and largest. Paper of every Booke new printed or reprinted by him
with Additions, and shall before any publique vending of the said Booke bring them to the Master of the Company
of Stationers and deliver them to him, One whereof shall by the said Master of the said Company of Stationers
within Ten dayes after he hath soe received the same be delivered to the Keeper of his Majestyes Library, and
the other two within the said ten dayes to be sent to the Vice Chauncellour of the two Universityes respe&bholigct;ively
for the use of the publique Libraries of the said Universityes</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. University Printers to do the like.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Printers or Master of the Company offending; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed That the Printers in the said Universityes and every of them respe&bholigct;ively from and
after the said Six and twentyeth day of December shall deliver one such printed Copy as aforesaid of every Booke
soe new printed or reprinted in the said Universityes or in either of them to the Keeper of His Majestyes Library
as aforesaid as alsoe to the Vice-Chauncellour of either of the said Universityes for the time being, two other
such printed Copyes for the use of the publique Libraries of the said Universityes respe&bholigct;ively. And if any of the
Printers aforesaid or the said Master of the Company of Stationers shall not observe the dire&bholigct;ion of this A&bholigct;
therein That then he and they soe makeing defaulte in not delivering the said printed Copies as aforesaid shall
severally forfeit besides the value of the said printed Copies the summe of Five pounds for every Copy not soe
delivered, as alsoe the value of the said printed Copyes not soe delivered, The same to be recovered by His
Majestie His Heires and Successors and by the Chauncellour Masters and Schollers of either of the said Universityes
respe&bholigct;ively by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster
wherein noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

