<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47378" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act for attainting Thomas Dolman Joseph Bampfield and Thomas Scott of High-Treason if they render not themselves by a day.[Rot. Parl. 17 C. II. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that the said Persons adhere to the King's Enemies beyond Sea.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The said Persons not returning into the Realm, and rendering themselves, by a Day, to stand attainted of High Treason</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">In all humble manner shew unto Your most Excellent Majestie Your Majestyes most dutyfull and loyall Subje&bholigct;s
the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons assembled in Parlyament That whereas it is notoriously
knowne that Thomas Dolman Joseph Bampfield alias Stepner and Thomas Scott sonne of Thomas Scott lately
executed as a most execrable Traitor and one of the horrid and bloody murderers of His late Royall Majestie
King Charles the First of ever blessed Memory contrary to the duty of their Allegiance have most trayterously
and wickedly adheered and still doe adheere to Your Majestyes Enimies beyond the Seas where they as yet remaine
and committ diverse Treasonable a&bholigct;s without any sence of Loyaltie to Your Majestie or of naturall Affe&bholigct;ion to
their native Country May it therefore please Your most Excellent Majestie That it may be ena&bholigct;ed And bee it
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the consent and advice of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and Co&bhooov;mons in this present Parlyament assembled That if the said Thomas Dolman Joseph Bampfield
alias Stepner and Thomas Scot shall not returne into the Realme of England and render themselves to some or
one of His Majestyes Justices of the Peace for the County wherein he or they shall first arrive at or before the
first day of February next ensueing and alsoe abide their legall Tryall for such their Treasons then every of them
the said Thomas Dolman Joseph Bampfield alias Stepner and Thomas Scott not rendring himselfe as aforesaid
or not abideing his Tryall aforesaid shall from and after the said First day of February stand and be adjudged
attainted of High Treason to all intents and purposes whatsoever and shall suffer and forfeite as a person attaint
of High Treason by the Lawes of the Land ought to suffer and forfeite</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. All Persons beyond Sea not rendering themselves, upon Proclamation made, attainted of High Treason.</head>
		<para id="p3">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every person and persons who now are
or hereafter shall be beyond the Seas and whom His Majestye by any of His Royall Proclamations to be issued
under the Great Seale of England dureing the continuance of this Warr with the States of the United Provinces
shall name and require to returne into England and render themselves by a certaine day therein to be mentioned
to some or one of His Majestyes [Justices<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Peace for the County wherein he or they shall first arrive and
shall not returne and render themselves accordingly and abide their legall Tryall shall from and after the day to
them to be prefixed by such Proclamation stand and be attainted of High Treason to all intents and purposes
and shall suffer such paines and penaltyes and undergoe all such forfeitures as persons attainted of High Treason
ought to doe,</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. The Time allowed to render.</head>
		<para id="p4">Provided That the time to be prefixed by such Proclama&bhocotil;n for the persons therein to bee named to render
themselves be not lesse then the time and terme of three Kalandar monethes from and after the Date of such
Proclamation</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Persons serving the United Provinces in certain Places attainted of High Treason.</head>
		<para id="p5">And bee it further declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every His Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s
who from and after the First day of February next ensueing shall at any time dureing the continuance of the
said Warr serve the States of the United Provinces either by Land or Sea as a Souldier or Seamen [on this side
the Straights or from and after the First day of May in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty
and six within the Straights, Or from and after the First day of August in the said yeare One thousand six
hundred sixty six in Affrica or America or any where beyond the Straights on this side the Equino&bholigct;iall, Or from
and after the First day of February in the said yeare One thousand six hundred sixty six in the East Indyes or
any part beyond the Equino&bholigct;iall<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] shall be and are hereby attainted of High Treason and shall suffer and forfeite to
all intents and purposes as persons attainted of High Treason ought to doe.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
	</section>
</report>


