<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47372" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664 &amp; 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XI. An A&bholigct; for drayning of the Fenn called Deeping Fenn and other Fenns therin mentioned.(<ref idref="n1">1</ref>)[O. nu. 21.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of an Order by Commissioners of Sewers, 20th August 41 Eliz.; another Order, that Thomas Lovell Esquire should be admitted to undertake the draining of Deeping Fen.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The said Orders confirmed by Parliament, I Jac. I. pr. ; Recital that the said Thomas Lovell entered on the said Lands; and that by the Negle&bholigct; of the Assigns of the said Thomas Lovell the said Lands, and also other Lands in Holland; have been overflowed.; The said former Decrees and A&bholigct; of Parliament repealed, except as herein mentioned.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas at a Session of Sewers holden at Bourne in the County of Lincolne the Twentieth day of
August in the One and fortieth yeare of the Raigne of Queene Elizabeth for the Recovery and dreyning
of certaine Fennes in Holland and Kesteven in the County of Lincolne called or knowne by the names of Deeping
Fenn Pinchbecke and Spalding South Fenn Thurlby Fenn Bourne South Fenn and Croyland Fenn al[ia]s Goggushland
It was by the Commissioners then and there assembled ordered and decreed That the Summe of Twelve thousand
pounds should be levyed and gathered upon the Lords and Inhabitants of certaine Townes in Kestiven and Holland
Commoners in the said Fennes for drayning the same and should bee paid in to certaine persons therin nominated
to receive the same at or before the Tenth day of September then next ensueing which said summe being negcle&bholigct;ed
to be paid the said Fenns by reason therof could not, bee drayned according to the Forme by the said Law intended
The said Com<emph type="p">rs</emph> therefore well tendering the great proffitt that would arise to all persons concerned and to the
C&bhooov;monwealth in generall if the same might be drained At severall Sessions of Sewers held at Markett Deeping
the Twentieth day of September in the said One and fortieth yeare of Queene Elizabeth and at Market Deeping
aforesaid the Twentieth day of August in the Two and fortyeth yeare of the Raigne of the said Queene did
ordaine and decree That the said Fennes and Marsh Grounds should be forthwith taken in hand to be drayned
And that Thomas Lovell Esq&bhoqesq; (a man skilfull in workes of that nature) should be admitted to undertake the same
under the Covenants therin mentioned, And in pursuance therof the said Thomas Lovell did undertake the said
Workes and made some progress therin And afterwards one third part of the said severall Fennes were by the
said Commissioners of Sewers sett out by Meets and Bounds and allotted to the said Thomas Lovell in recompence
of his costs charges [and endeavours applyed and expended therin, And after the said third part was by the [s[ai]d <ref idref="n2">2</ref>]
Com<emph type="p">rs</emph> of Sewers decreed to the said Thomas Lovell and his Heires in recompence of his said worke of drayning
and of his charges and expences therin To have and to hold to the said Thomas Lovell his Heires and Assignes
for ever And whereas by an A&bholigct; of Parliament made at Westminster in the First yeare of King James entituled
An A&bholigct; for releife of Thomas Lovell Esq&bhoqesq; the above recited Decrees of Sewers were ratified and confirmed
and the said third part of the said Fenns and Marsh Grounds as they were allotted and sett out by the said
C&bhooov;mis?ers were by the said A&bholigct; ordained ena&bholigct;ed and established to be held by the said Thomas Lovell his
Heires and Assignes for ever under the Provisoes Conditions and Appointments in the said Decrees and A&bholigct; of
Parliament mentioned and expressed as by the said A&bholigct; of Parlyament and Decrees of Sewers more fully may
appeare And, whereas the said Thomas Lovell immediately after the makeing the said A&bholigct; of Parlyament entered
into the said Lands sett out and assigned as a third part of the said severall Fennes and by vertue of the said
Decrees and A&bholigct; of Parliament became seised therof and he and his Heires and Assignes have ever since till of late
yeares held and enjoyed the same untill (by some negcle&bholigct; in the Assignes of the said Thomas Lovell and Fayler
in the maintaining scowering and cleansing the said Banckes Rivers Sewers and other Workes necessary thereunto)
occasioned by some differences arising betweene the said Assignes of the said Thomas Lovell and the Lords Owners
and Commoners of the said Fennes about the enjoyment of some additionall recompence alloted to the said Assignes
of the said Thomas Lovell by a subsequent Law of Sewers (made at Spalding) not onely the said Fenns and
Marsh Grounds are returned into their auncient condition of being hurtfully surrounded and annoyed with Waters
but a great and considerable part of some adjacent Townes of Holland have beene overflowed and laid desolate
and many Habitacio&bhocotil;ns and Families who formerly lived comfortably there, utterly ruined and destroyed thereby and
yet continue in manifest danger in all seasons of wett weather and floods to fall into the said calamities Which
great mischeife is by long and indubitable experience found to arise principally from severall imperfe&bholigct;ions in the
said Decrees &amp; A&bholigct; of Parliament To the end therfore that the said Country being in its owne nature very rich
and fertile and wherin the King, and Queenes Ma?ye His Mother have large Possessions (and many auntient
Families and Inhabitants their whole subsistance) may not longer remaine in such manifest danger of being utterly
lost nor the Commonwealth continue longer deprived of those advantages which would arise from the performance
of the said Workes Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestye by and with the consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Comons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authority of the same That
the said Decrees and A&bholigct; of Parliament above mentioned and every Clause Article and thing therin contained other
then such as are herein after mentioned ena&bholigct;ed ratified and confirmed shall be and are hereby repealed and made
void to all intents and purposes whatsoever</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Recital that the Earl of Berkshire, Lord Andover, &amp;c. have formerly held and derived Title, by Conveyances from William late Earl of Exeter and Elizabeth late Countess of Exeter, in the said third Part of the Lands so allotted to the said Thomas Lovell, and other Proportions, and that the said Earl, &amp;c. had expended great Sums of Money in draining, and are ready, as herein mentioned, to complete the same. ; Edward Earl of Manchester and others named Undertakers to drain the Fens.</head>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">What they undertake to do.; The Undertakers to maintain the Banks forever; and to cleanse Glean and Welland Rivers, and keep them Navigable.; What Streams they may divert.; To acquit all other Persons of the draining and repairing.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p4">And in as much as the Right Hon<emph type="p">ble</emph> Thomas Earle of Berkshire and the Lady Elizabeth, his Wife and Charles
Lord Howard of Charlton commonly called the Lord Viscount of Andover their Eldest Sonne and Heire Apparent
The Right Honourable Robert Lord Bruce Baron of Wharlton in the Kingdome of England and Earle of Elgin
in the Kingdome of Scotland and the Lady Diana his Wife The Right Honourable Anne Countesse of Stamford
and Thomas Lord Grey of Groby have formerly held and derived to themselves with Remainders over to severall
other Persons by severall Conveyances from or under the Right Honourable William late Earle of Exeter and
Elizabeth late Countesse of Exeter or one of them severall Interests in the said third part of the said Lands
allotted to the said Lovell his Heires and Assignes and to other proportions by subsequent Decrees of Sewers and
towards the drayning and maintaining therof they the said Right Honourable William late Earle of Exeter and
Elizabeth late Countesse Dowager of Exeter under whom or one of whom they clayme, and Thomas late Earle
of Exeter from whom the said William late Earle and Elizabeth late Countesse Dowager of Exeter derived their
Title have expended severall great Summes of Money but have not soe fully effe&bholigct;ed the said Workes nor
introduced those Benefitts &amp; Advantages which were expe&bholigct;ed And for reason doe alleadge that the third part
and subsequent Allotments are not recompence sufficient to answere the charge of a more perfe&bholigct; performance of
the said Worke but offer to proceed and perfe&bholigct;ly to effe&bholigct; the same if they may have a sufficient recompence and
compensation for their Hazard Charge and Paines therin Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That Edward
Earle of Manchester Lord Chamberlaine of His Majesties Household William Earle of Devonshire John Lord
Berkley of Stratton Anchatill Grey Esquire Henry Grey Esquire and their Heires and Assignes and the Survivour
of them shall bee and are hereby declared to be the Undertakers for the drayning of the said Fenns and every of
them in trust to and for such person and persons and to such Intents and purposes as are herein after mentioned,
And that within the space of Seaven yeares next ensueing they their Heires and Assignes shall and will at their
proper. Costs and Charges recover and make dry the said Fennes and every of them and make the same firme
and depasturable for Catle at all times of the yeare except Two or three hundred Acres or therabouts in the said
Fenns called Deeping Fenn and Goggisland, and Forty Acres or thereabouts in the said Fenns called Thurlby Fenn
and Bourne South Fenn which are to be left for Lakes and Sykes for the receipt of Waters within the same
And alsoe except such Draines and Sewers as now be or hereafter shall be made within the said Fenns or any
of them for the draining therof, and soe much of the Grounds adjoyning to the Rivers Draynes and Sewers within
the said Fenns as lye or shall lye betweene the said Rivers Draynes or Sewers and the Banckes made or to be
made for keeping the Waters lyeing in the said Rivers Draines or Sewers from overflowing the rest of the said
Fenns And alsoe shall for ever hereafter at their owne Costs and Charges not onely repaire exalt maintain and
keepe as need shall require the Banckes environing and encompassing the said Fenns and every of them but alsoe
the Bancke on the East side of the River of Welland from a place in Crowland called Brother House to Spalding
High Bridge, And alsoe the Bancke on the North side of the River Gleane from Gutheram Coate to a place called
Dovehurne in Pinchbecke and therof and of all and every the said Bancks above named shall for ever hereafter
exonerate acquitt discharge and save harmelesse as well the Kings Majestye His Heires and Successors as the Queene
Dowager her Tennants and Under Tennants and all other person and persons theire Heires and Assignes of and
for their repairing and amending of their severall parts and allotments of the same but alsoe that they the said
Trustees theire Heires and Assignes, and the Survivor of them at theire owne proper Costs and Charges shall for
ever maintaine and keepe the Rivers of Gleane and Welland with sufficient Dyking Roading Scowering and Bancking
(viz<emph type="p">t</emph>) The River of Welland from the Outgang at the East end of East Deeping leading into the said Fenns unto
the Outfall therof into the Sea, And to preserve and maintaine the Navigation therof without Imposition or paying
any thing whatsoever for the same but with liberty to alter and divert the Course and Channell of the same into
any other part or parts of the said Fenns before it cometh to the said Corner of Deeping Fenn abutting upon
Hawthorne. Bancke from whence through the said Towne of Spalding as it now passeth to the Sea it shall not be
lawfull to divert the Course therof And with like liberty to divert the [s[ai]d <ref idref="n3">3</ref>] River of Gleane before it cometh
to the place called Pinchbecke Barres or Dovehurne in Pinchbecke from which place called Dovehurne through
the said Towne [and the Towne<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] of Surflett as it now passeth to the Sea it shall not be lawfull to divert the
same or prejudice the Navigation therof And all manner of Draines Sewers and Passages for Waters, and other
Waterworkes whatsoever which now are or hereafter shall be made within or without the said Fennes for the
draining of the said Fenns or any of them which shall be necessary to be made or continued in order to the
preserving the said Fenns from surrounder And therof and of all and every the said Rivers to discharge exonerate
acquitt and save harmeles as well the Kings and the said Queenes Majesties His Heires and Successors their
Tennants and Undertennants as all other person and persons their Heires and Assignes of and for the repairing
and amending of their severall parts ?d allotments in them and every of them</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. The said Trustees to make and maintain Bridges with Gates over the drained Lands.</head>
		<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the
Survivo<emph type="p">r</emph> of them shall at their owne proper Costs and Charges make sett downe and maintaine such reasonable
and convenient Bridges w<emph type="p">th</emph> Gates unto the same in widenes not exceeding twelve Foote being well and sufficiently
railed or walled against the sides as well over any Draine on Ditch now made or hereafter to be made wherby
passage may be had into the Fenns in such and soe many fitt and convenient places as shall be thought fitt and
ordered by any six Commissioners of Sewers for the said County of Lyncolne in their publique and open Sessions
and the same shall for ever keepe and maintaine for convenient and ready passage with Carts and Carriages and
all sorts of Catle into and forth of the said Fenns and every of them</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. May desert, widen, and continue Drains, Sewers, and Ditches at their Pleasure.; making Satisfa&bholigct;ion to Persons suffering Damage.; inhabitants of Spalding may set down and stop Sluices, Tunnels, &amp;c. (Exception) as two Commissioners of Sewers in Holland may judge necessary.</head>
		<para id="p6">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the
Survivo<emph type="p">r</emph> of them for the better draining and keeping dry of the aforesaid Fenns shall and may at their wills and
pleasures desert or maintaine and continue all such Draynes as now are in the said Fenns or any of them at the
old or accustomable widenes and breadth or otherwise enlarge the same at their will and pleasure within the said
Fennes And likewise may at their will and pleasure make any new Draines Ditches and Sewers within the said
Fenns or any of them or without towards the Sea of what quantity depth or widenes they shall thinke best which
Draynes and every of them shall have liberty to run above the Soyle soe as the waters of the same be kept
within the Banckes of the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Draynes now made or hereafter to bee made except soe much
of the said waters as unavoidable shall soke through the Banckes for which alsoe satisfa&bholigct;ion is to be made to
any person or persons suffering damage thereby as shall be awarded by the said Commissioners of Sewers or any
Six of them in their open Sessions soe as the Inhabitants of Spalding and Pinchbecke may have a libertie to sett
downe and stopp such Sluces Tunnells and Gages of Water [and Locks<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] as are or shall be made upon any
the said Rivers and Draines (except the said Rivers of Welland Gleane and the Westlode) at such time or times
as two Commissioners of Sewers for the parts of Holland shall judge seasonable and necessary for the drayning
of their In-grounds Provided the same exceed not two Monthes in the yeare</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. Wapentake of Elloe being overflowed, may stop Drains, &amp;c. till Banks repaired</head>
		<para id="p7">And if at any, time or times hereafter for ever any of the Bancke or Bancks of the Drayne or Draynes
now or hereafter to bee made for the drayning of the said Fenns or preservation of the said Country happen
to breake or be overflowne wherby the waters have issue, and fall into any the severall Lands of any the Townes
in the Wapentake of Elloe that immediately upon such breach or overflowing it shall and may be lawfull for all or
any the Dikereeves Officers or other Inhabitans of any the Townes in Elloe aforesaid to sett downe the Clowe of
such Drayne or Draines or otherwise to stopp the same till the Banckes therof soe breaking or overflowed from
time to time bee sufficiently repaired strengthened and heigthened</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. Glean and Welland Rivers to be kept navigable.</head>
		<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Currents or Channells of the River of Gleane
and Welland and the Westlode shall not be diverted or turned into any other Tra&bholigct; or Course whatsoever (that
is to say) from a place called Dovehurne in Pinchbecke to the Outfall and from a Bancke in Spalding called
Hawthorne bancke to the Outfall, but shall be kepte navigable as formerly they were downe to the Sea,</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. If the said Trustees fail to repair Banks, who shall do it.</head>
		<para id="p9">
			<emph type="i">The said Trustees to pay for the same, &amp;c. upon a Note in Writing under the Hands of Two Commissioners of Sewers.; what such Notes are to contain.; Remedy for the Money against the said Trustees.; Distress.; Proceedings thereon.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p10">And bee it further ena&bholigct; by the Authority aforesaid That if any Goole or Gooles Breach or Breaches
Overflowing or Overflowings of waters shall happen at any time hereafter to be in over or through any of the said
Bancks made or to be made within the said Fenns for the defence and preservaco&bhocotil;n of the same other then the
Bancke called the Dozenes and the Bancke called Hawthorne bancke to the surrounding or annoyance of the said
Fenns or any part of them within their Charge as aforesaid and the same be not amended by the said Trustees
their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them within Tenn dayes after such Breach Goole or Overflowing
that [then<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] it shall and may be lawfull to and for any the Dykereeves or Surveyors of Sewers in Spalding or
Pinchbecke or any of the other Townes in the Wapentake of Nesse or Elloe in the said County of Lincolne
where the said Breach or Breaches Goole or Gooles Overflowing or Overflowings of waters shall happen to be
forthwith and immediately (after the said Tenn dayes) to repaire the same at the onely Costs and Charges of
them the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them. All which said Summe or Summes
of Money soe by the said Dykereeves and Surveyours of Sewers or any of them expended in and about the
takeing repairing and amending of any such Breach or Breaches Goole or Gooles Overflowing or Overflowings of
waters in or over the said Bancke or Banckes respe&bholigct;ively they the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the
Survivour of them shall pay or cause to be paid to the said Dykereever or Dikereeves. [Surveyor or Surveiors<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]
soe expending the same upon a Noate delivered in writing to the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the
Survivour of them [their<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Tennants or Undertenants Servants or Agents or any of them by the said Dykereeve
or Dykereeves Surveyour or Surveyours testified under the hands of Two Commissioners of Sewers one being of
the Quorum containing as well the Names of the Labourers that repaired the said Breach or Breaches Goole, or
Gooles Overflowing or Overflowings as the Wages paid to them and the Rates and Prizes of all other necessary
charges imployed and bestowed in and about the same with their convenient Salary and Wages for their paines in
that behalfe at the discretion of Two such Commissioners as aforesaid the which if the said Trustees their Heires
or Assignes or the Survivour of them or their Tennants or Undertenants Agents or Servants shall refuse or
negcle&bholigct; to doe that then it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Officers or persons or any of them that
shall make up any such Breach or Breaches Goole or Gooles Overflowing or Overflowings or sustaine such damages
as aforesaid to enter into the said Third part of the said Fenns or into the Five thousand Acres additionall recompence
herein after given by this present A&bholigct; or into any part thereof and to distraine and impound the Horses Beasts
Sheepe or Goods and Chattells of them the said Trustees their Heyres and Assignes, or the Survivor of them or
any Tennant or Tennants Farmer or Farmers Occupier or Occupiers of all or any part of the said Third part and
of the said Five thousand Acres And from and after the Fourth day of the said Distresse and Impoundment (in
case the said Su&bhouov;me or Su&bhouov;mes soe expended and demanded be not then, paid) Sale therof to make without allowance
of Replevin and with the Money therupon ariseing to pay and satisfie all summes of money for the said Workes
expended and to be allowed as abovesaid rendering the Overplus to the Owner if any Overplus be over and above
the Charges aforesaid and Charges of keeping</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. Banks of Dozens and Hawthorne, &amp;c. how to be repaired; at the Costs of the said Trustees.</head>
		<para id="p11">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any Breach Goole Hole or Holes or flowing of waters shall
happen to be in over or through the said Bancke called the Dozens the said Bancke called Hawthorne bancke the
said Bancke called the East Bancke the said Bancke on the North side of the River Gleane or any other Bancke
made or to be made without the said Fennes by the said Trustees their Heyres or Assignes or y<emph type="p">e</emph> Survivor of
them for or in order to the draining of the said Fenns That then and in every such case. It shall and may be
lawfull to and for the, Dykereeves and Surveyours of Sewers in Pinchbecke and Spalding or any of the Townes in the
Wapentake of Nesse or Elloe aforesaid where the said Breach Goole or flowing shall bee forthwith and immediately
to repaire the same at the Costs and Charges of the said Trustees their Heyres and Assignes, or the Survivor
of them to be had and leavyed in manner and forme as is before expressed and declared for or concerning the
said Banckes environing or made or to be made for the draining or preservation of the said Fenns</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>IX. In what case the said Trustees to satisfy for Losses to particular Persons by overflowings; to be awarded by Six Commissioners of Sewers for Holland.</head>
		<para id="p12">
			<emph type="i">Remedy to recover such Satisfa&bholigct;ion.; Distress.; No Replevin.; Cutting in another Man's Land.; Damage set down by Six Commissioners of Sewers.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p13">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if it fortune that at any time hereafter by the negligence
of the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them in not sufficiently maintaining scowering
dikeing or cleansing of any Rivers Banckes Sewers or Draynes whatsoever which now are or hereafter shall be
made for drayning of the said Fenns and securing of the Country or that by any inconvenient placeing setting
cutting or making of any Drayne Gote or Sluce upon the same that the Country or any private or perticular person
receive losse or harme thereby That the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them or some
of them shall make such recompence &amp; satisfaco&bhocotil;n for the same to every person and persons sustaining any Damage
thereby as six Commissioners of Sewers for the said part of Holland wherof Three to bee of the Quor? shall
award and appoint under their Hands and Seales (if the said Lords Adventurers their Heires or Assignes shall not
have otherwise satisfied the same) which if they, the said Lords Adventurers their Heires or Assignes shall negcle&bholigct;
to pay and satisfie to the person and persons sustaining the same their Executors or Assignes by the space of
Twenty dayes after demand made therof to them the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour
of them or the Agents Tennants or Underte?ants of them That then and from thenceforth it shall and may be
lawfull to and for every such person and persons sustaining the same Damage their Heires Executors Administrators
and Assignes and every of them respe&bholigct;ively to enter into the same Third part and into the said Five thousand
Acres and every or any part therof and to leavy the same Damages soe as aforesaid awarded and appointed by
Distresse and sale of the Goods and Chattells of them the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the
Survivour of them or any Tennant or Tennants Farmer or Farmers Occupier or Occupiers of all or any part
of the said Third part of the said Fenns or the said five thousand Acres and present Sale therof to make after
the fowerth day of Impoundment (and payment of such money then not made) without allowance of Replevin
rendering the Overplus to the Owner if any Overplus there be And if the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes
or the Survivour of them or any of them shall thinke it necessary for the inlargment of any old Drayne River or
Bancke out of the said Fenns above that which formerly they were or for making any new Drayne River or
Bancke or cutt or cover the severall Soyle of any person or persons That then the said Trustees their Heires and
Assignes or the Survivour of them shall compound and agree with the Owner or Owners therof, (if they can
agree) And if they cannot agree that the value of the Damage shall be sett downe by six of the Commissioners
of Sewers wherof three to be of the Quorum and the money shall be paid or tendered before such time as the
said Soyle shall be cutt or covered and upon payment or tender of the said money it shall be lawfull for them
to cutt or cover the said Soyle for makeing the said Draynes Rivers or Bancks.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s10">
		<head>X. Power to Trustees to pull up Bridges, Wears, and Purprestures; but to rebuild the great Bridge over Spalding River, and to make other new Bridges; and repaire them for ever.</head>
		<para id="p14">
			<emph type="i">In case of Default of Trustees,; Commissioners of Sewers may make Distress.; If Spalding Bridge not finished before 25th March 1670, Penalty on Trustees.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p15">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said
Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them to pull up any Cart bridges of Wood or Stone or any
Foote or Horse bridges Clowes or Water bridges that now lye over the said two Rivers of Gleane and Welland
the Rivers of Westloade and Starr fengraft Vernatts or any of them, or any other Drayne that be too strait or
narrow or otherwise may hinder the course &amp; passage of the waters in the said Rivers or of any Drayne to be
devised by the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the Survivour of them and alsoe to pull up all Weares
and Purprestures in the said Rivers and Draynes that hinder the passage of the water Provided that they shall
forthwith sufficiently build and make againe at their owne proper Costs and Charges the great Bridge over
Spalding River (commonly called the High Bridge) of Lime and Stone and all such other Cart bridges Horse
bridges Clowes or Water bridges of Lime Stone or Timber respe&bholigct;ively as the former were which have beene
or shall be soe pulled downe to be enlarged or made wider And that all and every the auncient Bridges &amp; Tunnells
under and over any of the Rivers and Draynes and every of them be repaired and for ever maintained at the
charges of them the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the Survivour of them And if it shall happen the
said Bridges or any of them shall not be made or repaired by the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the
Survivour of them in convenient time according to the true intent or meaning of this A&bholigct; That then it shall and
may bee lawfull to and for the Co&bhooov;mis?ers of Sewers in their publique Sessions from time to time to order and
decree how much or what su&bhouov;me or summes of money shall or may be necessary or fitting to be raised for effe&bholigct;ing
the same. And if after notice of the said Determinations of the said Commissioners by a Noate in writing under
the hand of the Clerke of the Sewers given to the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the Survivour of them
they shall not pay or cause the same soe adjudged to be paid within thirty dayes after such notice That then it
shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Com&bhopubr;s of Sewers by their Warrants to levy the same by Distresse
and sale of the Goods and Catle levant and couchant upon any the Lands within the said Fenns hereby vested
and setled in the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them. And if it shall fall out that
the said High Bridge over Spalding River be not finished before the Five and twentieth of March One thousand
six hundred seaventy That then the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them shall forfeit
the full and just summe of One hundred and fifty pounds to Peircy Church Es&bhoqesq; his Executors or Assignes which
shall and may be raised by the Com[missione]rs of Sewers for the time being [at their Publique Sessions<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] by sale of part
of the said Third part of the said Fennes or of the said Three thousand five hundred Acres herein mentioned and
be by them accordingly paid over to the said Peircy Church his Executors or Assignes, and the person and persons
and their Heires to whom such Sale shall be made shall and may for ever then after hold and enjoy the same
by vertue of such: Sale and of this present A&bholigct; Any thing herein to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s11">
		<head>XI. Power to Trustees to take Earth, &amp;c. for repairing Banks.</head>
		<para id="p16">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That for the better preservation of the said Bancks
environing the said Fenns or made within the said Fenns for defence of the same it shall and may be lawfull
to and for the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them to cutt the Ground lyeing betweene
the Outring Banckes and the said Rivers or either of them to take earth manure and litter for the repairing the
said Bancks soe often as need shall require or to them shall seeme meete and convenient soe that such cutting
be not extended or made above six score foote distant from the said Banckes and to ere&bholigct; make and keepe such
and soe many sufficient Barrs and Slakers and in such places as shall seeme most fitt and convenient to the said
Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them the Slakers to take off the Surplusage of Waters,
and the Barrs to hinder the passage of Horsemen and Drifts of Catle over the same Banckes in the times hereafter
prohibited</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s12">
		<head>XII. Cattle driven over the Banks in Winter (Exception) to pay Toll.</head>
		<para id="p17">And to the end that the Bancks should not be impaired by Horsemen Drifts of Sheepe Horses Beasts and
other Catle It is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe person or persons whatsoever. (except as
hereafter is excepted) shall at any time or times hereafter in any yeare betweene Michaelmas day and the first day
of May drive or cause to be driven any Horses. Oxen Sheepe or any other kinde of Catle over or upon any [of<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]
the said Banckes without first paying to them the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of
them after the rate of Foure pence for every Score of Sheepe and for every other Beast the su&bhouov;me of Fower pence
which they their Heires and Assignes are hereby authorized to demand and receive</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s13">
		<head>XIII. Owners of the Fens to pass free.</head>
		<para id="p18">
			<emph type="i">Exception.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p19">Provided neverthelesse and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the Lords Owners and Commoners of or in all
or any part of the said Fenns shall have free libertie at all times of the yeare for them their Horses Servants and
Catle to passe and repasse upon any Bancke or Banckes Drove or Droves in or compassing the said Fenns
without paying any thing for soe doeing if such person or persons claiming such freedome does not usually buy
Sheepe or Catle and trade that way to London with such Catle or Sheepe as are not of theire owne feeding for
a Moneth before.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s14">
		<head>XIV. Times and Places at which Persons keeping Horse Boats at Croyland, &amp;c. may land Horsemen with their Horses, &amp;c.; Penalty.</head>
		<para id="p20">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authorty aforesaid That noe person or persons whatsoever keeping a Horse boate
either at Croyland Cloote Deeping Baston Eastcoate Pinchbecke Spalding or Cowbett shall land any Horsemen with
their Horses or Catle upon any the said Banckes at any time hereafter betweene Michaelmas day and the first
day of May, but at Waldrome Hall Baston Spout Dovehurne Cloote or Croyland without licence first therunto
had and obtained from the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them upon paine and
forfeiture to bee made and paid for every Horse and neate Beast six pence and for every score of Sheepe fower
pence to the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them, And that noe manner of person
or persons shall draw any Boate on or over any the Banckes in or compassing the said Fenns but in such places
onely as are or shall be appointed for that purpose.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s15">
		<head>XV. Swine ringed or unringed not to be put between the Banks, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p21">
			<emph type="i">Swine put in Fens to be ringed; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p22">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid. That noe Swine of what sort soever ringed or unringed be
putt upon the said Fennes or any of them betweene the said Bancks and the Weare ditches but that they shall
be putt into the Fenns at usuall? places where other Catle are putt in And that the Swine there soe putt shall be
ringed upon paine of every Hogg soe found unringed to forfeit to them the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes
or the Survivour of them the summe of Two pence for every time soe found to be leavyed by Distresse and
impounding of such Hogg or Hoggs</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s16">
		<head>XVI. The Trustees not to have Common but in their Lots.</head>
		<para id="p23">
			<emph type="i">They are to keep the Poor dwelling within their Lots</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p24">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the
Survivour of them, their or any of their T?nants Farmers or Groundholders of any part of the said Third part or
of the said Fenn or of the said five thousand Acres shall not have, any time hereafter use or claime any Common
of Pasture or other Co&bhooov;monage or Pasturing in any part of the remainder of the said Fenns nor any of them nor
in the North Fenn of Pinchbecke and Spalding nor any part therof by vertue or pretence of his or [their<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]
resiance there, But all and every the Inhabitants that may hereafter be upon any part of the said Third part, or
upon any part of the said Five thousand Acres and are not able to maintaine themselves shall be maintained and
kept by the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes and the Survivour of them and never become chargable in any
kinde to all or any the respe&bholigct;ive Parishes wherin such Inhabitant or Inhabitants shall reside or dwell Any Statute
or Law to the contrary hereof notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s17">
		<head>XVII. No Water let out of Glean or Welland, but by License from said Trustees, or by Order of Six Commissioners of Sewers.</head>
		<para id="p25">
			<emph type="i">Abuse of Tunnels prevented.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p26">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe water shall be lett or taken out of the Rivers
of Gleane or Welland or any other the said Drayne or Draynes by any Sluce Cutt or Tunnell without the licence
of the s? Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the Survivour of them or by order of six C&bhooov;miss[ion]ers of Sewers who
likewise are to take care that such Cutt or Cutts made for the taking therof shall be made up againe at the
charge of such person or persons for whose benefitt the same were made, but for necessary household uses, by
such as now lye by some Law of Sewers already setled And in case any abuse of the said Tunnells happen to bee
that then the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the Survivour of them their Servants or Agents shall have
power immediately to stopp the same</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s18">
		<head>XVIII. Inhabitants of Pinchbeck and Spalding to have the use of Blewgate Sluice.</head>
		<para id="p27">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Inhabitants of Pinchbecke and Spalding shall
for ever hereafter have the use of a certaine Gote or Sluce called Blewgote and the Drayne leading thereto, soe
as the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes shall not be putt to any charge for the repairing or maintaining of
the same</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s19">
		<head>XIX. Dozens Drain to be enlarged.</head>
		<para id="p28">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Loads or Drayne under the Dozens from Baston
bancke to Winsoever be ditched Two hundred Foote more inward into the said Fenns then now it is and the earth
laid on that side of the Banke next the Towne of Pinchbecke,</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s20">
		<head>XX. Reward to Trustees for doing the said Works.</head>
		<para id="p29">
			<emph type="i">Of Part, amounting to 10,036 Acres, the Trustees to stand seised to the Use of the Earl of Berkshire, Lord Andover, &amp;c.; Of the Residue to other Uses.; If Commissioners do not nominate a Surveyor within Three Months after Nomination by the said Trustees, then Trustees may proceed.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p30">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That for and in consideraco&bhocotil;n of all the moneyes allready
expended in and about the Drayning of the said Fennes and in consideration of the doeing and performing of the
Workes aforesaid hereafter to be done and of all and every of them about the recovering ining &amp; draining of the
said Fenns and every of them that they the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them
shall from henceforth have hold peaceably occupy and enjoy to them their Heires and Assignes in Fee simple for
ever the said Third part of all the said Fenns and Marshes formerly assigned to the said Thomas Lovell his Heires
and Assignes as alsoe Three thousand five hundred acres added and allotted by a Decree of Sewers made at
Spalding in the said Fenns and one thousand Acres out of that part of the said Fenns formerly taken in for the
Queenes Improvement and five hundred Acres more to be taken proportionally out of the residue of the said
Fenns in Kestiven, and Holland next adjoyning to the said three thousand five hundred Acres which three thousand
five hundred Acres and one thousand Acres and five hundred Acres last mentioned are to be demeasured by
Statute measure by two Artists and sett out by them at the charge of the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes
or the Survivour of them one to be chosen by the Commissioners of Sewers of Kestiven and Holland and one
other by the said Undertakers but upon the Trusts hereafter menco&bhocotil;ned that is to say as touching &amp; concerning
Eight thousand thirty six Acres therof mentioned in a Schedule annexed to an Indenture of Fiveteene parts dated
the second of August One thousand six hundred fifty made betweene Elizabeth Countesse Dowager of Exeter and
others therin named and Two thousand Acres more to be indifferently sett out within six Monethes after the
passing [of<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] this A&bholigct; amounting in the whole to Tenn thousand thirty six Acres in trust that the said Trustees
their Heires &amp; Assignes or the Survivour of there shall grant and convey the same to such person or persons
or for such Estates in Fee simple or otherwise in such manner as the said Thomas Earle of Ber?s the said Lord
Andover Lord Bruce and John Lord Berkley of Stratton shall appoint, And as for touching and concerning the
residue of the said Fenns by this A&bholigct; allotted for recompence for the said draining moreover and above the said
Eight thousand thirty six Acres &amp; Two thousand Acres in trust for the said Earle of Berkeshire and the Lady
Elizabeth his Wife the said Lord Andover the said Earle of Elgin Countesse of Stamford and Lord Gray and
such other person and persons to whom the remainder upon their Estates are limitted according to their severall
and respe&bholigct;ive Interests and Estates as aforesaid made or derived from by or under the said William late Earle of
Exeter and Elizabeth late Countesse of Exeter or either of them their or either of their Heires or Assignes And
in case the said Commissioners shall not nominate a Surveyour within Three monthes after nomination by the said
Trustees their Heires or Assignees or the Survivour of them and both to be sworne by the said Co?n and notice
therof to be given to the said Commissioners That then the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the Survivour
of them shall proceed as aforesaid by their owne Artist.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s21">
		<head>XXI. The Trustees to inclose their Share, and maintain the Fences; in Default thereof, Trustees not to impound, have A&bholigct;ion, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p31">
			<emph type="i">General Issue.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p32">Provided alsoe and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said Trustees [Their Heyres and Assignes
and the Survivour of them<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] shall at all times hereafter sufficiently fence and incloase the said Third part and all
other the Lands by this A&bholigct; to them granted on all parts against the Lords and Commoners of and in the residue
of the said Fenns And if any of their Catle shall enter or breake into the said Third part and other Lands soe
granted or any part therof in default of the Inclosure therof It shall not be lawfull for the said Trustees their
Heires or Assignes or the Survivour of them to destraine or impound the same or to maintaine any A&bholigct;ion for
any such Entry depasturing or other Trespasse happening in such default And if any such A&bholigct;ion bee brought it
shall be lawfull for the Defendant or Defendants therin to plead the Generall Issue and to give this A&bholigct; in
Evidence.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s22">
		<head>XXII. Proviso for Continuance of Two Droveways called North Drove and South Drove.</head>
		<para id="p33">And that the twoe Drove wayes in the said Fenns called the North drove and South drove leading from the
parts of Keisteven into the parts of Holland be continued open and common through the said Third part and
Lands to them granted for the use and benefitt of the Lords &amp; Commoners for a Drift way for them and the said
Undertakers And alsoe that the Bancks or Draynes (by vertue of this A&bholigct;) to be continued or made shall not
stopp or hinder the Land-waters falling from the parts of Keisteven into the said Fenne but shall and may
receive and carry the same away</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s23">
		<head>XXIII. No Estates of the said Trustees liable except their said Estates in the said Fens.</head>
		<para id="p34">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; or any Clause Article Sentence or Penaltie therin contained mentioned or
expressed shall not extend to charge the persons of the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the Survivour
of them or any the Estate or Estates reall or personall of them the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the
Survivour of them other then their Estate and Estates of and in the said Fenns</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s24">
		<head>XXIV. If Trustees do not finish the draining in Seven Years; or do not maintain their Drains (Exception); from overflowing within Five Years; and the same adjudged by Twelve Commissioners of Sewers or the Majority; then their Estate to cease; and be vested in the Commissioners of Sewers; and they to drain.</head>
		<para id="p35">
			<emph type="i">The Trustees to convey their Share as Twelve Commissioners of Sewers shall appoint.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p36">Provided alsoe and upon Condition That if the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the Survivo<emph type="p">r</emph> of them
shall negle&bholigct; the Ining and drayning of the said Fenns and every or any of them and shall not fully &amp; perfe&bholigct;ly
finish the drayning of the same before the end and expiration of the said Seaven yeares as aforesaid according to
the intent and purport of this A&bholigct;, or shall not after the Ining or drayning therof keepe and maintaine the said
Fennes and every of them after the end and terme of the said Seaven yeares dry firme good &amp; depasturable
ground for Catle at all times in the yeare (except such Lakes Draynes Sewers Portions and Quantities of the said
Fennes as are before excepted) but shall wilfully and negligently suffer the said Fenns and Wasts or the most
part of the same to be againe drowned and overflowne by the space of Five yeares at any time after the expiraco&bhocotil;n
of the said Seaven yeares and the same be found and adjudged hurtfully surrounded in default of the said Trustees
their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them (contrary to this A&bholigct;) by Twelve Commissioners of Sewers
or the greater number of them, whereof six to be of the parts of Holland and six of Kesteven, of which [Twelve<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]
Commissioners three of either of the said parts to bee of the Quor&umacr; upon their view and inquisition or &bhopcrl;sentment
of Jury that the same hath soe long continued drowned, and that Judgment be certified of Record into the High
Court of Chauncery under theire Hands and Seales or the greater number of them That then and from thenceforth
the trust of the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them of in and to the said third part
and the said other parts and proportions added and allotted for a further recompence as aforesaid for the said
Earle and Countesse of Berkshire Lord Howard of Charlton Lord Bruce Countesse of Stamford Lord Grey and
other persons in remainder as aforesaid And all and every Estate and Estates whatsoever by them granted conveyed
or in any manner executed of all or any the said Third part or other proportions added and allotted for further
recompence to any person or persons whomsoever in execution pursuance or discharge of their said Trust or
otherwise shall cease determine and be utterly void to all intents &amp; purposes whatsoever and not to bee helped
altered or releived in any Court or by any course of Law or Equity And that then and from thenceforth the said
Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them shall stand and be seised of all the said. Third part
and the said additionall Allotments in trust to permitt and suffer the said Commissioners of Sewers of Kesteven
and Holland to take perceive and receive the whole Rents Issues and Proffitts to the end the same may be laid
out and expended for the regaineing of the said Fenns and to defray the Charge which the Country shall or may
be putt unto to preserve themselves and their other Lands from being surrounded or damnified by the said waters
in default of maintaining of the said Banckes and doeing other the said Works which ought to have beene made
and repaired by the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them, And upon further trust
likewise. That the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes or the Survivour of them shall and will from time to
times and at all times make and execute such Estate and Estates as Twelve Commissioners of Sewers of the parts
of Holland and Kesteven, wherof three of each part to be of the Quorum shall by writing under their Hands
and Seales dire&bholigct; and appoint</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s25">
		<head>XXV. Such Estates deemed good.</head>
		<para id="p37">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed and declared That all such Estate and Estates soe by them made shall be, and bee, and
bee deemed and taken to bee good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law to all intents and purposes as if the same were in this
present A&bholigct; perticularly and by proper Names mentioned and expressed,</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s26">
		<head>XXVI. If the Trustees before the Term of Seven Years do not pay &pound;100. into the Commissioners of Sewers Hands, to amend South Dozens and Hawthorn-Bank; then the said Commissioners may enter; and so from time to time, if not supplied by the said Trustees, the said Commissioners may raise the same.</head>
		<para id="p38">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the
Survivour of them shall not or doe not at or before the said terme of Seaven yeares well and truely pay or cause
to be paid the full and just summe of One hundred pounds of lawfull money of England into the hands of such
person or persons as the said Commissioners of Sewers in their publique Sessions from time to time shall appoint
to receive the same That then and in such case it shall and may be lawfull to and for the [said<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Commissioners
of Sewers by an Order in writing under their Hands and Seales to authorize such person or persons as they shall
thinke fitt to enter into any the said Lands part of the said Third part allotted to the said Thomas Lovell out of
any the Fenns by him formerly undertaken to bee drayned and the said additionall Lands And out of the Rents
Issues and Proffitts therof to raise the same summe of One hundred pounds To the end the same shall and may
be by them imployed and laid out in and about the necessary maintenance and reparaco&bhocotil;n of the Bancks above
menco&bhocotil;ned called the South Dozens and Hawthorne Banck and soe from time to times and all times as the said
One hundred pounds or any part therof shall be as abovesaid expended in and about the said Bancks as aforesaid
if the same be not againe supplyed by the s[ai]d Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the Survivo<emph type="p">r</emph> of them within six
Moneths then next following then it shall be in the power of the said Com[missione]<emph type="p">rs</emph> of Sewers out of the Rents Issues
and Proffitts aforesaid to raise the same or soe much therof as shall not be supplied as abovesaid from time to
time and at all times as occasion shall require</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s27">
		<head>XXVII. Power to make By-laws.</head>
		<para id="p39">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for
such person &amp; persons their Heires &amp; Assignes or any Three or more of them to whom the s[ai]d Trustees their
Heires or Assignes or the Survivo<emph type="p">r</emph> of them shall make or execute any Estate or Estates of the said Ten thousand
thirty six Acres before menco&bhocotil;ned or any part therof as Adventurers under the said Trustees their Heires or
Assignes or the survivo<emph type="p">r</emph> of them in draining the said Fenns at all times, &amp; from time to time from and im&bhomov;ediately
after execution of the s[ai]d Estate &amp; Estates to su&bhouov;mon call &amp; hold meetings of themselves [their<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Agents and
Workmen at such place and places by Warrant under three or more of their Hands &amp; Seales or under the Hand
&amp; Seale of their Co&bhooov;mon Clerke for the time being for the makeing altering or confirming And with Power and
Authority hereby granted unto them their Heires Executors Administo?o<emph type="p">rs</emph> and Assignes for making and to make
By Lawes for the better Government and more orderly manadgment of the said worke of draining the said Fenns
within themselves respe&bholigct;ively</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s28">
		<head>XXVIII. The said Trustees may make an Acre Tax.</head>
		<para id="p40">And alsoe bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That at all and every meeting and meetings as
aforesaid to be held It shall and may be lawfull, and they are hereby therunto impowered for any three or more
of the s?d Undertakers their Heires Executors Administrators and Assignes to assesse rate tax and charge all and
every the respe&bholigct;ive Owner or Owners their Heires Executors Administrators &amp; Assignes &amp; every of them of all
&amp; every the said Tenn thousand and thirty six Acres aforesaid by an equall and proporco&bhocotil;nable Acre tax with
any Su&bhouov;me or Su&bhouov;mes of Money as they shall adjudge necessary for the carrying on and effe&bholigct;ing the s?d Worke
&amp; to limit &amp; appoint such certain dayes and places for the respe&bholigct;ive payments therof to their Treasurer or
Treasurers for the time being as they the s[ai]d Undertakers their Heires Ex[ecuto]<emph type="p">rs</emph> Adm[inistrato]<emph type="p">rs</emph> or Assignes or any three or
more of them under their Hands &amp; Seales shall appoint soe as every of the s[ai]d Undertakers who shall at [any<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]
time, or times hereafter assesse rate tax &amp; charge the s[ai]d Su&bhouov;mes of Money be really then Owner of Two hundred
&amp; fifty Acres of Land or more &bhowssth;in the s[ai]d Fenn,</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s29">
		<head>XXIX. Tax not paid.</head>
		<para id="p41">
			<emph type="i">Adventurers may sell Lands of Defaulters; subje&bholigct; to the Conditions of this A&bholigct;.; Such Conveyances good against Defaulters; to be enrolled within Six Months.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p42">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed Upon default made by any person or persons soe assessed rated taxed &amp; charged
as aforesaid in his or their respe&bholigct;ive payments to be limitted &amp; appointed as aforesd by the space of three Months
after the time limitted for payment therof that it shall &amp; may be lawfull to &amp; for any three or more of the s[ai]d
Adventurers their Heires Ex[ecuto]<emph type="p">rs</emph> Adm[inistrato]<emph type="p">rs</emph> or Assignes to bargaine sell, convey &amp; assure all or soe much of the s[ai]d
Defaulter or Defaulters Lands respe&bholigct;ively within the s[ai]d Fenn for raising the S&bhouov;me or S&bhouov;mes of Money soe
assessed rated or charged as afores[ai]d to any other person or persons their Heires &amp; Assignes for such Estate or
Estates as the s[ai]d Defaulter or Defaulters had in him or them respe&bholigct;ively at the time of the s[ai]d Default or
Defaults made as afores[ai]d as to them or any three or more of them the s[ai]d Adventurers their Heires Ex[ecuto]<emph type="p">rs</emph> Ad<emph type="p">rs</emph>
or Assignes shall seeme meet, subje&bholigct; nevertheles to the Condico&bhocotil;ns &amp; forfeitures in this A&bholigct; contained &amp; exprest,
And all &amp; every Conveyance therof is &amp; shall be adjudged good &amp; available in Law &amp; Equity ag<emph type="p">t</emph> all &amp; every
such Defaulter &amp; Defaulters respe&bholigct;ively &amp; ag<emph type="p">t</emph> his or their respe&bholigct;ive Heires Ex[ecuto]<emph type="p">rs</emph> Adm[inistrato]<emph type="p">rs</emph> &amp; Assignes soe as the same
be inrolled in the High Court of Chauncery within Six Monethes after the makeing therof</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s30">
		<head>XXX. Owners of the Fens may inclose, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p43">
			<emph type="i">Exception.; Inclosures how to be held; subje&bholigct; to Powers given by this A&bholigct; to the said Trustees.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p44">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid, That it shall and may be lawfull for any person or
persons Bodyes Politique or Corporate,. their Heyres and Successors Owner or Owners of the Soyle of the said
Fenns or Wasts or who may or ought to have Co&bhooov;mon in any of the same to improve sett out, enclose divide
and sever such quantity or quantities of the said Fenns or Wasts (other then such of the same as by the tenor
of this A&bholigct; are appointed or allotted to the said Undertakers as aforesaid) as shalbe proportionable to his or their
respe&bholigct;ive Interest, or to his or their Lands and Tenements whereunto, or in respe&bholigct; whereof, the said Co&bhooov;mon
or Wast may or ought to be had or enjoyed: And such quantity or quantityes to have and to hold in severalty
by and according to such Tenures, Estate Right Tytle &amp; Interest as such person or persons have or shall have
in such Mannors Lands &amp; Tenements subje&bholigct; neverthelesse to all the Powers and Liberties given by this A&bholigct; to
the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes and the Survivor of them, for dreyning the said Fenns, as if the same
Lands had remained [common<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] and unenclosed: leaving and allowing convenient passages and wayes in and to
the s[ai]d Undertakers ground in the said Fenn.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s31">
		<head>XXXI. Names of Commissioners for the Bounds and Inclosures.</head>
		<para id="p45">
			<emph type="i">any Seven of them appointed; their Power to examine, &amp;c.; their Judgment certified into the Petty-Bag.; Appeals from such Judgments; Determination thereon certified into the Petty Bag.; How Inclosures adjudged to be held.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p46">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed That the Boundaryes of the said Wasts so to be enclosed Approvements and Enclosures
shall from time to time and at all times upon request of any person or persons concerned be determined &amp;
adjudged and finally ended by the persons hereafter named (that is to say) Thomas Lord Beaumont of ColeOrton, Sir George Villiers of Brucksby Baronet, Sir William Hartop of Rotherby Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>, William Hartop of Little
Dalby Esq&bhoqesq; Sir Henry Hudson of Melton Mowbray Baronet, Sir Edward Smith of Edmondthorpe Kn<emph type="p">t</emph> Richard
Lister of Thorpe Esq&bhoqesq; John Hacket of Kettleby Esq&bhoqesq; William Gilbert of Melton Mowbray Esq&bhoqesq; all of the County
of Leicester. Baptist Lord Viscount Campden Sir Edward Heath of Cottesmore Kn<emph type="p">t</emph> of the Bath, William Palmes
of Ashwell Esq&bhoqesq; Abell Barker of Hambleton Esq&bhoqesq; Samuel Browne of Stockins Esq&bhoqesq; Robert Mackworth of Empingham
Esq&bhoqesq; Philip Sherard Esq&bhoqesq; Alexander Noell of Whitwell Esq&bhoqesq; Christopher Browne of Towlthorpe Esq&bhoqesq; Edward
Falkener of Uppingh&amacr; Esq&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Mackworth of Normanton &bhobart; [Henry Noell Esq&bhoqesq; of Eaton Andrew Noell
Esq&bhoqesq; of Whitwell Charles Halford Esq&bhoqesq; of Weston, Thomas Pilkinton Esq&bhoqesq; of Belton Beaumont Bodenham Esq&bhoqesq; of
Ryhall, and Henry Mackworth Esq&bhoqesq; of Normanton<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] all of the County of Rutland. Mildmay Earle of Westmorland,
Obrian Lord Cockaine William Stafford Esq&bhoqesq; of Blatherwicke; Lewis Palmer Esq&bhoqesq; of Corlton, Edward Palmer Esq&bhoqesq;
of Stoake, Walter Kirkham of Tinshead Esquire Christopher Thursby Esq&bhoqesq; Humphrey Orme Esq&bhoqesq; Sir Henry Yelverton
&bhobart; Thomas Dove of Upton Esq&bhoqesq; [William Montague Esq&bhoqesq; Francis Quarles Esq&bhoqesq; George Quarles Jun: of Ufford
Esq&bhoqesq; Francis Kirkham Esq&bhoqesq; of Finshead, John Lyn Esq&bhoqesq; of Southwicke<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] all of the County of Northampton [Robert
Lord Willoughby of Eresby eldest Son to Montague Earle of Lindsy L[or]d Greate Chamberlane of England, Sir
Thomas Meres Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>; Sir John Newton &bhobart; Sir Anthony Irby Kn<emph type="p">t</emph> Peregrine Bartue Esq&bhoqesq; Anthony Thorold of
Marston Esq&bhoqesq; William Blythe of Straston Esq&bhoqesq; Philip Dallow of Bitchfeild Esq&bhoqesq; Thomas Harrington of Boothby
Esq&bhoqesq; Charles Bawdes of Somerby Esq&bhoqesq; Sir Edward Barkham &bhobart; all of y<emph type="p">e</emph> County of Lincolne<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] or by any Seaven
or more of them: W<emph type="p">eh</emph> said persons or any seaven or more of them are hereby constituted and appointed
Commissioners for that purpose, upon their view or examination of witnesses upon oath (which oath they are
hereby authorized to administer) or both, or other good and sufficient proofe by matter of Record Writings or
Evidences, and hearing the partyes concerned if they be present and desire it: which Determinac[i]on and Judgement
being certifyed by writing under the hands and seales of the said Judicature or any seaven or more of them into
y<emph type="p">e</emph> Petty bagg, there to be filed and kept on Record shall be finall and conclusive unto all partyes Provided
alwaies that in case any person or persons, Bodyes Politique or Corporate shall find him or themselves aggreived
with such Judgement and Determination of the said Judicature, and shall thereof, within sixe Moneths next after
the same, appeale to any thirteene or more other persons of the said Judicature, then such Determination as the
said thirteene more shall make, being certifyed by writing under the hands, and seales of the said thirteene or
more into the Pettibagg aforesaid there to be filed and kept or Record as aforesaid, shalbe finall and conclusive
to all partyes, the said former Judgement or Determination notwithstanding: And the Enclosures and Proporc[i]ons
so adjudged or decreed as aforesaid to such person or persons, Bodyes Politique and Corporate shalbe held by him or
them, and his and their Heires and Successors respe&bholigct;ively by and according to his and their Tenures Estate Tytle
and Interest which he or they had in the Mannors Lands or Tenements, for or in respe&bholigct; of which he or they
claymed or enclosed the said quantity or quantityes of the s[ai]d Wasts as abovesaid.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s32">
		<head>XXXII. These Commissioners to take an Oath.</head>
		<para id="p47">[Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said Commission&bhoccrl;<emph type="p">rs</emph> and every of them
before he or they take upon him or them the execuc&bhocotil;on of any the Powers or Authorities hereby given them
(other then the administring the Oath following to one another, which they shall have Authority by this present
A&bholigct; to administer to one another) shall take the Oath following (viz<ref idref="n11">11</ref>)</para>
		<para id="p48">I A: B: am not interessed in possession reverc&bhocotil;n or remainder of in or to the said Fenns or any part thereof And
shall and will without favour or affec&bhocotil;on hatred or malice truely and impartially according to the best of my
skill and knowledge execute and performe all and every the Powers and Authorities in mee established by this A&bholigct;
of Parliament.</para>
		<para id="p49">
			<emph type="i">Places for their Session.; Differences between the Commissioners, before any Judgment given by them, referred to Chief Justices and Chief Baron.; Two of whom may determine.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p50">Which Oath any one of the said Com[missione]<emph type="p">rs</emph> are hereby authorized to administer, And that the places where the said
Com[missione]<emph type="p">rs</emph> shall sitt to heare order and determine the matters referred to them by this A&bholigct; shall be at the Townes of
Stamford, Markett Deeping or Spalding in the said County of Lincolne And the said Com[missione]<emph type="p">rs</emph> or any seaven or
more of them are hereby dire&bholigct;ed by Warrant under their hands and seales to declare the places and tymes of
their meeting, The same Warrant to be published in open Markett in the said Townes of Stamford, Markett
Deeping and Spalding betweene the howres of twelve and two upon some Markett Day one and twenty dayes at
least before the said tyme or tymes of meeting, To the end all persons concerned may have sufficient tyme and
notice to attend, And shall have power and authority by warrant under the hands and seales of any three or more
of them to summon parties and witnesses to appeare before them And in case any controversy or differrence shall
happen or arise betweene or amongst the said Com[missione]<emph type="p">rs</emph> before any Judgment or Determination given by them in the
p&bhopcrl;misses touching or concerning the exposition of the words of this A&bholigct; or the powers or authorityes thereby to
them given Then the Lord Cheife Justice of the Kings Bench, the Lord Cheife Justice of the Common Pleas, and
the Lord Cheife Baron of His Majestyes Court of Exchequer for the tyme being are hereby constituted and established
a Judicature, And they or any two of them are hereby authorized to heare adjudge and determine such controversyes
and differences, And their Judgment or Determination thereof certifyed under their hands and Seales, shall be
observed, and shall be likewise certifyed together with the Judgments and Determinations of the said Com[missione]<emph type="p">rs</emph> into the
Petty bagg there to be kept on Record as aforesaid.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">From the Original A&bholigct; in the Parliament Office.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">interlined.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">interlined.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">interlined.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">interlined.</note>
		<note id="n7" number="7">interlined.</note>
		<note id="n8" number="8">interlined.</note>
		<note id="n9" number="9">interlined.</note>
		<note id="n10" number="10">annexed to the A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		<note id="n11" number="11">annexed to the A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
	</section>
</report>


