<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47371" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664 &amp; 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An A&bholigct; for continuance of a former A&bholigct; for repairing the Highwayes within the County of Hertford (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>)[O. nu. II.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 15 Car. II. c. I.; and that divers Gentlemen of the County had borrowed Money for repairing the said Roads; and that certain Parts of the said Roads had been amended; and that a certain Road in Hertford, shire was very ruinous.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Toll for Hertfordshire continued for 21 Years.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by a late A&bholigct; of Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; for repairing the Highwayes within the Countyes
of Hertford Cambridge and Huntington It was ena&bholigct;ed That for the repairing of the auntient Highway and
Poast road, leading from London to Yorke and from London into Lincolnshire, there should be a Toll paid at a
certaine place in every of the said [severall and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, and for Hertfordshire at Wades Mill in the said
County, Which said Toll so set is by the said A&bholigct; to continue the [space<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of eleaven yeares and no longer, with this.
Provision that if the Justices of the Peace at their Quarter Sessions in the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes shall before the
expiration of eleaven yeares, adjudge the said Repayres to be sufficiently done, that from thenceforth it should cease
And whereas divers Gentlemen within the County of Hertford have hartily set themselves to take care for
the repairing of the said wayes within, their County, And in order thereunto finding that Money could not be
advanced by the Toll in so speedy a manner as to repayre those ruinous wayes, And that none would lend their
Money on that Security did upon their owne creditts borrow Thirteen hundred pounds on Interest, to effe&bholigct; the
worke intended by the said A&bholigct;, which s&umacr;me accordingly is layd out together with such Money as hath proceeded
from the Toll before mentioned in the repayre of the said Highway, by which meanes they have so amended the
said Road, lying in that County, leading from London to Yorke, that they have made the same from a Road
impassable, to be to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of all that travell that way very passable and convenient, But by reason of the
great s&umacr;me expended and layd out so borrowed as aforesaid, the Toll, will not be sufficient to repaye the same
within the yeares mentioned in the former A&bholigct; with Interest for the same and to finish the said worke,
And whereas there is a Road in the said County of Hertford that leads from London to Cambridge and so
into Norffolke and likewise to Newmarkett and so into Suffolke, and other parts which goes out of the
forementioned Road at the end of the Towne of Puckeridge, and so leadeth to Barly in the said County of
Hertford, which is very ruinous and requires as much the helpe of the Toll in many places as the forementioned
Road did May it therefore please Your Majesty that it be ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
Excellent Majesty by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the C&bhooov;mons in
this present Parliament assembled, and by Authority of the same That the Toll aforementioned to be taken at
Wades Mill for the County of Hertford, that by the former A&bholigct; was to continue for eleaven yeares and no
longer, shall continue for the said County of Hertford for the space of One and twenty yeares and no longer
the said Terme to commence from the time mentioned in the A&bholigct; beforementioned, and the Money arising
therefrom to be imployed for the payment of the Debt aforesaid with Interest, and also for further repaire of the
said Highway.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. The former Commissioners to repair the said Road.</head>
		<para id="p3">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authority aforesaid, That the persons, impowered in the
forementioned A&bholigct; for the repayre of the Highwayes within the County of Hertford shall have the same power
to repayre the said Highwayes leading from Puckeridge to Barly in the said County, as they have to repayre the
Highway in the said County leading from London to Yorke; And that they shall and may apply such part of the
Toll thereunto (having an equall care of both Highwayes) as they in their Judgments shall finde needfull, Any
thing in the said former A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding,</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III.</head>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Cambridgeshire Toll removed from Caxton to Arrington Bridge.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p5">And whereas by the former recited A&bholigct; a Toll was ere&bholigct;ed and set to be taken at the Towne of Caxton in the
County of Cambridge, for and towards the repairing the Highwayes in the said Countie, The said Toll doth
prove useles and will not answer the, end for which the same was intended, by reason of the Inconveniency of
the place where the same was sett Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said Toll be and
is hereby removed from the said Towne of Caxton unto Arrington Bridge or the Towne of Arrington, as shall
seeme most convenient, by the Justices of the Peace of the said County at their next Easter Generall Quarter
Session of the Peace in the Countie aforesaid, And that the same Toll shall be taken and received at Arrington
Bridge or Arrington Towne aforesaid, according to the Rates and by the same wayes and meanes as in the former
A&bholigct; was appointed and declared, And to be imployed to the uses purposes and intents therein also declared, Any
thing to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Persons chargeable to repair the said Highways are to pay their Rates.</head>
		<para id="p6">Provided alwayes That all and every person and persons who by Law are chargeable towards the repairing of
the said Highwayes and places aforesaid shall still remaine so chargeable, and pay six pence in the pound yearely
according to the true value of their Estates for and towards the repayre of the said Highwayes during the time
of the continuance of this Toll, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. Colle&bholigct;ors to account weekly. Account to be on Oath,; and returned to Quarter Sessions.</head>
		<para id="p7">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Colle&bholigct;or of this Toll, shall weekly account
to the Receivor Generall for the whole Money received by virtue of this or the said former A&bholigct;, And the next
Justice of the Peace for the said County shall hereby have power to give an Oath to the said Colle&bholigct;ors for the
making of a true and perfe&bholigct;ct account of the Money so received, which said account so made shalbe returned into the
next Generall Quarter Sessions to be held for the said County, by the Justice of Peace before whom such Oath
was taken</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. The Toll to cease, if, the Money borrowed be sooner levied.</head>
		<para id="p8">Provided also That if at any tyme before the expiration of the said terme of one and twenty yeares the said
Highwayes shall be well and sufficiently, amended and repayred and so adjudged at the publique Quarter Sessions
for the County of Hertford, And that such s&bhouov;me or s&bhouov;mes of Money as is already borrowed and layd out or shall
be borrowed and layd out for the use aforesaid be repayd with Interest for the same, That from and after such
Adjudication made and repayment of such Money so borrowed and layd out as aforesaid, the aforesaid Toll in the
said County shall cease and determine.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. In default of Justices of Peace, Judges of Assize may adjudge the Money to be levied, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p9">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid, That in case the Highwayes within the said County of
Hertford shall be sufficiently amended, And that the Justices of the Peace at their Quarter Sessions shall fayle to
make an Adjudication thereof. That then in such default of the said Justices of the Peace, It shall and may be
lawfull to and for the Justices of Assize for the said County of Hertford to make such Adjudication, which being
entred with the Clerke of the Assizes shall be esteemed a good Adjudication of the amendment of the said Highwaynes,
And that, then and from thenceforth the said Debt being fully satisfyed to such as shall have advanced any
Moneys thereupon, the said Toll shall cease and determine, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof in any
wise notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. The Rate to be paid to a Treasurer.</head>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">Surveyors of the Highways may levy by Distress</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p11">[And whereas in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; it is provided That all and ev[er]ie person and persons who by Lawe are chardgeable
towards the repayring of the said High wayes and places aforesaid shall still remaine soe chardgeable and pay sixe pence
in the pound yearely according to the true valewe of their Estates for and towards the repaire of the said
High wayes during the time of the continuance of the said Toll Bee it therefore provided and ena&bholigct;ed by the
Authority aforesaid That the aforesaid summe of sixe pence in the pound shall bee payd unto the Threasurer
appointed to receive the aforesaid Toll in like manner as the said Toll is appointed to bee payd by thaforesaid A&bholigct; And
for default of paym&bhomsst; of the said Rate of sixe pence in the pound in manner as aforesaid by the space of sixe dayes
after demaund made That it shall and may bee lawfull for the Survey<emph type="p">rs</emph> of the High wayes for the time being
And they are hereby impowred to levy the same by Distresse and sale of the Goods of the party refusing to pay
the same accordingly, restoring the ov[er]plus (if any bee) to the owner <ref idref="n3">3</ref>].</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">From the Original A&bholigct; in the
Parliament Office.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the A&bholigct; in a separete Schedule.</note>
	</section>
</report>


