<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47386" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1666</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IV. An A&bholigct; for Burying in Woollen onely. [Rot. Parl. 18 &amp; 19 C. II. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Burying in Shirt, &amp;c. made other than of Wool; Penalty &pound;5.; Distress on Goods of the Party interred, or of Persons offending.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">For the Encouragement of the Woollen Manufa&bholigct;ures of this Kingdome and prevention of the Exportation of
the Moneyes thereof for the buying and importing of Linnen Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present
Parlyament assembled and by (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Authoritie thereof That from and A&bholigct;er the Five and twentyeth day of March in
the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty seaven Noe person or persons whatsoever shall be buryed
in any Shirt Shift or Sheete made of or mingled with Flax Hempe, Silke, Haire, Gold or Silver or other then
what shall be made of Wooll onely, or be putt into any Coffin lined or faced with any thing made of or mingled
with Flax Hempe Silke or Haire upon paine of the forfeiture of the summe of Five pounds to be imployed to
the use of the Poore of the Parish where such person shall be buryed for and towards the provideing a Stocke
or Worke house for the setting them at worke to be levyed by the Church wardens and Overseers of the Poore
of such Parish or one of them by Warrant from any Justice of the Peace or Maior Alderman or Head Officer of
Citty Towne or Place Corporate respe&bholigct;ively within their severall Limitts by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of
the partie interred contrary to this A&bholigct; rendering the overplus, or in defaulte thereof by Distresse and Sale of the
Goods of any that had a hand in the putting such person into such Shift Sheete or Coffin contrary to this A&bholigct;,
or did order or dispose the doeing thereof to be levyed and imployed as abovesaid.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Persons dying of the Plague.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided that noe penaltie appointed by this A&bholigct; shall be incurred for or by the reason of any person that
shall dye of the Plague though such person be buryed in Linnen.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">the <emph type="i">O</emph>
			</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


