<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47387" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1666</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An A&bholigct; for encourageing of Coynage.[Rot. Parl. 18 &amp; 19 C. II. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Gold and Silver to be coined gratis</emph>.
<emph type="i">For every Pound Troy of Gold or Silver brought, there is to be delivered a Pound Troy of Current Coin.; For every Pound Troy of Gold and Silver finer than Standard so much more than a Pound Troy delivered; and for baser Gold or Silver so much less</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas it is obvious that the plenty of Current Coynes of Gold and Silver of this Kingdome is of great
advantage to Trade and Commerce For the Increase whereof Your Majestie in Your Princely Wisedome
and Care hath beene gratiously pleased to beare out of Your Revenue halfe the Charge of the Coynage of Silver
money For the preventing of which Charge to your Majestie and the Encouragement of the bringing Gold and
Silver into the Realme to be converted into the Current Money of this Your Majestyes Kingdome Wee Your
Majestyes Dutyfull and Loyall Subje&bholigct;s doe give and grant unto Your Majesty the Rates Dutyes or Impositions
following, And doe beseech Your Majestie that it may be ena&bholigct;ed, and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present
Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That whatsoever person or persons Native or Foreigner
Alien or Stranger shall from and after the Twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred sixty and six
bring any Forreigne Coyne Plate or Bullion of Gold or Silver in Masse molten or allayed, or any sort of Manufa&bholigct;ure
of Gold or Silver into His Majestyes Mint or Mints within the Kingdome of England to be there melted downe
and coyned into the current Coynes of this Kingdome shall have the same there assayed melted downe and coyned
with all convenient speede without any Defalcation Diminution or Charge for the Assaying Coynage or Waste in
Coynage Soe as that for every pound Troy of Crowne or Standard Gold that shall be brought in and delivered
by him or them to be assayed melted downe and coyned as aforesaid there shall be delivered out to him or them
respe&bholigct;ively a pound Troy of the current Coynes of this Kingdome of Crowne or Standard Gold, And for every
pound Troy of Sterlin or Standard Silver that shall be brought in and delivered by him or them to be assayed melted
downe and coyned as aforesaid there shall be delivered out to him or them respe&bholigct;ively a pound Troy of the
current Coynes of this Kingdome of Sterlin or Standard Silver and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser weight.
And for every pound Troy of Gold or Silver that shall be brought in and delivered to be assayed melted downe
and coyned as aforesaid that shall be finer upon essay then Crowne Gold or Standard Silver there shall be delivered
for the same soe much more then a pound Troy as the same doth in proportion amount unto in finenes and value,
And for every pound Troy of Gold or Silver that shall be brought in and delivered to be assayed melted downe
and coyned as aforesaid that shall be courser or baser upon essay or worse in value then Crowne Gold or Standard
Silver there shall be delivered for the same soe much lesse then a pound Troy as the same doth fall short in
finenes or value and soe for a greater or lesser quantity.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Coined Money to be given out in turn and course without Preference.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Making undue Preference, by Officer ; Penalty and Loss of Office; by Deputy; Penalty and Incapacity</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That there shall be noe preference in point of
Assaying or Coynage, but that all Gold and Silver brought in and delivered into the Mint to be assayed and
coyned shall be assayed coyned and delivered out to the respe&bholigct;ive Importers according to the order and times
of bringing in and delivering the same into the Mint or Mints and not otherwise, Soe as he that shall first bring
in and deliver any Gold or Silver to be coyned shall be taken and accounted the first person to have the same
assayed coyned and delivered, And he or they that shall bring in and deliver any Gold or Silver next, to be
accounted the second person to have the same assayed coyned and delivered and soe successively in course, And
that the Gold and Silver brought in and coyned as aforesaid shall be in the same order delivered to the
respe&bholigct;ive bringers in thereof their Executors Administrators or Assignes successively without preference of one
before the other and not otherwise And if any undue preference be made in entring of any Gold or Silver or
delivering out of any money coyned contrary to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct; by any Officer or Officers
of the Mint or Mints then the partie or partyes offending shall be lyeable by A&bholigct;ion of Debt or in the Case to
pay the value of the Gold or Silver brought in and not entred and delivered according to the true intent meaning
and dire&bholigct;ion of this A&bholigct; as aforesaid with Damages and Costs to the partie or partyes greived and shall be
forejudged from his or their Place or Office, And if such preference be unduely made by any his or their Deputie
or Deputyes Clerke or Clerks without dire&bholigct;ion or privity of his or their Master or Masters then such Deputie or
Deputyes Clerke or Clerks onely shall be lyeable to such A&bholigct;ion Damage and Costs as aforesaid and be for ever
A&bholigct;er uncapeable of serveing or bearing Office in any Mint in the Kingdome of England.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Payment to Persons first applying on subsequent Orders no undue Preference.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwayes That it shall not be interpreted any undue preference to incurr any Penalty in point of delivery
of Moneyes coyned if the Officer or Officers or their Deputyes or Clerkes shall deliver out or pay any moneyes
coyned to any person or persons, that doe come and' demand the same upon subsequent Entryes before others
that did not come to demand their moneyes in their order and course soe as there be soe much money reserved
as will satisfie them which shall, not be otherwise disposed of but kepte for them</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Bills under the Mint Master's Hand to Persons bringing Gold or Silver to be coined.</head>
			<para id="p6">And for the more orderly and cleare performance [thereof <ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Bee it ena&bholigct;ed, And it is hereby, ena&bholigct;ed by the
Authoritie aforesaid That the Master worker of His Majestyes Mint or Mints for the time being shall at the time
of the delivery and entry of any Gold or Silver in the said Mint or Mints give unto the bringer or bringers in
thereof to be coyned a Bill under his hand denoteing the Weight Finenes and Value thereof together with the
day and Order of its Delivery into the said Mint or Mints.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Gold or Silver brought to be coined freed from Attachments, &amp;c.; 
and all such Gold, &amp;c. to be delivered, to the bringer.</head>
			<para id="p7">And for the further Encouragement and Assurance of such as shall bring any Gold or Silver into His Majestyes
said Mint or Mints to be coyned Bee it ena&bholigct;ed And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe
Confiscation Forfeiture Seizure Attachment Stop or Restraint whatsoever shall be made in the said Mint or Mints
of any Gold or Silver brought in to be coyned for or by reason of any Imbargo, breach of the Peace Letters of
Mart or Reprisall or Warr with any Forreigne [Nation <ref idref="n2">2</ref> or upon any other accompt or pretence whatsoever But
that all Gold and Silver brought into any of His Majestyes Mint or Mints within the Kingdome of England to be
coyned shall truely and with all convenient speede be coyned and delivered out to the respe&bholigct;ive bringer or
bringers in thereof their [respe&bholigct;ive<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Executors Administrators or Assignes according to the Rules and Dire&bholigct;ions
of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. The Charge of Coinage defrayed by a new Impost on certain Liquors.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Wine, Vinegar, Cyder, and Beer imported, 10s. Per Ton</emph>;
<emph type="i">Brandy-wines and Strong Waters, 20s. per Ton; Over and above all other Duties;
Colle&bholigct;ors to pay Duty Quarterly into the Exchequer, to be kept distin&bholigct;.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">And whereas it cannot be reasonably expe&bholigct;ed that the Expence Waste and Charge in assaying melting downe
and coynage be borne by Your Majestie And for the further encouragement of Coynage Bee it enaced And it is
hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That for every Tunn of Wines Vinegar Syder or Beere that shall be
imported or brought into the Port of London or into any other Port Creeke or place within the Kingdome of
England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede from any parts beyond the Seas or Scotland
from and after the twentyeth day of December in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and six
there shall be levyed colle&bholigct;ed and paid the summe of Ten shillings, And for every Tunn of Brandy wines or Strong Waters that shall be imported as abovesaid the summe of Twenty shillings and soe proportionably for a
greater or lesser quantity to be levyed, colle&bholigct;ed and paid at the respe&bholigct;ive Custome houses to the Colle&bholigct;ors and
other Officers of the Customes for the time being at the Importation of the said Commodities over and above all
other Dutyes charged levyable and payable upon the said Commodityes and, to be by them distinguished and kepte
apart from all other moneyes by them colle&bholigct;ed and levyed upon the same Co&bhooov;modityes or upon any other
Co&bhooov;modities or Merchandises whatsoever and to be by the said Colle&bholigct;ors or Colle&bholigct;ors repe&bholigct;ively soe answered and
paid quarterly into the Receipt of the Exchequer of Your Majestie Your Heires and Successors, there alsoe to be
kepte distin&bholigct; and apart from all other moneyes ariseing by the Customes or by any other, way or Revenue
whatsoever which said Duty they are hereby injoyned to receive and pay according to the severall Dire&bholigct;ions of
this A&bholigct; without any Salary or Fee.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Remedy for the Duties.</head>
			<para id="p10">[And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authoritie aforesaid That all manner of Wines Vinegar Sider.
Beere Brandy wines and Strong waters imported as aforesaid shall pay their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Dutyes
imposed, by this A&bholigct;, And upon non payment thereof shall be lyeable to such and the same paines penalties and
forfeitures as in and by the late A&bholigct;s for Tonnage and Poundage and for Frauds are ena&bholigct;ed and appointed upon
non payment of the Dutyes by the said A&bholigct;s imposed upon Goods and Merchandises of the same nature with those
mentioned in this A&bholigct;.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Liquorsre-exported within one Year, Duty to be repaid.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwayes and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed That for what of the aforesaid Commodities shall be transpouted
into any parts beyond the Seas within the terme and space of one yeare After the Importation thereof That the
Duty, paid by this A&bholigct; for the same shall be repaid by the respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;ors of the Customes for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Money raised to be applied to Coinage, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">No Monies to be issued out of Exchequer but by Warrant from Treasury.; Contents of such Warrants.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p13">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That noe moneyes levyable and payable by this A&bholigct; shall be applyed or
converted to any use or uses whatsoever other then to the defraying the charge [and expence<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] of the Mint or
Mints and of the, assaying melting downe Waste and Coynage of Gold and Silver and the encouragement of (<ref idref="n6">6</ref>)
bringing in of Gold and Silver into the said Mint or Mints there to be coyned into the current Coynes of this
Kingdome, Nor shall any of the said moneyes be issued out of the Exchequer but by Order or Warrant of the
Lord Treasurer or Under Treasurer or Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers of the Treasury for the time being to the Master and Worker
or Masters and Workers of Your Majesties Mint or Mints for the time being and mentioning that they are for
the use and service aforesaid to be kepte in His Majestyes Office of Receipte in the said Mint or Mints under the
usuall Keyes of the Warden Master and Worker and Comptroller for the time being and issued out thence from
time to time according to the manner and course of the said Mint or Mints respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. The annual Charge of Salaries and Repairs restrained to &pound;3000.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Overplus of Monies to be employed towards Coinage.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p15">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed. That there shall not be issued out of the Exchequer of the said Moneyes in
any one yeare for the Fees and Salaryes of the Officers of the Mint or Mints and towards the provideing
maintaining and repairing of the Houses Offices . and Buildings and other necessaries for assaying melting downe
and coyning above the summe of Three thousand pounds Sterlin money, And the overplus of the said moneyes soe
kepte or to be kepte as aforesaid shall be imployed for and towards the expence waste and charge of assaying
melting downe and coynage and buying in of Gold and Silver to coyne and not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p16">And lastly Bee it ena&bholigct;ed And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That this A&bholigct; shall continue and
be in force untill the twentyeth day of December which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred seaventy one, and untill the end of the first Session of Parlyament then next following and noe longer</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Proviso for Lady Villiers under Letters Patent of 20th August 12 Car. II.</head>
			<para id="p17">[Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That whereas His Majestie in and by his Letters Patents under
His Great Seale dated at Westminster the Twentyeth day of August in the Twelfth yeare of His Raigne did for
diverse good causes and considerations Him moveing give and grant to Dame Barbara Villiers Widdow the summe
of Two pence by tale out of every pound weight Troy of Silver moneyes which from thenceforth should be
coyned by vertue of any Warrant or Indenture made and to be made by His Majestie His Heires and Successors
To have hold receive perceive and take the same unto the said Dame Barbara Villiers her Executors
Administrators and Assignes from the Ninth day of the then instant August weekely as the said moneyes should
be coyned for and dureing the terme of one and twenty yeares as by the same doth appeare That His Majestie
may out of the moneyes leviable by this A&bholigct; appoint and cause reasonable satisfa&bholigct;ion to be made yearely to
the said Dame Barbara Villiers her Executors and Administrators for her Interest in the Premisses not exceeding
the summe of Six hundred pounds in any one yeare.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">hereof <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a feparate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


