<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47380" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act for a more speedy and effe&bholigct;uall Proceeding upon Distresses and Avowryes for Rents. [Rot. Parl. 17 C. II. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Remedy upon a Nonsuit before Issue.; Writ of Inquiry of Damages.; On Notice to Plaintiff, Sheriff to execute Writ.; Judgment for Defendant.; Execution.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Forasmuch as the ordinary Remedy for Arrearages of Rents is by Distresse upon the Lands chargable
therewith And yet neverthelesse by reason of the intricate and dilatary Proceedings upon Replevins that
Remedy is become ineffe&bholigct;uall For remedy thereof It is ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie with the
Advice and Assent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Co&bhooov;mons in this p&bhopcrl;sent Parlyament assembled and by
Authoritie of the same That whensoever any Plaintiffe in Replevin shall be Nonsuite before Issue joyned in any
Suite of Replevin by [Plaint or<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Writt lawfully returned removed or depending in any of the Kings Courts at
Westminster That the Defendant makeing a Suggestion in nature of an Avowry or Cognizance for such Rent to
ascertaine the Court of the cause of Distresse The Court upon his Prayer shall award a Writt to the Sheriffe of
the County where the Distresse was taken to enquire by the Oathes of Twelve good and lawfull men of his
Balywicke touching the Summe in Arreare at the time of such Distresse taken and the value of the Goods or
Cattell destrained, And thereupon notice of Fifteene dayes shall be given to the Plaintiffe or his Attourney in
Court of the sitting of such Enquiry and thereupon the Sheriffe shall enquire of the trueth of the matters contained
in such Writt by the Oathes of Twelve good and lawfull men of his County, and upon the Returne of such
Inquisition the Defendant shall have Judgement to recover against the Plaintiffe the Arrearages of such Rent in
case the Goods or Cattell destrained shall amount unto that value, And in case they shall not amount to that
value then soe much as the value of the said Goods and Cattell soe destrained shall amount unto together with
his full Costs of Suite and shall have Execution thereupon by Fieri facias or Elegit or otherwise as the Law
shall require,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Remedy upon a Nonsuit after Issue.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Judgment for Avowant.; Execution.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And in case such Plaintiffe shall be Nonsuite after Conusance or Avowry made and Issue joyned or if the
Verdi&bholigct; shall be given against such Plaintiffe then the Jurors that are impannelled or returned to inquire of such
Issue shall at the Prayer of the Defendant enquire concerning the summe of the Arreares and the value of the
Goods or Cattell destrained And thereupon the Avowant or he that makes Conusance shall have Judgement for
such Arrearages or soe much thereof as the Goods or Cattell destrained amounts unto together with his full
Costs and shall have Execution for the same by Fieri facias or Elegit or otherwise as the Law shall require</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Remedy after Demurrer.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Judgment for Avowant.; Execution.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if Judgement in any of the Courts aforesaid be
given upon Demurrer for the Avowant or him that maketh Conusance for any Rent the Court shall at the
Prayer of the Defendant award a Writt to inquire of the value of such Distresse and upon the Returne thereof
Judgement shall be given for the Avowant, or him that makes Conusance as aforesaid for the Arreares alledged
to be behinde in such Avowry or Conusance if the Goods or Cattell soe destrained shall amount to that value,
And in case they shall not amount to that value, then for soe much as the said Goods or Cattell soe destrained
amount unto together with his full Costs of Suite and shall have like Execution as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Where Goods not of sufficient Value, Distress from time to time for residue.</head>
			<para id="p7">[Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That in all Cases aforesaid where the value of the Cattell destrained as
aforesaid shall not be found to be to the full value of the Arreares destrained for that the partie to whom such
Arreares were due his Executors or Administrators may from time to time destraine againe for the Residue of the
said Arreares.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


