<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47384" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1666</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An A&bholigct; against importing Cattell from Ireland and other parts beyond the Seas and Fish taken by Forreigners.[Rot. Parl. 18 &amp;19 C. II. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 15 C. II. c. 7. 13.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Importation of Cattle declared a common Nuisance.; Importing Cattle; (Exception); Cattle to be seized.; How Seizure to be proceeded with.; In what Case to be forfeited</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament entituled An A&bholigct; for the encouragement of Trade amongst
other things some Provision was made for the preventing of comeing in of vast Numbers of Cattell
whereby the Rents and Values of the Land of this Kingdome were much fallen and like dayly to fall more to the
great Prejudice Detriment and Impovrishment of this Kingdome which neverthelesse hath by experience beene found
to be ineffe&bholigct;uall and the continuance of any Importation either of the Leane or Fatt Cattell dead or alive
herein after specified not onely unnecessary but very destru&bholigct;ive to the welfare of this Kingdome Bee it therefore
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled That such Importation from and after the second
day of February in this present yeare One thousand six hundred sixty and six is a publique and common Nusance
and shall be soe adjudged deemed and taken to be to all intents and purposes whatsoever, And that if any great
Cattell Sheepe or Swine or any Beefe Porke or Bacon (excepte for the necessary Provision of the respe&bholigct;ive Shipps
or Vessells in which the same shall be brought not exposeing the same or any part thereof to Sale) shall from
and after the said second day of February by any wise whatsoever be imported or brought from beyond Seas into
this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede That then it shall and may
be lawfull for any Constable Tythingman Headborough Churchwardens or Overseers of the Poore or any of
them within their respe&bholigct;ive Liberties Parishes or Places to take and seize the same and keepe the same dureing
the space of Eight and forty houres in some publique and convenient place where such Seizure shall be made
within which time if the Owner or Owners or any for them or him shall make it appeare unto some Justice [of
the Peace<emph type="p">2</emph>] of the same County where the same shall be soe seized by the Oath of two credible Witnesses which
Oath the said Justice of Peace is hereby impowered and required to administer That the same were not imported
from Ireland or from any other place beyond the Seas not herein after excepted after the said Second day of
February Then the same upon the Warrant of such Justice of Peace shall be delivered without delay But in defaulte
of such Proofe and Warrant then the same to be forfeited, One halfe [thereof<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to be disposed to the use of the
Poore of the Parish where the same shall be soe found or seized the other halfe to be to his or their owne use
that shall soe seize the same.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Importing Fish taken by Foreigners;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">to be seized and disposed of</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the better encouragement of the Fishery of this Kingdome Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie
aforesaid That if any Ling, Herring, Codd or Pilchard fresh or salted, dryed or bloated or any Salmons Eeles or
Congers taken by any Forreigners Aliens to this Kingdome shall be imported uttered sold or exposed to sale in
this Kingdome That then it shall and may be lawfull for any person or persons to take and seize the same, The
one halfe thereof to be disposed of to the use of the Poore of the Parish where the same shall be soe found or
seized, the other halfe to his or their owne use which shall soe seize the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Importation of Cattle from the Isle of Man.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Continuance of A&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">Provided alwayes That noe thing in this A&bholigct; shall be construed to hinder the Importation of Cattell from the
Isle of Man in this Kingdome of England soe as the number of the said Cattell doe not exceede Six hundred
Head yearely And that they be not of any other Breed then of the Breed of the Isle of Man And that they be
landed at the Port of Chester or some of the members thereof and not elsewhere This A&bholigct; to continue untill the
end of seaven yeares and from thence to the end of the first Session of the next Parlyament.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


