<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47390" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1666</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for rebuilding the Citty of London. [Rot. Parl. 18 &amp; 19 C. II. nu.8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that the City of London had been destroyed by Fire.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;; All future Buildings to be after the Method herein mentioned.; Building Houses otherwise; Nuisance, and Builder to enter into a Recognizance to abate the same; on Default, Imprisonment; or House may be demolished by Order of Court of Aldermen</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Forasmuch as the Citty of London being the Imperiall Seate of His Majestyes Kingdomes and renowned for
Trade and Commerce throughout the world by reason of a most dreadfull Fire lately happening therein was
for the most part thereof burnt downe and destroyed within the compasse of a few dayes and now lyes buryed in
its owne Ruines For the speedy Restauration whereof and for the better Regulation Uniformity and Gracefulnes
of such new Buildings as shall be ere&bholigct;ed for Habitations in order thereunto, And to the end that great and
outragious Fires (through the blessing of Almighty God soe farr forth as humane Providence (with submission to
the Divine pleasure) can foresee may be reasonably prevented or obviated for the time to come, both by the
matter and forme of such building, And further to the intent that all Incouragement and Expedition may be given
unto, and all Impediments and Obstru&bholigct;ions that may retard or protra&bholigct; the undertakeing or carrying on a
worke soe necessary and of soe great Honour and Importance to His Majestie and this Kingdome and to the rest
of His Majestyes Kingdomes and Dominions may be removed. Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present
Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the Rules and Dire&bholigct;ions hereafter in this A&bholigct;
prescribed be duely observed by all persons therein concerned And first That noe Building or House for
Habitation whatsoever be hereafter ere&bholigct;ed within the limitts of the said Citty and Liberties thereof but such as
shall be pursuant to such Rules and Orders of Building and with such materialls as are herein after perticularly
appointed and according to such Scantlings as are sett downe and prescribed in a Table in this present A&bholigct;
hereafter specified, And if any person or persons shall presume to build contrary thereunto and bee convi&bholigct;ed of
the same by the oathes of two or more credible witnesses to be taken before the Lord Maior for the time
being or any two or more of the Justices of the Peace for the said Citty who are hereby impowered to administer
the same oathes That then and in such case the said House soe irregularly built as aforesaid shall be deemed as
a common Nusance and the Builder and Levier thereof shall enter into a Recognizance in such summe as the said
Maior and Justices respe&bholigct;ively in their Discretions shall appoint for abatement and demolishing the same in
convenient time or otherwise to amend the same according to such Rules and Orders as aforesaid, and in defaulte
of entring into such Recognizance the Offender shall be committed to the common Goale of the said Citty there
to remaine without Baile or Mainprize till he shall have abated or demolished or otherwise amended the same, or
else such irregular House shall or may be demolished or abated by Order of the Court of Aldermen.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Surveyors ele&bholigct;ed by Mayor, &amp;c. to prevent irregular Buildings.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Surveyor's Oath</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And that the said irregular Buildings may be the better prevented or more effe&bholigct;ually discovered Be it further
ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Lord Maior Aldermen and Common Councill of the said Citty shall
and may at their will and pleasure ele&bholigct; nominate and appoint one or more discreet and intelligent person or
persons in the Art of Building to be the Surveyors or Supervisors to see the said Rules and Scantlings well and
truely observed, And that it shall be lawfull for the said Maior Aldermen and Common Councill, or for the
Maior and Aldermen in their Court of Aldermen to administer to all the said Surveyours or Supervisors an Oath
upon the Holy Evangelists for the true and impartiall execution of their Office in that behalfe and to appoint the
severall Precin&bholigct;s which shall be under their severall Surveyes,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Four Sorts of Houses.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Uniformity of Roofs of the first Three Sorts</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And to the end that all Builders may the better know how to provide and fitt their materialls for their severall
Buildings Be it ena&bholigct;ed That there shall be onely fower sortes of Buildings and noe more, and that all manner
of Houses soe to be ere&bholigct;ed shall be of one of those [four<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] sortes of Buildings and noe other (that is to say) The
First and least sort of Houses fronting By lanes, the Second sort of Houses fronting Streets and Lanes of note, the
Third sort of Houses fronting high and principall Streetes, the Fourth and largest sort of Mansion houses for
Citizens or other persons of extraordinary quality not fronting either of the three former Wayes And the Roofes
of each of the said first three sorts of Houses respe&bholigct;ively shall be uniforme.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Lord Mayor, &amp;c. to declare the Streets and Lanes.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Marks and Stakes; Removing them; Penalty &pound;10 or Imprisonment.; Poor Offender to be publickly whipped.; Reward to Informer.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">And for avoiding any uncertainety to the Builders or others herein Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Lord Maior
Aldermen and Common Councill of the said Citty for the time being shall on or before the first day of Aprill
next ensueing declare which and how many shall hereafter be accounted and taken to be By lanes, which and how
many shall hereafter be deemed Streets or Lanes of note and high and principall Streets by A&bholigct; of Co&bhooov;mon Councill
to be passed for that purpose, which Declaration being made as aforesaid, all and singular the said Streets and
Lanes (hereby intended to be rebuilt) shall by Order of the said Lord Maior Aldermen and Common Councill or
such persons as they under the Co&bhooov;mon Seale of the said Citty shall order and appoint be marked or staked out
and distinguished to the end the Breadth Length and Extent thereof may be the better knowne and observed. And
if any person or persons whatsoever shall wittingly or willingly without good Authority plucke up or remove any
of the said Stakes or Marke stones thereby to obscure or confound the bounds of such Streetes or Lanes or any
of them and shall be thereof legally convi&bholigct;ed by the Oath of one Witnesse (other then of the Informer) to be
taken before any one or more Justices of the Peace of the said Citty, That then the said Justice or Justices shall
or may send such Offender to the Co&bhooov;mon Goale of the said Citty there to remaine by the space of three Moneths
without Baile or Mainprize unlesse he shall pay or cause to be paid to the use of the Maior Co&bhooov;monaltie and
Citizens of the said Citty the summe of ten pounds to be imployed in and towards the repaireing of the publique
Buildings of the said Citty Provided alwayes That where any such Offence shall be committed by any person or
persons of low and meane condition whom the said Justice or Justices of the Peace shall in, his conscience beleive
to be unable to satisfie the said Penaltyes That then and in such case the said Justice or Justices of the Peace shall
and may by Order and Warrant under his or their Hands and Seales cause such Offender to be openly whipped
neere unto the place where the Offence shall be committed till his body be bloudy. And that it shall and may
be lawfull for the said Justice or Justices of the Peace to reward the said Informer out of the Pecuniary Penalty
to be incurred according to his discretion not exceeding a Third part of the said Penaltie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Buildings to be of Brick, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Archwork to sustain the Burden of the Fabrick</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And in reguard the building with Bricke is not onely more comely and durable but alsoe more safe against
future perills of Fire Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by and with the Authoritie aforesaid That all the outsides of all
Buildings in and about the said Citty be henceforth made of Bricke or Stone or of Bricke and Stone together
except Doore cases and Window Frames the Brest Summers and other parts of the first Story to the Front,
betweene the Peeres which are to be left to the discretion of the Builder to use substantiall Oaken Timber instead
of Bricke or Stone for conveniency of Shopps, And that the said Doores Brest Summers and Window frames be
sufficiently discharged of the burthen of the Fabricke by Archworke of Bricke or Stone either straight or circular</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Surveyor's Charge.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Party Walls.; Toothing.; First Builder to be paid for Moiety of Party Wall and Piers with Interest.; If difference between first and later Builders in respe&bholigct; thereof, Remedy</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That the said Surveyors or Supervisors soe to be appointed [as aforesaid<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and every of them
within their severall Precin&bholigct;s shall take care That in building of all Houses within the said Citty and Libertyes
thereof there be, and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That there shall be Partie walls and Partie
peeres sett out equally on each Builders ground to be built up by the first beginner of such Building and that
convenient Toothing be left in the Front wall by the said first Builder for the better joyning of the next House
that shall be built to the same, And that noe man be permitted by the said Surveyours to build on the said Partie
wall or on his owne contiguous ground untill he hath fully reimbursed the said first Builder the full moyety of
the charges of the said Partie wall and Peeres together with Interest for the same after the rate of Six pounds
per Centu&bhooov;m per Ann? for forbearance thereof to be accounted from the begining of the said first building. And
in case any difference shall arise betweene the first and latter builders, concerning the true value of the said Charge
that then the same be referred to the Alderman of that Ward where such building shall be and to his Deputie
to mediate an agreement of such difference And where the said Alderman and his Deputie or one of them shall
be partyes or where they cannot compose such difference as aforesaid that the matter be referred to the Examination
of the Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen who shall heare and finally determine the same without any appeale
to be had.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. The Contents of least sort of Houses.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Thickness of Party Walls.; Scantlings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that the said Houses of the first and least sort of Building fronting By streetes or
Lanes as aforesaid shall be of two Stories high besides Cellers and Garrets, That the Cellars thereof be six foote
and a halfe high if the springs of water hinder not, that the first Story be nine foote high from the Floore to
the Cieling, and the second Story nine foote high from the Floore to the Cieling, that all Walls in front and reere
as high as the first Story be of the full thicknes of the length of two Bricks and thence upwards to the Garrets
of the thicknes of one Bricke and an halfe, and that the thicknes of the Garrat walls on the backe part be left
to the discretion of the builder soe that the same be not lesse then the length of one Bricke, And alsoe that the
thicknes of the Party walls betweene these Houses of this first and lesser sort of building be one Bricke and an
halfe as high as the said Garrets and that the thicknes of the Partie Wall in the Garrets be of the thickenes of
one Bricke in length at the least, and that the Scantlings of Timber and Stone to be used about the building
thereof be as in the said Table are sett downe and prescribed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Contents of Second Sorts of Houses.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Thickness of Party Walls.; Scantlings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Houses of the second sort of building fronting Streets and Lanes of note
and the River of Thames shall consist of three Stories high beside Cellars and Garrets as aforesaid, that the Cellars
thereof be six foote and [an<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] halfe high (if the springs of water hinder not) that the first Story containe full tenn foote
in height from the Floore to the Sieling the second full ten foote, the third nine foote, That all the said Walls in
front and reere as high as the first Story be of the full thicknesse of the length of two Bricks and an halfe, and 
from thence upwards to the Garret Floore of the thicknes of one bricke and an halfe, and that the thicknes of
the Garret walls on the backe part be left to the discretion of the builder soe that the same be not lesse then
the length of one Bricke, and alsoe that the thicknes of the Partie walls betweene every House of this second
and larger sort of building be two Bricke lengths as high as the first Story, and thence upwards to the Garrets
of the thicknes of one Bricke and halfe, the Scantlings of Timber and Stone to be as in the said Table are
prescribed,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Contents of Third Sort of Houses.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Thickness of Party Walls.; Scantlings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">Alsoe that the Houses of the third sort of buildings fronting the high and principall Streetes shall consist of
four Stories high besides Cellars and Garrets as aforesaid, that the first Story containe full ten foote in height
from the Floore to the Cielling, the second ten foote and an halfe, the third nine foote, the fourth eight foote and
an halfe, That all the said Walls in front and reere as high as the first Story be of the full thicknes of the
length of two Bricks and an halfe, and from thence upwards to the Garret Floore of the thicknes of one Bricke
and an halfe, that the thicknes of the Garret walls on the backe part be left to the discretion of the builder soe
as the same be not lesse then the length of one Bricke, and alsoe that the thicknes of the Party walls betweene
every house of this third and larger sort of building be two Bricks lengths as high as the first Story, and thence
upwards to the Garrets of the thicknes of one bricke and halfe, the scantlings of Timber and Stone to be as in
the said Table are prescribed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Scantlings of Fourth Sort.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Height, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that [all Houses of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the fourth sort of building being Mansion houses and of the
greatest bignes not fronting upon any of the Streets or Lanes as aforesaid shall beare the same scantlings as in
the Table are sett downe for the same, and that the number of Stories and the height thereof be left to the
discretion of the builder soe as he exceede not foure Stories.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Balconies with Rails and Bars of Iron in High Streets.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Penthouses.; Water carried off</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that in the Front of all Houses [hereafter<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] to be ere&bholigct;ed in any such Streets as by
A&bholigct; of Common Councill shall be declared to be High Streets Belconies fower foote broad with Railes and Barrs
of Iron of equall distance from the ground shall be placed, every of which Belconies shall containe in length two
parts of the Front of the House on which it shall be placed in three parts to be divided, and the remaining
vacancy of the Front shall be supplyed with a Penthouse of the breadth of the Belcony to be covered with Lead
Slate or Tile and to be cieled with Plaistering underneath, and that the Water falling aswell from the topps of the
said Houses as from the said Belconies and Penthouses be conveyed into the Channells by Party pipes on the
sides or fronts of the said Houses, and that Pavements under every of the said Belconies and Penthouses be made
of good and sufficient broad flatt Stone at the charge of the builder,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Height of the First Floor of Second and Third Sorts of Houses.</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Steps up to Houses.; Extent of Bulks, Jetties, &amp;c.; Extent of Stall Boards</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that noe builder of any of the Houses fronting any of the said High Streets, Streets
or Lanes of note be permitted to lay his first Floore over the Cellar more then Eighteen inches above the said
Streete or lesse then Six with one Circular step to leade up thereunto to be placed without the building, And
that noe Trapp doores or open Grates to be in any wise suffered to be made into any such Cellar or Warehouse
without the foundations of the Front, but that all Lights to be made into any of them be henceforth made upright
and not otherwise, and that noe Bulks Jettyes Windowes Posts Seates or any thing of like sort shall be made or
ere&bholigct;ed in any Streets Lanes or By Lanes to extend beyond the auntient foundation of Houses nor that any House
be sett further into the streete then the auncient foundation saveing onely that in the high and principall Streetes it
shall be lawfull for the Inhabitants to suffer their Stall boards (when their Shop windowes are set open) to [turne
over and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] extend eleaven inches and noe more from the Foundation of their Houses into the Streets for the better
conveniency of their Shop windowes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Ground not built upon in Three Years;</head>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Notice to build.; Negle&bholigct;ing to build; Warrant by Lord Mayor, &amp;c. to Sheriff to impannel a Jury.; Jury to estimate Value of Ground on Oath; and then the same to be sold under Common Seal of the City; and the Money paid to the Owner.; Sale made and enrolled to be final, and Purchaser may hold and enjoy</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed that if any person or persons bodies Pollitique or Corporate being seised possessed
or interessed of or in any Ground which was formerly builded upon, and the Houses thereupon being now burned
or pulled downe at the time of the late Fire shall not within three yeares next ensueing build up the same that
then the Maior Aldermen and Co&bhooov;mon Councill of the Citty of London by A&bholigct; of Co&bhooov;mon Councill may cause
Proclamation [publiquely to be<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] made betweene the houres of twelve and two of the clocke in the afternoone as
well at or upon the said Ground as [alsoe<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] at or upon the publique Exchange of the said Citty thereby to give
notice to all persons that shall be or may be therein concerned to cause the same to be rebuilded according to the
dire&bholigct;ion of this [p&bhopcrl;sent<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] A&bholigct; within the space of nine moneths then next following, And in case the Owners thereof
or other person or persons haveing Interest therein shall refuse or negcle&bholigct; to rebuild the same in manner and
within such time as aforesaid that then in such case the said Maior and Court of Aldermen of the said Citty are
hereby authorized to issue out Warrants to the Sheriffes of London for the time being requiring them to impanell
and returne before them a Jury of good and lawfull men of the said Citty which the said Sheriffes are hereby
authorized and required to doe accordingly, which Jury soe returned shall upon their Oathes to be administred to
them by the said Maior and Court of Aldermen (who are likewise hereby authorized to minister the same) enquire
estimate and assesse the true and just value of such void Ground according to their Judgements, and that from
and after such Inquiry and Valuation thereof made as aforesaid (by Inquest of the said Jury) it shall and may be
lawfull to and for the said Maior Aldermen and Co&bhooov;mon Councill of the said Citty to make Sale of the Fee or
Inheritance thereof by Conveyance under their Common Seale to any person or persons that will purchase the same
at such Price at which the same shall have beene soe as aforesaid estimated and valued by the said Jury, and the
moneyes thereupon to be received of the purchasers thereof shall be paid into the Chamber of London and from thence 
to be issued out. and paid by the Chamberlaine of London for the time being unto such person or persons who
shall have any Estate or Interest into or out of the same according to his or their respe&bholigct;ive Estate or Estates
Title or Interest which Sale soe made and inrolled of Record according to the Custome or Usage of the said
Citty for Inrolment of Bargaines and Sales shall be finall and conclusive to all other persons whatsoever and shall
barr them their Heires and Assignes to claime any Estate Right Title or Interest of in or out of the Grounds
soe sold precedent to the said Sale And the Purchaser or Purchasers thereof his and their Heires and Assignes
shall and may by vertue of this A&bholigct; have hold and enjoy the same against all persons claiming any Estate Right
Title or Interest into, or out of the same his and their Heires, Executors Administrators and Assignes freed and
discharged of and from [all<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Incumbrances in Estate Title Charge or otherwise precedent to the said Sale.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Two Judges of K.B. may set the Prices of Brick, Tiles, and Lime.</head>
			<para id="p27">And to the end the said Builders may receive due encouragement by haveing the materialls for building at
reasonable prices and getting of Workemen for moderate wages Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that in case of Combination
or unreasonable Exa&bholigct;ion by Bricke makers Tile makers and Lime burners It shall and may be lawfull for the
Justices of the Court of Kings Bench or any two or more of them upon the complaint of the said Maior and
Court of Aldermen to call before them such a number of Bricke makers Tile makers and Lime burners makeing
or burning Bricke Tile or Lime at any place within Five miles distance of the River of Thames as they shall
thinke fitt, and upon conference with them had concerning the premisses if they will be present or otherwise in
their absence to assesse such reasonable, prices from time to time upon every thousand of the said Bricks and
Tiles and upon every hundred of the said Lime and every greater or lesser quantity to be delivered at the severall
Kilnes And alsoe of all Carriages of the same Materialls from the said Kilns to the said Citty whether by Land
or by Water as may equally respe&bholigct; the honest proffitt of the said Brickemakers Tile makers Lime burners and
Carriers and the necessity and convenience of the Builder.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. In case of Combinations and Exa&bholigct;ions of Workmen and Labourers for their Hire; Lord Mayor, &amp;c. may appoint Wages, Prices of Materials, &amp;c.;</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Table thereof to bind Persons concerned.; Artificers, &amp;c. refusing to sell or work at such Prices; or leaving Work unfinished; or giving more Wages than allowed; Imprisonment or Penalty.; Satisfa&bholigct;ion to Party injured out of Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">And to the intent noe Brickemaker Tile maker Lime burner Carpenter Brickelayer Mason [Plaister<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Joyner
Plumber or other Artificer Workeman or Labourer may make the common calamity a pretence to extort unreasonable
or excessive Wages Bee it likewise ena&bholigct;ed That in case of combination or exa&bholigct;ion of unreasonable Wages by
the said Artificers Workemen or Labourers or any of them the said Justices of the Court of Kings Bench or any
two or more .of them upon the like complaint of the said Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen, shall and may
from time to time limitt rate and appoint the wages of the said Artificers Workemen and Labourers by the day
weeke or otherwise, and what wages every of the said Workemen shall have by the great, by the Foote Yard
Rodd or Pearch, or for any greater Quantity, which said Rates together with the Prices of the said Materialls
and Carriages soe assessed being sett downe in a Table and Proclamation thereof made by the Lord Maior for the
time being accordingly the same shall efte&bholigct;ually binde all persons therein concerned. And if any of the said
Artificers refuse to sell the said Materialls for the prices soe assessed or any of the said Carpenters Brickelayers
Masons Plaisterers Joyners Plumbers or other Workemen or Labourers shall either refuse to worke for the wages
soe assessed or shall depart from his said worke after he hath undertaken to doe the same without Licence of such
person or persons as imployed him, and before it be finished unlesse it be for non payment of his hire or other
just cause to be allowed before one Justice of the Peace of such place where the offence shall be co&bhooov;mitted or if
any person or persons whatsoever shall by any secret wayes or meanes give covenant article or agree to give
dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly by himselfe or any other for him any other or greater wages prices or other co&bhooov;modity then
shall be soe assessed the said Offender and Offenders being thereof legally convi&bholigct; by the Oaths of one or more
witnesses, which Oath the said Justice is hereby impowered to administer shall be by the said Justice of the peace
[forthwith<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] co&bhooov;mitted to the Co&bhooov;mon Goale there to remaine by the space of one moneth without Baile or Maineprize
unlesse he shall pay or cause to be paid for every such Offence [to the said Justice of the peace<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] such Fine as
by the discretion of the said Justice shall be sett upon any such Offender not exceeding Ten pounds, Out of
which Fine the said Justice shall and may award and pay unto the partie injured such satisfa&bholigct;ion as he shall
judge reasonable and the residue thereof shall pay unto the Chamberlaine of London for the time being to be
imployed [for and<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] towards the reedifying of the publique Buildings of the Citty aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Artificers working made free of London; and liable to serve in Offices as Freemen.</head>
			<para id="p30">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That all Carpenters Brickelayers Masons Plaisterers Joyners and other Artificers
Workemen and Labourers to be imployed in the said Buildings who are not Freemen of the said Citty shall for
the space of seaven yeares next ensueing and for soe long time after as untill the said buildings shall be fully
finished have and enjoy such and the same liberty of workeing and being sett to worke in the said building as the
Freemen of the Citty of the same Trades and Professions have and ought to enjoy, Any Usage or Custome of
the Citty to the contrary notwithstanding: And that such Artificers as aforesaid which for the space of seaven
yeares shall have wrought in the rebuilding of the Citty in their respe&bholigct;ive Arts shall from and after the said
seaven yeares have and enjoy the same Liberty to worke as Freemen of the said Citty for and dureing their
naturall lives. Provided alwayes that such Artificers claiming such priviledges shall be lyeable to undergoe all such
Offices and to pay and performe such Dutyes in reference to the Service and Government of the Citty as Freemen
of the Citty of their respe&bholigct;ive Arts and Trades are lyeable to undergoes pay and performe</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Differences about placing or stopping Lights may be determined by Alderman of the Ward or Deputy; or if concerned or cannot determine, then by Lord Mayor, &amp;c.; No further Appeal.</head>
			<para id="p31">And to remove all obsticles which otherwise may hinder soe good and proffitable a worke Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed
by the Authority aforesaid that all differences ariseing betweene the said Builders or any others concerning placeing.
and, stoping up of Lights Windowes Watercourses or Gutters which may hinder or retard the said building shall
and may be heard mediated and determined (if it may be) by the Alderman of the Ward where the cause of any 
such difference shall arise and his Deputie, and if either the said Alderman or his Deputie be concerned as parties
in the controversie, or that they cannot determine the said Differences that then and in every such case the same
be certifyed by the said Alderman or his Deputie unconcerned therein to the said Maior and Court of Aldermen
who upon deliberate heareing of all partyes shall finally determine the same without further or other Appeale.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Sewers, Vaults, and pitching and paving Streets, by Persons appointed by Lord Mayor, &amp;c. and Surveyors.</head>
			<para id="p32">
				<emph type="i">The said Persons may impose a Tax on Houses for the said Purpose.; In Default of Payment; Distress.; All other Commissioners suspended as to the said City and Liberties for Seven Years, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p33">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the numbers and places for all co&bhooov;mon Sewers
Draines and Vaults and the order and manner of paveing and pitching the Streets and Lanes within the said Citty
and Liberties thereof shall be designed and sett out by such and soe many persons as the said Maior Aldermen
and Co&bhooov;monalty in Co&bhooov;mon Councill assembled shall from time to time authorize and appoint under their Co&bhooov;mon
Seale or the more part of them, which said persons soe authorized and appointed or any seaven or more of
them together with the said Surveyours or some or one of them within his or their Precin&bholigct; respe&bholigct;ively shall at
their meeteing have power and authority to order and dire&bholigct; the makeing of any new Vaults Drains and Sewers,
or to cutt into any Draine or Sewer already made, and for the altering inlargeing amending cleansing and scouring
of any old Vaults Sinks or Co&bhooov;mon Sewers, For the better effe&bholigct;ing whereof it shall and may be lawfull to and
for the said persons soe authorized and appointed as aforesaid or any seaven or more of them at their said
meeting to impose any reasonable Taxe upon all Houses within the said Citty and Libertyes thereof in proportion
to the benefitt they shall receive thereby for and towards the new makeing cutting altering inlargeing amending
cleansing and scouring all and singular the said Vaults Draines Sewers pavements and pitching aforesaid : And in
defaulte of payment of the said summes soe to be charged it shall and may be lawfull [to and<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] for the said
persons soe authorized as aforesaid or any seaven or more of them by Order and Warrant under their hands
and seales to leavy the said summe and summes of moneyes soe assessed by Distresse and sale of the goods of
the party chargeable therewith and refuseing or negcle&bholigct;ing to pay the same rendering the overplus (if any be)
And that all other Co&bhooov;mis?ers whatsoever be altogether suspended to intermedle in the premisses within the said
Citty and Liberties thereof for the space of seaven yeares next, and for soe long after untill the said intended
buildings shall be fully finished Any Law or Statute to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Noisome and perilous Trades not to be in principal Streets.</head>
			<para id="p34">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Lord Maior Aldermen and Co&bhooov;mon
Councill of the said Citty from time to time to prohibit such Trades and Occupations as they shall judge
noysome, or perilous in respe&bholigct; of Fire to be used or exercised in the high or principall Streets of the said Citty.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Lord Mayor, &amp;c. may remove, &amp;c. Conduits.</head>
			<para id="p35">And forasmuch as the freedome and opennes of the Streete conduceth much to the advancement of Trade and
Ornament of the Citty Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Maior Aldermen
and Co&bhooov;monalty by Order of Co&bhooov;mon Councill in that behalfe to be made from time to time and at their will and
pleasure to remove out of any of the high Streets all or any of the Conduits now standing or hereafter to be
ere&bholigct;ed, and to sett up and to ere&bholigct; the same in such other publique places within the said Citty as they shall
thinke fitt, or to contra&bholigct; the same into any smaller or lesser compasse in the places where they now stand or
hereafter shall be ere&bholigct;ed as aforesaid according to their discretions,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Streets herein named to be enlarged.</head>
			<para id="p36">And whereas many auntient Streets and Passages within the said Citty and Libertyes thereof, and amongst
others those which are hereafter mentioned were narrow and incommodious for Carriages and Passengers and
prejudiciall to the Trade and Health of the Inhabitants and are necessary to be inlarged as well for the Convenience
as Ornament of the Citty Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Maior Aldermen and Co&bhooov;mons of
(<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) the said Citty for the time being in Co&bhooov;mon Councill assembled shall and may and are hereby impowered and
required to inlarge all and every the Streets and Places hereafter mentioned where and in such manner as there
shall be cause by and with the Approbation of his Majestie and not otherwise that is to say, The Streete called
Fleete Streete from the place where the Gray hound Taverne stood to Ludgate and from thence to Saint Pauls
Church yard, The Streete leading from the East end of Saint Pauls Church into Cheapeside, The Streete and
Passage at the East end of Cheapeside leading into the Poultry, The Streete and Passage out of the Poultry leading
into the West end of Cornhill at or neere the place [late<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] called the Stocks, The Streete called Blow bladder streete
leading from the West end of Cheapeside towards Newgate Market, and to inlarge the streete and passage from
thence towards Newgate Market by laying the Ground where the Midle Row in the Shambls there lately
stood into the said streete, and in like manner to inlarge the passage from Newgate Market towards Newgate by
laying the Ground of the late fower Houses betweene Warwicke lane end in Newgate Market and the late Bell
Inne there into the Streete, And in like manner to inlarge as there shall be cause the Lane called [Ava<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Maria
Lane leading from Pater noster Row to Ludgate Streete, And the Streete or Passage at the end of Saint Martins le
Grand towards Blow bladder Streete aforesaid; And alsoe the Passage from Saint Magnus Church to the Conduit
in Gratious Streete and the North end of Gratious Streete, and alsoe Thames Streete from the West corner of
Saint Magnus Church aforesaid to the Tower Docke and to inlarge Old Fish Streete by laying the Midle Row there
into the Streete.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Other Passages, &amp;c. to be enlarged at Discretion.</head>
			<para id="p37">And the said Maior Aldermen and Co&bhooov;mon Councill alsoe shall and may by vertue of this present A&bholigct; inlarge
and make wider any other such strait and narrow passages within the said Citty as are lesse then fowerteene
foote in breadth, Soe as notice be given to the Owners or partyes interessed in the Ground to be soe taken for
the inlarging thereof on or before the first day of May next ensueing And are and shall be alsoe further enabled
by vertue of this A&bholigct; to make or cause to be made a new Streete leading and extending from the Guildhall of
the said Citty into Cheapeside, the same to be of such breadth and widenes as they shall judge meete and
convenient</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Satisfa&bholigct;ion to Losers of Ground.</head>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">Lord Mayor, &amp;c. may issue Warrant to Sheriff to impannel Jury; who are to assess Damages.; Verdi&bholigct; of Jury and Judgment of Lord Mayor, &amp;c. and Payment or Tender of Money adjudged, final</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">And to the end that reasonable satisfa&bholigct;ion may be given For all such Ground as shall be taken and imployed
for the uses aforesaid The Maior Aldermen and Co&bhooov;mon Councill shall and may treate and agree with the
Owners and others interessed therein, And if there shall be any Persons Bodyes Corporate or Collegiate that shall
wilfully refuse to treate and agree as aforesaid, or through any disability by Non age Coverture or especiall intaile
or other impediment cannot, That in such cases the said Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen are hereby authorized
by vertue of this A&bholigct; to issue out a Warrant or Warrants to the Sheriffes of London who are hereby required
accordingly to impannell and returne a Jury before the said Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen, Which Jury
upon their Oathes to be administred by the said Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen are to inquire and assesse
such Damage and Recompence as they shall judge fitt to be awarded to the Owners and others interested according
to their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Interests and Estates of and in any such Houses or Ground or any part thereof for
their respe&bholigct;ive Interests and Estates in the same as by the said Lord Maior Aldermen and Commons in Co&bhooov;mon
Councill assembled shall be adjudged fitt to be converted for the purposes aforesaid, And such Verdi&bholigct; of the
Jury and Judgement of the said Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen thereupon And the payment of the summe or
summes of money soe awarded or adjudged to the Owners, and others haveing Estate or Interest or tender and
refusall thereof shall be binding to all intents and purposes against the said Partyes their Heires Executors
Administrators and Assignes and others claiming any Title or Interest in the said Houses or Ground and shall be
a full Authority for the said Lord Maior Aldermen and Co&bhooov;mons to cause the same to be converted and used for
the purposes aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Houses improved by opening Streets to pay to Losers of Ground.</head>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">Jury impannelled as aforesaid may assess.; Monies so assessed to be paid to Chamberlain; whose Receipt to be a Discharge; and who is to be accountable for the same.; Money so raised how employed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">And forasmuch as the Houses now remaining and to be rebuilt will receive more or lesse advantage in the
value of their Rents by the liberty of Air and free recourse for Trade and other Conveniencies by such Regulation
and Inlargements It is alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That in case of refusall or incapacity as aforesaid
of the Owners or others interessed of or in the said Houses to agree and compound with the said Lord Maior
Aldermen and Co&bhooov;mons for the same, Thereupon a Jury shall and may be impanneled in manner and forme
aforesaid to judge and assesse upon the Owners and others interessed of and in such Houses such competent summe
and summes of Money with respe&bholigct; to their severall Interests in consideration of such improvement and melioration
as in reason and good conscience they shall thinke fitt, And all summes of Money that shall be soe assessed and
raised as aforesaid shall be paid to the Chamberlaine of the Citty of London for the time being who is hereby
enabled [from time to time<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] to receive and recover the same by A&bholigct;ion at Law and whose Receipte shall be a good
Discharge to such Owners or others interessed, And who is hereby appointed to receive and pay and be accomptable
for the same according to such Dire&bholigct;ions as shall from time to time be given him by the said Lord Maior Aldermen
and Co&bhooov;mons And the Money soe raised shall be wholly imployed towards payment and satisfa&bholigct;ion of such Houses
and Ground as shall be converted into Streets Passages Markets and other publique places aforesaid, And such
satisfa&bholigct;ion soe given or tendered and refused as aforesaid shall divest the Propriety Estate and Interest of the
respe&bholigct;ive Owners and others haveing Interest of and in such parcells of Ground soe to be taken and imployed
for the uses aforesaid by vertue of this A&bholigct;, Which shall be and are hereby a&bholigct;ually setled and invested in the
said Lord Maior Co&bhooov;monalty and Citizens of the Citty of London and their Successors in like manner as other the
Co&bhooov;mon streetes and Highwayes within the said Citty.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. In Controversies about Titles; Three Judges may decide finally in a summary Way.</head>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">Purchase Money to he paid by Chamberlain accordingly</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">And in case any Controversies or differences shall happen to arise betweene severall persons that shall claime
severall Estates or Interests into or out of any Grounds to be sould by the said Maior Aldermen and [Comon<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]
Councill or by them to be taken and disposed of by vertue and in pursuance of this A&bholigct; to and for the uses
aforesaid That then the Justices of the Courts of Kings Bench and Co&bhooov;mon Pleas and Barons of the Coife of the
Exchequer for the time being or any three or more of them shall be and are hereby authorized to heare and
finally to order and determine the same in a summary way of proceeding and without the formalities or ordinary
course of proceedings used in any the said Courts to order and award such Distribution to be made of the Money
thereby ariseing for the satisfying [of<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] such severall Interests and Claimes as to them shall seeme just and reasonable
according to the respe&bholigct;ive Estate or Estates Title or Interests of the person or persons makeing Claime thereunto
according to which order and distribution to be made and appointed by the said Justices and Barons or any three
or more of them the said Purchase money shall be satisfyed and paid by the said Chamberlaine to the said
severall persons respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. A solemn Fast yearly in Memory of the Desolation.</head>
			<para id="p44">And that the said Citizens and their Successors for all the time to come may retaine the Memoriall of soe sadd
a Desolation and refle&bholigct; seriously upon their manifold Iniquities which are the unhappy causes of such Judgements
Be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Second day of September (unlesse the same happen to be Sunday and if soe then
the [next day<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] following) be yearely for ever hereafter observed as a day of Publique Fasting and Humiliation within
the said Citty and Libertyes thereof to implore the Mercies of Almighty God upon the said Citty to make devout
Prayers and Supplication unto him to divert the like Calamity for the time to come,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. A Pillar to be ere&bholigct;ed.</head>
			<para id="p45">And the better to preserve the memory of this dreadfull Visitation, Be it further ena&bholigct;ed That a Columne or
Pillar of Brase or Stone be ere&bholigct;ed on or as neere unto the place where the said Fire soe unhappily began as
conveniently may be, in perpetuall Remembrance thereof with such Inscription thereon as hereafter by the Maior
and Court of Alderman in that behalfe be dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Places of Tender of Money altered.</head>
			<para id="p46">And be it ena&bholigct;ed And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie [aforesaid<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] That all Tenders of Money or Payment
thereof which by any Bonds Covenants or other Obligations or Assurance whatsoever ought to be made in the
late Assurance Office or in any other place on the late Royall Exchange London, shall or may be made at or in
the present Assurance Office in Gresham House And shall, be as valid and legall to all intents and purposes
and discharge the Obligor as fully and amply as if they had beene made in the first intended place on the said
Royall Exchange.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. No more than Thirty-nine new Churches.</head>
			<para id="p47">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That the Parish Churches to be rebuilded within the said Citty of London in
lieu of those which were demolished by the late Fire shall not exceede the number of thirty nine Which shall
be sett out and appointed by and with the advice and consent of the Lord Archbishop of Canterbury and the
Bishop of London for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Materials of Churches not rebuilt, and the Church Yards, how to be disposed of.</head>
			<para id="p48">Provided alsoe And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Scites and Materialls of such Churches
as by this Bill are not intended to be rebuilt together with the Church yards belonging to such Churches shall
be and are hereby vested in the Lord Maior and Aldermen of the Citty of London for the time being to the end
soe much of the said Ground as shall not upon the Rebuilding of the said Citty be laid into the Streets be sold
and disposed of by the said Lord Maior and Aldermen or the major part of them for the time being with the
consent of the Archbishop of Canterbury and Bishop of London for the time being, and the Money raised by
such Sale shall be by the said Maior and Aldermen or the major part of them with the consent of the said
Archbishop and Bishop disposed of and imployed for and towards the Rebuilding of such Parish Churches as by
this A&bholigct; are intended to be rebuilt and for noe other use or purpose whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Proviso for St. Faiths and St. Gregory by St. Paul's.</head>
			<para id="p49">Provided alwayes That any thing in this A&bholigct; contained shall not extend or be taken to vest or setle the
Church of Saint Paul and Saint Faithes or any part thereof or the Church of Saint Gregories (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) or any of them, or
the Church yards to any of them belonging or appertaining in the Maior Aldermen and C&bhooov;mons of the Citty of
London or any of them Any thing in this A&bholigct; notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Thames Street, &amp;c. to be raised.</head>
			<para id="p50">And be it ena&bholigct;ed That for the preventing Inundations and for easines of Ascent the Streete called Thames
Streete and all the ground betweene the said Streete and the River of Thames shall be raised and made higher
by three foote at the least above the surface of the ground as now it lyeth,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Distances of Houses from the River and Fleet Ditch, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p51">Provided alsoe And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe House Outhouse or other
building whatsoever (Cranes and Sheds for present use onely excepted) shall be built or ere&bholigct;ed within the
distance of Forty foote of such part of any Wall Key or Wharfe as bounds the River of Thames, from Tower
Wharfe to London Bridge and from London Bridge to the Temple Staires, Nor any House Outhouse or other
building (Cranes onely excepted) be built or ere&bholigct;ed within the distance of threescore and ten foote of the midle
of any part of the Co&bhooov;mon Sewers co&bhooov;monly called or knowne by the [nams<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] of Bridewell Docke Fleete Ditch and
[Turmill<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Brooke from the River of Thames to Clarkenwell upon either side of them before the fower and
twentieth day of March which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty eight,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. An additional Custom upon Coals for building the public Buildings of the City.</head>
			<para id="p52">
				<emph type="i">Coals sold by Chaldron, 12d. per Chaldron.; Coals sold by the Ton, 12d. per Ton.; Duty to be paid to Mayor, &amp;c. by Master, &amp;c. of Ship before Bulk broke or Meter assigned; at such Places as Mayor, &amp;c. shall appoint</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p53">And for the further enableing of the said Maior and Co&bhooov;monalty and Citizens of the said Citty of London and
their Successors to performe and accomplish the workes in this A&bholigct; mentioned Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority
aforesaid That for all sorts of Coales which from and after the fower and twentyeth day of June One thousand
six hundred sixty seaven, and Before the fower and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy
seaven shall be imported and brought into the Port of the Citty of London or the River of Thames within the
liberty of the said Citty of London upon the same River to be sould by the Chaldron or Tun, there shall be
paid by way of Imposition thereupon (over and besides all other Impositions and Dutyes due and payable-for any
sort of the said Coales by vertue of any Law or Statute now in force) according to the Rates hereafter mentioned
That is to say for such sorts of Coales as are usually sold by the Chaldron for every Chaldron thereof containing,
thirty six bushells Winchester measure the summe of twelve pence and for all such sorts of Coales as are sould
by the Tunn, for every Tunn thereof containing twenty hundred weight the like summe of twelve pence, which
said Imposition of twelve pence for every Chauldron or Tunn of Coales shall from time to time dureing the terme
aforesaid be answered and paid unto the said Maior and Co&bhooov;monalty and Citizens and their Successors, or to their
Deputie or Deputyes Officer or Assignes by the Master Owner or Owners or other person or persons takeing
charge of any Shipp or Vessell whereupon the same shall be laden before they shall breake Bulke or have a
Meter assigned for the measureing or weighing of any Coales aforesaid to be delivered from on board any such
Shipp or Vessell the same to be paid at such place or places as by the said Maior and Court of Aldermen shall
from time to time be appointed for the receipte thereof, Upon receipt whereof the partie appointed to receive
the same shall without delay fee or reward deliver a Receipt to the person or persons who shall pay the said
Duty, which Receipt shall for soe much be a sufficient discharge.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. Rules and Remedy for the said Duty.</head>
			<para id="p54">
				<emph type="i">Coal Meters to deliver to Officer a Certificate of Sorts and Quantities of Coals; Penalty.; If it appear by Certificate that greater Quantity of Coals on board than paid Duty; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p55">And to the end that the said Imposition may be duely answered and paid without fraude or covin, and for the
better leavying and colle&bholigct;ing thereof and for discovery of the just quantityes of all sorts of Coales to be imported
as aforesaid be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that the Coale meeters for the Citty of London
appointed or to be appointed and every of them and their respe&bholigct;ive Deputyes in their turne and course of
attendance respe&bholigct;ively soe soone as any Shipp or Vessell fraight with Coales shall be unladen shall forthwith
deliver a true Certificate in writeing unto the Deputie or Deputyes Officers or Assignes of the said Maior and
Commonalty and Citizens who shall be appointed to receive the said Imposition of the sorts quantityes and number
of Chaldrons or Tunns of Coales respe&bholigct;ively which shall be measured or weighed and delivered from on Board
any such Shipp or Vessell on paine for his or their defaulte therein to be suspended from the execution and benefitt
of his or their Office or Imployment for one whole yeare from thence next following; And in case it shall
appeare by such Certificate or otherwise that there was on Board any such Shipp or Vessell a greater number of
Chaldrons or Tuns of Coales then for which the said Imposition shall have beene answered and paid as aforesaid
that then in such case there shall be paid to the said Maior and Co&bhooov;monalty and Citizens and their Successors for
every Chaldron or Tunn of Coales soe concealed over and above the Imposition aforesaid the summe of Five
shillings, for which (in case of refusall to pay the same) such Shipp or Vessell or any the tackle furniture or
Apparell thereof may be attached and detained by warrant from the Maior of the said Citty for the time being
untill payment thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Post-Entry and Payment of Duty for Surplus to discharge Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p56">Provided neverthelesse that if the importer upon such Certificate delivered in by the Coale meter shall within fower
and twenty houres give in his Post entry and satisfie and pay the whole Duty for the surplusage of Coales appearing
upon the unladeing of such Shipp or Vessell that then upon such payment the penaltie aforesaid shall be discharged.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. How Duty to be applied.</head>
			<para id="p57">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that all and every such summe and summes of Money which shall be raised
upon the Receipt of the said Imposition of Twelve pence for every Chaldron or Tunn of Coales or by such
additionall Duty in case of concealement as aforesaid shall in the first place be applyed and disposed unto and
for the satisfa&bholigct;ion of such persons whose Grounds shall by vertue and in pursuance of this A&bholigct; be taken and
imployed for the inlarging of the Streets and narrow passages within the said Citty, And after satisfa&bholigct;ion given
for the same the residue of the said Moneyes shall be applyed and disposed unto and for the satisfa&bholigct;ion of such
persons whose Grounds shall be imployed for the makeing of Wharfes or Keyes on the North side of the River
of Thames, and upon each side of the Sewer called by the name or names of Bridewell Docke, Fleete Ditch
and Turnmill Brooke, and alsoe for the building and makeing such Prisons within the said Citty as shall be
necessary for the safe Custody and Imprisonment of Felons and other Malefa&bholigct;ors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. Books of Account of the Duty, and Application thereof.</head>
			<para id="p58">
				<emph type="i">Persons concerned to have free Access to such Books without Fee.; Copy of Books to be delivered by Chamberlain into the Exchequer, where Access may be had without Fee</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p59">And to the end the Moneyes to be raised upon the Imposition aforesaid may be duely applyed to the uses for
which the same is by this A&bholigct; appointed, Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that there shall [be<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] from time to time (<ref idref="n18">18</ref>) provided
and kepte in the Chamber of London one or more booke or bookes of Velome or Parchment in which all moneyes
thereupon to be received shall from time to time be entred and sett downe, And alsoe other like booke or
bookes wherein the Accompts of all payments and disbursements out of the same shall be likewise entred, expressing
the time when, the occasion for which, and the name of the person or persons to whom the same were soe paid
or disbursed And that it shall and may be lawfull to and for all and every person and persons that shall or
may be in any wise concerned soe to doe to have free accesse unto and view the said respe&bholigct;ive bookes of
Receipts and Disbursements at all times when the Chamberlaines Office is open without any Fee or Reward to
be taken or demanded for the view or inspe&bholigct;ion thereof And that the Chamberlaine of London for the time being
before the end of Michaelmas Terme in every yeare shall transmit and upon his Oath deliver into the Receipte
of the Exchequer a true Copy or Duplicate of the aforesaid bookes of Accompts containing the Receipts and
Disbursements of all Moneyes which shall be raised and paid by or out of the said Imposition upon Coales in
the yeare preceeding and ending upon the fower and twentyeth day of June next before there to be received
gratis by the proper Officer and kepte amongst the Records of the said Court; where it shall alsoe be lawfull
for any person or persons who shall be in any wise concerned soe to doe to have accesse thereunto and to view
and peruse the said bookes of Accompts without any Fee or Reward to be taken or received for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. Proviso for re-building Thomas Morris's Water-house with Timber.</head>
			<para id="p60">Provided alwayes that it shall and may be lawfull for the Water house called Mr. Thomas Morris his Waterhouse
formerly adjoyning to London Bridge to be rebuilt upon the place it formerly stood with Timber for the supplying
the South side of the Citty with water as it for almost this hundred yeares hath done, Any thing in this A&bholigct;
to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. Lord Mayor, &amp;c. may open Water Lane, and Streets herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p61">
				<emph type="i">Satisfa&bholigct;ion to Proprietors of Ground, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p62">[Provided alsoe And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that the Lord Maior and Aldermen
of London may and shall open and inlarge a Streete or passage called Water Lane leading from Fleete streete
to White Fryars Docke by the River of Thames, as alsoe open and inlarge a Streete or passage to the said River
from Cheapeside through Soper Lane to Thames Streete and from the Three Cranes to the Thames, And open and
inlarge one other Streete or passage through Minceing Lane by Saint Dunstons in the East to Thames Streete
neere the Custome house And to make the said Streetes or passages twenty fower foote in breadth for the conveniency
of Trade and better passage of Carts and other carriages to and from the said River giveing notice of what they
shall herein resolve to the proprietors and persons concerned before the last day of May which shall be in the yeare
of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty seaven and giveing them satisfa&bholigct;ion for their ground according to
the Rules and Dire&bholigct;ions of this A&bholigct; for the inlarging of other Streetes and places.<ref idref="n19">19</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p63">[A SCHEME of Proportions and Scantlings for Stories Walls and Timbers for the building of lesser and larger
Houses within the Citty of London.</para>
			<table id="t1">
				<tr>
					<td cols="9"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Bricke.</td>
					<td>Division of Story</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Height of Story</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Thicknes of Walls</td>
					<td>Bricks</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Bricks</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">First sort being the least Houses fronting By Streets and Lanes</td>
					<td>Cellars</td>
					<td/>
					<td>6&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>To the First Floore</td>
					<td>2</td>
					<td/>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>1 Story</td>
					<td/>
					<td>9</td>
					<td/>
					<td>2d</td>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>2 Story</td>
					<td/>
					<td>9</td>
					<td>3d</td>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Garrets</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>1</td>
					<td/>
					<td>1</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="5">Second sorte Houses fronting all Streets Lanes of Note and River of Thames.</td>
					<td>Cellars</td>
					<td>6&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>To the First Floore</td>
					<td>2&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>2</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>1 Story</td>
					<td>Not lesse [in<ref idref="n20">20</ref> height cleare then</td>
					<td>10</td>
					<td>Thicknes of Walls in Front and Reere from the Foundation</td>
					<td>2d</td>
					<td>2</td>
					<td>Thicknes of Walls betweene House and House</td>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>2 Story</td>
					<td>Where y<emph type="p">e</emph>
					</td>
					<td>10</td>
					<td>3d</td>
					<td>2</td>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>3 Story</td>
					<td>Springs p&bhopcrl;vent not</td>
					<td>9</td>
					<td/>
					<td>4th</td>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Garrets</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>1</td>
					<td/>
					<td>1</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="5">Third sort Houses fronting all High Streets and Lanes of Note</td>
					<td>1 Story</td>
					<td/>
					<td>10</td>
					<td/>
					<td>1st</td>
					<td>2&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>2</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>2 Story</td>
					<td/>
					<td>10&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>2d</td>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>3 Story</td>
					<td/>
					<td>9</td>
					<td/>
					<td>3d</td>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>4 Story</td>
					<td/>
					<td>8&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>4th</td>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td>1&frac12;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Garrets</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>1</td>
					<td/>
					<td>1</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<para id="p64">Scantlings of Timber for the first sort of Houses.</para>
			<table id="t2">
				<tr>
					<td cols="10"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td>Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
					<td>Length Foote</td>
					<td>Thicknes</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Depth</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="2">For the Floors</td>
					<td>Summers under</td>
					<td>15</td>
					<td>12</td>
					<td>and</td>
					<td>8</td>
					<td>Joysts to 10</td>
					<td>3</td>
					<td>and</td>
					<td>7 Inches</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Wall plates</td>
					<td/>
					<td>7</td>
					<td>and</td>
					<td>5</td>
					<td>Garret Floores</td>
					<td>3</td>
					<td>and</td>
					<td>6</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="3">For the Roofe</td>
					<td>Principall Rafters under</td>
					<td>15</td>
					<td>at foote</td>
					<td>8</td>
					<td>6 Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>at top</td>
					<td>5</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Single Rafters</td>
					<td>4</td>
					<td>and 3 Inches.</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<para id="p65">Scantlings of Timber for the other two sortes of Houses.</para>
			<table id="t3">
				<tr>
					<td cols="11"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="18">For the Floors</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td>Breadth Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Depth Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Thicknes Inches</td>
					<td>Depth Inches</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="5">Summers or Girders which beare in length from</td>
					<td>10</td>
					<td>to</td>
					<td>15</td>
					<td>11</td>
					<td>and</td>
					<td>8</td>
					<td rows="5">Joysts which beare 10 Foote</td>
					<td>3</td>
					<td>6</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>15</td>
					<td/>
					<td>18</td>
					<td>13</td>
					<td/>
					<td>9</td>
					<td>3</td>
					<td>7</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>18</td>
					<td/>
					<td>21</td>
					<td>14</td>
					<td/>
					<td>10</td>
					<td>3</td>
					<td>7</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>21</td>
					<td/>
					<td>24</td>
					<td>16</td>
					<td/>
					<td>12</td>
					<td>3</td>
					<td>8</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>24</td>
					<td/>
					<td>26</td>
					<td>17</td>
					<td/>
					<td>14</td>
					<td>3</td>
					<td>8</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Principall Discharges upon Peeres</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>13</td>
					<td>and</td>
					<td>12</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>In the first Story in the Fronts</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>15</td>
					<td/>
					<td>13</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches.</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Binding Joysts with their Triming Joysts</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>5</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>depth equall to their owne Floores</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="3">Wall plates or raiseing Pieces and Beames</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>10</td>
					<td>and</td>
					<td>6</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>8</td>
					<td/>
					<td>6</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>7</td>
					<td/>
					<td>5</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches.</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="2">Lintells of Oake in the</td>
					<td>1st and 2d story</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>8</td>
					<td>and</td>
					<td>6</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>3d story</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>5</td>
					<td/>
					<td>4</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<table id="t4">
				<tr>
					<td cols="9"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="17">For the Roofe</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Length</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Thickness</td>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="8">Principall Rafters from</td>
					<td>15</td>
					<td>to</td>
					<td rows="2">18</td>
					<td>at foote</td>
					<td>9</td>
					<td/>
					<td>7</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>at topp</td>
					<td>7</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>18</td>
					<td/>
					<td rows="2">21</td>
					<td>at foote</td>
					<td>10</td>
					<td/>
					<td>8</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>at topp</td>
					<td>8</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>21</td>
					<td/>
					<td rows="2">24</td>
					<td>at foote</td>
					<td>12</td>
					<td/>
					<td>8&frac12;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>at topp</td>
					<td>9</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>24</td>
					<td/>
					<td rows="2">26</td>
					<td>at foote</td>
					<td>13</td>
					<td/>
					<td>9</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>at topp</td>
					<td>9</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Length</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="2">Purlines from</td>
					<td>15</td>
					<td>to</td>
					<td>18</td>
					<td/>
					<td>9</td>
					<td/>
					<td>8</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>18</td>
					<td/>
					<td>21</td>
					<td/>
					<td>12</td>
					<td/>
					<td>9</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td>Inches</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="2">Single Rafters</td>
					<td/>
					<td>not exceeding in length</td>
					<td/>
					<td>9</td>
					<td>5</td>
					<td/>
					<td>4</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td>not exceeding in length</td>
					<td/>
					<td>6</td>
					<td>4</td>
					<td/>
					<td>3&frac12;</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<para id="p66">Scantlings for Sawed Timber and Lathes usually brought out of the West Country not lesse then</para>
			<table id="t5">
				<tr>
					<td cols="7"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td>Breadth Inches</td>
					<td>Thickness Inch</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Single Quarters in length</td>
					<td>8</td>
					<td>3&frac12;</td>
					<td>1&frac34;</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double Quarters in length</td>
					<td>8</td>
					<td>4</td>
					<td>3&frac12;</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Sawed Jousts in length</td>
					<td>8</td>
					<td>6</td>
					<td>4</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="2">Lathes in length</td>
					<td>5</td>
					<td>1&frac14;</td>
					<td>1 quarter &amp; &frac12; of Inch</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>4</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Inches</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="9">Stone<br/>Where Stone is used to keepe to these Scantlings.</td>
					<td rows="4">First sort of Houses</td>
					<td>Corner Peeres</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>18 square</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Middle or single Peeres</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>14 and 12</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double Peeres betweene House &amp; House</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>14 and 18</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Doore jambes and Heads</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>12 and 8</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td>Inches</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">2d and 3d sorts</td>
					<td>Corner Peers</td>
					<td/>
					<td>2</td>
					<td>6 square</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Midle or single Peeres</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>18 square</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double Peeres betweene House and House</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>24 and 18</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>[Doores<ref idref="n21">21</ref>]Jams and Heads</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>14 and 10</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td>Foote</td>
					<td/>
					<td>Thickness</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="2">Scantlings for Sewers</td>
					<td>3 wide</td>
					<td>Side walls</td>
					<td>1 bricke(<ref idref="n22">22</ref>)</td>
					<td>Bottome paved plaine and then 1 bricke and edge circular.</td>
					<td/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>5 high</td>
					<td>Arch</td>
					<td>1 bricke on end</td>
					<td/>
					<td/>
				</tr>
			</table>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>GENERALL RULES</head>
			<para id="p67">In every Foundation within the Ground adde one Bricke in thicknes to the thicknes of the Wall (as in the
Scheme) next above the Foundation to be sett off in three Courses equally on both sides.</para>
			<para id="p68">That noe timber be laid within twelve Inches of the Foreside of the [Chimney<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Jambs, And that all Joysts on the
Backe of any Chimney be laid with a Trimmer at six Inches distance from the Backe.</para>
			<para id="p69">That noe Timber be laid within Tunnell of any Chimney upon penalty to the Workeman for every defaulte
ten shillings, and ten shillings every Weeke it continues unreformed.</para>
			<para id="p70">That noe Joysts or Rafters be laid at greater distances from one to the other twelve Inches, and noe Quarters
at greater distance then fowerteene Inches.</para>
			<para id="p71">That noe Joysts beare at longer length then ten Foote and noe single Rafters at more in length then
nine Foote.</para>
			<para id="p72">That all Roofes Windows frames and Cellar Floores be made of Oake.</para>
			<para id="p73">The Tile pins of Oake.</para>
			<para id="p74">Noe Summers or Girders to lye over the Head of Doores and Windowes.</para>
			<para id="p75">Noe Summer or Girder to lye lesse then ten Inches into the Wall, noe Joysts then eight Inches and to be laid
in Lome.<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">to bee publiquely <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Plaisterer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Ave <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">Day next <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">by Saint Paul's <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Names <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">Turnemill <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">be <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">Doore <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">&frac12; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">Chimneyes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


