<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47393" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1666</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XI. An Act for Redresse of Inconveniencies by want of Proofe of the Deceases of Persons beyond the Seas or absenting
themselves, upon whose Lives Estates doe depend. [Rot. Parl. 18 &amp; 19 C.II. nu. 11.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Cestui que vies have gone beyond Sea, and that Reversioners cannot find out whether they are alive or dead.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Cestui que vie remaining beyond Sea for Seven Years together and no Proof of their Lives, Judge in an A&bholigct;ion to dire&bholigct; a Verdi&bholigct; as though Cestui que vie were dead</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas diverse Lords of Mannours and others have used to grant Estates by Copy of Court Roll for
one two or more life or lives according to the Custome of their severall Mannours and have alsoe granted
Estates by, Lease for one or more life or lives, or else for yeares determinable upon one or more life or lives And
it hath often happened that such person or persons for whose life or lives such Estates have beene granted have
gone beyond the Seas or soe absented themselves for many yeares that the Lessors and Reversioners cannot finde
out whether such person or persons be alive or dead by reason whereof such Lessors and Reversioners have beene
held out of possession of their Tenements for many yeares after all the lives upon which such Estates depend are
dead in regard, that the Lessors and Reversioners when they have brought A&bholigct;ions for the recovery of their
Tenements have beene putt upon it to prove the death of their Tennants when it is almost impossible for them
to discover the same, For remedy of which mischeife soe frequently happening to such Lessors or Reversioners
Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and the Co&bhooov;mons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That if
such person or persons for whose life or lives such Estates have beene or shall be granted as aforesaid shall
remaine beyond the Seas or elsewhere absent themselves in this Realme by the space of scaven yeares together and
noe sufficient and evident proofe be made of the lives of such person or persons respe&bholigct;ively in any A&bholigct;ion
commenced for recovery of such Tenements by the Lessors or Reversioners in every such case the person or
persons upon whose life or lives such Estate depended shall be accounted as naturally dead, And in every A&bholigct;ion
brought for the recovery of the said Tenements by the Lessors or Reversioners their Heires or Assignes, the Judges
before whom such A&bholigct;ion shall be brought shall dire&bholigct; the Jury to give their Verdi&bholigct; as if the person soe remaining
beyond the Seas or otherwise absenting himselfe were dead.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Challenge to Jurors for Leases for Lives.</head>
			<para id="p3">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That in any such A&bholigct;ion wherein the life or death of any such person or persons
shall come in question betweene the Lessor or Reversioner and the Tennant in possession it shall and may be
lawfull to the Lessor or Reversioner to take exception to any of the Jurors returned for the tryall of that cause
that the greatest part of the reall Estate of any (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) such Jurors is held by Lease or Copy for lives who upon
proofe thereof shall be sett aside as in case of other legall challenges.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for the Duke of York as to Lands of attainted Persons granted to him.</head>
			<para id="p4">[Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe thing in this A&bholigct; contained shall
extend to any Lands held by the life or lives of any person or persons attainted of Treason for the horrid murder
of his late Majestie of blessed memory who now conceale or hide themselves which Lands are or have beene vested
in His Majestic and are now granted to his Royall Highnesse the Duke of Yorke but that the course of Evidence
heretofore used in such cases shall be had and used Any thing to the contrary in this A&bholigct; notwithstanding.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. If the supposed dead Man prove to be alive, then the Title is revested.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">A&bholigct;ion for mean Profits with Interest</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">[Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That if any person or [person or<ref idref="n3">3</ref>
			] persons shall be evi&bholigct;ed out of any Lands or
Tenements by vertue of this A&bholigct;, and afterwards if such person or persons upon whose life or lives such Estate
or Estates depend shall returne againe from beyond the Seas, or shall on proofe in any A&bholigct;ion to be brought for
recovery of the same [to<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] be made appeare to be liveing; or to have beene liveing at the time of the Evi&bholigct;ion
That then and from thenceforth the Tennant or Lessee who was outed of the same his or their Executors
Administrators or Assignes shall or may reenter repossesse have hold and enjoy the said Lands or Tenements in
his or their former Estate for and dureing the Life or Lives or soe long terme as the said person or persons upon
whose Life or Lives the said Estate or Estates depend shall be liveing, and alsoe shall upon A&bholigct;ion or A&bholigct;ions to
be brought by him or them against the Lessors Reversioners or Tennants in possession or other persons respe&bholigct;ively
which since the time of the said Evi&bholigct;ion received the Proffitts of the said Lands or Tenements recover for damages
the full Proffitts of the said Lands or Tenements respe&bholigct;ively with lawfull Interest for and from the time that he
or they were outed of the said Lands or Tenements, and kepte or held out of the same by the said Lessors
Reversioners Tennants or other persons who after the said Evi&bholigct;ion received the Proffitts of the said Lands or
Tenements or any of them respe&bholigct;ively as well in the case when the said person or persons upon whose Life or
Lives such Estate or Estates did depend are or shall be dead at the time of bringing of the said A&bholigct;ion or A&bholigct;ions
as if the said person or persons were then liveing.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


