<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47399" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1667 &amp; 1668</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IV. An Act for assigning Orders in the Exchequer without Revocation[Rot. Parl 19 &amp; 20 C.II. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Orders registered in the Auditor's Office of the Receipt may be assigned.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof; Assignor may not revoke his Assignment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas it hath beene found by experience upon the late A&bholigct; for Twelve hundred and fifty thousand
pounds made att Oxford and other A&bholigct;s of Parliament since that time that the power of assigning of
Orders in the Exchequer upon those A&bholigct;s without Revocation hath beene of great use and advantage to the persons
concerned in them and to the Trade of this Kingdome and given great Credit to his Majesties Exchequer Be it
ena&bholigct;ed and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majesty by and with the advice and consent of the
Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled That every person or persons
Nativer or Forreigner Bodies Politique or Corporate to whom any Moneys shall be due in your Majesties Exchequer
and shall have any Order registred in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt for the payment thereof out of
any Branch of your Majesties Revenue that such person or persons Native or Forreigner Bodies Politique or
Corporate theire Successors Executors Administrators or Assigns respe&bholigct;ively by Endorsement of theire Order may
assign and transfer their Right Title Interest and Benefitt of such Order or any part thereof to any other which
being notified in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt aforesaid and an Entry and Memorial thereof alsoe
made in the Booke of Registry aforesaid for such Orders (which the Officers shall on request accordingly make)
shall entitle such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes or Successors respe&bholigct;ively to the benefitt
thereof and payment thereon and such Assignee may in like manner assign again and. so toties quoties and
afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person or persons who have made such Assignments to make void
release or discharge the same or any the Moneys thereby due or any part thereof</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Auditor's, ad valorem Fee.</head>
			<para id="p3">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That in case any Assignement shall be for any summ
not exceeding One hundred pounds Sterling that the Auditor of the Receipt shall not take or receive by way of
Fee or Reward for himselfe and his Clerks above the su[m]m of Sixpence for making an Entry or Memorial thereof
And in case any Assignment shall be for any sum exceeding One hundred pound Sterling that the Auditor of the
Receipt shall not take or receive for himselfe and his Clerks by way of Fee or Reward above Twelve pence for
making an Entry or Memorial thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Continuance of Act.</head>
			<para id="p4">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; shall continue and be in full force untill the tenth day of
September which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred seventy four and unto the
end of the Session of Parliament then next ensuing and no longer.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


