<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47397" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1667 &amp; 1668</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act for banishing and disenabling the Earl of Clarendon. [Rot. Parl. 19 &amp; 20 C. II. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that the Earl of Clarendon having been impeached had withdrawn himself.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The said Earl to suffer perpetual Exile and Disability of Office</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas Edward Earl of Clarendon having been impeached by the Commons assembled in Parliament of
Treason and other misdemeanours hath knowingly withdrawn himselfe and is fled whereby Justice cannot
be done upon him according to his demerit Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the
advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall &amp; Temporall and Commons in Parliament assembled and by Authority
of the same That the said Edward Earle of Clarendon shall and doe suffer perpetuall Exile and be for ever
banished this Realm and all other His Majesties Dominions and shall be for ever disabled from having holding or
enjoying any Office or Place of Publique Trust or any other imployment whatsoever</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. If the said Earl return, to suffer the Penalties of Treason, and to be incapable of Pardon except by Act of Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Corresponding with the said Earl; (Exception); Penalty.; Letters sent to and received from the said Earl to be shewed to Secretary of State</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That it shall bee and be taken to be Treason for the
said Earle at any time to return into or bee found in England or any other His Majesties Dominions after the
first day of February according to the Accompt of England One thousand six hundred sixty seven And that in
case the said Earle shall att any time returne into or be found in England or any other His Majesties Dominions
after the said first day of February That the said Earle shall suffer the paines and penalties of Treason and be
made incapable of any pardon from the Kings Majesty his Heires and Successors but by A&bholigct; of Parliament And
that all correspondency with the said Earl except it be of his Children or such persons as shall be licensed by the
King in Council concerning his Estate and domestick Affairs only after the said first day of February shall be
and be taken to be of the same nature as correspondency with a Traitor and the offender therein shall suffer
such paines and penalties as by the Lawes of this Realm are to be inflicted upon such persons as keepe
correspondence with Traitors [And that all Letters sent to the said Earle be shewed to one of the Principal
Secretaries of State before they be sent And that all Letters which shall be received from the said Earle be
likewise shewed to one of the Principal Secretaries within ten dayes next after such receipt under the penalties
aforesaid<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for the said Earl rendering himself for Trial before 1st February next.</head>
			<para id="p5">[Provided alwaies that if the said Earle of Clarendon shall on or before the said first day of February next
render himselfe unto one of His Majesties Principal Secretaries of State or to the Leiutenant of the Tower of
London for the time being in order to his tryall which shall bee in Parliament That then and in such case all
and every the penalties and disabilities by this A&bholigct; imposed upon the said Earle of Clarendon shall be utterly
void and of no effe&bholigct; Any thing herein before contained to the contrary notwithstanding
<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


