<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47395" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1666</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An A&bholigct; for granting the Summe of Twelve hundred fifty six thousand three hundred forty seaven pounds
thirteene shillings to the Kings Majestie towards the Maintenance of the present Warr. [Rot. Parl. 18 &amp; 19 C. II. nu. 13.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Grant of &pound;1,256,347. 13s.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Recital of 16 &amp; 17 C. II. c.1.; and of 17 Car. II. c. 1.; and of 17 Car. II. c.9</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee Your Majestyes most dutyfull and Loyall Subje&bholigct;s the Commons assembled in Parlyament as a further
Aid and Assistance of Your Majestie dureing the present Warrs have given and granted and by these
presents doe give and grant unto Your most Excellent Majestie the Summe of Twelve hundred fifty six thousand
three hundred forty seaven pounds thirteene shillings to be raised and levyed in manner following. And wee doe
most humbly beseech Your Majestie that it may be ena&bholigct;ed and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Commons in this
present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same that the Summe of twelve hundred fifty six
thousand three hundred forty seaven pounds thirteene shillings shall be raised levyed and paid unto Your Majestie
within the space of eleaven Moneths in manner following that is to say, Whereas in and by a certaine A&bholigct; of
Parlyament lately passed entituled An A&bholigct; for granting a Royall Ayd unto the Kings Majestie of Twenty fower
hundred threescore and seaventeene thousand and five hundred pounds to be raised levyed and paid in the space
of three yeares It was amongst other things ena&bholigct;ed that the Summe of threescore and eight thousand eight
hundred and nineteene pounds and nine shillings by the moneth for thirty six moneths from the five and twentyeth
day of December One thousand six hundred sixtie fower should be assessed taxed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid by
twelve quarterly payments in the severall Counties Cittyes Burroughes Townes and places within England and
Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede according to the severall Rates and Proportions and in such 
manner as in the said A&bholigct; is expressed And whereas alsoe in and by one other A&bholigct; of Parlyament passed in the
Sessions of Parlyament lately held at Oxford entituled An A&bholigct; for granting the Summe of Twelve hundred and
fifty thousand pounds to the Kings Majestie for his present further Supply It was amongst other things further
ena&bholigct;ed that the Summe of Fifty two thousand fower score and three pounds six shillings eight pence by the
moneth for twenty fower moneths begining from the five and twentyeth day of December One thousand six
hundred sixty and five should be likewise assessed taxed colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid by Eight Quarterly payments
in the severall Cittyes Burroughes Townes and places within England and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede over and above the said Summe of threescore and eight thousand eight hundred and nineteene pounds
and nine shillings as an addition to and increase of the said Monethly Assesment according to the Rates and
Proportions therein expressed, Both which Summes together amount unto the Summe of One hundred and twenty
thousand nine hundred and two pounds fifteene shillings eight pence by the moneth And whereas alsoe in and
by one other A&bholigct; of Parlyament passed in the same Sessions entituled An A&bholigct; for granting one Monethly Assesment
to his Majestie It was amongst other things ena&bholigct;ed That the Summe of One hundred and twenty thousand nine
hundred and two pounds fifteene shillings and eight pence for one Moneths Assessment begining upon the six and
twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred sixty and seaven and ending upon the Six and twentyeth
day of January in the same yeare should be assessed taxed colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid in the severall Countyes
Cittyes Burroughes Townes and places within England and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede
according to the rates and proportions therein expressed</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. An Eleven Months Tax.</head>
			<para id="p3">It is now further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Summe of One hundred and fowerteene thousand
two hundred and thirteene pounds eight shillings five pence halfe penny by the moneth for eleaven moneths
begining from the Six and twentyeth day of January One thousand six hundred sixty and seaven shall be assessed
taxed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid by fower payments in the severall Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes &amp; places
within England and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede according to the rates rules and proportions
and in such manner as herein [here<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] after is expressed that is to say for every of the said Eleaven moneths.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>Rates of the several Counties.</head>
			<para id="p4">For the County of Bedford the summe of One thousand five hundred seaventy five pounds twelve shillings six
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p5">For the County of Berks the summe of One thousand nine hundred eighty nine pounds fower shillings nine
pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p6">For the County of Bucks Two thousand three hundred and ten pounds fowerteene shillings three pence.</para>
			<para id="p7">For the County of Cambridge One thousand seaven hundred ninety one pounds eighteene shillings one penny
halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p8">For the Isle of Ely Six hundred and fowerreene pounds thirteene shillings nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p9">For the County of Chester One thousand three hundred thirty seaven pounds five shillings five pence</para>
			<para id="p10">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester the summe of threescore and ten pounds seaven shillings
eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p11">For the County of Cornwall the summe of two thousand seaven hundred and seaven pounds seaven pence
farthing.</para>
			<para id="p12">For the County of Cumberland the summe of two hundred ninety and five pounds thirteene shillings fower
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p13">For the County of Derby the summe of One thousand five hundred and fifteene pounds one shilling three
pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p14">For the County of Devon the summe of Five thousand six hundred seaventy fower pounds five shillings eleaven
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p15">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Exon the summe of two hundred and fower pounds eight shillings six
pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p16">For the County of Dorset the summe of two thousand three hundred sixty two pounds two pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p17">For the Towne and County of Poole the summe of Nineteene pounds five shillings eleaven pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p18">For the County of Durham the summe of Five hundred sixty eight pounds eighteene shillings two pence
farthing.</para>
			<para id="p19">For the County of Yorke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke and Towne and County of Kingstone
upon Hull the summe of Six thousand ninety fower pounds thirteene shillings nine pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p20">For the County of Essex the summe of Five thousand fower hundred forty three pounds fower shillings
eleaven pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p21">For the County of Gloucester the summe of three thousand one hundred seaventy seaven pounds two shillings
nine pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p22">For the Citty and the County of the Citty of Gloucester the summe of threescore and nine pounds fower
shillings three pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p23">For the County of Hereford the summe of One thousand nine hundred eighty eight pounds one shilling five
pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p24">For the County of Hartford the summe of two thousand three hundred sixty fower pounds five shillings eight
pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p25">For the County of Huntingdon the summe of One thousand one hundred and thirteene pounds five shillings
six pence.</para>
			<para id="p26">For the County of Kent with the Citty and County of the Citty of Canterbury the summe of Five thousand
eight hundred forty fower pounds thirteene shillings two pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p27">For the County of Lancaster the summe of One thousand seaven hundred sixty eight pounds nine shillings ten
pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p28">For the County of Leicester the summe of One thousand nine hundred and five pounds eleven shillings nine
pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p29">For the County of Lincolne with the Citty and County of the Citty of. Lincolne the summe of Fower thousand
five hundred twenty three pounds seaventeene shillings two pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p30">For the Citty of London with the Libertyes of Saint Martins le Grand the summe of two thousand two hundred
fifty five pounds ten shillings and two pence.</para>
			<para id="p31">For the County of Midlesex with the Citty and Liberty of Westminster the summe of three thousand nine
hundred thirty six pounds ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p32">For the County of Monmouth the summe of six hundred eighty five pounds two shillings nine pence three
farthings.</para>
			<para id="p33">For the County of Northampton the summe of two thousand fower hundred eighty three pounds eighteene
shillings three pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p34">For the County of Nottingham with the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham the summe of One
thousand five hundred thirty fower pounds seaven shillings two pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p35">For the County of Norfolke the summe of Five thousand nine hundred twenty one pounds seaven shillings fower
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p36">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Norwich the summe of three hundred and sixteene pounds fower
shillings fower pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p37">For the County of Northumberland with the towne of Newcastle and Berwicke upon Tweede the summe of six
hundred fifty fower pounds seaventeene shillings eleaven pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p38">The County of Oxon the summe of one thousand nine hundred ninety fower pounds seaventeene shillings fower
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p39">The County of Rutland the summe of fower hundred twenty two pounds eight shillings one penny farthing.</para>
			<para id="p40">The County of Salop the summe of two thousand one hundred and fowerteene pounds twelve shillings eight
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p41">The County of Stafford the summe of one thousand fower hundred ninety seaven pounds fifteene shillings nine
pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p42">The Citty and County of the Citty of Litchfield the summe of twenty two pounds sixteene shillings nine pence
farthing.</para>
			<para id="p43">The County of Somerset the summe of fower thousand eight hundred sixtie eight pounds eighteene shillings ten
pence three-farthings.</para>
			<para id="p44">The Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll the summe of three hundred and fifty pounds six shillings six
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p45">The County of Southampton with the Towne and County of Southampton and Isle of Wight the summe of
three thousand eight hundred forty six pounds six shillings seaven pence.</para>
			<para id="p46">The County of Suffolke the summe of five thousand seaven hundred ninety fower pounds fifteene shillings three
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p47">The County of Surrey with the Burrough of Southwarke the summe of two thousand eight hundred and five
pounds eleaven shillings six pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p48">The County of Sussex the summe of three thousand one hundred ninety nine pounds fifteene shillings one penny
three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p49">The County of Warwicke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry the summe of two thousand and
ninety fower pounds fifteene shillings and eleaven pence.</para>
			<para id="p50">The County of Worcester the summe of one thousand eight hundred fifty one pounds ten shillings and ten
pence.</para>
			<para id="p51">The Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester the summe of ninety seaven pounds nine shillings and three
farthings.</para>
			<para id="p52">The County of Wilts the summe of three thousand fower hundred fifty five pounds seaven shillings one penny
halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p53">The County of Westmerland the summe of two hundred and three pounds fifteene shillings eight pence halfe
penny.</para>
			<para id="p54">The Isle of Anglesey the summe of two hundred and twenty pounds fifteene shillings and ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p55">The County of Breknocke the summe of fower hundred ninety six pounds six shillings, six pence.</para>
			<para id="p56">The County of Cardigan the summe of one hundred eighty five pounds sixteene shillings and eleaven pence
three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p57">The County of Carmarthen the summe of fower hundred and seaventy eight pounds ten shillings three pence
halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p58">The County of Carnarvon the summe of two hundred fifty seaven pounds eleaven shillings three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p59">The County of Denbigh the summe of three hundred ninety two pounds thirteene shillings eight pence halfe
penny.</para>
			<para id="p60">The County of Flint the summe of two hundred and eight pounds sixteene shillings three pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p61">The County of Glamorgan the summe of six hundred and sixty five pounds fowerteene shillings one penny three
farthings.</para>
			<para id="p62">The County of Merioneth the summe of one hundred seaventy seaven pounds one shilling nine pence three
farthings.</para>
			<para id="p63">The County of Mountgomery the summe of fower hundred eighty five pounds eighteene shillings eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p64">The County of Pembrooke the summe of five hundred seaventy three pounds eleaven shillings seaven pence three
farthings.</para>
			<para id="p65">The County of Radnor the summe of three hundred and six pounds five shillings two pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p66">The Towne of Haverford-West the summe of twenty six pounds and thirteene shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>III. Commissioners under 16 &amp; 17 C. II. c. 1. and 18 C. II. c. 1. to a&bholigct; as Commissioners under this A&bholigct;; and to have like Power and Authority; and Officers employed under this A&bholigct; to have the like Benefits,and to be subje&bholigct; to the like Penalties.</head>
			<para id="p67">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every the persons who are nominated in and
by the said first recited A&bholigct; and in and by an A&bholigct; passed this present Session of Parlyament entituled An A&bholigct; for
raiseing money by a Poll and otherwise towards the Maintenance of the present Warr, to be Co&bhooov;mis?ers of and
for the [severall and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places therein, or in either of them
mentioned shall likewise be soe and soe are hereby appointed to be Co&bhooov;mis?ers for execution of this present A&bholigct;
within the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places for which they were nominated
in the aforesaid A&bholigct;s or either of them, and shall have and execute the like power and authority rules and dire&bholigct;ions
touching the better assessing colle&bholigct;ing levying receiving and paying the said One hundred and fowerteene thousand
two hundred &amp; thirteene pounds thirteene shillings halfe penny by the moneth dureing the said eleaven moneths
as in and by the said first mentioned A&bholigct; were given to the said Co&bhooov;mis?ers touching the better assessing colle&bholigct;ing
receiving and paying the threescore and eight thousand eight hundred and nineteene pounds nine shillings by the
moneth payable as aforesaid; And all and every person or persons who shall be lyeable unto or any wayes concerned
or imployed in the assessing colle&bholigct;ing levying receiving or paying any of the moneyes by this A&bholigct; imposed
shall have like benefitt advantages allowances and discharges and shall be subje&bholigct; to like penalties and forfeitures
in case of any negcle&bholigct; or refusall to pay their respe&bholigct;ive Assesments, or to performe their respe&bholigct;ive, Dutyes as
any other person or persons lyeable unto or concerned or imployed in the assessing colle&bholigct;ing levying receiving or
paying any of the Moneyes by the said former A&bholigct;s imposed ought to have or be subje&bholigct; unto as fully and amply
as if the same Clauses matters and things had beene in this A&bholigct; perticularly repeated and ena&bholigct;ed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>IV. Commissioners to meet 2d Tuesday in Feb. 1667; and may divide themselves; and to meet Three Weeks before each Payment of Assessment, which is to be paid to Receivers of Counties, and by them into Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p68">To the end that the said eleaven monethly Assesments granted by vertue, of this present A&bholigct; may be duely
answered and paid in as aforesaid Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the severall Co&bhooov;mis?ers shall meete together at the
most usuall and co&bhooov;mon place of meeting as in the said first recited A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed on or before the second
Tuesday in February which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty seaven to putt this
A&bholigct; in execution according to the best of their judgements and discretions, and shall then if they see cause
subdivide as well themselves as others as by the said A&bholigct; is further dire&bholigct;ed concerning the said former Assesment.
And further That they meete at least three weekes before each payment of the said severall Assesments for the
purposes aforesaid, And that the said payments of one hundred and fowerteene thousand two hundred and thirteene
pounds eight shillings and five pence halfe penny by the moneth shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed leived and paid to the
Receiver of the severall Countyes appointed or that shall be appointed by his Majestie and by them answered and
paid into his Majesties Exchequer on the dayes and times hereafter mentioned and expressed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>V. &pound;228,426.16s.11d. to be paid to Receiver General 1st May 1668.</head>
			<para id="p69">
				<emph type="i">&pound;342, 640. 5s. 4&frac12;d. Second Payment, 1st August 1668.; &pound; 342, 640. 5s. 4. &frac12;d. Third Payment, 1st Nov. 1668.; &pound; 342, 640. 5s. 4&frac12;d. Fourth and last Payment, 1st Feb. 1668</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p70">Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the summe of two hundred twenty eight thousand fower hundred
twenty six pounds sixteene shillings and eleaven pence being the first payment for the first two moneths of the
aforesaid eleaven moneths hereby imposed shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid in to the said Receiver Generall
of the said severall Countyes who shall be appointed by his Majestie and who are hereby required to transmitt or
cause the same to be paid into his Majesties Receipt of His Exchequer on or before the first day of May in the
yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and eight, And the summe of three hundred forty two thousand
six hundred and forty pounds five shillings fower pence halfe penny being the second payment of the said eleaven
moneths on or before the first day of August in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and
eight, And the summe of three hundred forty two thousand six hundred and forty pounds five shillings fower
pence halfe penny being the third payment of the said eleaven moneths on or before the first day of November
in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and eight, And the summe of three hundred forty
two thousand six hundred and forty pounds five shillings fower pence halfe penny being the fowerth and
last payment of the said eleaven moneths on or before the first day of February in the yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred sixty and eight.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VI. Repayment of such Monies how to be secured.</head>
			<para id="p71">
				<emph type="i">Books to be provided.; No Monies to be issued out of Exchequer but by Order of Treasury.; Persons lending Moniesorfurnishing Goods, &amp;c. may have free Access to Books without Fee.; Tally of Loan to Lenderand Warrant for Interest at &pound;6. per Cent. per Ann. payable every Six Months.; Orders for Repayment to be registeredaccording to Date of Tally, and paid in course.; Monies to come in by this A&bholigct; liable to satisfy such Loans.; No Fee for providing ormaking Books, &amp;c. or for Payment of Money lent.; Penalty.; Punishment.; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty and Loss of Office.; By Deputy; Penalty and Incapacity.; Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller not making Payments in due Order.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p72">And to the intent that all moneyes to be lent to your Majesty and the moneyes that shall be due upon such
contra&bholigct;s for Wares Shipps Goods or Vi&bholigct;ualls or other necessaries which shall be delivered for your Majestyes
Service upon the Credit of this A&bholigct; by any person or persons Native or Forreigner Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate
may be well and sufficiently secured out of the moneyes ariseing and payable thereby Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by 
the Authority aforesaid That there shall be provided and kepte in your Majestyes Exchequer to witt in the Office
of the Auditor of the Receipt one Booke or Registry in which all moneyes that shall be paid into the Exchequer
ariseing or payable by this A&bholigct; shall be entred and registred apart and distin&bholigct; from all other moneyes paid or
payable to your Majestie or to your Heires or Successors upon any other branch of your Revenue or upon any
other account whatsoever, And that there be one other booke or Registry provided and kepte in the said Office of
all Orders and Warrants to be made by the Lord Treasurer or Under Treasurer or by the Co&bhooov;mis?ers of the
Treasury for the time being for payment of all and every summe and summes of moneyes to all persons for
moneyes lent Wares Goods or Vi&bholigct;ualls or other necessaries bought, or Shipps hired, or other payments dire&bholigct;ed
by your Majestie relateing to the Service of this Warr upon the moneyes ariseing and payable by this A&bholigct;, And
that noe moneyes levyable by this A&bholigct; be issued out of the Exchequer but by such Order or Warrant mentioning
that the moneyes payable by such Order or Warrant are for the Service of your Majestie in the said Warr
respe&bholigct;ively dureing the said Warr, That alsoe there be the like Booke or Registry provided and kepte by the
said Auditor of all moneyes paid out or issued by vertue of such Orders and Warrants, And that it shall be
lawfull for any person or persons willing to lend any moneyes, or to furnish any Wares Vi&bholigct;ualls Shipps goods
or other necessaryes on the Credit of this A&bholigct; at the usuall times when the Exchequer is open to have accesse
unto, and view and peruse all or any of the said Bookes for their information of the state of those moneyes and
all ingagements upon them for their better encouragement to lend any moneyes or furnish any Goods Wares
Vi&bholigct;ualls Shipps or other necessaries as aforesaid. And that the Auditor of the Receipte his Deputie or Clerke
shall be assistant to such persons for their better and speedier satisfa&bholigct;ion in that behalfe, And that all and every
person and persons who shall lend any moneyes to your Majestie and pay the same into the Receipte of the
Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally of Loane strucke for the same and an Order for his repayment beareing
the same date with his Tally, in which Order shall be alsoe contained a Warrant for payment of Interest for
forbearance after the rate of six per cen? per annum for his consideration to be paid every six moneths, untill
the repayment of his Principall. And that all person and persons who shall furnish your Majestie your Offices of
the Navy or Ordnance with any Wares Goods Shipps Vi&bholigct;ualls or any other necessaries for the Service aforesaid
shall upon Certificate of the Co&bhooov;mis?ers and Officers of the Navy or of the Master or Co&bhooov;mis?ers and Officers of the
Ordnance or some of them without delay forthwith have made out to them Warrants or Orders for the payment
of the moneyes due or payable unto them, which Certificates the said Officers of your Navy Co&bhooov;mis?ers and
Officers of the Ordnance shall make without fee charge or delay, And that all Orders for repayment of moneyes
lent shall be registred in course according to the date of the Tallies respe&bholigct;ively, And that all Orders signed
by the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer of the Exchequer for payment of moneyes for Goods Wares and
Vi&bholigct;ualls and other necessaries furnished to your Majestie your Officers Master or Co&bhooov;mis?ers as aforesaid shall be
registred in course according to the time of bringing to the Office of the Auditor of Receipte the Certificates
above mentioned And that all Orders soe signed for Payments dire&bholigct;ed by his Majestie shall be entred in course
according to their respe&bholigct;ive Dates, And none of the sorts of Orders above mentioned either for Loanes of Moneyes
Supplyes of Wares Goods [Shipps Vi&bholigct;ualls<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] or other necessaries or by speciall dire&bholigct;ion shall have preference one
before another but shall all be entred in their course according to the dates of the Tallyes, the times of bringing
the Certificates and the dates of the Orders for [Payment<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] dire&bholigct;ed by his Majestie as they are in point of time
respe&bholigct;ively before each other, And that all and every person and persons shall be paid in course according as their
Orders shall stand entred in the said Register booke, Be it Orders for Payments dire&bholigct;ed by his Majestie or for
moneyes lent, or for Wares Co&bhooov;modities or other necessaries furnished as aforesaid, Soe as that that person his
Executors Administrators and Assignes who shall have his Warrant or Order Warrants or Orders first entred in
the said booke of Registry shall be taken and accounted as the first person to be paid upon the moneyes to come
in by vertue of this A&bholigct;, And he or they that shall have his [or theire Warrants or Orders Warrant or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Order next
entred shall be taken and accounted the second person to be paid and soe successively and in course. And that
the moneyes to come in by this A&bholigct; shall be in the same order lyable to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said respe&bholigct;ive
partyes their Executors Administrators or Assignes Native or Forreigner successively without preference of one
before another and not otherwise and not be divertible to any other use intent or purpose upon any accompt or
reason whatsoever, And that noe Fee Reward or Gratuity dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly be demanded or taken of any your
Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s for provideing or makeing such Bookes Registers Entryes Views Search Certificate in, or for
payment of money lent or the Interest thereof, or for payment of any money upon any Order upon any Contra&bholigct;
for Wares and Goods furnished to the use of your Majestyes Navy and Ordnance as aforesaid by any of your Majesties
Officer or Officers their Deputyes or Clerkes on paine of payment of treble damages to the party greived by the
partie offending with costs of Suite. And if the Officer himselfe take [or demand<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] any such Fee or Reward then to
loose his place alsoe, And if any undue preference of one before another shall be made either in point of registring
contrary to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; by any such Officer or Officers then the party offending shall be lyeable
by A&bholigct;ion of Debt or on the Case to pay the value of the Debt damages and Costs to the partie greived and shall
be forejudged from his place or Office, And if such preference be unduely made by any his Deputie or Clerke
without dire&bholigct;ion or privitie of his Master then such Deputie or Clerke onely shall be lyable to such A&bholigct;ion debt
damages and costs and shall for ever after be incapeable of the same And in case the Auditor shall not dire&bholigct;
the Order or the Clerke of the Pells record, or the Tellar make payment according to each persons due place
and order afore dire&bholigct;ed then he or they shall be judged to forfeite and their respe&bholigct;ive Deputyes and Clerkes
herein offending be lyeable to such A&bholigct;ion debt damages and costs in such manner as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VII. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p73">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That If it happen that severall Tallyes of Loane or Certificates for
Wares delivered, or Orders for Payments from his Majestie as aforesaid beare date or be brought the same day
to the Auditor of the Exchequer to be registred Then it shall be interpreted noe undue preference which of
these he enters soe he enter them all the same day.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>VIII. Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded, no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Orders.</head>
			<para id="p74">Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpreted any undue preference to incurr any penalty in point of
payment if the Auditor dire&bholigct; and the Clerke of the Pells record, and the Tellar doe pay subsequent Orders of
persons that come to demand their money and bring their Orders before other persons that did not come to
demand their money and bring their Orders in their course soe as there be soe much money reserved as will
satisfie their Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kepte for them Interest upon Loane being to cease
from the time the money is soe reserved and kepte in Banke for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>IX. Orders for Payment of Money lent may be assigned by Endorsement. Memorial thereof without Fee.</head>
			<para id="p75">
				<emph type="i">Assignee may in like manner assign</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p76">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that every person or persons to whom any money
shall be due by vertue of this A&bholigct; after warrant or Order entred for payment thereof his Executors Administrators
or Assignes by Indorsement of his Order or Warrant may assigne and transferr his interest and benefitt of such
Warrant to any other, which being notified and an entry and memoriall thereof alsoe made in the said Registry
for Warrants (which the Officer shall on request without Fees or Charge, accordingly make) shall intitle such an
Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the benefitt thereof and payment thereon, And such Assignee
may in (<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) like manner assigne againe and soe toties quoties, And afterwards it shall not be in the power of such
person or persons who have made such Assignements to make void release or discharge the same or the moneyes
thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>X. Out of the Monies raised by this A&bholigct; &pound;380,000 to be applied to the Payment of Seamen, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p77">
				<emph type="i">Manner and Regulation of Payments</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p78">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that the summe of three hundred and
eighty thousand pounds shall be charged and registred in the Booke of [Registr<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] appointed by this A&bholigct; to be kepte
in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt of the Exchequer to be paid to the Treasurer of the Navy for the
time being out of the money payable for the last ten moneths of the eleaven mon&bholigct;hcs Assesment granted by this
A&bholigct; for the Salaries and Wages of such Officers Seamen Marriners and Souldiers as are or shall be imployed
aboard Your Majesties Navy for this present Winter begining at the First day of January One thousand six hundred
sixty six and aboard Your Majesties Navy for the Summer in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
sixty seaven, The said three hundred and eighty thousand pounds to be charged and registred as aforesaid in
manner and forme following (that is to say) When Orders shall be first registred for one hundred thousand
pounds for the Service of the Warr to be paid out of the money ariseing upon the said ten moneths in course
as is by this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ed and prescribed that then and immediately after one or more Orders shall be registred
for the payment of two hundred thousand pounds part of the three hundred and eighty thousand pounds above
mentioned to the Treasurer of the Navy to be by him imployed for the paying of the Wages of Officers Marriners
Seamen and Souldiers as is above mentioned, And when Orders shall be registred for One hundred thousand
pounds more for the Service of the Warr upon the said ten moneths then and immediately after one or more
Orders shall be registred for the summe of One hundred thousand pounds more in further part of the three
hundred and eighty thousand pounds above mentioned, And when Orders shall be registred for One hundred
thousand pounds more for the Service of the Warr then and immediately after one or more Orders shall be
registred for the summe of Eighty thousand pounds in full of the three hundred and eighty thousand pounds
above-mentioned, Which said summes of two hundred thousand pounds, one hundred thousand pounds and eighty
thousand pounds shall be paid in course as they stand registred according to the rules and dire&bholigct;ions and under
the penalties upon the Officers of the Exchequer their Deputyes and Clerkes prescribed and contained in the
Proviso of this A&bholigct; for registring and paying in course,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XI. Treasurer of the Navy misapplying the said Monies.</head>
			<para id="p79">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p80">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed that if the Treasurer of the Navy doe divert or imploy the said three hundred
and eighty thousand pounds or any part thereof to any use or service whatsoever other then for the payment of
the Salaries and Wages of such Officers Seamen Marriners and Souldiers as shall be imployed aboard Your
Majesties Navy as aforesaid untill the said Wages and Salaries shall be fully and intirely paid and discharged,
that then and in such case he shall forfeit treble the value of the money diverted or imployed contrary to the
intent and meaning hereof to be recovered in any of His Majesties Courts at Westminster by A&bholigct;ion of Debt
Bill Plaint or Information wherein noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion Wager of Law Aid Prayer Priviledge Injun&bholigct;ion or Order
of Restraint shall be in any wise granted or allowed, nor any more then one Imparlance, One moyety whereof
to be to such person as shall sue for the same and the other moyetie to Your Majestie Your Heires and
Successors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XII. Deficiency of the &pound;1,250,000 granted 17 C. II.c. 1. to be supplied out of the first Monies granted by this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p81">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that whatever moneyes shall be wanting or fall
short of the twelve hundred and fifty thousand pounds granted by an A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament entituled An
A&bholigct; for granting the summe of Twelve hundred and fifty thousand pounds to the Kings Majestie for his present
further Supply towards the paying in course the severall summes of Money registred for the Service of the present
Warr according to the Power and Dire&bholigct;ion of the said A&bholigct; shall be supplyed and paid out of the first moneyes
granted by this A&bholigct; and payable for and in the first moneth therein mentioned and granted, Any thing in this A&bholigct;
to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIII. Allowance to Treasurer, &amp;c. of Navy and Ordnance.</head>
			<para id="p82">And bee if further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authorise aforesaid that the Treasurer of His Majestyes Navy for himselfe
his Deputyes and Clerkes hall receive and retaine onely the summe of one penny in the pound and noe more And
the Lieutenant or Treasurer of His Majestyes Ordnance for himselfe and his Clerke shall likewise receive and
retaine onely one penny in the pound and noe more out of all the moneyes raised borrowed and paid unto and
issued out by either of them to any person or persons by vertue and in pursuance of this A&bholigct; to be allowed in their
respe&bholigct;ive Accompts thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XIV. Receivers of Monies under any former A&bholigct; not having accounted, and intermeddling under this A&bholigct;; Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p83">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any person being a Receiver of moneyes
due upon any former A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament not haveing accompted for all the moneyes by him received
and to be accounted for upon such A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s before Christmas One thousand six hundred sixty seaven shall
be appointed Receiver for any the moneyes due by this A&bholigct; and shall intermedle therein every such person shall
forfeite the summe of Five hundred pounds to be recovered by any person or persons that will sue for the same
in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill Plaint or other Information wherein noe Essoyne
Prote&bholigct;ion Wager, of Law, Aid, Prayer Priviledge Injun&bholigct;ion or Order of restraint shall be in any wise prayed
granted or allowed; nor any more then one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XV. Proceedings for Recovery of Tax in Forts or Garrisons.</head>
			<para id="p84">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That where any money shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; be assessed
upon any Inhabitants or place being within any Castle Fort or Garrison if such money soe assessed be not paid
within twenty dayes after such assessment That then the C&bhooov;mis?ers for such places shall make Certificate thereof
unto the Barons of the Exchequer who shall cause such Proceedings to be had for the recovery thereof as for
any other Debt due to His Majestie,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVI. No new Fees on Monies by this A&bholigct; assigned for vi&bholigct;ualling the Navy.</head>
			<para id="p85">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that in case any part of the moneyes which
shall be raised by vertue of this A&bholigct; or any other A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s of this present Parlyament shall be assigned or
issued for and towards the vi&bholigct;ualling of His Majesties Navy the same shall be subje&bholigct; to noe charge nor shall any
manner of fee or dedu&bholigct;ion be taken or made out of the same to any other Officer or person whatsoever save
onely the usuall fees in such cases due and payable, to the Tellers and other His Majestyes Officers of the
Exchequer,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVII. Letters Patent, &amp;c. not to bean Exemption.</head>
			<para id="p86">[And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that noe Letters Patents granted by the Kings Majestie
or any of His Royall Progenitors or to be granted by His Majesty to any person or persons Cittyes Burroughes
or Townes Corporate within this Realme of any manner of Liberties Priviledges or Exemptions from Subsidies
Tolls Taxes Assesments or Ayds shall be construed or taken to exempt any person or persons Citty Burrough
or Towne Corporate or any the Inhabitants of the same from the burthen and charge of any summe or summes
of money granted by this A&bholigct; or any other A&bholigct; of this Parlyament now in force to the aid and supply of His
Majesty, in the present Warr, And all Non obstantes in any such Letters Patents made or to be made in barr
of any A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s or Parlyament for the Supply or Assistance of His Majestie are hereby declared to be void and
of none effe&bholigct;. Any such Letters Patents Grants or Charters or any clause of Non obstante or Other matter or
thing therein contained, or any Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p87">Item qued? peti?es privatas personas concernentes (in se form? A&bholigct;us continentes) exhibite fuerunt ??co D?no
Regi in Parliamento P&bhopcrl;?co quar? tituli subscribuntur.</para>
			<para id="p88">1. An Act to enlarge the time given by a former A&bholigct; for Redemption of Mortgages made by the Earle of
Cleaveland.</para>
			<para id="p89">2. An Act for [the<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] naturalizing of Isabella of Nassaw wife of the Right Honourable the Lord Arlington one
of his Majestyes Principall Secretaries of State.</para>
			<para id="p90">3. An Act for supply of part of the Joynture of the Lady Elizabeth Noell.</para>
			<para id="p91">4. An Act for setleing the Estate of John Bodnell Es&bhoqesq; deceased.</para>
			<para id="p92">5. An Additionall A&bholigct; for enableing the sale of Lands to pay the Lord Strangford's debts.</para>
			<para id="p93">6. An Act for naturalizing of Hesther Je Lou the daughter and Coheir of Gideon le Lou Lord of Coliumbers
in Normandy the now wife of the Right Honourable Denzill Lord Hollis of Ifeild.</para>
			<para id="p94">7. An Act for confirming explaining and enlarging an A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; to enable John Lord Abergaveny
sonne and heire of Henry late Lord Abergaveny to sell certaine Lands for payment of his debts and preferment of
his brother and sisters.</para>
			<para id="p95">8. An Act for the illigitimation of the children of the Lady Anne Roos.</para>
			<para id="p96">9. An Act for sale of a Messuage in Chiswicke for payment of the debts of Edward Russell Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p97">10. An Act for confirmation of a setlement of the Estate of Sir Seymour Shirley Baronet.</para>
			<para id="p98">11. An Act for setleing the Moyety of the Mannour of Iron A&bholigct;ion on Sir John Pointz.</para>
			<para id="p99">12. An Act for setleing an Estate in trust for the benefit of M<emph type="p">rs</emph> Elizabeth Pride and her children.</para>
			<para id="p100">13. An Act for the ascertaining the bounds of the severall Rectories of Swafham Saint Ciriac and of Swafham
Saint Maries within the Towne of Swafham Prior in the County of Cambridge, and for the uniteing of the two
Churches there.</para>
			<para id="p101">14. An Act for the restoreing of Francis Scawen Gen? in bloud.</para>
			<para id="p102">15. An Act for naturalizing Dame Mary Frazer and others.</para>
			<para id="p103">16. An Act to enable a Sale of Lands for payment of the debts of Henry Kendall Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p104">17. An Act for setleing part of the Lands of Henry Mildmay Es&bhoqesq; deceased for payment of his debts and
makeing provision for his children.</para>
			<para id="p105">18. An Act to enable Leicester Grosvenor and his trustees to sell certaine Lands for payment of debts.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Vi&bholigct;uall Shipps <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Paiements <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">in <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Register <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a feparate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


