<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47407" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1667 &amp; 1668</title>
	<subtitle>C A P. XII. An Additional Act against the Importation of Forreign Cattel [Rot. Parl. 19&amp; 20 C.II. nu.12.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 18 Car. II. c.2 &sect; 1.; and that notwithstanding the said Act great Numbers of Cattle, &amp;c. have been imported, and that divers Churchwardens, &amp;c. had combined with the Owners for colourable Seizures, and that others who had discharged their Duty had been molested by Suits in distant Counties; </head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Officers who have seized any imported Cattle indemnified</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; of this present Parliament intituled An A&bholigct; against importing Cattel from Ireland and
other parts beyond the Seas and Fish taken by Forreigners. amongst other things Provision was made
against Importation of Cattel from parts beyond the Seas And it was thereby enacted That such Importation from
and after the second day of February which was in the yeare One thousand six hundred sixty six was a publick
Nusance and should be so adjudged deemed and taken to all intents and purposes And that if any great Cattel
Sheepe or Swine or any Beef Pork or Bacon (except for the necessary Provision of the respe&bholigct;ive Ships or Vessels
in which the same should be brought not exposing the same to sale) should from and after the said second day
of February by any wise whatsoever be imported or brought from beyond the Seas into this Kingdom of England
Dominion of Wales or Town of Berwick upon Tweed That then it should and might be lawfull for any Constable
Tithingmari Headborough Church warden or Overseers of the Poore or any of them within their respe&bholigct;ive Liberties
Parishes or Places to take and seize the same and keepe the same during the space of eight and fourty houres
in some publick or convenient place where such seizure should be made within which time if the Owner or
Owners or any for them or him should make it appeare unto some Justice of the Peace of the same County where
the same should be so seized by the Oath of two credible Witnesses that the same were not imported from
Ireland or from any other place beyond the Seas not therein after excepted after the said second day of February
Then the same upon the Warrant of such Justice of Peace should be delivered without delay but in default of
such Proof and Warrant then the same to be forfeited one halfe thereof to be disposed to the use of the poor of
the Parish where the same shall be so found or seized the other to be to his or theire owne use that should soe
seize the same Notwithstanding which A&bholigct; and the good Provision thereby great number of Cattell Sheep and
Swine and great quantities of Beefe Pork and Bacon have since the time limited by the said A&bholigct; been imported
from Ireland and other places beyond the Seas as well in Forreign as English Ships and Vessels contrary to the
good intent of the said A&bholigct; and in continuance of the said Nusance and in high contempt of the Authority of
Parliament And divers Church wardens Constables Tithing men and Overseers of the Poore living neere the Sea for
theire owne private Lucre having combined with the Owners of such Cattel Sheep Swine Beef Pork and Bacon
imported as aforesaid or with theire Agents have colourably seized and afterwards privately and fraudulently sold
the same at very low and inconsiderable Rates to the said Owners or theire Agents And other of the said officers
who have discharged theire Duties in the due execution of the said A&bholigct; have been molested therefore and several
A&bholigct;ions Suits Plaints and Informations have [been
<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] brought and prosecuted against some of them in Counties and
places far distant from theire Habitations to theire great charge and discouragement For the Vindication therefore
of the Authority of Parliament from such bold Affronts and the Indempnifying as well of such Officers who have
faithfully endeavored the Execution of the said A&bholigct; (although they have not stri&bholigct;ly pursued the same in every
Circumstance) as of such other person and persons who have a&bholigct;ed in their aid and assistance and for the better
and further suppression of the said Nusance Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the
Advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal &amp; Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by
authority of the same That all and every Constable Tithingman Headborough Church warden and Overseer of the
Poor and every other person or persons who have a&bholigct;ed in or concerning the seizure keeping detaining or
disposing of any Cattel Sheep Swine Beef Pork or Bacon imported contrary to the said A&bholigct; after the said second
day of February shall be and are hereby saved harmeles and indemnified in that behalfe against the Owner or
Owners thereof at the time of such Importation their Executors and Administrators and every other person and
persons claiming from by or under their Gift Grant or other Disposition and against all and every person and
persons to whom any fraudulent Sale hath been made [after<ref idref="n1">1</ref>
] such Importation as aforesaid and their and every
of theire Executors and Administrators</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Any Person may seize imported Cattle, and deliver them to the Officers.</head>
			<para id="p3">[And it is provided and further ena&bholigct;ed That not only the Constables and Officers above named but every
or any other Inhabitant or Inhabitants of or within the Liberties Parishes and places where such Importation shall
be made shall and may take and seize the Cattel and Goods so imported and after such seizure shall forthwith
deliver or cause them to been delivered to the Constable Tithingman Headborough Church warden or Overseers of
the Poore or any of them within the respe&bholigct;ive Liberties Parishes and Places aforesaid to be kept ordered and
disposed in the manner and to the uses and purposes in this A&bholigct; and in the said recited A&bholigct; or either of them
mentioned and dire&bholigct;ed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Neglecting to seize,</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound; 100; Penalties accounted for as Overseers of the Poor account under 43 Eliz. c. 2</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed That if no Seizure at all shall be made by the Officers or Inhabitants nor any of
them within the Liberty Parish or Place where such Cattel or Goods as aforesaid shall be first imported Then such
Liberty Parish and Place and the Inhabitants thereof negle&bholigct;ing to make such Seizure for every default shall
forfeit the s&bhouov;m of One hundred pounds which shall be imployed for the use of the House of Corre&bholigct;ion within
the County or Liberty where such default of Seisure shall be and the Moneys so to be forfeoted and other the
Penalties and Forfeitures which are to accrue to the Poor by vertue of this A&bholigct; and the said recited A&bholigct; or either
of them shall be accounted for to such persons att such times and in such manner as the Overseers of the Poore
are appointed to accompt by the Statute made in the Three and fortieth yeare of the Reign of Queen Elizabeth
Chapter the second<ref idref="n2">2</ref>
]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Ships bringing Cattle, &amp;c. from beyond Sea, to be forfeited, seized and sold.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">The Seamen to be apprehended, and allothers concerned, and sent to the Common Gaol</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That every Shipp or Vessel with all her Tackle and
Apparel in which any great Cattel Swine Sheepe Beef Pork or Bacon from and after the Four and twentieth
day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and seaven shall be imported from
Ireland or any other parts beyond the Seas into the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Town of Berwick
upon Tweed and out of which they or any of them shall be put on Shore there shall be forfeited And that it
shall and may be lawfull to and for any person or persons within the space of one yeare after such Importation
to take and seize the same Shipp or Vessel with all her Tackle and Apparel and to make sale thereof to the
best advantage and that one halfe of the Moneys to be raised by such Sale shall be disposed of to the use of
the Poor of the Parish where the same shall be so seized the other halfe to be to his or their use that, shall
so seize the same And alsoe that it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Justice of Peace of the County or
Cheif Officer of the Port Town in or neare the place where such Importation shall be made or where any
of the Cattel Sheep Swine Beef Pork or Bacon so imported shall be driven or brought by Warrant under the
Hand and Seale of such Justice of Peace or Cheif Officer to cause to be apprehended all and every the Masters
Mariners and Seamen having Charge of or belonging to such Ship or Vessel in which such Importation shall be
made and all and every other person and persons a&bholigct;ing or imployed in the landing driving attending on or taking
care or charge of the said Cattel Sheep Swine Beef Pork or Bacon imported as aforesaid and them to commit
to the Common Goal of the said County there to remain without Bail or Mainprize for me space of three
Moneths</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Cattle, &amp;c. seised and then driven, &amp;c. into another Parish, Constable, &amp;c. of such other Parish may seise and dispose thereof.</head>
			<para id="p8">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid That whensoever and as often as it shall
happen either through any fraudulent Agreement or unfaithfull Connivance of any Constable Headborough Tithingman
Church warden or Overseer of the Poor or that it shall happen any otherwise howsoever that any great Cattel
Sheep Swine Beef Pork or Bacon after the first Seizure of them or any of them by vertue of the aforesaid A&bholigct;
shall be driven brought carried into or found in any other Parish or place then where the same shall be first
seized as aforesaid That then and so often and from time to time it shall and may be lawfull to and for the
Constable Tithingman Headborough Church warden or Overseer of the Poor of every or any such other Parish or
place where such great Cattel Sheep Swine Beef Pork or Bacon shall be brought driven or carried into or found
as aforesaid to seize take and dispose the same and every or any of them as forfeited The one moyety thereof
to the use of the Poor of such other Parish or place where such Seizure shall be made the other to the use
of such Officer or Officers who shall seize the same as aforesaid Any other or former Seizure or Seizures in
any other Parish or Parishes place or places notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Information laid in the same County where Cause of Action.</head>
			<para id="p9">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion Bill Plaint Suit or Information is or shall
be commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for any Seizure or other thing made or done or to
be made or done by vertue or colour of this or the aforesaid A&bholigct; and upon the Triall of such A&bholigct;ion Bill Plaint
Suit or Information it shall not be proved to the Jury that shall try the same that the Cause of such A&bholigct;ion
Bill Plaint Suit or Information did arise within such County where such A&bholigct;ion Plaint Suit or Information is laid
and tried the Defendant &amp; Defendants shall be found Not guilty without having regard to any Evidence given by
or for the Plaintiff Informer or Prosecutor</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. In Action for executing Act,</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">General Issue may be pleaded.; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any Action Bill Plaint Suit or Information hath
been or shall be commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for any seizure or other thing done or
made or to be done or made in pursuance or execution of this or the aforesaid A&bholigct; such person or persons
so sued in any Court whatsoever may plead the General Issue and give this and the aforesaid A&bholigct; and the
special matter in Evidence for theire Excuse or Justification And if the Plaintiff or Prosecutor shall become Nonsuit
or forbear prosecution or suffer Discontinuance or if a Verdi&bholigct; passe against him in any such A&bholigct;ion Bill. Plaint
Suit or Information as aforesaid the Defendants shall have treble Costs for which they shall have the like Remedy
as in any Case where Costs by the Law are' given to the Defendant</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for Importation of Cattle from Isle of Man.</head>
			<para id="p12">Provided alwaies That no thing in this A&bholigct; shall be construed to hinder the Importation of Cattel from, the
Isle of Man into this Kingdom of England so as the Number of the said Cattel do not exceed six hundred
Head yearly [and that they be not of any other breed then of the breed of the Isle of Man<ref idref="n3">3</ref>
] and that they
be landed att the Port of Chester or some of the Members thereof and not elsewhere</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Confederacy to elude this Act, Premunire.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">16R. II. c. 5.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p14">[And it is lastly ena&bholigct;ed That if any person or persons shall wilfully and fraudulently conspire confederate or
agree togeather to avoide or evade the seizures or forfeitures upon Importation of Cattel or Goods in this present
A&bholigct; particularly specified and the same shall put in execution then every such person and persons being thereof
lawfully indi&bholigct;ed or presented within one yeare next after such Offence by him or them committed and being
thereof lawfully convi&bholigct;ed or attainted at any time after according to the Laws of this Realm shall incur the
dangers penalties paines and forfeitures contained and provided in and by the Statute of Provision and Premunire
made in the sixteenth yeare of the Reigne of King Richard the Second.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>
]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


