<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47409" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act to prevent and suppresse Seditious Conventicles. [Rot. Parl. 22 C. II. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Persons of the Age of 16 Years and upwards being present at any Conventicle.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Justices to record Offence, and such Record deemed a Conviction.; Penalty for First Offence.; The Record, &amp;c. to be returned to next Quarter Sessions</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For providing further and more speedy Remedies against the growing and dangerous pra&bholigct;ices of Seditious
Se&bholigct;aries and other disloyall Persons who under pretence of tender Consciences have or may at their Meetings
contrive Insurre&bholigct;ions (as late experience hath shewen) Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by
and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by authoritie of the same That if any person of the Age of Sixteene yeares or upwards being
a Subje&bholigct; of this Realme at any time after the Tenth day of May next shall be present at any Assembly Conventicle
or Meeteing under colour or pretence of any Exercise of Religion in other manner then according to the Liturgy
and pra&bholigct;ice of the Church of England in any place within the Kingdome of England, Dominion of Wales or
Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede, at which Conventicle, Meeting or Assembly there shall be five persons or more
assembled together over and besides those of the same Household, if it be in a House where there is a Family
inhabiting, or if it be in a House, Feild or place where there is noe Family inhabiting then where any five
persons or more are soe assembled as aforesaid it shall and may be lawfull to and for any one or more
Justices of the Peace of the County Limitt, Division, Corporation or Liberty wherein the offence aforesaid shall
bee committed or for the Cheife Magistrate of the place where such offence aforesaid shall be committed,
and he and they are hereby required and enjoyned upon proofe to him or them respe&bholigct;ively made of such offence
either by Confession of the partie or Oath of two Witnesses (which Oath the said Justice and Justices of the
Peace and cheife Magistrate respe&bholigct;ively are hereby impowered and required to administer, or by notorious Evidence
and Circumstance of the Fa&bholigct; to make a Record of every such offence under his or their Hands and Seales
respe&bholigct;ively which Record soe made as aforesaid shall to all intents and purposes be in Law taken and adjudged
to be a full and perfe&bholigct; Conviction of every such Offender for such Offence, and thereupon the said Justice,
Justices and cheife Magistrate respe&bholigct;ively shall impose on every such Offender soe convi&bholigct; as aforesaid a Fine of
Five shillings for such first Offence which Record and Convi&bholigct;ion shall be certifyed by the said Justice Justices
or cheife Magistrate at the next Quarter Sessions of the Peace for the County or place where the Offence was
committed,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Penalty for further Offence.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalties in Cases of Poverty levied on the Goods of other Offenders.; Coustables, &amp;c. to levy the same under Warrant, and pay it to the Justice immediately.; How Penalties to be divided.; Charge and Discharge of the King's Share to be certified together into the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That if such Offender soe convi&bholigct;ed as aforesaid shall at
any time againe committ the like Offence or Offences contrary to this A&bholigct; and be thereof in manner aforesaid
convi&bholigct;ed, then such Offender soe convi&bholigct; of such like Offence or Offences shall for every such Offence incurr the
penaltie of Ten shillings which Fine and Fines for the first and every other Offence shall be leavyed by Distresse
and Sale of the Offenders Goods and Chattells, or in case of the povertie of such Offender upon the Goods and
Chattells of any other person or persons who shall be then convi&bholigct;ed in manner aforesaid of the like Offence at
the same Conventicle at the discretion of the said Justice, Justices or cheife Magistrate respe&bholigct;ively soe as the Summe
to be leavyed on any one person in case of the povertie of other Offenders amount not in the whole to above
the summe of Ten pounds upon occasion of any one Meeting as aforesaid. And every Constable Headburrough
Tything man Churchwardens and Overseers of the Poore respe&bholigct;ively are hereby authorized and required to leavy
the same accordingly haveing first received a Warrant under the Hands and Seales of the said Justice, Justices
or cheife Magistrate respe&bholigct;ively soe to doe, the said Moneys soe to be leavyed to be forthwith delivered to the
same Justice Justices or cheife Magistrate and by him or them to be destributed, the one third part [thereof to the
use of the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors to be paid to the High Sheriffe of the County for the time
being in manner following that is to say the Justice or Justices of Peace shall pay the same into the Court of the
respe&bholigct;ive Quarter Sessions which said Court shall deliver the same to the Sheriffe and make a Memoriall on
Record of the payment and delivery thereof, which said Memoriall shall be a sufficient and finall Discharge to
the said Justice and Justices and a Charge to the Sheriffe, which said Discharge and Charge shall be certifyed into
the Exchequer together and not one without the other, And noe Justice shall or may be questioned or accountable
for the same in the Exchequer or elsewhere then in Quarter Sessions, and other third part thereof<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to and for the
use of the Poore of the Parish where such Offence shall be committed, And the other third part thereof to the
Informer and Informers and to such person and persons as the said Justice, Justices or cheife Magistrate respe&bholigct;ively
shall appoint haveing reguard to their diligence and industry in the discovery, disperseing and punishing of the said
Conventicles,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Preaching, &amp;c. in a Conventicle; Penalty, First Offence, &pound;20.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">If Preacher fled, or not able to pay, Penalty to be levied upon Goods of Persons present.; Further Offence, &pound;40</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That every person who shall take upon him to preach
or teach in any such Meeting, Assembly or Conventicle and [shall<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] thereof be convi&bholigct;ed as aforesaid shall forfeite
for every such first offence the Summe of Twenty pounds to be leavyed in manner aforesaid upon his Goods and
Chattells, And if the said Preacher or Teacher soe convi&bholigct;ed be a Stranger, and his Name and Habitation not
knowne, or is fled and cannot be found, or in the judgement of the Justice Justices or cheife Magistrate before
whom he shall be convi&bholigct;ed shall be thought unable to pay the same, the said Justice, Justices or cheife Magistrate
respe&bholigct;ively are hereby impowered and required to leavy the same by Warrant as aforesaid upon the Goods and
Chattells of any such persons who shall be present at the same Conventicle Any thing in this or any other A&bholigct;,
Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding. And the Money soe leavyed to be disposed of in manner aforesaid,
And if such Offender soe convi&bholigct;ed as aforesaid shall at any time againe committ the like Offence or Offences
contrary to this A&bholigct; and be thereof convi&bholigct;ed in manner aforesaid then such Offender soe convi&bholigct;ed of such like
Offence or Offences shall for every such Offence incurr the penalty of Forty pounds to be leavyed and disposed
as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Persons suffering Conventicles in their Houses, &amp;c. Penalty &pound;20.</head>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That every person who shall wittingly and willingly suffer
any such Conventicle, Meeteing or unlawfull Assembly aforesaid to be held in his or her House, Outhouse Barne
Yard or Backeside and be convi&bholigct;ed thereof in manner aforesaid shall forfeite the summe of Twenty pounds to be
leavyed in manner aforesaid upon his or her Goods and Chattells, or in case of his or her povertie or inability
as aforesaid upon the Goods and Chattells of such persons who shall be convi&bholigct;ed in manner aforesaid of being
present at the same Conventicle, and the Money soe leavyed to bee disposed of in manner aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Person to pay more than &pound;10. on account of Poverty of other Persons.</head>
			<para id="p8">[Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That noe person shall by any Clause of this
A&bholigct; be lyable to pay above Ten pounds for any one Meeteing in regard of the poverty of any other person or
persons.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Proviso for Appeals, and to whom, and in what Cases.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Trial by Jury.; If Appeal not prosecuted with Effect, &amp;c. Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">Provided alsoe and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That in all cases of this A&bholigct; where the penalty or summe charged
upon any offender exceeds the summe of Ten shillings and such offender shall finde himselfe agreived it shall and
may be lawfull for him within one weeke after the said penalty or Money charged shall be paid or leavyed to
appeale in writeing from the person or persons convi&bholigct;ing to the judgement of the Justices of the Peace in their
next Quarter Sessions, to whom the Justice or Justices of Peace, cheife Magistrate or Alderman that first convi&bholigct;ed
such offender shall returne the Money leavyed upon the Appellant. and shall certifie under his and their Hands
and Seales the Evidence upon which the Convi&bholigct;ion past with the whole Record thereof and the said Appeale,
whereupon such offender may pleade and make defence and have his Tryall by a Jury thereupon, And in case
such Appellant shall not prosecute with effe&bholigct; or if upon such Tryall he shall not be acquitted or Judgement
passe not for him upon his said Appeale the said Justices at the Sessions shall give treble Costs against such
offender for his unjust Appeale, And noe other Court whatsoever shall intermedle with any Cause or Causes of
Appeale upon this Act but they shall be finally determined in the Quarter Sessions onely.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Appellant to enter into a Recognizance or Appeal void.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That upon the delivery of such Appeale as aforesaid the person
[or<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] persons Appellant shall enter before the person or persons convi&bholigct;ing into a Recognizance to prosecute the
said Appeale with effe&bholigct;. Which said Recognizance the person or persons convi&bholigct;ing is hereby impowered to take
and required to certifie the same(<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) to the next Quarter Sessions And in case noe such Recognizance be entred into
the said Appeale to be null and void, Provided alwayes That every such Appeale shall be left with the person
or persons soe convi&bholigct;ing as aforesaid at the time of the makeing thereof.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Justices of Peace, Constables, &amp;c. may break open Doors.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Lieutenants, Deputy Lieutenants, and Commissioned Officers of the Militia, Sheriffs, &amp;c. on Certificate of Justice, to prevent or disperse Conventicles</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the Justice, Justices of the Peace and cheife Magistrate
respe&bholigct;ively, or the respe&bholigct;ive Constables Head-boroughs and Tythingmen by Warrant from the said Justice, Justices
or cheife Magistrate respe&bholigct;ively shall and may with what aide force and assistance they shall thinke fitt for the
better execution of this A&bholigct; after refusall or denyall to enter, breake open and enter into any House or other
place where they shall be informed any such Conventicle as aforesaid is or shall be held as well within Liberties
as without and take into their custody the persons there unlawfully assembled to the intent they may be proceeded
against according to this A&bholigct;, And that the Lieutenants or Deputy Lieutenants or any C&bhooov;issionated Officer of the
Militia or other of his Majesties Forces with such Troopes or Companies of Horse and Foote, and alsoe the
Sheriffes and other Magistrates and Ministers of Justice or any of them joyntly or severally within any the Countyes
or places within this Kingdome of England, Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede with such
other Assistance as they shall thinke meete or can gett in readines with the soonest on Certificate made to them
respe&bholigct;ively under the Hand and Seale of any one Justice of the Peace or cheife Magistrate of his perticular
Information or Knowledge of such unlawfull Meeting or Conventicle held or to be held in their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes
or places, and that he with such assistance as he can gett together is not able to suppresse and dissolve the same
shall and may and are hereby required and enjoyned to repaire unto the place where they are soe held or to be
held and by the best meanes they can to dissolve, dissipate or prevent all such unlawfull Meetings, and take into
their Custody such and soe many of the said persons soe unlawfully assembled as they shall thinke fitt to the
intent they may be proceeded against according to this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Proviso as to searching Dwelling Houses of Peers of the Realm.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided alwayes That noe Dwelling house of any Peere of this Realme where he or his Wife shall be then
resident shall be searched by vertue of this A&bholigct;, but by immediate Warrant from his Majestie under his Signe
Manuall, or in the presence of the Lieutenant or one Deputy Lieutenant or two Justices of the Peace whereof one
to be of the Quorum of the same County or Rideing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Constables, and other Officers, omitting their Duty;</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound; 5; Justices of Peace, &amp;c.; Penalty &pound; 100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That if any Constable Headborough Tythingman Church
warden or Overseer of the Poore who shall know or be credibly informed of any such Meeteings or Conventicles
held-within his Precin&bholigct;s Parish or Limitts and shall not give information thereof to some Justice of the Peace or
the cheife Magistrate and endeavour the convi&bholigct;ion of the partyes according to his duty, but such Constable,
Headburrough, Tythingman, Churchwarden, Overseers of the Poore; or any person lawfully called in aide of the
Constable, Headburrough or Tythingman shall wilfully and wittingly oramitt the performance of his duty in the
execution of this A&bholigct; and be thereof convi&bholigct;ed in manner aforesaid he shall forfeite for every such offence the summe
of Five pounds to be leavyed upon his Goods and Chattells and disposed in manner aforesaid. And that if any
Justice of the Peace or cheife Magistrate shall wilfully and wittingly ommitt the performance of his duty in the
execution of this A&bholigct; he shall forfeite the summe of One hundred pounds the one moyety to the use of his
Majestie, the other Moyetie to the use of the Informer to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion, Suite, Bill or Plaint in any of
his-Majesties Courts at [Westwininster<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] wherein noe Essoyne, Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall lye.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. In Action for executing Act,</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">General Issue,; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That if any person be at any time sued for putting in
execution any of the powers contained in this A&bholigct; otherwise then upon Appeale allowed by this A&bholigct; such person
shall and may pleade the generall Issue and give the speciall matter in Evidence, and if the Plaintiffe be Nonsuite
or a Verdi&bholigct; passe for. the Defendant, or if the Plaintiffe discontinue his A&bholigct;ion, or if upon Demurrer Judgement
be given for the Defendant every such Defendant shall have his full treble Costs.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Act to be interpreted most beneficially for suppressing Conventicles.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Proceedings not void for Form.; Justices to certify as to Offenders Inhabitants of other Counties, or having fled thereto, to Justices of such other Counties.; who are to levy the Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That this A&bholigct; and all Clauses therein contained shall
be construed most largely and beneficially for the suppresseing of Conventicles and for the justification and
encouragement of all persons to be employed in the execution thereof, And that noe Record, Warrant or
Mittimus to be made by vertue of this A&bholigct;, or any proceedings thereupon shall be reversed avoided or any way
impeached by reason of any defaulte in forme, And in case any person offending against this: A&bholigct; shall be an
Inhabitant in any other County or Corporation or fly into any other County or Corporation after the offence
committed the Justice of the Peace or cheife Magistrate before whom he shall be convi&bholigct;ed as aforesaid shall certifiethe same under his Hand and Seale to any Justice of Peace or cheife Magistrate of such other County or
Corporation wherein the said person or persons are Inhabitants or are fled into, which said Justice or cheife


Magistrate respe&bholigct;ively is hereby authorized and required to leavy the penalty or penaltyes in this A&bholigct; mentioned
upon the Goods and Chattells of such person or persons as fully as the said other Justice of Peace might
have done in case he or they had beene Inhabitants in the place where the offence was committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Limitation of Prosecution.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">No Double Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">Provided alsoe That noe person shall be punished for any offence against this A&bholigct; unlesse such Offender be
prosecuted for the same within three moneths after the Offence committed, And that noe person who shall be
punished for any offence by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be punished for the same offence by vertue of any other
Act or Law whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Aldermen within London to have the same Power there, and subje&bholigct; to the same Penalties, as Justice of Peace elsewhere.</head>
			<para id="p23">Provided and bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That every Alderman of London for the time
being within the Citty of London and the Liberties thereof shall have (and they and every of them are hereby
impowered and required to execute) the same power and authority within London and the Liberties thereof for the
examining convi&bholigct;ing and punishing of all offences within this A&bholigct; committed within London and the Liberties
thereof, which any Justice of Peace hath by this A&bholigct; in any County of England and shall be subje&bholigct; to the
same penalties and punishments for not doeing that which by this A&bholigct; is directed to be done by any Justice of Peace
in any County of England.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Penalty on Feme Covert to be levied on Husband.</head>
			<para id="p24">Provided and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That if the person offending and convi&bholigct;ed as aforesaid
be a Feme-covert cohabiting with her Husband the penalties of Five shillings and Ten shillings soe as aforesaid
incurred shall be leavyed by Warrant as aforesaid upon the Goods and Chattells of the Husband of such
Feme-covert.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Imprisonment, &amp;c. of Peers.</head>
			<para id="p25">Provided alsoe That noe Peere of this Realme shall be attached or imprisoned by vertue or Force of this
A&bholigct;. Any thing matter or clause therein to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Proviso for the King's Supremacy in Ecclesiastical Affaires.</head>
			<para id="p26">Provided alsoe That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend to invalidate or avoid his
Majesties Supremacy in Ecclesiasticall Affaires, But that his Majestie and his Heires and Successors may from time
to time and at all times, hereafter exercise and enjoy all powers and authorities in Ecclesiasticall Affaires as fully
and as amply as himselfe or any of his Predecessors have or might have done the same. Any thing in this A&bholigct;
notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Westminster <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


