<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47408" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1667 &amp; 1668</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An Act for the taxing and assessing of the Lands of the Adventurers within the Great Levell of the Fenns(<ref idref="n1">1</ref>)</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 15 Car. II. c. 17.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that since the said Act the Corporation had imposed Taxes at a certain Rate per Acre; and that inconvenient; Taxes hereafter to be assessed by the Governor, &amp;c. by a gradual Acre Tax</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; made in this present Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; for settling the Dreyneing of the
Great Levell of the Fenns called Bedford Levell, It is amongst other Things ena&bholigct;ed That the Governor
Bayliffes and Conservators of the Corporacon in the said A&bholigct; menso&bhocotil;ned and by vertue of the same from tyme to
tyme to be elected and appointed for the time being or any five or more of them (whereof the Governor and Bayliffes
for the tyme being or any of them to be two) should and might from thenceforth use the Power and Authority
of Commissio[ner]s of Sewers within the said Great Levell, and from tyme to tyme lay and impose Taxes upon the nynety
five thousand Acres within the said Levell, in the said A&bholigct; menco&bhocotil;ed for the Maintenance and Preservacon of the same,
as by the said A&bholigct; appeareth And whereas since the makeing of the said A&bholigct;, the Governor Bayliffes and Conservators
of the said Corporacon in Execu&bhocotil;n of the Power and Authority thereby to them given, have laid and imposed
Taxes upon the said nynety five thousand Acres for the Purposes by the said A&bholigct; specified and appointed, wherein
they have proceeded by way of an Acre taxe at a certaine Rate by the Acre and have enforced the Paiement of
the same after that Manner to the great Damage of [diverse<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] the Adventurers and Participants, for that the said
nynety five thousand Acres are not only much different in the naturall Richnesse and Barrennesse of their Soyle but
likewise some Parts of the said Lands are by frequent Inunda&bhocotil;ns and otherwise exceedingly pejorated and made
worse, and. the Corne Hay Seed or Grass thereupon often destroyed, yett the same Lands are equally taxed with
the best and most secure Lands in the said Levell as [aforesaid<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] the which said Way of raiseing Dreyneing taxes
upon the said nynety five thousand Acres by an equall Acre rate hath been found to be inconvenient, and for
removeing the said Inconvenience, the said Governor Bayliffes and Conservators have of late proceeded to a more
indifferent way of taxeing of the said nynety five thousand Acres (that is to say) by a graduall Acre taxe of five
Sorts upon eighty three thousand Acres Part of the said nynety five thousand Acres, and by a Medium of the
twelve thousand Acres Residue of the said nynety five thousand Acres, And to the Intent that incouragement may
bee given for the better improveing of the said nynety five thousand Acres, and that a constant and certaine way
of taxeing may bee continued and established for the future Bee it enacted by the Kings most excellent Majestie
by and with the Advice and Assent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and C&bhooov;mons in this Parliament assembled
and by the Authority of the same That all Taxes hereafter to bee sett and imposed for the Maintenance and
Preserva&bhocotil;tion of the said Great Levell are hereby appointed and declared to be from tyme to tyme assessed
and, taxed by the said Governor Bayliffes and Conservators or their Successors or any five or more of them
whereof the said Governor and Bayliffes for the tyme being or any of them to bee two upon the said eighty
three thousand Acres Part and Parcell of the said nynety five thousand Acres by a graduall Acre tax of diferent
Sorts and Values of Lands the which said graduall Acre tax sett as aforesaid and all future graduall Acre taxes to bee
sett shall be received paid and leavied with like Penalties in the said recited Act provided for Non payment of
Taxes by such and the like Wayes and Meanes as by the said recited A&bholigct; are provided for to be paid and
leavied, And the said eighty three thousand Acres for raiseing of Taxes for Support and Maintenance of the Great
Levell are not to bee rated or assessed otherwise or in any other Manner then according to a graduall Acre taxe
of different Sorts and Degrees, and according to the respe&bholigct;ive Values and Rates thereby sett and rated and to
be sett and rated as is hereafter is appointed upon the said eighty three thousand Acres, taxe
other Thing to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Whenever there is a Tax of &pound; 6,110. 7s. 1&frac12;d. upon the said 95,000 Acres, then the said 12,000 Acres to be rated at Fifteen-pence per Acre;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and so in proportion</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And whereas the said twelve thousand Acres Residue of the said nynety five thousand Acres are by the said
graduall Acre tax towards the raiseing of the S&bhooov;me of Six thousand one hundred and tenn pounds seaven shillings
one penny halfe penny are rated and taxed at one shilling three pence p[er] Acre being a Medium as if the whole
nynety five thousand Acres had been rated taxed and assessed at fifteene pence &bhopubr; Acre Bee it further enacted by
the Authority aforesaid, That when and soe often as a Taxe of the said S&bhouov;me of six thousand one hundred and
tenn pounds seaven shillings one penny halfe penny shall be taxed and assessed upon the said nynety five thousand
Acres, that then the said twelve thousand Acres shall be rated taxed and. assessed by the said Governor Bayliffes
and Conservators and their Successors or any five or more of them where of the said Governor and Bayliffes or
any of them to be two at fifteene pence the Acre and according to the Propor&bhocotil;on for the raiseing of any greater
or a lesser S&bhouov;me then six thousand one hundred and tenn pounds seaven shilling one penny halfe penny to be
received paid and leavyed together with Penalties in such and the like Manner as the Taxes sett and imposed or
to be sett and. imposed upon the said eighty three thousand Acres are by this Act provided for to be received
paid and leavyed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Days on which Tax on the 95,000 Acres to be set.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authority aforesaid That noe Taxes to be sett by vertue of this
A&bholigct; shall be sett or imposed upon the said nynety five thousand Acres by the said Governor Bayliffes and
Conservators or their Successors or any five or. more of them, but upon Wednesday Thursday and Friday next
after, the first Sunday in Aprill or some or one of them, three Days yearely for ever and not at any other tyme
Any Law Custome or Usaged to the contrary thereof notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. 15 C. II. c. 17. &sect; 8. Days for Sales for Non-payment of Taxes appointed.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Serjeant at Mace of the Great Levell to deliver Possession to Purchaser by Precept under Corporate Seal</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And whereas by the said recited A&bholigct; it is amongst other Things provided That Sales for Non payment of Taxes
shall be made at Ely upon Wednesday and Thursday in Whitson weeke yearely, the which Season is found to be
inconvenient For Remedy whereof bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid, That from and after Whitson
weeke which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred sixty eight those Dayes for Sales shall
be altered and changed unto the said Wednesday Thursday and Friday after the said first Sunday in Aprill in
every Yeare and all other Matters and Things concerning or relateing to Sales for Non payment of Taxes by the
said recited A&bholigct; provided are to stand in Force and to be observed with this that the Serjant at Mace of the said
Great Levell shall from tyme to tyme by Precept under the Seale of the Corpora&bhocotil;on of the said Great Levell in
Nature of a Writt of Habere fac possession&emacr; at Comon Law deliver Possession unto such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons as shall
purchase any part of the said nynety. five thousand Acres for Non payment of Taxes, and the said Governor
Bayliffes and Conservators are hereby required and authorized to affixe the Seale of the said Corporation from
tyme to tyme to such Precept or Precepts at the Charge of the Parties requireing the same Any Law Statute
Usage or Custome to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Names of the Surveyors who are to digest the 83,000 Acres into Seven Sorts;</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">who are to return Schedules thereof upon Oath</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And to the end that the said eighty three thousand Acres may be more equally rated by a graduall Acre Taxe
not under the Number of seaven Sorts, Bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That Edward Partheridge
Es&bhoqesq;: Samuell Fortery Esquire Richard Mariott Esquire John Myngay Jonas Moore Peter Diamond Esquires Anthony
Hamond Esquire Mark le Pla Ge&ntilde; and John Bridgeman junio<emph type="p">r</emph> Gent. or any three or more of them are hereby
constituted and appointed to be Surveyors and Valuers of the said eighty three thousand Acres, and are within
twelve Moneths next after the passing of this A&bholigct; to digest the said eighty three thousand Acres into such Number
of Sorts or Degrees of Land not under the Number of seaven Sorts and Degrees, and to rate and tax such
Degrees and digest the same into Schedules in Writeing and make Returnes thereof upon their Oathes into the
Fenn Office, the Forme of which said Oath shall be (vizt)</para>
			<para id="p10">I: A: B: doe sweare That according to the best of my Skill and Knowldge, I will faithfully discharge the Trust
of surveying sorting devideing and rateing of eighty three thousand Acres Parcell of nynety five thousand
Acres within the Great Levell of the Fenns knowne by the Name of Bedford Levell according to seaven Degrees
or more as I upon my Oath shall thinke most equall,</para>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Returns made within One Month from Survey, and to be set up publickly in the Fen-Office.; Appeal to Commissioners; Names of such Commissioners; their Power as to Relief and Costs; Limitation of Appeal.; Schedules to form the Rule of taxing.; The 12,000 Acres how to be rated</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">The which said Oath the said Governor Bayliffes and Conservators or any three or more of them are hereby
authorized to administer and alsoe to allow unto the said Surveyors or Valluers such reasonable Charges for their
Traill and Paines therein as they shall think fitt, and after the same are returned into the said Fenn Office and
there publiquely sett up, which said Returne is hereby enacted to be made within one Moneth after the Survey
taken and the severall Valua&bhocotil;ns by the Parties to that Purpose by this Act: appointed and agreed upon, and all
Parties agrived may take their Excep&bhocotil;ns within thirty Dayes next after the same are sett up and within forty
Dayes next after such Excep&bhocotil;ns taken may appeale for Releife unto the said Governor Bayliffes and Conservators
or any five or more of them [for<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] altering the said Schedules in the Rates and Values complained off, soe as
the Parties appealeing shall prosecute their said Appeale within the said forty Dayes, and not at any Tyme after,
And in case the said Governor: Bayliffes and Conservators shall not within the said forty Dayes releive the said
Parties grived or if the said Parties shall not bee satisfied with the Determina&bhocotil;n of the said Governor Bayliffes
and Conservators That then the [said<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Parties may appeale unto S<emph type="p">r</emph>. Henry North Barr<emph type="p">t</emph>: S<emph type="p">r</emph> Levinus Bennett Barronett
S<emph type="p">r</emph>: Robert Brooke of Yoxford Knight S<emph type="p">r</emph>: Edmond Pooley Knight Henry Williams Robert Apreece, Richard Nailer
Houmphrey Orme, Morris Tresham Lawrence Oxborough Henry Farer junior Edward Barber Mathew Wren Thomas
Marsh Henry Hitch D[oct]o<emph type="p">r</emph>: of Lawes Thomas Steward Anthony Fisher Mathias Tayler John Towers Esquires and
Burrage Martin Gent or any three or more of them who are hereby constituted and appointed Comission[er]s of
Appeale to heare and determine such Complaints and to give Relief therein as they shall see cause and to award
Costs to either Parties as they shall see cause the which said Costs may bee recovered by Ac&bhocotil;n of Debt in
any of his Majesties Courts of Record at Westmr: wherein noe Essoigne or Wager of Law shall bee [allowed
which said Appeales to the C&bhooov;missio shall be<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] duely prosecuted by the said Parties grieved within two Moneths
next after the Expira&bhocotil;n: of the forty Dayes and not at any tyme after, The which [said<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Schedules with the
Altera&bhocotil;ns if any shall be made by the said Corpora&bhocotil;n wherew<emph type="p">th</emph>: The Parties shall rest satisfied or by the Determinacion
of the said Co[mmissioner]s of Appeale are hereby confirmed and shall bee a constant Rule and Founda&bhocotil;n for the rateing
and taxeing of the said eighty three thousand Acres for the Future for Maintenance and Preserva&bhocotil;n of the Works,
made and to bee made within or without the said Great Levell of. the Fe&ntilde;s And that the said Governor: Bayliffes
and Conservators nor their Successors nor any of them shall taxe or assesse the said eighty three thousand Acres
otherwise then by and according to the said Schedules to be returned or confirmed as aforesaid, And it is declared
That the said twelve thousand Acres Residue of the said nynety five thousand Acres shall bee rated and taxed by
a Medium towards all Taxes hereafter to be laid, as by the said Taxe made the said twentieth Day of June is
provided, and not otherwise</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Tax of &pound;6,110. 7s. 1&frac12;d. laid on the 83,000 Acres according to gradual Acre Tax.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Sales for Non-payment when to be made</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That a Taxe of the said S&bhouov;me of Six thousand one hundred and tenn pounds
seaven shillings one penny halfe penny shall and may bee sett by the said Governor; Bayliffes and Conservators
or any five or more of them in Whitson weeke next upon the said eighty three thousand Acres according to the
said graduell Acre Taxe of five Degrees upon the said twelve thousand Acres at fifteene pence &bhopubr; Acre and for
Non payment shall and may be levied by Sales on Wednesday Thursday or Friday, after the sayd first Sunday in
Aprill then next following and that from thenceforth all future Taxes shall be laid and imposed upon the said
eighty three thousand Acres by a graduall [Acre<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Taxe not under seaven Degrees and twelve thousand Acres
in such Manner and Forme as by this A&bholigct; is provided and not otherwise</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Recital that Samuel Sandys the elder had a Right to a Conveyance of certain Shares of Sir Miles Sandys the elder and others under an Indenture of 12th June, 1 Car. II.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">15 Car. II. c. 17; The said Shares vested in Samuel Sandys and Edwin Sandys, Sons of the said Samuel Sandys the elder, free from Taxes to the Time of passing this Act; but liable to Debts, Jurisdictions and future Taxes, as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And whereas S<emph type="p">r</emph>. Myles Sandys the Elder and S<emph type="p">r</emph> Miles Sandys the Younger were Adventurers and Participants
with Francis late Earle of Bedford in the said Levell, and had an Interest in severall Shares Lotts and Propor&bhocotil;ns
in the said Great Levell, the Right Title and Interest in great Part of which said Shares and Lotts were as appeares
by Indenture beareing Date the twelveth Day of June in the first Yeare of his now Majesties Raigne, made
betweene S<emph type="p">r</emph>. Miles Sandys the Younger of the one Part, and Thomas Sandys Esquire and Robert Sandys Clerke,
Humberston Marsh Esquire Samuell Spalding Gent William Wolson Clerke, and John Kirke of the second Part,
and Samuell Sandys of Ombersley Es&bhoqesq;. on the third Parte, setled in severall Trustees therein named in Trust for
the Payment of all such Taxes as should be due, for or in respe&bholigct; of the said Lands menc&bhocotil;ed in the said Indenture,
and after in Trust for the secureing of the said Samuell Sandys Es&bhoqesq; from all such Debts as hee the said Samuell
Sandys stood engaged for the proper Debts of the said S<emph type="p">r</emph>. Miles Sandys the Elder, and S<emph type="p">r</emph>. Miles Sandys the
Younger, since which said Indenture soe had and made the said Samuell Sandys the Elder has paid great S&bhouov;mes
of Money for and towards the Satisfact&bhocotil;n of the said Debts of S<emph type="p">r</emph> Myles Sandys the Elder, and S<emph type="p">r</emph>. Miles Sandys
the Younger, and yett hath reaped noe Benefitt by vertue of the said Deed of Trust [soe<emph type="p">r</emph>] as aforesaid made
for his Security although by an A&bholigct; made by this present Parliament, entituled An A&bholigct; for setling the dreining
of the Great Levell of the Fenns called Bedford Levell, the said Samuell Sandys ought to have had a Conveyance
of the Shares and Lotts menc&bhocotil;ed in the said Indenture, but in. regard the said Samuell Sandys Esquire nor any
in Trust for him could procure any Conveyance which hath proved very prejudiciall to the said Samuell Sandys
the Elder, Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie, the Lords Spirituall and Temporall, and
[the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] C&bhooov;ons in this present Parliament assembled [and by Authority of the same<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] That all the said Lotts
and Shares in the said Indenture menc&bhocotil;ed [except only such Lands of the said Halfe Share as were really sold
by S<emph type="p">r</emph> Miles Sands y<emph type="p">e</emph> Elder or S<emph type="p">r</emph>. Miles Sands the Younger for full &amp; valuable Considera&bhocotil;ns<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] and such of the
said [two Shares which have<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] been sould for the Payment of Taxes [or Debts<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] in pursuance of the said Indenture
by the said [S<emph type="p">r</emph>. Miles Sandys and the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Trustees Partyes [to<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the said Indenture are hereby vested and settled in
Samuell Sandys the Younger Esquire and Edwyn Sandys Gent Sonnes of the said Samuell Sandys the Elder their
Heires, and Assignes [freed and discharged from all Manner of Taxes whatsoever to the time of the passing this
A&bholigct;<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] And by the Authority aforesaid the Freehold and Inheritance of the said Lot&bhotcrl; and Shares aforesaid [except
before excepted<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] shall bee deemed and adjudged to bee in the said Samuell Sandys the Younger and Edwyn Sandys,
theire Heires and Assignes for ever, neverthelesse the said Shares and Lott&bhotcrl; hereby vested shall bee liable to [the
Payment of the Debts aforesaid and to all Powers and Jurisdi&bhocotil;ns togeather with the Residue of the said nynety
five thousand Acres as the same are subje&bholigct; &amp; lyable by the said recited A&bholigct; for the future and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of all such
Taxes and Penalties as shall be hereafter assessed or laid for the Preserva&bhocotil;n of the said Great Levell in such
Sort and Manner as the eighty three thousand Acres Parcell of the nynety five thousand Acres shall be assessed
and taxed, Any Law Statute or Thing to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Sales for Non-payment of Taxes of those Lands void;</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">15 Car. II, c. 17; and the Lands sold (Exception) vested in the said Samuel and Edwin; Sandys</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">Provided alsoe and it is hereby further declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every
[of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the Sale or Sales made [agreed or contracted for, for Non payment of Taxes<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of any of the Lands of the
said S<emph type="p">r</emph>. Miles Sandys the Elder or S<emph type="p">r</emph>. Miles Sandys the Younger, or the said Samuell Sandys the Elder Es&bhoqesq; by the
Governors Bayliffes and Conservato<emph type="p">ts</emph>. constituted and elle&bholigct;ed by Authority of an Act of this present Parliament
intituled An Act for settling the dreyneing of the Great Levell of the Fenns called Bedford Levell to any Person or
Persons whatsoever by vertue or colour of the said A&bholigct; is are and shall bee null and void, and that the said
Lands sould by the said Governors Bayliffes and Conservators [except before excepted<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] are and shall bee vested
and settled by this present A&bholigct; in the said Samuell Sandys the younger and Edwyn Sandys their Heires and
Assignes freed and discharged of and from all Taxes laid by the said Governors Bayliffes and Conservato
Any Thing in the said recited Act to the contrary not&bhowssth; standing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Sergeant at Mace, by virtue of Precept under Corporation Seal, may remove; Occupants not paying Taxes, and deliver Possession to the said Samuel Sandys the younger and Edwin Sandys</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">And to the end the said Samuell Sandys and Edwin Sandys may have the Effe&bholigct; and Benefitt hereby intended
them and that the Occupiers and Possessors of the said Shares and Lotts vested in them the said Samuell Sandys
and Edwyn Sandys as aforesaid may not by their continueing in Possession and Negle&bholigct; of payeing the Taxes
hereafter to be imposed on the said Shares and Lotts or any Part of them cause the same to be forfeited and
sold for Non payment of the respe&bholigct;ive Taxes that shall become due for the same. Bee it therefore hereby
further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That in case any Occupier [or<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Possessor of any the said Shares
or Lotts in the said Deed of Trust menc&bhocotil;ed as aforesaid or of any Part of them pretending to clayme under
the said Shares or Lotts to them the said Sedwyn Sandys and Edwyn Sandys or there Assignes and shall not
the said Shares or Lotts to them the said Samuell Sandys and Edwyn Sandys or their Assignes and shall not
duely pay the Taxes hereafter to be imposed on the same before our Lady day one thousand six hundred seaventy
one, That then the Serjant at Mace for the tyme being attending the said Corpora&bhocotil;n: is hereby authorized and
impowred by Precept under the Seale of the, Corpora&bhocotil;n of the said Great Levell (who are hereby required to graunt
and issue out the same) in the Nature of a Writt of Habere facias possessionem at the Common Lawe to deliver
unto and put them the said Samuell Sandys and Edwyn Sandys their Heires or Assignes in the quiet and peaceable
Possession of such Shares and Lot&bhocent; or any Part of them, and all and every such Occupier or Occupiers Possessor
or Possessors thereof, of and from the same to eje&bholigct; expell and amove They the said Samuell Sandys and Edwyn
Sandys upon reasonable Notice first payeing or tendering such Taxes as shall become due for the same from the
Tyme of the passing this A&bholigct; one Moneth before the next Day of Sale for Non payment of such Taxes hereafter
to be imposed, which said Samuell Sandys and Edwyn Sandys and their Heires are thereupon hereby a&bholigct;ually
vested in the same;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Recital that, by the Refusal of the Corporation to convey the said Lands, Rents had accrued due.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">The said Samuel Sandys and Edwin Sandys declared entitled thereto, and the several Occupiers to pay the same; to be recovered by the said Samuel and Edwin Sandys</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And whereas the said severall Shares and Lotts of the said nynety five thousand Acres herein before vested
and setled in the said Samuell Sandys the Younger and Edwyn Sandys and their Heires as aforesaid ought to
have been conveyed unto the said Samuell Sandy the Elder or his Trustees by the said Governor Bayliffes and
Conservators of the said Corpora&bhocotil;n by virtue of the said before men&bhocotil;ed Act, as in and by the same they were
required and dire&bholigct;ed which they refused to doe, whereby the Rents Issues and Profitts thereof have not been paid
to, nor could bee received by the said Samuell Sandys the elder or his Trustees or by any other by to or for
his or their Use Bee it therefore hereby further enacted by the Authority aforesaid, That the said Samuell
Sandys and Edwyn Sandys shall and are hereby intituled to the said Rents Issues and Profitts of the said Shares
and Lot&bhotcrl; since the passing of the said recited A&bholigct; which have not really been paid to the said Corpora&bhocotil;n for
Taxes or to the said Samuell Sandys the Elder and the Occupiers and Possessers thereof, are hereby appointed
to pay the same accordingly, and in default of Payment thereof or of any prete thereof they the said Samuell
Sandys and Edwyn Sandys are hereby authorized and impowered to sue for and by virtue of this A&bholigct; shall recover
the same wherein noe Esoigne Prote&bhocotil;n or Wager of Law shall be allowed, and shall likewise have their Costs
of Suite expended therein Any thing herein to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Who are to pay thereout Arrears of the said gradual Acre Tax.</head>
			<para id="p23">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed That after the said Edwyn and Samuell Sandys shall have recovered and
received Satisfa&bhocotil;n for the meane Profitts or any &bhopubr;te of them, That then they their Heires and Assignes shall
pay soe much of the [said<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Arreares of the said graduall Acre Tax imposed upon the said respe&bholigct;ive Lands
propor&bhocotil;nably to what they shall receive and noe more.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Proviso for Thomas Lord Culpeper.</head>
			<para id="p24">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That whereas severall Parcells of the said
ninety five thousand Acres ought to have beene conveyed to Thomas Lord Culpeper or his Trustees by the said
Governour Bayliffes and Conservators of the said Corpora&bhocotil;n by vertue of the said before recited A&bholigct; as in and
by the same, they were required and dire&bholigct;ed, which they delayed to doe, whereby the Rents, Issues, and Proffitts
thereof have not beene paid to, nor could be received by the said Thomas Lord Culpeper or his Trustees, that
the said Thomas Lord Culpeper and his Trustees shall and are hereby entituled to the said Rents Issues and
Proffitts of the said Parcells since the passeing the said recited A&bholigct;, which have not beene really paid to the
Corpora&bhocotil;n for Taxes or to him or them, and the Occupiers and Possessors thereof are hereby required to pay
the same accordingly, and in Default of Payment thereof or any Parte therof he the said Thomas Lord Culpeper
and his Trustees are hereby authorized and impowered to sue for, and by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall recover the
same; wherein noe Essoyne Protec&bhocotil;n or Wager of Law shall be allowed and shall likewise have their Costs of
Suite. expended herein, Any thing to the contrary hereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>ITEM queda Peti&bhocotil;nes privatas personas concernentes (in se formam A&bholigct;us continentes) exhibite fuerunt &bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o Domino
Regi in Parliamento &bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o quarum Tituli subscribuntur.</head>
			<para id="p25">PRIVATE ACTS</para>
			<para id="p26">1. An Act for setling part of the Possessions of John late Earle of Clare deceased and enabling Gilbert Earle
of Clare his Son and Heire to dispose of some other part thereof for payment of debts &amp; portions</para>
			<para id="p27">2. An Act to enable John Lord Bishop of Durham and his Successours, to make Leases for three lives of certain
Lead Mines.</para>
			<para id="p28">3. An Act for confirmation of an Exchange of certain Lands between Horatio Lord Townsend and the Rector
of East and West Reynham in the County of Norfolk.</para>
			<para id="p29">4. An Act for the naturalization of Alvaro de Costa and others.</para>
			<para id="p30">5. An Act for setling the Lands therein mentioned upon Sir Richard Wiseman and John Plott and their heires
to enable them the better to perform a Trust.</para>
			<para id="p31">6. An Act for exchanging certain Mannors and Lands of William Palmes Esquire for other Lands setled upon
him and his issue by Mary his Wife.</para>
			<para id="p32">7. An Act to indempnifie the late Sheriffs of the City of London and the Warden of the Fleet touching the
Escapes of Prisoners and other matters occasioned by the late Fire</para>
			<para id="p33">8. An Act for the taxing and assessing of the Lands of the Adventurers within the Great Levell of the Fenns</para>
			<para id="p34">9. An Act for setling of certain Mannours Lands and Tenements of Sit Thomas Leventhorp Baronett in the
Counties of Essex &amp; Hertford.</para>
			<para id="p35">10. An Act to enable Sir Thomas Heblethwaite to sell or dispose of Land to pay debts and make provision for
younger Children</para>
			<para id="p36">11. An Act for confirmation of the Settlement of Sir Kingsmill Lucy Baronet in the said A&bholigct; men&bhocotil;ned, &amp; for
transferring over some other parts of the Real Estate of Sir Richard Lucy Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>. &amp; Baronet deceased from Francis
Lucy Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p37">12. An Act to confirm an Agreement between William Paston Es&bhoqesq; Lord of the Mannor of Horton &amp; the
Tennants of the said Mannor for an inclosure of part of the Wastes of the said Mannor for the &bhopcrl;servaci&bhocotil;n &amp;
growth of Wood &amp; Timber.</para>
			<para id="p38">13. An Act for enabling of Sir William Juxon Knight and Baronet Executor of the last Will and Testament of
William Juxon late Lord Arch Bishop of .Canterbury to recover part of his Estate</para>
			<para id="p39">14. An Act for the better securing of a portion of 5000.<ref idref="n5">5</ref> to &amp; for the Lady Frances Savile an infant daughter
of Thomas late Earle of Sussex deceased out of part of the Estate of James Earle of Sussex also an infant in
pursuance of the Will of the said Thomas Earl of Sussex.</para>
			<para id="p40">15. An Act on the behalfe of Dawes Wimondseld Es&bhoqesq; for selling certaine customary Lands held of the Mannor
of Wimbleton in the County of Surry.</para>
			<para id="p41">16. An Act to enable the Execution of a Trust for payment of the debts &amp; providing for the younger Children
of Richard Tayler Es&bhoqesq; deceased.</para>
			<para id="p42">17. An Act for enabling Trustees to make Leases for payment of the debts &amp; providing for the Children of
Sir Charles Stanley.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">From the Original A&bholigct; in the Parliament Office.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


