<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47402" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1667 &amp; 1668</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act for the better Payment of Moneys received for the Use of the Crown [Rot. Parl. 19 &amp; 20 C. II. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Monies received for the King's Use and not paid into the Exchequer 1st July 1668; Interest at &pound;12. per Cent. per Ann. till Principal paid.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">For some remedy of the great abuses by Receivers Reeves Bailiffs Colle&bholigct;ors and other Officers and persons
not making due payment of Moneys and Duties received for his Majesties use and in detaining the same in
theire owne hands for theire private lucre and advantage Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majesty by
and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the authority of the same That all the said Officers and Ministers aforesaid doe use all diligence
to receive and gather the moneys due to his Majesty within theire several and respe&bholigct;ive. Receipts and Colle&bholigct;ions
and after the receipt thereof to answer and pay the same according to theire respe&bholigct;ive Duties And that all and
every the person and persons aforesaid whoe having received the said moneys have not duely accompted and
thereupon paid so much as by such accompt rested due to his Majesty into the Receipt of the Exchequer or to
such person or persons and in such manner as the same ought to be paid and shall not pay the same as aforesaid
before the first day of July which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty eight
shall from henceforth answer and pay to his Majesty Damages after the rate of Twelve pounds per Cen&bhocent; by the
yeare untill the principal moneys be fully accompted for and paid in togeather with such Damages as aforesaid
which shall be charged upon them in theire accompt whereof they shall not be discharged until payment made
as well of the said Damages as principal moneys according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct;</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Bodies Politic and Corporate not accounting for and paying Monies due, according to the Course of the Exchequer, to pay Interest at &pound;12 per Cent. per Ann. till Principal paid.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Process to be awarded</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And further That all and every person and persons Bodies Politique and Corporate who having received
any Moneys or Duties due to the Kings Majesty shall not duly accompt for and pay the same according to the
course of the Exchequer into the Receipt there or to such person or persons to whom the same ought to be
paid according to Law within two moneths next after the same shall have been so received shall from thenceforth
answer and pay to the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors Damages for all such Moneys and Duties after
the rate of Twelve pounds per Cen&bhocent; by the yeare for soe long time as the same shall be detained or not paid
by the judgement and dire&bholigct;ion of the Court of Exchequer without any power of abatement or installment to be
made or allowed for the same or any part thereof And that the processe of the said Court shall be forthwith
awarded against all the said persons Bodies Politique and Corporate theire Heires Executors and Administrators
chargeable with any of the said moneys for the speedy and effe&bholigct;uall levying thereof with Damages for the same
as aforesaid according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; Any other Law Statute Usage Priviledge or Pretence
whatsoever to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Sheriffs Accounts of the ancient Revenue.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwaies That no thing herein contained shall extend to alter the time or way of accompting of any
Sheriffe within this Kingdome for any part of his Majesties ancient Revenue or other Profits anciently colle&bholigct;ed or
accompted for by the Sheriffs or to make them lyable to any new Penalty for the same.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


