<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47401" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1667 &amp; 1668</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) An Act for raising Three hundred and ten thousand pounds by an Imposition on Wines and other Liquors. [Rot. Parl. 19 &amp; 20 C. II. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Imposition upon Retailers of Wines, Brandies, Spirits, and Strong Waters.</head>
		<para id="p1">The Commons assembled in Parliament for the supply of your Majesties present Occasions have given and
granted and by these Presents doe give and graunt unto your most excellent Majestie the S&bhouov;m of Three
hundred and ten thousand pounds to be raised and levied upon the vending and retailing of Wines and other the
Liquors hereafter mentioned in manner following and doe most humbly beseech your Majesty that it may be
ena&bholigct;ed and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majesty by and with the advice and consent of the Lords
Spiritual and Temporal and [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>
] the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authoritie of the
same That all Vintners Taverners Wine Coopers Merchants or any other person or persons who do or shall utter
or sell by way of Retaile any French Wines Spanish Wines or other Wines whatsoever between the four and
twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred sixty eight and the four and twentieth day of June which shall
be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and seaventy And alsoe all and every the Strong water men
Distillers and all and every other person and persons which do or shall utter or sell by way of Retail any imported
Brandies or other Spirits and alsoe Strong waters [either or any of them &amp; alsoe all Brandies or other Spirits and
alsoe Strong waters<ref idref="n1">1</ref>
] any or either of them made of Wine or Lees of Wine or any other Materials imported
between the Four and twentieth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty eight and
the Four and twentieth day of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and
seventy shall yeild and pay unto your Majesty the Rates and Duties herein after following that is to say</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">French Wine 4d. per Quart</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">All and every the Retailers of Wine shall yeild and pay for every Quart of any French Wine by them retailed
within the time aforesaid the S&bhouov;m of Four pence by the Quart and so after that Rate for any greater or lesser
quantity</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Spanish Wine 6d. per Quart</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p5">And alsoe for every Quart of any Spanish Wines or of any other Wines whatsoever by them retailed within the
time aforesaid the S&bhouov;m of Six-pence by the Quart and so after that Rate for any greater or lesser quantity</para>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">Spirits 12d. per Quart</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p7">And all and every the Strong water men Distillers and other Retailers or first Buyers of all Brandy and other
Spirits and alsoe all Strong waters imported shall yeild and pay for every Quart of any the Liquors aforesaid by
them retailed within the time aforesaid the Su[m]m of Twelve pence and so after that Rate for a greater or lesser
quantity</para>
		<para id="p8">And alsoe all and every the Distillers of Spirits made of Wine or Lees of Wine or other Materials imported
shall yeild and pay for every Quart of the first Extra&bholigct;ion so distilled and made and by them retailed within the
time aforesaid the S&bhouov;m of Twelve pence per Quart and so after that Rate for a greater or lesser quantity</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. What shall be taken for Strong Water or Brandy imported.</head>
			<para id="p9">And for the better prevention of Frauds Be it further enacted That all sorts of Strong waters of the first or
any other Extra&bholigct;ion made in England of English Materials which shall be mingled with Brandy or other Spirits
or with any Strong waters imported or Spirits made in England of Wine or Lees of Wine imported shall be
deemed and taken for Strong water or Brandy imported and shall pay after the Rate of Twelve [pence
<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] per Quart
as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Merchants not to sell Wine, &amp;c. to any but Retailers.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Proviso.; Penalty. and such Wine may be seized, unless Certificate of Duty paid. ; Who shall be deemed a Retailer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That no Merchant Importer of Wine do or shall att any
time between the said Four and twentieth day of June One thousand fix hundred sixty eight and the Four and
twentieth day of June One thousand six hundred and seventy utter or sell any Wine in greater or lesser quantityes
to any person or persons other then such as sell Wine by way of Retail unlesse such Merchant or Importer before
the delivery of the Wine do or shall pay unto the Commissioners for execution of this A&bholigct; so much Money for
his Majesties use as the Duties of Wine sold or delivered would have amounted unto in case the same had been
uttered or sold by way of Retail upon pain of forfeiture of double the value of the Wine so sold and delivered
one moiety to his Majesty the other moyety thereof to such person or persons as do or shall sue for the same
And all Wine delivered by the Merchant Importer within the time aforesaid to any but Retailers shall and may
[be lawfully
<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] seized as aforesaid unlesse such Merchant before the delivery thereof shall obtain a Certificate under
the Hands and Seales of the Commissioners for Execution of this A&bholigct; or any two of them that the Duty hath
been paid and satisfied as aforesaid And it is hereby declared That all and every person and persons other then
the Merchant Importer who shall utter or sell any manner of Wine shall be adjudged a Retailer within the meaning
of this A&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The Prices of Wine sold by Retail.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Proviso as to French Wines</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And for the better enabling the several and respe&bholigct;ive Retailers aforesaid to pay the Duties hereby imposed
It shall and may be lawfull to and for every Retailer of Wine during the time aforesaid to ask demaund and
receive of all and every theire Customers to whom they shall utter or sell by way of Retail or otherwise any
French Wines Spanish Wines or other Wines the S&bhouov;m of Four pence for every Quart of French Wine by them
retailed uttered or sold over and above the Price at which the said Wine ought to have been sold if this Act had
not been made and soe after that Rate for a greater or lesser quantity and alsoe the S&bhouov;m of Six pence for every
Quart of Spanish Wines or any (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) Wines whatsoever soe retailed uttered or sold over and above the Price att which
the said Wine ought to have beene sold if this Act had not beene made and soe after that Rate for a greater or
lesser quantity Provided that no French Wines shall be sold above the Rate of Twelve pence the Quart nor any
Spanish Wines above the Rate of Twoe shillings the Quart the addi&bhocotil;nall Duty being included.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Retailers forthwith to give an account to the Commissioners of Stock on Hand, and so from time to time of all Additions thereto.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Not to vend Wines, &amp;c. till Duty paid, or Security; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That from and after the Foure and twentieth day of June
One thousand six hundred sixty eight all &amp; every the Retaylers of Wines or other the Liquors chargeable as
aforesaid during the continuance of this A&bholigct; being thereunto required by the C&bhooov;missioners authorized to execute
this A&bholigct; shall forthwith deliver unto the said Commissioners within such Place or &bhopcrl;cin&bholigct; where such Retailer shall
dwell a true account of what Wines or other the Liquors chargeable as aforesaid he or any person in trust for
him have in store and shall not att any time afterward during the time aforesaid receive take in or make any
new or other store of any the Wines or Liquors aforesaid without first giving a particular account thereof in
Writing under his hand to the said C&bhooov;missioners nor shall vend utter or sell any French Spanish or other Wines
or any the Liquors aforesaid before he shall have paid or given Security by his owne Bond for the payment of
the respe&bholigct;ive Duties imposed by this A&bholigct; for all such Wines or other the Liquors aforesaid which shall be then
in his custody the same to be paid within twelve moneths next ensuing the Date of such Bond by four equall
quarterly payments upon pain of forfeiture of double the value of all such Wines and other the Liquors aforesaid
as shall be found in his custody which shall not be so certified or whereof the Duty shall not be secured as
aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Commissioners may grant Warrants to search.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Retailers to permit Search; Hours when Search to be made; Retailer opposing Search; Justice, &amp;c. may issue Warrant to enter.; Doors to be broke open upon Refusal, and Seizure made. Constables, &amp;c. to assist</emph>.
</para>
			<para id="p17">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the Commissioners to be appointed for execution of
this A&bholigct; or so many of them as shall be appointed of the Quorum shall have power to appoint any one or
more persons as to them shall seeme meet by Warrant under theire Hands and Seales to enter into the Cellars
Vaults Storehouses Warehouses Store-cellars Shops Roomes or other places belonging to every or any such
Retailer to search see and take an account of what quantity of Wines or other the Liquors chargeable as
aforesaid every or any such person hath in his hands or any other person to his use And all and every such
Retailers in whose Cellars Vaults Store cellars Warehouses or other Roomes or places any the Wines or Liquors
aforesaid of any such Retailer are or shall be lodged are hereby required and enjoyned quietly to permitt and
suffer the said Officers to enter into theire several and respe&bholigct;ive Cellars Vaults Store cellars Warehouses Shops
Roomes and other places and there to search see and take account of as aforesaid Provided That no search be made or
required to be made without the consent of the Owner but betwixt Sun rising, and Sun setting And in case any
such Retailer shall refuse oppose or resist the persons appointed to search as aforesaid or shall not discover
declare or shew to them all such Cellars Vaults Store cellars Ware houses Shops Roomes or other places wherein
he or they have any Wines or other the Liquors aforesaid lying or remaining for theire use that then upon Oath
thereof made before the Mayor or other cheife Magistrate of any City Borough or Town corporate or any Justice
of the Peace of the County City or Place where such Offence shall be committed (which Oath they are hereby
authorised and required to administer) it shall and may be lawfull to and for any such cheife Magistrate or Justice
of the Peace and they are hereby required to issue out a Warrant to the person or persons so complaining thereby
to enable him or them with the assistance of a Constable or other like Officer of the Place where such offence
shall be committed to enter in the day time into the House or Houses of any such Retailer or into any other
Room Cellar or place which att any time during the continuance of this A&bholigct; shall be in such Retailers Occupation
for the laying in of Wines or other the Liquors aforesaid And in case of resistance to breake open any Doores and
to search for any Wines or the Liquors aforesaid soe concealed or not discovered and to seize and secure the
same And all Constables and other Officers aforesaid are hereby authorized and required to be aiding and assisting
thereunto</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Retailer to give Notice of Wines taken in.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.; Officers to make Returns of Search.; Penalty.; Incapacity</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And to the end no person whatsoever may defraud his Majesty of the Duty intended by this A&bholigct; by concealing
the Wines or other Liquors thereby charged belonging to any person by this A&bholigct; declared a Retailer Be it further
ena&bholigct;ed That if any person or persons shall knowingly have or take [into<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] any Ware house Cellar or other place in
his or theire possession any of the Wines or other Liquors chargeable by this A&bholigct; belonging to any Retailer
without giving notice thereof under his or theire hands respe&bholigct;ively within two dayes after the same shall be in
his or theire custody aswell of the place where the said Wines or other Liquors aforesaid are lodged as of the
quantity and kind of Wines or other Liquors to the best of his or theire knowledge so in his or theire custody
unto the Commissioners appointed to execute this A&bholigct; some or one of them In every such case the person or
persons so offending shall forfeit and lose the full value of the Wines that he or they shall so conceal without
giving notice as aforesaid And all and every person and persons appointed to view and search as aforesaid shall
make theire Returns in Writing under theire Hands unto the Commissioners for execution of this A&bholigct; and shall
first deliver a Duplicate thereof to the person or persons concerned containing the Names of the persons viewed
and searched and the quantity of the respe&bholigct;ive Liquors aforesaid by him found and discovered to them belonging
at such time and place as in and by the Warrant or Warrants to him or them dire&bholigct;ed shall be limited and
appointed on pain of forfeiture for every such negle&bholigct; of double the value of the Wines or other Liquors aforesaid
by him not returned as aforesaid and of being made uncapable of executing the same or any other Office of
Trust whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. The Commissioners may summon and examine upon Oath.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Persons summoned refusing to appear.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Commissioners
for execution of this present A&bholigct; or so many of them as shall be of the Quorum within the Place or Precin&bholigct;
where such Retailer shall dwell by Warrant under theire Hands and Seales to send for and summon such person
and persons as they in theire discretions shall thinke fitt other then the party himselfe and the persons so
summoned to examine upon his or theire corporal Oaths touching the matters and things contained in this A&bholigct;
relating to the Retailers or Merchant Importers aforesaid And if any person or persons so as aforesaid summoned
shall refuse to appeare or appearing shall refuse to be examined That then and in such case all and every
person and persons so as aforesaid refusing to appeare or to be examined shall for every such refusall forfeit
such s&bhouov;m as shall be imposed upon him or them not exceeding Five pounds by the said Commissioners</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Commissioners to appoint Collectors, and Monies to be paid into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">When the Duty to cease.; Proviso for levying Arrears.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p23">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Commissioners appointed by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall and may appoint under
theire Hands and Seales such and soe many Colle&bholigct;ors of whom they shall take good Security in every County
City and Place as they shall thinke fitt to receive the Moneys arising by this A&bholigct; and all and every the s&bhouov;ms of
money so as aforesaid colle&bholigct;ed or levied shall be paid into his Majesties Receipt of Exchequer or unto such
person or persons as his Majestie shall appoint within thirty dayes after the receipt thereof And the Commissioners
for execution of this A&bholigct; shall cause Duplicates to be made of all Entries made in pursuance of this A&bholigct; and
of all moneys payed or payable thereupon and the same to be returned to the Lord Treasurer or C&bhooov;missio?s of
the Treasury for the time being once every Quarter to the end that by the view and examination of such Returns
it may appeare when the S&bhouov;m of Three hundred and ten thousand pounds togeather with such Interest as shall
grow due for moneys lent and advanced upon the Creditt of this A&bholigct; att the rate of Six pounds per Cen&bhocent; for one
yeare will be satisfied and discharged and that from and after the Foure and twentieth day of June One thousand
six hundred and seventy all power of requiring any new Entries or charging any Retailer or others by vertue of
this A&bholigct; shall cease and determine Saving neverthelesse to his Majesty his Heires &amp; Successors the power of
levying any arrearages of the Rates Duties Fines or Forfeitures before that time grown due or imposed by vertue
of this A&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Proviso for Retailers travelling in obedience to Act.</head>
			<para id="p24">Provided alwayes and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That no Retailer chargeable by this
A&bholigct; nor any other person or persons who shall be summoned by the Commissioners for the execution of this
A&bholigct; in manner aforesaid and for any the ends or purposes aforesaid shall be obliged to travel beyond ten miles
from his common and usuall place of abode</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Repayment of Duty upon Exportation.</head>
			<para id="p25">Provided alsoe That if any Retailer of any Strong waters imported Brandy or other Spirits herein before
charged shall export into Forreign Parts any such Strong waters Brandy or other Spirits so as aforesaid charged
and shall before the Shipping out or Lading on board of such Strong waters Brandy or other Spirits make Oath
before the Commissioners for execution of this Act or so many of them as shall be of the Quorum That the
said Strong waters Brandy or other Spirits soe intended to be exported are such for which the rate of Twelve
pence a Quart hath beene formerly paid and unmingled with any Waters made of English Materials which Oath
the said Commissioners or so many as shall be of the Quorum have hereby power to administer that then and in such
case there shall be [re<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]paid unto every such Retailer at the time of such Exportation the whole Duty of Twelve
pence per Quart by him formerly paid Any thing herein before contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Merchant Importer selling contrary to A&bholigct;; or asking Reward, &amp;c. exceeding the due Price.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;20.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p27">And to the end that all and every the Retailers of Wine may be the better enabled to carry on their Trade
and to pay and satisfie all and every the Duties imposed Be it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any Merchant Importer
from and after the said foure and twentieth day of June during the continuance of this A&bholigct; shall utter or sell
any Wine to any Retailer or other person (other then such person who shall export the same) and shall dire&bholigct;ly
or indire&bholigct;ly ask demand or receive of or from such person any s&bhouov;m of Money Gift or other Reward exceeding
the Price at which the same ought by Law to be sold That then and in such case every [such<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Merchant Importer
shall forfeit and lose for every Tun of Wine soe unduly sold and uttered as aforesaid the s&bhouov;m of Twentie pounds
and soe after that rate for a greater or lesser quantity</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. How Penalties to be recovered and divided.</head>
			<para id="p28">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That one moyety of all and every the penalties and s&bhouov;ms of money herein before
appointed to be forfeited shall be forfeited unto the Kings Majesty and the other moyetie unto such person or
persons as shall or will sue for the same and shall and may be sued for in any Court of Record and recovered
by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information wherein no Essoyn Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed nor
any more then one Imparlance</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Commissioners to take an Oath.</head>
			<para id="p29">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That all and every the Commissioners to be appointed
[for execu&bhocotil;n of this A&bholigct; shall before they intermeddle with<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] the execution of this A&bholigct; or any other part of theire
Commission take an Oath before two or more of his Majesties Justices of the Peace in the County where such
Commission is to be executed or before one of the Barons of the Exchequer which Oath he or they have power
to administer in these words.</para>
			<para id="p30">You shall swear well and truly to execute the Place of a Commissioner for execution of an A&bholigct; intituled An
A&bholigct; for raising of Three hundred and ten thousand pounds by an Imposition on Wines and other Liquors and
therein you shall spare no person for favour or affe&bholigct;ion nor any person greive for hatred or ill will
So helpe you God.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. And the Officers also;</head>
			<para id="p31">And all and every person and persons to be imployed by the Commissioners for execution of this A&bholigct; shall
before they execute such theire Employment take an Oath before the Commissioners for execution of this A&bholigct; or
any twoe of them which Oath they have hereby power to administer in these words.</para>
			<para id="p32">You shall sweare well and truly to demean your selfe in the execution of the Warrants to you dire&bholigct;ed in
pursuance of an A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for raising Three hundred and ten thousand pounds by an Imposition
on Wines or other Liquors You shall spare no person for favour or affe&bholigct;ion nor any person greive for hatred
or ill will 
So helpe you God.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Commissioners to be appointed by the King under the Great Seal.</head>
			<para id="p33">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for his Majestie
from time to time during the continuance of this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; by Commissions to be therefore issued under his
Majesties Great Seale of England to nominate and appoint such persons as his Majestie shall thinke fitt to be
Commissioners for putting in execution this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; and all and every the powers and authorities to such
Commissioners respe&bholigct;ively limited and appointed and alsoe to appoint such or so many of them to be a
Quorum as his Majesty shall thinke fitt</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. To prevent the Duties being twice charged. Retailer paying or securing Duties to have Certificate thereof from Commissioners without Fee.</head>
			<para id="p34">And to the end that no sorts of Wines or Strong Waters mentioned in this A&bholigct; shall be twice charged with
the Duties imposed by this A&bholigct; or any part thereof (though it may happen to passe through the hands of
several Retailers) Be it further ena&bholigct;ed That wheresoever any Retailer shall sell any the Liquors aforesaid to
any other person retailing the same every such Retailer shall before the delivery thereof pay or secure the Duty
due for the same by vertue of this A&bholigct; or make Oath the same hath beene formerly paid or secured and take a
Certificate under the Hands and Seales of the Commissioners or any two of them of the payment or securing
thereof Which Oath and Certificate the Commissioners or any two of them are hereby authorized and required
to administer and give without Fee or Reward which said Certificate shall be a sufficient Discharge to the Buyer
for retailing the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Persons taking false Oath, Perjury.</head>
			<para id="p35">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any person or persons to whom by authority of
this A&bholigct; an Oath shall be administred shall wilfully and falsely forsweare him or her selfe such wilfull and false
forsweareing shall be taken and adjudged for wilfull Perjury and such person or persons shall and may be
proceeded against in such manner to all intents and purposes as by the Lawes and Statutes of this Realm in cases
of Perjury is provided and appointed and shall suffer and incur (upon Conviction) like paines and penalties as
by the said Lawes and Statutes are appointed to be infli&bholigct;ed and imposed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. A Tenth Part allowed for Lees, Leakage, &amp;c. Retailer to make Entries.</head>
			<para id="p36">And whereas the severall sorts of Vessels or Caske wherein Wines are imported are of different and uncertain
Gage and Content and that the Retailers of Wine by reason of Lees Leakage Spillage Bottomes and Decayes of
Wine and other Waste cannot be &bhopcrl;sumed to sell or retail so many Quarts of Wine as they must necessarily
enter or be returned att as aforesaid Be it provided and enacted by the authority aforesaid That the Entries
from time to time of all and every the Retailers of Wines and the Returnes of such person or persons as shall
be soe as aforesaid appointed to view search and take accompt of Wines shall be according to the true and just
quantityes of Wines and Lees contained in all and every the severall Vessells and Cask aforesaid And that all
and every the Retailers of Wine having accordingly made true and just Entries of the quantities of theire Wines
and Lees in such Vessells or Cask contained shall for and in respe&bholigct; of Lees Leakage Spillage Bottomes and
Decayes of Wine and other Waste whatsoever have the allowance or abatement of one tenth part Any thing
herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Commissioners to deliver Quarterly Accounts upon Oath to Persons herein named, appointed under c. I. ante.</head>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">What such Accounts to contain.; If the Sum of &pound;310,000 be not fully raised before 24th June 1670, Commissioners to declare to the King and Parliament the Deficiency; and the same to be made up by an additional Duty at the Custom house, as by 12 Car. II. c.4. or any other Act of this Parliament, repaying the Duty on Exportation of the said Wine, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p38">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Commissioners to be appointed by vertue of this A&bholigct; or such other person
or persons as shall be appointed by his Majesty to colle&bholigct; the moneys arising thereupon shall once every
Quarter deliver in a true account in writing under his or theire hands upon theire corporal Oathes unto William
Lord Brereton Baron of Laughtin in the Kingdome of Ireland William Peirpoint Esquire Sir George Savill Baronet
Giles Dunster Esquire Sir James Langham Knight Henry Osborne Esquire Sir William Turner Alderman of the
City of London George Thompson Esquire and John Gregory Esquire or the major part of them Commissioners
appointed by an A&bholigct; of this present Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; for taking the Accompts of several sums of
Money therein mentioned (which Oath the said Commissioners or the major part of them have hereby power to
administer) of all the moneys received or secured by vertue of this A&bholigct; as well for Duty as Penalty with the
persons Names who have soe paid or secured the same as likewise to examine the said Accompts and all persons
concerned in paying or colle&bholigct;ing the same as effe&bholigct;ually to all intents and purposes and in such manner as the
said Commissioners before named have power to do by vertue of the A&bholigct; of Parliament aforesaid in reference to the
accompts in the said A&bholigct; mentioned to the intent it may appeare when the aforesaid S&bhouov;m of Three hundred and
ten thousand pounds with Interest for the same (after the rate of Six pounds per centum which Interest is to be
accounted only from such time as such money shall be lent and paid to his Majesty upon the Credit of this A&bholigct;)
is fully raised or secured to be raised as this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;s And in case the aforesaid S&bhouov;m upon examination of the
said Commissioners before particularly named or the major part of them shall be found not to be fully raised or
secured to be raised by vertue of this A&bholigct; by or before the Foure and twentieth of June which shall be in the
yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and seventy then the said Commissioners before particularly named
or the major part of them that shall bee then living are hereby authorised and required to declare under theire
Hands and Seales unto the Kings Majesty and also to both Houses of Parliament (if then sitting what part of the
aforesaid S&bhouov;m intended to be raised by this Act shall not appeare to be paid or secured to be paid by or on the
said Foure and twentieth of June One thousand six hundred and seventy Then to the end a good and visible
Security may appeare to all persons who shall advance any money as aforesaid on Security of this A&bholigct; Be it
further ena&bholigct;ed That it shall and may be lawfull for his Majesty his Heires and Successors for such time onely
not exceeding one yeare as may raise the money so declared to be behind unpaid or unsecured to be accompted
from the said Four and twentieth day of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
and seventy to receive and take by way of additionall Duty att the Custome house upon all kind of Wines and
other Liquors chargeable by this A&bholigct; the Sum of Four pounds for every Tun that shall be imported within that
yeare (repaying the whole Duty hereby imposed for so much thereof as shall be exported before the Duty hereby
granted shall cease) out of such colle&bholigct;ion of the Duty hereby granted as shall afterwards be made over and
above all Charges Rates and Duties imposed upon them or any of them before this A&bholigct; was made to be raised
and leavied according to such Rules and Powers and with such Allowances as are now appointed by virtue of an
A&bholigct; of this present Parliament intituled A Subsidy granted to the King of Tonnage and Poundage and other
S&bhouov;ms of Money payable upon Merchandise exported and imported Or of any other A&bholigct; of this present Parliament
for the levying and colle&bholigct;ing the Duty upon Wines arising by Customes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. The additional Duty to be accounted for once a Month upon Oath.</head>
			<para id="p39">Provided alwaies and be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Commissioners Customers or such persons as shall be
appointed by his Majesty to receive the said additional Duty of Four pounds per Tun shall once every moneth
give in a true account under theire Hands and Seales upon theire corporal Oaths unto the Commissioners particularly
before named or the major part of them that shall be then living of all the moneys so received or secured to be
received upon the last mentioned additional Duty of Four pounds a Tun hereby charged upon all sorts of Wines
and other Liquors aforesaid which Oath the said Commissioners particularly named or the major part of them
have hereby power to administer) to the end that if the aforesaid S&bhouov;m so declared to be unpaid or unsecured
on the Foure and twentieth of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and
seventy shall be raised or secured to be raised upon the aforesaid additional Duty of Four pounds per Tun in lesse
time then one yeare then and from thenceforth the said additional Duty is to cease and no further to be collected
or demanded or any part thereof by any person or persons whatsoever other then what shall be then secured and
unpaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. When the Commissioners shall signify to the King and Parliament, &amp;c. that the full Money is raised, the Act to determine.</head>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">Treasury on Notice to issue Orders that no further Colle&bholigct;ion be made</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">And that the determination and expiration of this A&bholigct; and all the matters and things therein contained may
clearly appeare to all persons concerned the Commissioners in this A&bholigct; or the major part of them that shall be
then living are hereby authorized and required to take special care that at what time soever they shall find the
moneys mentioned and intended by this A&bholigct; for his Majesties Supply to be fully raised that then they signifie
the same under theire Hands and Seales to the Kings Majesty and alsoe to both Houses of Parliament (if then
sitting) and to the Lord Treasurer or Lords Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being which said Treasurer
or Lords Commissioners of the Treasury are hereby authorized and required to issue out Orders within ten dayes
after such notice and declaration to the Officers imployed and appointed by his Majestie for colle&bholigct;ing the aforesaid
additional Duty of Four pounds per Tun upon all Wines and other Liquors chargeable by this A&bholigct; to the intent
that no person may presume further to colle&bholigct; or demand the, same or any part thereof but that this A&bholigct; and
every clause matter and thing therein contained from the expiration of the said ten dayes shall cease and determine
as if the same had never been made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. The Money raised by this A&bholigct; to be employed in fitting out an extraordinary Fleet.</head>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">Charge of Colle&bholigct;ion not to exceed &pound; 10,000</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That the whole sum of Three hundred and ten thousand pounds granted by
this present A&bholigct;, shall be imployed and issued out of your Majesties Exchequer for defraying the charge and
expence of setting out an extraordinary Fleet to Sea for the yeare One thousand six hundred. sixty eight and for
the pay of such Officers Mariners Seamen and others as shall serve aboard the said Fleet for the- time they shall
serve in the same and shall not be imployed or issued for any other use service or purposes whatsoever charge
of, colle&bholigct;ion and bringing in of the said moneys only excepted which in the whole is not to exceed Ten thousand
pounds. And that to this end all the money arising by this A&bholigct; and paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer shall
be there kept apart and distin&bholigct; from all other moneys paid or payable to your Majesty or to your Heires or
Successors upon any other Branch of your Majesties Revenue or upon any other accompt whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. A distin&bholigct; Registry of Money lent upon the Credit of this A&bholigct; a to be kept in the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p44">
				<emph type="i">Orders to be registered and paid in course</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p45">And to the intent that all moneys to be lent to your Majesty upon the Credit of this A&bholigct; by any person or
persons Native or Forreigner Bodies Politique or Corporate may be well and sufficiently secured out of the moneys
arising and payable, thereby Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That there shall be [provided and<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]
kept in your Majesties Exchequer to wit in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt a Booke of Registry of all
Orders to be made and signed by the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer or by the Commissioners of the
Treasury for the time being for payment of all such sums of money as shall be lent and furnished to your Majesty
upon the Credit of this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; togeather with the Interest thereof after the Rate of Six per Cen&bhocent; for a yeare
as, likewise for all other Orders made and signed as aforesaid for the payment or issuing, of the said Three hundred
and. ten thousand pounds and every part thereof to any person or persons whatsoever for the uses, and purposes
herein before mentioned and intended And that no money arising by this A&bholigct; or furnished upon the Credit thereof
be issued out of the Exchequer but by such Order men&bhocotil;ning that the moneys payable, by the same are for the
charge; and expence of the said Fleet or for the payment of the Officers Mariners Seamen and others imployed
therein as aforesaid or for the charge of collection and bringing in of the moneys arising by this A&bholigct; And that all
the Orders before mentioned shall be registred in course according to the respe&bholigct;ive Dates so as that the person
his Executors Administrators or Assignes who shall have his Order or Orders first entred in the said Booke of
Registry shall be taken and accounted as the first person to be paid out of the moneys to come in by vertue of
this A&bholigct; and he or they who shall have his or theire Order or Orders next entred shall be taken and accounted
the second person to be paid and so successively and in course and that the moneys to come in by this A&bholigct;
shall be in the same order liable to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said respe&bholigct;ive parties theire Executors Administrators
or Assignes Native or Forreigner Bodies Politique or Corporate successively without preference of one before
another and not otherwise and not to be divertible to any other use intent or purpose upon any account or reason
whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Register to be provided, &amp;c. without Fee.</head>
			<para id="p46">
				<emph type="i">Monies issued for the Navy and Ordnance to be so employed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p47">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That all moneys lent upon the Credit of this A&bholigct; shall
be imployed and issued for the uses above men&bhocotil;ned and no other and that no Fee Reward or Gratuity dire&bholigct;ly
or indire&bholigct;ly be demanded or taken of any of your Majesties Subje&bholigct;s for providing or making of such Register
or Entries or for payment of any money lent or the Interest thereof And that all moneys arising by this A&bholigct;
or lent upon the Credit thereof which shall be paid and issued out of the Exchequer to the Treasurer or Vi&bholigct;ualler
of your Majesties Navy or to the Leiutenant of the Ordnance shall be by them respe&bholigct;ively wholly imployed to
the uses aforesaid and not otherwise</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Allowance to Treasurer of Navy, and Lieutenant or Treasurer of Ordnance.</head>
			<para id="p48">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the Treasurer of his Majesties Navy for himselfe his
Deputies and Clerkes shall receive and retaine only the su[m]m of One penny in the pound and no more and the
Leiutennant or Treasurer of his Majesties Ordnance for himselfe and his Clerke shall likewise receive and retaine
onely One penny in the pound and no more out of all the moneys raised borrowed and paid unto and issued out
by either of them to any person or persons by vertue and in pursuance of this A&bholigct; to be allowed in theire respe&bholigct;ive
Accompts thereof</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">The common printed Editions contain this and the following A&bholigct;s until the 22 Car. II. as of the 20 Car. II. but there is no
Distin&bholigct;ion on the Roll as to a new Session, except that the Membranes of the Roll containing the preceding A&bholigct;s up to
Chapter V. and also part of that Chapter are indorsed 19 Car. II. and those containing the Remainder of Chapter V. and this A&bholigct;
and the subsequent A&bholigct;s are indorsed 20 Car. II. and the preceding A&bholigct;s are described in the Long Calendar at the Parliament
Office to have passed on the 19 Dec. 19 Car. II. and this and the subsequent A&bholigct;s are therein described to have passed on the
9th of May 20 Car. II.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">lawfully be <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


