<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47405" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1667 &amp; 1668</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for giving Liberty to buy and export Leather and Skins tanned or dressed.[Rot. Parl. 19 &amp; 20 C. II. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>After the 25th of March 1668, all Sorts of Leather may be exported,; on Payment of Duty of 12d. per Cwt.</head>
		<para id="p1">Whereas it is found by experience since the late stri&bholigct; Prohibition of the exporting of Leather That the
Prices thereof and consequently of Raw Hides are very much abated to the great discouragement of the
Breed and feeding of Cattel and fall of the Rents and Value of Land and yet that the Makers of Bootes and
Shooes and other Workers in Leather have still during this time sold theire Wares and C&bhooov;modities very dear Be
it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice &amp; consent of the Lords Spiritual and
Temporal and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That from and
after the Twenty fifth day of March which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty
eight It shall and may be lawfull for any person or persons Native or Forreigner to buy in open Faire or Markett
and to export and transport into Scotland or Ireland or any Forreign Parts beyond the Seas all sorts of Leather
Sheep skins or Calve skins tanned tawed or dressed Any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding Paying for each Hundred weight of all sorts of Leather Sheep skins and Calve skins containing
One hundred and twelve pounds and so proportionable for a greater or lesser quantity the s&bhouov;m of Twelve pence
and no more</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Continuance of Act.</head>
			<para id="p2">[And<ref idref="n1">1</ref>
] it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority hereof That this A&bholigct; shall continue and be in force until
the Five and twentieth day of March One thousand six hundred seventy five and until the end of the first Session
of Parliament then next ensuing and no longer</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


