<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47418" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for sale of part of the Estate of Sir John Prittiman for satisfa&bholigct;ion of a Debt by him due to the
Kings Majestie. [Rot. Parl. 22. C. II. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Sir John Prittiman had been found indebted to the Crown on Inquisition in the Exchequer.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Manor of Loddington in the County of Leicester to be sold, and to that end settled in Trustees.; How the Money arising by the Sale to be disposed of</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas Sir John Prittiman of Loddington in the County of Leicester Baronet, late Receiver to your most
Excellent Majestie of your Majestyes First-fruits and Tenths hath before the Barons of your Majestyes
Exchequer beene found by Inquisition and other due Processe of Law indebted to your Majestie upon his Accompt
of the last of December One thousand six hundred sixty and three in the Summe of Nineteene thousand eight
hundred sixty fower pounds nine shillings and nine pence by him received of your Majestyes said Revenew, and
still remaines indebted to your Majestie in the Summe of Sixteene thousand six hundred pounds more then he
hath answered to the Receipt of your Majestyes Exchequer, in great Diminution of your Highnesses Revenue;
And whereas upon Processe of Extent issued out of your Majestyes said Exchequer the said Sir John Prittiman hath
beene by Inquisition duely executed and returned the Nineteenth of June One thousand six hundred sixtie and eight
found seised in his Demeasne as of Fee of and in the Mannour of Loddington in the County of Leicester with the
Rights Members and Appurtenances of the cleare yearely value of Seaven hundred eighty eight pounds nineteene
shillings and eight pence which will not satisfie your Majestyes said Debt by perception of the Proffitts thereof at
the said extended value in a long time. Wherefore to the end your Majestie may be more speedily satisfyed your
said Debt may it please your most Excellent Majestie That it may be ena&bholigct;ed And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings
most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the
Commons in Parlyament assembled That the said Mannour or reputed Mannour of Loddington with the Messuages
Lands Tenements and Hereditaments parcell or reputed parcell thereof with their and every of their Appurtenances
in the said County of Leicester, be and is hereby vested and settled in Henry Conventry and Edward Progers
Esquires Groomes of your Majestyes Bedchamber Sir Allan Apsley and Sir Winston Churchill Knights and their
Heires upon Trust that the said Henry Coventry Edward Progers Sir Allan Apsley and Sir Winston Churchill
and the Survivour of them and the Heires of such Survivour shall forthwith sell the said Mannour and every part
and parcell thereof with the Appurtenances and out of the proceede of such Sale and of the meane Proffits by
them to be received untill such Sale or Sales made satisfy and reimburse themselves all such Charges and
Expences which they shall any ways sustaine in or by reason of such Sales (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) of the Trust hereby in them reposed,
And out of the residue of such Purchase money shall pay or cause to be paid into His Majestyes Receipt of
Exchequer the full summe of Sixteene thousand pounds with Interest for the same onely at the Rate of Six pounds
per Cent from the said last day of December One thousand six hundred sixty and three in Discharge of the
said Debt of the said Sir John Prittiman the residue of the moneys to be raised by such Sale to be paid into the
Hands of John Morris and Robert Clayton of London Gentlemen to be disposed and imployed as followeth (videlicet)
In the first place to reimburse Sir Edward Hungerford and Sir Thomas Doleman and either of them such moneys
as they or either of them have paid for the proper Debts of Sir John Prittiman, in the next place for the payment
of such Debts of the said Sir John Prittiman as they or either of them are obliged to pay, In the next place
for the payments unto William Prittiman Brother of Sir John [such<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] moneys as he hath paid for the proper Debt
of Sir John upon any Obligation where the said Sir Edward Hungerford, Sir Thomas Doleman, Sir George Prittiman
and the said William Prittiman or any two of them stood or stand joyntly bound, In the next place for the payment
of all the Debts of the said Sir John Prittiman where any of them the said Sir George Prittiman Sir Edward
Hungerford and Sir Thomas Doleman stand bound, In the next place for the payment unto Sir Edward Hungerford
and Sir Thomas Doleman and either of them all such moneys as they or either of them have paid, or are obliged
to pay for the proper Debts of the said Sir George Prittiman as farr as the same will extend; the residue (if any)
to be divided betweene Sir John Prittiman and Sir George Prittiman as Francis Winington and James Hayes Esquires
and the said John Morris and Robert Clayton or the survivour or survivours of them shall thinke fitt.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Saving, other than to Sir John and Sir George Prittiman, and their Heirs, all Right, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">And further bee it ena&bholigct;ed That from and after the said Summe of Sixteene thousand pounds soe paid to
his Majestie as aforesaid as well the said Sir John Prittiman his Heires Executors Administrators and Assignes as
all his Mannours Lands Tenements and Hereditaments whatsoever and alsoe all and every person and persons their
Heires Executors Lands Tenements and Hereditaments who were Security for the said Sir John Prettiman for or
concerning any matter or thing relateing to the said First-fruits or his the said Sir John Prittimans Office of Receiver
thereof shall be by vertue hereof acquitted for ever released and indempnyfyed, saveing to all and every person
and persons Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate other then the said Sir John Prittiman and Sir George Prittiman and
his and their Heires all such Estate, Right, Title, Interest, Trust, Use and Demand which he or they have or
claime of, in, to or out of the said Mannour of Loddington or any part thereof in such sort and manner and noe
other as if this A&bholigct; had never beene made, Any thing herein to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso that such Persons cause their Claim to be entered, &amp;c. in the Exchequer before March 1670.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided That such person or persons their Heires Executors or Administrators and such Bodyes Pollitique and
Corporate doe by themselves or their respe&bholigct;ive lawfull Attourney or Guardian, produce and cause to be entred and
enrolled in the Office of the Kings Remembrancer in the Exchequer a sufficient and certaine particular of his and
their said Title, Claime or Incumbrance before the First day of March which shall be in the yeare One thousand
six hundred and seaventy.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The Trustees may mortgage the said Manor till it can be sold.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That for the [more<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] speedy raiseing of moneys for and
towards satisfa&bholigct;ion of your Majestie and performance of the Trusts aforesaid it shall and may be lawfull to and
for the said Henry Coventry Edward Progers Sir Allan Apsley and Sir Winston Churchill and the survivours and
survivour of them and his heires to mortgage the said Mannour and Premisses or any part thereof for any Estate
or Estates subje&bholigct; neverthelesse to a further sale of the Reversion or equity of Redemption thereof to be made
according to this A&bholigct; for the purposes aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. All Extents for the King, and all his Claim to the said Manor to be assigned to the Purchasers.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for the Lady Prittiman, and Sir John Heath and his Lady.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">And it is hereby declared and further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid for the encouragement of such person
or persons as shall be willing to purchase the said Mannour and Premisses or any part or parts thereof That all
extents already had or to be had and returned of the said Mannour and Premisses for satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said Debt
of Sixteene thousand pounds and Estate and Interest of your Majestie of and in the said Mannour and Premisses
by. vertue thereof upon payment or satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said Debt of Sixteene thousand pounds and Interest as
aforesaid to your Majestie your Heires and Successors your or their Assignee or Assignees shall and may be
assigned to such person or persons as shall purchase the said Mannour and Premisses or any part or parcell thereof,
or to any other person or persons which he or they shall [for that<emph type="p">1</emph>] purpose, nominate or appointe, and shall remaine
continue and be in force and vertue for the prote&bholigct;ing the said Premisses against all Incumbrances and Charges
of Sir John Prittiman and Sir George Prittiman his Sonne in such sort and manner as the same would have done
if this A&bholigct; had never beene made untill such Purchaser or Purchasers shall out of the Rents Issues and Proffitts
of the said Premisses have received the said summe of Sixteene thousand pounds with Interest for the same after
the rate of Six pounds per Cen? per Annu? from the said last day of December One thousand six hundred sixty
three, Saveing neverthelesse to the Wife of the said Sir John Prittiman (if he hath any) all such Right and Title
of Dower as she might have claimed or may claime in the Premisses if this A&bholigct; had never beene made, And alsoe
saveing unto Sir John Heath Knight and Dame Margaret his Wife and their Assignes all such Estate, Right of
Entry Right, Title, Interest, Use, Trust, Claime or Demand whatsoever in Law or Equity of and into any of the Messuages
Lands Tenements and Hereditaments aforesaid parcell or reputed parcell of the said Mannour of Loddington as if
this A&bholigct; had never beene made, Any thing in the same to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


