<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47412" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IV. An Act for setleing the Imposition on Brandy.; [Rot. Parl. 22 c. II. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 12 Car. II. c. 23.; 12 Car. II. c. 24.;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Brandy a Strong Water chargeable by the said Two A&bholigct;s.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by two A&bholigct;s made in the twelfth Yeare of his Majesties Raigne and confirmed by this present
Parlyament there was laid upon every Gallon of Spirits made of any Kinde of Wine or Sider imported
the Rate and Duty of fower Pence namely by each of the said A&bholigct;s two Pence, And upon every Gallon of
Strong water perfe&bholigct;ly made imported from beyond the Seas the Rate and Duty of eight Pence, and whereas
some Doubts have beene made and raised concerning a certaine Liquor imported from beyond the Seas called
Brandy, whether the same should pay the Rate and Duty laid by the said A&bholigct;s upon Spirits made of any Kinde
of Wine or Syder imported, or the Rate and Duty thereby laid upon Strong water perfe&bholigct;ly made imported from
beyond Seas, Bee it therefore declared by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by Authoritie of
the same That the said Liquor called Brandy was at the time of makeing and confirming the said A&bholigct;s, and is
a Strong Water perfe&bholigct;ly made, and being imported from beyond the Seas was and is charged and chargeable in
and by the said A&bholigct;s with the Rate and Duty of eight Pence per Gallon sett and imposed in and by both the
said A&bholigct;s upon Strong Water perfe&bholigct;ly made imported from beyond the Seas, and was not nor is not chargeable
with the Rate and Duty of fower Pence onely per Gallon by the said A&bholigct;s sett and imposed upon Spirits made
of Wine or Syder imported.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Eight-pence per Gallon not demanded before 1st Nov. 1666; no Person having imported before that time chargeable for more than Four-pence.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes and it is hereby en&bholigct;ed That in reguard it doth not appeare that the Rate or Duty of
eight Pence per Gallon was by his Majesties Commissioners Farmers or other Officers in that Behalfe claimed or
demanded by vertue of the said A&bholigct;s before the first Day of November in the Yeare of our Lord one thousand
six hundred sixty and six That noe Person or Persons who have imported any Brand yes before that Time shall
be charged or chargeable with any more then the Rate and Duty of fower Pence per Gallon for any of the
said Liquor called Brandy imported from beyond the Seas before the (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) first Day of November in the Yeare of
our Lord one thousand six hundred sixty and six. Any Thing in the said A&bholigct;s or in this present A&bholigct; to
the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Penalties how and when to be levied.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Juri&egrave;s free from Attaint for Verdi&bholigct;s heretofore given.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p5">[Provided alwayes and bee it further en&bholigct;ed That noe Penalty infli&bholigct;ed by the Two aforesaid or any other
A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s of Parlyament for Non payment of the said Dutyes since the first Day of November one thousand
six hundred sixty and six shall be leavyed upon any Person now in arreare untill the said Person soe in arreare
shall upon Demand to be made after the passing of this A&bholigct; refuse to pay the said Dutyes, or to secure the
same to be paid within three Moneths after such Demand, and upon such Payment or Security given all former
Bonds or Obligations given for the Payment of the Fower pences formerly in Controversy shall be delivered up
by the severall Person or Persons in whose Custodie the same or any of, them are, and that noe Jury shall be
subje&bholigct; to any Attaint by reason of any Verdi&bholigct; heretofore by them given concerning any Matter relateing to this
or any of the aforesaid A&bholigct;s.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


