<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47419" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XI. An Additionall, Act for the rebuilding of the Citty of London, uniteing of Parishes and rebuilding of the
Cathedrall and Parochiall Churches within the said City. [Rot. Parl. 22 C. II. nu. 11.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Recital that under 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 8. (19 C. II. c. 3.) several Streets, &amp;c. of London have been enlarged, &amp;c. and that certain other Streets require Enlargement and Regulation.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">The said Streets, &amp;c. to be enlarged as they are now staked out;</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas by vertue and in pursuance of an A&bholigct; of this present Parliament entituled, An A&bholigct; for rebuilding
the Citty of London severall Streets in the said A&bholigct; perticularly mentioned and described, have beene
inlarged and made wider by the Maior Aldermen and Commons of the said Citty by and with the approbation of
the Kings most Excellent Majestie; And forasmuch as certaine other Streets within the said Citty not perticularly
mentioned in the aforesaid A&bholigct;, did alsoe require some Regulation and Enlargement (that is to say) the Streete
called Pater-noster-row, the Lane called Warwicke lane at the North side thereof, Watling streete, Candle wike
streete Eastcheape, Saint Swithins lane, Little Wood streete, Milke streete, Tower streete. Water-lane scituate on the
East side of London bridge neare the Custome house, Rood lane Saint Mary hill Thames streete, from London
bridge to Pudle docke, Pye corner next to Smithfield and Thread-needle streete; And to that end and purpose
the same by Order and Dire&bholigct;ion of the Maior, Aldermen and Commons of the said Citty in Common Councell
assembled by and with his said Majesties approbation have beene surveyed and are found necessary to be enlarged:
Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by authoritie of the same That
the said Streetes and Lanes in this A&bholigct; before nominated and appointed to be inlarged, and every of them shall
be inlarged and regulated in such parts and places thereof and in such manner and according as the same are
marked and staked out for that purpose and not otherwise;</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. and also the Royal Exchange, Guildhall, Sessions-house in the Old Baily, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Ground to be assigned for public Market-places, and other Places.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And to the end that fitt and commodious places within the said City and Liberties thereof may be sett out
and appointed for the rebuilding and keepeing of Markets with more convenience then heretofore they were, soe
as the principall Streets may not be pestered and obstru&bholigct;ed thereby as heretofore hath beene accustomed, And
that the Royall Exchange, Guildhall, the Sessions house in the Old Bayly and the common Goales and Prisons
[in<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the said Citty may be enlarged and made more commodious for the publique use and ornament of the Citty and
better secured from the danger and casualtie of Fire, and that some convenient distance, intervall and circuit of
Ground may be left betweene the Royall Exchange and other Houses to be built within the said Citty. Bee it
further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the Maior Aldermen and Commons of the said Citty in Common
Councell assembled shall and may and are hereby impowered to imploy such places and portions of Ground
within the said City and Liberties thereof as by and with his said Majesties approbation now are or before the tenth
day of March One thousand six hundred sixty nine shall be sett out and adjudged necessary and convenient aswell
for the publique Market places there as alsoe for the ornament enlargement and convenience of the said Royall
Exchange and other places aforementioned, and every or any of them respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Satisfa&bholigct;ion to Owners for Ground taken away.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">The Mayor, Aldermen, and Commons to treat and agree with Owners, and in case of wilful Refusal, to impanel a Jury, whose Verdi&bholigct;, and the Judgment of the Mayor and Court of Aldermen thereupon, with Payment of the Money so awarded into the Chamber. Iains Office, shall be binding and conclusive.; Proviso.; Controversies to be decided by the Judges, or Three of them, and in what manner.; Such Decision to be final.; 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 7. (19 C. II. c. 2.)</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And to the intent that reasonable satisfa&bholigct;ion may be given to the Owners and others haveing any Estate or
Interest in the Grounds and places which have beene or shall be sett out to be taken and imployed for publique
Market places or for the ornament and convenience of the Royall Exchange Guild hall and other places in this
A&bholigct; mentioned or any of them or for inlargeing the said Streets or any part thereof called Pater-noster-row,
Warwicke lane Watling streete Candlewike streete Eastcheap Saint Swithins lane Litle Wood-streete Milke streete
Tower streete Water lane Rood lane Saint Mary Hill Thames streete Pye corner next unto Smithfeild and Threade
needle streete before mentioned; The said Maior Aldermen and Commons shall and may (by themselves or others
in that behalfe to be appointed and authorized) treate and agree with the Owners and others interessed therein;
And in case of wilfull refusall or any such disabilitie or impediment as in the aforesaid A&bholigct; are mentioned or
other incapacitie whatsoever in the Owners thereof or others interessed therein to treate and agree; The said Maior
and Court of Aldermen shall and are hereby authorized and required to cause a Jury to be impannelled in such
manner and forme as by the aforesaid A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed and appointed, Soe as noe two of the said Jurors soe
to be impannelled shall come out of one and the same Ward to adjudge &amp; [assesse<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] what recompence and
satisfa&bholigct;ion in every of the cases aforesaid ought to be awarded and given to the respe&bholigct;ive Owners and others
interessed in the Grounds and places soe sett out to be taken and imployed for any the uses or purposes aforesaid;
in pursuance of this A&bholigct; according to such their respe&bholigct;ive Estates and Interests: And the Verdi&bholigct; of such Jury
in that behalfe to be taken, and the Judgement of the said Maior and Court of Aldermen thereupon; and the
payment of the money soe awarded or adjudged at or in the Office of the Chamberlaine of the said City of London
for the time being to the said Chamberlaine there to remaine by the space of six monethes for the Owners or
others interessed therein as aforesaid and after that time to be paid unto them by the said Chamberlaine upon
demand (if that within that time there shall not arise any controversie touching the payment thereof by reason of
different claimes made thereunto as hereafter is expressed) shall be binding and conclusive to and against the
Owners and all others haveing or claimeing or to claime any Estate, Right, Title or Interest of, in, to, or out of
the same their Heires Executors Administrators Successors and Assignes and every of them; And shall be a full
authority for the said Maior Aldermen and Commons to cause the same to be converted and used to and for the
respe&bholigct;ive uses and purposes aforesaid; And in case any Controversie shall arise betweene any person or persons
Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate or his or their Assignes or Under tennants or other persons claimeing any Estate,
Right, Title, or Interest in Law or Equity, Trust, Charge or Incumbrance of or in the said Ground soe to be
purchased or converted as aforesaid, who shall finde him or themselves agreived for or by reason that the said
moneyes soe given in satisfa&bholigct;ion for the said Ground is not or shall not be equally or indifferently apportioned
according to the true value of his or their Interests in the said Grounds, that then the Justices of the Courts of
Kings Bench and Common Pleas and Barons of the Coife of the Court of the Exchequer for the time being or
any three or more of them sitting together at the same time and place upon the petition of the said partie or
partyes grieved to be preferred to any one of them within six monethes after the said Verdi&bholigct; soe had and given
and not after, are hereby authorized to heare and finally determine the same, and to order and award such
destribution of the moneyes soe paid unto the Chamberlaine aforesaid to the said person or persons Bodyes
Pollitique or Corporate respe&bholigct;ively, according to his and their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Interests in the same in
such manner and forme as the said Justices and Barons or any three of them may determine any Differences or
Demands which have arisen or shall arise betweene any Landlord or Tennant touching repaireing or rebuilding
any of the Houses burnt downe or demolished by the late Fire by vertue of an A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament
entituled An A&bholigct; for ere&bholigct;ing a Judicature for determination of Differences touching Houses burnt downe or
demolished by the late Fire which happened in London, According to which Order and Distribution the said
summe and summes shall be paid by the said Chamberlaine to the said severall persons respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Where several Persons having several Estates in one House or Ground, and some delay to build, to the prejudice of others, the rest may rebuild the whole, if they will, and enjoy it to their own Use till re-imbursed.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">In case of Negle&bholigct;, &amp;c. to pay Proportion of rebuilding within Two Years from the covering in, Rebuilders paying or tendering to their Co-partners the Value of their Estate may enjoy.; Difference about Charge of building to be determined by the City Surveyors, or by the Mayor and Court of Aldermen.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That in case it shall happen that where there were
two, or more Co-Partners, Joynt tennants, or Tennants in common of any House or Houses burned or demolished
by the said late Fire; or that two or more persons, Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate had severall Estates or Interests
in, severall Romes, Stories or parts of any such House or Houses burned or demolished; and that some or one
of them is desireous and willing to build the same or such Part, Rome or Story of or in the same as to him
or them doth or may appertaine according to his or their Estate or Interest as aforesaid, And that any other of
the said Co-partners Joynt tennants or Tennants in common or others haveing such Estate or Interest as aforesaid in
any of the Roomes Stories or Parts thereof shall delay or refuse to joyne in rebuilding of the same or to contribute
his and their reasonable part and proportion towards the charge thereof That then it shall and may be lawfull
to or for any one or more of such Copartners Joynt tennants, Tennants in common or others haveing Estate or
Interest in any the Roomes Stories or Parts thereof as aforesaid that will rebuild the said House or Houses to
cause such House or Houses to be wholly rebuilt in such sort and manner as the same was or were before the
said late Fire or as neare thereunto as conveniently may be (the present Modell of Building considered) and respe&bholigct;
being had to the different Interests of the partyes concerned as aforesaid, and the same House or Houses soe
rebuilt to holde and enjoy to his and their owne proper use and benefit untill that he or they shall be fully
satisfyed and reimbursed all such, and soe much of the charge of such building as in a due proportion ought to
have beene contributed or allowed towards the building thereof by such Co-partners Joynt-tennants Tennants in
common or others haveing such Estate or Interest as aforesaid according to his or their Estate or Interest therein
as aforesaid together with Dammages for the same after the rate of Six pounds per Cent, per Annu[m] for the
forbearance thereof to be accompted from the covering of the said Building; And in case of negle&bholigct; or refusall
to satisfie and pay such proportion of the charge of rebuilding thereof by the space of Two yeares to be accompted
from the covering as aforesaid that then it shall and may be lawfull to and for such Rebuilders from and after
the end and expiration of the said Two yeares to be accompted as aforesaid paying to such Copartners Joynt
tennants Tennants in Common or others haveing such Estate or Interest as aforesaid therein; soe much as such
their Estate or Interest shall be reasonably worth, or upon tender and refusall thereof to hold and enjoy such
House or Houses soe rebuilt as aforesaid wholly and intirely against the partyes soe refuseing their Heires Executors
Administrators Successors and Assignes for and dureing the continuance of such joynt or other Estate or Interest
aforesaid as the partie or partyes by whome such House or Houses shall be soe rebuilt had in the same or in
any Roome Story or other part thereof; And in case any Difference shall happen betweene such Builders, and
any the partyes refuseing to build as aforesaid concerning the charge of rebuilding the same; or concerning the
value of the Estate or Interest of the partyes soe refuseing to build as aforesaid, and what money ought to be
paid or given for the same by such Rebuilder after such time and in manner as aforesaid; that then the same
shall be referred to the Surveyors to be appointed for the said City for the time being, who, or any two
of them shall and may upon their view adjudge estimate and determine the same respe&bholigct;ively; And in case the
said partyes or either of them shall refuse to submitt to such the judgement and determination of the said Surveyours,
that then the said matters shall be referred to the examination of the said Maior and Court of Aldermen who
shall heare and finally determine the same without further Appeale;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Difference about Party Walls to be determined in the like manner.</head>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That where there were severall Owners or others interessed of, or
in severall Roomes Stories or other parts of any House or Houses which shall or may obstru&bholigct; or hinder the
makeing of the Partie walls intire and upright; and that the partyes therein concerned cannot or will not come
to an Agreement touching the same; that then it shall be referred to the said Surveyours for the time being or
any two of them to determine the difference thereby ariseing (if they can) who shall and may order and appointe
an indifferent exchange to be made betweene the said partyes [by<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] dividing their Ground, Roomes or Stories; or
otherwise as to them shall seeme most meete and reasonable for accommodateing of their severall Interests, or
otherwise shall and may award satisfa&bholigct;ion to be given in money to such of the said partyes as there shall be
cause to the intent the Walls may be made upright according to the dire&bholigct;ion of the aforesaid A&bholigct; for rebuilding;
And in case the partyes therein concerned or either or any of them shall refuse to submitt to such the Order
and Determination of the said Surveyours that then the said matter shall be referred to the said Maior and Court
of Aldermen to heare and finally determine the same without further Appeale.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Holborn Bridge Passage to be enlarged.</head>
			<para id="p10">And whereas the Way or Passage of Holbourne bridge is now too straight and incommodious for the many
Carriages and Passengers dayly useing and frequenting the same and is therefore necessary to be enlarged Bee it
therefore likewise ena&bholigct;ed That it shall and may be lawfull for the said Maior, Aldermen and Commons soe to
enlarge and make wider the same as that the said Way and Passage may runn in a Bevill Line from a certaine
Timber house on the North side thereof commonly called or knowne by the Name or Signe of the Cocke unto
the Front of the Buildings of a certaine Inne called the Swan Inne scituate on the North side of Holbourne Hill
as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. The Dimension of Corner Piers.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Posts of Oak may be used for Corner Piers.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p12">And to prevent any doubts that may hereafter arise concerning Corner peeres and with what Materials the
same ought to be made Bee it ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authoritie aforesaid That all Corner peeres of Stone
or Bricke hereafter to be ere&bholigct;ed shall be of the Demensions of the Peeres of Stone mentioned in the said A&bholigct;.;
And that it be left to the liberty of all and every the Builders of Corner houses to use a substantiall Post of
Oake Timber to prevent the danger that may happen by Carts and Carriages instead of the Corner peere of Bricke
or Stone of such Demensions and Scantlings as the Surveyours of the said City shall dire&bholigct; and appoint; The said
A&bholigct; or any thing therein contayned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Water from Tops of Houses to be carried down by Pipes.</head>
			<para id="p13">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That the Water from the tops of all Houses already built since the late Fire, and hereafter
to be built and fronting or that shall front upon any the Streets, Lanes or Passages within the said City and
Libertyes shall bee carryed and conveyed into the Channells by Pipes and Partie pipes (as the case shall require)
to be brought downe on the Sides or Fronts of the said Houses.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Recital of 18 &amp; 19 Car. II. c. 8. &sect; 32. (19 C. II. c. 3. &sect; 34.) Thames Street, &amp;c. to be raised Three Foot at least.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Breadth of the Streets and Passages.; The enlarged Passage from Cheapside to the Thames confirmed.; Owners of Grounds to take Notice of Stakes.; Levels and Marks for raising and sinking of Streets to be observed.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p15">And whereas by the said A&bholigct; for the rebuilding of the said City of London It is alsoe ena&bholigct;ed for the preventing
of Inundations and for easines of assent That the Streete called Thames streete and all the Ground betweene the
said Streete and the River of Thames should be raised and made higher by three Foote at the least above the
surface of the Ground as then it lay. And alsoe that the Lord Maior and Aldermen of London should and
might open and enlarge a Streete or Passage to the River of Thames from Cheapeside through Soaper lane, and
to Thames streete and thenceforth to the River of Thames And from [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Three Cranes to the Thames aforesaid;
and to make the same Streets and Passages fower and twenty Foote in Breadth. Now for prevention of any doubt
that may arise touching the manner of cutting the said Streets and ordering the same; and to the end the said
Streete called Thames streete and the Ground betweene the same and the River of Thames may be raised according
to the intent of the said A&bholigct;; and that other Streetes and Passages leadeing to and from the same may be answerable
to their Levells thereunto, and that the steepenes and difficultie of the riseing and assent from the said River may
with the more ease be abated Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the said Streetes or Passages from
Cheapeside through Soaper lane to Thames streete and thenceforth to the River of Thames, and alsoe from the
Three Cranes to the said River shall be and remaine in such manner and forme as now they are; Any matter or
thing to the contrary in anywise notwithstanding. And all Owners, Occupiers and all other person or persons any
way interessed of, or in any the Grounds soe staked and sett out for the cutting, opening and enlargeing of the said
Streets, Lanes or Passages or any of them are hereby required to take notice thereof, and to conforme thereunto
accordingly. And alsoe that the Levells and Markes for raiseing or sinkeing aswell of the said Streete called Thames
streete and the Ground betweene the same and the River of Thames as all other Streetes in and about the said
City and Liberties thereof, in such manner as the same are or shall be appointed to be done before the twenty
nineth day of September One thousand six hundred seaventy one by the Commissioners of Sewers and Pavements
appointed by A&bholigct; of Parlyament be henceforth observed in all places within the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Proviso in respe&bholigct; of Houses built or that were in building before the 14th May 1668.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Surveyors refusing to do their Duty; Appeal to Lord Mayor and Court of Aldermen.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p17">Provided neverthelesse That where any House or Houses for Habitation have beene built or were in building
within the said City and Liberties thereof on or before the Fowerteenth day of May in the yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred sixtie and eight, at which time the said Rules and Levells for raiseing or sinkeing of
the said Streetes were either not published or not generally knowne that it shall and may be, lawfull for the
said Surveyours (who are hereby authorized and required soe to doe) with as litle variation from the said Rule
as conveniently may be soe, to alter the said Levells or Markes or any of them, as that the said Buildings soe
ere&bholigct;ed may receive as litle dammage thereby as may be; And if the said Surveyours or either of them upon
request and due notice to be given by the Owner or Occupyer of such House shall refuse to doe his and their duty
herein; or the said Owner or Occupier shall have any just Exceptions to their determination in the premisses that
then and in such case it shall and may be lawfull for the said Owner or Occupier of such House (soe thereby
greived) to appeale by his Petition in Writeing to the Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen, who upon deliberate
heareing of both sides shall finally determine such Controversie without further or other Appeale.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Recital of 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 8. (19 Car. II. c. 3.)</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">No Builders to lay Foundation till Surveyor has viewed the same.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p19">And whereas in and by the said A&bholigct; for rebuilding of the said City It is further provided That the Surveyours by
vertue of the said A&bholigct; appointed and every of them within their severall Precin&bholigct;s shall take care for the equall
setting out of all Party Walls and Party Peeres and that they permitt noe person to build either on the said
Party Walls or on his owne contiguous Ground till the same be performed accordingly Now to the intent that all
Exa&bholigct;ion in takeing the said Surveys, and that all Differences which may hereafter arise betweene any the said
Builders may be prevented Bee it ena&bholigct;ed That noe Builders bee permitted by the said Surveyours to lay his or
their Foundations untill the said Surveyours or one of them according to the true intent of the said A&bholigct; have first
viewed the same and seene the said Party Walls and Peeres equally sett out accordingly;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Builders to pay to the Chamberlain of London 6s. 8d. before they lay their Foundation.</head>
			<para id="p20">For the defraying whereof and all incident charges of measureing, stakeing out, takeing the Levell, and
surveying the said Streets and Grounds. Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the said Builders before
his or their Foundation shall be laid, or such Survey taken, shall repaire to the Chamberlaine of London, and
there enter his Name together with the Place where [the<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] said Building is soe to be sett out, and pay downe to
the said Chamberlaine the summe of six shillings and eight pence for every Foundation soe to be built respe&bholigct;ively,
upon Receipt whereof the said Chamberlaine shall give his Acquittance; which said Acquittance being produced
to the said Surveyours or any of them, they and every of them are hereby required within three dayes next
after such Request to survey and sett out all and every the said Foundations accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. So in respe&bholigct; of Builders who have laid Foundation since the 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 8. (19 C. II. c. 3.) A&bholigct;ion for Chamberlain.</head>
			<para id="p21">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the said Builders who have at any time since the makeing of
the said A&bholigct; for rebuilding the said City laid any Foundations to be built upon shall forthwith pay unto the
Chamberlaine aforesaid for every the Foundations severally ere&bholigct;ed to be inhabited the summe of Six shillings and
eight pence unlesse the same hath beene formerly paid, And in defaulte thereof it shall and may be lawfull to
and for the said Chamberlaine for the time being by A&bholigct;ion of Debt to be commenced in the Name of the said
Chamberlaine in the Kings Majestyes Court to be holden in the Chamber of the Guild hall of the said City before
the Lord Maior and Aldermen of the same City to recover the same, in which A&bholigct;ion noe Essoyne or Wager of
Law shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Difference about the true Value of Party Walls, stopping Lights, &amp;c. to be decided by Alderman of Ward or his Deputy or by Lord Mayor and Court of Aldermen.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Not obeying such Determination; Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p23">And whereas it is provided in and by the said A&bholigct; That all Differences ariseing betweene any the Builders
within the said City or Liberties thereof concerning the true Value of Party Walls, and all Differences ariseing
betweene the said Builders or any others concerning placeing or stopeing up of any Lights Windowes, Watercourses
or Gutters which may hinder or retard the said Buildings shall and may be heard mediated and determined (if it
may be) by the Alderman of the Ward where the cause of any such Difference shall arise and his Deputy; and
where the said Alderman and his Deputie or any of them be concerned as partyes in the Controversies, or that
they cannot determine the said Differences that then and in every such case the same be certifyed by the said
Alderman or his Deputy unconcerned therein to the said Maior and Court of Aldermen who upon deliberate
heareing of all partyes shall finally determine the same without further Appeale; Neverthelesse in the said A&bholigct;
there is noe certaine Penaltie provided for such as shall obstinately refuse to obey the said Determination; Now to
the end there may be a due Obeidience yeilded to such Determinations as have beene or shall be made in any
of the cases last mentioned and in all other Cases hereby left to the finall Determination of the said Maior and
Court of Aldermen; Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every partie and partyes any way
concerned to give obeidience to any such Determination as aforesaid shall obey and performe the same under such
paines and penaltyes as by the said A&bholigct; arc or may be infli&bholigct;ed upon the Builder or Levyer of any irregular built
House contrary to the meaning of the same late A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Difference concerning obstru&bholigct;ing Common Ways, Passages, &amp;c. to be determined by Alderman of Ward or his Deputy, or by Lord Mayor and Court of Aldermen.</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">Not obeying such Determination; Penalty.; Obstru&bholigct;ions to be abated.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p25">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all Differences which shall or may arise concerning the misplaceing, straightning
or stopping up or any wayes obstru&bholigct;ing any common or private Entryes [Allies<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Wayes Staires Landing Places or
Passages, Houses of Office, Tunnells, Draughts, and other Easements heretofore used &amp; enjoyed within the said
City of London or the Libertyes thereof shall and may by vertue of this A&bholigct; be heard, mediated and determined
(if it may be) by the Alderman of the Ward where the Cause of any such Difference shall arise and his Deputie;
And where the said Alderman and his Deputy or one of them be concerned as Partyes in the said Controversie,
or that they cannot determine the same Differences that then upon the complaint of the partie or partyes concerned,
to the said Maior and Court of Aldermen they shall heare and finally determine the same in such manner as by
the aforesaid A&bholigct;; for the rebuilding of the said City of London is appointed in case of differences concerning
placeing and stopping of Lights, Windowes and Watercourses, And all partyes concerned are hereby required to
obey and submitt to such their Determination under such and the like penaltyes as by the aforesaid A&bholigct; are or
may be infli&bholigct;ed upon such irregular Builders as aforesaid. And that all such obstru&bholigct;ions aswell where any Lights,
Windowes Watercourses or Gutters are or shall be hindred and stopped up, as whereby any common or [private<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]
Allyes, Entryes, Wayes, Staires, Landing Places or Passages are or shall be stopped up, straightned or misplaced
as aforesaid shall and may by Order of the said Maior and Court of Aldermen be abated and removed by vertue
of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Rates for Wharfage and Cranage to be assessed by His Majesty and Privy Council. Table of Rates to be hung up at Wharfs.; Exa&bholigct;ing higher Rates, or refusing to suffer Goods to be landed, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;10.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p27">And forasmuch as great Exa&bholigct;ions have beene and are exercised by Wharfingers and others imployed about the
Wharfage and Cranage of Goods landed or shipped off, at or from the said City of London, For remedy thereof
Bee it ena&bholigct;ed That such Rates and noe other shall from time to time be taken for Wharfage and Cranage aswell
of Timber and other Materialls for building as of Coles and other Goods and Merchandizes as by his said Majestie
with the Advice of his Privy Councell shall for that purpose be assessed and allowed to be taken, a Table of
which Rates shall be hanged up at every of the said Wharfes respe&bholigct;ively, And if any Wharfinger or other shall
exa&bholigct; or demand, or dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly, take or receive for Wharfage or Cranage, or by colour thereof, more
then according to the Rates which shall be soe assessed, or shall refuse to suffer any Goods or Merchandize to
be landed or shipped at [of<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] or from any Wharfe or Wharfes within the said City or the Liberties thereof at the
Rates aforesaid, such Offender shall forfeite for every such offence the summe of Ten pounds to the partie or
partyes thereby greived to be recovered with full Costs of Suite by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Information in
any of his Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster or within the said City of London as the cause shall arise,
wherein noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed, nor any more then one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Recital that 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 7. (19 C. II. c. 2.) is expired; and that divers Causes thereunder remained undertermined, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">The said A&bholigct; revived, with an additional Authority to the Judges.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p29">And whereas the aforesaid A&bholigct; for ere&bholigct;ing a Judicature for determination of Differences touching Houses burned
or demolished by the reason of the late Fire which happened in London, is expired, and for that there were
many Causes brought before the said Judicature which are yet undetermined, and diverse other Causes proper to
receive a determination before the said Justices and Barons which they found not to be within the authoritie given
them by the aforesaid A&bholigct;; and that many more differences doe and may arise which could not be heard and
determined within the time limited by the said A&bholigct;: And for a further and additionall authoritie to the said Justices
and Barons to heare and determine all the aforesaid differences and for a more easy Execution of the said
authoritie It is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the same A&bholigct; and the Judicature thereby ere&bholigct;ted and all
and every the Powers and Authorityes thereby given to the Justices of the Court of Kings Bench and Common
Pleas and Barons of the Coife of the Exchequer for the time being or any three or more of them and all other
matters and things therein contained shall from henceforth stand and be revived and remaine in full force untill the
Twenty nineth day of September One thousand six hundred seaventy one Any clause, matter or thing in the said
A&bholigct; contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. No Term to exceed Sixty Years.</head>
			<para id="p30">[Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That the terme of forty yeares shall not be added to any Estate for life,
or terme of yeares in being soe as thereby to make the whole terme exceede the number of sixty yeares by any
Decree hereafter to be made by vertue of this or the said former A&bholigct;.<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Complaints to be exhibited before the 29th Sept. 1670, otherwise Landlords, &amp;c. may re-enter and rebuild.</head>
			<para id="p31">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That the said Judges and Barons the respe&bholigct;ive Courts aforesaid
or any of them shall not take Cognizance of; nor proceede to heare or determine any Differences or Demands
which have arisen or may in any wise arise betweene any Landlords, Proprietors, Tenants, Lessees, Under Tennants,
or late Occupiers of any the said Houses or Buildings or any other matter or things by the aforesaid A&bholigct; in that
behalfe made referred to the determination of the said Judicature upon any Complaint or Request unlesse the
same shall bee exhibited or depending before the said Judicature at or before the twenty ninth day of September
One thousand six hundred and seaventy; And that in all such cases where noe Complaint or Request shall before
that time be exhibited or depending before the said Judges and Barons it shall and may be lawfull to and for all
Landlords and Proprietors from and after the [said<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] twenty ninth day of September One thousand six hundred and
seaventy to reenter upon the Ground or Soyle to be rebuilt upon, and to avoid the Interest and Terme aswell
of the Tennants in possession, as all other Mean-Tennants and to rebuild thereupon, whereby to preserve his or
their Estate or Interest therein from being sold by the said Maior, Aldermen and Common Councell by vertue of
the said late A&bholigct; for rebuilding the City of London.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Lessees for Years omitting to build, and Landlords having begun to rebuild, &amp;c. such Lessees to lose their Term.</head>
			<para id="p32">And whereas diverse Lessees for yeares haveing Termes to come at the time of the said Fire have omitted to
rebuild, and their Landlords for saveing their Inheritances from forfeiture have rebuilt, or begunn to rebuild Houses
thereupon, and many of them have lett the same to other Tennants who with their Trades and Familes are setled
therein; To the end the said Rebuilders and their Assignes may not bee disquieted in their Possessions Bee it
ena&bholigct;ed That where any Termer for yeares to come at the time of the said Fire hath soe ommitted to rebuild;
and the Landlord or his Assignee or Assignees hath rebuilt or begunn to rebuild, that the Leases of such Termors,
who have ommitted to rebuild be from henceforth absolutely void; Neverthelesse the said Judges are hereby
authorized to award such Controbution or Recompence to the said Termors as they shall thinke fitt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Decrees signed by surviving Judge or Judges effe&bholigct;ual in certain Cases.</head>
			<para id="p33">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if after any Order, Judgement or Decree hath beene
or hereafter shall be pronounced by any three or more of the said Justices or Barons, any one or more of the said
Justices or Barons soe pronounceing the same are already dead or shall die before such Order Judgement or Decree
shall be signed according to the said recited A&bholigct;, the Signing thereof by the Survivour or Survivours of the said
Justices and Barons shall be as good and effe&bholigct;uall to all intents and purposes as if the same were signed by
Three or more of the said Justices and Barons, Any thing in the said recited A&bholigct; contained to the contrary thereof
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Persons being absent or beyond Sea, the Court, after Three Months, may determine.</head>
			<para id="p34">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That where any person or persons concerned in any of the
demolished premisses is or shall be beyond the Seas, or cannot be found or summoned to appeare in the said
Court, that upon the Complaint or Petition of the Partie agreived filed in the said Court for the space of three
monethes or more, and Oath in Writeing made of the endeavour to summon such absent person or persons, That
then the said Court shall or may after the end of the said three moneths proceede to heare and determine the
said Cause; And that such Order, Judgement or Decree as the said Justices and Barons or any three or more
of them shall make in such case shall be binding to such absent person or persons their Heires Executors
Administrators and Assignes as if he or they were a&bholigct;ually summoned and present at the makeing such Decree.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Leases to be made according to Decree of the said Judicature and adjudged good.</head>
			<para id="p35">
				<emph type="i">Present and additional Terms may be united in one Lease.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p36">And alsoe bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That for the avoiding difficultyes in the recovering of
Rents, and for the ascertaining of Covenants Termes and Conditions ordered or to be ordered or decreed according
to this or the said recited A&bholigct;, All and every person and persons Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate respe&bholigct;ively
bound by such Order or Decree their respe&bholigct;ive Heires Successors and Assignes shall and may execute Leases
and Counterparts thereof according to the tenoure of the said Orders and Decrees, and they are thereunto required
by vertue of this present A&bholigct;, All which Leases shall be binding and good in Law. Any Law Statute or Inability
whatsoever to the contrary notwithstanding. And that where Leases in reversion or additionall Termes are or
shall be ordered or decreed by force of this or the said recited A&bholigct; the respe&bholigct;ive Partyes concerned shall or may
at their pleasure unite &amp; joyne together both the present and additionall Termes into one Lease which shall be
good and effe&bholigct;uall against the Lessors their Heires Executors Successors and Assignes Any Law, Statute, Usage,
or Custome whatsoever to the contrary t ereof notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Justices and Barons may appoint a Seal.</head>
			<para id="p37">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the said Justices and Barons or the greater number of
them shall or may appoint a Seale to be and remaine with the Register of the said Court for the sealeing of all
Warrants, and that all such Warrants which shall be sealed with the said Seale and signed by the said Register
for the summoning or warning any persons Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate concerned in the late demolished Houses
and Premisses, or Witnesses shall oblige them to appeare according to the tenoure of such Warrants. Any thing
in the said former A&bholigct; to the contrary [thereof <ref idref="n8">8</ref>] notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Decrees how to be made against Infants.</head>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">Infants attaining Age, or dying before, then their Heirs, &amp;c. to execute Leases.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p39">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That where the Inheritance or other Estate of or in any of the
said Houses or Premisses are or shall be in any Infant or Infants under the age of One and twenty yeares or in
any Trustees for them or any of them, It shall be in the Power of the said Justices and Barons or any Three or
more of them upon the Petition of the Father, Mother or next of Kinn, or other Friend to such Infant or Infants
to order or decree a Lease or Leases against such Infant or Infants and their Trustees for any terme or termes
of yeares not exceeding Fifty one yeares in the whole to such Father Mother or other person that shall or will
undertake the rebuilding of such Houses at and under such Rent or Rents, and under such Convenants, Conditions
and Agreements as they the said Justices and Barons or any three or more of them shall thinke fitt and adjudge;
which said Leases and Termes soe decreed shall and may be held and enjoyed accordingly by vertue of this
present A&bholigct;; And that such Infant or Infants upon request after they shall attaine to their respe&bholigct;ive ages of
One and twenty yeares; and in case of the death of such Infant or Infants, his and their Heires Executors or
Administrators shall and are hereby required to execute such Leases accordingly; and the respe&bholigct;ive Tennants the
Counterparts thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Orders to bind Tenants in Tail, and also Reversioners, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p40">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That for the encouragement of Builders and secureing their
Estates, every Order Judgement and Decree that hath beene or shall hereafter be made by the said Justices and
Barons or any three or more of them by force of this or the said recited A&bholigct; touching the Interests and Estates
of Tennants in Taile shall conclude and binde aswell Tennants in Taile and their Issues as alsoe the Estates in
Remainder and Reversion according to the tenor of such [Order<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Judgement or Decree,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Persons decreed to build rendering an annual Rent, may build and enjoy.</head>
			<para id="p41">And for better secureing the Estates of the said Builders Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid
That all and every person and persons and their Executors Administrators and Assignes who are or shall be
decreed by the said Judicature to build any Messuages or Tenements or any the said demolished Premisses upon
any Terme or Estates rendering an annuall Rent, have or shall build the same accordingly shall hold and enjoy
such their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Termes and Estates under the Rents and Covenants decreed notwithstanding any
other Estate, Right, Title, Interest in Law or Equity Trust Charge or other Incumbrance whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. A&bholigct;ions may be brought to enforce the Performance of the Judges Decrees.</head>
			<para id="p42">And for the better obligeing of all psons to the performance of the Orders and Decrees made or to be made
by the said Judicature Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That where any person or persons are or shall
be ordered or decreed to pay any Rate, Contribution, Summe or Summes of Money in pursuance of this or the
said recited A&bholigct; for ere&bholigct;ing the said Judicature it shall be lawfull for the partyes concerned upon non-payment
thereof to sue for and recover the same by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, or upon the Case in any of his Majestyes Courts
of Record at Westminister or within the City of London, and to give such Order or Decree in Evidence to prove
the same; In which A&bholigct;ion noe Essoyne, Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed; And where any person
or persons are or shall be ordered, adjudged or decreed to build, seale a Lease, give Security, or doe any other
A&bholigct; in pursuance of this or the aforesaid A&bholigct;, It shall and may be lawfull for the partie or partyes concerned,
in default of performance thereof by A&bholigct;ion upon his Case, to be brought in any of his said Majestyes Courts
of Record aforesaid to recover Dammages for such non performance, or to have or bring his Bill in any Court
of Equity to inforce the a&bholigct;uall performance of the same;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Justices and Barons may administer Oaths out of Court.</head>
			<para id="p43">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for the said Justices and
Barons or any of them out of Court to administer Oathes and take Affidavits in Writeing concerning any matter
relateing to the proceedings in the said Judicature, which Affidavits shall or may be made use of in Court as the
said Justices and Barons or any three or more of them shall thinke fitt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Recital that in certain Cases the Party had not time to appeal.</head>
			<para id="p44">
				<emph type="i">Appeals allowed in such Cases.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p45">And whereas some Orders and Decrees in the late Court of Judicature ere&bholigct;ed by the late A&bholigct; of Parlyament
touching the houses burnt in London were made the same weeke that the power of the said Court of Judicature
determined whereby the partyes concerned had not the same time and liberty of exception and appeale as others
had; Bee it therefore provided and ena&bholigct;ed by this present Parlyament and the authoritie thereof That where any
such Order or Decree was made by a lesser number of Justices and Barons then Seaven, if the said Order or
Decree were made since the One and twentyeth day of December in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred sixtie and eight, It shall be lawfull for any persons agrieved by such Order or Decree to present their
Exceptions to the same in Writeing within Seaven dayes next after the first sitting of the said Justices and Barons
by vertue of this present A&bholigct;; And that the same Examination, Proceedings, Review and Determination shall be
thereupon had and made, and as effe&bholigct;ually to all intents as if the said Exceptions had beene presented within
the due time limitted and appointed by the said late A&bholigct; of Parliament. Any thing in this or the said late A&bholigct;
of Parlyament to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Further Power given to the Judges as to certain Houses burnt before the great Fire.</head>
			<para id="p46">And whereas there were severall Houses in the City of London consumed by Fire within three yeares next
before the said late dreadfull Fire which by reason of some differences and doubts ariseing in point of Title the
same were not, nor are likely to be rebuilt unlesse some course be taken for the decideing of such differences
For remedy whereof Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the said Judges and Barons or any
three or more of them be and are hereby authorized and impowered to heare and determine all such cases for
all such Houses and Tenements as fully and amply and in like manner to all intents and purposes as they can
or may heare and determine any other matter herein mentioned; And all Decrees and Orders in such cases to
be made shall binde and be obeyed by all partyes therein concerned and shall be of like effe&bholigct; as if the same
were made for any other matter or thing herein mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Recital that by reason of making certain Streets divers Slips of Ground are rendered useless.</head>
			<para id="p47">
				<emph type="i">Justices and Barons to determine Controversies respe&bholigct;ing the same.; Jury to be impannelled.; Orders made therein to bind; and Parties may hold and enjoy accordingly.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p48">And whereas by reason of inlargeing several Streets, and of makeing the new Streets called Kings streete leading
from Guild hall into Cheapeside and Queene streete leading from Soaper lane to the River of Thames there are
diverse slipps and small parcells of ground remaineing altogether uselesse to the Owners thereof in reguard the
same are not capeable of any house being built thereupon It is therefore hereby further provided and ena&bholigct;ed
That for the makeing the said Streets and Buildings conformable, and for the better determining of all Controversies
concerning the same that the said Justices and Barons or any Three or more of them be and are hereby authorized
and impowered to heare and determine all Controversies and Differences ariseing by reason or occasion thereof
in like manner as they can or may heare or determine any other Matter or Cause referred to their Judgement
by vertue of this or the aforesaid A&bholigct; for ere&bholigct;ing the said Judicature and may make such Orders and Decrees
either for [the<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] transferring the propriety of such parcells of Ground left next the said Streets to the Owners of
the backeward Ground, or by transferring the propriety of a proportion of the backeward Ground to the Owners
of any the said small parcells of Ground, or by annexing it to the next adjoyning and contiguous Ground in
order to the regular building thereupon; And for all such parcells of Ground the propriety whereof shall be soe
transferred by such Order or Decree of the said Justices and Barons or any Three or more of them as aforesaid
and for all Charges and Damages concerning the same such Recompence and Satisfa&bholigct;ion shall be given by the
Builders to the respe&bholigct;ive Proprietors and others interessed therein as shall be awarded by a Jury for that purpose
to be impannelled by the Lord Maior and Court of [Alderman<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] in like manner as by the aforesaid A&bholigct; for rebuilding
the said City of London is appointed in case of satisfa&bholigct;ion to be given for grounds taken and imployed for the
uses in that A&bholigct; mentioned in case the partyes concerned will not, or by reason of Infancy or other impediment
cannot come to agreement touching the same; Which Orders and Decrees in that behalfe to be made shall binde
all partyes therein concerned, their Heires, Executors, Administrators, Successors and Assignes and shall be of like
effe&bholigct; as other Decrees made by the said Justices and Barons or any Three or more of them by vertue of this
or the aforesaid A&bholigct;, to the intent that the Building thereupon may extend to the said Streets, in a right line
with other Houses there built, and the Owners and others interessed of and in the said adjacent and contiguous
Grounds paying to the Owners and others interessed, of and in the said small slipps and parcells of Ground such
satisfa&bholigct;ion as shall be ordered and awarded by the said Justices and Barons or any Three or more of them upon
heareing of the partyes concerned (who are hereby authorized and impowered to heare and determine the same,
and therein to make such Orders and Decrees as in other Causes referred to their Judgement and Determination
by this or the aforesaid A&bholigct;) shall and may for ever holde and enjoy the same by vertue of this present A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Recital that by 18 &amp; 19 Car. II. c.8. &sect;34. (19 C. II. c. 3. &sect;36.) an Imposition on Seacoals, and all other Coals, should be paid to the Mayor, &amp;c. and employed for enlarging the Streets, and other public Works, from the 24th June 1667 to 24th June 1677. but that greater Sums are required.</head>
			<para id="p49">
				<emph type="i">A Duty to be paid on all such Coals imported from 1st May 1670 to 29th Sept. 1687.; Rules and Authorities of 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c.8. &sect; 34. (19 C. II. c.3. &sect;36.) and other Powers in force for colle&bholigct;ing the said Duty.; Duties paid into the Chamber of London, and then issued for the Purposes of A&bholigct;.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p50">And whereas for the further enableing of the said Maior and Commonalty and Citizens of the said City of
London and their Successors to performe and accomplish the workes in the said A&bholigct; for rebuilding the said City
mentioned It was thereby ena&bholigct;ed That for all sortes of Coles, which from and after the Twenty fourth day of
June One thousand six hundred sixtie seaven, and before the Twenty fourth day of June One thousand six hundred
seaventy seaven should be brought into the Port of London or River of Thames within the Liberties of the said
City upon the same River to be sould there should be paid by way of Imposition thereupon for every Chauldron
or Tunn of Coles the summe of Twelve pence to be answered to the said Maior and Commonaltie &amp; Citizens
and their Deputyes and Assignes and to be applyed and disposed unto and for the satisfa&bholigct;ion of such persons
whose Grounds should by vertue [and in pursuance<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] of the said A&bholigct; be taken and imployed for the inlargeing
of the Streets and narrow Passages within the said City and other uses and purposes in the said A&bholigct; mentioned
But forasmuch as it doth and will require farr greater summes of money to give satisfa&bholigct;ion for the Ground to
be taken and employed for the enlargeing of the Streetes by this and the aforesaid A&bholigct; appointed to be enlarged,
and for publique Market places and other the publique uses and purposes in this A&bholigct; mentioned then at the time
of the passing of the said A&bholigct; was or could be foreseene, Therefore for the further enableing of the said Maior,
Commonaltie and Citizens of the said City and their Successors to performe the Workes in this, and the said
A&bholigct; for rebuilding mentioned, And alsoe for the rebuilding of the respe&bholigct;ive Parish Churches by this A&bholigct; appoynted.
to be rebuilt, Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authorise aforesaid That for all sortes of Coles which. (from and after the
First day of May One thousand six hundred and seaventy, and before the Twenty ninth day of September which
shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty seaven) shall be imported and brought into
the [said<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Port of the City of London, or the River of Thames within the Liberties of the said City upon. the
same River there shall be paid by way of Imposition thereupon according to the Rates hereafter mentioned (that
is to say) for all such Coles as shall be there imported and brought in from and after the said First, day of
May One thousand six hundred and seaventy and before the Twenty fourth day of June One thousand six hundred
seaventy seaven there shall be paid for every Chauldron or Tunn thereof Two shillings over and beside the
aforesaid Imposition of Twelve pence the Chauldron or Tunn by the said A&bholigct; for the rebuilding the City of London
appointed to be paid, And for all such Coles which shall be there imported and brought in from and after the
said Fower and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy seaven and before the [said <ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Twenty
ninth day of September One thousand six hundred eighty seaven, there shall be paid for every Chaldron or Tunn
thereof Three shillings and the same shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; be colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid in such sort and
manner in all and every respe&bholigct; as in and by the said A&bholigct; is limitted and appointed for the colle&bholigct;ing and leavying
the Duty of Twelve pence the Chauldron or Tunn of Coles imposed by the said A&bholigct;, and all and every the
powers, authorities, dire&bholigct;ions and provisions in, or by the said A&bholigct; mentioned or provided for the leavying and
colle&bholigct;ing thereof, or for the ordering or regulateing the payment of the said Cole-meters, or others in the discharge
of their respe&bholigct;ive Offices and Dutyes, or for the preventing of Fraude and Covin, and discovery of the just
Quantityes of all sortes of Coles to be imported as aforesaid, and all other things relateing thereunto shall remaine
and be in force and by vertue of this present A&bholigct; shall and may be exercised and putt in ure for the colle&bholigct;ing
and leavying the severall Dutyes aforesaid and of either of them respe&bholigct;ively according to the purport and effe&bholigct;
of the aforesaid A&bholigct; in all and every respe&bholigct;: and that for and dureing all the time by this A&bholigct; limitted and
appointed for the payment of the said Impositions or either of them respe&bholigct;ively, as if the same were expressely
mentioned in this present A&bholigct; with reference to the said Impositions thereby imposed; all which moneyes soe to
be received upon accompt of the said respe&bholigct;ive Impositions or either of them shall from time to time be paid into
the Receipt of the Chamber of the City of London, and from thence shall be issued and paid according to the
dire&bholigct;ion and appointment of this present A&bholigct; and not otherwise; And the said Chamber of the City of London
shall stand and be charged with all the residue of the said moneyes there paid in, which shall not be issued out
and paid accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. How the Money received by means of the several Impositions are to be disposed, and by whose Order and Dire&bholigct;ion.</head>
			<para id="p51">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every Summe and Summes of money which shall be raised upon the
Receipt of the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Impositions aforesaid, or by such additionall Duty, in case of concealement
thereof, as by the aforesaid A&bholigct; is appointed shall be imployed and disposed in manner and forme following (that
is to say) Three fourth parts of all the moneyes which from and after the said First day of May One thousand six
hundred seaventy and before the said Twenty fourth day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven
shall be raised or payable upon the Receipt of the aforesaid Imposition of Two shillings for every Chaldron or
Tunn of Coles, or in case of concealment thereof as aforesaid shall be imployed and disposed for and towards
the rebuilding, ere&bholigct;ing or repaireing of the said Parish Churches respe&bholigct;ively according to such Order and Dire&bholigct;ion
as by the Lord Archbishop of Canterbury, the Lord Bishop, and Lord Maior of London for the time being or any
two of them shall be given in that behalfe, and the same shall from time to time be issued out and paid accordingly
unto such person and persons as they or any two of them shall by Warrant under their Hands and Seales for
that purpose dire&bholigct; and appoint; And the other fourth part residue thereof shall be imployed for and towards the
giveing Satisfa&bholigct;ion for Grounds sett out and imployed for inlargeing of the Streetes, makeing of Wharfes, Keyes,
Publique Market places, and other Publique uses in this and the aforesaid A&bholigct; mentioned and appoynted ; And that
one moyety of all the moneyes which from and after the said twenty fourth day of June One thousand six hundred
seaventy and seaven shall be raised or payable upon the aforesaid Imposition of Three shillings the Chaldron or
Tunn of Coles, or in case of concealement thereof as aforesaid shall be imployed and disposed for and towards
the rebuilding ere&bholigct;ing and repaireing of the said respe&bholigct;ive Parish Churches by such Order and Dire&bholigct;ion, and to
be issued and paid by such Warrant of the said Lord Archbishop of Canterbury, Lord Bishop and Lord Maior
of London for the time being as aforesaid : And the other moity thereof shall from time to time be imployed and
disposed for the giveing of Satisfa&bholigct;ion for Ground sett out and imployed as aforesaid, and such other publique
uses and purposes as in this and the aforesaid A&bholigct; are mentioned and appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. Ten Shillings out of every &pound; 100 to be retained by the Chamberlain, &amp;c. out of the Duty for the Use of the Corporation of London.</head>
			<para id="p52">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authoritie aforesaid That for all moneyes ariseing upon the
Receipt of the severall Impositions aforesaid or either of them respe&bholigct;ively, which in pursuance of this A&bholigct; shall
be paid into the Chamber of the City of London, It shall and may be lawfull for the Chamberlaine or such
other person or persons who shall be appointed to issue out and pay the same, thereout to defaulke and retaine
for the use of the said Maior and Co&bhooov;monalty and Citizens of the said City and their Successors the summe of
Ten shillings for every hundred pounds, and soe after that rate for any greater or lesser summe thereof in lieu of
the Trouble, Hazard, and incident Charges attending the Receipt and Payment thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. One Fourth of the Money for Repair, &amp;c. of Churches may be employed in Repair of St. Paul's Church.</head>
			<para id="p53">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That it shall and may be lawfull for the Lord Archbishop of Canterbury,
the Lord Bishop of London and Lord Maior of London for the time being or any two of them as aforesaid to
imploy or dispose for and towards the building, [or <ref idref="n12">12</ref>] repaireing the Cathedrall Church of Saint Paul One fourth
part of the money by this A&bholigct; given and appointed for the building, ere&bholigct;ing or repaireing the Parish Churches
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. The said Duty may be engaged for Money to be borrowed.</head>
			<para id="p54">
				<emph type="i">How such Money to be employed.; Lord Mayor, &amp;c. may assign Proportions of Duty to Lenders.; Residue of the said Impositions to be also engaged for other Monies.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p55">And forasmuch as the moneyes to be raised by such Receipt of the Impositions aforesaid for every Chaldron
or Tun of Coles by vertue of this and the aforesaid A&bholigct; will not at present raise such a stocke or summe of
money as may be sufficient for the effe&bholigct;ing the ends and purposes in this and the aforesaid A&bholigct; mentioned and
intended. It is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the Lord Archbishop of Canterbury, the Lord Bishop
of London, and Lord Maior of London for the time being, shall bee and are hereby impowered by Indenture
under their Hands and Seales to engage the proffitts ariseing of the respe&bholigct;ive Impositions, by this A&bholigct; imposed,
and thereby appointed to be imployed for and towards the rebuilding and ere&bholigct;ing or repaireing of the Cathedrall
and Parish Churches within the said City respe&bholigct;ively or any part or parts thereof as a Security for any summe
or summes of money, by them to be borrowed for that purpose to any person or persons that shall or will
advance any [summe or <ref idref="n13">13</ref>] summes of money upon that Security; All which moneys soe to be borrowed shall be
imployed for and towards the rebuilding and ere&bholigct;ing or repaireing of the said Cathedrall and Parish Churches
respe&bholigct;ively according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;. And in like manner alsoe are hereby further
impowered to assigne such proportion or proportions of the moneys to be paid in course out of the said Impositions
to the Parishioners of any the said respe&bholigct;ive Parish Churches, or any other person or persons who shall
and will secure the advancement of present moneyes for the rebuilding of their respe&bholigct;ive Parish Churches and
shall be willing to accept of such Assignments for his or their satisfa&bholigct;ion of the moneyes to be disbursed and
laid out in the rebuilding thereof; And that the said Maior, Commonaltie and Citizens of the City of London
and their Successors shall be and are hereby enabled to engage the residue of the proffits ariseing of the
said Imposition either by vertue of this or the aforesaid A&bholigct; respe&bholigct;ively, as a Security for any summe or summes
of money by them to be borrowed and taken up for that purpose by Indenture under their Common Seale to
any person or persons that shall or will upon that Security, advance any present summe or summes of money:
All which summe or summes of money soe to be borrowed shall be imployed for and towards the makeing of
such satisfa&bholigct;ion and other the uses intents and purposes whereunto the said respe&bholigct;ive Impositions are by this and
the aforesaid A&bholigct; appointed to be converted and imployed and not otherwise; And alsoe in like manner shall
and may assigne any summe or summes of money to be paid in course out of the said Imposition to any person
or persons whose Grounds shall be taken as aforesaid, who are or shall be willing to accepte thereof for his or
their satisfa&bholigct;ion.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. A new Key or Wharf to be made on a certain Tra&bholigct; of Ground from London Bridge to the Temple Forty Foot broad.</head>
			<para id="p56">
				<emph type="i">Buildings fronting to be of Second or Third Rate according to 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 8. (19 C. II. c. 3.)</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p57">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That for the better benefitt and accommodation of Trade
and for other great Conveniencies there shall be left a continued Tra&bholigct; of Ground all along from London bridge
to the Temple of the breadth of Forty Foote of Assize from the North side of the River of Thames to be
converted to a Key, or publicke and open Wharfe, and that in order thereunto all Buildings, Sheds, Pales,
Walls, Inclosures and other obstru&bholigct;ions and impediments whatsoever now standing or being within, Forty Foote
Northward of the said River of Thames betweene the places aforesaid (Cranes, Staires and Dockes onely excepted)
shall within eight monethes now next ensueing be taken downe and removed, and the said Ground cleared and
levelled, and that from henceforth there shall be noe Building or Ere&bholigct;ion whatsoever (except onely Craines,
Staires and Dockes as aforesaid) placed or sett within or upon the said Forty Foote of Ground or any part
thereof betweene the places aforesaid, And that all Buildings that shall hereafter immediately border upon any
part of the said Ground upon the North side thereof shall front and be placed in the Line that shall be sett out
for the Bounds of the Breadth of the said Forty Foote of, Ground Northward. And that the same Building
shall be of the Second or Third sorte or rate of Buildings mentioned in a former A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament
entituled An A&bholigct; for the rebuilding of the City of London at the Ele&bholigct;ion of the builder thereof, wherein such
regularity of Building shall be observed, and under such penaltyes as are contained in the said A&bholigct; in that behalfe
and wherein such Uniformity [alsoe<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] shall be had as in other Streets of the said City except Common Halls
for Companyes and other Buildings which shall be otherwise allowed of by his Majestie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. The said Tra&bholigct; of Ground to be open. Bounds to be distinguished only by Denter Stones.</head>
			<para id="p58">
				<emph type="i">Regulation as to Lighters, &amp;c. lying before the said Wharf;</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p59">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That, all the said Tra&bholigct; of Ground of the said breadth of Forty Foote from the
said River shall lie open and at large without any division or separation, and that the Bounds of each Proprietors
Ground therein shall be distinguished onely by Denter stones to be placed in the Pavement thereof, And that
the Line of the whole Key or Wharfe betweene the places aforesaid and alsoe the severall Cranes and Staires
within the same places shall be ascertained by the dire&bholigct;ion of the Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen, and sett
out by their Surveyour accordingly with his Majestyes Approbation, on or before the Fower and twentyeth day
of June One thousand six hundred and seaventy, And further That noe Lighter, Boates or other Vessells shall
lye before any the said Wharfes or Keyes betweene the places aforesaid on the North side of the said River longer
then shall be necessary for the ladeing or unladeing of Goods without the consent and permission of the
Wharfingers or Proprietors thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. and as to lading and unlading Rates, &amp;c. at the said Wharf.</head>
			<para id="p60">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That it shall and may be lawfull for any person or persons to lade
or unlade any Goods or Merchandices at any of the said Wharfes or Keyes for Wharfage and Cranage, whereof
every Proprietor, Wharfinger or other Person concerned shall and may demand and receive such Rates and noe
other for the same as shall from time to time be sett out and appointed by his Majestie with the advice of his
Privy Councill.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. The Channel of Bridewell Dock from the Thames to Holborn Bridge to be made navigable. Breadth of Wharfs, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p61">
				<emph type="i">Buildings to front and be of the Second Rate, according to 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 8. (19 Car. II. c. 3.) Regulations as to Lighters, &amp;c. lying before the Wharfs, and landing 
Goods; and as to Rates to be set by the King and Council. Certain other Rates may be set by Lord Mayor and Court of Aldermen, with the Approbation of Two Barons of the Exchequer.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p62">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That for the further convenience of Trade the Channell
of Bridewell docke from the Channell of the River of Thames to Holbourne bridge shall be sunke to a sufficient
Levell, whereby to make it navigable. And that the Ground to be sett out for the breadth of the said Channell
and of the Wharfes on each side thereof shall not be lesse in breadth then One hundred foote, nor shall exceede
One hundred and twenty foote in breadth. And that the Line of the said Channell and Wharfes and Levells
thereof together with the Cranes and Staires to be placed thereon shall be ascertained by the said Lord Maior and
Court of Aldermen with his Majestyes Approbation, and sett out by the Surveyours accordingly at or before the
first day of May next ensueing. And that all the said Wharfe ground on each side of the said intended River
shall lye open and at large (Cranes and Staires onely excepted) without any division or separac&bhocotil;n, and each
persons propriety therein to be distinguished onely by Denter stones in the pavement thereof, [And that all Buildings
that shall hereafter immediately border upon each side of the said Wharfes shall front and be placed in the Line
that shall be sett out for the bounds of the breadth of the Wharfes from the Channell, And that the said
Buildings shall be of the second rate of Buildings mentioned in the said A&bholigct; for rebuilding wherein such Regularity
of Building shall be observed and under such penaltyes as are contained in the said A&bholigct;,<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] And that noe Lighter,
Boate or Vessell shall lye before any the [said<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] last mentioned Wharfes or Keyes longer then shall be necessary for
the ladeing or unladeing of Goods without the consent or permission of the Wharfingers or Proprietors thereof.
And that it shall [and may<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] be lawfull for any person or persons to land any Goods or [Merchandices<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] at any
of the said Wharfes or Keyes within the intended Channell or Cutt soe to be made for Wharfage &amp; Cranage,
whereof every Proprietor, Wharfinger or other person concerned shall demand and receive such Rates and noe
other for the same as shall from time to time be sett and appointed by his said Majestie with the advice of his
Privy Councill as aforesaid. And that certaine reasonable Rates for Tolls and other Proffitts ariseing by the Navigation
of the said Channell or Cutt shall be sett and appointed by the Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen with Approbation
of the Barons of the Exchequer or two or more of them and the same Tolls or Proffitts vested in the Maior
Commonaltie and Citizens of the City of London for preservation of the said Navigation Sluces and other incident
charges thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. How the Charge of sinking and making the said Channel to be defrayed.</head>
			<para id="p63">[Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the sinking and makeing of the said intended
Channell of Bridgewell docke and Fleet ditch from the Channell of the Thames to Holbourne bridge and the Sasses
and Sluces for the better Navigation thereupon and the raiseing and sinkeing [other<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] Wharfes or Keyes on each side
of the said Bridewell docke and Fleete ditch (whereby to bring the same to a Levell) shall be borne and first
defrayed by the Maior and Commonaltie and Citizens of the said City of London out of the said fourth part of
the Imposition to be raised upon Coles by vertue of this A&bholigct;. And that the said Maior and Commonaltie and
Citizens shall cause the said Chaunnells to be sunke and Wharfes or Keyes to be reduced to such a Levell as may
be proper for the Proprietors of the Ground immediately bordering upon the said Wharfes or Keyes to build upon
with convenient accesse thereto before the first of August One thousand six hundred and seaventy. And in the
next place after the charge before mentioned shall be borne out of the said fourth part, satisfa&bholigct;ion shall be made
out of the same fourth part to the Proprietors whose Ground hath beene or shall be laid open, or from whom
any Ground hath beene or shall be taken for the said publique use.<ref idref="n19">19</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>XLIII.</head>
			<para id="p64">
				<emph type="i">Proceedings for giving Satisfa&bholigct;ion to Parties, and for assessing Monies in respe&bholigct; of making the said Wharfs, to be according to 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 8. (19 C. II. c. 3.); Key at White Friars Dock.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p65">And whereas some parts of the said Ground soe as aforesaid designed for publique Wharfes on the North
side of the said River of Thames and on each side of the said Channell or Cutt will be much improved, and
some other parts thereof will be much impaired in value by reason of converting the same to the uses aforesaid,
To the end therefore that an equall and reasonable course may be held and used on each hand without wrong
to any partie therein concerned Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That aswell for the giveing satisfa&bholigct;ion
to such persons whose Ground shall be imployed as aforesaid or thereby impaired or lessened in value, As alsoe
for the assessing and raiseing of moneyes upon those that shall by the meanes aforesaid make improvement or
melioration of any of the said Ground soe imployed, The same powers, authorities forme and course of proceedings
shall in all things be used, exercised, putt in pra&bholigct;ice and observed as are by the said recited A&bholigct; (made for the
rebuilding of London) ordained, provided and appointed for satisfa&bholigct;ion to be made for Ground imployed for the
enlargement of Streets and Passages, and for assessments to be made in consideration of improvements and
melioration of Houses and Ground, and that the returne of the Key about White-Fryers docke shall not exceede
the breadth of Twenty Foote.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>XLIV. Provision for Persons rebuilding, against secret Charges and Incumbrances.</head>
			<para id="p66">And for the security and encouragement of such as have or shall rebuild upon the Scite of any House or Houses
burned or demolished by reason of the said late Fire against secret Charges and Incumbrances wherewith or
whereunto the, same shall or may be charged or lyable Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That noe
such House or Houses already built, or to be rebuilt within the said City of London or Liberties thereof, nor the
Owners or others interessed therein shall after the rebuilding thereof be further lyable to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of any
charge or charges, incumbrance or incumbrances wherewith or whereunto the same are or may be lyable, by any
matter or thing before the said late Fire, then the value of the Ground or Soyle in case the same had not beene
rebuilt upon, might or would extend to satisfie, unlesse such Charges or Incumbrances as were contra&bholigct;ed thereupon
by the now Owners or others interessed therein who shall themselves be and remaine lyable to satisfie the same as
if this present A&bholigct; had never beene had or made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>XLV. Twenty-one Years Possession, or more, shall enable the Owner to make Leases.</head>
			<para id="p67">And whereas many Deeds Evidences and other Writeings were in the said Fire lost, burnt or imbezilled by
which misfortune many persons who have Land in the said City are rendred unable to make their Right and Title
soe apparent as can satisfie such as would take Leases of their said Lands and build upon them Bee it ena&bholigct;ed That
if any person or persons who have beene lawfull Possessors and esteemed Owners of any Ground within the said
City for the space of One and twenty yeares or more shall grant a Lease to any person or persons of the [said
Land<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] upon a valuable Ground rent soe to be esteemed by the said Maior and Aldermen or any three of them if
the said Lands shall afterward be recovered from the said person soe granting That the Lease shall be good and
valid the Builders onely paying the aforesaid Ground rent to the person unto whom the Ground shall rightly belong
shall be freed from all charge and trouble, Any Law or Custome to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>XLVI. Indemnity to Owners of Water-house at Broken Wharf for rebuilding the same with Timber.</head>
			<para id="p68">
				<emph type="i">Proviso as to building the Water-house at London Bridge.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p69">And whereas the Water house at or neere Broken Wharfe was wholly burnt downe and consumed in the time
of the late dreadfull Fire, which being found impossible to be rebuilt with Bricke the Owners thereof have at
their very great charge lately rebuilded the said House with Timber and made the same usefull for serveing the
Inhabitants of the City with Water Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authoritie aforesaid That the said
Owners and their Assignes are hereby and shall for ever hereafter be saved harmelesse and indempnifyed from
all trouble or penalties for or by reason of [their<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] building the said House with Timber as aforesaid: Any
thing in this A&bholigct; or in the former A&bholigct; for rebuilding the City of London to the contrary thereof in any wise
notwithstanding. Provided That noe continuance of the said restraint from building shall extend to the Water house
at London bridge but that the same may be built according as in the former A&bholigct; is provided.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>XLVII. Proviso as to leaving old Foundations unbuilt, paving new Streets allowed to be made, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p70">Provided alwayes That it may be lawfull for any person or persons Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate Owners and
Proprietors of any such Ground meant or contained within this A&bholigct; to leave any old Foundations of his or theirs
unbuilt to make any new Streete or Passage or to enlarge any old one the said Owners or Proprietors taking
care within convenient time after their building sufficiently to pave and amend all such, Streete and Passages.
Any thing in this A&bholigct; or one other A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for rebuilding the City of London to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>XLVIII. A Street to open Fourteen Foot wide from Threadneedle Street to, Lothbury.</head>
			<para id="p71">Provided alsoe and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That the Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen shall be hereby impowered
to cause a streete to be opened fowerteene Foote wide if they shall thinke soe fitt from the West end of Threadneedle streete downe to Loathbury in case the Proprietors doe not voluntarily [soe<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] open it before the Fower
and twentyeth day of June next makeing such Allowances to the Owners and others interessed as by the former
A&bholigct; for opening of Streets is dire&bholigct;ed; which Streete shall be and continue an open Streete for ever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>XLIX. Bury Street in Beavis-Marks.</head>
			<para id="p72">Provided alwayes and bee it [hereby<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] ena&bholigct;ed That the remainder of Bury streete in Beavis-Markes which is
not yet new built may be built after the Patterne and Modell of the other new Building in the said Streete.
Any thing in this or the said former A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s50">
			<head>L. Recital that many Builders have advanced their Foundations further than formerly, for the more regularity, &amp;c. of the new Streets.</head>
			<para id="p73">
				<emph type="i">Indemnity to such Builders.; Giving Satisfa&bholigct;ion to the Lord Mayor, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p74">And whereas many Builders of Houses within the said City and the Liberties thereof have (for the more
regularity of building and makeing many of the Streets and Lanes more straight and beautyfull then otherwise
they [would<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] have beene) by and with the appointment and approbation of the said Surveyours advanced their
Foundations in many places further into the Streets and Lanes thereof upon the Soyle of the said Streets and Lanes
then the same formerly stood, whereby some difference may hereafter possibly arise either betweene our Soveraigne
Lord the King his Heires and Successors or betweene the Maior Commonaltie and Citizens of the said City, or
other Proprietors of the Ground soe built upon, and the said Builders or such person or persons Bodyes Pollitique
and Corporate to whom the Inheritance of the said Houses soe built now doth or hereafter shall belong. For
prevention whereof Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all Ground and Soyle soe taken or which hereafter shall or may
be soe taken out of the said Streets or Lanes or any of them shall from henceforth for ever be united and
annexed to the said Houses. And that all and every person and persons whatsoever Bodyes Pollitique and
Corporate giveing such satisfa&bholigct;ion to his Majestie or to the said Maior Commonalty and Citizens of the said City,
or other the respe&bholigct;ive Owners or Proprietors of the Ground soe built upon, and according to such rates as
are or ought to be given and allowed for Ground taken and imployed for the enlargeing of Streets by vertue of the
aforesaid A&bholigct;, for rebuilding the said City shall and may hold and enjoy the said respe&bholigct;ive parcells of Ground
or Soyle soe built upon united and annexed to such Buildings for and dureing such Termes and Estates as he
and they respe&bholigct;ively have or hereafter shall have of and in the said Houses and Buildings; Any matter or
thing to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s51">
			<head>LI. Recital that the Company of Mercers are building a new School House, &amp;c. on the Scite of St. Paul's School.</head>
			<para id="p75">
				<emph type="i">The Scite of the late School, &amp;c. confirmed to the said Company; the Residue of the said Scite vested in the Dean, &amp;c. of St. Pauls.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p76">And whereas the Wardens and Commonaltie of the Mistery of the Mercers of the City of London are now
building pursuant to a Designe approved of by his Majestie a new Schoole-house with Houses thereunto adjoyneing
for the Accom&bhooov;odation of the Master, Sur-master and Chaplain thereof partly upon the Scites and Tofts of the late
Schoole called Saint Pauls-schoole and the former Houses of the said Masters and Chaplin, and partly upon some
Ground next adjoyning being part of the Church-yard, belonging to the Cathedrall Church of Saint-Pauls London.
And whereas other parts of the former Scite of the said late Schoole and of other Houses adjoyning have beene
alsoe by his Majestyes dire&bholigct;ions cutt of and laid into the said Church-yard for the enlargement and accommodation
of the Passage at the East end of the said Cathedrall. Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed That soe much of the said Ground
adjoyning to the Scite of the said late Schoole and former Houses as is comprised within the Foundation of the
said new Schoole and Houses now building for the said Masters and Chaplain be and are hereby vested and setled
on the said Wardens and Commonaltie and their Successors for ever, as the said late Schoole and former Houses
were before the said Fire: And that the said other parts of the former Scite of the said late Schoole and other
Houses adjoyning laid unto the said Church-yard as aforesaid for the enlargement of the late Passage shall continue
a Passage for ever; and be and are hereby vested and setled on the Deane and Chapter of the Cathedrall
Church of Saint Pauls aforesaid and their Successors for ever as the residue of the said Church-yard is and was
heretofore, Any thing in A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s52">
			<head>LII. Proviso for the Churches of St. Pauls, St. Faith, and St. Gregory.</head>
			<para id="p77">[Provided alwayes That noe thing in this A&bholigct; contained shall extend or be taken to vest or setle the Church of
Saint Paul and Saint Faith or any part thereof or the Church of Saint Gregory by Saint Pauls or any of them, or
the Church Yards to any of them belonging or appertaining, or any part of any of them, in the Maior, Aldermen
and Commons of the City of London or any of them, or in any other person or persons Bodyes Pollitique or
Corporate other then the Ground whereupon Saint Pauls Schoole and Houses thereunto belonging are by this A&bholigct;
appointed to be rebuilt, Any thing in this A&bholigct; notwithstanding.<ref idref="n22">22</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s53">
			<head>LIII. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing rebuilding several Houses in White's Alley, Coleman Street.</head>
			<para id="p78">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That whereas the Alley called Whites Alley in
Coleman streete London was not wholly burnt downe in the said late Fire, but the one halfe part thereof, or neere
thereabouts is yet standing, neither was the said Alley ever any thorow Passage, nor will the enlargeing thereof be
any Ornament or Advantage to the said City, Therefore it shall and may be lawfull to and for the severall
Proprietors of and in the said Alley, to rebuild their severall Houses on both sides thereof, which were burnt
or demolished by reason of the said late Fire, upon their old Foundations respe&bholigct;ively. This present or the said
former A&bholigct; for rebuilding the Citty of London or any thing therein contained or any other matter or thing to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s54">
			<head>LIV. Market Place within Newgate to be granted to the City by Lease from the Dean and Chapter of St. Paul.</head>
			<para id="p79">And further bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That for ever hereafter the said Maior and C&bhooov;monaltie
and Citizens of London may and shall have a Market to be kept three or fower dayes in the weeke as to them
shall seeme convenient upon the Ground now sett out by the assent of the Deane and Chapter of the Cathedrall
Church of Saint Paul London for a Market place within Newgate, And that the said Deane and Chapter shall
make and give one or more Lease or Leases of the said Ground to the said Maior Commonaltie and Citizens,
and alsoe of the Wall of the said Church Yard abutting severally upon Pater noster Row and the Old Change
for the Terme of forty yeares reserveing the yearely Rent of fower pounds for the Ground of the said Market
place, and two pence for every Superficiall Foote of the Ground or Soyle of the said Wall as it is now sett out
by the Surveyours of the City and of the said Deane and Chapter, and soe from forty yeares to forty yeares
for ever at the like yearely Rent, and one yeares Rent after the Rates aforesaid to be paid by way of Fine for
each of the said Grounds respe&bholigct;ively upon the makeing every new Lease thereof, Which said Lease and Leases
shall be good and effe&bholigct;uall in the Law as against the said Deane and Chapter and their Successors and all persons
claimeing by from or under them, and that noe House, Shed, or other Building shall stand, or hereafter be ere&bholigct;ed
and fixed upon the said Market place other then the Market house already built without the consent of the said
Deane and Chapter, Any thing in this or any other A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s55">
			<head>LV. Recital of 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 8. &sect; 29. (19 C. II. c. 3. &sect; 31.)</head>
			<para id="p80">
				<emph type="i">Fifty-one Parishes to be within the City of London.; The Names of the Fifty-one Parishes.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p81">And whereas by a late A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament entituled An A&bholigct; for rebuilding the City of London, It
was ena&bholigct;ed That the Parishes to be rebuilded within the said City of London in lieu of those which were
demolished by the late dreadfull Fire should not exceede the number of Thirty nine. But forasmuch as upon
an exa&bholigct; Survey taken of the number of Houses to be rebuilded, and of the extent of the respe&bholigct;ive Parishes
necessary to be setled and continued within the said City, It doth appeare that the Parishes to be setled and
continued, and the Parish Churches to be rebuilded within the said City of London in lieu of those demolished
or consumed by the said rate Fire cannot conveniently by Union or otherwise be reduced to a lesse number then
Fifty one Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the number of Parishes to be setled and of
Parish Churches to be rebuilded within the said City of London shall be Fifty one, The aforesaid A&bholigct; or any
thing therein contained to the contrary notwithstanding. And that the Fifty one Parishes soe to be continued
shall be as hereafter followeth That is to say Alhallowes [Lumber<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] streete, Saint Bartholimew Exchange, Saint
Bridges alias Brides, Saint Bennets Finck, Saint Michaels Crooked lane, Saint Christophers, Saint Dionesse. Backe
Church, Saint Dunstons in the East, Saint James Garlike-hithe, Saint Michaell Cornhill, Saint Michaell Bassishaw, Saint
Margaret Loathbury, Saint Mary Aldermanbury, Saint Martin Ludgate, Saint Peters Cornhill Saint Stephens Coleman
streete and Saint Sepulchres shall remaine and continue as heretofore they were. And that the respe&bholigct;ive Parish
Churches to each of the said Parishes belonging shall be rebuilded and continued for the use of the said Parishes,
and that the severall Parishes hereafter mentioned shall be respe&bholigct;ively united into one Parish in manner [hereafter<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]
following that is to say,</para>
			<para id="p82">
				<emph type="i">Parishes herein mentioned to be united.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p83">The Parishes of Alhallowes Breedstreete and Saint John Evangalist shall be united into one parish, and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Alhallowes Breed streete shall be rebuilded, and shall be
the parish Church of the said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p84">The parishes of Alhallowes the Great and Alhallowes the Lesse shall be united into one parish, and the Church
heretofore belonging to the said parish of Alhallowes the Great shall be the parish Church of the said parishes
soe united.</para>
			<para id="p85">The Parishes of Saint Albans Woodstreete and Saint Olaves Silver streete shall be united into one parish, and
the Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Albanes Woodstreete shall be the parish Church of
the said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p86">The parishes of Saint Anne and Agnes and Saint John Zacharie shall be united into one parish, and the Church
heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Anne and Agnes shall be the parish Church of the said parishes
soe united.</para>
			<para id="p87">The parishes of Saint Austins and Saint Faiths shall be united into one parish, and the Church heretofore
belonging to the said parish of Saint Austins shall be the parish Church of the said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p88">The parishes of Saint Andrew Wardrobe and Saint Anne Blacke-Fryers shall be united into one parish, and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Andrew Wardrobe shall be the parish Church of the said
parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p89">The parishes of Saint Antholins and Saint John Baptist shall be united into one parish, and the Church heretofore
belonging to the said parish of Saint Antholins shall be the parish Church of the said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p90">The parishes of Saint Bennet Grace Church and Saint Leonard Eastcheape shall be united into one parish, and
the Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Bennet Grace Church shall be the parish Church of
the said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p91">The parishes of Saint Bennet Pauls-Wharfe, and Saint Peter Pauls-wharfe shall be united into one parish, and
the Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Bennet Pauls-wharfe shall be the parish Church of the
said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p92">The parishes of Christ Church and Saint Leonard Foster lane shall be united into one parish, and the Church
heretofore belonging to the said parish of Christ Church shall be the parish Church of the said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p93">The parishes of Saint Edmond the King, and Saint Nicholas Acons shall be united into one parish, and the Church
heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Edmond the King shall be the parish Church of the said parishes
soe united.</para>
			<para id="p94">The parishes of Saint George Buttolph lane, and Saint Buttolph Billinsgate shall be united into one parish, and
the Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint George Buttolph lane shall be the parish Church of
the said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p95">The parishes of Saint Lawrence Jury and Saint Magdalens Milke streete shall be united into one parish, and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Lawrence Jury shall be the parish Church of the said
parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p96">The parishes of Saint Magnus and Saint Margaret New-Fish streete shall be united into one parish; and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Magnus shall be the parish Church of the said parishes
soe united.</para>
			<para id="p97">The parishes of Saint Michaell Royall and Saint Martins Vintry shall be united into one parish, and the Church
heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Michaell Royall shall be the parish Church of the said parishes
soe united.</para>
			<para id="p98">The parishes of Saint Mathew Friday streete and Saint Peters Cheape shall be united into one parish and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Mathew Friday streete shall be the parish Church of the
said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p99">The parishes of Saint Margaret Pattens and Saint Gabriell Fenn Church shall be united into one parish, and
the Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Margaret Pattens shall be the parish Church of the
said [parises<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] soe united.</para>
			<para id="p100">The parishes of Saint Mary Atthill and Saint Andrew Hubbord shall be united into one parish, and the Church
heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Mary Atthill shall be the parish Church of the said parishes soe
united.</para>
			<para id="p101">The parishes of Saint Mary Woolnoth and Saint Mary Wool Church shall be united into one parish, and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Mary Woolnoth shall be the parish Church of the said
parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p102">The parishes of Saint Clement Eastcheap and Saint Martins Orgars shall be united into one parish, and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Clement Eastcheap shall be the parish Church of the said
parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p103">The parishes of Saint Mary Ab-Church and Saint Lawrence Pountney shall be united into one parish, and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Mary Ab-Church shall be the parish Church of the said
parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p104">The parishes of Saint Mary Aldermary and Saint Thomas Apostles shall be united into one parish, and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Mary Aldermary shall be the parish Church of the said
parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p105">The parishes of Saint Mary le Bow, Saint Pancras Soaper lane, and Alhallowes Honey lane shall be united into
one parish, and the Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Mary le Bow shall be the parish
Church of the said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p106">The parishes of Saint Mildreds Poultrey and Saint Mary Cole Church shall be united into one parish, and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Mildreds Poultrey shall be the parish Church of the said
parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p107">The parishes of Saint Michaell Woodstreete and Saint Mary Staining shall be united into one parish, and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Michaell Woodstreete shall be the parish Church of the
said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p108">The parishes of Saint Mildred Bread Streete and Saint Margaret Moses shall be united into one parish and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Mildred Bread streete shall be the parish Church of the
said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p109">The Parishes of Saint Michael Queene Hythe and Trinity shall be united into one parish, and the Church
heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Michaell Queene Hythe shall be the parish Church of the said
parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p110">The parishes of Saint Mary Magdalens Old Fish Streete and Saint Gregories shall be united into one parish and
the Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Mary Magdalen Old Fish Streete shall be the parish
Church of the said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p111">The parishes of Saint Mary Somerset and Saint Mary Munthaw shall be united into one parish, and the Church
heretofore belonging to the parish of Saint Mary Somerset shall be the parish Church of the said parishes soe
united.</para>
			<para id="p112">The parishes of Saint Nicholas Cole Abby and Saint Nicholas Olaves shall be united into one parish, and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Nicholas Cole Abby shall be the parish Church of the said
parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p113">The parishes of Saint Olaves Jury and Saint Martins Pomroy alias Iremonger lane shall be united into one
parish, and the Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Olaves Jury shall be the parish Church
of the said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p114">The parishes of Saint Stephen Walbrooke and Saint Bennet Sher hogg shall be united into one parish, and the
Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Stephen Walbrooke shall be the parish Church of the
said parishes soe united.</para>
			<para id="p115">The parishes of Saint Swithin and Saint Mary Bothaw shall be united into one parish, and the Church
heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Swithin shall be the parish Church of the said parishes soe
united.</para>
			<para id="p116">The parishes of Saint Vedost alias Saint Fosters and Saint Michaell Quern shall be united into one parish, and
the Church heretofore belonging to the said parish of Saint Vedost alias Saint Fosters shall be the parish Church
of the said parishes soe united.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s56">
			<head>LVI. The same Parishes to continue united, and the Parish Churches to be rebuilt according to Models appointed by the Archbishop of Canterbury, Bishop of London, and Lord Mayor, with the King's Approbation.</head>
			<para id="p117">
				<emph type="i">To whom Tithes of the said united Churches to be paid.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p118">[And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the said respe&bholigct;ive Churches to be rebuilded within the
said City of London and Libertyes thereof shall be built and ere&bholigct;ed according to such Models, and of such
Demensions and in such Manner and Forme in all respe&bholigct;s as by the said Lord Archbishop of Canterbury Lord
Bishop of London and Lord Maior of London for the time being (with his Majestyes Approbation thereof) shall
[dire&bholigct; and appoint.<ref idref="n26">26</ref>]<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] And the said respe&bholigct;ive Parishes herein before mentioned and appointed to be united as
aforesaid shall for ever hereafter remaine and continue soe united, and consolidated and annexed unto the severall
and respe&bholigct;ive Parish Churches by this A&bholigct; appointed to be rebuilded as aforesaid: And the respe&bholigct;ive Parishioners
and the Inhabitants of the said severall Parishes soe to be united as aforesaid by force of this present A&bholigct; shall
hereafter resorte to the said Churches respe&bholigct;ively as to their proper Parish Church, And all Tythes and other
Dutyes heretofore due and payable to the respe&bholigct;ive Incumbents of the said Parish Churches respe&bholigct;ively shall
hereafter be paid and payable to the Incumbent of that Church onely which by this A&bholigct; is appointed to be
rebuilded and established for the Parish Church of the Parishes soe united as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s57">
			<head>LVII. Regulations as to the Use of Plate and Goods belonging to Churches not to be rebuilt.</head>
			<para id="p119">[And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That any Plate and Goods heretofore belonging to any of the Churchwardens of
any the Parishes of those [Parishes<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] burnt downe, which are not now to be rebuilded for the use of the said
Churches shall be enjoyed by the respe&bholigct;ive Churchwardens and their Successors of the respe&bholigct;ive Parishes of such
Churches to be rebuilded respe&bholigct;ively, whereunto the said other Churches burnt downe are united by this A&bholigct; to
the use of the said Churches and Parishes respe&bholigct;ively.<ref idref="n27">27</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s58">
			<head>LVIII. Church-yards, &amp;c. of Churches demolished to be enclosed with Walls to make Burial Places.</head>
			<para id="p120">
				<emph type="i">Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p121">Provided alwayes That the Scites of the Churches to be demolished and the Church Yards belonging to the
same shall be inclosed with Bricke or Stone walls for buryall [places<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] for the Parishes formerly belonging to the
same, and the Parishes to which they are respe&bholigct;ively united as aforesaid, and not used or imployed for any other
purpose whatsoever, excepting such of the Scites and Church Yards or parts of Scites and Church Yards of the
said Parish Churches soe demolished as aforesaid as are already laid into the Streets and Market places or sett
out for that purpose, or such other as shall within two yeares now next following be thought fitt by the Maior and
Aldermen of the said City with the consent of the Lord Archbishop of Canterbury and Lord Bishop of London,
and by his Majesties Approbation to be laid into the Streets and Markets for enlargement and accommodation
thereof or for publique Store places,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s59">
			<head>LIX. In what cases Parts of Church-yards may be used for enlarging Streets.</head>
			<para id="p122">Provided alwayes That where any part of the Churches or Church Yards of any of the said Parish Churches
hereby appointed to be rebuilt and continued have beene thought fitt by the Maior and Court of Aldermen of the
said City to be laid into any of the Streets within the said City for enlargement thereof, and by Order of the said
Maior and Court of Aldermen shall have beene before the five and twentyeth day of March one thousand six
hundred and seaventy staked and sett out accordingly It is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the Grounds
soe staked out shall be made use of for the enlargeing of the said Streets according as the same were for that
purpose staked and sett out as aforesaid, This present A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s60">
			<head>LX. Notwithstanding the Union, the Parishes as to all Rates, Charges, and Privileges to remain distin&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p123">
				<emph type="i">Presentation</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p124">Provided alwayes and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That notwithstanding such Union as aforesaid, each and
every of the Parishes soe united as to all Rates, Taxes, Parochiall Rites, Charges and Dutyes and all other
Priviledges, Liberties and Respe&bholigct;s whatsoever other then what are herein before mentioned and specifyed shall
continue and remaine distin&bholigct;, and as heretofore they were before the makeing of this present A&bholigct;. And that the
severall and respe&bholigct;ive Patrons of the said Churches soe united shall and may present by turns to that Church
onely which by this A&bholigct; is appointed to be rebuilded and established for the Parish Church of the Parishes soe
united as aforesaid. The first presentment to be made by the Patron of such of the said Churches the Endowments
whereof are of the greatest yearely value.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s61">
			<head>LXI. Proviso for the present Incumbent of Churches not to be rebuilt, as to Tithes.</head>
			<para id="p125">
				<emph type="i">Saving to the Crown of Tenths and First Fruits of united Churches.; Saving of Pensions, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p126">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be
construed to deprive the present Incumbents which at the time of the said late Fire were or now are in possession
of any of the said Parish Churches not to be rebuilded or any of them of the Tythes or other proffitts heretofore
belonging to their respe&bholigct;ive Churches soe long as they shall assist in serveing the Cure and other Offices belonging
to their Duty in the Parish Church whereunto their respe&bholigct;ive Parishes shall be united and annexed by vertue of
this A&bholigct; according to the dire&bholigct;ion of the Ordinary Any thing in this present A&bholigct; [contained<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] to the contrary
notwithstanding. Saveing to the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors the Tenthes and First fruits of all such
Parish Churches as by force of this present A&bholigct; shall be united or consolidated as aforesaid according to such
Rates and Valuations as the same doe respe&bholigct;ively stand rated and valued at in his Majestyes Court of First fruits
and Tenthes, Any thing in this present A&bholigct; notwithstanding. Saveing alsoe to all other person and persons Bodyes
Pollitique and Corporate, Ecclesiasticall and Civill their Heires and Successors all Pensions Annuities and Payments
whatsoever heretofore due from and payable by any of the Re&bholigct;ors Viccars and Curates of any of the said
Churches united or consolidated as aforesaid Any thing in this present A&bholigct; notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s62">
			<head>LXII. Proviso for Minor Canons of St. Paul as to Tithes, &amp;c. of St. Gregory.</head>
			<para id="p127">Provided alwayes That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Warden and Minor-Canons of Saint Pauls
Church London, Parson and Proprietors of the Re&bholigct;ory of. the Parish of Saint Gregories aforesaid to receive and
enjoy all Tythes, Oblations &amp; Dutyes ariseing or growing due within the said Parish in as large and beneficiall
manner as formerly they have or lawfully might have done, Any thing herein to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s63">
			<head>LXIII. Recital that the Mercers Company have designed a Free School on the Site of St. Mary Cole-Church.</head>
			<para id="p128">
				<emph type="i">The said Site, &amp;c. vested in the said Company.; Money to be paid by the Company towards rebuilding the Church to which St.Mary Cole-Church is united</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p129">And whereas the Wardens and Commonaltie of the Mistery of the Mercers of the City of London at the time
of the said Fire were seised in Fee of the Re&bholigct;ory and Parish [Church<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] Impropriate of Saint Mary Cole-Church
(the said Church being an upper Roome about Ten Foote higher then the Streete and lyeing over certaine
Roomes and arched Vaults or Cellars of the said Wardens and Commonalty) upon the Scite of which Church
they have designed to build a Free Schoole and other Buildings conformable to the Rules of the said former
A&bholigct;, and to remove the Dead Bodyes and Bones of such as have been buryed upon the Arches, and to cause
them to be decently reposed within the Body of their Chappell commonly called Mercers Chappell, Bee it
therefore hereby ena&bholigct;ed That the Scite of the said Parish Church and the Materialls thereof remaining upon
the said Scite be, and are hereby setled upon the said Wardens and Commonaltie and their Successors for ever,
And that the said Wardens and Commonaltie shall pay to the Lord Maior and Aldermen of the City of London
for the same such summe of Money towards the rebuilding of the Church whereunto the same is by this A&bholigct;
appointed to be united as shall be agreed upon betweene the said Lord Maior and Aldermen and the said Wardens
and Commonalty, or be assessed by a Jury impanneled and sworne, as by the said former A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed in any
other case, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s64">
			<head>LXIV. Provision that Parsons of Churches consumed may not be sued for Dilapidations.</head>
			<para id="p130">And whereas severall Parish Churches, Chancells, Parsonage and Vicaridge Houses were consumed in the late
dismall Fire, To the end therefore the Incumbents Parsons and Vicars may not be lyeable to the rebuilding of
their Chancells Parsonage and Vicaridge houses (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>) be sued for Dilapidations Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid
That the Incumbents Parsons and Viccars of the aforesaid Churches their Executors and Administrators shall be
and are hereby indempnifyed as to the rebuilding of their respe&bholigct;ive Chancells, Parsonage and Vicaridge houses, and
shall not be lyeable to any Suites, Troubles or Molestations that may arise for Dilapidations aforesaid, And that noe
Processe shall be issued out of any Court whatsoever against the persons aforesaid for their not rebuilding their
respe&bholigct;ive Chancells and Parsonage and Vicaridge Houses, Any Law or Statute to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s65">
			<head>LXV. The said Parsons and Vicars exempted from First Fruits, Tenths, and Pensions, and from Dues, until they receive the Profits of their Livings.</head>
			<para id="p131">And whereas First-fruits, Tenthes and severall Pensions are from the said Parsons and Vicars to be yearely paid
to his Majestie and severall Dutyes to the Ordinary and Arch-deacon That his Majestie will be graciously pleased
that it may be ena&bholigct;ed And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the said Parsons and Vicars
be indemnifyed, and are hereby indemnifyed from the payment of all First fruits, Tenthes and Pensions due or
which shall be due to his Majestie, And from all Dues to the Ordinary and Arch-Deacon and all other Dues
whatsoever chargable upon them respe&bholigct;ively untill such time as they shall receive the Proffitts ariseing from the
same as formerly, And that noe Processe shall be issued out of any Court whatsoever against the persons aforesaid
for their Non-payment of First-fruits, Tenthes, Pensions or any other the Dues aforesaid, Any Law or Statute
to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s66">
			<head>LXVI. Ministers indemnified for not reading the Thirty nine Articles.</head>
			<para id="p132">And whereas diverse Ministers have beene already since the Fire or may be from time to time presented and
instituted, and being soe are lyable to the Forfeitures of their severall Liveings for not reading the Thirty nine
Articles, and for not doeing other things enjoyned by Law in their severall Parish Churches, Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by
the authoritie aforesaid That all such Ministers as have beene or shall be from time to time presented and instituted
since the said Fire, be and are hereby indemnyfied from the severall Penaltyes and Forfeitures incurred and to be
incurred [by or<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] for not reading of the Thirty nine Articles, or not doeing other things enjoyned by Law as aforesaid,
untill such time as the said severall Churches be reedifyed or made fitt for publicke-Worship.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s67">
			<head>LXVII. Empowered to let Leases of their Glebe Lands.</head>
			<para id="p133">
				<emph type="i">Proviso as to Lapses incurred</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p134">And whereas the said Parsons and Vicars or some of them are interessed in severall Gleabe-Lands or
Grounds, the which they cannot rebuild themselves, nor let such Lease or Leases as may be an Encouragement
for others to rebuild the same Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the said Parsons and Vicars and
every of them respe&bholigct;ively be impowered and are hereby impowered to lett such Lease or Leases of their said
Gleabe Lands or Grounds with the consent and approbation of the Patron or Patrons and Ordinary for any terme
not exceeding forty yeares, and at such yearely Rents without Fine as can be obtained for the same; And that
noe Lapses incurred upon any Non-presentation in due time of any of the Patrons of the said Liveings since,
the said Fire shall any wayes prejudice or make void the Presentations [that the said Patrons<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] have since made
whereupon any Incumbent is since instituted and indu&bholigct;ed, Any Law or Statute to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s68">
			<head>LXVIII. The Judges to determine Controversies in which the City of London is a Party.</head>
			<para id="p135">Provided alwayes, and it is hereby declared and ena&bholigct;ed That if the Maior and Commonaltie and Citizens of
the said City of. London shall be concerned in Estate or Title in any controversie or difference whereof the
determination is by this, or the aforesaid A&bholigct; referred to the Heareing and Judgement of the said Maior and Court
of Aldermen That then and in every such case the Justices of the Courts of Kings Bench and Common Pleas,
and the Barons of the Coife of the Exchequer for the time being or any three or more of them upon complaint
to them made shall be and are hereby authorized to heare and finally order and determine the same, Any thing
in this or the aforesaid A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s69">
			<head>LXIX. Two Posterns at Ludgate to be made, and the Gate enlarged.</head>
			<para id="p136">[Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed [That<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] the Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen are hereby authorized and
required to cause to be made two Posterns, one on either side of the Gate c&bhooov;monly called Ludgate for the better
ease and convenience of Foote Passengers, and in order hereunto are alsoe impowered to enlarge the said Gate
as they shall finde cause.<ref idref="n34">34</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s70">
			<head>LXX. Recital of 18 &amp; 19 Car. II. c. 8. &sect; 13. (19 C. II. c. 3.&sect; 15.)</head>
			<para id="p137">
				<emph type="i">Sales for not rebuilding not to be before 24th March 1671.; In what Case such Ground not to be sold</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p138">And whereas by the said A&bholigct; for the rebuilding the City of London it was ena&bholigct;ed That where any Ground
formerly builded upon (the Houses whereupon built were demolished at the time of the said late Fire) should
not within three yeares then next ensueing be rebuilded upon Then after Proclamation publickly made and Inquiry
and Valuation made and taken of the Ground whereupon such Houses were scituate by Inquest of a Jury in such
sort and manner as in and by the said A&bholigct; is mentioned and appointed the said Maior and Aldermen and Common
Councell might make Sale thereof, It is hereby declared and ena&bholigct;ed That the said Maior, Aldermen and C&bhooov;mon
Councell shall not by vertue of the said A&bholigct; proceede to the Sale of any such Ground or Soyle whereupon any
such Houses were scituate for not rebuilding thereupon before the fower and twentyeth day of March which shall
be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and one; nor shall any Ground be sold by vertue
of this or the aforesaid A&bholigct; in case any person for the makeing of any [Court<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] Yard, Garden or [other<ref idref="n32">32</ref>]
Easement shall leave some part of the auntient Foundation unbuilt upon backwards.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s71">
			<head>LXXI. Tenants in Tail. &amp;c. may demise their Ground at the most. improved Rent without Fine.</head>
			<para id="p139">
				<emph type="i">Such Leases to bind Reversioner, &amp;c.; Houses thereupon built to be enjoyed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p140">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That all persons seised or interessed of any House or Houses burned
or demolished by reason of the said late Fire, in Taile for life or lives or yeares determinable upon life with remainder
to their Heires or Issue male or female or to their first or other Sonne or Sonnes, Daughter or Daughters in Taile
or other like Estate, That it shall and may be lawfull to and for such Tennant in Taile for Life or Yeares with
such Remainder as aforesaid by Indenture under their respe&bholigct;ive Hands and Seales to demise the Ground or Soyle
of such burned or demolished Houses without any Fine or Fines, and at the most improved annuall Rent to any
person or persons that shall or will rebuild thereupon for any terme of yeares not exceeding fifty yeares, Which
Leases soe made shall binde and conclude aswell all and every the [Heires and<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] Issue of such Tennant in Taile as
the first and every other Sonne and Sonnes, Daughter or Daughters or other Issue of such Tennant for Life or
Yeares as those in Reversion or Remainder, and the Houses thereupon built shall be held and enjoyed by the
respe&bholigct;ive Lessees thereof and their Assignes (paying the said Rent to the persons in Reversion or Remainder dureing
the Terme and according to the purporte of such Leases) by vertue of this present A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s72">
			<head>LXXII. The King and Privy Council may determine Differences concerning Sergeants Inn in Fleet Street;</head>
			<para id="p141">
				<emph type="i">and to order Recompense to Rob: Mellish Esq. and to decree a Lease of Premises belonging to Dean and Chapter of York</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p142">Provided alwayes, and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That as to the House called Sergeants
Inne in Fleete streete, of which the Society of Judges and Sergeants at Law were Tennants at the time of the late
Fire and many yeares before That the Kings most Excellent Majestie his Heires &amp; Successors and his or their
Privy Councell shall be and are hereby impowered to heare and determine all Differences and Demands whatsoever
touching the said House with the appurtenances and all things else to doe relateing to the rebuilding thereof, and
to make Orders and Decrees concerning the same as fully to all intents and purposes as the Judges of the Courts
of Kings Bench and Common Pleas and Barons of the Exchequer might, could or may doe concerning any [other<ref idref="n32">32</ref>]
Houses burnt downe by the late Fire by vertue of this and the said former A&bholigct; or either of them; And his
said Majestie and Councell are [hereby alsoe<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] impowered to order and decree such satisfa&bholigct;ion and recompence unto
Robert Mellish of the Inner Temple Esquire as to them shall seeme just and reasonable, and to order and decree
one Lease of the Premisses whereof the Inheritance belongeth to the Deane and Chapter of Yorke not exceeding
in the whole sixty yeares for the use of the said Society, and the said Deane and Chapter and their Successors
[are<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] hereby enabled and enjoyned to make accordingly, And what shall be soe ordered or decreed by his said
Majestie &amp; Councell as aforesaid shall be good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law to all intents and purposes by vertue of this
A&bholigct;; And the said Judges and Barons of the Exchequer are hereby excluded from makeing any Order or Decree
touching the said House with the appurtenances.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s73">
			<head>LXXIII. Houses pulled down near Tower Ditch not to be rebuilt.</head>
			<para id="p143">
				<emph type="i">Differences about certain other Houses, as to Breach of Covenant, referred to the said Judges</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p144">And whereas a great number of Houses heretofore ere&bholigct;ed and built upon or very neare to the Tower Ditch
of the City London were at, or a litle time after the said late great Fire pulled or blowne downe for safeguard
of the said Tower and are not thought fitt to be rebuilt there, And whereas some Houses are yet standing which
were in Lease for severall yeares yet to come, with other Houses pulled downe at and for certaine intire yearely
Rents, which said [Houses<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] are wholly now claimed by diverse Landlords as if the said Houses were yet standing:
and diverse Suites in Law are and will be dayly brought against Tennants for breach of Covenants of the said
Leases incurred since that time Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the said Justices and
Barons or any three or more of them shall have full power and authority to heare and determine all Differences
that may arise betweene the said Landlords and Tennants as if the said Houses had perished by the late
dreadfull Fire.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s74">
			<head>LXXIV. Shops, &amp;c. in Smithfield, Moor-fields; and other void Places ere&bholigct;ed since the Fire, to be taken down and removed before the 29th Sept. 1674.</head>
			<para id="p145">And whereas severall Sheds Shops and other Buildings have beene ere&bholigct;ed (since the late dreadfull Fire) in
Smithfeild, Moore feilds and other void places within the said City and Libertyes thereof by License of the Lord
Maior Aldermen and Common Councell of the said City for the accommodation of such Inhabitants whose Houses
were then burnt or demolished for the better carrying on of their respe&bholigct;ive Trades, which if they should be
suffered to have longer continuance then the present Exigency of the Occupiers thereof doth require would be
an occasion to divert the Trade of the City, and to discourage such as have rebuilt Houses within the said City
Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen for the time
being shall be and are hereby impowered and required to cause all and every the said Sheds, Shops and other
Buildings aforesaid to be taken downe and removed at or before the nine and twentyeth day of September which
shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy fower.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s75">
			<head>LXXV. In A&bholigct;ion brought for executing A&bholigct; General Issue may be pleaded.</head>
			<para id="p146">
				<emph type="i">Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p147">Provided alwayes, and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion or Suite shall be brought
or prosecuted against any person or persons for any matter or thing done, committed or executed by vertue of
this or the aforesaid A&bholigct; for rebuilding the said City of London, or of any Clause or Article in. this or the
aforesaid A&bholigct; contained, That then and in every such Case the Defendant or Defendants may pleade the Generall
Issue (Not guilty) and give this A&bholigct; and the speciall matter in Evidence at any Tryall thereupon to be had, and
if a Verdi&bholigct; shall passe for the Defendant, or the Plaintiffe shall be Nonsuite, or discontinue his A&bholigct;ion after the
Defendant hath appeared, the Defendant shall recover double Costs to be awarded for this or their wrongfull
vexation in that behalfe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s76">
			<head>LXXVI. Proviso for A&bholigct;s done by virtue of Commissions pursuant to 1 Eliz. c. 11. &sect;2. 14(13&amp;14) C. II. c. 11. &sect; 14. as to appointing Wharfs, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p148">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be construed to alter or
make void any matter or thing done or to be done by vertue of any Commission or Commissions given or
granted or to be given or granted by his Majestie his Heires or Successors in pursuance of two A&bholigct;s of Parlyament
[viz<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] One in the first yeare of Queene Elizabeth and another in the fowerteenth yeare of his now Majestyes Raigne,
or of either of them, or of any other Law or Right, whereby his Majesty his Heires and Successors may or ought
to appoint such and soe many open places to be Keyes and Wharfes within the City of London, and may alsoe
declare the Bounds, Limitts, Extents and Priviledges of the Port of London and all other Ports of England with
severall other Powers and Priviledges for the preservation of his Majestyes Revenue of the Customes colle&bholigct;ed there,
Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">within <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">his <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Aldermen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">Merchandize <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">o'the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a feparate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">interlined on the Roll <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">could <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">Lumbard <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">Parishes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">be dire&bholigct;ed and appointed <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">Churches <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">nor <emph type="i">O</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">alsoe hereby <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">Rents <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


