<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47420" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII An Additionall Act for the better repairing of Highwayes and Bridges. [Rot. Parl.22 C. II. nu. 12.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Surveyors, &amp;c. to cause A&bholigct;s of Parliament for repairing the Highways to be executed.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i"> Negle&bholigct;ing, &amp;c, Penalty; how to be levied and employed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the better repairing and amending of the Highwayes, now generally spoyled by the extraordinary and
unreasonable ladeing of Waggens and other Carriages and the negle&bholigct; of repaireing and preserveing the same
Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That
all Constables and Surveyours of the Highwayes from time to time dureing their continuance in such their Office
or Offices shall cause the severall A&bholigct;s of Parlyament heretofore made and yet in force for or touching the repaireing;
amending or enlargeing of Highwayes not hereby in any part altered or repealed to be putt in Execution within
the Limits of their respe&bholigct;ive Parishes and places, and the penaltyes thereby imposed to be leavyed and disposed of
as by the said severall A&bholigct;s is dire&bholigct;ed, And every Constable &amp; Surveyour of the Highwayes refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing
to putt the said A&bholigct;s in Execution or wilfully suffering any Waggons or Carts to passe through his respe&bholigct;ive
Limitts with any more Horses or other Carle or in other manner then by this A&bholigct; is allowed shall upon complaint
thereof made to any Justice of the Peace of the place or division, where such negle&bholigct; shall be proved to be
done by the Oath of any one credible Witnesse (which Oath such Justice is hereby impowered to administer) or
upon view of the Justice himselfe be thereof convi&bholigct;ed, and shall incurr such Fine as the same Justice shall thinke
fitt to impose on such Officer not exceeding the summe of forty shillings for any one offence, The same Fine
to be leavyed by the High Constable of such place or division, or any other Officer [by Warrant<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] under the Hand
and Seale of such Justices of the Peace upon the Goods and Chattells of the persons soe offending (rendering the
overplus to the Owner thereof, all necessary charge in leavying the same being first dedu&bholigct;ed) to be imployed
for the amending of the Highwayes of the Parish or place where such negle&bholigct; shall be found as the said Justice
or Justices shall appoint for the doeing thereof</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Lands given for Maintenance of Causeys, &amp;c. to be farmed at the most improved yearly Value without Fine.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Justices in Sessions to inquire into the Value of Lands, &amp;c. Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That where any Lands have beene or shall be given for the maintenance of
Causeys, Pavements, Highwayes and Bridges, all such persons that are or shall be enfeoffed or trusted with any
such Lands shall lett them to farme at the most improved yearely value without Fine, And that the Justice of
the Peace in their open Sessions shall and may enquire by such wayes and meanes as they thinke fitting into
the value of all such Lands soe given or to be given, and order the improvement and imployment of the Rents
and Proffitts thereof according to the Will and Dire&bholigct;ion of the Donor of such Lands if they finde that the persons
[soe<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] intrusted have beene negligent or faulty in the performance of their Trust (except such Lands as have beene
given to the Uses aforesaid to any Colledge or Hall in either of the Universityes of this Kingdome which have
Visitors of their owne) Any Law, Statute, Usage or Custome to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. 14 (13 &amp; 14) C. II. c. 6. &sect; 8. repealed.</head>
			<para id="p5">And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed That one Clause contained in the A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament Entituled An A&bholigct;
for enlargeing of Highwayes concerning the breadth of the Tyre of all Waggon and Cart Wheeles, is and shall
hereby stand repealed and be void.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Resisting Officers employed in executing A&bholigct;, rescuing Goods, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 40s or Imprisonment; A&bholigct;ions brought under this A&bholigct; to be laid in the proper County; General Issue, Treble Costs, Times for repairing the Highways</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed That in case any person or persons shall resist or make forceable opposition against
any person or persons imployed in the due Execution of this A&bholigct; or any the A&bholigct;s before mentioned, or shall
make any Rescue of any Cattell or other Goods destrained by vertue of this or any of the said A&bholigct;s That every
such person being thereof convi&bholigct;ed in manner aforesaid shall for every such Offences forfeite the summe of forty
shillings, And in case he doe not pay the said summe within seaven dayes after notice of such Convi&bholigct;ion,
Then it shall and may be lawfull for any Justice of the Peace resideing neere the place where such Opposition
or Rescue shall be made to committ such person or persons to the Common Goale of the County where such
Offence shall be committed, there to remaine untill the said Forfeiture shall be paid to the Surveyour or
Surveyours of the Highwayes for that Parish where the Offence was committed to be imployed for the amendment
of the Highwayes of the same Parish; And if any A&bholigct;ion or Suite shall be brought against any person or persons
for or by reason of any matter or thing done by meanes of this A&bholigct;, the same shall be laid in the proper
County where the Fa&bholigct; was done and not elsewhere, and the Defendants may pleade the generall Issue and give
the speciall matter in Evidence, And if it appeare at the Tryall that the Fa&bholigct; was done by Authoritie of this
A&bholigct;, and the Jury shall finde for the Defendant, he thereupon (as alsoe in case the Plaintiffe be Non suite
or discontinue his A&bholigct;ion) shall recover his treble Costs sustained by reason of such A&bholigct;ion or Suite, Provided
That in such places where the Highwayes cannot be sufficiently repaired before the Feast of the Nativity of Saint
John Baptist yearely, the same may and shall be sufficiently repaired before the Feast of Saint Luke yearely
without incurring any penalty for the not doeing thereof before the said Feast of the Nativity of Saint John Baptist
according to the said former A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Defe&bholigct;s to be presented in the County where the Places defe&bholigct;ive lie.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">When Certiorari allowed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all defe&bholigct;s of Repaires of Causeys, Pavements,
Highwayes or Bridges shall be presented in the County onely where such Causeys, Pavements Highwayes or
Bridges doe lye, and not elsewhere, and that noe such Presentment or Indi&bholigct;ment shall be removed by Certiorari
or otherwise out of the said County, till such Indi&bholigct;ment or Presentment be traversed and Judgement thereupon
given.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Lands, Houses, &amp;c. in the Suburbs of London, South wark, and Westminster, made liable to Assessments for the Scavengers, as by 14 (13 &amp; 14) C. II. c. 6.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Quarter Sessions may determine Disputes as to Liability</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That the severall Occupiers and Inhabitants, or where there are noe
Inhabitants or Occupiers the respe&bholigct;ive Owners of all and singular the Lands, Houses, Outhouses, Walls and
Buildings fronting and adjoyning to any of the Highwayes Streetes or Lanes within the Suburbs of London and
the Liberties thereof and the Burrough of Southwarke, and the City and Liberty of Westminster or Precin&bholigct;s
thereof which are or shall be paved shall and are hereby lyeable to all Rates, Assessments, Penaltyes and Distresses
which shall be had or made towards the Scavengers Rates for the places aforesaid, in such manner as by an
A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament made and ena&bholigct;ed in the fowerteenth yeare of his Majestyes Raigne for repaireing
of the Highwayes and Sewers is dire&bholigct;ed and appointed, [And<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] that where any Ground shall lye at the end of any
of the said Streets or Lanes, or any other place of which there may be a dispute who ought to pave or amend
the same that in such case the Justices of Peace for the said places respe&bholigct;ively shall have hereby full power and
authoritie in their Quarter Sessions to order and determine the same which Order shall be binding to all persons
whatsoever therein concerned, Any Law or Statute to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Travelling Waggons, Wains, &amp;c. carrying Goods, &amp;c. shall be drawn but with Five Horses in Length; a greater Number to draw in Pairs.</head>
			<para id="p12">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That from and after the Fower and twentyeth day of
June next ensueing noe traveling Waggon, Wayne, Cart or Carriage wherein any Burdens Goods or Wares are
or shall be carryed (other then such Carts and Carriages as are imployed in and about Husbandry and Manureing
of Lands and in the carrying of Hay, Straw, Corne unthresht, Coale, Chalke, Timber for Shipping, Materialls
for Building, Stones of all sortes, or such Ammunition or Artillery which shall be for his Majestyes Service) shall
at any one time travell or be drawne, or goe in any common or publique Highway or Road with above Five Horse
Beasts at length, and if any shall draw with a greater number of Horses or Oxen they shall all draw in paires that is
to say two a breast for such number as they shall use except one Horse; Any Law, Statute or Usage to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Owners of Waggons, &amp;c. offending;</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 40s.; How levied</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That every Owner of any Wagon, Cart, Carriage, Horse Beasts or Oxen offending
contrary to this A&bholigct; shall forfeite for every of the said Offences the summe of forty shillings, One third part
thereof to the Surveyours of the Highwayes of the Towne, Village or Hamblet where any the said Offences shall
be committed to be employed in the Repaires of the said Highwayes, One other third part to the Overseers
of the Poore of the Parish, where any of the said Offences shall be committed to the use of the Poore of the
said Parish, and the other third part to him that shall discover the same to be [imposed and<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] leavyed in such
manner as the penaltyes in this A&bholigct; imposed on every Constable or Surveyour of the Highwayes for refuseing
or negle&bholigct;ing to putt in Execution the severall A&bholigct;s of Parlyament yet in force for, or touching the repaireing,
amending or enlargeing of such Highwayes are dire&bholigct;ed and appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. In Places where Carta or Teams not used for mending the Highways, Inhabitants to send Horses and other Carriages.</head>
			<para id="p15">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That in such places where there is noe use of Carts and
Teemes for the amendment of Highwayes, but the Usage and Pra&bholigct;ise is to carry Stones, Gravell, Earth, or other
Materialls for such amendment upon the backes of Horses, or by any other kinds of Carriages, That in all such
places the Inhabitants useing any such Horses or other Carriages shall send in such their Horses as are accustomed
to that kinde of labour, and such their other Carriages with able persons to worke with the same in like manner,
and under the like Dire&bholigct;ions, Forfeitures and Penaltyes as by any former Statute for repaireing of Highwayes, is
appointed for Carts and Teemes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Making Default in repairing Highways;</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Surveyor to complain to Justices; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">Provided alsoe and it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any person or persons shall faile or
(<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) make defaulte to doe their respe&bholigct;ive Dayes Labour in every yeare for and towards the repaireing of the
Highwayes or negcle&bholigct; to send their respe&bholigct;ive Carriages Horses and Carts according as by Law they are respe&bholigct;ively
required, It shall and may be lawfull for the Surveyour or Surveyours of every Parish, and they are hereby
required to make complaint thereof to the next Justices of the Peace, who are hereby authorized and required upon
proofe of any such Defaulte or Negle&bholigct; made before them by the Oath of one credible Witnesse (which Oath
they are hereby impowered to administer) to leavy by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of every person faileing
or negle&bholigct;ing as aforesaid (and not haveing a reasonable Excuse to be allowed by the said Justices) the severall
Penaltyes hereafter mentioned (rendering the Overplus) reasonable Charges of destraining being first dedu&bholigct;ed)
that is to say</para>
			<para id="p18">For every Day labourer faileing or negle&bholigct;ing as is aforesaid One shilling and six pence,</para>
			<para id="p19">And for every Man and Horse that shall make defaulte three shillings,</para>
			<para id="p20">And for every Cart with two Men ten shillings for every respe&bholigct;ive day wherein they shall make defaulte,</para>
			<para id="p21">Which respe&bholigct;ive Penaltyes soe leavyed shall be employed for and towards the repaireing of the Highwayes in
every respe&bholigct;ive place and Parish.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Assessment, when to be made by Quarter Sessions for repairing the Highways.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">To be levied by Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That where the Justices of the Peace of any County, City
or other place, or the major part of them at their generall Quarter Sessions [shall be fully satisfyed<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] that the
common Highwayes, Causeys or Bridges within any Parish, Towneshipp or Hamblet within their respe&bholigct;ive
Jurisdi&bholigct;ion may not, or will not be sufficiently amended, repaired and supported by meanes of the Lawes now in
force without the helpe of this present A&bholigct;, in all such cases one or more Assesment or Assesments upon all and
every the Inhabitants Owners and Occupyers of [Houses, Lands<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Tenements and Hereditaments, or any personall
Estate usually rateable to the poore within any such Parish, Township or Hamlet shall be made, leavyed, colle&bholigct;ed
and allowed by such person and persons and in such manner as the said Justices by their Order at such Sessions
shall dire&bholigct; and appoint in that behalfe, And the Money thereby raised shall be employed and accounted for
according to the order and dire&bholigct;ions of the said Justices for and towards the amending, repaireing and supporting
such Highwayes Causeys and Bridges from time to time as neede shall require. And the said [Assessment or<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
Assessments shall be leavyed by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of every person soe assessed (not paying the
same within ten dayes after demand) rendering the Overplus of the value of the Goods soe destrained to the Owner
or Owners thereof (the necessary charges of makeing and selling such Distresse being first dedu&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Assessment not to exceed Sixpence in the Pound of yearly Value of Lands, nor Sixpence for &pound; 20 of Personal Estate.</head>
			<para id="p24">Provided neverthelesse and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That noe such Assesment or Assesments to be made in any one
yeare shall exceede the rate of six pence in the pound of the yearely value of any Lands Houses Tenements and
Hereditaments soe assessed, nor the rate of six pence for twenty pounds in personall Estate, and that noe such
Assesment be made or leavyed from and after the five and twentyeth day of March in the yeare One thousand six
hundred seaventy and three.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Surveyors of Highways when to be chosen as by</head>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">2 &amp; 3 P. &amp; M. c.8; their Duty in appointing Days for Work, &amp;c.; to make a Return of Defaulters to Justice, who is to present the same to Quarter Sessions; Offenders to incur Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That from and after the nine and twentyeth day. of
September next in every Parish within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke.
upon Tweede the Surveyours and Orderers of the worke for amendment of the Highwayes within their respe&bholigct;ive
Parishes shall be yearely chosen and nominated by such persons as by an A&bholigct; made in the second and third
Yeares of King Phillip and Queene Mary is appointed upon some day in the same weeke that the Feast of the
Birth of our Lord commonly called Christmas day shall be: Which persons soe nominated and chosen shall take
upon them the said Office and shall appoint six dayes for the provideing Stones, Gravell and other Materialls
for the amendment of and for workeing in the Highwayes haveing respe&bholigct; to the Season of the Yeare and the
Weather, and giveing Notice publiquely some convenient time before the severall dayes; at which dayes all persons
lyable to the said Worke shall attend and worke accordingly: And the said Surveyours and Orderers shall make
Returne of the Defaulters and every of them within one moneth after every defaulte made, to some neighbouring
Justice of the Peace of the same County; and the said Justice shall present the same at the Quarter Sessions of
the Peace held next after such Returne made unto him; And the Offenders against this A&bholigct; in all cases not
perticularly dire&bholigct;ed in this A&bholigct;, shall respe&bholigct;ively incurr the same Forfeitures, Paines and Penaltyes infli&bholigct;ed and
appointed by the Lawes and Statutes of this Kingdome now in force for the amending of the Highwayes as fully
as if they had beene perticularly mentioned and imposed in and by this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Recital that there are many Rivers in Cheshire and Lancashire that are dangerous for want of Bridges.</head>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">Bridges to be built in Cheshire and Lancashire within Ten Years, and Bridges demolished in the late War to be repaired; Charges for the same to be levied as by 22 H. VIII. c. 5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p28">And whereas in the Countyes of Chester and Lancaster there are many and sundry great and deepe Rivers
which runn crosse and through the common and publique Highwayes and Roads within the said Countyes which
many times cannot be passed over without hazard and losse of the Lives and Goods of the Inhabitants and
Travellers within the said Countyes for want of convenient, good and sufficient Bridges in the said Highwayes and
Roads, to build and ere&bholigct; which there is noe Law [now<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] in force Therefore bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie
aforesaid That for ten yeares next following and noe longer the respe&bholigct;ive Justices of Peace within the said
respe&bholigct;ive Countyes shall upon the presentment of the Grand Jury at their respe&bholigct;ive generall Quarter Sessions
have power and authority by Order or Warrant under the Hands and Seales of all, or the major part of the
said Justices being six at least then present to cause to be ere&bholigct;ed and builded any new Bridge or Bridges in
such place or places in any of the said Highwayes over any of the said Rivers within their respe&bholigct;ive Jurisdi&bholigct;ions
as they shall judge fitt and necessary and soe declare by such Order as aforesaid, and likewise to repaire or
rebuild such other Bridges as were demolished in the late Warr, And by their said Order to charge either their
whole respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, or any Hundred or Hundreds within their said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes with the ere&bholigct;ing
and building any such Bridge or Bridges, and from time to time (as neede shall require) with the repaireing
&amp; amending of all or any the said Bridges, which shall be assessed, leavyed and gathered in such sort, manner
and forme as the Moneyes for repaireing of Bridges now in being are used to be assessed leavyed and gathered
by vertue of the late Statute in the two and twentyeth yeare of the Raigne of the late King Henry the Eighth
in that case made and provided.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Six Justices of Monmouth in Sessions may levy for Usk and Basalegg Bridges.</head>
			<para id="p29">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for any six
or more Justices of Peace of the County of Monmouth whereof two to be of the Quorum at [the<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] generall Sessions
of the Peace to be held for that County at any time hereafter dureing ten yeares and noe longer to impose and
leavy any summe or summes of Money upon the said County for the repaireing and amending of Uske and
Basalegg Bridges which are scituate upon great Rivers, and lye on very publique Roads of that County, soe as
the summe soe imposed as aforesaid exceede not in the whole in any one yeare the summe of forty pounds,
Which Imposition soe laid shall be leavyed and accounted for by the same way and manner as the other Rates
raised for Bridges formerly setled by A&bholigct; of Parlyament for that County are made and provided.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Lands Houses <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">their <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


