<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47428" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act for revesting the Power of granting Wine Licences in his Majesty his Heires and Successors and for; setleing a Recompence on his Royall Highnesse in liew thereof.; [Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 <emph type="i">C. II. p. 1. nu</emph>. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 15 C. II. c. 14. &sect;1.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">&sect;11.; and that by reason of 20 C. II. c. I. (19 &amp; 20 C. II. C. 6.); and 22 Car. II. c. 3. the Prices of Wine had been raised, and that the Revenue of Wine Licences should be vested in the Crown, and that in Recompence a yearly Sum of &pound;24,000 was to be granted to the Duke of York, issuing out of the Duties of Beer, &amp;c. by; 12 C. II. C. 24.; 13 C. II. st. I. c. 7.; Recital of Tenure and Times of Payment of the said Annuity; and of Power for the Duke and his Heires Male to make Provision there out for their Wives and Children; and that the said Annuity had been granted for Two Years by Letters Patent 28th Sep. 22 Car. II.; The Revenue of Wine Licences, and Moiety of all Penalties, vested in the King.; 15 Car. II. c. 14.; Freed from Jointures and Provisions for younger Children by the Duke</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in and by one A&bholigct;t passed this present Parliament in the fifteenth yeare of his Majestyes Raigne
Entituled An A&bholigct;t for setling the Proffitts of the Post-Office and Power of granting Wine-Licences on his
Royall Highnesse the Duke of Yorke and the Heires Males of his Body It is amongst other things ena&bholigct;ted That
the said Duke of Yorke and the Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten should have all and every
the powers and authorities of granting Licences to such person or persons as he or they shall thinke fitt to sell
and utter by Retaile all and every and any kinde of Wine or Wines whatsoever to be drunke or spent aswell
within the House and Houses or other place in the Tenure or Occupation of the party soe licensed as without
in any Citty, Towne or other place whatsoever within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne
of Berwicke upon Tweede together with all benefitt thereof. And alsoe that the said Duke and the Heires Males
of his Body begotten or to be begotten should have that moyety of the [Forfeitures<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and Penalties which by vertue
of a former A&bholigct;t therein recited was given to his Majestie his Heires and Successors. And therein it was [further<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
provided That it should be lawfull for the said Duke and the Heires Males of his Body begotten and to be
begotten to setle any part of the Premisses not exceeding a third part of the cleare yearely value above Charges
and Reprises for a Joynture for his or their Wife or Wives, And alsoe to lease any other part of the said
Premisses for any number of yeares not exceeding One and twenty yeares, and not exceeding one other third
part of the cleare yearely value of the Premisses in order to raise Portions for his and their younger Children as
by the said recited A&bholigct;t amongst other things therein contained, relation being thereunto had more at large may appeare.
And whereas by reason of one other A&bholigct;t passed this present Parlyament in the twentyeth yeare of his now
Majestyes Raigne Entituled An A&bholigct;t for raiseing three hundred and ten thousand pounds by an Imposition upon
Wines and other Liquors. And one other A&bholigct;t passed this Parlyament in the two and twentyeth yeare of his now
Majestyes Raigne Entituled An A&bholigct;t for granting unto his Majestie an Imposition upon all Wines and Vinegar imported
betweene the fower and twentyeth day of June thousand six hundred and seaventy and the fower and twentyeth
day of June one thousand six hundred seaventy eight the prices of Wines have beene much raised, and the
Retailers much discouraged from takeing Licence, Whereupon his Majestie hath thought it fitt and most advantagious
for his Service that the Revenue ariseing by granting Licences to sell Wine by Retaile should be vested in his
Majesty his Heires and Successors, And in compensation and full satisfa&bholigct;tion thereof hath agreed to and with
his said dearest Brother James Duke of Yorke to grant and convey by his Letters Patents under the Great Seale
of England hereafter to be made the yearely Rent or yearely Summe of twenty fower thousand pounds to be
issueing out of that part of his Majestyes Revenue ariseing from the Excise of Beere, Ale and other Liquors
which is setled upon his Majestie his Heires and Successors by vertue of an A&bholigct;t or reputed A&bholigct;t made in the
Twelfth yeare of his Majestyes Raigne Entituled An A&bholigct;t for takeing away the Court of Wards and Liveryes and
Tenures in Capite and by Knight Service and Purveyance taken away and for setleing a Revenue on his Majesty
in lieu thereof, And of another A&bholigct;t passed in this Parlyament in the thirteenth yeare of his [now<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Majestyes
Raigne whereby the last mentioned A&bholigct;t is confirmed, The which said yearely summe of twenty fower thousand
pounds is to be issueing out of the Excise of Beere Ale and other Liquors ariseing and growing due unto his
Majestie [out<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] of all and every the severall Countyes and Shires of Buckingham, Essex, Kent, Norffolke, Suffolke,
Berkeshire, Bedfordshire, Cambridgeshire, Yorkeshire Hertfordshire and Somersetshire To have and to hold the said
yearely Rent or yearely Summe of twenty fower thousand pounds soe issueing out of the said Countyes as aforesaid
from the fower and twentyeth day of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
seaventy and two unto the said James Duke of Yorke and the Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be
begotten payable upon the fower most usuall Feasts in the yeare That is to say Upon the Feasts of Saint Michaell
the Arch Angell, the Nativity of our Lord Christ, the Annunciation of the Blessed Virgin Mary, and the Nativity
of Saint John the Baptist by even and equall portions, The first payment to beginne and be made at the Feast of
Saint Michaell the Arch Angell which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and
two, And with the like Powers for the said Duke and the Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten
to make provision for [his and<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] their Wives and Children as the said Duke and the Heires Males of his Body had
in the Revenue of the Wine Licences setled upon him by the said first recited A&bholigct;t of Parlyament. The which said
yearely Summe of twenty fower thousand pounds his Majesty by his Letters of Privy Seale dated or to be dated
on or about the eight and twentyeth day of September in the two and twentyeth yeare of his Majestyes Raigne
did grant to be paid for two yeares to commence from the fower and twentyeth day of June in the two and
twentyeth yeare of his Majestyes Raigne in such manner and by such quarterly payments as is therein mentioned
for the payment thereof. Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ted by the Kings most excellent Majesty by and with the advice
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the
authority of the same That the said Revenue of Wine Licences with all the Proffitts thereof together with all
such Estate, Right, Title and Interest thereof which was setled upon the said Duke and the Heires Males of his
Body begotten by the said first recited A&bholigct;t of Parlyament together with all and every the Powers of granting
Licences for the retaileing of Wines within the Kingdome of England, Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede and all Benefitts, Proffitts and Advantages of the said Powers and alsoe all that moyety of the
Forfeitures and all other the Forfeitures and Penaltyes for retaileing Wines without Licence incurred for any Offence
which shall be committed after the fower and twentyeth day of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred and seaventy except as is hereafter in this A&bholigct;t excepted shall from and after the fower
and twentyeth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and seaventy be setled and
vested in his said Majesty his Heires and Successors discharged of all Joyntures and Powers of makeing Joyntures
and Provisions for younger Children made by the said James Duke of Yorke if any such be for or notwithstanding
any A&bholigct;t, Matter or Thing contained in the said first recited A&bholigct;t whereby the said Revenue is setled upon the said
James Duke of Yorke in manner as aforesaid.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for a Moiety of the Forfeitures incurred before the 24th November 1670, and of Arrears of Rent to 24th June 1670, to the Duke.</head>
			<para id="p3">Saveing and excepting out of this A&bholigct;t unto the said Duke of Yorke all that moyety or moyetyes of all and
every the Forfeitures and Penaltyes incurred or to be incurred for retaileing of Wines without Lincence before the
fower and twentyeth day of November in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and seaventy. And
alsoe reserveing to the said Duke all Rents and Arreares of Rents due on or before the twenty fowerth Day of
June in the said yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and seaventy for the benefitt of the said Duke
with the like Power to sue for the same as the said Duke had before the passing of this A&bholigct;t Any thing therein
contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Letters Patent of the 1st Nov. 22 Car. II. For granting &pound;24,000 per Annum to the Duke and his Heirs Male in lieu of the Wine Licences, to stand good in Law.</head>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the authoritie aforesaid That his Majestyes Letters Patents under the Greate
Seale of England to beare date any time after the first day of November in the two and twentyeth yeare of his
Majestyes Raigne or at any time hereafter to be made wherein and whereby there shall be granted or mentioned
to be granted unto the said James Duke of Yorke and the Heires males of his Body begotten or to be begotten
the said yearely Rent or yearely summe of twenty fower thousand pounds to be issueing out of his Majestyes
Revenue of Excise of Beere Ale and other Liquors setled upon his Majesty his Heires and Successors in manner
as aforesaid And out of the said Countyes of Buckingham, Essex, Kent Norffolke Suffolke Berks Bedfordshire
Cambridgeshire Yorkeshire Hertfordshire and Somersetshire lyable to the payment thereof and to be paid at such
dayes and times and by such proportions and subje&bholigct;t to such powers for makeing Joyntures and Provisions for
younger Children of the said Duke and of the Heires males of his Body begotten or to be begotten as shall be
mentioned in the said Letters Patents or in any other Letters Patents or Writeings hereafter to be made for the
granting conveying and setleing of the said yearely Rent or yearely Summe of twenty fower thousand pounds to
the said Duke and to the Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten, or which shall concerne the
yearely payment of the said twenty fower thousand pounds unto the said Duke and the Heires Males of his Body,
and alsoe his Majestyes Letters of Privy Seale for payment of twenty fower thousand pounds per ann? dureing
the two yeares therein mentioned shall stand, be good effectuall [and <ref idref="n3">3</ref>] available in the Law to all purposes
constructions and intents whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Nonrecitals or Mis recitals in the same Letters Patent.</head>
			<para id="p5">And alsoe it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the Clauses Articles Provisoes, Reservations Powers
Limitations and Agreements to be contained in his said Majestyes Letters Patents hereafter to be made, or
in any other Letters Patents or Writeings hereafter to be made of for or concerning his Majestyes conveying and
setleing of the said yearely Summe of twenty fower thousand pounds unto the said Duke of Yorke and to the
Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten, or of, for or concerning the yearely or quarterly payments
thereof at such respe&bholigct;ive times as shall be appointed for the true payment thereof and every part thereof shall
be and are hereby enacted to be good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law according to the tenour and purport thereof in the
said Letters Patents to be expressed, Any misrecitall or non-recitall o&bhooov;mission or other defe&bholigct;t or imperfection in
the said Letters Patents or Writeings made or hereafter to be made of for or concerning the granting of the said
[yearely <ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Rent or yearely Summe of twenty fower thousand pounds unto the said Duke and to the Heires Males of
his Body begotten or to be begotten in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. By whom and how the &pound;24,000 per Ann. is to be paid;</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">without Deduction.; Acquittance of the Duke, &amp;c. to be a Discharge</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwayes and it is hereby further enacted and declared That the said yearely Rent or yearely Summe
of twenty fower thousand pounds shall be paid unto the said Duke of Yorke and to the Heires Males of his Body
begotten or to be begotten at the said fower usuall Feasts of the yeare by and from the immediate Hands of all
and every the Farmers Co&bhooov;mis?ers Sub-Co&bhooov;mis?ers Receivers or Colle&bholigct;ors for the time being of the said Revenue
ariseing from the said Excise of Beere Ale and other Liquors in all and every the said Countyes or of any other
person or persons who shall receive the said Revenue of the said Countyes before the same be paid into the Receipt
of his Majestyes Exchequer without any abatement, dedu&bholigct;ion or defalcations whatsoever for or by reason of the
payment of the same and that the Acquittance of the said Duke or of the Heires Males of his Body, or of his
or their Receiver shall be a sufficient discharge to all intents and purposes whatsoever for the true payment
thereof. Any Contra&bholigct;t Covenant or other matter or thing made or to be made to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. The same to be paid Quarterly without Fee, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p8">And it is alsoe hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the said yearely Rent or yearely Summe of twenty
fower thousand pounds shall be satisfyed and paid unto the said Duke of Yorke and to the Heires Males of his
Body begotten or to be begotten or to his or their Receiver Generall for the time being at the said fower usuall
Feasts of Saint Michaell the Arch Angell, the Nativity of our Lord Christ, the Annunciation of the Blessed Virgin
Mary and the Nativity of Saint John Baptist by equall portions without paying or allowing any Fees or other
abatement whatsoever either in the said Court of Exchequer or to any Officers of the said Court or elsewhere
upon payment of the said [yearely <ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Summe of twenty fower thousand pounds or upon payment of any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Commissioners, &amp;c. neglecting Payment of the said &pound;24,000;</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">the Duke may prosecute</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And if the said Farmers Co&bhooov;missers Sub Co&bhooov;missers Receivers Colle&bholigct;ors or such other person or persons which
shall receive the said Dutye of the said Countyes for the time being or any of them shall refuse or negcle&bholigct; to
pay the said twenty fower thousand pounds per ann? or any part thereof to the said Duke and the Heires Males
of his Body begotten or to be begotten. That then the said Duke and the Heires Males of his Body begotten or
to be begotten may sue, prosecute and impleade the said Farmers Co&bhooov;missers Sub Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers Receivers Colle&bholigct;ors or
such other person or persons as shall receive the said Duty of the said Countyes or any of them and all or any
of their Securityes by Bill Plaint A&bholigct;ion of Debt or Information either in his Majestyes Name or in his or their
owne Names, and shall and may recover, have Judgement and Executions thereupon against the said Farmers,
Co&bhooov;mis?ers Sub co&bhooov;mis?ers, Receivers, Colle&bholigct;ors, or such other person or persons as shall receive the said Dutye in
the said Countyes their Securityes or any of them their Executors or Administrators.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for Persons having sold Wines. by Retail before the 24th November 22 Car. II.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwayes That noe person or persons shall be sued, prosecuted, impleaded or molested for the selling
and uttering of Wines by Retaile without Licence before the said fower and twentyeth day of November in the
two and twentyeth yeare of his Majestyes Raigne or for any the herein before excepted Penaltyes and Forfeitures
therefore incurred unlesse such person or persons already have beene or shall be sued, prosecuted and impleaded
by some Action of Debt Bill Plaint or Information to be therefore commenced or exhibited before the fowerteenth
day of February which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy two. Any thing
before contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Forfeiture <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


