<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47423" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act to &bhopcrl;vent Malitious maiming and wounding. [Rot. Parl. 22. &amp; 23. C. II. p. 1. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Preamble</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Sir Thomas Sandys, &amp;c. not rendering them selves by a Day to be perpetually banished</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas upon the one and twentyeth day of December in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
and seaventy a violent and inhumane Attempt was made upon the person of Sir John Coventry Knight of
the honourable Order of the Bath being a Member of the Commons House of Parliament and then attending
the Parlyament, and upon the person of his Servant William Wilkes by a considerable number of armed men,
both on Foote and Horsebacke whereby the said Sir John Coventry and his said Servant then lost severall Goods,
and the said Sir John Coventry received diverse Wounds some of which were given him in such barbarous manner
that some of the Offenders held him whilst others wounded him. And whereas by severall Bills of Indi&bholigct;tment
found by the Grand Jury for the Citty and Liberty of Westminster, where the said Facts were committed Sir
Thomas Sandys Knight, Charles Obrian Esquire, Symon Parry and Miles Reeves among others stand indi&bholigct;ted of
Fellony and Robbery for the same but have fled from Justice not dareing to abide a legall Tryall, Bee it therefore
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and of the Commons assembled in Parliament and by the authoritie of the same That if the said Sir
Thomas Sandys Charles Obrian Symon Parry and Miles Reeves shall not render themselves to the Lord Cheife
Justice of his Majestyes Court of Kings Bench or to some other of the Justices of the said Court on or before
the tenth day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and seaventy in order to their Tryalls
for the Fa&bholigct;s aforesaid That then such of them the said Sir Thomas Sandys Charles Obrian Simon Parry and Miles
Reeves as shall not soe render himselfe as aforesaid shall and doe suffer perpetuall Exile and be for ever banished
this Realme and all other his Majestyes Dominions.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Adjournment of the Gaol Delivery for Middlesex.</head>
			<para id="p3">[And bee it ena&bholigct;ted That the Goale delivery for the County of Middlesex and the Citty of London which is
intended to be holden the two and twentyeth day of February One thousand six hundred and seaventy shall be
adjourned till the said tenth day of March, and the Justices of the said Goale delivery or any two of them
are hereby authorized and required to adjourne the same accordingly, and that noe Tryalls shall be there proceeded
upon before the tenth day of March aforesaid.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Sir Thomas Sandys, &amp;c. not rendering, or returning and not rendering themselves, adjudged Felons.</head>
			<para id="p4">And if the said Sir Thomas Sandys Charles Obrian Simon Parry and Miles Reeves or any of them shall not
render themselves as aforesaid, and shall at any time returne into or be found in England, or any other his
Majestyes Dominions after the said tenth day of March Then such of them the said Sir Thomas Sandys Charles
Obrian Symon Parry and Miles Reeves as shall not render himselfe and yet returne or be found as aforesaid shall
from the said one and twentyeth day of December in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and seaventy
be deemed and adjudged to be guilty of the said Fellonyes and Robberyes, and shall by vertue of this A&bholigct;t be
adjudged to be convi&bholigct;ted [and attained<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of Felony and Robbery without any benefit of Clergy to all intents and
purposes as if they had beene thereof convi&bholigct;ed and attainted by due Tryall and Judgement of Law and shall
suffer such paines [penalties<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] and forfeitures as by Law are to be infli&bholigct;ed upon Felons attaint not haveing benefitt
of Clergy.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. No Pardon for the said Sir Thomas Sandys, &amp;c. but by A&bholigct;t of Parliament, and to be therein particularly named.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That neither the said Sir Thomas Sandys Charles Obrian
Symon Parry Miles Reeves nor any who upon the attempt aforesaid a&bholigct;ually tooke away any Goods from the
persons of Sir John Coventry or his said Servant, or a&bholigct;tually gave any Blow or Wound to the said Sir John
Coventry or his said Servant, or held or kepte downe the said Sir John Coventry or his said Servants while they
the said Sir John Coventry and his said Servant or either of them were robbed beaten or wounded, nor any who
commanded the Party either of Horsemen or Footemen in executeing the aforesaid vilanous and barbarous attempt
shall be pardoned any of the Offences in this A&bholigct;t mentioned, but are made incapeable of any Pardon for the same
from the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors unlesse by A&bholigct;t of Parlyament, wherein such person or persons
shall be perticularly named.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Any of the Offenders (Exception) rendering themselves and informing;</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">and giving Security to give Evidence; Pardoned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the authority aforesaid That if any the said Offenders other then the said Sir
Thomas Sandys Charles Obryan Simon Parry and Miles Reeves and such as did a&bholigct;tually rob, strike, or wound
the said Sir John Coventry or his said Servant, or held or kept them or any of them downe, till they or either
of them were robbed, beaten or wounded as aforesaid, and other then such as commanded any Partie in the said
attempt shall before the [eigth<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and seaventy
voluntarily render him or themselves to the Lord Cheife Justice of the said Court, of Kings Bench, or to some
other of the Justices of the said Court, and acknowledge his said Offences and declare his whole knowledge of
the Fa&bholigct;ts aforesaid, and of the persons a&bholigct;ting therein, and shall discover to the Lord Cheife Justice or other
Justice as aforesaid some of the persons, who wounded or held, robbed or strucke as aforesaid Sir John Coventry
or his Servant, or commanded as aforesaid, and shall give such Security as the said Cheife Justice or other the
said Justice before whome such Render shallbe made as aforesaid shall thinke reasonable to give Evidence, if
lawfully required against the Offenders by this A&bholigct;t made incapeable of Pardon, soe that the said Lord Cheife
Justice or such other Justice of the said Court, to whome such Render shall be made as aforesaid shall be
satisfied that he or they soe rendering him or themselves have declared the truth according to the best of their
knowledge, and obtaine a Certificate from the said respe&bholigct;tive Cheife Justice, or Justice before whome such Render
was made to that effe&bholigct;t under the Hand and Seale of the said Cheife Justice or Justice, He and they soe rendering
him and themselves and delareing as aforesaid shall by the authority aforesaid be pardoned the said Assaults,
Felonies and Robberies, and immediately from and after the obtaining such Certificate as aforesaid he and they
soe rendering him and themselves and declareing as aforesaid shall be deemed adjudged and taken to be hereby
to all intents and purposes pardoned acquitted and discharged from the said Crimes and Felonies and from all
further Prosecutions and Imprisonments, Indi&bholigct;tments, Convi&bholigct;tions Attainders Paines, Penalties or Forfeitures that may
accrew for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Malicious maiming made Felony.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Blood, Dower, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And for the prevention of the like mischeifes for the time to come, Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority
aforesaid That if any person or persons from and after the fower and twentyeth day of June which shall be in
the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred seaventy and one on purpose and of malice forethought
and by lyeing in waite shall unlawfully cutt out, or disable the Tongue, putt one out an Eye, slitt the Nose, cutt off a
Nose or Lipp, or cutt off, or disable any Limbe or Member of any Subje&bholigct;t of his Majestie with intention in soe
doeing to maime or disfigure in any the manners before mentioned such his Majestyes Subje&bholigct;, that then and in
every such case the person or persons soe offending, their Councellours Ayders and Abetters (knowing of and
privy to the Offence as aforesaid) shall be and are hereby declared to be Felons, and shall suffer Death as in
cases of Felony without benefit of Clergy. Provided That noe Attainder of such Felony shall extend to corrupt
the Blood or forfeite the Dower of the Wife, or the Lands Goods or Chattells of the Offender.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Session of Parliament not determined.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared and enacted That his Majesties Royall Assent to this Bill shall not
determine this Session of Parliament.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">punishments <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">eighth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


