<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47432" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for the better setling of Intestates Estates.[Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 1. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>All Ordinaries who have Power to grant Administrations to take Bond.</head>
		<para id="p1">Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authority of the same That
all Ordinaries aswell the Judges of the Prerogative Courts of Canterbury and Yorke for the time being as all
other Ordinaries and Ecclesiasticall Judges and every of them haveing power to committ Administration of the
Goods of persons dying Intestate, shall and may upon their respe&bholigct;ive granting and co&bhooov;itting of Administrations
of the Goods of persons dying Intestate after the first day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy and one
of the respe&bholigct;ive person or persons to whome any Administration is to be c&bhooov;mitted, take sufficient Bonds with
two or more able Suretyes, respe&bholigct; being had to the value of the Estate in the Name of the Ordinary with the
Condition in forme and manner following, mutatis mutandis viz.</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">The Condition of the Bonds</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">The Condition of this Obligation is such That if the within bounden A B Administrator of all and singular the
Goods, Chattells and Credits of C D deceased doe make or cause to be made a true and perfe&bholigct; Inventory of all
and singular the Goods Chattells and Credits of the said deceased which have or shall come to the Hands Possession
or Knowledge of him the said A B, or into the Hands and Possession of any other person or persons for him,
and the same soe made doe exhibite or cause to be exhibited into the Registry of Court at or
before the day of next ensueing, And the same Goods, Chattells and Credits, and
all other the Goods, Chattells and Credits of the said deceased at the time of his Death which at any time after
shall come to the Hands or Possession of the said A B, or into the Hands and Possession of any other person or
persons for him, doe well and truely administer according to Law, And further doe make or cause to be made
a true and just accompt of his said Administrac&bhocotil;on at or before the day of And all
the rest and residue of the said Goods, Chattels and Credits which shall be found remaining upon the said
Administrators Accompt, the same being first examined and allowed of by the Judge or Judges for the time being
of the said Court shall deliver and pay unto such person or persons respe&bholigct;ively as the said Judge or Judges by
his or their Decree or Sentence pursuant to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct; shall limitt and appoint.
And if it shall hereafter appeare That any last Will and Testament was made by the said deceased and the
Executor or Executors therein named doe exhibite the same into the said Court, makeing request to have it
allowed and approved accordingly, if the said A B within bounden being thereunto required, doe render and
deliver the said Letters of Administration (Approbation of such Testament being first had and made) in the said
Court. Then this Obligation to be void and of none effe&bholigct;, or else to remaine in full Force and Vertue.</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Ordinaries may call Administrators to account, and make Distribution amongst the Wife and Children, &amp;c.; Appeal</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p5">Which Bonds are hereby declared and ena&bholigct;ed to be good to all intents and purposes, and pleadable in any
Courts of Justice. And alsoe that the said Ordinaries and Judges respe&bholigct;ively shall and may, and are enabled to
proceede and call such Administrators to accompt for and touching the Goods of any person dyeing Intestate,
and upon heareing and due Consideration thereof to order and make just and equall destribution of what remaineth
cleare (after all Debts, Funeralls and just Expences of every sort first allowed and dedu&bholigct;ed) amongst the Wife
and Children, or Childrens Children if any such be or otherwise to the next of Kindred to the dead person in
equall degree, or legally representing their Stocks pro suo cui?ire according to the Lawes in such cases and
the Rules and Limitation hereafter sett downe, and the same destributions to decree and setle, and to compell such
Administrators to observe and pay the same by the due course of his Majestyes Ecclesiasticall Lawes. Saveing
to every one supposeing him or themselves agreived their Right of Appeale as was alwayes in such cases used.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Customs of London and Province of York. &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided That this A&bholigct; or any thing herein contained shall not any way prejudice or hinder the Custome
observed within the Citty of London, or within the Province of Yorke, or other places haveing knowne and
received Customs peculiar to them, but that the same Customs may be observed as formerly Any thing herein
contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. How and to whom Surplus to be distributed.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Advancement by Portion, &amp;c.; Heir at Law, although he take Land, to have an equal Part.; If no Children then Moiety to Wife, and Residue to next of Kin</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That all Ordinaries and every other person
who by this A&bholigct; is enabled to make distribution of the Surplusage of the Estate of any person dying intestate
shall distribute the whole Surplusage of such Estate or Estates in manner and forme following, That is to say,
One third part of the said Surplusage to the Wife of the Intestate, and all the residue by equall portions to and
amongst the Children of such persons dyeing intestate, and such persons as legally represent such Children in
case any of the said Children be then dead, other then such Childe or Children (not being Heire at Law) who
shall have any Estate by the Setlement of the Intestate, or shall be advanced by the Intestate in his Life time
by portion or portions equall to the share which shall by such distribuc&bhocotil;on be allotted to the other Children, to
whome such distribuc&bhocotil;on is to be made. And in case any Childe other then the Heire at Law who shall have
any Estate by Setlement from the said Intestate, or shall be advanced by the said Intestate in his Life time by
portion not equall to the share which will be due to the other Children by such distribution as aforesaid, then
soe much of the Surplusage of the Estate of such Intestate to be distributed to such Childe or Children as shall
have any Land by Setlement from the Intestate, or were advanced in the Life time of the Intestate as shall make
the Estate of all the said Children to be equall as neere as can be estimated. But the Heire at Law notwithstanding
any Land that he shall have by descent or otherwise from the Intestate is to have an equall part in the distribution
with the rest of the Children without any consideration of the value of the Land which he hath by descent or
otherwise from the Intestate. And in case there be noe Children nor any legall Representatives of them, then one
Moyety of the said Estate to be allotted to the Wife of the Intestate, the residue of the said Estate to be distributed
equally to every of the next, of Kindred of the Intestate who are in equally degree and those who legally
represent them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Representation amongst Collaterals. If no Children then to next of Kin.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided That there be noe Representations admitted among Collaterals after Brothers and Sisters Children,
And in case there be noe Wife then all the said Estate to be distributed equally to and amongst the Children,
And in case there be noe Childe then to the next of Kindred in equall degree of, or unto the Intestate and their
legall Representatives as aforesaid and in noe other manner whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Distribution till after one Year. If Debts afterwards appear, then all to refund proportionably.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alsoe and bee it likewise ena&bholigct;ed by the authorise aforesaid To the end that a due reguard be had
to Creditors that noe such distribution of the Goods of any person dying intestate be made till [after<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] one yeare be
fully expired after the Intestates death, and that such and every one to whome any distribution and share shall be
allotted shall give Bond with sufficient Suretyes in the said Courts that if any debt or debts truely oweing by the
Intestate shall be afterwards sued for and recovered, or otherwise duely made to appeare That then and in every
such case he or she shall respe&bholigct;ively refund and pay backe to the Administrator his or her rateable part of that
Debt or Debts, and of the Costs of Suite and Charges of the Administrator by reason of such Debt out of the
part and share soe as aforesaid allotted to him or her, thereby to enable the said Administrator to pay and satisfie
the said Debt or Debts soe discovered after the distribution made as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Proviso for Administration cum Testamento annexo.</head>
			<para id="p11">[Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That in all cases where the Ordinary hath
used heretofore to grant Administration cum Testamento annexo, he shall continue soe to doe, and the Will of
the deceased in such Testament expressed shall be performed and observed in such manner as it should have
beene if this A&bholigct; had never beene made.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p12">[Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; shall continue in force for seaven yeares, and from thence to the end of the
next Session of Parlyament and noe longer.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


