<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47438" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVI. An Act for the discovery of such as have defrauded the Poore of the Citty of London, of the Moneys given for
their Releife at the times of the late Plague and Fire, and for recovery of the Arreares thereof.[Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 2. nu.4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Contribution under Proclamations, 6th July, 17 C. II. 13th Sept. 18 C.II. and 26th Sept. 1668, and that a great Part of the Money so contributed had been misemployed.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">All Monies received upon Charity for the Poor of London to be paid into the Chamber before 1st Nov. 1671.; If the Receivers are dead, their Executors or Administrators to pay it.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">In most humble manner shew unto your most Excellent Majestie the Lord Maior, Aldermen and Co&bhooov;ons of the
Citty of London in Common Councell assembled That in the late dreadfull Calamities of the Plague and Fire
happening in your Majestyes Citty of London and Libertyes thereof and other parts of this Kingdome diverse well
disposed persons aswell within your Majestyes Dominions as in other parts beyond the Seas were pleased to contribute
their Charity towards the Releife of the Poore visited and Sufferers thereby and most were excited by your Majestyes
gracious Proclamations to doe the same, [the one beareing Date the sixth day of July in the seaventeenth yeare of
your Majestyes Raigne, another beareing Date the thirteenth day of September in the eighteenth yeare of your
Majestyes Raigne, The other beareing Date the twenty sixth day of September One thousand six hundred sixty
eight.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] But a great part thereof hath beene misimployed, concealed, or in an unchristianlike manner detained, or at
leastwise never came to the uses intended, by meanes whereof many thousands of the said Poore for want of that
Releife, remaine in great extremity and are likely to perish. For remedy and recovery thereof may it please your
Majesty that it may be ena&bholigct;ed, And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majesty, by and with the advice
and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by
the authoritie thereof That all and every person and persons who have received any of the Moneys colle&bholigct;ed for
the uses, intents or purposes aforesaid or any of them, or in pursuance of any of the said Proclamations for those
purposes made, and have not hitherto paid the same according to the dire&bholigct;ions of the said Proclamations respe&bholigct;ively,
that then such person or persons in case they are now liveing, and in case they are dead, then the Executors of
Administrators of such persons haveing Assets wherewith to pay the same shall pay the same before the first day
of November which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six hundred seventy one to the Chamberlaine
of the Citty of London for the time being at his Office in the Guildhall London, or to such person or persons as
he shall depute or give authority unto for the receipte thereof within the severall Countyes wherein any Money is
behinde and unpaid, upon paine of forfeiture and payment of twenty shillings for every twenty shillings soe unpaid
or detained, and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser Summe besides the Money soe unpaid or detained.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. All Bishops, &amp;c. in Visitations to give it in charge to Churchwardens, &amp;c. to present the Names of Persons detaining Money.</head>
			<para id="p3">And for the better discovery of the Offenders in detaining the said Moneyes all Arch-bishops, Bishops, Arch
Deacons, Deanes and Officialls in their Visitations shall give it in charge to all Ministers Churchwardens and
Sidesmen that they present the Names of all such persons as they know or beleive doe detaine any of the said
Moneyes and the Summe soe detained by them, And further that upon request made unto them by the said
Chamberlaine of the Citty of London, or his Attourneys or Agents or any of them, by causeing search to be
made into their Registryes and other Offices, and by other expedient meanes they shall contribute their assistance
to the discovery of such persons and Offenders as may justly be suspe&bholigct;ed to have or detaine any such Moneys.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. So Justices of Assize, &amp;c. to Grand Juries.</head>
			<para id="p4">And likewise that all Judges and Justices of Assizes and Generall Goale delivery, and all Justices of Peace in
their Quarter Sessions shall in open Court give in charge [to<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] the Grand Juryes to enquire of, and present such
Offenders.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Justices of Peace may grant Warrants for taking Parties;</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">and upon their Appearance may bind them to appear at the next. Quarter Sessions, or may commit them on refusal to be bound.; Quarter Sessions may proceed summarily.; If Money not paid to Chamberlain pursuant to Order; Committal,; or Distress.; Order of Sessions to be final</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And that upon complaint made to any Justice of Peace in any County Citty or Towne Corporate by the
Chamberlaine of the Citty of London or his Attourneys, Sollicitors, Receivers Agents or any of them, made or
appointed by him, by any Writeing under his Hand and Seale for prosecuteing the Recovery or for recovering
the said Moneys or any of them against, any person or persons for their unjust detaining of any Moneys colle&bholigct;ed
for the uses aforesaid or any of them, that then such Justice of Peace shall grant his Warrant against such persons
soe complained of for the bringing of them before him, and upon their appearance before him if it shall seeme
probable to the said Justice upon examineing of the matter, and evidence given by any witnesse upon Oath,
which the said Justice may administer, or other evidence, that the person complained of doth unjustly detaine any
Moneys colle&bholigct;ed, or appointed for the uses aforesaid or any of them, then such Justice shall by sufficient
Recognizance binde him to appeare at the next Generall Quarter Sessions to answere the matter complained of,
and to observe and abide such Order touching the same as the Justices shall then make, and upon his refusall
soe to be bound to committ to the Goale, there to remaine without Baile or Mainprize untill he shall become
bound by such Recognizance, And at the said Quarter Sessions whether he shall there appeare or make default,
yet the Justices then shall summarily proceede to the Examination of the matter complained of, And if upon
Oath of one or more Witnesse or Witnesses or any other Evidence the Court shall be satisfyed that he doth
unjustly detaine any such Moneys, the Court shall adjudge and order the payment of the same presently, together
with the penalty hereby appointed for not paying thereof, and such costs for the prosecution of the same as the
Court shall thinke fitt, And if he shall not presently pay the same accordingly to the said Chamberlaine of London
or his Attourneys or Agents or some of them shall committ him to the Goale if he be there present there to
remaine without Baile-or Mainprize untill he shall observe the said Order of Sessions, And if he shall be absent
that then they shall grant their Warrant for the apprehending and committing of him to the Gaole there to remaine
untill he shall pay the Money soe ordered, And that if he cannot be taken then for the destraining of his Goods
or Chattells and sale of the same rendering the Overplus whereby the Moneys soe ordered may be answered and
paid, And [that<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] the definitive Order of the said Justices shall be finall, as touching the matters complained of
or contained in such Order, from which there shall be noe Appeale or Review, nor shall any Writt of Error
or Certiorari lye for the Removall or Reversall of the same, nor shall the same be any wayes impeached.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Distin&bholigct; Accounts to be kept by Chamberlain.</head>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further hereby ena&bholigct;ed That the Receivers or Agents for the Chamberlaine of the Citty of London
shall within two Monethes after the Receipt of any such Moneys pay or cause the same to be transmitted and
paid to him the said Chamberlaine, and that distin&bholigct; Accompts according to the severall Diocesses and Countyes
shall be made and kepte by him of all such Moneyes as he shall hereafter receive in reference to the Sufferers
by the Fire, and of such as he shall receive in reference to the Plague.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Bishops of Dioceses visited by the Plague in 1665, 1666, 1667, to certify to Bishop and Chamberlain of London what Money hath been expended out of Public Stocks, or borrowed, towards the Support of Persons sick of the Plague within their Dioceses.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">How such Monies to be repaid.; To whom to be paid.; How the Surplus to be disposed of</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That each Bishop of the severall Diocesses which were
visited by the Plague in the yeares One thousand six hundred sixty five, One thousand six hundred sixty six or
One thousand six hundred sixty seaven shall within six Moneths after the end of this Session of Parlyament by
Certificate under his Hand and Seale deliver or cause to be delivered unto the Lord Bishop of London and the
Chamberlaine of the Citty of London to be entred in a Register of his Office a particular Accompt of such Summes
of Money as have beene lent or taken out of the publique [Stocke<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of any and every Citty, Towne Corporate and
places adjacent to them respe&bholigct;ively, or borrowed of any person or persons for the Releife of the Poore soe infe&bholigct;ed
with the Plague within any Citty or Towne corporate or the places adjacent to them in his Diocesse, and
perticularly from whence they were soe taken, and by whome lent, And that the Moneys soe certifyed to be
taken out of Publique Stockes, or lent as aforesaid shall by. Order of the Lord Bishop of London to the said
Chamberlaine of London be by him repaid in the first place out of the Moneys which shall hereafter be received
in reference to the Plague, in case the Monies soe received out or from such Diocesse [which was<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] soe
infe&bholigct;ed shall suffice for repayment thereof without any respe&bholigct; or consideration had to the charge in getting or
bringing in the same, And if there shall not be sufficient for such repayment each Summe soe lent by any person,
or taken out of such Publique Stocke shall suffer and abate proportionably, And that the payment of such Moneys
by Order as aforesaid shall be made to the Bishop, or Deputy of the Bishop of every such Diocesse respe&bholigct;ively
to be forthwith repaid to every Citty, Towne Corporate or person according to the intent of this A&bholigct;, And if
there shall be any Surplusage left, that then the same, as alsoe all other moneys which shall hereafter be soe
received by the said Chamberlaine of London in reference to the said Plague or Fire, the necessary Charges
in getting and bringing in of the same being first dedu&bholigct;ed and abated shall by the Order and Advice of the
Lord Bishop of London and Lord Maior of London be paid by the said Chamberlaine for reimburseing the said
Citty of London all such moneys as were by them disbursed, taken or borrowed out of their Publique Stocke
for the Releife of the Sufferers by the said Fire or Plague in London or the Suburbs thereof, the residue (if
any be) to goe for and towards the releife of the Poore of the said Citty Sufferers by the said Fire.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Provison for Ordinaries Jurisdi&bholigct;ion. Continuance of A&bholigct; as to Recovery of Monies.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided, and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That nothing in this A&bholigct; contained shall be any way
prejudiciall or hurtfull to the Jurisdi&bholigct;ion or Power of the Ordinary or any other Jurisdi&bholigct;ion whatsoever, and that
this A&bholigct; as to the recovery of any moneys herein mentioned or intended shall continue and be in force untill
the first day of November which shall be in the yeare One thousand six hundred seaventy fower and noe
longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. In A&bholigct;ions for executing A&bholigct;, General Issue.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And lastly it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed That if any A&bholigct;ion or Suite shall be brought against any person for any
matter or thing done or executed by vertue of this A&bholigct;, that then and in every such case the Defendant or
Defendants may pleade the generall Issue, Not guilty, and give this A&bholigct; and the speciall matter in Evidence at
any Tryall therupon to be had, and if a Verdi&bholigct; shall passe for the Defendant, or the Plaintiffe shall be Non
suite, or discontinue his A&bholigct;ion after the Defendant hath appeared, the Defendant shall recover double Costs to
be awarded for his or their wrongfull vexation in that behalfe.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Stocks <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


