<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47436" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for determination of Differences touching Houses burnt or demolished within fower yeares since the late dreadfull Fire of London</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Differences about Houses within Bills of Mortality, demolished by Fire, to be determined by the Judges under 19 C. II. c. 2. (18 &amp; 19 C. II. c.7.) 22 C. II. C. II</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas there were severall Houses and Buildings in the Citty of London and Burrough of Southwarke
and other places within the Weekely Bill of Mortality consumed by Fire or otherwise demolished by
reason thereof betweene the first day of O&bholigct;ober One thousand six hundred sixty and six, and the first day of
O&bholigct;ober One thousand six hundred and seaventy. Which by reason of some differences and doubts ariseing
therein the same are not likely to be rebuilt unlesse some course be taken for the decideing of such differences.
For Remedy whereof Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by authoritie,
of the same That the Justices of the Courts of Kings Bench and Common Pleas and the Barons of the Coife of
the Exchequer for the time being or any three or more of them be, and are hereby authorized and impowered
to heare and determine all such Cases, for all such Houses and Buildings as fully and amply and in like manner
to all intents and purposes as they can or may heare and determine any other matter mentioned in one A&bholigct; of
this present Parlyament Entituled An A&bholigct; for ere&bholigct;ing a Judicature for determination of Differences touching Houses
burned or demolished by reason of the late Fire which happened in London, and in another A&bholigct; of this present
Parlyament intituled, An Additionall A&bholigct; for rebuilding of the Citty of London, uniteing of Parishes and
rebuilding of the Cathedrall and Parochiall Churches within the said Citty or in either of them; And that all
Decrees and Orders in such Cases to be made shall binde and be obeyed by all partyes therein concerned and
shall be of like Effe&bholigct; and Force as any Orders [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Decrees made for any matter or thing in the said recited
A&bholigct;s or either of them mentioned.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Longer Time given to the said Judicature.</head>
			<para id="p3">And forasmuch as the Judicature by the said recited A&bholigct;s appointed or either of them are to continue in force
but untill the nine and twentyeth day of September One thousand six hundred seaventy and one, It is hereby
further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the Judicature by the said recited A&bholigct;s, and every Clause, Article and Thing
therein mentioned or contained, relateing to the said Judicature, and all and every the Powers and Authorities
thereby, or by either of them given to the said Justices and Barons or any three or more of them shall stand and
be continued and remaine in full force untill the nine and twentyeth day of September One thousand six hundred
seaventy and two, Any clause, matter or thing in the said A&bholigct; or either of them contained to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The Time limited for receiving Complaints.</head>
			<para id="p4">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the said Judges and Barons shall and may receive any
Complaint [and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Petition concerning any Differences or Demands by this, or the said recited A&bholigct;s or either of them
referred to the determination of the aforesaid Judicature, and proceede and determine the same soe as the said
Complaints or Petitions be exhibited or depending before the said Judicature on or before the twenty ninth day of
September One thousand six hundred seaventy and one, Any thing herein or any other Statute to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Lord Mayor, &amp;c. when to dispose of Ground unbuilt.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwayes and it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That the Maior, Aldermen, and Common Councell of the
Citty of London shall not proceede to the Sale of any Ground or Soyle whereon any House was scituate at the
time of the late dreadfull Fire for not building thereupon before the nine and twentyeth day of September which
shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and two, Any thing in this or the afore
recited A&bholigct;s or either of them to the contrary hereof notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Leases of the Savoy Ground not exceeding 40 Years may be granted by the Master and Chaplains.</head>
			<para id="p6">And whereas the Brothers Lodgeings in the Savoy lately burnt downe are not by the Lawes and Statutes of
this Land demiseable, for any long terme of yeares, Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That for
the encouragement of the present rebuilding the same, it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Master and
Chaplaines of the Savoy to demise the said Lodgeings for any terme not exceeding forty yeares under such
yearely Rent or Rents as the Master and Chaplaines can reasonably procure without renewing any time for the
same. Any Law, Statute or Custome to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

