<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47439" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVII. An Act for the better paveing and cleansing the Streets and Sewers in and about the Citty of London.[Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 2. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 8. &amp;18. (19 C. II. c. 3. 20.)</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Persons authorized by the said A&bholigct; may impose a Tax upon Houses for making Vaults, &amp;c.; and may levy by Distress.; The said Clause made perpetual.; No other Commissioners or Persons to intermeddle</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by a late A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament entituled An A&bholigct; for rebuilding the Citty of London,
It is ena&bholigct;ed (amongst other things) that the numbers and places for all Common Sewers, Draines and
Vaults, and the order and manner of paveing and pitching the Streets and Lanes within the said Citty and
Libertyes thereof shall be designed and sett out by such and soe many persons as the said Maior Aldermen
and Commonalty in Common Councell assembled shall from time to time authorize and appoint under their
Common Seale or the more part of them, Which said persons soe authorized and appointed or any seaven or
more of them together with the said Surveyours or some or one of them within his or their Precin&bholigct;s repe&bholigct;ively
shall at their Meeting have power and authority to order and dire&bholigct; the makeing of any new Vaults Draines and
Sewers, or to cutt into any Draine or Sewer already made, and for the altering enlargeing amending cleansing
and scowring of any old Vaults, Sinks or Common Sewers. For the better effe&bholigct;ing whereof it shall and may
be lawfull to and for the said persons soe authorized and appointed as aforesaid or any seaven or more of them
[at theire said Meeting<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to impose any reasonable Taxe upon all Houses [with<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] in the said Citty and Liberties thereof
in proportion to the benefit they shall receive thereby, for and towards the new makeing, cutting, altering
enlargeing [amending<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] cleanseing and scowring all and singular the said Vaults Draines Sewers Pavements and
Pitching aforesaid. And in defaulte of payment of the said Summes soe to be charged it shall and may be
lawfull to and for the said persons soe authorized as aforesaid or any seaven or more of them by Order and
Warrant under their Hands and Seales to leavy the said Summe and Summes of Money soe assessed, by Distresse
and Sale of the Goods of the party chargeable therewith, and refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing to pay the same, rendering
the Overplus (if any be) and that all other Commis?ers whatsoever be altogether suspended to intermedle in the
Premisses within the said Citty and Libertyes thereof for the space of seaven yeares next, and for soe long, after
untill the said intended Buildings shall be fully finished. Any Law or Statute to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding. Bee it ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and
consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by
authoritie of the same That the said Clause or Branch of the said A&bholigct; herein before recited shall remaine and
continue in force, and be made perpetuall, and the powers and authorities thereby given and appointed to be
executed by such persons as shall in that behalfe be authorized and appointed by the said Maior Aldermen and
Commons in Common Councell assembled according to the tenoure thereof [under theire Co&bhooov;on Seale<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] or any
seaven or more of them shall and may from time to time for ever hereafter be putt in execution according to
the purport and effe&bholigct; of the aforesaid A&bholigct;; and that noe other Co&bhooov;is?ers or any other persons whatsoever shall
at any time hereafter intermedle in the Premisses within the said Citty or Liberties thereof. Any Law or Statute
to, the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The sole Power of Paving, &amp;c. to be in the Mayor, Commonalty, and Citizens.</head>
			<para id="p3">And to the end that for the future all Irregularities in Paveing and Pitching of the Streets, Lanes, and
Passages within the said City and Liberties thereof and the frequent defaults of cleansing the same may be prevented
and remedied Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That from henceforth the sole power and authority
of ordering designeing and regulating aswell the cleansing and keepeing cleane all the Streets Lanes and Passages
whatsoever within the said Citty and Liberties, and the pitching and paveing with the order and manner thereof,
and for makeing and cleansing Dranies and Sewers shall be and remaine in the Maior Commonalty and Citizens
of the said Citty to be managed, executed; and done by such persons as by the said Maior Aldermen and
Commons in Common Councell assembled shall be thereunto authorized and appointed or by any seaven or
more of them (being all Members of the said Court) and noe other persons whatsoever, and in such sort and
manner as from time to time shall by them be found most convenient for the publique benefit of the Inhabitants
of the said Citty in generall.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Paviors, Scavengers, &amp;c. required to observe their Dire&bholigct;ions.</head>
			<para id="p4">And all Paviers Scavengers, Carters Labourers and Lightermen and all other persons that have beene heretofore
or [that<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] may hereafter be imployed in any of the workes belonging to the Draines or Sewers, pitching, paveing
or cleansing of the Streets, Lanes or Passages within the said Citty or Liberties thereof are hereby enjoyed and
required duely and constantly to obey, observe and execute all such Orders Rules and Dire&bholigct;ions as shall be
from time to time appointed or prescribed by the persons in that behalfe to be authorized or any seaven. or
more of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Offending against this A&bholigct;;</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And that the partyes therein offending contrary to this present A&bholigct; shall and may be proceeded against, and
thereof convi&bholigct;ed by Indi&bholigct;ment at the next Sessions of the Peace to be held for the said Citty and Libertyes.
thereof, according to his or their severall Offences, unlesse they shall submitt to the Judgement and Censure of
the persons soe to be authorized and appointed as aforesaid or any seaven or more of them, and shall satisfye
and pay such mul&bholigct; or penalty as by them shall be sett and imposed for such Offence into the Chamber of the
Citty of London, to be imployed for and towards the Workes in this A&bholigct; mentioned. Any Law, Statute, Usage
or Custome to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Persons authorized by 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 8. (19 C. II. c. 3.) may impose a reasonable Tax on Wards and Precin&bholigct;s, and dire&bholigct; Precepts to Deputies, &amp;c. to assess and levy the same. </head>
			<para id="p7">Ground unbuilt on, empty Houses, &amp;c. liable.</para>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That for the better enableing the said Maior, Commonalty
and Citizens to effe&bholigct; and performe all and singular the Workes in and by this [present<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] A&bholigct; mentioned and appointed
to be done, and for the defraying the Charge thereof it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said persons soe
to be authorized and appointed as aforesaid, or any seaven or more of them at their publique meetings from time
to time as oft as neede shall be, or require, to impose any reasonable Taxe or Assesment upon the severall Wards
and Precin&bholigct;s thereof within the said Citty and Libertyes, and to dire&bholigct; Precepts or Warrants under their Hands
and Seales or of any seaven or more of them unto the respe&bholigct;ive Deputies and Common councell men of the said
severall Wards thereby requireing them to rate and assesse the said Taxes and Assessments in manner hereafter
following, And alsoe to dire&bholigct; like Precepts or Warrants to such and soe many of the Scavengers within the
respe&bholigct;ive Wards as they shall thinke fitt thereby requireing them to colle&bholigct; and leavy the moneys soe assessed.
upon receipt whereof the said Deputyes and Common councell men thereunto appointed are hereby required to make
an Assesment and Distribution of the proportion charged upon their respe&bholigct;ive Wards and Precin&bholigct;s thereof as
aforesaid, aswell upon the Tennants and Occupiers of Houses, Shopps or other Tenements or Hereditaments, as upon
the Owners or others interessed of or in such Houses, Tofts of Ground unbuilt, and other Hereditaments whereof
there shall be noe present Occupier.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. In what Case Churchwardens to pay for a Church, or Churchyard.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Duplicates in Writing of Assessments to be returned, together with Scavengers Names, who are to colle&bholigct; In default ofrating, Proceedings; In Default of Payment, Proceedings after Six Days; Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And where any Church or Church yard shall be fronting or adjoyning to any of the said Streets Lanes or
Passages to rate and assesse a reasonable proportion thereof upon the Parish thereunto belonging, the same to
be paid by the Church Wardens of every such Parish for the time being, who are hereby required to pay the
same accordingly in the behalfe of the said Parish; Of which Assesments the said Deputyes and Common councell
men shall returne Duplicates in writeing together with the Names of the Scavengers to be appointed for the
colle&bholigct;ion thereof within twenty dayes next after the receipt of such Precept or Warrant respe&bholigct;ively; and in case
of their negcle&bholigct; or default in rateing or assessing the same, or in returning such Duplicates of their Assesments
within the time limitted as aforesaid, it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said persons soe to be authorized
and appointed or any seaven or more of them to rate and assesse the respe&bholigct;ive Taxes and Assessments within
the severall Wards and Precin&bholigct;s where such defaults shall be, upon the respe&bholigct;ive Inhabitants and others in
manner as aforesaid, all which Summe and Summes of money soe to be rated and assessed in pursuance of this
A&bholigct; shall from time to time be colle&bholigct;ed and leavyed by the Scavengers to be appointed for the colle&bholigct;ing thereof
as aforesaid, who are hereby authorized and required to colle&bholigct; and leavy the same accordingly; And in default
of payment of the Summes to be charged and assessed as aforesaid or any part thereof by the space of six dayes
after demand thereof, it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Scavengers to be appointed for the colle&bholigct;ing
and leavying thereof as aforesaid, and they are hereby authorized and required thereunto to leavy all such Summe
and Summes of money soe assessed by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of the parties refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing to
pay the same, rendering the Overplus, if any shall be, besides the reasonable Charge of takeing such Distresse to
the party and partyes soe distrained.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. The Tax to be paid into the Chamber of London, and no Money issued without Warrant.</head>
			<para id="p11">All which summe and summes of money from time to time hereafter to be colle&bholigct;ed and leavyed by vertue
of this present Act shall be paid into the Chamber of the Citty of London by the said Scavengers who shall
colle&bholigct; the same respe&bholigct;ively, where Bookes of Accompts shall be kepte of the Receipt thereof by the Chamberlaine
of the said Citty of London for the time being, And noe moneys shall be issued thereout otherwise then by
Order or Warrant under the Hands of the said persons soe to be appointed and authorized as aforesaid or any
seaven or more of them for the uses and purposes in and by this Act mentioned and appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. In case of defe&bholigct; of Paving; Proceedings.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Reward to Informer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That where any Citizen or Inhabitant within the said Citty or Libertyes
thereof shall finde himselfe agreived through the defe&bholigct; or decay of the Pavements in any of the said Streets,
Lanes or Passages within the said Citty or Liberties thereof or for want of due cleansing thereof, the same being
made appeare to the persons soe to be authorized and appointed by the said Maior, Aldermen and Commons as
aforesaid or any seaven or more of them at their publique Meeting, And upon due proofe made that such grievance
is unreformed, that then and in such case the person and persons complaining shall forthwith receive the order
and directions of the said persons soe authorized and appointed or any seaven or more of them for redressing
thereof, together with a Warrant under their Hands and Seales directed to the Chamberlaine of the Citty of London
for the time being to issue out moneys for defraying the Charge thereof, together with any Summe of money not
exceeding ten shillings for incouragement of his or their Diligence therein, who upon Receipt of such Warrant
shall pay the same accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Laystalls, &amp;c. to be provided for receiving the Dirt, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p14">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authorise aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Maior
Aldermen and Commons in Common Councell assembled to appoint, sett out and purchase for the publique Use
and Benefitt of the said Citty of London in places convenient and where the same may be least Annoyance such
and soe many pieces, or parcells of Ground for Laystalls, and places for publique Stores as they shall adjudge
necessary and convenient for the Receipt of the Soyle, Dirt and Rubbish, which shall be removed and carryed out
of the said Citty and Libertyes thereof, as for other Materialls and Commodities.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Ground for Laystalls, &amp;c. to be purchased with Monies arising from Imposition on Coals, under 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 8. &sect;34. (19 C. II. c. 3. &sect;36.) &amp; 22 C. II. C. 11. &sect;38.</head>
			<para id="p15">And that all such pieces of Ground for Laystalls and places for publique Stores, as by them shall be purchased
as aforesaid shall be satisfyed and paid for out of the moneys raised or hereafter to be raised by the Imposition
upon Coales appointed for publique Uses of the said Citty by vertue of the said A&bholigct; for rebuilding the City,
and of another A&bholigct;entituled An Additionall A&bholigct; for rebuilding of the City of London, Uniteing of Parishes and
rebuilding of the Cathedrall and Parochiall Churches within the said City, (other then the money appointed for
building of the Cathedrall Church of Saint Pauls, and other Churches within the said City and reserveing sufficient
to satisfy such persons whose Grounds have beene taken from them) or either of them. Any Law or Statute to
the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Appeal.</head>
			<para id="p16">And in case that any person or persons shall finde him or themselves agreaved by reason of any Taxe Assesment
or other Charge to be imposed by vertue or colour of this present A&bholigct;, that then it shall and may be lawfull to
and for the party or parties soe agrieved within five dayes after demand thereof to appeale to the Maior and
Court of Aldermen of the said City for the time being for Redresse therein, whose Order in that behalfe shall
be finall.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Persons liable to Charge of altering or cleansing any Lanes, Sewers, &amp;c. not to be farther chargeable.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That noe person or persons Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate who by
this Act are made lieable to be rated or assessed towards the publique Charge of altering, enlargeing, amending
or cleanseing of the said Vaults or Sewers, or of cleansing, pitching or paveing the Streets, Lanes, Alleys and other
common Passages within the said City and Liberties thereof, for, or in respe&bholigct; of any Houses Tofts or other
Hereditaments shall from and after the first day of May One thousand six hundred seaventy one be otherwise charged
therewith, or lyable thereunto, or to be troubled molested or prosecuted for or in respect thereof. Any other Law,
Statute Custome or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Stocks <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


