<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47431" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IX. An A&bholigct; for laying Impositions on Proceedings at Law.[Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 1. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for the present Grant.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Duties to commence 1st May 1671.; For the Term of Nine Years</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee your Majestyes most dutyfull and loyall Subjects the Commons assembled in Parlyament haveing entred
into a due' and serious consideration of the extraordinary Occasions which oblige your Majestie to a great
and present Expence for the necessary Defence of your Realmes, and considering your Majestyes great Debts, and
being desireous to raise such aides and supplyes as may be proportionable to these Occasions doe humbly present
your Majesty with the free Gift of the Rates and Aides herein after mentioned and doe beseech your Majesty that
it may be ena&bholigct;ed And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same
That from and after the first day of May which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
seaventy and one there shall be throughout your Majestyes Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne
of Berwicke upon Tweede raised, leavyed, colle&bholigct;ed and paid unto your Majestie your Heires and Successors dureing
the terme of nine yeares for the severall and respe&bholigct;ive things herein after mentioned over and above the Rates
Dutyes and Summes of Money now due and payable to your Majestie or to any person or persons Bodyes Pollitique
or Corporate whatsoever for the same the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Rates Impositions, Dutyes, Charges and Summes
of Money herein after expressed in manner and forme following (That is to say)</para>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Grants of Franchises, &amp;c. not above one Skin</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">For every Charter or Grant which shall be made of any Franchise, Liberty or Priviledge to any
person or persons Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate that shall passe the Great Seale of England or the
Seale of the County Palatine of Lancaster not exceeding one Skin of Parchment written in such manner
as things of that nature are or heretofore have beene usually written Forty Shillings&nbsp;Xl<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">Exceeding one Skin</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">And if the same shall exceede one Skin soe to be written, then for every other Skin of Parchment
soe to be written Twenty shillings&nbsp;XX<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p7">
			<emph type="i">Other Grants not above one Skin</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p8">For every Grant of Lands in Fee, Perpetuity, Lease for yeares and other Grant that shall passe the
Great Seale of England, Seale of the Exchequer, Seale of the Dutchy or County Palatine of Lancaster
not exceeding one skin of Parchment written in such manner as things of that nature are now, or
heretofore have beene usually written Twenty shillings&nbsp;XX<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p9">
			<emph type="i">Exceeding one Skin</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p10">And if the same shall exceede one Skin soe to be written, then for every other Skin of Parchment
soe to be written Ten Shillings&nbsp;X<emph type="p">l</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p11">
			<emph type="i">Grants of Money or Pardons not above one Skin</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p12">For every Grant of any Summe of Money, and for every Pardon of or for any Crime or
Offence or of any S&bhouov;me of Money or Forfeiture that shall passe the Great Seale or Privy Seale,
not dire&bholigct;ed to the Great Seale not exceeding one Skin of Parchment to be written in such manner
as things of that nature are now or heretofore have beene usually written, Forty shillings&nbsp;Xl<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p13">
			<emph type="i">Exceeding one Skin</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p14">And if the same shall exceede one Skin soe to be written, then for every other Skin of Parchment
soe to be written Twenty shillings&nbsp;XXs<emph type="p">l</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p15">
			<emph type="i">Presentation to Benefices of &pound;20 or above in the King's Books</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p16">For every Presentation and Donation which shall passe the Great Seale of England, and for every Collation to be made by any Archbishop or other Bishop, and for every Presentation and Donation to be made by any Patron whatsoever of or to any Benefice, Dignity or Spirituall or Ecclesiasticall Promotion whatsoever provided such Benefice Dignity or Promotion be of the value of Twenty pounds or above in the Kings Bookes Forty shillings [XXsl]</para>
		<para id="p17">
			<emph type="i">Of &pound;10 and above</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p18">But if such Spirituall Promotion Dignity or Benefice be but of the value of Ten pounds or above in the Kings Bookes then but Ten shillings&nbsp;X<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p19">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for Vicarages under &pound;100 per Annum</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p20">Provided That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to Charge any Viccaridge under the improved value
of One hundred pounds per ann?. the same to be proved by the [Certificates of the<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] respe&bholigct;ive
Ordinaries.</para>
		<para id="p21">
			<emph type="i">Deeds enrolled</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p22">For every Conveyance, Surrender Release and other Deed whatsoever which shall be enrolled of Record In any of the Courts at Westminster, or in any other Court of Record whatsoever, or by any Custos Rotulor&umacr;, or Clerke of the Peace Five shillings&nbsp;V<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p23">
			<emph type="i">Writs of Covenant for levying Fines at and above 6s. 8d. and under 20s</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p24">For every Writt of Covenant for leavying of Fines in the Alienation Office at or above Six shillings eight pence, and under Twenty shillings, and for which there is now Six shillings eight pence or above usually paid, there shalbe paid over and above such Six shillings and eight pence or above the Sume of three shillings and fower pence&nbsp;iij<emph type="p">s</emph> iiij<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p25">
			<emph type="i">Writs at and above 20s</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p26">And for every Writt of Covenant for leavying of Fines in the Alienation Office at or above Twenty shillings, and for which there is now Twenty shillings or above usually paid there shall be paid over and above such Twenty shillings or above the Summe of Six shillings and eight pence.&nbsp;vj<emph type="p">s</emph> viij<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p27">The said Additionall Su&bhouov;es not to be accounted any part of the Pre-fine, or to extend to the Post-fine.</para>
		<para id="p28">
			<emph type="i">Writs of Entry for suffering of Common Recoveries.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p29">For every Writt of Entry for suffering of Common Recoveries in the Alienation Office there shall be paid over and above the Fines now or heretofore usually rated and paid there upon such Writs Six shillings and eight pence&nbsp;vj<emph type="p">s</emph> [viij.<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]</para>
		<para id="p30">
			<emph type="i">Original Writs, and other Writs, and Process.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p31">For every Originall Writt not before [by<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] this A&bholigct; charged, Subpoena, Bill of Midlesex, Latitat, Writ of Capias Quo minus, Writ of Dedimus Potestat? to take Answers, examine Witnesses, or sweare Guardians and every other Writ whatsoever, and alsoe for every other Processe or Mandate that shall issue out of, or passe the Seales of any of the Courts of Westminster, Courts of the Great Sessions in Wales; Courts in Countyes Palatine, or any other Court whatsoever holding Plea, where the Debt or Dammage doth amount to Forty shillings, or above; Six pence&nbsp;vj<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p32">
			<emph type="i">Renewing Process.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p33">For the renewing of every such Processe, or Mandate Fower pence&nbsp;jv<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p34">
			<emph type="i">Entry of A&bholigct;ion in Mayor's Court, &amp;c.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p35">
			<emph type="i">For the Entry of every A&bholigct;ion in the Maiors and Sheriffes Courts of London, and in Courts in all Corporations, and other Courts whatsoever, out of which noe Writts, Processe or Mandates issue holding Plea, where the Debt or Dammage doth amount to forty shillings or above, Six pence</emph>.&nbsp;vj<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p36">
			<emph type="i">Exemplifications not above one Skin.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p37">For every exemplification of what nature soever, that shall passe the Seale of any Court whatsoever, not exceeding one Skin of Parchment to be written with as many Words in every Line, and with asmany Lines in every Skin, as are now, or heretofore have beene usually written in things exemplified. Seaven shillings and six pence&nbsp;vij<emph type="p">s</emph> vj<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p38">
			<emph type="i">Exceeding one Skin.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p39">And if the same shall exceede one Skin soe to be written, then for every other Skin of Parchment soe to be written, Five shillings.&nbsp;v<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p40">
			<emph type="i">Bills and Pleadings in Equity.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p41">For every Bill, Answere, Plea, Demurrer, and every other Pleading whatsoever in the Courts of Chauncery Exchequer and Dutchy chamber of Lancaster One shilling.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p42">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Bills and Pleadings in Equity.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p43">For the Copy of every Bill, Answere Plea, Demurrer, and of all other Pleadings whatsoever, and of all Interrogatories and Depositions taken out of the respe&bholigct;ive Offices, and attested by the respe&bholigct;ive Officers in the Courts of Chauncery, Exchequer and Dutchy Chamber of Lancaster, there shall be paid for every Sheete to be written with as many Words in every Line, and with as many Lines in every Sheete as are now, or heretofore have beene usually written in such Copies One penny.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p44">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Bills, &amp;c. in inferior Court.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p45">For the Copy of every Bill, Answere, Plea, Demurrer, and of all other Pleadings whatsoever, and of all Interrogatories and Depositions: in all and every other Court of Equity or Conscience whatsoever holding Plea where the Debt or Dammage doth amount to Forty shillings or above there shall be paid for every Sheete to be written with as many Words in every Line, and with as many Lines in every Sheete as are now, or heretofore has beene usally written in such Copies One penny&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p46">
			<emph type="i">Orders and Reports in Equity.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p47">For every Order entred and Report filed in any of the said Courts of Chauncery, Exchequer and Dutchy Chamber of Lancaster Six pence&nbsp;vj<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p48">
			<emph type="i">Copies thereof.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p49">For the Copy of every such Order and Reporte signed by the proper Officer Three pence&nbsp;iij<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p50">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Declarations, &amp;c. in Courts at Westminster, for which 8d. per Sheet is now payable.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p51">For the Copy of every Declaration, Plea, Demurrer Issue and of all and every other Proceedings whatsoever in any of the Courts at Westminster for which there is now payable Eight pence per Sheete, there shall be paid for every Sheete to be written with as many Words in every Line, and with as many Lines in every Sheets as are now, or heretofore have beene usually written in such Copies, One penny.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p52">
			<emph type="i">Copies of such Declarations, &amp;c. for which 4d. per Sheet is now payable</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p53">For the Copy of every Declaration, Plea and Issue Demurrer, and of all and every other Proceedings in any of the Courts at Westminster, for which there is now payable but Fower pence per Sheete, there shall be paid for every Sheete to be written with as many Words in every Line and with as many Lines in every Sheete as are now, or heretofore have beene usually written in such Copies, over and above the said Fower pence per Sheete, One penny&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p54">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Declarations and Pleadings in other Courts</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p55">For the Copy of every Declaration, Plea, Issue, Demurrer, and of all and every other Proceedings whatsoever in all and every other Court whatsoever holding Plea, where, the Debt or Dammage doth amount to Forty, shillings, or above, for every Sheete to be written with as many Words in every Line, and with, as many Lines, in every Sheete as are now, or heretofore have beene usually written in such Copies, One penny&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p56">
			<emph type="i">Affidavits</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p57">For every Affidavit that shall be made in writeing, and sworne to before any person whatsoever authorized to take an Oath, where any Fee by Law is due to any Officer for the same, Six pence.&nbsp;vj<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p58">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Affidavits.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p59">For the Copy of every Affidavit that shall be filed or reade in any Court whatsoever, Fower pence.&nbsp;iiij<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p60">
			<emph type="i">Bails and Appearances</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p61">For every Speciall Baile to be taken in any of the Courts at Westminster, or before any of the Judges of the said Courts, or in any other Court whatsoever, and for every Co[m]on Baile whatsoever that shall be filed in any of the said Courts, or any other Court whatsoever, and for every apparance that shall be made or entred in any of the said Courts, or any other Court whatsoever, or in any Office belonging to the same, Six pence.&nbsp;vj<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p62">
			<emph type="i">Rules and Orders in the Courts at Westminster. (Exception.)</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p63">For every Rule or Order to be made or given in any of the Courts at Westminster, except in the English side of the Chauncery, the English side of the Exchequer, and the English side of the Court of the Dutchy or County Palatine of Lancaster and Rules for Answere, Two pence.&nbsp;ij<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p64">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Rules and Orders.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p65">And for the Copy of every such Rule or Order Two pence.&nbsp;ij<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p66">
			<emph type="i">Judgments.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p67">For every Judgement in Debt, or other Judgement whatsoever, which shall be signed by the Master of any Office, or his Deputy, or Secondary, or by any Prothonotary or his Secondary, Deputy or Clerke, or by any other Officer belonging to any of the Courts at Westminster who hath power, or usually, doth or shall signe Judgements, One shilling.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p68">
			<emph type="i">Decrees and Dismissions</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p69">For every Decree and Dismission made by or in the Court of Chauncery, Exchequer, Court of the Dutchy of Lancaster, Courts of the Countyes Palatine of Chester and Durham, Five shillings&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p70">
			<emph type="i">Record of Nisi Prius</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p71">For every Record of Nisi Prius Two shillings and six pence&nbsp;ij<emph type="p">s</emph> vj<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p72">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Records, Copies of Proceedings upon Writs of Error</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p73">For the Copies of all Records to be taken out of any of the Courts at Westminster, or any Office belonging to the same, and not herein before charged, and for the Copies of all Proceedings upon Writts of Error in the Exchequer Chamber not herein before charged for every Sheete to be written with as many Words in every Line, and with as many Lines in every Sheete as are now, or heretofore have beene usually written in such Copies, One penny.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p74">
			<emph type="i">Posteas</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p75">For every Postea that shall be returned by any Clerke of Assize, Associate, or other person authorized to returne Postea's, One shilling.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p76">
			<emph type="i">Recognizances and Statutes</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p77">For every Recognizance and Statute of the Staple, or Statute Merchant that shall be inrolled or entred of Record in any Court or Office whatsoever, Two shillings and six pence.&nbsp;ij<emph type="p">d</emph> vj<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p78">
			<emph type="i">Writs of Error.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p79">For every Writt of Error over and above what is before charged, Six pence.&nbsp;vj<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p80">
			<emph type="i">Orders and Rules.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p81">For every Order or Rule thereupon, One shilling.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p82">
			<emph type="i">Citations</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p83">For every Citation or Monition Ad instantia partis which shall issue out of, or be made in any Ecclesiasticall Court whatsoever, Fower pence.&nbsp;iiij<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p84">
			<emph type="i">Libels.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p85">For every Libell or Allegation, One shilling.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p86">
			<emph type="i">Depositions.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p87">For every Deposition of Witnesses, Fower pence.&nbsp;iiij<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p88">
			<emph type="i">Answers and final Decrees.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p89">For every Answere, Sentence, or Finall Decree, Six pence.&nbsp;vj<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p90">
			<emph type="i">Commission out of Ecclesiasticall Court.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p91">For every Commission issueing out of, any Ecclesiasticall Court Ad instanti? partis, Two shillings&nbsp;ij<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p92">
			<emph type="i">Court</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p93">For every Inventory that shall be exhibited into any Ecclesiasticall Court whatsoever which shall amount to Forty pounds or above, and not to One hundred pounds. One shilling.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p94">
			<emph type="i">Inventories</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p95">For every Inventory that shall be exhibited into any Ecclesiasticall Court whatsoever, which shall amount to One hundred pounds, or above, and not to Five hundred hundred pounds. Six shillings.&nbsp;vj<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p96">For every Inventory that shall be exhibited into any Ecclesiasticall Court whatsoever which shall amount to Five hundred pounds, or above, and not to Five thousand Six shillings.&nbsp;xij<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p97">For every Inventory which shall be exhibited into any Ecclesiasticall Court whatsoever, which shall amount to One thousand pounds or above, One pound two shillings.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph> xj<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p98">
			<emph type="i">Institutions</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p99">For every Institution that shall passe the Seale of any Archbishop or Bishop, Chauncellour or other Ordinary or of any Ecclesiasticall Court, whatsoever Five shillings.&nbsp;V<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p100">
			<emph type="i">Licences from Ecclesiastical Courts</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p101">For every Licence whatsoever that shall passe the Seale of any Ecclesiasticall Court (except Licences for dispenceing the eating of Flesh in Lent) One shilling.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p102">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Wills</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p103">For the Copy of every Will registred in any Ecclesiasticall Court whatsoever, for every Sheete containing as many Words in every Line and as many Lines in every Sheete as are now, or heretofore have beene usually written in such Copies. One penny.&nbsp;i<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p104">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Inventories</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p105">For the Copy of every Inventory which shall be exhibited into any Ecclesiasticall Court, there shall be paid per Presse. Two pence.&nbsp;ii<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p106">
			<emph type="i">Appeals to Delegates.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p107">For every Appeale to the Delegates Ten shillings.&nbsp;X<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p108">
			<emph type="i">Other Appeals.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p109">For every other Appeale from any Inferiour Ecclesiasticall Court to a Superiour Three shillings and fower pence.&nbsp;iij<emph type="p">s</emph> iv<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p110">
			<emph type="i">Significavit pro Corporis deliberatione. Dispensations.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p111">For every Significavit pro Corporis deliberatione, Five shillings.&nbsp;V<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p112">[For every Dispensation to hold Two Ecclesiasticall Dignities, or both a Benefice and a Dignity Fifteene shillings.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]&nbsp;XV<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p113">For every other Dispensation which shall be passed by the Lord Archbishop of Canterbury for the time being or the Master of the Faculties. Ten shillings.&nbsp;X<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p114">
			<emph type="i">Admiralty Proceedings.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p115">For every Warrant Monition and personall Decree, and for every Libell, Allegation, and for every Deposition of every Witnesse, and [for<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] every personall Answere, which shall issue out of, or be made in the Court of the High Admirall of England or in any Court of his Vice-Admiralls, or the Cinque-Ports exerciseing Jurisdi&bholigct;ion. One shilling.&nbsp;I<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p116">
			<emph type="i">Commissions</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p117">For every Co&bhooov;mission that shall issue under the Seale of any of the said Courts of Admiralty last mentioned. Five shillings.&nbsp;V<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p118">
			<emph type="i">Sentences</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p119">For every Sentence that shall be given in any of the said Courts of Admiralty. Five shillings.&nbsp;V<emph type="p">s</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p120">
			<emph type="i">Attachment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p121">For every Attachment that shall be made out of any of the said Courts of Admiralty Three shillings and fower pence.&nbsp;iij<emph type="p">s</emph> iv<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p122">
			<emph type="i">Relaxations of Attachment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p123">For every Relaxation of every Attachment made out of any of the said Courts of Admiralty, Three shillings and fower pence.&nbsp;iij<emph type="p">s</emph> iv<emph type="p">d</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p124">
			<emph type="i">What Officers to colle&bholigct; Duties as follow.; Duties arising from the Great Seal</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p125">Which said severall Rates, Impositions, Dutyes, Charges and Summes of Money shall be colle&bholigct;ed and received by
the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Officers for the time being, and other persons hereafter appointed, or their sufficient
Deputyes for whome they will answere, and in such manner, as is hereafter dire&bholigct;ed, That is to say The said
Duty for every Charter, Writt, and other thing that shall passe the Greate Seale of England as aforesaid shall
be received by the, Clerke of the Hanaper before the said Charter or other thing as aforesaid be sealed.</para>
		<para id="p126">
			<emph type="i">From the Privy Seal.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p127">And the said Duty for every Grant of any Summe of Money or other thing as aforesaid that shall passe the
Privy Seale, and not be dire&bholigct;ed to the Great Seale shall be received by the Clerke attending before the said
Grant or other thing as aforesaid shall be sealed.</para>
		<para id="p128">
			<emph type="i">Deeds, &amp;c. inrolled in Chancery.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p129">And the said Duty for every Deed and Recognizance that shall be inrolled in the Court of Chauncery shall
be received by the Deputy Clerks of the Inrollments respe&bholigct;ively before the inrolling thereof.</para>
		<para id="p130">
			<emph type="i">Orders and Reports.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p131">And the said Duty for every Order and Report in the said Court and for Copies of the same shall be received
by the Register of the said Court before the entring or signing of the same, and that the same shall not be of
any effe&bholigct; untill they are soe signed.</para>
		<para id="p132">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Pleadings.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p133">And the said Duty for the Copy of every Bill Answere, Plea, Demurrer and all other Pleadings whatsoever as
aforesaid in the said Court, and of all Interrogatories and Depositions taken by Commission out of the said Court,
and alsoe the said Dutyes for all Decrees and Dismissions in the said Court, shall be received by the Six Clerkes
of the said Court respe&bholigct;ively before the signing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p134">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Interrogatories.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p135">And the Dutyes for all Copies of all other Interrogatories and Depositions not taken by Commission as aforesaid
shall be received by the Examiners of the said Court respe&bholigct;ively before the signing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p136">
			<emph type="i">Proceedings in the Petty Bag not of Effe&bholigct; till Copies signed by Clerk.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p137">And noe Declaration, Plea Demurrer or other Proceeding in the Pettibag in the said Court, of Chauncery shall
be of any effe&bholigct; untill the respe&bholigct;ive Copies of the same shall be signed by the Clerks of the Pettibag respe&bholigct;ively,
who are hereby required before such signing thereof to receive the Dutyes by this A&bholigct; appointed to be paid for
the same respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p138">
			<emph type="i">Affidavits before Masters.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p139">And the said Duty for every Affidavit made before any of the Masters of the Chauncery in Ordinary shall
be received by the said, Master respe&bholigct;ively, who is alsoe hereby required to signe the Affidavit and to receive
the said Duty upon the signing thereof.</para>
		<para id="p140">
			<emph type="i">Weekly Accounts of Duty.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p141">And the said Duty shall be accounted for every Weeke to such person or persons as his Majesty his Heires
and Successors shall for that purpose nominate and appoint as is hereafter provided.</para>
		<para id="p142">
			<emph type="i">Affidavits before Masters extraordinary.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p143">And the said duty for every Affidavit made before any Master of the Chauncery extraordinary shall be received
by the said Master respe&bholigct;ively, and the said Master is hereby required to signe the same and to receive the said
Duty upon the signing thereof.</para>
		<para id="p144">
			<emph type="i">Writs, &amp;c. of the Court of K. B.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p145">And the said Duty for every Writt, Processe or Mandate as aforesaid that shall issue out of or passe the
Seale of the Court, of Kings Bench shall be received by the Keeper of the said Seale before the sealing of
the same.</para>
		<para id="p146">
			<emph type="i">Bills of Middlesex.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p147">And the said Duty for every Bill of Midlesex as aforesaid shall be received by the Clerke that signs and seales
them before the signeing and sealing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p148">
			<emph type="i">Deeds inrolled in K.B.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p149">And the said Duty for every Deed that shall be inrolled in the said Court of Kings Bench shall be received
by the Prothonotary of the said Court before the inrolling of the same.</para>
		<para id="p150">
			<emph type="i">Recognizances in K. B.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p151">And the said Duty for every Recognizance as aforesaid that shall be acknowledged in the said Court shall
be received by the Secondary on the Crownes side in the said Court at the time of the acknowledgement of
the same.</para>
		<para id="p152">
			<emph type="i">Declarations, &amp;c. in K.B. of no Effe&bholigct; till Copies signed by Secondary.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p153">And noe Declaration, Plea, Replication, Demurrer Rejoynder Issue or other Proceeding upon the same in the
said Court of Kings Bench shall be of any effe&bholigct; untill the respe&bholigct;ive Copies of the same shall, be signed by the
Secondary of the Pleas side, who shall and is hereby required before such Signiture to receive the Dutyes by
this A&bholigct; appointed to be paid for the same respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p154">
			<emph type="i">Bails and Appearances.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p155">And the said Duty for every Baile and Apparance in the said Court shall be received by the Clerke of the
Bailes in the said Court before the fileing and entring of the same respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p156">
			<emph type="i">Rules and Orders in K. B.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p157">And the said Duty for every Rule and Order as aforesaid made or given in the said Court shall be received
by the Clerke of the Rules before the entring of the same.</para>
		<para id="p158">
			<emph type="i">Affidavits in K. B.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p159">And the said Duty for every Affidavit made in the said Court shall be received by the Clerke of the Rules
of the said Court upon the signing or makeing thereof.</para>
		<para id="p160">
			<emph type="i">Affidavits out of Court.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p161">And the said Duty for every Affidavit made before any of the Judges of the said Court out of Court shall
be received by such person or persons from time to time as the said. Judges shall for that purpose respe&bholigct;ively
appoint.</para>
		<para id="p162">
			<emph type="i">Records of Nisi Prius.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p163">And the said Duty for every Record of Nisi Prius in the said Court shall be received by the Custos Breviu&bhouov;
of the said Court before the sealeing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p164">
			<emph type="i">Posleas.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p165">And the said Duty for every Postea in the said Court shall be received by the respe&bholigct;ive Clerks of the Assize
and Associates respe&bholigct;ively upon recording of the Verdi&bholigct;s.</para>
		<para id="p166">
			<emph type="i">Judgments.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p167">And the said Duty for every Judgement as aforesaid in the said Court shall be received by the said Secondary of the Pleas side before the signing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p168">
			<emph type="i">Process in C. P.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p169">And the said Duty for every Writt or Processe that shall passe the Seale of the Court of Common, Pleas as
aforesaid shall be received by the Seale-keeper of the said Court before the sealeing thereof.</para>
		<para id="p170">
			<emph type="i">Deeds inrolled.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p171">And the said Duty for every Deed that shall be inrolled in the said Court of Common Pleas shall be received
by the Clerke of the Warrants of the said Court before the enrolling thereof.</para>
		<para id="p172">
			<emph type="i">Recognizances.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p173">And the said Duty for every Recognizance entred into the said Court of Common Pleas shall be received by
the Prothonotaries of the said Court respe&bholigct;ively at the time of the acknowledgeing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p174">
			<emph type="i">Declarations, &amp;c. in C.P. of no Effe&bholigct; till Copies signed by Prothonotary.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p175">And noe Declaration, Plea, Replication, Demurrer, Rejoynder, Issue or other Proceeding upon the same in the
said Court of Common Pleas shall be of any effe&bholigct; untill the respe&bholigct;ive Copies of the same shall be signed by
the respe&bholigct;ive Prothonotaries of the said Court who shall and are hereby required before such Signiture to receive
the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Dutyes by this A&bholigct; appointed to be paid for the same.</para>
		<para id="p176">
			<emph type="i">Bail.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p177">And the said Duty for every Baile taken in the said Court shall be received by the respe&bholigct;ive Prothonotaries of
the said Court before the entring and fileing of the same respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p178">
			<emph type="i">Appearance.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p179">And the said Duty for every Apparance given upon any Processe made by any of the Filizers of the said Court
shall be received by the said respe&bholigct;ive Filizers, and upon all other Processe by the respe&bholigct;ive Prothonotaries before
the entring of the same.</para>
		<para id="p180">
			<emph type="i">Rules and Orders.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p181">And the said Duty for every, Rule and Order as aforesaid made or given in the said Court shall be received by
the respe&bholigct;ive Secondary of the said Court before the entring of the same.</para>
		<para id="p182">
			<emph type="i">Record of Nisi Prius.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p183">And the said Duty for every Record or Nisi Prius in the said Court shall be received by the respe&bholigct;ive
Prothonotaries of the said Court before the sealeing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p184">
			<emph type="i">Posteas.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p185">And the said Duty for every Postea in the said Court shall be received by the respe&bholigct;ive Clerke of Assize or
Associates that record the Verdi&bholigct; upon recording of the said Verdi&bholigct;.</para>
		<para id="p186">
			<emph type="i">Judgments.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p187">And the said Duty for every Judgement as aforesaid in the said Court of Common Pleas shall be received by
the Prothonotaries of the said Court respe&bholigct;ively before the signeing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p188">
			<emph type="i">Affidavits.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p189">And the said Duty for every Affidavit made in the said Court shall be received by the Secondaries of the said
Court respe&bholigct;ively upon the signing or makeing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p190">
			<emph type="i">Affidavits out of Court.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p191">And for every Affidavit made out of Court before any of the Judges of the said; Court, the said Duty shall be
received by such person or persons as the said Judges respe&bholigct;ively shall from time for that purpose appoint.</para>
		<para id="p192">
			<emph type="i">Grants, &amp;c. under the Exchequer Seal</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p193">And the said Duty for every Grant or other thing as aforesaid which shall passe the Exchequer Seale shall be
received by the Chauncellour of the Exchequer for the time being before such Grant or other thing shall be
sealed.</para>
		<para id="p194">
			<emph type="i">Deeds, &amp;c. inrolled in the Exchequer.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p195">And the said Duty for every Deed or Recognizance that shall be inrolled either in the Kings or Treasurers
Remembrancers Office, or in the Office of Pleas in the Court of Exchequer shall be received by the Masters of
the said severall Offices respe&bholigct;ively before the enrolling of the same.</para>
		<para id="p196">
			<emph type="i">Proceedings in Court of Exchequer of no Effe&bholigct; till Copies signed by Attornies</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p197">And noe Declaration or Information Plea Replication Demurrer Rejoynder Issue or other Proceeding upon
the same in the Kings or Treasurers Remembrancers Offices in the said Court, of Exchequer shall be of any
effe&bholigct; untill the respe&bholigct;ive Copies of the same shall be signed by the respe&bholigct;ive Attourneys of the said severall
Offices who are hereby required before such Signature to receive the Dutyes by this A&bholigct; appointed to be paid
for the same respe&bholigct;ively, the like to be done by the Clerke of the Pleas of the said Court of Exchequer within
his Office respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p198">
			<emph type="i">Bail and Appearance.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p199">And the said Duty for every Baile and Apparance in the said severall Offices in the said Court of Exchequer
shall be received by the Attourneys of the said Court respe&bholigct;ively before the fileing and entring of the same.</para>
		<para id="p200">
			<emph type="i">Rules, Orders, &amp;c.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p201">And the said Duty for every Rule Order and Reporte as aforesaid to be made in the said Court of Exchequer.
and for Copies of the same shall be received by the respe&bholigct;ive Officers or Clerks that signe the same before the
entring, signing or fileing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p202">
			<emph type="i">Record of Nisi Prius.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p203">And the said Duty for every Record of Nisi-prius in the said Court of Exchequer shall be received by
such Officer or Clerke as shall signe the same or the Warrant for the same before the signing of such Record
or Warrant.</para>
		<para id="p204">
			<emph type="i">Postea.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p205">And the said Duty for every Postea in the said Court of Exchequer shall be received by the respe&bholigct;ive Clerke
of Assizes and Associates respe&bholigct;ively upon recording of the Verdi&bholigct;s.</para>
		<para id="p206">
			<emph type="i">Judgments.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p207">And the said Duty for every Judgement in the said Court of Exchequer as aforesaid shall be received by the
severall Officers of the said Court, who shall signe the same respe&bholigct;ively, upon the signing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p208">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Pleadings</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p209">And the said Duty for the Copy of every Bill Answere Plea Demurrer and all other Pleadings whatsoever
as aforesaid in the said Court of Equity in the. Exchequer, and of all Interrogatories and Depositions taken by
Commission out of the said Court, and alsoe the said Duty for all Decrees and Dismissions in the said Court
shall be received by the Attourneys in the Kings Remembrancers Office in the said Court respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p210">And the Dutyes for all Copies of all other Interrogatories and Depositions not taken by Commission as aforesaid
shall be received by the Examiners of the said Court respe&bholigct;ively before the signing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p211">
			<emph type="i">Copies of Proceedings in Error in Exchequer Chamber</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p212">And the said [Dutyes<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] for all Copies of any Proceedings upon Writts of Error in the Exchequer Chamber
upon Judgements given in the said Court of Exchequer shall be received by the respe&bholigct;ive Officer that signs
the same upon the signing thereof, and upon Judgements out of any other Court by the Clerke of the Errors
in like manner.</para>
		<para id="p213">
			<emph type="i">Grants, &amp;c. under Seal of C. P. of Lancaster.</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p214">And the said Duty for every Charter or Grant that shall passe the Seale of the County Palatine of Lancaster
shall be received by the Keeper of the said Seale before the sealeing of the same.</para>
		<para id="p215">
			<emph type="i">Deeds inrolled in Dutchy Court of Lancaster.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p216">And the said Duty for every Deed inrolled and every other thing as aforesaid charged by this A&bholigct; as aforesaid
in the Court of the Dutchy of Lancaster the same shall be received in manner aforesaid by the Clerke of the
said Dutchy Court.</para>
		<para id="p217">
			<emph type="i">Deeds inrolled in any other Court of Record.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p218">And the said Duty for every Deed inrolled in any other Court of Record then the Courts before mentioned
in this A&bholigct; shall be received by the respe&bholigct;ive Officer of the said Courts that shall inroll the same before the
inrolling thereof, and if by any Custos Rotulor? or Clerke of the Peace, then by the Clerke of the Peace
respe&bholigct;ively in manner as aforesaid.</para>
		<para id="p219">
			<emph type="i">Duties in other Counties Palatine.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p220">And the said severall Dutyes by this A&bholigct; ariseing within any other County Palatine shall in like manner be received
by the respe&bholigct;ive Chauncellours or Chamberlaine of the said Countyes Palatine or such as they from time to
time shall for that purpose nominate and appointe respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p221">
			<emph type="i">Plaints in Courts of the Mayor and Sheriffs of London.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p222">And the said Duty for Entry of an A&bholigct;ion or Plaint in the Courts of the Maior or Sheriffes of the Citty of
London, and the Duty of or for any other thing ariseing within the said Courts or any of them shall be
received in manner as aforesaid by the proper Officer that shall a&bholigct; in those severall things from or for which
the said Duty doth arise respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p223">
			<emph type="i">The proper Officer determined.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p224">And if any doubt or question shall arise who is the said proper Officer the same shall be judged and
determined by the said Courts respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p225">
			<emph type="i">Court of Marshalsey Corporation Courts.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p226">And the said severall Dutyes charged by this A&bholigct;, ariseing within the Court of Marshalsey or within any other
Court within any other Corporation then those already mentioned in this A&bholigct; shall be received by the respe&bholigct;ive
Prothonotary Towne-Clerke or Clerke of such Court, and in other inferiour Courts by the respe&bholigct;ive Stewards or
other like Officers of the said Courts in manner as aforesaid.</para>
		<para id="p227">
			<emph type="i">Presentations.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p228">And the said severall Dutyes for every Presentation Collation, Institution, and other thing charged by this A&bholigct;
which shall passe the Episcopall Seale, or the Seale of the Ordinary shall be received by the said Ordinary
respe&bholigct;ively before the sealeing of the same who is hereby required to keepe a Register or Entry of the same.</para>
		<para id="p229">
			<emph type="i">Ecclesiastical Courts.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p230">And the said severall Dutyes ariseing within the Court of the Arches or any other Ecclesiasticall Court as
aforesaid shall be received by the Registers of the said severall Courts respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p231">
			<emph type="i">Inhibitions on Appeals.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p232">And the said Duty for every Inhibition that shall issue upon an Appeale as aforesaid shall be received by
the respe&bholigct;ive Registers of the Courts to which the said Appeales shall be made.</para>
		<para id="p233">
			<emph type="i">Dispensations.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p234">And the said Duty for every Dispensation Faculty and License as aforesaid which shall be passed by the Lord
Archbishop of Canterbury or Master of the Facultyes shall be received by the said Master of the Facultyes for
the time being.</para>
		<para id="p235">
			<emph type="i">Admiralty Courts.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p236">And the said Dutyes ariseing within any of the [said<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Courts of the Admirall or his Vice-Admiralls or of
the Cinque-Ports shall be received by the respe&bholigct;ive Registers of the said Courts.</para>
		<para id="p237">
			<emph type="i">Copies of any other Records in the Courts of Westminster.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p238">And the said Dutyes for the Copies of any other Records that shall be taken out of any of the said Courts
of Westminster or any Office belonging to the said Courts the Receipt and Colle&bholigct;ion whereof is not herein
already disposed or appointed shall be received by the severall Officers and other persons that shall make or signe
the same upon the makeing or signing of them.</para>
		<para id="p239">
			<emph type="i">Courts of Marches of Wales.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p240">And the said Dutyes ariseing within the Court or Councell of the Marches of Wales as aforesaid shall be
received by the Clerke of the Signet, or Secretary of the said Court or Councell in manner as aforesaid.</para>
		<para id="p241">
			<emph type="i">Courts of Grand Sessions in Wales.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p242">And the said Dutyes ariseing within the severall Courts of the Grand Sessions in Wales as aforesaid shall be
received by the Baron of the Exchequer in each Circuit, and by the Prothonotary, and the Register and the two
Attourneys in Chauncery of each Circuit respe&bholigct;ively in manner following that is to say.</para>
		<para id="p243">
			<emph type="i">Original Writs and other Matters herein mentioned.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p244">For Originall Writts and other matters that passe the Seale for Originalls shall be received by the said Barons
respe&bholigct;ively. and for Judiceall Writts, Inrolment of Deeds and Recognizances, Rules and Orders in Proceedings at
Common Law, and Copies of them, Copies of Declarations Pleas and other Proceedings at the Common Law, and
for Bailes and Apparances Judgements and other things as aforesaid relateing to the Common Law to be received
by the respe&bholigct;ive Prothonotaries of each Circuit, and for Copies of all Bills, Answers, Pleas, Demurrers and other
Proceedings as aforesaid relateing to Equity, to be received by the respe&bholigct;ive Register and the said two Attourneys
in Chauncery of each Circuit respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p245">
			<emph type="i">The said several Duties to be paid by Persons so receiving to Receiver General</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p246">And the said severall Rates, Impositions Dutyes Charges and Summes of Money soe to be received by the said
severall and respe&bholigct;ive Officers and other persons as aforesaid shall be respe&bholigct;ively charged upon them, and by
them duely and perticularly accounted for, answered and paid to such person and persons as by his Majestie, his
Heires and Successors shall be thereunto specially appointed to be the Generall Receiver or Receivers by Warrant
under the Great or the Privy Seale at or before the dayes hereafter limitted that is to say, at or before the first
day of Michaelmas Terme, the first day of Hillary Terme, and the first day of Easter Terme in every yeare
dureing the continuance of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		<para id="p247">
			<emph type="i">Receivers of Duties to account upon Oath</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p248">And as to the Dutyes ariseing in any of the said Courts every of the said respe&bholigct;ive persons who shall receive
any of the said Dutyes shall from time to time make Oath before some or one of the Judges of the same
Court, where the said Dutyes doe or shall arise of the truth of their respe&bholigct;ive Accounts.</para>
		<para id="p249">
			<emph type="i">Duties arising elsewhere than as aforesaid to be accounted for on Oath to Justice of Peace, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p250">And for all such of the said Dutyes as shall arise otherwhere, and are not relateing to any of the said Courts
Ecclesiasticall or Temporall, or the Officers or Ministers of the same, the persons by this A&bholigct; appointed to receive
the same shall make Oath of the truth of such their Accounts before some Justice of the Peace, or Master in
Chauncery in Ordinary or Extraordinary who are hereby authorized and required to administer such Oathes.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Receiver General's Acquittance a Discharge without Fee.</head>
			<para id="p251">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the said Receiver or Receivers Generall at every time of
payment appointed by this A&bholigct; as aforesaid shall give unto the said severall Officers and persons aforesaid upon
the payment of any of the Summes of Money due by this A&bholigct; severall Acquittances under their Hands and
Seales without takeing any thing for the same. Which said Acquittances shall be a full and perfe&bholigct; discharge for
the Summes of Money therein mentioned to the said severall Officers and persons paying the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The Receivers to keep Books of Entries; to be from time to time produced to Receiver General.</head>
			<para id="p252">And to the end the said severall Dutyes may be the better accounted for and answered to his Majestie his
Heires and Successors in manner aforesaid Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That every of the said Officers and other
persons soe as aforesaid appointed to receive the said Dutyes respe&bholigct;ively shall keepe Bookes, wherein all Moneys
by him to be received in pursuance of this A&bholigct;, expressing the Names of the persons from whome, and for what
the same were received shall be duely entred and sett downe, which Bookes shall from time to time be produced
and shewn to the said Receiver or Receivers General soe to be appointed or such other person or persons as
shall be thereunto lawfully authorized by his Majestie his Heires and Successors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Receiver General to have View of Records, and may take Notes, &amp;c. without Fee.</head>
			<para id="p253">And the said Receiver or Receivers Generall or such other person or persons as shall be thereunto lawfully
authorized by his Majestie his Heires and Successors as aforesaid shall likewise have free resorte at any seasonable
time to any Record or Entry of any Proceedings or other matters aforesaid, to search, view and peruse the same,
and as occasion shall be to take Notes or Abstra&bholigct;s out of the same without any thing paying for the same, and
the Officers of the severall Courts before mentioned are hereby required to be aiding and assisting to such Receiver
or Receivers Generall therein.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Officers to give Security.</head>
			<para id="p254">And the said severall Officers and other persons in their respe&bholigct;ive Courts aforesaid shall give such Security
for the due entring, accompting for, answering and paying the said severall Dutyes and S&bhouov;mes of Money by them
respe&bholigct;ively to be received as aforesaid as by the said Courts respe&bholigct;ively shall be dire&bholigct;ed and appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Negle&bholigct;ing to pay or receive the Duties;</head>
			<para id="p255">
				<emph type="i">First Offence; Penalty.; Second Offence; Forfeiture of Office and Incapacity</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p256">And if any Attourney, Sollicitor or other person whatsoever charged or chargeable with any of the said Dutyes
by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall not duely and fully answere and pay the same to the proper Officer appointed to
receive the same as aforesaid, or if such Officer shall wilfully refuse or negcle&bholigct; to receive the same, or shall
not truely enter the same in a Booke, and justly accompt for, answere and pay the same to the respe&bholigct;ive Receiver
Generall in manner aforesaid, then every such person soe offending shall upon convi&bholigct;ion for the first defaulte
for which he shall be questioned and convi&bholigct;ed forfeite and pay to the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors
ten times the value of the Duty or Dutyes which his Majesty his Heires or Successors shall lose by such defaulte
to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill Plaint or Information in any of his Majestyes Courts of Record wherein
noe Essoyne Wager of Law or Prote&bholigct;ion is to be allowed, and upon a second convi&bholigct;ion for the like default
afterwards committed shall forfeite such his Office and imployment, and be for ever uncapeable of holding or
enjoying the same or the like Office or Employment.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. The Judges of the respe&bholigct;ive Courts to make Rules and Orders for colle&bholigct;ing, &amp;c. Duties.</head>
			<para id="p257">And the Judges of the severall Courts respe&bholigct;ively are hereby authorized and required from time to time to
take such security as aforesaid, and to give, make and publish such Rules, Orders and Dire&bholigct;ions for the better
entring colle&bholigct;ing accompting for answering and paying of the said severall Dutyes by the Officers of the said
respe&bholigct;ive Courts, or such [other<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Officers as shall be thereunto authorized by his Majestie in the said severall Courts;
and for preventing all Fraudes and Abuses therein as to the said Judges of the respe&bholigct;ive Courts aforesaid shall
seeme meete, Soe as they impose noe other Forfeitures or Penalties then are contained in this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Criminal Proceedings and Suits in forma pauperis.</head>
			<para id="p258">Provided alwayes and it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That none of the Rates Impositions Dutyes
Charges or Summes of Money before in this A&bholigct; expressed shall be raised, leavyed, colle&bholigct;ed or paid or payable
unto his Majestie by vertue of this A&bholigct; upon any Information Indi&bholigct;ment or other Proceedings at his Majestyes
Suite in [any of<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] the said Courts for or in respe&bholigct; of any Felony Trespasse or other criminall matter whatsoever;
nor to any person or persons that shall be admitted to sue or defend in forma pauperis. Any thing herein
contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Recital of Intention of 43 Eliz; c. 6.</head>
			<para id="p259">
				<emph type="i">In Personal A&bholigct;ions wherein no Judges Certificate of Assault, &amp;c. or of Title of Land is in Question, and Damages under 40s. no more Costs than Damages; otherwise Judgment void, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p260">[And for prevention of triviall and vexatious Suites in Law, whereby many good Subje&bholigct;s of this Realme have
beene and are dayly undone contrary to the intention of an A&bholigct; made in the three and fortyeth yeare of Queene
Elizabeth for avoiding of infinite numbers of small and trifling Suites commenced in the Courts at Westminster
Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed for makeing the said Law effe&bholigct;uall That from and after the first of May aforesaid in all
A&bholigct;ions of Trespasse, Assault and Battery and other personall A&bholigct;ions wherein the Judge at the Tryall of the
Cause shall not finde and certifie under his Hand upon the backe of the Record that an Assault and Battery
was sufficiently proved by the Plaintiffe against the Defendant, or that the Freehold or Title of the Land mentioned
in the Plaintiffes Declaration was cheifely in question, the Plaintiffe in such A&bholigct;ion in case the Jury shall finde
the Dammage to be under the value of forty shillings shall not recover or obtaine more Costs of Suite, then the
Dammages soe found shall amount unto, And if any more Costs in any such A&bholigct;ion shall be awarded, the
Judgement shall be void, and the Defendant is hereby acquitted of, and from the same, and may have his A&bholigct;ion
against the Plaintiffe for such vexatious Suite, and recover his Damages and Costs of such his Suite in any of
the said Courts of Record.<ref idref="n9">9</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">xls <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">viij d. <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Duty <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


