<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47437" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XV. An Act for the better Setlement of the Maintenance of the Parsons Vicars and Curates in the Parishes of the
Citty of London burnt by the late dreadfull Fire there.[Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 2. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;. </head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">22 Car. II. c. 11</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Tythes in the City of London were leavyed and paid with great Inequality and are since
the late dreadfull Fire there in the rebuilding of the same by takeing away of some Houses, altering the
Foundations of many and the [new<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] ere&bholigct;ing of others soe disordered that in case they should not for the time to
come be reduced to a certainty many Controversies and Suits of Law might thence arise Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the
Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the
Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That the Annuall certaine
Tythes of all and every Parish and Parishes within the said Citty of London and the Libertyes thereof whose
Churches have beene demolished, or in part consumed by the late Fire, and which said Parishes by vertue of an
A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament entituled An Additionall A&bholigct; for the rebuilding of the Citty of London, uniteing
of Parishes and rebuilding of the Cathedrall and Parochiall Churches within the said Citty. remaine and continue
single as heretofore they were or are by the said A&bholigct; annexed or united into one Parish respe&bholigct;ively, shall be as
followeth (That is to say) The annuall certaine Tythes or Summe of Money in lieu of Tythes.</para>
		<table id="t1">
			<tr>
				<td cols="2"/>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of the Parish of Alhallowes [Lumber<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] streete One hundred and ten pounds</td>
				<td>cx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Bartholomew Exchange One hundred pounds.</td>
				<td>c<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Bridget alias Brides One hundred and twenty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Bennet Finck One hundred Pounds</td>
				<td>c<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Michaell Crooked lane One hundred pounds</td>
				<td>c<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Christopher One hundred and twenty pounds</td>
				<td>cxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Dionis Back church One hundred and twenty pounds</td>
				<td>cxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Dunstan in the East Two hundred pounds</td>
				<td>cc<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint James Garlicke hythe One hundred pounds</td>
				<td>c<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Michaell Cornhill One hundred and forty pounds</td>
				<td>cxl<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Michaell Bassishaw One hundred thirty and two pounds and eleaven shillings.</td>
				<td>cxxxij<emph type="p">l</emph> xj<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Margaret Lothbury One hundred pounds</td>
				<td>C<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Mary Aldermanbury One hundred and fifty pounds</td>
				<td>cl<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Martin Ludgate One hundred and sixty pounds.</td>
				<td>clx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Peter Cornhill One hundred and ten pounds</td>
				<td>cx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Stephen Coleman streete One hundred and ten pounds</td>
				<td>cx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Sepulchre Two hundred Pounds</td>
				<td>cc<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Allhallowes Bread streete and Saint John Evangelish One hundred and forty pounds</td>
				<td>cxl<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Alhallowes the Great and Alhallowes the Lesse Two hundred pounds.</td>
				<td>cc<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Albanes Woodstreete and Saint Olaves Silver Streete One hundred and seaventy pounds.</td>
				<td>Clxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Anne and Agnes and [S<emph type="p">t</emph>.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] John Zachary One hundred and forty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxl<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Augustine and Saint Faith One hundred seaventy and two pounds.</td>
				<td>clxxij<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Andrew Wardrobe and Saint Anne Blacke Fryers One hundred and forty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxl<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Antholin and Saint John Baptist One hundred and twenty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Bennet Grace Church and Saint Leonard Eastcheape One hundred and forty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxl<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Bennet Pauls-Wharfe and Saint Peter Pauls Wharfe One hundred pounds.</td>
				<td>c<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Christ Church and Saint Leonard Foster lane Two hundred pounds.</td>
				<td>cc<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Edmond the King and Saint Nicholas [Acows<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] One hundred and eighty pounds.</td>
				<td>clxxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint George Buttolph lane and Saint Buttolph Billingsgate One hundred and eighty pounds.</td>
				<td>clxxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Lawrence Jury and Saint Magdalen Milke streete One hundred and twenty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Magnus and Saint Margaret New Fish streete One hundred and seaventy pounds.</td>
				<td>clxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Michaell Royall and Saint Martin Vintry One hundred and forty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxl<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Mathew Friday streete and Saint Peter Cheape One hundred and fifty pounds.</td>
				<td>cl<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Margaret Pattons and Saint Gabriell Fen Church One hundred and twenty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Mary at Hill and Saint Andrew Hubbard Two hundred pounds.</td>
				<td>cc<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Mary Woolnoth and Saint Mary Woolchurch One hundred and sixty pounds.</td>
				<td>clx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Clement Eastcheape and Saint Martin Orgars One hundred and forty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxl<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Mary Abchurch and Saint Lawrence Pountney One hundred and twenty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Mary Aldermary and Saint Thomas Apostles One hundred and fifty pounds.</td>
				<td>cl<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Mary le Bow, Saint Pancras Soper lane and Alhallowes Honey lane Two hundred pounds.</td>
				<td>cc.<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Mildred Poultrey and Saint Mary Cole Church One hundred and seaventy pounds.</td>
				<td>clxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Michaell Woodstreete and Saint Mary Staining One hundred pounds.</td>
				<td>c<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Mildred Bread streete and Saint Margaret Moses One hundred and thirty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Michaell Queene hyth and Trinity One hundred and sixty pounds.</td>
				<td>clx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Magdalen Old Fish streete and Saint Gregory One hundred and twenty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Mary Somerset and Saint Mary Mounthaw One hundred and ten pounds.</td>
				<td>cx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Nicholas Cole Abbey and Saint Nicholas Olaves One hundred and thirty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Olave Jury and Saint Martin Ironmonger-lane One hundred and twenty pounds</td>
				<td>cxx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Stephen Walbrooke and Saint Bennet Sheerehog One hundred pounds</td>
				<td>c.<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Swithin and Saint Mary Bothaw One hundred and forty pounds.</td>
				<td>cxl<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Of Saint Vedast alias Fosters and Saint Michaell Querne One hundred and sixty pounds</td>
				<td>clx<emph type="p">l</emph>
				</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">The said Rate in lieu of Tithes to be paid to Parsons and their Successors</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">Which respe&bholigct;ive Summes of Money to be paid in liew of Tythes within the said respe&bholigct;ive Parishes and
assessed as herein after is dire&bholigct;ed shall be and continue to be esteemed deemed and taken to all intents and
purposes to be the respe&bholigct;ive certaine Annuall Maintenance (over and above Glebes and Perquisites Gifts and
Bequests to the respe&bholigct;ive Parson Vicar and Curate of any Parish for the time being, or to his or their
respe&bholigct;ive Successors or to other persons for his or their use) of the said respe&bholigct;ive Parsons, Vicars and Curates,
who shall be legally instituted, indu&bholigct;ed and admitted into the respe&bholigct;ive Parishes aforesaid.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Who to make the Assessments, and when.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Assessments to be made upon Houses, Shops, Ground unbuilt on, &amp;c.; Proviso for Parsonage Houses, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And that the said severall Summes of Money for Tythes may be more equally assessed upon the severall
Houses Buildings and all other Hereditaments whatsoever within all the said respe&bholigct;ive Parishes Bee it ena&bholigct;ed
by the authoritie aforesaid That the Alderman of such respe&bholigct;ive Ward or Wards within the said Citty, wherein
any of the said Parishes respe&bholigct;ively lye, and his or their Deputy or Deputyes, and the Co&bhooov;mon councell men of
such respe&bholigct;ive Ward or Wards with the Churchwardens and one or more [of the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Parishioners of such respe&bholigct;ive
Parish wherein the Maintenance aforesaid is respe&bholigct;ively to be assessed, to be nominated by such respe&bholigct;ive
Aldermen, Deputy, Common councell men and Churchwardens or any five of them, whereof the Alderman or his
Deputy to be one, shall at some convenient and seasonable time before the twentyeth day of May in the yeare
of our Lord [God<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] One thousand six hundred and seaventy one, assemble and meete together [at<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] some convenient
place within every of the respe&bholigct;ive Parishes in such respe&bholigct;ive Ward wherein the Maintenance aforesaid is to be
assessed, And they or the major part of them soe assembled shall proportionably assesse upon all Houses,
Shopps, Warehouses and Cellars, Wharfes, Keyes, Cranes, Waterhouses (which Waterhouses shall pay in their
respe&bholigct;ive Parishes where they stand and not elsewhere) and Tofts of Ground (remaining unbuilt) and all other
Hereditaments whatsoever (except Parsonage and Vicarage Houses) the whole respe&bholigct;ive Summe by this A&bholigct;
appointed, or soe much of it as is more then what each Impropriator is by this A&bholigct; enjoyned respe&bholigct;ively to allow,
in the most equall way that the said Assessors according to the best of their Judgements can make it; which
said Assessments shall be made and finished before the fower and twentyeth day of July then next ensueing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Variance arising upon the Assessments to be determined by Lord Mayor and Court of Aldermen.</head>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any variance or doubt shall happen to arise
about any Summe soe assessed as aforesaid, or that any Parishioner or Parishioners or Owner or Owners of any
House, Shopp, Warehouse or Cellar, Wharfe, Key, Crane, Waterhouse, Toft of Ground or other Hereditament
within any of the said Parishes shall finde himselfe or themselves agreived by the assessing of any Summte or
Summes of money in manner and forme aforesaid That then upon complaint made by the party or partyes
agreived to the Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen of the said Citty, within fowerteene dayes after notice
given to the party or partyes assessed of such Assesment made. the said Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen
summoning aswell the party or partyes agreived, as the Alderman and such others as made the said Assesment
shall heare and determine the same in a summary way, and the Judgement by them given shall be finall and
without Appeale.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. A Review, if Occasion be, of any Assessment within Three Months.</head>
			<para id="p8">[Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That any Assesment or Rate to be made or laid by vertue of this A&bholigct;
shall or may in all or any the Parishes aforesaid in like manner be reveiwed or altred or laid againe within three
Moneths after the twenty fowerth day of June One thousand six hundred and seaventy fower according to the
aforesaid Rules and any such Assesment or Rate shall or may be againe reviewed or reassesed within three Moneths
after the twenty fourth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty one, And that all
and every such new Assesment and Rate shall be lyable to the like Appeals as aforesaid, and shall be colle&bholigct;ed
leavyed and paid as any other Assesment or Rate mentioned in this A&bholigct; may or ought to be.<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. If the Persons appointed by this A&bholigct; refuse to a&bholigct;, then others to be chosen by the Lord Mayor, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p9">And if the said Alderman, Deputy, Common councell men and Parishioner or Parishioners soe appointed as
aforesaid shall after summons and requests made in that behalfe unto them by the Lord Maior and Court of
Aldermen, or the Incumbent or Incumbents of any the said respe&bholigct;ive Parish or Parishes refuse and negcle&bholigct; to
meete and make such Assesment as aforesaid then it shall and may be lawfull to and for such person or persons
as shall be thereunto authorized and required by the said Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen to make such Assesment
as by the said Aldermen Deputy Common Councell-men Churchwardens, Parishioner or Parishioners aforesaid should
or ought to have beene made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Three Transcripts of Assessments to be made and subscribed by Assessors;</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">One to be returned to Lord Mayor, another to Bishop of London's Registry, the other to remain in the Vestry</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the said Assessors within ten dayes after such
Assesments made, and the respe&bholigct;ive Appeales (if any be) determined shall make three Transcripts thereof in
Parchment containing the respe&bholigct;ive Summes to be payable or appointed to be paid out of all and every the
Premisses within such respe&bholigct;ive Parish and subscribe the same under their Hands and within twenty dayes after
such Subscription as aforesaid, one of the said Transcripts shall be returned to the Lord Maior of the Citty of
London to be kept and preserved by the said Lord Maior in and among the Records of the said Citty for a
perpetuall memoriall thereof; And another of the said Transcripts shall be returned into the Registry of the Lord
Bishop of London to be kept and preserved as aforesaid, And the other of the said Transcripts shall remaine and
be kept in the Vestry of such respe&bholigct;ive [Parish<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] for a perpetuall memoriall as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Assessments to be paid Quarterly to Parson.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Payment to commence from Incumbent officiating</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And for the surer and better payment of the said respe&bholigct;ive Summes of Money soe to be assessed and taxed
towards the raiseing of the said Maintenance of the respe&bholigct;ive Parsons, Vicars and Curates of the said respe&bholigct;ive
Parishes as aforesaid Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That all and every such respe&bholigct;ive Summe
and Summes of Money soe to be assessed and taxed as aforesaid towards the raiseing of the said Maintenance
of the said respe&bholigct;ive Parsons Vicars and Curates of the said respe&bholigct;ive Parishes shall be paid to the said respe&bholigct;ive
Parsons, Vicars and Curates and their Successors respe&bholigct;ively at the fower most usuall Feasts (that is to say) at the
Annunciation of the Blessed Virgin Mary, the Nativity of Saint John Baptist, the Feast of Saint Michaell the Arch
Angell and the Nativity of our Blessed Saviour, or within fowerteene dayes after each of the Feasts aforesaid by
equall payments; the respe&bholigct;ive payments thereof to beginne and commence onely from such time and times as the
Incumbent or Incumbents of such respe&bholigct;ive Parish shall beginne to officiate or preach as Incumbent or Parson in
the respe&bholigct;ive Church belonging to such respe&bholigct;ive Parish, or in some other convenient place or places in such
respe&bholigct;ive Parish or Parishes to be nominated or appointed by the Lord Bishop of London for the time being, or
by the Archbishop of Canterbury in any place within his peculiars.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Impropriators to make the same Allowances they did before the Fire.</head>
			<para id="p14">And in any Parish or Parishes where any Impropriations be Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That all
and every the Impropriator or Impropriators of any of the said Parishes shall pay and allow what really and bona
fide they have used and ought to pay and satisfye to the respe&bholigct;ive Incumbent of such respe&bholigct;ive Parish at any
time before the said late Fire, and the same shall be esteemed and computed as part of the maintenance of
such Incumbent, notwithstanding this A&bholigct; or any Clause or Matter or thing therein contained.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Inhabitants refusing Payment,</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">being lawfully demanded at the House, &amp;c.; Lord Mayor may grant Warrant to levy the same by Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any the Inhabitants in any the respe&bholigct;ive Parish
or Parishes as aforesaid shall or doe refuse or negcle&bholigct; to pay to the respe&bholigct;ive Incumbents aforesaid of any of
the said respe&bholigct;ive Parishes any Summe or Summes of Moneys to him respe&bholigct;ively payable or appointed to be
paid by this A&bholigct; or any part thereof contrary to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct; (being lawfully demanded
at the House or Houses, Wharfe, Key, Crane, Cellar or other p&bhopcrl;misses whereout the same is payable) that then
it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Lord Maior of the Citty of London for the time being upon Oath
to be made before him of such refusall or negcle&bholigct; to give and grant out Warrants for the Officer or person
appointed to colle&bholigct; the same with the assistance of a Constable in the day time to leavy the same Tythes or
Summes of Money soe due, and in arreare and unpaid, by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of the party or
partyes soe refuseing or negcle&bholigct;ing to pay, restoreing to the Owner or Owners the Overplus of such Goods
over and above the said Arreares of the said Moneys soe due and unpaid, and the reasonable [Charge<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] of makeing
such Distresse, which he is to dedu&bholigct; out of the Moneys raised by Sale of such Goods.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. If Lord Mayor refuse, &amp;c. to execute this A&bholigct;, Lord Chancellor or Keeper or Two Barons of the Exchequer may, by Warrants under their Hands and Seals, appoint Officers, &amp;c. to levy by Distress, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That in case the Lord Maior or Court of Aldermen shall refuse or
negcle&bholigct; to execute any of the respe&bholigct;ive powers to them by this A&bholigct; granted, or to performe all and every such
thing relateing either to the assessing or leavying of the respe&bholigct;ive Summes aforesaid as they are by this A&bholigct;
authorized and required to performe, That then it shall and may be lawfull for the Lord Chauncellour or Lord
Keeper of the Great Seale of England [for the time being<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] or any two or more of the Barons of his Majestyes
Court of Exchequer by Warrant or Warrants under his or their respe&bholigct;ive Hands and Seales to doe and performe
what the said Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen according to the true intent and meaning of this present A&bholigct;
might or ought to have done, and by such Warrant either to impower any person or persons to make the
respe&bholigct;ive Assesments as aforesaid, or to authorize the respe&bholigct;ive Officers or persons appointed to colle&bholigct; the Summes
aforesaid to leavy the same by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of any person or persons that shall refuse or
negcle&bholigct; to pay the same in manner and forme aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Proviso for Incumbents of united Parishes.</head>
			<para id="p18">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That where any of the Parishes within the said Citty have since the late
Fire by Death or otherwise become vacant, the surviveing or remaining Incumbent of (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) the other Parish thereto
united, or therewith consolidated shall have and enjoy, and have like remedy to recover the Tythes hereby setled
to be paid as if he had beene a&bholigct;ually presented, admitted, instituted and indu&bholigct;ed into both the said Parishes since
the Union and Consolidation thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. No Court to hold Plea for any Duty arising upon this A&bholigct;, other than herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p19">Provided alwayes That noe Court or Judge Ecclesiasticall or Temporall shall hold Plea of, or for any the Summe
or Summes of Money due and oweing, or to be paid by vertue of this A&bholigct; or any part thereof other then the
persons hereby authorized to have Cognizance thereof. Nor shall it be lawfull to or for any Parson, Vicar, Curate
or Incumbent to convent or sue any person or persons assessed as aforesaid, and refuseing or negcle&bholigct;ing to pay
the same in any Court or Courts or before any Judge or Judges other then what are authorized and appointed by
this A&bholigct; for the heareing and determineing of the same in manner aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for Minor Canons of St. Pauls, Parson of St. Gregory's Church, as to Tithes, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p20">Provided alwayes That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Warden and Minor Canons of Saint Pauls
Church London, Parson and Proprietors of the Re&bholigct;ory of Saint Gregory aforesaid to receive and enjoy all Tythes,
Oblations and Dutyes ariseing or growing due within the said Parish in as large and beneficiall manner as formerly
they have, or lawfully might have done. Any thing herein to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Lumbard <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Acons <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">in <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">annexe to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">charges <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


