<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47435" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An Act for exporting of Beere Ale and Mum.[Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 2. nu. p.I.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Strong Ale, Strong Beer and Mum may be exported, paying Customs, </head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">in the Presence of Officer, and on Notice to Commissioners, &amp;c. 
The Rates of Custom; Officer to certify Quantity shipped.; Allowance of Excise Duty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the advancement of Trade and encouragement of the Tillage and Manufa&bholigct;ure of this Realme Bee it
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and Commons in Parlyament assembled and by authority of the same That from and after the six and
twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy one, it shall be lawfull for any person in any Sea-Port
or upon any navigable River to export and shipp off as Merchandize, [within any of the usuall and allowed
Ports by Law, and at the common Keyes for exportation and ladeing on board of Merchandize, or Keyes to be
appointed for that purpose, and within the usuall Hours of Excise<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] for accompte of himselfe or any other (to be
exported into Forreigne Parts) in the presence of a sworne Gauger or other Sworne Officer to be appointed by
the Farmers, Commissioners or Sub Commissioners of his Majestyes Excise upon notice thereof to them given at
the Office of Excise within the limitts whereof the said Ale, Beere or Mum was brewed, of the respe&bholigct;ive Port
or Place whence the same shall be shipped any sort of strong Ale, strong Beere or Mum to be spent beyond
the Seas paying Custome for the same after the Rate of one shilling for every Tunn which shall be exported in
any English or Forreigne Vessell and noe more or other Duty whatsoever, Which said Gauger or Officer aforesaid
shall certifie the quantity of the said Beere, Ale or Mum shipt off, to the Co&bhooov;missioners and Officers of Excise
where the Entry thereof shall be made, who are hereby required to make allowance, or repay the Excise of the
Beere, Ale or Mum soe exported unto the Brewer thereof dedu&bholigct;ing one shilling per Tunn for the Charges of
their Officers and noe more.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Unlading the same in any Places but beyond Sea;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any Merchant or Master of any Shipp or Vessell or other person shall
cause or suffer any of the said Liquors soe shipt in any Vessell as Merchandize to be unshipt unladen and laid
on Land, or putt into any other Shipp or Vessell within the Kingdome of England, Dominion of Wales or Towne
of Berwicke upon Tweede, he shall forfeite the same and One hundred pounds of lawfull money of England more
for every Caske he shall soe unduely land or putt [on board<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] any Vessell to be recovered in any of his Majestyes
Courts of Record by Information, Bill or Plaint, The one moyety of which Forfeiture shall be to the use of our
Soveraigne Lord the King, the other moyety to the Informer and Prosecutor.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Quantity of Beer, &amp;c. to be charged to Master of Ship in his Vi&bholigct;ualling Bill.</head>
			<para id="p5">And to the intent [that<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] his Majestyes Duty of Excise may not be prejudiced for such Beere Ale or Mum as
shall be spent on Shipp board, his Majestyes Co&bhooov;missioners and Officers of the Customes are hereby required and
enjoyned to charge every Master of any Shipp or Vessell in his Vi&bholigct;ualling Bill with soe much Beere, Ale or
Mum and noe more as such number of men use to spend in such Voyages, the Excise whereof to be recovered
according to the Lawes and Rules already established.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Duty to be levied as by Tonnage and Poundage.</head>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the aforesaid Rate of One shilling the Tun for Beere, Ale and Mum to be
exported as aforesaid shall be leavyed and paid under such Rules and Penaltyes, and for such time, and in such
manner as by the Lawes of Tonnage and Poundage are ordained.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No. Duty to be repaid on Exportation of Foreign Mum.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That noe Mum imported from Forreigne
Parts dureing the continuance of this A&bholigct;, shall have any part of the Duty of Custome or Excise paid at the
Importation thereof, repaid upon Exportation, Any Law, Statute or Usage to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p8">This A&bholigct; to continue in force for six yeares from the twenty sixth of June One thousand six hundred seaventy
one, and from thence to the end of the next Session of Parlyament and noe longer.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">aboard <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


