<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47445" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIII. An Act to revive an A&bholigct;, Entituled An A&bholigct; to prevent the disturbances of Seamen and others, and to preserve the
Stores belonging to his Majestyes Navy Royall, with some Alterations and Additions. [Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 2. nu. ii.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 18 &amp; 19 C. II. c. 12. (19 C.II.C.7.)</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The said A&bholigct;, except &sect; 5. continued</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas at a Session of this present Parlyament holden at Westminster the eighteenth day of September One
thousand six hundred sixty and six An A&bholigct; of Parlyament was made Entituled, An A&bholigct; to prevent the
disturbances of Seamen and others, and to preserve the Stores belonging to his Majestyes Navy Royall, which was to
continue two yeares from the first of February One thousand six hundred sixty and six, and from thence to the end
of the next Session of Parlyament, which is already past, and the time for the continuance of the said A&bholigct; expired.
And whereas the said A&bholigct; is by experience found to be of necessary use and fitt to be revived and continued, in all
the matters therein contained, except as is hereafter excepted. Bee it therefore enacted by the Kings most excellent
Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the C&bhooov;mons in Parlyament
assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the said A&bholigct; of Parlyament and all and every the Clauses, Sentences
and Articles therein contained, (excepting one Clause in the said A&bholigct; contained, whereby it is ena&bholigct;ed That noe
Ordinary, Register, or other Officer belonging to any Ecclesiasticall Court or Court of Orphans, or any Jurisdi&bholigct;ion
whatsoever within the Kingdome of England, Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede shall take or
receive of the Executor or Administrator, Executors or Administrators of any Mariner or Souldier dyeing in the Pay
of his Majestyes Navy dureing this present Warr, above the Summe of Twelve Pence for the Probate of any Will,
registring the same; granting Letters of Administrations, exhibiting any Inventory, or for any other matter or thing
relateing thereunto; together with such Forfeitures and Penaltyes as is therein expressed, for the Defaults and
Transgressions therein mentioned) shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; be revived and continued, and have the full force and
vertue of a Law dureing the continuance of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Recital that divers Persons embezzle His Majesty's Stores, and cannot be convicted by reason of the Absence of Witnesses.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Where the Value of the Stores embezzled is under 203. Treasurer, &amp;c. of the Navy may convi&bholigct;, and impose Penalty; which may be levied by Distress.; If not sufficient Distress, Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And whereas diverse ill disposed persons upon pretence of carrying his Majeftyes Navall Goods, Provisions
Victualls Stores and Ammunition from his Majestyes Yards, Wharfes, Storehouses or other places to his Majestyes
Ship or Ships, or to such Shipp or Shipps as are employed in his Majestyes Services, or such persons as are
imployed to recarry or remove from the said Ship or Ships such Navall Goods, Provisions, Vi&bholigct;ualls, Stores and
Ammunition to [such<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] his Majestyes Yards, Wharfes, Storehouses or other places doe frequently imbezill, take, and
carry them away where they cannot be found, and remove themselves to places unknowne before they can be
convi&bholigct;ed by due processe of Law, by reason that those Witnesses that should prove the said Fa&bholigct;s are bound
forth to Sea, or otherwise imployed elsewhere. And it is found necessary that Justice be more speedily done in
such cases then by ordinary course of Law it can be, Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the
Treasurer, Comptroller, Surveyour, Clerke of the A&bholigct;s and Commissers of the Navy for the time being, or any one or
more of them where the value of the Goods soe imbezelled, taken or carryed away shall be under the value of Twenty
shillings, shall have full power and authority upon the Oath of two or more Witnesses (which they or any of them
have hereby power to (administer) or confession of such party soe offending as aforesaid, or other legall proofe thereof,
to convi&bholigct; the party or partyes soe offending, by writeing under his or any of their Hands and Seales, and to impose
such Fine or Fines upon all or every such person or persons soe offending and convi&bholigct;ed as aforesaid, as to the said
Treasurer, Comptroller, Surveyour, Clerke of the A&bholigct;s, and the Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers of the Navy for the time being, or any
one or more of them shall in his or their discretion seeme meete; The said Fine or Fines not exceeding double the
value of the Navall Goods soe imbezelled, or carryed away, Which Fine or Fines shall be leavyed by distresse and sale
of the Goods of such Offender, by vertue of the Warrant of such Officer or Officers who shall soe convict the said
Offender directed in manner aforesaid to the person or persons aforesaid, or in case noe sufficient distresse can be
found, as aforesaid, the party or partyes soe offending shall by vertue of the Warrant of such person before whome
such person or persons shall be convicted, be imprisoned in the next Goale for any space of time not exceeding
three Moneths without Baile or Mainprize.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Power to Treasurer, &amp;c. to grant Warrant to enter any Ship in the Day-time, and search for stolen Goods.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Contents of Warrant.; In case of Resistance the Persons deputed may enter and break open Hatches, and take the Goods.; Proviso respe&bholigct;ing undue Seizures.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the said Treasurer, Comptroller, Surveyour Clerke
of the Acts and Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers of the Navy for the time being or any one or more of them, upon Oath of two or
more credible Witnesses (which he and they have hereby power to administer) testifying that his Majestyes Navall
Goods, Stores and Navall Provisions or any part thereof are conveyed into any Shipp or Vessell whatsoever, and
mentioning the name of such Shipp or Vessell being at Anchor, and not ready to saile that Tyde, within any of the
Rodes, Harbours, Creekes or Rivers within his Majestyes Dominions, or any person or persons by their or one of their
Warrant or Warrants, in which Warrant or Warrants the quantity or quality of such Goods shall be specifyed, thereunto
authorized and appointed in the day time in the presence of any knowne Officer or Officers of the Admiralty shall
have full power and authority to goe on board any such Ship or Vessell whatsoever being within any of the places
aforesaid, and in case resistance or refusall be made, upon demand to enter and breake open the Hatches and Cabines
of other places of the said Shipp, and search therein for any such Stores, Ammunition, Provisions or any other.
Navall Goods belonging to his Majestyes Navy, which have beene imbezelled, purloyned and taken away, and the
same to seize, take and carry away to his Majestyes [Storehouse, to be applyed to the Kings use, unlesse the said
Officers and Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers upon heareing the matter shall finde they were unduely seized, and thereupon restore them to
the party claimeing the same, which they are hereby impowered to doe, with liberty hereby reserved to the said Party,
finding himselfe agrieved with the Judgement of the said Officers or Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers to take his remedy for his said Goods
soe seized by course of Law.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Personating Seamen, &amp;c. in the Presence of Commissioners or Paymaster, in order to receive Money due to Seamen, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Punishment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That whatsoever person or persons shall be discovered
fraudulently to personate any Seaman Soldier, Artificer, Workeman or Labourer aforesaid, in the presence of any of his,
Majestyes said Officers or Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers, or in the presence of the Paymaster or Cashier of his Majestyes Navy in order
to his or their receiveing of any money due from his Majestie to the Seaman, Soldier, Artificer, Workeman or Labourer
aforesaid, the person or persons soe offending [may be Imediately arrested and committed to prison, by any of the said
principall Officers or Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers until he or they shall finde Baile to answere the said Offence at the next Assizes, or
Quarter Sessions for the County or place where he or they shall be soe arrested, and being there convi&bholigct;ed of the said
Offence,<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] shall for every such Offence forfeite double the Summe he would by such fraude have gained, to the
Governours of the Chest at Chatham for the use of the poore and maimed Seamen belonging thereto, and shall
moreover suffer Imprisonment by any space of time, not exceeding one whole yeare without Baile, at the discretion of
the Court where he or they shall be soe convi&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Counterfeiting the Hands of the Treasurer, &amp;c. of the Navy;</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">or producing a counterfeit Ticket; committed, or to find Surety.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p10">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That every person or persons who shall counterfeite the
Hands of the Treasurer, Comptroller Surveyour Clerke of the A&bholigct;s, or of the Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers of the Navy, or of any of
them, or the Hand or Hands of the Signeing or Vouching Officers of his Majestyes Navy, Ships, or Yards, or the
Hand or Hands of any one or more of them, to any Bill, Ticket or other Papers, by vertue whereof his Majestyes
Navall Treasure is or may be paid or disposed of, or shall knowingly produce any such counterfeite Ticket, Bill or 
other Paper, every such person or persons soe offending shall or may be lawfully co&bhooov;mitted to prison, by the said
Officers or Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers or any one of them, untill he shall finde Surety at the next generall Assizes, or Quarter Sessions
of the Peace for the County, Towne or place where such Offender shall be soe comitted to prison to be there proceeded
against according to Law.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Power to Treasurer, &amp;c. of the Navy to administer an Oath.</head>
			<para id="p11">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said
Treasurer, Comptroller, Surveyour, Clerke of the. Acts, and the Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers of His Majestyes Navy for the time being
or [for<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] any one or more of them to administer an Oath or Oathes in any case or cases relateing to the receiveing,
keeping, issueing and accompting for any part of his Majestyes Treasure, Vi&bholigct;ualls Stores or Provisions of his Majestyes
Navy, or for the preservation of due Order and Discipline therein in all matters cognizable by the said Officers and
Commissioners.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. A general Liberty given to the said Treasurer, &amp;c. to execute their Power.</head>
			<para id="p12">And it is hereby further declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the said Treasurer, Comptroller,
Surveyour, Clerke of the A&bholigct;s and the C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers of the Navy for the. time being or any one or more of them
may execute all and every the Powers hereby given them or any of them on all and every the Offenders aforesaid
in all places aswell within Liberties as without. Any Law, Statute, Ordinance, Charter or Priviledge to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Only Five Shillings to be paid for the Probate of any Will, or granting Letters of Administration of the Estate of any Person dying in the Pay of His Majesty's Navy, except the Estate be of the Value of &pound; 20 and upwards.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound; 10.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p14">And bee it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That noe Ordinary, Register or other Officer or Officers
belonging to any Ecclesiasticall Court or Court of Orphans, or any Jurisdiction whatsoever within the Kingdome
of England, Ireland or Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede, shall take or receive of the
Executor. or Administrator Executors or Administrators (being the Wife Childe or Children or next of Kindred)
of any Marriner, Souldier, Seaman or before named Artificer or Workeman (except where the deceased shall
leave an Estate of twenty pounds or more) dyeing in the pay of His Majestyes Navy above, the summe of five
shillings for the whole Charges of the Probate of any Will and registring the same, and granting Letters of
Administration, and exhibiting an Inventory, or in doeing any other matter or thing relateing thereunto, Every
Officer performeing his Duty in the said Probate to have his proportion of the said Summe according as the
Judge of the said Court shall dire&bholigct;, And if any such Officer or Officers shall presume to take more then the said
summe of Five shillings for the whole Probate of the said Will, or shall wilfully delay the doeing, granting or
executeing the Premisses, the person or persons soe offending shall forfeite to the party grieved the summe of
ten pounds, to be recovered by, A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Information in any of his Majestyes Courts of
Record or elsewhere, wherein noe Essoyne, Priviledge, Protection or Wager of Law shall be allowed, Any Law,
Statute or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. The A&bholigct; of 22 Car. II. c. 5. confirmed.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That noe clause, sentence or other matter in this A&bholigct; contained
shall repeale, alter, change or be interpreted to make void any of the clauses, matters or things specifyed or contained
in one A&bholigct; of Parliament made in the two and twentyeth yeare of his [now<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Majestyes Raigne entituled An A&bholigct; for
takeing away the Benefit of Clergy from such as steale Cloth from the Racke, and from such as shall steale or
imbezile his Majesties A&bhomov;unic&bhocotil;on and Stores. But that the same A&bholigct; shall remaine in full force and vertue for and
notwithstanding any thing herein contained.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Powers given by this A&bholigct; may be executed by Lord High Admiral.</head>
			<para id="p16">Provided alsoe and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the Powers hereby given to any Officer or
C&bhooov;mis[sion]er of the Navy may be exercised by the Lord High Admirall of England for the time being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. No Double Punishment.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided alsoe and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That noe person or persons who shall be punished by vertue of
this A&bholigct;, shall be punished by force of any other Law for the same Offence.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p18">[Provided lastly and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; shall continue in force dureing the space of seaven
yeares from the first day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and one, and from
thence to the end of the Session of Parlyament then next ensueing, and noe longer.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


