<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47441" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIX. An Act to prevent Fraudes in the buying and selling of Cattell in Smithfeild and elsewhere. [Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 2. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>2 &amp; 3 Ed. VI. c. 15.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">5. 15 Car. II. c. 8. recived.; Except &sect; 4.; 3 &amp; 4 Ed. VI. c. 20</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the preventing of Frauds and Abuses in buying and selling of Cattell, Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
Excellent Majestie and by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons
in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same That one A&bholigct; made in the second and
third yeare of the Raigne of King Edward the Sixth, Entituled, An A&bholigct; touching Vi&bholigct;ualls and Handyeraftsmen,
And one other A&bholigct; made in the fifteenth yeare of his now Majestyes Raigne, Entituled An A&bholigct; to prevent the
buying and selling of live fatt Cattel by Butchers. And every Article Clause and Sentence therein be, and are
hereby revived continued and confirmed. Except one Branch of the said Statute concerning Vi&bholigct;uallers and
Handycraftsmen since repealed by a Statute made in the third and fowerth yeares of the Raigne of the said King
Edward the Sixth, and except all such Clauses matters or things therein or in any of them contained as shall
be altered or repealed by this ensueing A&bholigct;, And that the same shall for ever hereafter be duely holden, observed
and kept in all points for all times to come.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Jobber, Broker, &amp;c. buying Cattle, except Swine or Calves, within Fourscore Miles of London, or a&bholigct;ing as a Jobber contrary to A&bholigct;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That noe Jobber, Salesman or other Broker or Fa&bholigct;or,
who doe or shall commonly buy or sell Cattell for others be allowed or imployed either for buying or selling any
fatt Cattell other then Swine or Calves by or for any Butcher or other person or persons whatsoever within
fowerscore miles of the Cityes of London and Westminster upon paine of the Forfeiture of the value of the said
Cattell soe bought or sold for him or them as aforesaid to be paid by the Owner of such Cattell, And upon
further paine That all and every person and persons takeing upon him or them to use or exercise the said
imployment of a Jobber or Broker, or of a Salesman or Fa&bholigct;or for the buying or selling of Cattell contrary to
this present A&bholigct;, shall forfeite for every such Offence the Value of all such Cattell soe bought or sold or exposed
to sale by him or them as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Butcher within 10 Miles of London, &amp;c. selling to another Butcher;</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any person or persons exerciseing the Trade of a Butcher within the Cityes
of London or Westminster or within ten miles thereof shall buy any fatt Cattell and sell the same againe either
alive or dead to any person or persons exerciseing [or using<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the same Trade, that the Seller thereof shall
forfeite for every such Offence the value of such Cattell soe bought and sold as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Licence to Drover by Justice of Peace within Fourscore Miles of London void.</head>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That noe Drover from and after the Twenty fourth day of June One thousand
six hundred seaventy and one shall be licensed, appointed or assigned by the Justices of Peace in their Quarter
Sessions or otherwise within London and Westminster or fowerscore miles of the said Cityes of London and
Westminster, And that all such Licences shall be null and void. Any former Law or Statute to the contrary in
any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Who may be licensed Drovers.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">To be bound with Sureties; and known to Justices to be of sufficient Estate</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And that from and after the fower and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy and one
it shall not be lawfull for any Justices of [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Peace at their Quarter Sessions or otherwise to license any person
to be a Drover who doth use or exercise [the Profession<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] or Trade of a Grasier or Butcher nor any other person
or persons whatsoever, unlesse the person or persons soe licensed shall become bound to his Majestye his Heires
and Successors with two sufficient Suretyes of the same County, Division or place where such License shall be
obtained by a Recognizance in such Summe as the said Justices shall thinke fitt, not to sell any Cattell by him
or them to be bought within the distance of sixty miles [from the place<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] where he bought the same. And that
the person soe licensed shall be knowne to the said Justices or some of them to be of sufficient Estate and Ability
to answere the Penalty of such Recognizance in case he shall incurr the Forefeiture thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Onus probandi upon the Party offending.</head>
			<para id="p10">And bee it further enacted and declared That where upon any Information or other Prosecution to be brought
or prosecuted for any Offence committed in buying or selling of Cattell contrary to this present A&bholigct; or any
[other<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] A&bholigct; or Statute now in force any question shall arise concerning the intervall or distance of time or place
betweene the buying and selling of such Cattell, the proofe thereof shall be incumbent upon the Offender or party
accused of such Offence; And in case any such Salesman or Factor as aforesaid upon any prosecution against him
for the selling the Cattell of any other person, shall pleade or affirme That the Cattell soe sould were his owne
it shall be incumbent upon him to make proofe of his Property therein, and a lawfull Sale bona fide made to
him of the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Vexatious Information;</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">Butt neverthelesse for preventing of vexatious Informations and Prosecutions by colour of this A&bholigct; Bee it
further enacted That if upon any Information or [other<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Prosecution grounded upon this A&bholigct;, it shall appeare to
the Justices before whome the said, cause shall be brought that any such Information or Prosecution was promoted
onely for vexation and without any reasonable cause, the said Justices shall and are hereby required by vertue
of this A&bholigct; to award to the party soe unjustly accused or prosecuted treble Costs to be occasioned by such
vexatious Prosecution, the same to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, or upon the Case, wherein noe Essoigne
Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Quarter Sessions may determine Offences.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">To make Extra&bholigct;s of one Moiety of Penalties to the King; to award Execution of the other Moiety to the Informer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the Justices of the Peace in every County, Rideing,
Division Citty or Towne Corporate within the Kingdome of England, Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede at their Quarter Sessions shall have full power and authority by vertue of this A&bholigct; to enquire, heare
and determine all and every the defaults and offences in buying or selling of Cattell [committed<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] contrary to this
A&bholigct;, or any other Law or Statute now in force within the County, Rideing, Division, City or Towne Corporate
where any such Offence shall be committed by Inquisition, Presentment, Bill or Information before them exhibited,
and to make Processe thereupon, and upon Convi&bholigct;ion of the [Offenders<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] to make Extracts of the one moyety of
the Forfeitures to be leavyed to the Kings use, as they use to doe of other Fines, Issues, and Amerciaments
growne in Sessions of the Peace, and to award Execution of the other moyety to the Informer or Prosecutor by
Fieri Facias or Capias as the Kings Bench at Westminster may doe and use to doe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. No Certiorari to be allowed.</head>
			<para id="p15">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That noe Certiorari shall be allowed to remove any Information
or other Proceedings in the Quarter Sessions for or concerning any matter or thing in this or the before recited
A&bholigct;s or any of them, but the Justices of the Peace then present shall proceede thereupon, Any such Writt or
Writts of Certiorari notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Fat Cattle bought in Smithfield, not to be there sold again; Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p16">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any fatt Cattell bought in Smithfeild Market from and after the fower and
twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy and one as aforesaid shall afterwards be brought into
the said Market to be sold or exposed to sale alive, the same shall and may be seized by the Bayliffe Toll-taker
or other Officer; appointed to have the Care and Oversight of the said Market to the use of the Maior Aldermen
and Commonalty of the City of London.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Cattle there sold, how to be marked.</head>
			<para id="p17">And for the better discovery thereof Bee it further enacted That the said Bayliffe Toll taker or other Officer
aforesaid shall cause all Cattell which shall be sold to be marked by cutting off two inches or more of the further
Horne of every Oxe, Steere or other Bullocke soe sold to the intent the same may be seized as forfeit by vertue
of this present A&bholigct; as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Customs of Foreign bought and Foreign sold not to prevent Foreigners buying and selling.</head>
			<para id="p18">And forasmuch as the Customes of Forreigne bought and Forreigne sold used within the City of London is
found to be prejudiciall to the Sellers of Cattell in the Markets of Smithfeild Bee it ena&bholigct;ed from and after the
fower and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy and one, it shall and may be lawfull aswell
for Forreigners as Freemen to buy and sell any Cattell in the said Markets without Restraint, Any such Custome
or other Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Calves under Five Weeks old may be killed.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">A Clause in 1 Jac. I. c. 22. repealed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">And it is hereby, further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That one certaine Clause restraining the killing of any Calfe to
sell being under five Weekes old upon paine to forfeite six shillings eight pence for every Calfe soe to be killed
and sold, contained in a certaine A&bholigct; of Parlyament made in the first yeare of the Raigne of King James over
England &amp;c entituled An A&bholigct; concerning Tanners, Curriers, Shoe-makers and other Artificers occupying the
Cutting of Leathers, stand repealed and be utterly null and void.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Limitation of Prosecution.</head>
			<para id="p21">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that neither this A&bholigct;, nor any thing therein
contained shall extend to charge any person or persons for any the Offences above mentioned, unlesse he or they
be prosecuted for the same within six Moneths next after such Offence done or committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p22">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; shall continue in force for three yeares to commence from the twenty fourth
day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy one aforesaid, and from thence to the end of the next Sessions
of Parlyament and noe longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Compounding Offences.</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And if any person or persons discovering any Offence committed against this A&bholigct; shall make any Composition
for the same and not prosecute according to the dire&bholigct;ion of this A&bholigct;, every such person or persons soe
offending shall forfeite twenty pounds for every such Offence to be recovered and disposed in like manner as all
Penaltyes and Forfeitures in this A&bholigct; are dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Offender <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


