<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47442" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XX. An Act for the Releife and Release of poore distressed Prisoners for Debt. [Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C.II; p. 2. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Justice of Peace to require Prisoner to be brought before him.; Cause of Imprisonment to be certified</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Forasmuch as very many persons now detained in Prison are miserably impoverished either by reason of
the late unhappy Times, the sadd and dreadfull Fire, their owne Misfortunes, or otherwise, soe as they are
totally disabled to give any Satisfa&bholigct;ion to their Creditors, and soe become without advantage to any a Charge and
Burthen to the Kingdome, and by Noysomnes (inseperably incident to extreame Poverty) may become the
occasion of Pestilence and contagious Diseases to the great prejudice of the Kingdome Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed
by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall
and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authority of the same That it shall and may
be lawfull to and for any Justice of the Peace of any County City, Towne or Liberty within the Kingdome
of England, Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede by Warrant under his Hand and Seale to
require the Sheriffe, Goaler or Keeper of any Prison within his respe&bholigct;ive Jurisdi&bholigct;ion to bring without delay the
Body of any Person being in Prison for Debt, on the fourteenth day of Aprill One thousand six hundred seaventy
and one, or damages (and petitioning such Justice to be discharged) to some convenient place within the distance
of One mile from the said Prison, and shall certifie the cause and causes of the Imprisonment before the same
Justice; which Warrant every such Sheriffe, Goaler and Keeper is hereby commanded to obey. And in case such
Prisoner comeing before such Justice, shall take an Oath to this effe&bholigct; (viz).</para>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Form of Oath by Prisoner.; Prisoner to be remanded, and Certificate thereof to Prisoner.; 
Notice to be left with Plaintiff to appear at the next Quarter Sessions.; In what case Prisoner to be discharged without Fee or Chamber Rent</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">I A B doe upon my corporall Oath solemnely professe and declare before Almighty God That I have not any
Estate Reall or Personall in Possession, Reversion or Remainder of the value often pounds in the whole, or
sufficient to pay the Debt or Dammages for which I am imprisoned, and that I have not dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly
sold, leased or otherwise conveyed, disposed of, or entrusted all or any part of my Estate, thereby to secure the
same to receive or expe&bholigct; any Proffitt or Advantage thereof, or defraude or deceive any Creditor or Creditors
whatsoever to whome I stand indebted.</para>
		<para id="p5">Then after the takeing of such Oath the said Justice shall remand the Prisoner to Prison and shall give a Certificate
thereof, in writeing under his Hand and Seale to the same Prisoner to be served upon such person or persons
his or her Executors or Administrators, or to be left at the place of the usuall abode of such person or persons
at whose Suite the Prisoner standeth charged and imprisoned, thereby appointing aswell the said person or persons
as the said Prisoner to appeare before the Justices at the next generall Quarter Sessions of the Peace to be holden
for the same County, City, Towne or Liberty, when, if it shall appeare upon Oath (which Oath the said Justices
are impowered to administer) that the said Certificate was soe served or left forty dayes or more before the said
Sessions, and that the said Oath taken by the said Prisoner be not disproved by good Testimony of any credible
person or persons upon Oath, to be administred by the said Justices by vertue of this A&bholigct;, then the said Justices
being satisfyed therein shall dire&bholigct; their Warrant under their Hands and Seales commanding the said Sheriffe,
Goaler or Keeper of the Prison to sett at Liberty, and discharge the said Prisoner if imprisoned for the causes
aforesaid and noe other, without paying any thing for Fee or Chamber-Rent, which Warrant shall be a sufficient
Discharge to the same Sheriffe, Goaler or Keeper of Prison, and noe A&bholigct;ion of Escape, or other A&bholigct;ion shall be
brought against them or any of them for the same in any wise.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. If Creditor willfully insist on Prisoner continuing in Goal, then he is to pay a weekly Sum to Prisoner.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">On Non-payment thereof Prisoner discharged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">Provided alsoe and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That when such prisoner or prisoners for debt
shall have legally taken the said oath in this a&bholigct; proposed to be taken, and shall have duely summoned his or
[her<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Creditor or Creditors, and after the said forty dayes time if the said Creditor or Creditors shall make noe
discovery of his, her or their Estates, nor disprove or dete&bholigct; the said prisoner or prisoners of forsweareing themselves,
that then if such Creditor or Creditors will not be satisfyed therewith (that the said prisoner or prisoners may be
sett at liberty) or will insist to have the said prisoner continued in Goale that then the said Creditor or Creditors
shall at his and their owne proper costs and charges allow and pay weekely a reasonable Maintenance to the said
prisoner or prisoners such as the said Commissioners of the Peace or any three of them in their respe&bholigct;ive Divisions
shall order and appoint not exceeding eighteene pence a weeke, And upon non-payment of the same weekely,
the said prisoner or prisoners shall be sett at liberty according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. On A&bholigct;ion against Sheriff, &amp;c. General Issue may be pleaded.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That upon any A&bholigct;ion of Escape or other Suite brought
or to be brought against any Sheriffe, Goaler or Keeper of any such Prison, or other officer or person for any
thing done in obedience to this A&bholigct;, it shall and may be lawfull [to and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] for such Sheriffe, Goaler or Keeper of
Prison or other Officer or person to pleade the generall Issue, and give this A&bholigct; in Evidence, which shall be a
good and sufficient discharge, and shall save harmlesse every such Sheriffe, Goaler or Keeper or Prison pleading
the same, And if the Plaintiffe in any such A&bholigct;ion shall be nonsuited or Verdict passe against him the Defendant
shall have double Costs to be taxed by the Court where such A&bholigct;ion shall be brought.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Judgments against Prisoner to stand good notwithstanding the Discharge.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">New Execution against Real and Personal Estate, except Wearing Apparel, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That notwithstanding the discharge of
the person of such prisoner as aforesaid upon takeing the Oath aforesaid, all and every Judgement had, and taken
against him or her shall be and stand good and effe&bholigct;uall in the Law to all intents and purposes against the
Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, Goods and Chattells onely of the said prisoner soe discharged as aforesaid.
And it shall and may be lawfull to and for such Creditor of such prisoner or prisoners soe discharged as
aforesaid, his Executors Administrators or Assignes to take out any new Execution against the Lands Tenements,
Hereditaments Goods and Chattells of such prisoner or prisoners, (his or her weareing Apparell, Beding for him
and his or her Family, and Tooles necessary for his or her Trade and Occupation onely excepted) for the
satisfa&bholigct;ion of his or their said Debt in such sort, manner, and forme as he or they might have done, if the
person or persons of such prisoner or prisoners had never beene taken in Execution, Any A&bholigct; Statute or Custome
to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Prisoner taking a false Oath convi&bholigct;ed of Perjury.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">5 Eliz. c. 9.; A new Execution to be awarded against him, upon which he may be remanded</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">Provided alsoe and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if at any time after the takeing of
the said Oath the said prisoner or prisoners shall upon any Indi&bholigct;ment or Indi&bholigct;ments, or by his or their owne
Confession or Verdi&bholigct; of twelve men be convi&bholigct;ed of false swearing in any point or Article contained in the said
Oath, as he or they shall or may be by force of this A&bholigct;, then such prisoner or prisoners soe convi&bholigct;ed as
aforesaid shall suffer all such paines and forfeitures, as [by<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] the Statute of Quinto of Queene Elizabeth are to
be infli&bholigct;ed upon any person convi&bholigct;ed of wilfull Perjury, And alsoe the Court by Processe out of which the
prisoner was imprisoned shall award a Capias ad satisfaciend? infinite or other Processe dire&bholigct;ed to any Sheriffe
or Sheriffes, for the apprehending of the said prisoner and upon returne of Cepi Corpus, shall remand the said
prisoner into the prison whence he or she was dismissed, there to remaine in Execution in such manner and
condition as he or she was before his or her said Enlargement. And then and from thenceforth he or she shall be
adjudged to be in Execution fully, as if he or she had never beene discharged thereof, And the Execution and
Executions upon his or her Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, Goods and Chattells if any such happen to be
after his or her said discharge out of Prison, and before he or she shall be remanded shall stand alsoe good
and effe&bholigct;uall in Law, Any A&bholigct;, Statute or Custome to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Officer delaying to bring Prisoner before a Justice, or to discharge him; Penalty &pound;100.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided, and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That in case any Sheriffs, Goaler or Keeper of Prison
shall refuse or delay to bring or discharge or sett at Liberty any Prisoner according to the order of the Justice or
Justices to be made in manner as aforesaid, every such Sheriffe Goaler or Keeper of Prison shall forfeite and pay
to such Prisoner detained contrary to such Order the summe of one hundred pounds to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion
of Debt in any Court, of Record, and shall be alsoe subje&bholigct; to any Fine and Punishment as the said Justices shall
order or award.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. No Sheriff, &amp;c. to carry any Person to Tavern, Alehouse, &amp;c. without his free Consent;</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">nor demand or receive any greater Sum than by Law ought to be taken for Arrest, waiting, &amp;c.; nor take unreasonable Sum for Lodging, &amp;c.; nor procure such Prisoner to pay for other Wine, &amp;c. than he shall freely call for</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And whereas it is found by common experience That such person or persons that are under Arrests, or committed
to the Custodie of Sheriffes, Bayliffes, Goalers Keepers of Prisons or Goales are much abused and wronged by
extorting of great Fees, Rewards and other Exactions, and putt to great Expences under pretences of favour or
otherwise, whereby they are greatly oppressed and many times ruined in their Estates. For remedy thereof Bee it
ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any Under Sheriffe, Bayliffe Sergeant at Mace or other Officer or
Minister whatsoever shall at any time or times hereafter have in his or their Custody any person or persons by
vertue or colour of any Writt, Processe or other Warrant whatsoever, it shall not be lawfull for such Officer or
Officers to convey or carry, or cause to bee conveyed or carryed the said person or persons to any Taverne Alehouse
or other publique Victualling or Drinking House without the free and voluntary consent of the said person, or
persons soe as to charge such Prisoner with any Summe of Money for any Wine, Beere, Ale, Vi&bholigct;ualls, Tobacco
or any other things whatsoever, but what the said person or persons shall call for, of his, her or their owne accord,
and shall not demand, take or receive, or cause to be demanded taken or received directly or indire&bholigct;ly any other
or greater Summe or Summes then what by Law ought to be taken or demanded for such Arrest, takeing. or
waiteing (untill such person or persons shall have procured an appearance, found Baile, agreed with his or their
Adversaryes, or be sent to the proper Goale belonging to the County, City, Towne or place where such Arrest
or takeing shall be) [nor take and exa&bholigct; any other reward or gratuity for soe keeping the said person or persons
out of the Goale or Prison, then what he, she or they shall or will of his, her or their owne accord voluntarily
and freely give,<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Nor take nor receive any other or greater summe or summes for each nights lodgeing or other
expences then what is reasonable and fitting in such cases, or shall be soe adjudged by the next Justice of the
Peace or at the next Quarter Sessions, and shall not cause or procure the said person or persons to pay for any;
[other<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Wine, Beare, Ale, Victualls, Tobacco or other things then what the said person or persons shall voluntarily,
perticularly and freely call for.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Sheriffs, Gaolers, &amp;c. to permit their Prisoners to send for necessary Food, Bedding, &amp;c. where they please;</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">and not to demand greater Tee for Commitment, &amp;c. than is allowable, until the same be settled as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And that every Under Sheriffe, Goaler, Keeper of Prison or Goale, and every person or persons whatsoever to
whose custody any person or persons shall be delivered or committed by vertue of any Writt of Processe or any
pretence whatsoever shall permitt and suffer the said person or persons at his and their will and pleasure to send
for, and have any Beere, Ale, Victualls and other necessary foode where and from whence they please, as alsoe
to have and use such Beding, Linen and other things as the said person or persons shall thinke fitt, without any
purloyning, detaineing or paying for the same or any part thereof, nor shall demand, take or receive of the said
person or persons any other or greater Fee or Fees whatsoever for his [her<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] or their commitment, release or discharge,
or for his, her or their Chamber-rent then what is allowable by Law, untill the same shall be setled by three Justices
of the Peace, whereof one to be of the Quoru of each particular County, City and Towne Corporate in their
severall Precin&bholigct;s, and for the City of London and Countyes of Midlesex and Surrey the two Lord Cheife Justices
of the Kings Bench and Common Pleas and the Lord Cheife Baron or any two of them, and the Justices of the
Peace of the same in their severall Jurisdictions.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Inquiry to be made by Lord Chief Justices, &amp;c. into all charitable Uses given for the Benefit of poor Prisoners.</head>
			<para id="p19">And likewise that the said Lord Cheife Justices, Lord Cheife Baron and Justices of the Peace in their severall
Jurisdi&bholigct;ions and all Commissioners for charitable Uses doe use their best endeavours and diligence to examine and
finde out the severall Legacies, Gifts and Bequests bestowed and given for the benefitt and advantage of the poore
Prisoners for Debt in the severall Goales and Prisons in this Kingdome, and to send for any Deeds, Wills,
Writeings and Bookes of Accounts whatsoever and any person or persons concerned therein, and to examine them
upon Oath to make true discovery thereof (which they have full power and authority hereby to doe) and the
same soe found out and ascertained, to order and setle in some manner and way that the Prisoners hereafter may
not be defrauded, but receive the full benefitt thereof according to the true intent of the Donors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Accounts of such Gifts, Rates of Fees, and Government of Prisons to be signed, &amp;c. by the Lord</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Chief Justices, &amp;c. and hung up in every Gaol, fairly written; and registered by Clerk of the Peace</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And that these Accounts of the severall Legacies, Gifts and Bequests given and bestowed upon the severall
Prisoners for Debt within this Kingdome, and the severall Rates of Fees and the future Government of Prisons
be signed and confirmed by the Lord, Cheife Justices and Lord Cheife Baron or any two of them for the time
being, and the Justices of the Peace in London, Midlesex, and Surrey, and by the Judges for the severall Circuits
and Justices of the Peace for the time being in their severall Precin&bholigct;s, and fairely written, and hung up in
a Table in every Goale and Prison before the first day of November One thousand six, hundred seaventy and
one, and likewise be registred by each and every Clerke of the Peace within his or their particular Jurisdiction,
And after such Establishment noe other greater Fee or Fees then shall be soe established shall be demanded or
received.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Recital that Felons and Prisoners for Debt are lodged together.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Sheriff, Gaoler, &amp;c. so lodging Prisoners; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And whereas it is become the common practice of [the<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Goalers and Keepers of Newgate, the Gatehouse at
Westminster and sundry other Goales and Prisons to lodge together in one Roome, or Chamber and Bed Prisoners
for Debt and Felons, whereby many times honest Gentlemen, Tradesmen and others Prisoners for Debt are disturbed,
and hindred in the night time from their naturall rest by reason of their Fetters and Irons, and otherwise much
offended and troubled by their lewd and prophane language and discourses, with most horrid curseing and swearing
(much accustomed to such persons) Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That it shall not be lawfull hereafter
for any Sheriffe, Goaler or Keeper of Goale or Prison to putt, keepe or lodge Prisoners for Debt and Felons
together in one Roome or Chamber, but that they shall be putt, kepte and lodged seperate and apart one from
another in distinct Roomes upon paine that he, she or they which, shall offend against this A&bholigct;, or the true intent
and meaning thereof or any part thereof shall forfeite and lose his or her Office, Place or Imployment, and shall
forfeite treble dammages to the party grieved to be recovered by vertue of this A&bholigct;. Any Law, Statute, Usage or
Custome to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Offender <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">their <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


