<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47443" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXI. An Act for takeing the Accompts of Sixty thousand pounds and other Moneys given to the loyall and indigent
Officers. [Rot. Part. 22 &amp; 23. C. II. p. 2. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 14 (13 &amp; 14) C. II. c. 8.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that Commissioners were to assess Offices of the Value herein mentioned; and that Complaint had been made that no Account had been given of certain Monies received. Commissioners to take the Accounts of Treasurers, &amp;c. Power to administer Oaths</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament made in the fowerteenth yeare of the Raigne of our most
grations Soveraigne Lord King Charles the Second Entituled An A&bholigct; for distribution of Threescore thousand
pounds amongst the truely loyall and indigent Commission Officers and for assessing of Offices and distributing
the Moneys thereby raised for their further Supply. It was enacted That the summe of Threescore thousand
pounds should with the most convenient speede be distributed amongst such truely loyall and indigent Officers,
who have had reall Command of Souldiers according to their severall Commissions, and who had never deserted
his Majestyes nor his blessed Fathers Service, dureing the late times of Rebellion and Usurpation, and who have
not a sufficient Livelyhood of their owne, nor have since his Majestyes Returne obtained any Reward Office or
Imployment sufficient for a Livelyhood by such wayes, meanes and proportions as by the said A&bholigct; is appointed;
And by the said A&bholigct; the said Threescore thousand pounds was to be paid to such Treasurer as should be nominated
and appointed according to the true meaneing of the said A&bholigct; And whereas the said Commissioners by the said
A&bholigct; were to asesse all and every Office and Offices within the Realme of England, Principality of Wales and
Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede of the yearely value of five pounds or more, and forasmuch as severall persons
were appointed Treasurers, Collectors, and Receivers for the receipt of the said Threescore thousand pounds, and
for the receipt of the summes of money to be raised by the Assessment of Offices. And forasmuch as severall
summes of money have beene paid to the said Treasurers, Colle&bholigct;ors and Receivers in pursuance of the said A&bholigct;s,
whereof complaint hath beene made that some of them have given noe Accompt, Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed, and
it is ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authority of the same That
the persons hereafter to be named by his Majestie under his Great Seale or any three or more of them shall be
Commissioners for the takeing of the respe&bholigct;ive Accompts of the said Treasurers, Colle&bholigct;ors and Receivers, upon
the respe&bholigct;ive Oathes of the said Treasurers, Colle&bholigct;ors and Receivers, and alsoe to examine Witnesses and to take
Depositions upon Oath concerning the chargeing or dischargeing of the said Treasurers, Colle&bholigct;ors or Receivers,
which Oathes the said Commissioners or any three or more of them are hereby authorized to administer, and by
all other wayes and meanes to examine what moneys have beene bona fide received or paid in pursuance of the
former A&bholigct; for distribution of Threescore thousand pounds by any person or persons whatsoever.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Power to summon Treasurers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Proviso as to Distance</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the said C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers or any three or more of them
may from time to time issue their Warrants under their Hands and Seales, to the said Treasurers, Colle&bholigct;ors and
Receivers respe&bholigct;ively, commanding thereby the said Treasurers, Colle&bholigct;ors and Receivers, to appeare before them
or any three or more of them at such time and place as by the said Warrants shall be appointed, soe as the
place in which the said Treasurers, Colle&bholigct;ors, and Receivers be appointed to appeare, be within three miles of
the Cityes of London and Westminster.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. A Duplicate of the Accounts to be signed and transmitted by Commissioners into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Quietus est or Process thereupon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the said Com&bhooov;is[sion]ers soe as aforesaid to be appointed
by his Majestie or any three or more of them shall upon the takeing the Accompts of the said Treasurers, Receivers
and Colle&bholigct;ors make and transmitt into his Majestyes Court of Exchequer a Duplicate of the same Accompt faire
written in Parchment and signed by the said C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers or any three or more of them, Which said Accompt
soe signed and transmitted, is by the authority aforesaid declared and adjudged to be, and shall to all intents
and purposes be received and taken by all and every the Officers and Ministers of his Majestyes said Court of
Exchequer as an Accompt declared before the Lord Treasurer Chauncellor or Barons of the said Exchequer
according to the usuall course of the said Court, and shall have the same effe&bholigct; and be accordingly proceeded upon
either for passing a Quietus est to the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Accomptants, or for issueing of Processe where the
case requires, All which the said Court of Exchequer and the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Officers and Ministers thereof,
to whome it shall or may appertaine, are hereby authorized and required to performe and doe accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Monies levied to be issued and paid without Fee.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">How and to whom such Monies to be distributed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That after the said summe and summes of money shall
be leavyed and paid into his Majestyes Court of Exchequer as aforesaid, That then the said summe or summes
of money or soe much thereof as shall be leavyed and paid as aforesaid shall be issued forth and paid without
any Fee unto such Treasurer as his Majestie shall appoint, or unto his Deputy, to be appointed under his hand
and seale, for whome he is to be responsable, to which Treasurer shall be from time to time paid all money due,
ariseing or leavyed by vertue of the said first recited A&bholigct;, or this present A&bholigct;, which said C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers or any three or
more of them shall by their Warrants under Hand and Seale to the said Treasurer or his Deputy as aforesaid
cause to be paid out the said moneys to such truely, loyall, indigent Commission Officers as aforesaid, as have not
already received their full Share, haveing relation [and respe&bholigct;<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to the methods and dire&bholigct;ions of the said former
A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s and proceedings thereupon; and alsoe to the methods already proceeded in by Lots, as the Countyes
stand in the rule of Lotts, had and made by the former Commissioners for this purpose sitting in the Starr chamber,
And therefore the said former Treasurers, Receivers and Colle&bholigct;ors, as alsoe the former Registers and Clerks and
every of them for distribution of the said threescore thousand pounds are hereby required to deliver to the said
C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers all such Bookes and Papers, relateing to this affaire, as came to their or any of their hands or custodie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Commissioners Warrant a sufficient Discharge to Treasurer.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Treasurer to obey Commissiouers Warrant, and to be accountable to Commissioners.; Accounts certified proceeded upon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And further bee it ena&bholigct;ed That the said Warrants of the said C&bhooov;mis?ers and the Acquittances of the respe&bholigct;ive
C&bhooov;mission officers thereupon shall be vouchers and sufficient [dischargers<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to the said Treasurer for such moneys
as he shall accordingly pay, [And such Treasurer shall give obedience to every such Warrant and make ready
payment accordingly if any such moneys remaine in his hand, and he shall pay noe such money without such
Warrant,<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] and for all such money as he shall soe receive, and pay as aforesaid he is hereby made accomptable
to the said C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers, and his Accompts soe taken by them or the major part of them shall be certified under
their hands, and seales unto the Exchequer, which Accompts soe certifyed by the said C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers or any three or
more of them is hereby declared and adjudged, and shall be taken by all the Officers and Ministers of the
said Exchequer as an Accompt declared in manner as is before in this A&bholigct; expressed, and shall accordingly be
proceeded upon.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Any Certificate counterfeit or unduly granted to postpone the Payment till cleared.</head>
			<para id="p11">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That if it shall appeare upon Oath before the said C&bhooov;mis?ers or any three or more of
them that any Certificate is false or counterfeite or corruptly or not duely procured or granted according to the
former A&bholigct;s made for that purpose That then it shall and may be lawfull for such C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers to postpone the
payment of the moneys due upon such Certificate untill the party concerned therein shall upon Oath prove the
contrary or cleare himselfe or his said Certificate from all such Obje&bholigct;ions. All which Oathes aforesaid the said
C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers are hereby impowered to administer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Commissioners to levy all Monies formerly assessed and not paid, and to assess such Offices as had not been assessed according to 14 (13 &amp; 14) C. II. c. 8.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">To administer Oath as to Value of Offices</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the said C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers or any three or more of them are
hereby authorized and required by Warrant as aforesaid to leavy or cause to be leavyed according to the powers
of the said A&bholigct;s or any of them all such moneys formerly assessed as shall appeare to them not to have beene
accordingly paid, and to assesse all and every Officer and Officers for their respe&bholigct;ive Offices within the Realme
of England, Principality of Wales, and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede as hath not beene formerly assessed
accordingly to the true intent of the said first mentioned A&bholigct;, intituled, An A&bholigct; for the distribution of Threescore
thousand pounds amongst the truely loyall and indigent Commission officers and for assessing of Offices and,
distributeing the moneys thereby raised for their future Supply. And they are hereby impowered and dire&bholigct;ed
by Oath (other then of the Officer himselfe) if they finde cause, and by all other lawfull meanes to finde out
with convenient speede the full value of all Offices aforesaid, to the intent all Officer and Officers may be truely
assessed for their respe&bholigct;ive Offices according to the rates and proportions hereafter mentioned; that is to say To
rate every Officer and Officers as hath not already beene assessed, and to rate and assesse every of them
soe much as he or they ought to have beene assessed and paid according to the true intent and meaning of
the said A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Commissioners to appoint Colle&bholigct;ors and a Register.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Duty of Register.; Power to Colle&bholigct;ors to levy</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">And the said C&bhooov;mis?ers or any three or more of them are hereby enabled to nominate such Colle&bholigct;or or
Collectors for the Countyes, Cityes and Corporations within, the Kingdome of England, Principality of Wales and
Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede for the colle&bholigct;ing receiving and gathering every s&bhouov;me and summes of money
imposed (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) or taxed upon every Officer and Officers as aforesaid for their respe&bholigct;ive Offices, and alsoe to appoint
a Register, which said Register is hereby appointed to enter all Rates and Assesments soe made by the said
C&bhooov;mis?ers or any three or more of them into a Booke fairely. writt, and to deliver Duplicates, to the said Colle&bholigct;or
and Colle&bholigct;ors under the hands and seales of the said C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers or any three or more of them, And the said
Colle&bholigct;ors and every of them are hereby impowered to demand and leavy respe&bholigct;ively according to the powers of
the said A&bholigct; the severall summes of money therein contained in the said Duplicates.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Non-payment of Tax within Ten Days after Notice.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That if any such Officer shall not pay his Taxe or Proportion soe rated or assessed,
sometime within ten dayes after notice thereof in writeing left at his Office, or at the usuall place of his
abode, and after demand thereof made at such place by some Colle&bholigct;or, That then it shall and may be lawfull
for such Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors to distraine upon any of the Goods and Chattells of such Officer, and the same
to sell, and restore the Overplus, dedu&bholigct;ing his owne reasonable Charges in takeing the Distresse.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Colle&bholigct;ors may use the Powers given by 16 &amp; 17 C.II. c. 1.</head>
			<para id="p18">And bee it further enacted That the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors herein appointed for the better leavying and
receiveing the severall Rates and Taxes that are, or shall be imposed according to this A&bholigct;, are hereby impowered
to make use of all other Powers and Authorities as are given to any Colle&bholigct;or or Sub colle&bholigct;ors by the late A&bholigct;,
entituled,. An A&bholigct; for granting a Royall Ayde unto the Kings Majestie of Twenty fower hundred threescore and
seaventeene thousand and five hundred pounds to be raised, levyed and paid in the space of three yeares.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Proviso for Payments made by Sir John Bennct, although paid upon false Certificates.</head>
			<para id="p19">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That all payments of Money made by
Sir. John Bennet Knight, of the Honourable Order of the Bath, late Treasurer or his Deputy according, to the
dire&bholigct;ion of the said A&bholigct;, which shall appeare upon Oath before the said Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers to be really paid, shall be
allowed to the said Treasurer, notwithstanding the said payments or any of them were made upon false and
surreptitious Certificates or Letters, of Attourney,. unlesse upon examination there shall appeare any privity thereof,
deceit or collusion, in the said Treasurer or his Deputy, and the said Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers are hereby impowered to administer
all or any the Oathes aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Orders signed by former Commissioners confirmed.</head>
			<para id="p20">[Provided alsoe and bee it enacted That all Warrants and Orders signed by the former Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers for the
payment, of Officers according to the rules and dire&bholigct;ions of the former A&bholigct;s being transferred and made over to
the present Treasurer, shall be ratifyed, confirmed and allowed by the Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers to be appointed as aforesaid, and
payments made thereupon accordingly; Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for Receivers who have their Quietus.</head>
			<para id="p21">Provided alwayes, and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all such Receivers as have accompted in the Exchequer
for any summe or summers of money that were received and paid by vertue of the said A&bholigct; or any other A&bholigct;,
and have their Quietus est shall not be accomptable for the said summe or summes already accounted for by this
A&bholigct;; Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">discharges <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">or to be imposed <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


