<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47440" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVIII. An Act for the better regulateing of Workehouses for setting the Poore on Worke.[Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 2. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>14 (13 &amp; 14) C. II. c. 12.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">To whom the Money, when colle&bholigct;ed, to be paid.; Officers of Corporation to account Quarterly.; No further Monies raised till Account given</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the more effe&bholigct;uall putting in Execution of an A&bholigct; of Parlyament made in the fowerteenth yeare of your.
Majestyes Raigne entituled, An A&bholigct; for the better Releife of the Poore of this Kingdome. And to the end
that the Poore of the severall Parishes within the City and Liberties of Westminster and other Parishes within the
County of Midlesex mentioned within the weekely Bill of Mortality, may for the future be duely provided for
according to the intent and meaneing of the intent said A&bholigct;, May it please your most excellent Majesty that it may be
ena&bholigct;ed, and bee it enacted by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same
[That all moneys assessed or ordered to be assessed upon any person in pursuance of the said A&bholigct; since the first
day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and five shall be colle&bholigct;ed and paid in to
the Treasurers of the respe&bholigct;ive Corporations by or before the nine and twentyeth day of September in the yeare
of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and one. And all moneys already colle&bholigct;ed by authority of
the said A&bholigct; shall be paid into the said Treasurers by or before the first day of June in the yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred seaventy &amp; one. And<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] that the Officers of the said Corporations ere&bholigct;ed and constituted
in pursuance of the said A&bholigct; and their Treasurers shall make and give Quarterly Accompts to the Justices of
Peace, who are hereby required to demand and call for the said Accompts, and are not to raise any more moneys
upon any new Certificates whatsoever, untill there be a just Accompt given to, and allowed by the Justices of
the Peace aforesaid according to the true intent and meaning of the said former and this present A&bholigct;.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Accounts made according to the said A&bholigct; confirmed.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Moniesunaccounted for to be accounted for as by the said A&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And whereas some Accompts have beene made by the former Governours of part of the moneys raised by
the A&bholigct; aforesaid, and some of them stand engaged for payment of certaine Summes of money, which were
borrowed and expended in pursuance of the said former A&bholigct;, Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all such Accompts
which shall appeare to the said Justices (not haveing beene Governours of the said Corporations) to have beene
made according to the A&bholigct; aforesaid shall be and are hereby ratifyed and confirmed, and that such moneys as
have not beene accompted for as aforesaid shall be accompted for according as in the said A&bholigct; is provided.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Debts owing by Corporations to be paid by Treasurers.</head>
			<para id="p5">And that all moneys lent, and all such Debts, as any of them, or any of the Members of the said
Corporations aforesaid stand engaged for, and have beene contra&bholigct;ed for the Uses expressed in the said A&bholigct;, shall
upon order from the Justices aforesaid (ascertaining the same) be discharged and satisfyed by the respe&bholigct;ive
Treasurer or Treasurers for the time being, and shall from time to time be allowed in their respe&bholigct;ive accompts.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The Tax not to exceed One-fourth of the Poors Rate.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">When to be paid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That noe Summe or Summes of money to be leavyed
upon the Inhabitants of any of the said respe&bholigct;ive Parishes according to the said former or this present A&bholigct; shall
in any one yeare exceede one fowerth part of the Assesment to the Poore for that yeare, laid on any of the
Parishes and Liberties aforesaid, Which said Summe shall be paid by the respe&bholigct;ive Inhabitants of the said Parishes
at two severall payments to the Treasurer or Treasurers for the said Corporations (that is to say) at the Feast
of Saint Michael the Arch-Angell, and the Annunciation of the blessed Virgin Mary, or within fowerteene dayes
after either of the said Feasts as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Assessments after 29th Sept. 1675.</head>
			<para id="p8">And bee it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed That noe Assesment shall be laid or made on any the Parishes aforesaid after the nine
and twentyeth day of September which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and
five, Any thing in the said former or this present A&bholigct; to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Proviso for Powers of former A&bholigct; as to London, and St. Margarets Westminster.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alwayes That noe thing herein contained shall in any sorte extend to the superseding, altering or
vacating any of the Powers given by the said former A&bholigct; to the Lord Maior and Governours for the Corporation
within the City of London or the Parish of Saint Margarets Westminster but that the same and all the other Clauses
and Articles in the said former A&bholigct; shall to all intents and purposes be fully executed and observed within the
City of London, and Parish of Saint Margarets Westminster as if this A&bholigct; had not beene made. Any thing herein
contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


