<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47457" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1672</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for continuing a former A&bholigct; concerning Coynage. [Rot. Parl. 25 C. II. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of the Advantages of 18 (18 &#x0026; 19) C. II. c. 5.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The said A&bholigct; continued for Seven Years, &#x0026;c.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Forasmuch as great advantage hath accrewed to this Kingdome by one A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament
passed in the eighteenth yeare of your Majestyes Raigne entituled An A&bholigct; for Encouragement of Coynage.
for that very great quantities of Gold and Silver have beene brought into this Realme, and converted into the
current Coynes thereof by reason of the encouragement given thereto by the said A&bholigct;; And whereas the said
A&bholigct; was to continue untill the twentyeth of December in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
seaventy and one, and untill the end of the first Session of Parlyment then next following and noe longer, soe
as that unlesse the said A&bholigct; be now renewed, the encouragement given thereby to Coynage will cease, and this
Kingdome be deprived for the future of soe great a good as it hath thereby for these yeares last past enjoyed;
Wee therefore your Majestyes Dutyfull and Loyall Subje&bholigct;s, doe humbly pray that it may be enacted and bee it
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and Commons now be in Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That the said A&bholigct; shall
continue and be in force for the space of seaven yeares to commence from and after the determination of this present
Session of this Parlyament, and untill the end of the first Session of Parlyament then next following and noe longer.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Recital of 18 (18 &#x0026; 19) C. II. c.5. ? 6. and of the Inconvenience thereof.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Regulation as to what Officers the Monies levied under this A&bholigct; are to be paid.; Certificate from Comptroller General of the Customs.; Quietus.; Further like Regulations where the Customs farmed.; Certificate.; Quietus.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes that whereas by the said A&bholigct; it is ena&bholigct;ed That the moneys leavyed, colle&bholigct;ed and paid by
vertue thereof should be leavyed, colle&bholigct;ed and paid at the respe&bholigct;ive Custome-houses to the Colle&bholigct;ors and other
Officers of the Customes for the time being, and be by them respe&bholigct;ively paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer,
whereby each of the said Colle&bholigct;ors are oblidged to passe a distin&bholigct; accompt in the Exchequer for the moneyes
received by them by vertue of the said A&bholigct;s, although the summes received by many of them are very small
and inconsiderable, and yet noe allowance to bee made unto them for the doeing thereof; For the avoiding of
this unnecessary trouble and inconvenience to the said Colle&bholigct;ors bee it enacted and it is hereby enacted by the
authoritie aforesaid That during such time as the Customes shall be in Colle&bholigct;ion under the mannagement of
Commissioners, the moneys colle&bholigct;ed, leavyed and paid by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be levyed, colle&bholigct;ed and paid
to such Officers, as doe or shall from time to time colle&bholigct; and receive the Customes in the respe&bholigct;ive Ports upon
the Commodities charged by this A&bholigct;, and shall be by them respe&bholigct;ively answered and paid to the Receiver
Generall of the Customes now and for the time being, whose acquittance shall be to them and every of them a
sufficient discharge for the moneys by them paid to him and a Certificate by them obtained, yearely or oftner
from the Comptroller Generall of the Accompts of the customes now and for the time being with the allowance
of the Commissioners of the Customes or any three or more of them, of their haveing soe paid all the moneys
by them received shall be to them and every of them a Quietus and free them from all other accompts or trouble
for the same. And in case the Customes shall be farmed that the moneys leavyed.; colle&bholigct;ed and paid by vertue
of this A&bholigct; dureing such time shall be colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid in the respe&bholigct;ive Ports to such [person.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] as shall
be appointed [to<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] the Lord Treasurer or Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being to leavy, colle&bholigct; and
receive the same and be by them paid to such person as shall be in like manner appointed to receive the said
moneys from them, whose acquittance shall be to them and every of them a sufficient discharge for the moneys
by them paid to him, and a certificate by them obtained yearely or oftner from such person or persons as shall
be in like manner appointed to give such Certificate of their haveing soe paid all the moneys by them received
shall be to them and every of them a Quietus, and free them from all other accompts or trouble for the said
moneys, Any thing in the said A&bholigct; for the encouragement of Coynage, or any other Law, Statute or Usage to
the contrary, in, any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Duties to be paid at the Importation of the Commodities.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the moneys to be leavyed, colle&bholigct;ed and paid by
vertue of this A&bholigct;, shall be leavyed colle&bholigct;ed and paid at the Importation of the Commodities charged thereby,
and that over and above all other Dutyes and Summes of Moneys charged and payable upon the same and under
the same Penalties and Forfeitures as for non payment of, or defrauding his Majestie of his Customes upon the
said Commodities.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Money to be kept distinct, and paid monthly in London, and quarterly in the Out Ports to Receiver General.;</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">to whom to be paid where no. Receiver General.; Duty of Receiver General, or such other Person.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the moneys colle&bholigct;ed in the respe&bholigct;ive Ports
by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be by the respe&bholigct;ive Officers who shall colle&bholigct; the same distinguished and kept apart
from all other moneys by them colle&bholigct;ed upon the same Co&bhooov;odities, or upon any other Commodity or Merchandize
whatsoever, and shall be by them respe&bholigct;ively soe answered and paid monethly at least from the Officers of the
Port of London, and quarterly at (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) least from the Officers of the Outports to the Receiver-Generall of the Customes
for the time being; And when there shall be noe such Receiver Generall to such other person as shall be appointed
as aforesaid to receive the same from them; and that such Receiver Generall or other person who shall receive
the said moneys from the Officers of the respe&bholigct;ive Ports shall alsoe keepe the same distin&bholigct; from all other
moneys whatsoever, and soe pay the same once in every moneth at least into the Receipt of the Exchequer,
there alsoe to be kept distin&bholigct; and apart from all other moneys ariseing by the Customes, or by any otherway
or Revenue whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Salaries to Officers.</head>
			<para id="p9">And lastly Bee it ena&bholigct;ed-by the authoritie aforesaid That for the encouragement of the respe&bholigct;ive Officers before
mentioned it shall bee lawfull for the Lord Treasurer, or Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being, to
allow unto them out of the moneys ariseing by this A&bholigct; for the Services above-mentioned such Sallaries and
Allowances as to them shall seeme meete and reasonable; soe as that the said Sallaries and Allowances doe not
exceede in the whole the summe of twelve pence in the pound of the moneys colle&bholigct;ed by this A&bholigct;.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Persons <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">by <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


