<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47450" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1672</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An A&bholigct; for raising the Summe of Twelve
hundred thirty eight thousand seaven hundred, and fifty Pounds for supply of his Majesties extraordinary
occasions. [Rot. Parl. 25 C. II. nu. I.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Grant of &pound;1,238,750.; to be raised within 18 Months, at the times, in manner, and on, the Counties, &amp;c. herein mentioned.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee Your Majestyes most dutyfull and loyall Subje&bholigct;s the C&bhooov;mons assembled in Parliament acknowledging
with all humility and thankfulnes your Majesties abundant care for our preservation and being deepely
sensible of that extraordinary charge and expence with which your Majesties present occasions are to be supported
have chearfully and unanimously given and granted, and doe hereby give and grant unto your Most Excellent
Majestie, the summe of Twelve hundred thirty eight thousand seaven hundred and fifty pounds, to be raised and
leavyed in manner following. And doe humbly beseech your Majestie That it may be ena&bholigct;ed and bee it ena&bholigct;ed
by the Kings Most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lord Spirituall and Temporall
and of the C&bhooov;mons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That the summe of
twelve hundred thirty eight thousand seaven hundred and fifty pounds shall be raised leavyed and paid unto your
Majestie within the space of eighteene moneths in manner following that is to say the summe of threescore and
eight thousand eight hundred and nineteene pounds and nine shillings by the moneth for eighteene moneths
begining from the fourth day of February One thousand six hundred seaventy and two shall bee assessed taxed
colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid by six quarterly payments in the severall Counties Cittyes Burroughs Townes and
Places within England and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede according to the severall rates
and proportions and in such manner as is hereafter expressed, that is to say For every moneth of the said
eighteene moneths.</para>
		<para id="p3">For the County of Bedford the summe of Eight hundred ninety six pounds seaventeene shillings and
nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p4">For the County of Berks the summe of One thousand one hundred thirty two pounds six shillings and
seaven pence.</para>
		<para id="p5">For the County of Bucks the summe of One thousand three hundred and fifteene pounds six shillings and
five pence.</para>
		<para id="p6">The County of Cambridge, the summe of One thousand and twenty pounds</para>
		<para id="p7">The Isle of Ely the summe of Three hundred forty nine pounds seaventeene shillings and eleaven pence.</para>
		<para id="p8">The County of Chester with the Citty and County of the Citty. of Chester the s&bhouov;me of eight hundred and
one pounds five, shillings and six pence.</para>
		<para id="p9">The County of Cornwall the summe of One thousand five hundred and forty pounds eighteene shillings and
three pence.</para>
		<para id="p10">The County of Cumberland the s&bhouov;me of One hundred sixty eight pounds six shillings and one penny.</para>
		<para id="p11">The County of Derby the summe of Eight hundred sixty two pounds eight shillings and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p12">The County of Devon the summe of Three thousand two hundred twenty nine pounds nineteene shillings and
two pence.</para>
		<para id="p13">The Citty and County of the Citty of Exon the su[m]me of One hundred and sixteene pounds seaven shillings and
fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p14">The County of Dorsett the summe of' One thousand three hundred forty fower pounds ten shillings and
five pence.</para>
		<para id="p15">The Towne and County of Poole the su[m]me of-ten pounds nineteene shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p16">The County of Durham the summe of three hundred twenty three pounds sixteene shillings and nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p17">The County of Yorke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke and Towne and County of Kingston
upon Hull the summe of Three thousand fower hundred sixty nine pounds five shillings and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p18">The County of Essex the summe of Three thousand ninety eight pounds eight shillings and ten pence.</para>
		<para id="p19">The County of Gloucester the summe of One thousand eight hundred and eight pounds ten shillings and
three pence.</para>
		<para id="p20">The Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester the summe of thirty nine pounds and eight shillings.</para>
		<para id="p21">The County of Hereford the summe of One thousand one hundred thirty one pounds thirteene shillings and
fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p22">The County of Hereford the summe of One thousand three hundred forty five pounds sixteene shillings [and<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
three pence.</para>
		<para id="p23">The County of Huntington the summe of six hundred thirty three pounds fowerteene shillings and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p24">The County of Kent with the Citty and County of the Citty of Canterbury the summe of three thousand three
hundred twenty six pounds eighteene shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p25">The County of Lancaster the summe of One thousand and six pounds thirteene shillings and six pence.</para>
		<para id="p26">The County of Leicester the summe of One thousand and eighty fower pounds fowerteene shillings and three
pence.</para>
		<para id="p27">The County of Lincolne with the Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne the summe of Two thousand five
hundred seventy five pounds two shillings.</para>
		<para id="p28">The Citty of London with the Liberty of Saint Martines le Grand the summe of Five thousand ninety one pounds
eleaven shillings and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p29">The County of Midlesex with the Citty and Liberty of Westminster the summe of two thousand two hundred
and forty pounds ten shillings.</para>
		<para id="p30">The County of Monmouth the summe of Three hundred and ninety pounds.</para>
		<para id="p31">The County of Northampton the summe of One thousand fower hundred and thirteene pounds eighteene
shillings and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p32">The County of Nottingham with the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham the summe of eight
hundred seaventy three pounds and eight shillings.</para>
		<para id="p33">The County of Norffolke the summe of three thousand three hundred seaventy pounds and twelve shillings.</para>
		<para id="p34">The Citty and County of the Citty of Norwich the summe of One hundred and eighty pounds.</para>
		<para id="p35">The County of Northumberland with the Townes of Newcastle and Berwicke upon Tweede the summe of Three
hundred seaventy two pounds fifteene shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p36">The County of Oxon the summe of Eleaven hundred thirty five pounds ten shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p37">The County of Rutland the summe of Two hundred and forty pounds eight shillings and eleaven pence.</para>
		<para id="p38">The County of Salop the summe of One thousand two hundred and three pounds fowerteene shillings and
two pence.</para>
		<para id="p39">The County of Stafford the summe of Eight hundred fifty two pounds eleaven shillings and eight, pence.</para>
		<para id="p40">The Citty and County of the Citty of Litchfeild the summe of thirteene pounds.</para>
		<para id="p41">The County of Somersett the summe of Two thousand seaven hundred seaventy one pounds ten shillings and
eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p42">The Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll the summe of One hundred ninety nine pounds eight shillings
and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p43">The County of Southampton with the Towne and County of Southampton and the Isle of Weight, the summe
of Two thousand one hundred eighty nine pounds eight shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p44">The County of Suffolke the summe of Three thousand two hundred ninety eight pounds ten shillings and
eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p45">The County of Surrey with the Burrough of Southwarke the summe of One thousand five hundred ninety
seaven pounds and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p46">The County of Sussex the summe of One thousand eight hundred twenty one pounds seaven shillings and
nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p47">The County of Warwicke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry the summe of One thousand
one hundred ninety two pounds eight shillings and nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p48">The County of Worcester the summe of One thousand fifty three pounds and nineteene shillings.</para>
		<para id="p49">The Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester the summe of fifty five pounds nine shillings, and six pence.</para>
		<para id="p50">The County of Wilts the summe of One thousand nine hundred sixty six pounds seaventeene shillings and seaven
pence.</para>
		<para id="p51">The County of Westmerland the summe of One hundred and sixteene pounds.</para>
		<para id="p52">The Isle of Anglesey the summe of One hundred twenty five pounds thirteene shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p53">The County of Brecknocke the summe of Two hundred eighty two pounds ten shillings and five pence
halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p54">The County of Cardigan the summe of One hundred and five pounds; fifteene shillings and nine pence halfe
penny.</para>
		<para id="p55">The County of Carmarthan the summe of Two hundred seaventy two pounds six shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p56">The County of Carnarvan the summe of One hundred forty six pounds twelve shillings and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p57">The County of Denbigh the. summe of Two hundred twenty, three, pounds ten shillings and seaven-pence.</para>
		<para id="p58">The County of Flint the summe of One hundred and eighteene pounds seaventeene shillings and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p59">The County of Glamorgan the summe of Three hundred seaventy eight pounds seaventeene shillings and ten
pence.</para>
		<para id="p60">The County of Merioneth the summe of One hundred pounds sixteene shillings and one penny.</para>
		<para id="p61">The County of Mountgomery the summe of Two hundred seaventy six pounds twelve shillings and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p62">The County of Pembrooke the summe of Three hundred twenty six pounds and ten shillings.</para>
		<para id="p63">The County of Radnor the summe of One hundred seaventy fower pounds six shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p64">The Towne of Haverford-West the summe of Fifteene pounds three shillings and five pence.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners named.</head>
			<para id="p65">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That all and every the persons hereafter named shall
be C&bhooov;missers of and for the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, Cittyes, Burroughes, Townes and Places hereafter
named, that is to say.</para>
			<para id="p66">[Bedford<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p67">For the County of Bedford William Russell Esquire Sir George Carteret Vice-Chamberlaine Sir John Duncombe
Chauncellour of his Majestyes Exchequer, Charles Leigh Esquire, Sir John Cotton Sir John Nappier Sir Roger Burgoyne
Sir Thomas Alston Sir Anthony Chester Sir Humphrey Winch Sir Humphrey Monox Sir Saint John Charnocke Sir
Stephen Anderson Sir William Gostwicke Baronets, Sir William Fleetewood Sir William Palmer Sir John Huxley
Sir William Beecher Sir George Blundell Sir Clement Arminger Sir Francis Wingate Knights, Pawlet S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Oliver
Luke John de la Fountaine Francis Crawley Witt Duncombe Witt Palmer Thomas Palmer Thomas Browne William
Dyer John Osborne Humphrey Monox Villars Charnocke Richard Stone S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Thompson William Boteler Thomas
Snag John Keeling John Vaux William Spencer John Alston John Copin Francis Wingate William Gerey William
Francklin Francis Dive Walter Carey George Wyan Gaius Squire James Mountague Humphrey Fish John Neele
John Cockayne John Ventris Robert Crompton Robert Awdley. Samuell Bedford Mathew Denton Mathew Dennis
Richard Orliber Jasper Edwards Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p68">[For the Towne of Bedford<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p69">The Maior of Bedford for the time being William Russell Esquire Sir John Napier Sir Humphrey Winch Sir
William Beecher Pawlet Saint John (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) John Gardiner William Foster Esquiers Thomas Christy Simon Becket Robert
Beverley John Beaumont William Scott Thomas Fitzhugh Crawley Richard Elmes John Cobb John
Spencer Francis Becket and John Becket Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p70">[Berks<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p71">For the County of Berks Henry Earle of Sterling of the Kingdome of Scotland Charles Earle of Ancram of
the Kingdome of Scotland Henry Viscount Cornbury Sir George Carteret Knight Vice-Chamberlaine to his Majestie
Thomas Howard Esquire Sir Humphrey Forrester Sir George Stonehouse Sir Henry Henn Sir George Pratt Sir
Francis Wenman Sir Richard Braham Sir Thomas Draper Sir Anthony Craven Sir William Rich Sir Cecile Bishop
Sir Thomas Clerges Sir Edward Fettiplace Sir Edward Hobby Baronets Sir Richard Powle Knight of the Bath
Sir Edmond Sawyer Sir Robert Pye Sir William Armorer Sir William Craven Sir Thomas Dolman Sir John Davis
Sir John Elwes Sir Richard Bishop Sir Richard Harrison Knights Humphrey Hyde senior Richard Nevill Edward
Manfeild William Barker Peregrine Hobby Robert Packer William Chiffinch Richard Aldworth Edmund Fettiplace
James Bridgman Thomas Vachell Thomas Fettiplace George Fettyplace John Harrison William Wilmott Francis
Piggot Edward Keate Henry Barker Henry Murray John Blagrave John Kingsmill John Stonehouse Hungerford
Dunch Edmond Fettyplace Edmond Wiseman William Lovelace William Trumball Henry Pro&bholigct;or William Nelson
Humphry Hyde junior John Finch Paul Calton William Barker of Hurst Major Dunch William Ball Roger
Draper William Hussey Charles Garret John Southby John Powney senior William Kendrick Phillip Jemmot
Phillip Weston Thomas Holt Thomas Staples Richard Lightfoote Esquiers William Offley Charles Perrot Do&bholigct;ors of
Law Hugh Parker Francis Hungerford Do&bholigct;ors of Phisicke John Whitwick Robert Leigh Michaell Mallet Hartgill
Baron John Hersey William Tailor William Smith James Smith Simon Smith Francis Ridley Charles Whitacre
Richard Brickenden William Hamersly Richard Southby Francis Peacocke George Blagrave John Peacocke Nicholas
Hyde Thomas Southby William Langton John Due James Heron Captaine Charles Gerrard Captaine Henry Barker
John Powney junior Richard Lovelace Roger Knight Nathan Knight Charles Perce Richard Palmer Bartholimew
Yate Esquiers The Maior of Reading for the time being The Maior of Abingdon for the time, being The Maior
of Windsor for the time being The Maior of Wallingford for the time being The Maior of Newbury for the
time being.</para>
			<para id="p72">[Bucks<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p73">For the County of Bucks Charles Earle, of Ancram in the Kingdome of Scotland Phillip Lord Wenman Viscount
Tuam in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Thomas Tyrrell Sir John Burlace Sir Anthony Chester Sir Thomas Proby
Sir William Bowyer Sir William Smith Sir Ralph Varney Sir William Drake Sir Henry Andrews Sir John Croke
Sir Humphry Winch Sir Thomas Leigh Sir Edmond Pye Knights and Barronets Sir Richard Temple Sir William
Terringham Sir Richard Ingoldesby Sir Robert Gayer Knights of the Bath Sir Francis Wainman Sir Richard Napier
Sir Richard Piggot Sir Henry Herbert Sir John Dormer Sir Thomas Clayton Sir Robert Croke Sir Thomas Clerges
Sir Peter Tyrrell Sir [Burbecke<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Temple Sir John Trevor Knights James Herbert Daniell Finch Edward Manfeild
Charles Cheney Esquires Thomas Waller Edward Baldwin Edmund Waller senior Edmund Waller junior William Penn
Edmund West Brett Norton Thomas Hackett John Duncombe of Great Brick William Lane Robert Lovett Richard
Barringer Thomas Butler William Sergeant junior Edward Nicholas Thomas Ferrer senior Cesar Wood late Cranmer
John Ristey Knigtley Purefoy Roger Price Thomas Napier Edmund Hampden John Whiterong Thomas Saunders
of Hadnum Francis Ingoldesby Edmund Darrell George Russell Richard Winwood Richard Grinvile Sir Roger Hill
Sir Dennis Hampson Baronet Bud Wayes Richard Hambden Bazill Brent William Hill Thomas Farrer junior James
Lowe Thomas Stafford Edward Back well Robert Tompson Bernard Tourney Christopher Eyeton Francis Tyrringham
Robert Dormer John Loggings George Wyan William Clever William Abraham Nicholas Salter junior Henry
Seamore Captaine Robert Stiles John Grub John Greene Henry Alnot William Bowyer George Gosnell Thomas
Owen Andrew Duffeild Edmund Medlicot Marmaduke Dorrell Edmond Varney Esq&bhoqesq; Edmond Dorrell [Esq&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] William
Coleing [Esq&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Dudley Reuse John Dormer Esquier John Burlace.</para>
			<para id="p74">[Towne of Buckingham<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p75">The Towne of Buckingham The Bayliffe for the time being Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath and Baronet
Sir William Smith Baronet John Risley [Esq&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Edmond Varney Esquier Edward Andrews Gentleman John Turner
Edmond Dorrell Esquiers Hugh Ethersay George Dancer John Rogers Pelham Sandwell Walter Arnott John Grove.</para>
			<para id="p76">[Towne of Wickombe<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p77">For the Towne of Wickombe Richard Lucas Maior Edward Bedder senior Samuell Wells Edward Humphrey
Jonathan Randall Alexander Parnham Henry Bigg Edward Beddar junior Thomas Davis Aldermen William Hawkins
William Kempe Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p78">[Cambridge<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p79">For the County of Cambridge Richard Lord<ref idref="n4">4</ref> Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland William Lord Allington of the
Kingdome of Ireland Sir Charles North [K&ntilde;t<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Sir Thomas Chichley Knight Sir Thomas Hatton Sir Robert Cotton
John Cotton Sir Thomas Willis Sir Lovinus Bennet Sir George Downing Baronets Sir Thomas Wendy Knight of the
Bath Sir Robert Cotton [K&ntilde;t<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Sir Francis Dayrell Knight John Millecent Samuell Fortrey Gerrard Russell Geoffrey
Nightingale Humphry Gardner William Layer Thomas Duckat Roger Pepys Mildmay Dowman Tyrrell Dalton
William Ayloffe George Pike Thomas Buck Devereux Martin Edward Pickering Roger Jenyns Henry Slingsby [Esq&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]
Humphry Weld Esquier</para>
			<para id="p80">[University and Towne of Cambridge<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p81">For the University and Towne of Cambridge The Vicechauncellour of the University of Cambridge for the
time being, The Maior of the Towne of Cambridge for the time William Lord Allington of the Kingdome of Ireland
Sir Thomas Chichley Knight one of his Majesties most Honourable Privy Councell James Duport James Fleetewood
Theophilus Dillingham Do&bholigct;ors of Divinity Robert King Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Thomas Crouch Clement Nevill Thomas
Page Robert Pepys Esquiers John Herring Nathaniell Crabb Edward Lawe Phillip Williams George Farwell and John
Hunt Aldermen of Cambridge Samuell Moody Sir Thomas Slater Baronet Thomas Stephens Do&bholigct;or of Divinity
Edward Stoyt Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Nicholas Jacob Esq&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p82">[Isle of Ely<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p83">For the Isle of Ely Robert Mapletoft Do&bholigct;or of Divinity and Deane of Ely Edward Partridge Esq&bhoqesq; Lawrence
Woomocke Do&bholigct;or of Divinity Henry Hitch Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Thomas Steward Charles Wren William March
Thomas Towers John Childe [Sir<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] John Norton Thomas Dockwray Henry Brunsell Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Thomas Wrenn
Archdeacon of Ely William Holder Richard Marryot Esquiers Richard Lord Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland
Sir Lyonell Walden [K&ntilde;t<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Sir Robert Sewster Knight William Colvile Peter Diamond Robert Balaam Thomas Edwards
Michaell Holman Anthony Fisher Anthony Buckworth Roger Jenings Mathias Taylor Richard Reede John Fincham
Hugh Underwood Anthony Hammond Peter Dyamond Gentlemen George Farewell [Esq&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] William Wrenn Esquier</para>
			<para id="p84">[Chester<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p85">For the County of Chester Robert Lord [Chalmoundley<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] William Lord Brereton Thomas Needham [Esq&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n9">9</ref>]
Henry Booth Esquier Sir Thomas Wilbraham (<ref idref="n10">10</ref>) Sir Thomas [Deles<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Sir Willoughby Ashton (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>). Sir Thomas
Powell (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir Thomas Smith (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir George Warburton (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir Thomas Mainwaring (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir Peter Leicester (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir
Richard Brooke (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>)'Sir William Standley (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir Peter Standley (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir John Bellolt (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir Peter Pindar (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>)
Sir Robert Duckenfeild [Baronets<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Sir Robert Cotton (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Sir Jeoffrey Shakerley (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Sir Peter Brooke (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Sir John
Booth (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Sir Foulke Lucy (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Sir John Ardern (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Sir Phillip Egerton (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Sir John Trevour [Knights<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Peter
Venables Baron of Kinderton John Crew of Crew Esq[uire] Collonell Thomas Leigh (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Henry Leigh (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Richard
Leigh (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Nathaniell Booth (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas [Cholmondsey<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] John Crew (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Roger Wilbraham (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Somerford Oldfeild (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>)
William Marbury (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Robert Venables (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) William Venables (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Daniell (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Daniell (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) George Vernon (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>)
Thomas Leigh the Younger of Adlington (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Leigh of Lime(<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Randall Dod (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Roger Wilbraham of
Townsend (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) William Davenport of Woodford (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Ralph Wilbraham (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Richard Walthall (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Edward Glegg(<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John
Starkey (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Moston (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Henry Bunbury (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Jonathan Braen (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Leigh (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Henry Brooke (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John
Leech (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Button of Hatton(<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Hurlston (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) William Brocke (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Edward Swettenham (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas
Tatton (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Henry Mainwaring (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Edward Leigh (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Minshall (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Peter Wilbraham (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Smethwicke (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>)
Edmund Jawdrell (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Aldersey (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Anthony Eyre [Esquiers.<ref idref="n14">14</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p86">[Citty of Chester<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p87">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester The Maior for the time being Sir Thomas Smith Baronet
William Williams Es&bhoqesq; Recorder William Ince [Alderman<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Richard Taylor Alderman William Street Alderman
Richard Bird Alderman George Booth Esq&bhoqesq; John Brerewood (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Ralph Whitly (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) James Bradshaw [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>]
Collonell Werden Edward Hubwicke (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Nathaniell Williamson (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Kendricke Gaton [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] M<emph type="p">t</emph> Alderman Lloyd
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Gowen Hudson M<emph type="p">r</emph> Alderman Maddocke. M<emph type="p">r</emph> Alderman Simpson. M<emph type="p">r</emph> Alderman Murrey M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Gregg.</para>
			<para id="p88">[Cornwall<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p89">For the County of Cornwall Robert Roberts (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Arundell (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Hender Roberts [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Sir Boucher
Wrey Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir Jonathan Trelawney (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir John Carew (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir Violl Viveon (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir
John Coryton (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Sir William Godolphin [Baronets<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Sir Richard Edgecombe (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Sir John Aubin [Knights<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Sir
Nicholas Slaning Knight of the Bath Sir Peter Killigrew (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Sir John Arundell (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Sir James Smith (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) Sir Walter
Moyle [Knights<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Sir William Morris Baronet Sir Joseph Tredinham Knight Hugh Buscowen (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Bernard Greenvile (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>)
William Courtney (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Charles Trevanian (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Francis Buller (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Buller (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Speccot (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Tanner (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>)
Jonathan Raishley (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) senior Jonathan Raishley junior (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Trelawney senior (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Trelawney junior (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John
Elliot (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Edmond Predeux [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] John Predeux Gentleman of Padslowe John Tregagle Esq&bhoqesq; Nathaniell Moyle
Gent. John Harris (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) William Scawen (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Coriton (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) William Bond (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Walter Langden senior (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Walter
Langden junior.(<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Edward Buscowen (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Edward Herle (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Cooke (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Nicholas Glinn (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Herle (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>)
James Pride (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Connocke (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John S<emph type="i">t</emph> Aubin (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Nichols.(<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) of Trewane Thomas Dorrell [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] John
Nicholas of Litlewood Gentleman Arthur Fortescue (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) John Vivean (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Vivean (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Joseph Saule (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) William
Mohun senior (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) William Mohun junior [Esquiers] Hanniball Buggin (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Lewis Tremayne(<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Golan Blewet (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>)
John Blight [Gentlemen<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Francis Basset Es&bhoqesq; John Rashley (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Robert Hoblin (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Thomas Robinson (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Richard
Erisey, (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Christopher Harris [Gentlemen<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] John Molesworth (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Humphry Courteny (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Charles Buscowen.(<ref idref="n14">14</ref>)
Robert Scawen (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Waddon (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) William Ascott (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Edward Noseworthy [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] John Polewheele Gent.
John Penrose (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Edmond Prideaux.(<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) William Godolphin (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Sydney Godolphin [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Sir John Godolphin
Knight Arthur Spry (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Edward Elliot [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Thomas Piper (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) John Kelly (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Thomas Kelly of Trewint (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>)
Richard Pendrees (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Hugh Trewanian (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) George Spry (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Nathaniell Trewaneon (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) John Howell (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Ezekiell
Arundell Gent Walter Kendall (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Hugh Smith [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] John Battersby (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Charles Grills (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Francis Grills (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>)
Francis Calmady [Gentlemen<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Humphry Noy (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Edward Harris (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Nicholas Courtney [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Renold Hawley
Gent. Thomas Achim (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) William Panter [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Michaell Hill of Wendron Gent. John Carnsew (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Samuell
Ends (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Thomas Trifrey [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Anthony Chenoweth (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Francis Burges (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) John Silly (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Richard Tippat (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>)
Thomas Carew [Gentlemen<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Christopher Billet. (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Humphrey Burlace [Esquiers<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Samuell Langford (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Walter
Vincent (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) John Verman,(<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Humphry Lower (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) James Robbins Gent. Francis Lutterell (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) James Erisey Es&bhoqesq; The
Maior of Truro for the time being The Maior of Leskeard for the time being The Maior of Bodmin for the time
being. John Arundell of Dewlow Gent. M<emph type="p">r</emph> Phillip Mayow of Bray senior M<emph type="p">r</emph> Phillip Mayow Junior Thomas Benhallow
Es&bhoqesq; Nicholas Sprey Gent. John Barret of Killegreene Richard Williams Gent. John Williams Gent. Able French
Gent. John Peirce of Dewstow Gent. Joseph Hawke Gent. John Newman Gent. John Tamlin Gent. William Beall
Gent. Thomas Hicks of Paule Gent. Richard Martin of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Nyot M<emph type="p">r</emph> Martin of Tallond M<emph type="p">t</emph> Martin of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Gennes
John Kendall Es&bhoqesq; Ambrose Mannerton Gent. Humphrey Lansford Gent. Samuell Roll Es&bhoqesq; Charles Trevanean of
Tregoes Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p90">[Cumberland<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p91">For the County of Cumberland Edward Lord Morpeth sonne and heire apparent to Charles Earle of Carlisle
Sir Phillip Musgrave Baronet Sir Richard Greyham Baronet Sir William Dalston Baronet Sir George Fletcher Sir John
Lowther senior Sir John Lowther Junior Sir Edward Musgrave Baronets Sir Thomas Dacre Sir Wilfrid Lawson Sir
Phillip Howard Sir George Dalston Sir John Dalston Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir Joseph Williamson Knights John
Lamplugh Es&bhoqesq; Daniell Fleming Es&bhoqesq; William Layton Es&bhoqesq; Christopher Blencow Es&bhoqesq; William Musgrave Es&bhoqesq; John
Alyonby Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Denton Es&bhoqesq; Richard Tolson Es&bhoqesq; Andrew Hubleston Es&bhoqesq; Robert Cobly Es&bhoqesq; Richard
Musgrave Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Warwicke Es&bhoqesq; Richard Patrickson Es&bhoqesq; Fardinando Hudleston Es&bhoqesq; Richard Lamplugh
Es&bhoqesq; John Clarke Es&bhoqesq; Christopher Richmond Es&bhoqesq; William Penington Es&bhoqesq; Bernard Kerkbride Es&bhoqesq; Edward Stanley
Es&bhoqesq; Miles Pennington Es&bhoqesq; William Fenwicke Es&bhoqesq; Leonard Dykes Es&bhoqesq; Nicholas Foster Es&bhoqesq; The Maior of
Carlisle for the time being William Feilding Es&bhoqesq; [Wilfrod<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Lawson Es&bhoqesq; John Leubons Es&bhoqesq; Henry Fletcher Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p92">[Derby<ref idref="n18">18</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p93">For the County of Derby Henry Earle of Ogle sonne and heire apparent to William Duke of Newcastle, William
Lord Cavendish sonne and heire apparent to William Earle of Devonshire, Sir John Gell Baronet High Sheriffe
of the County of Derby. Anchetill Grey Es&bhoqesq; Sir Francis Lee Knight and Baronet Sir Robert Sherley Sir Francis
Rhodes Sir Thomas Greisley Sir Francis Burdet Sir John Harpur Sir John Curson Sir Robert Coke Sir Henry
Ivery Sir William Boothsby Baronets Sir John Harpur Sir Samuell Sleigh Sir Gilbert Clarke Sir Simeon Degge
Sir John Shore Knights John Ferrers German Poole John Coke Charles Agard George Vernon Henry Cavendish
Robert Coke John Munday Henry Milward William Fitzherbert Charles Cotton William Sacheverell Henry Gilbert
Walter Horton Gilbert Thacker Francis Leeke Robert Eyre William Eyre of Holme Nicholas Wilmot John
Shalcrosse Ravell Ashenhurst Francis Mennell Thomas Milward Henry Kendall Edward Abney Henry Wigfall
James Abney Adrian Munday John Low of Accasley John Low of Denby Cornelius Clerke Edward Pegg Francis
Barker William Wright George Savill John Moorewood William Bage John Spateman junior Esquiers Lawrence
Sleigh William Hopkinson John Smithson John Wigley Robert Heywood Robert Mower Gervas Reynor Gent.
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Hugh Bateman M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Allestry M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Meller M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Osborne The Maior of Derby for the time
being M<emph type="p">r</emph> Humphrey Yates M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Brackhouse M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Walker Aldermen M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Walker M<emph type="p">r</emph> Samuell
Goodwin Mr Joseph Parker Policarpus Dakin Doctor in Phisicke M<emph type="p">r</emph> James Ward The Maior of Chesterfeild for
the time being Richard Clerke Thomas Britland James Milns Aldermen M<emph type="p">r</emph> George Backwell John Dalton Es&bhoqesq;
Robert Wandall Alderman M<emph type="p">r</emph> Andrew Clayton John Every Es&bhoqesq; John Stanhope Alexander Stanhope of [Elveston<ref idref="n19">19</ref>]
Henry Keyes Francis Revell William Milward junior Walter Wolsley Esquiers Samuell Holden Thomas Eyre
Councellours at Law.</para>
			<para id="p94">[Devon<ref idref="n18">18</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p95">For the County of Devon Edward Seymour Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons Arthur Earle of
Dunnigall Sir George Cartwright Vice-Chamberlaine of his Majestyes Household Sir William Morrice one of
his Majestyes Privey Councell Sir Edward Deymour Sir Peter Predeaux Sir Henry Hele Sir George Childeigh
Sir Ames Pollard Sir Francis Drake Sir Courtney Poole Sir Coplestone Bampfeild Sir John Northcott Sir John
Davye Sir William Courtney Sir Hugh Acland Sir Edmond Fowell Sir John Drake Sir William Morrice Sir
Thomas Carew Sir Nicholas Slaning Baronets Sir John Rolle Sir Richard Edgecombe Sir Edward Wise Sir Henry
Vane Knights of the Bath Sir Peter Fortescue Barronet Sir Henry Carew Sir William Strode [Sir<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Robert Cary
Sir John Mainard Sir Peter Ball Sir James Smith Sir John Mallet Sir Thomas Carew Sir William Waldron Sir
Thomas Bury Sir Henry Ford Knights Peter Predeaux John Poole John Fowell Arthur Northcott Samuell Rolle
John Rolle Francis Drew Robert Fortescue Richard Strode Arthur Harris John Harris Nicholas Dennis Richard
Duke Edmond Waldron William Bragg Josias [Galmady<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] John Tanner John Chichester of Hall John Frye Egidion
Heydon John Crocker William Savery Mathew Halse John Gifford of Brightley Esquier Edward Yard John
Kelland Henry Northley Samuell Sentall John Tuckfeild Richard Hillersdon Samuell Tanner Thomas Were Richard
Lee John Chichester of Woodwortley John Reymond Elias Bartlet senior Leonard Yeo John Drake of Ivye Bridge
Edmond Prideaux of Ford Jonathan Prideaux Henry Stevens James Clifford William Bastard John Bere of Berescomb
Roger Pomeroy William Bruton Bartholomew Gidley John Blewet Arthur Bury John Hale John Giffard Roger
Wallocombe Sebastian Isaac James Huish Edward Yard of Tresbery Edward Lovett Lewis Ingleton John Courtney
Aaron Baker John Hore Sir Thomas Higgon James Rode Nicholas Heydon Peter Holwell Bamfeild Rode Mathew
Hele John Vaughan William Bogan Thomas Reynoll Henry Frye John Arscot Arthur Tremeane Henry Walter
William Kelley Phillip Champernon Shelston Calmady Walter Elford Thomas Pine Jonathan Sparke William Jenings
Thomas Poyntington Phillip Shapcott Henry Carew Thomas Hele Anthony Salter James Calwoodley Esquiers, The
High Sheriffe of the said County for the time being. The Maiors of Totnes Barnestaple Plymouth Dartmouth and
Tiverton for the time being John Davy of Cannontin Rawlin Mallock Henry Worth Thomas Bere John Coish
Esquiers George Southcout of Dulcehays Gent. Phillip Harris of Torrington Es&bhoqesq;, John Harris of Wortham Es&bhoqesq; Phillip
Harris of Stowford Gent. Richard Coffin John Quick Edward Greenwood of Bredsborn.</para>
			<para id="p96">[Exon<ref idref="n18">18</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p97">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Exon The Maior for the time being Sir Peter Ball Recorder Sir
James Smith Knight Robert Walker Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Carew Knight Sir John Mallet Knight The Sheriffe for the
time being Alderman Butler Major Thomas Walker Alderman Isaac Alderman Samford John Bidgood Do&bholigct;or of
Phisick John Fowell Es&bhoqesq; Edmond Davye Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Major Hadyedote Isaac Maudit Captaine Glyde Samuell
Issaac Towne Clerke.</para>
			<para id="p98">[Dorset<ref idref="n22">22</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p99">For the County of Dorset John Lord Digby some and here apparent to George Earle of Bristoll Anthony Lord
Ashley some and heire apparent to Anthony Earle' of Shaftsbury Lord High Chauncellour Sir Hugh Wyndham
Knight one of his Majestyes Justices of the Common Pleas Michaell Harvey Es&bhoqesq; High Sheriffe Sir Francis Holies
Baronet Sir John Moreton Baronet Sir William Portman Baronet Sir Gerrard Napper Baronet Sir John Nicholas Knight
of the Bath Sir Ralph Banks Knight Giles Strangwayes Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Strode Knight Sir Nathaniell Napper Knight
Sir Winston Churching Knight Sir Roger Cuttens Knight Thomas Freake Es&bhoqesq; John Strangwayes Es&bhoqesq; John Tregonwell
of Milton Es&bhoqesq; John Tregonwell of Anderston Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Browne Es&bhoqesq; Edward Miller Es&bhoqesq; Samuell Hobbs Es&bhoqesq;
James Long Es&bhoqesq; William Strode Es&bhoqesq; Humphrey Bishop Es&bhoqesq; Humphrey Welde Es&bhoqesq; George Fulford Es&bhoqesq; Collonell
Francis Wyndham Robert Napper Es&bhoqesq; William Uvedall Es&bhoqesq; Robert Culleford Es&bhoqesq; John Ryves Es&bhoqesq; William Okederi
Robert Coker Thomas Baynard George Browne Henry Eynes Mathew Davyes Henry Whittaker William Thomas
John Hoskins Robert Williams John Bennet Thomas Turbervill John Churchill George Rives Richard Fowens John
Michell Henry Butler George Savage Robert Browne John Lawrence Audley Grey Robert Teymbur Maximilian
Mohun Francis Mohun George Trenchard John Still William Boules John Trenchard John Gould John Ironside
Hugh Hodges John Harden Anthony Ettricke Henry Henley of Coleway William Floyer Nathaniell Heymour Thomas
Chafe John Jeffris Charles Brewen Thomas Hussey of Edmonsham Georg Strangwayes Bonham Strangwayes
Hubert Arnole George Stile Thomas Gallop John Gallop Seymour Bowman Nathaniell Bond John Hardey Richard
Greene Robert Lewer William Churchill William Collier Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p100">[Poole<ref idref="n22">22</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p101">For the Towne and County of Poole Anthony Lord Ashley Sir John Moreton Baronet Thomas Strangways Es&bhoqesq;
Nicholas Efford Maior Anthony Ettrich Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Robert Lewen Gent. Moses Durell Robert Clewes Edward
Mann William Orchard John Curtis Henry Jubbar Isaac Hart Merchants.</para>
			<para id="p102">[Palatine of Durham.<ref idref="n22">22</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p103">For the County Palatine of Durham The Right Honourable Charles Lord S<emph type="p">t</emph> John of Basing Sir Francis Goodrick.
Temporall Chauncellour Do&bholigct;or Burwell Chauncellour of the Diocesse of Durham Sir Christopher Conyers Sir Ralph
Cole Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir James Clavering Sir James Pennyman Sir Robert Eden Baronets Sir George Vane Sir
Francis Anderson Sir Francis Bowes Sir Ralph Delavall Knights James Darcey Henry Lambton John Tempest
Collonell William Blakeston Thomas Craddock William Bellases Richard Neile Nicholas Conyers Humphrey Wharton
Ralph Carre Cuthbart Carre Robert Wharton Ralph Davison John Jefferson William Davison Lieutenant Collonell
Bellises Major Baker Isaac Basire John Morland Thomas Foster George Morland Daniell Collingwood Collonell
Stother [Esq[ui]rs<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Miles Stapilton Thomas Wright Thomas Carnaby Esquiers [Major Christian<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] The Maior of the Citty
of Durham for the time being M<emph type="p">r</emph> Alderman Hall M<emph type="p">r</emph> Alderman Hodson Captaine Henry Barnes M<emph type="p">r</emph> Anthony Wharton
M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Deacon M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Roper M<emph type="p">r</emph> George Mires M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Ellyot Walter Etherick [Gent.<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Robert Jackson of
Stockton, Cooke of Stockton William Atkinson of Stockton Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p104">[Essex<ref idref="n22">22</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p105">For the County of Essex Sir Harbotle Grimstone Baronet Master of the Rolls Sir Edward Turner Lord Cheife
Baron of the Exchequer Robert Berty Charles Mildmay Richard Barret Banistre Mainard Esquiers Sir John Barington
Knight and Baronet .Sir John Bendish Sir Henry Apleton Sir William Ayloffe Sir William Hicks Sir Andrew Jenour
Sir William Wiseman Sir Richard Everard Sir Martin Lumley Sir Thomas Nightingale Baronets Sir Capell Luckin
Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Abdy Knight and Baronet Sir John Abdy Baronet Sir William Wiseman Kn[igh]t &amp;
Bar[one]t [Sir Edward Smith<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Baronet Sir James Altham Sir John Brampston Knights of the Bath Sir John Tyrrell Knight
Sir Thomas Bowes Knight Sir Cranmer Herris Knight Sir Henry Clerke Knight Sir Anthony Browne Knight Sir
Richard Wiseman Knight Sir Mondeford Brampston Knight one of the Masters in Chauncery Sir John Shaw Knight
Sir Richard Everard Knight Sir Francis Leeke Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Litleton Baronet Sir William Glascocke
Knight one of the Masters in Chauncery Sir Thomas Fanshaw Knight Sir William Hicks Knight Francis Bramston
Sergeant at Law Richard Summer Thomas Meade Peter Seame Esquiers Sir Robert Smith Sir John Tyrrell Baronets
Thomas Argoll Oliver Reymond John Symonds William Glascocke John Tyndall Tristram Conyers Thomas Luther
Esquiers Sir Eliab Harvey Knight William Maynard Es&bhoqesq; Sir John James Knight Sir William Holecroft Knight Sir
James Rushout Baronet John Wroth Thomas Turner William Umphrevill Thomas Roberts William Appleton John
Berners Robert Clerke John Turner Richard Kirkby Thomas Cheeke Edward Bullocke Carew Harvey Mildmay
Stephen Smith Robert Mildmay Henry Whight Samuell Hare Francis Osbiston William Palmer Esquiers Sir James
Norffolke Knight Sergeant at Arms Cuthbert Martin Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Talcott Henry Ayloffe Zachariah Gee Esquiers
George James Thomas King William Harris Gentlemen Giles Dent Es&bhoqesq; Sir Phillip Mathews Baronet Sir Thomas
Garret Baronet Sir Edward Turner junior Knight Sir Edward Farmer Knight Richard Staines William Gore Samuell
Grimston Charles Hancocke Anthony Knightbridge Esquiers Jeremiah Lacey William Wade Samuell Reynolds Richard
Collins Gentlemen Edward Pascall William Coney John Rotheram George Scot Nicholas Rotheram Richard Lightfoote
Thomas Bland Esquiers Richard Rudge Thomas Cullam Robert Cole Gentlemen John Lemot Honeywood Thomas
Bowes Richard Luther Henry Dawtree John Marshall George Walton James Milbourn William Lingwood. Francis
Gardner Henry Southcott Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p106">[Colchester<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p107">For the Towne of Colchester The Maior for the time being Sir Harbotle Grimstone Baronet Master of the Rolls
Sir John Shaw Knight Recorder of the said Towne Sir Mondeford Brampstone Knight John Shaw Es&bhoqesq; Thomas
Talcott Henry Lambe Esquiers Aldermen of the said Towne William More Gent. Samuell Reynolds Es&bhoqesq; Joseph
Thurston Gent..</para>
			<para id="p108">[Maldon<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p109">For the Towne of Maldon The Bayliffes for the time being Francis Gourney Anthony Gratiano M<emph type="p">r</emph> Simonds Gent.
Aldermen of the said Towne.</para>
			<para id="p110">[Harwich<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p111">For the Towne of Harwich The Maior for the time being Sir Capell Luckin Baronet Samuell Newton Thomas
King Thomas Langley Daniell Smith John Roffe Gent..</para>
			<para id="p112">[Gloucester<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p113">For the County of Gloucester Charles Lord Herbert of Ragland, John Viscount Scudamore of the Kingdome of
Ireland John Viscount Tracy of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Mathew Hale Knight Lord Cheife Justice Sir Robert
Atkins Knight of the Bath one of the Justices of the Court of C&bhooov;mon Pleas George Mountague Es&bhoqesq; [Sir<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] Charles
Berkley Sir Henry Capell Knights of the Bath Sir John Tracy Baronet Sir Baynham Throckmorton Knight and
Baronet Sir Richard Ashfeild Sir William Ducy Sir Henry Fredericke Thynne Sir Edward Bathurst Sir Richard
Howe Sir Robert Jenkinson Sir Richard Francklin Sir William Juxon Sir William Keyte Sir John Guise Sir John
Newton Sir Edward [Husse<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] Sir Richard Cocks Sir Robert Cann Baronets Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath Sir
William Catchmaid Sir Edmond Bray Sir Thomas Stephens Sir Thomas Overbury Sir Gabriell Lowe Sir Humphrey
Hooke Sir Thomas Howe Sir John Poyntz Sir Scroope Howe Sir Robert Atkins junior Evan Seyes Sergeant at Law
John Grubham Howe Henry Norwood Thomas Thynne William Cooke Thomas Master William Dutton John
Winter Thomas Escourt Reginald Bray Giles Fettiplace Robert Coddrington William Trye Miles Sands John Higford
Henry Dennis John Chamberlaine William Bouchier Thomas Chester Richard Atkins Richard Stephens John Stephens
Fleetewood Dormer Robert Pleydall William Leigh William Stratford Thomas Horton George Pitt John Sackvile
John Delabere Thomas Barrow Edward Rich Anthony Sanbach Benjamin Barret Edmund Chamberlaine Thomas
Jennins Es&bhoqesq; Samuell Horner Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Veele of Symonds Hall William Stratford William Cope John George
William Morgan David Williams Robert Bromage Thomas Marriet John Browneing William Selwin John Smith,
Miles Rutter Henry Browne Thomas Rich Andrew Barker James Stephens Silvanus Wood Richard Dowdeswell,
John Guise of Abbods Court Esquiers Robert Logan Ducombe Colchester Henry Powle John Meredeth Richard
Baugh Thomas Smith Phillip Sheppard Richard Norwood Robert Oldsworth and William Oldsworth Thomas
Carpender John Robbins Edward Smith Henry Guise Robert Gowning [William<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] Woorley Henry Sims John Dowle
Christopher Cole John Holmes Paul Foley James Hawkins William Player John Langley Henry Heylin John Coles
John Stafford Edward Selwin William Dowdswell Nicholas Veele Richard Browne. Thomas Browne of Corn Fawn
Roger Lingen William Hancock Paul Castleman Hanger of Griffeild Samuell Astry Hugh Browne
Richard Jones of Hanham Richard Hart Paul Dodwell Thomas Wise John Driver Edward Nott William Banister
Waiman Winniat William Gough Edmond Madocke Richard Machen Christopher Woodward Thomas Pyrke George
Bond of Redbrook Conway Whittorn Roger Haward The Bayliffes of Tewksbury for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p114">[Citty of Gloucester<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p115">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester Collonell Henry Norwood Maior of the said Citty and
the Maior for the time being Sir Edward Massey Knight Evan Seyes Es&bhoqesq; Sergeant at Law William Cooke (<ref idref="n27">27</ref>) John
Stanion (<ref idref="n27">27</ref>) John Guise (<ref idref="n27">27</ref>) William Selwin [Esquiers<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] Robert Feilding Doctor of Phisicke William Russell Thomas
Price John Wagstaffe Henry Fowler Thomas Aram John Gethings John Rogers, Aldermen James Stephens Lawrence
Singleton John Marston William Jordan Toby Jordan William Lambe John Webbe Nicholas Webbe William
Scudamore William Hodges Citizens Thomas Viner Doctor in Divinity Deane of the Cathedrall Church of
Gloucester Thomas Washborne Do&bholigct;or in Divinity Prebend of the same Church, Abraham Gregory Clerke Prebend
of the same Church.</para>
			<para id="p116">[Hereford<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p117">For the County of Hereford John Lord Viscount Scudamore Sir James Bridges Sir John Kirle Sir William
Powell Sir Thomas Morgan Sir John Scudamore Sir John Holman Sir Herbert Croft Baronets Sir Edward Harley
Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Tomkins Sir Thomas Hambury Sir Job Charleton Sir John Barnaby Sir Herbert
Perrot Sir John' Payne Knights Thomas Cornwall .pollonell Somerset Fox of Stapleton Thomas Price Humphrey
Cornwall Collonell John Birch Herbert Westfailing Reginold Graham Wallop Brabazon Thomas Whitney Walter
Pye Robert Pye John Scudamore Edward Cornwall Herbert Aubery Richard Reed William Gregory Bennet Hoskins
Thomas Cox John Skipp Edward Freeman James Pitt Thomas Harley Richard Hopton Thomas Geeres senior
Thomas Geeres junior Thomas Carpender Humphrey Baskerville Humphrey Howorth Francis Unett John Barnaby
of Brockampton John Booth of Hereford Rudhall Guillim William Lambe Paul Foley, Doctor Thomas Williams
John Nourse Bridstocke Harford Robert Rodd Marshall Bridges John Hoskins Francis Pember of Elsdon John
Hoskins of Harwood Henry Williams of Cabalea Ambrose. Elton Thomas Duppa Robert Blany Esquiers John
Darnall junior Anthony Rowden Nicholas Walwyn Richard Walwyn of Hellens Thomas Rodd Martin Sandys. of
Cradley Gent. John Dansy William Dansy George Barner of Buttus Edward Beresford John Booth of Brainton
William Westfailing Herbert Masters Edward Williams of Oldfeild Thomas Wigmoore William Broome John Guylim
of Wellington John Kirle of Rosse Humphrey Taylor of Wythington Thomas Carpenter of Tillington John Kyely
of Bromley John James Thomas Gomond of Kilpecke Higgens James George Kline of Wormebridge Edward
Lloyd of the Batch Henry Hyett John Cornwall Francis Geeres of Garnons Gentlemen The Bayliffe of the Burrough
of Lemster for the time being John Tomkins Gent. For Lemster Michaell Broughton of Knighton.</para>
			<para id="p118">[The Citty of Hereford<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p119">For the Citty of Hereford The Maior for the time being John Lord Viscount Scudamore Herbert Westfailing
Thomas Price William Gregory Esquiers Richard Philpotts Thomas Holmes Thomas, Clerke Thomas Paynard
Thomas Bond Hugh Rodd [William Edwin Edward Rodd <ref idref="n25">25</ref>] Nicholas Philpotts Thomas Smith Thomas Symonds
Richard Williams Mercer Roger Boulcott John Cooke William Mayton John Barnes.</para>
			<para id="p120">[County of Hertford<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p121">For the County of Hertford Thomas Lord Viscount Fanshaw Sir Harbotle Grimston Master of the Rolls Algernon
Cecill Es&bhoqesq; Sir. Richard Francklyn Sir John Mounson Sir Thomas Leventhorp Sir Richard Spencer Sir John
Whitwrongle Sir Jonathan Keate Sir John Austin Sir Richard Anderson. Sir Richard Atkins Sir Robert Jocelyn Sir
William Lemon Sir Edward Alston Baronets Sir Phillip Boteler Sir John Mounson Knights of the Bath Sir Rowland
Lytton Sir John Gore Sir Francis Boteler Sir William Glascocke Sir Henry Blunt Sir Charles Cesar Sir John Watts
Sir Humphrey Gore Sir Richard Combe Sir Thomas. Bide Sir Charles Clever Sir Robert Viner Sir William Bucknell
Sir Benjamin Titchbourne Sir Ralph Radcliffe Sir Walter Wa[l<ref idref="n25">25</ref>]ker Sir Robert Daces Knights Samuell Grimston
William Lytton William Hale John Garrard Thomas Dockwra Richard Harrison Thomas Priestley Ralph Freeman
Thomas Pope Blunt Mathew Blucke Richard [Gouston<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] Nicholas Miller Henry Guy George Cooper [Silus Titus<ref idref="n27">27</ref>]
Edward Atkins Francis Shalcrosse Arthur Pulter Henry Baldwin Thomas [Stanby<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] Edward Wingate Thomas Carpenter
Thomas Atkins Richard Blackwell Edmond Feild George Nodes Edward Watts Richard Crofts James Willymot
Edward Briscoe William Greenhill Arthur Sparks William Cotton Edward Crosby Henry Childe John Eccleston
Edmond Smith John Briscoe Ralph Gore Robert Robotham John Fotherly Thomas Nicholl of Bushy
Sanders Henry Chauncey Anthony Farrington George Throckmorton Francis Wethered Marmaduke Rawden
senior Henry Dunstar William Nuce Richard Reeves John Ellis Marmaduke Rawden junior Francis King Henry
Becker Peter Calvert George Needham John Dyos Humphry Hall Alexander Welde Esquiers Thomas Arras Doctor
in. Phisicke Thomas Burgesse Gent. Robert Deane Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke Maior of Hertford for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p122">[Saint Albans<ref idref="n28">28</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p123">For the Burrough of Saint Albans Sir Harbotle Grimston Do&bholigct;or Arris Samuell Grimston The Maior for the time
being John Simpson Recorder Robert Robotham Major Crosby William Cotton Anthony Farrington Edmond Smith
Thomas Cowley William Marston Thomas Oxton John New John Gape Robert New John Doggat William Oxton
William Kause William Rugg Haward Pollard Edward [Crasby<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] Thomas Eccieston.</para>
			<para id="p124">[County of Huntington.<ref idref="n28">28</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p125">For the County of Huntington Richard Earle of Arran in the Kingdome of Ireland George Mountague Es&bhoqesq;
Sir Francis Compton Knight Sir John Cotton Baronet Sir John Hewet (<ref idref="n34">34</ref>) Sir Thomas Proby Sir John Barnard Baronets
Sir Nicholas Pedley Sir Lyonell Walden Knights Henry Williams John Stone Robert Apreece Anthony Hamond
Lawrence Torkington John Heron Richard Naylour John Dryden Jasper Trice John, Ferrar Nicholas Johnson Saint
John Hare Esquiers John Trice Gent..</para>
			<para id="p126">[Towne of Huntington<ref idref="n28">28</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p127">For the Towne of Huntington Sir John Cotton (<ref idref="n34">34</ref>) Sir John Bernard [Baronets<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] The Maior for the time being
Sir Nicholas Pedley Sir Lionell Walden Knights Lawrence Torkington Es&bhoqesq; Samuel Pout Phillip Castell Gentlemen
Thomas Walwyn James Fairside William Dowse Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p128">[Kent<ref idref="n28">28</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p129">For the County of Kent Phillip Viscount Strangford Charles Lord Buckhurst Sir Vere Fane Knight of the Bath James
Herbert(<ref idref="n35">35</ref>) John Tufton (<ref idref="n35">35</ref>) Richard Tufton(<ref idref="n36">36</ref>) Sackvile Tufton [Esquiers<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] Sir Thomas Twisden one of the Justices of
the Kings Bench Sir William Wilde one of the Justices of the Kings Bench Sir Heneage Finch Baronet his Majestyes
Attourney Generall Sir Phillip Howard Knight Sir Thomas Peyton Sir William Twisden Sir Edward Hales Sir Henry
Palmer Sir John Rivers Sir William Merideth Sir Edward Deering Sir Thomas Stiles Sir Oliver Boteler Sir Norton
Knatchbull Sir John Tufton Sir John Rayney Sir Robert Hales Sir William Ducy Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir
Stephen Lennard Sir Humphrey Miller Sir John Marsham Sir John Banks Sir Robert Barnham Sir Thomas Peirce
Sir Nathaniell Powell [Knights<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] Sir John Austin Sir Thomas Selliard Sir Jonathan [Leete<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] Baronets Sir George Sonde
Knight of the Honourable Order of the Bath Sir Anthony Aucher Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Godfrey Sir
Arnald Braems Sir Henry Oxenden Sir Thomas Engham junior Sir Richard Powle Knight of the Hononrable Order
of the Bath Sir Phillip Warwicke Sir William Broadnax Sir John Darell senior Sir John Darell junior Sir Thomas
Scott Sir Francis Clerke Sir Thomas Culpeper Sir Theophilus Bidolph Knight and Baronet Sir William Leech Sir
William Boreman Sir Bernard Hyde Sir William Swan Knight and Baronet Sir Walter Vane Sir John Heath Attourney
of the Dutchy of Lancaster Sir Thomas Lee Sir William Hugesson Sir James Oxenden Thomas Broome Sergeant
at Law Thomas Hardresse Sergeant at Law Edward Hales of Tonstall Es&bhoqesq; John Strode Es&bhoqesq; John Boys of
Fredvile Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Hales of Becksborne Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Peke Thomas Crisp of Quex Thomas Hardresse junior
Walter Braems James Masters of Langdon James Masters of Yoakes Thomas Turnor William Rooke John Cason
Henry Oxenden of Brookes Richard Aldworth Herbert Randolfe Nicholas Toke of Godington Henry Thornhill of
Mantigh John Knatchbull James Brockman Henry Deering Edward Hales Richard Hulse John Naylor Robert
Leuknor Peter Heyman John Moyle Zouch Brockman (<ref idref="n30">30</ref>) Phillip Warwicke [Esquiers<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] Thomas [Hoodd<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] William
Cage Francis Barnham Sir Demetrius James Ferdinando Marsham Es&bhoqesq; Sir George Curtis Thomas Knatchbull Richard
Wilkinson Thomas Munn Ralph Bufkin Walter Francklin Richard Marsh Thomas English Thomas Harlakendon
Henry Howton Alabaster Fludd Francis Twisden Captaine John Clerke Richard Duke William Maddox The Maior
of Rochester for the time George Newman Richard Manley Richard Head Esquiers Sir Charles Bickerstaffe Knight
Robert Fowle Francis Barrell Thomas Manley Thomas Brewer Samuell Boys William Boys Thomas Culpeper of
Bedgbury Edward Finch Esquiers Sir John [Bunch<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] Knight Thomas Lambert Phillip Packer George Polhill Henry
Gilborne Marke Cotle John Hyde Esquiers Sir William Hooker Knight Norton Curtis Edward Curtis Robert
Heath Francis Heath John Evelin Sir Eliab Harvey Knight Thomas Papillon of Aucris William Swan Thomas
Seyliard James Fortrey William Boothby Christopher Allison Ralph Petley John Bridger Francis Farnaby Edward
Badby John Sydley James Thurborne George Boreman Esquiers Sir John Hendon Knight William Hammond of
Saint Albans William Campion Esquiers Thomas Andrews Edward Gulston Reginald Peckham Edward Short Thomas
Stace Maior of Tenterdenne for the time Robert Austin Maior of Sandwich for the time Phineas Ellwood John Verier
Valentine Jekin Jeoffrey Wells Jeoffrey Sacket Edward Elsted John Pauntry Maior of Dover for the time John
Watson Richard Jacob Walter Breme Es&bhoqesq; Doctor Golder George West Edward Wivell John Bullocke Nathaniell
Denew Sir Henry Boswell Knight M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Sands Sir Peircivill Hart M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Manning Edmond Tooke Es&bhoqesq;
Sir John Shaw Knight and Baronet Maior of Hyth for the time Robinson Beane William Knight Elias Basset John
Basset George Thourborne Maior of Feversham for the time John Troates Robert Watson Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Southerst
Bayliffe of Lydd for the time John Bateman William Sudell Thomas Bedingfeild Michaell Chidwicke Maior of
Folkestone for the time John Preagle Gent. Clement Preagle (Gent.<ref idref="n34">34</ref>) Maior of Fordwitch for the time Thomas Norton
John Luckyn Michaell Chidwicke Piercy Goreing William Kingsley Roger Payne Esquiers Sir Robert Faunce Sir
Nicholas Strode Sir Richard Ford Archibald Clyncard John Henley Edward Deering Edwin Wyat George Duke
Esquiers William Outrim Samuell Plummer John Cooke Sir Francis Leeke Sir Francis Lee Sir Leoline Jenkins
Thomas Fane Es&bhoqesq; Anthony Nowers Julius Deedes Edward Master Es&bhoqesq; Charles Wheeler Joseph Finch M<emph type="p">r</emph> Marsham
Es&bhoqesq; M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Gombledon Richard Merideth Es&bhoqesq; Sir George Moore Baronet William Trumbull Doctor of Lawes
Francis Head (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>) Henry Frere [Esquiers<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] Christopher Wade (<ref idref="n35">35</ref>) Richard Mathews [Gent.<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] George Pickes of
Hawkehurst Crossell Draper (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>) Edward Deering [Esquiers<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] Sir John Cutler James Codd (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>) Robert Fane (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>)
Thomas Hooper [Esquiers<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] Edmond Steed of Bidenden M<emph type="p">r</emph> Ash Sir John Cutler Knight and Baronet Sir Edward
Graves Baronet Peter Godfrey Es&bhoqesq; The Bayliffe of Rumney Marsh for the time being, The Expenditers of
Rumney Marsh for the time being John Buggin Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Fagge Baronet George Cowper Es&bhoqesq; Maior of
New Rumney for the time William Lancaster John Bryant Peter Lancaster John Shoosmith James Payne John
Hunt John Murall Gentlemen Roger Twisden Sir John Griffith Francis Wythen Sir Phillip Honywood.</para>
			<para id="p130">[Canterbury<ref idref="n36">36</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p131">For the Citty and County of Canterbury The Maior for the time being Sir Edward Master Knight Thomas
Hardresse Sergeant at Law Recorder William Mann (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>) Edward Master (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>) Edward Nutt (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>) William Kingsly [Esquiers<ref idref="n31">31</ref>]
William Stanley (<ref idref="n46">46</ref>) Thomas Ockman Alderman Squire Peverton Alderman Avery Hilles Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p132">[Lancaster<ref idref="n45">45</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p133">For the County of Lancaster Sir Robert Carr Knight and Baronet Chauncellour of the County Palatine of
Lancaster Charles of Ancram Lord Gorge William Spencer Henry Booth Esquiers Sir Richard Houghton Sir Robert
Binlos Sir Ralph Ashton of Whaley Sir Ralph Ashton of Midleton Baronets Sir Gilbert Ireland Sir Roger Bradshaigh
Sir Peter Brookes Sir Henry Slater Sir Jeoffrey Shakerley Sir John Heath Sir Edward [Chrisnwall<ref idref="n47">47</ref>] Sir William Bucknell
Sir Jervis Elwayes Knights John Mollineux Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Hesketh Richard Kirkby Richard Harrison Roger Nowell
Edward Fleetwood Christopher Banister Henry Farrington Robert Hoult Thomas Preston senior Lawrence Rawstorne
Richard Standish Nicholas Townley John Parker of Extwisley Daniell Fleming Curwin Rawlinson Thomas Bradill
Alexander Rigby of Midleton Edward Rigby Thomas Norris Christopher Parker Richard Leigh Richard Fleetwood
of Roshall Henry Slater Alexander Nowell Thomas Butler Edward Hearle John Halsted of Bankhouse [Es&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] Major
John Byrom Robert Heywood Robert Hesketh James Duckinfeild John Entwisley John Risley Thomas Latham
Jeoffrey Holcroft Edward Ogle Henry Houghton Miles Dodding John [Atway<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] Thomas Ashton William Hulton
Thomas Greenhalgh William Hulme William Kirkby William Banks William Daniell Ambrose Pudsey Thomas
Ashhurst Alexander Rigby of Layton Alexander Rigby of Aspell Edward [Dodson<ref idref="n49">49</ref>] Alen Pricket John Hartley
Thomas Bispham George Leigh of Barton John Crosse of Crosse-hall John Shalcrosse Josuah Radcliffe Alexander
Butterworth Collonell John Birch of Ordsall Stephen Radley Peter Addington Esquiers Thomas Preston junior
Thomas Holt junior James Chetham William Worthington William Leigh John Kirkby Thomas Leigh Roger Kenyon
Ralph Livesay Nicholas Fezakerley Captaine Longworth Gentlemen Edward Moore Es&bhoqesq; Nicholas Penington
William Leigh of Grange Thomas Turner Luke Hodkinson John Greenwood Francis Medcalfe William Waller
Thomas Winkley George Addison John Chaundler William Langton James Sorocold John Widdowes Thomas Patten
Jonathan Blackbourne James Peake John Tetlocke William Blackbourne Richard Parcivall Silvester Richmond Oliver
Lyme Arthur Burren Robert Birley Gabriell Garside Thomas Forster (<ref idref="n50">50</ref>) George Sharples of Freckleton (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) Thomas
Wittingham [Gentlemen<ref idref="n51">51</ref>] John Stursaker Doctor Keurden Captaine Newton The Maior of Lancaster for the time
being The Maior of Preston for the time being The Maior of Wiggon for the time being The Maior of Leverpoole
for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p134">[Leicester<ref idref="n52">52</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p135">For the County of Leicester Thomas Lord Beaumont John Lord Rosse Bennet Lord Sherrard John Grey Es&bhoqesq;
Sir George Villiers(<ref idref="n53">53</ref>) Sir Thomas Halford (<ref idref="n53">53</ref>) Sir Woolstan Dixie (<ref idref="n54">54</ref>) Sir Lewis Palmer (<ref idref="n55">55</ref>) Sir William Noell (<ref idref="n55">55</ref>)
Sir Henry Hudson [Baronets<ref idref="n56">56</ref>] Sir William Hartopp (<ref idref="n57">57</ref>) Sir Thomas Doleman [Knights<ref idref="n57">57</ref>] Sir Clement Clarke
Baronet Phillip Sherrard (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) George Faunt(<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Richard Varney (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) William Villiers (<ref idref="n59">59</ref>) Richard Lister (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) John
Fountaine (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Thomas Merry senior (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Henry Beaumont (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Thomas Boothby (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Thomas Babington (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Silus
Titus (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) S<emph type="i">t</emph> John Bennet (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) William Boothby (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) William Halford (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Samuell Jervis(<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Thomas Caldecott(<ref idref="n58">58</ref>)
Samuell Cotton (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) John Hackett (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Neale Hewett(<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Richard Brudenall (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Walter Rudeing(<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) John Crew (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>)
William Whalley (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) George Hewet (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Richard Bradgate(<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Roger Roe (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Roger Smith (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Edward Needham(<ref idref="n58">58</ref>)
Richard Orton (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) John Needham (<ref idref="n59">59</ref>) William Trimnall (<ref idref="n59">59</ref>) Robert Bernard (<ref idref="n59">59</ref>) William Bent (<ref idref="n59">59</ref>) William
Belgrave (<ref idref="n59">59</ref>) Henry Vernon (<ref idref="n59">59</ref>) George Faunte [Esquiers<ref idref="n52">52</ref>] Sir William Wale Knight Edward Abney (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) William
Skeiffinton (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Henry Hastings (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Francis Chamberlaine (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Jeremy Dove [Esquiers<ref idref="n58">58</ref>] Sir John Heath Knight
Thomas Staveley (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Henry Farnham [Esquiers.<ref idref="n58">58</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p136">[Burrough of Leicester<ref idref="n52">52</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p137">For the Burrough of Leicester The Maior for the time being Walter Rudeing Es&bhoqesq; John Herricke Gent.
Terringham Stephens Es&bhoqesq; George Reasons (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) Daniell Deacon (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) William Alsopp (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) Thomas Overing (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) William
Deane(<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) William Stubbins (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) William Maior (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) Edward Browne (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) Richard Palmer (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) Alexander Baker (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>)
Andrew Freeman [Gentlemen.<ref idref="n51">51</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p138">[Lincolne<ref idref="n52">52</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p139">For the County of Lincolne and Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne George Lord Viscount Castleton
Thomas Lord Viscount Fanshaw John Lord Rosse William Mountague William Pierpoint Esquiers Sir Humphrey
Winch Sir Henry Massingboard Sir Dreynard Massingboard Sir Christopher Wray Sir Carr Scroope Baronets Sir
John Bennet Sir Francis Goodricke Sir John Moreton Knights Rutland Sanderson William Marwood George
Sanderson Edward Merbury Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Mounson senior Sir John Booles (<ref idref="n60">60</ref>) Sir William Hickman Sir Edward Lake
Baronets William Godfrey Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Mounson junior Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Meeres Knight Sir
William Ellis Baronet Cicill Turwhit George Healy Robert Sanderson John Farmery of Northrop Edward Tourny
Esquiers Sir Edmund Wyn Baronet Sir Edward Ayscough Knight William Darwyn (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Charles Pelham [Esquiers<ref idref="n58">58</ref>] Jervas
Holles Master of Requests Charles Sanderson Es&bhoqesq; Sir William Wentworth Baronet William Broxholme (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Marmaduke
Dorrell William Bard Alexander Emerson Edward Nelthorpp John Boswell Charles Newcomen William Fitzwilliams
Esquiers Sir John Hanby Knight George Knight Charles Radley William Ballet junior Thomas Elly John Elly
Dymocke Walpoole George Neveile George Osney George Midlemoore Charles Woolley George Langton John
Ludington Christopher Pym George Willoughby Henry Masterman Thomas Hall of Ketlethorpe Henry Andrews
Esquiers William Pople Christopher Clayton John Smith of Grimsby Francis Grantham Edward Berisford Bevercotes
Cornwallis Esquiers Richard Crackroft William Hooton (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) Francis Manby Gent. M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Coventry James Harrington
Samuell Ludington Gent. Charles Anderson Es&bhoqesq; Sir Gilbert Gerrard Knight Robert Long of Kirkby Es&bhoqesq; Henry
Wornis of Hundleby(<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) William Hall of Lincolne [Gentlemen<ref idref="n51">51</ref>] Nicholas Smith of Thetlethorpe Es&bhoqesq; Sir Francis Fane.
Knight of the Bath Peregrine Barty Sir William Ellis Knight one of the Justices of the Common Bench Sir
Thomas Hussy Sir William Thorold Sir John Newton Sir Richard Rothwell Baronets Charles Dymocke Es&bhoqesq; Sir
Lewis Palmer Baronet Sir John Brownlow Sir Robert Markham Sir William Trollop Baronets Sir Thomas Orby
Sir Christopher Clapham Knights Moulineux Disney Christopher Nevill Esquiers Sir Edmund Turner Knight John
Hatcher William Lister Richard Cust John Hobson Richard Ryley [Esquiers<ref idref="n58">58</ref>] Henry Stone Anthony Williams Robert
Laming John Colehurst Gentlemen Thomas Hatcher Erasmus De ligne Thomas Harrington John Saunders William
Saville Francis Wingfeild Esquiers Stephen Rothwell Henry Hall Francis Charleton Thomas Skip with William
Hyde Anthony Tredway Esquiers Peregrine Bucke Gent. William Trollop William Welby Lister Teigh Richard
Bertie Mountague., Cholmeley John Newton Francis Stringer Richard Pell Edmond Syler [Esquiers<ref idref="n58">58</ref>] William Yorke unior Miles Long <ref idref="n51">51</ref> Austin Caudron Gent. Redman Burrell Es&bhoqesq; Edward Browne of Horblynne William Perkins
junior Miles Long (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) Austin Caudron Gent. Redman Burrell Esquire Edward Browne of Horblynne William Perkins
Thomas Grant Anthony Palmer James Trollop Gent. M<emph type="p">r</emph> Goodwell of Holliwell M<emph type="p">r</emph> Wilson of the Sheepwash
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Woodroffe of Cerby Sir Robert Carr Knight and Baronet Chauncellour of the Dutchy and County Palatine of
Lancaster Sir Henry Heron Knight of the Bath Sir Phillip Harcourt Sir Anthony Irby Knight Sir William Humble
Baronet Anthony Irby Es&bhoqesq; Charles Skipwith John Empson Joseph Whiteing (<ref idref="n61">61</ref>) Anthony Hall Adlard Welby (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) David
Bonnell [Esquiers<ref idref="n62">62</ref>] Slater Perkins Henry Burrell Israel Jackson Thomas Markhall Gentlemen Richard Milliner The
Maior of the Citty of Lincolne for the time being The fower senior Aldermen Lawrence Stamford William Couthropp
John Ayscough Christopher Ayscough Esquiers Andrew Slee John Bolt John Barnaby William Wilson The Maior
of Stamford and Great Grimsby and the Aldermen of Grantham for the time being Daniell Througood Daniell
Wigmore John Shaw Gent. John Humphris Charles Bawds Stephen Mason (<ref idref="n63">63</ref>) Daniell Rhodes [Esquiers<ref idref="n62">62</ref>] William
Byfeild Samuell Browne William Dickinson Gentlemen Anthony Butler Peter Pallar of Sutton John Butler [Esquiers<ref idref="n62">62</ref>]
Francis Johnson of Spalding Gent. Moore Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke.</para>
			<para id="p140">[London<ref idref="n64">64</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p141">For the Citty of London The Right honourable Sir Robert Hanson Knight Lord Maior and the Lord Maior for
the time being Sir William Wilde Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Chiverton Knight Sir Thomas Allen Knight and
Baronet Sir John Fredericke Knight Sir John Robinson Knight and Baronet Sir John Lawrence (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Thomas
Bludworth Sir William Peake(<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir William Turner (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Richard Ford (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Samuell Sterling (<ref idref="n66">66</ref>) Sir George
Waterman [Knights<ref idref="n65">65</ref>] Sir John Howell Knight Recorder and the Recorder for the time being Sir William
Hooker Knight Sir Robert Viner Knight and Baronet Sir Joseph Sheldon (<ref idref="n66">66</ref>) Sir Dennis Gauden (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Thomas
Davis [Knights<ref idref="n66">66</ref>] Alderman John Forthe Sir Francis Chaplin (<ref idref="n66">66</ref>) Sir John Smith [Knights<ref idref="n66">66</ref>] Sir James Edwards
Knight Alderman Dannett Forth Alderman Patience Ward Sir Robert Clayton (<ref idref="n66">66</ref>) Sir John Moore (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir William
Pritchard(<ref idref="n66">66</ref>) Sir James Smith (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir William Thompson (<ref idref="n66">66</ref>) Sir Theophilus Biddolph (<ref idref="n66">66</ref>) Sir Thomas Player (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>)
Sir William Bucknall [Knights<ref idref="n66">66</ref>] John Jolliffe (<ref idref="n62">62</ref>) Henry Dunstar (<ref idref="n67">67</ref>) William Love (<ref idref="n62">62</ref>) John Jones (<ref idref="n62">62</ref>) Edward
Waldoe (<ref idref="n62">62</ref>) John Bence (<ref idref="n62">62</ref>) George Jeoffryes (<ref idref="n62">62</ref>) William Lluellyn [Esquiers<ref idref="n62">62</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> Jasper Churchill Sir Phillip
Mathewes Baronet Richard Mills Treasurer of Saint Bartholimews Hospitall Erasmus Smith Edward Arris (<ref idref="n62">62</ref>) James
Hayes [Esquiers<ref idref="n62">62</ref>] William Gibbons Gent. Edward Dudson Es&bhoqesq; M<emph type="p">r</emph> George Nicholas Sir Arthur Ingram Sir Andrew
King M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Short.</para>
			<para id="p142">[Midlesex<ref idref="n64">64</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p143">For the County of Midlesex Edward Seymour Es&bhoqesq; Speaker of the House of Commons Sir George Carteret
Knight and Baronet Vice Chamberlaine of his Majestyes Household Henry Coventry one of the Principall Secretaryes
of State Sir John Duncombe Knight Sir Robert Carr Knight and Baronet Chauncellour of the Dutchy of Lancaster
Sir Thomas Osborne Baronet Treasurer of his Majestyes Navy Sir Mathew Hale Lord Cheife Justice of the Kings
Bench Sir Harbotle Grimston Baronet Master of the Rolls Sir John Vaughan Lord Cheife Justice of the Common
Pleas Sir Edward Turner Knight Lord Cheife Baron Sir Thomas Twisden Baronet one of the Justices of the [Kings<ref idref="n68">68</ref>]
Bench Sir Christopher Turnor Knight one of the Barons of the Exchequer Sir Richard Rainsford Knight one of the
Justices of the Kings Bench Sir William Wilde Knight and Baronet one of the Justices of the Kings Bench Sir
Timothy Litleton Knight one of the Barons of the Exchequer Sir Hugh Windham Knight one of the Justices of
the Common Pleas Sir Robert Atkins Knight of the Bath one of the Justices of the Common Pleas Sir William
Ellis Knight one of the Justices of the C&bhooov;mon Pleas George Mountague Henry Brunkard Edward Grave Thomas
Killigrew Edward Progers Esquiers Sir William Hicks Baronet Sir Francis Gerrard Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas
Litleton Baronet Sir John Mainard Knight one of his Majestyes [Sergeants<ref idref="n69">69</ref>] at Law Sir Heneage Finch Knight and
Baronet [Sir<ref idref="n70">70</ref>] Majestyes Attourney Generall Sir Francis North Knight his Majestyes Sollicitor Generall William
Mountague Es&bhoqesq; one of his Majestyes Councill and Attourney Generall to the Queenes Majesty Sir William Boyer
Baronet Sir John Robinson Knight and Baronet Lieutenant of the Tower of London Sir Jeremy Whitchcott Baronet
Sir John Lowther Baronet Sir Joseph Ash Baronet Sir John Cutler Knight and Baronet Sir George Viner Knight and
Baronet Sir Reginald Foster Baronet Sir William Roberts Baronet Sir Thomas Wolstonholme Baronet Sir Phillip
Mathews Baronet Sir John Bramston Knight of the Bath Sir John Bennet Knight of the Bath Sir Edmond Windham
Knight Marshall of his Majestyes Household Sir Thomas Beverley Knight Master of Request to his Majesty Sir
Charles Harbord Knight his Majestyes Surveyour Generall Sir Edward Walker Knight Sir Anthony S<emph type="p">t</emph> Leger Sir
Charles Lee (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir William Palmer (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Thomas Allen (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Allen Apsley (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Henry Herbert (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir
John Talbot [Knights<ref idref="n65">65</ref>] Sir Fredericke Hyde Knight and Sergeant at Law to her Majestie Sir Phillip Warwicke
Knight Sir John Howell Knight Sergeant at Law Recorder of the Citty of London Sir Lancelott Lake (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir
William Poultney (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir John Baber (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir William Pecke (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Phillip Howard (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir James Smith (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir
Thomas Player (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Allen Brodericke (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Thomas Byde [Knights<ref idref="n65">65</ref>] Sir Thomas Escourt Knight one of
the Masters of Chauncery Sir Robert Hanson (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Gilbert Gerrard of Harrow Sir James Norffolke (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>)
Sir Paul Whitchcott (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir James Griffith (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir George Churnucke (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Christopher Eyres (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Robert
Southwell (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Phillip Froud (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Thomas Foster (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Thomas Offley (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Jeremy Smith Sir John
Ernly Sir Edwin Rich Sir Robert Peyton Sir Edmond Godffrey Sir William Bowles (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Sir Thomas Stringer Sir
John James Sir John Churchill Sir Thomas Lake Sir Edward Rich Sir Joseph Williamson Sir James Butler Knights
Christopher Wrenn Doctor of [Lawes <ref idref="n71">71</ref>] Surveyour of his Majestyes Workes Sir William Bucknell Knight Daniell
Finch Humphrey Weld William Ashburnham George Pitt Francis Lucy Charles Cheney, George Marsh Charles
Bennet Francis Crawley Henry Barker Clerke of the Crowne John Phillip one of his Majestyes Auditors of the
Exchequer John Tippet George Walsh Mathew Bluck William Barker Roger-Jenning John Bill Thomas Midleton
Samuell Pepes William Peacock Nicholas Townley William Wordour Joseph Ayliffe Thomas Bayles Nicholas
Raynton Ralph Hawtrey Thomas Roe Thomas Robinson Humphrey Worley Thomas Collet John [Carew <ref idref="n72">72</ref>] Thomas
Povey Robert Filmore James Clithero Richard Dunton Thomas Rosse John Hawtrey Edward Walcop Richard
Adams Charles Pitfeild Henry Hawley James Smith Henry Elwayes William Goldsburrough Thomas Thomlins
John Harvey John Ball William Glascocke Martin Clifford Henry Revell Richard Lightfoote Richard Mountney
George Hill John Baker Lawrence Squib William Wood Henry Hodges Leonard Hammond Christopher Blake
Peter Sabbs John Swanley Richard Bayly Josias Ricroft John Jones Richard Morley Charles Cornwallis Esquiers
Sir Cerill Witch Sir Edward Massey junior Knight Sir John Barnard Baronet Sir Richard Francklin Knight and
Baronet Pawlet S<emph type="p">t</emph> John (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) John Wolstenholme [Esquiers<ref idref="n73">73</ref>] Francis Bramston Sergeant at Law Sir William Smith
Baronet Thomas Owen (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) William Wogan (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) Daniell Waldoe (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) Edward Waldoe (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) John Thorpe [Esquiers<ref idref="n74">74</ref>]
Sir Richard Napier Knight Thomas Napier Es&bhoqesq; Sir William Bolton Knight Richard Harrison Es&bhoqesq; Symon Smith (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>)
George Day John Paulford Erasmus Smith John Pawlet John Jolliffe John Lloyd Richard Cheney William Fenn
Jasper Churchill Charles Hencocke Anthony Collins (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) Henry Collins (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) William Northy (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) Edward Pecke
[Esquiers<ref idref="n73">73</ref>] John Walker Gent. Roger Gardiner (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) Roger Stoughton [Esquiers<ref idref="n73">73</ref>] Lord Cornbury Sir John
Berkenhead Thomas Aram John Watts Richard Morley Henry Slingsby [Esquiers<ref idref="n73">73</ref>] Sir Theodore De Vaux Sir
Gilbert Talbot Sir Edward Low Robert Blaney (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) Edward Leigh [Esquiers<ref idref="n73">73</ref>] Josua Beal.</para>
			<para id="p144">[Westminster<ref idref="n75">75</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p145">For the Citty and Liberty of Westminster Lord Clifford Lord Cornbury George Mountague Es&bhoqesq; Sir Heneage
Finch Sir Kingsmill Lucy Sir John Nicholas Sir Allen Apsley Peregrine Barty Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Litleton Sir Robert
Long Sir Edward Massey Sir Thomas Osborne Sir John Bennett Sir Thomas Clarges Sir Phillip Warwicke Sir
Richard Everard Sir Joseph Williamson Sir Michaell Heneage Sir Phillip Howard Sir Edmond Windham Sir Edmond
Pye Sir Edward Carteret Sir Edward Greaves Sir Phillip Mathews Sir John Duncombe Sir [Robert<ref idref="n76">76</ref>] Carr Sir Theodore
de Vaux Sir Edward Brett Sir Phillip Meadowes Sir John Griffith Sir Francis Holles Sir Charles Harboard Sir John
Copleston Sir Phillip Froude Sir George Downing Sir William Doyley senior Sir John Talbot Sir William Doyley
junior Sir Henry Herbert Sir Robert Pye Sir Thomas Meeres Sir Anthony Irby Sir John Cotton Do&bholigct;or (<ref idref="n77">77</ref>) Shalmer
Sir James Smith Sir Cerill Wich Sir John Cutler Sir John Baber Sir Richard Mason Sir John Birkenhead Sir
Thomas Woodcocke Sir William Poultney Sir Gilbert Gerrard Baronet Sir Ralph Banks Do&bholigct;or Thomas Sydenham
David Walter (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) Henry Brunkard William Ashburnham (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) Charles Cornwallis Daniell Finch Phillip Packer Edmond
Waller George Nicholas Daniell Sheldon William Harboard John Tregonwell Reynald Graham Thomas Thinne Thomas
Morrice Charles Bennet Edmond Warcup Richard Stevens Thomas Owen Mathew Locke John Browne John Ferres
Justinion Paget Richard Cateline William Dolbin Lawrence Squibb Richard Newman Phillip Lloyd Francis Lucy
Thomas Bailes Edward Griffin John Currance William Glascocke Robert Filmer Adlard Welby Richard Sherwin
Job Williams George Farwell [Esquiers<ref idref="n73">73</ref>] Do&bholigct;or Samuell Barrow Doctor Christopher Wrenn Hugh May Walter Brydall
Bevis Lloyd Symon Smith John Mann Richard Pagett Thomas Morris Michaell Brighouse Lancelot Thornton
Captaine Boheye Hugh Squire John Baynes Henry Pecke Anthony Samwell Emery Hill Humphrey Wirley George
Hill Roger Higgs John Russell Thomas Hawood William Wardour Richard Morley Do&bholigct;or (<ref idref="n77">77</ref>) Shalmer Edward Clarke
Thomas Bayly Robert Harcourt John Walker Thomas Russell Do&bholigct;or Barwicke William Lloyd William Morgan
Do&bholigct;or Benjamin Worsley Butler Kinkead David Lloyd John Clutterbuck Nicholas Baxter Thomas Crumpe John
Ball Do&bholigct;or John Clarke Esquiers William Blake Jasper Churchill John Chase William Gape George Cowper Phillip
Hanbury Ambrose Scudamore John Jeffs Richard Bull John Minchen John Leeson Bryan Barnaby Michaell Arnold
George Plucknet John Sibley Nicholas Edlin Norris Hunt Thomas Halfepenny Richard Mill Thomas Tyndall
Humphrey Grinsall John Greene Nehemiah Arnold William Brewer Ralph Halsey John Tyson of the Citty of
Westminster Miles Mitchell Richard Farthing Christopher Sheene John Francis William Wheeler Peter [Griffits<ref idref="n78">78</ref>]
Charles Rampaine William Austin John Fisher Samuell Baker Morrice Kingswell William Hargrave Thomas Butler
Edmond Doyley Henry Mountague John [Kockier<ref idref="n79">79</ref>] Gent. John Watts [Es&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n80">80</ref>] Bartholomew Vermeuden Sir Gilbert
Tolbott Robert Blaney (<ref idref="n73">73</ref>) Henry Slingsby [Esquiers<ref idref="n73">73</ref>] Robert Harcourt Sir Robert Peyton M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Crurnp.</para>
			<para id="p146">[Tower Division.<ref idref="n75">75</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p147">For the Tower Division in the County of Midlesex Sir Edward Massey junior Sir Thomas Marsh Richard
Cheney Joseph Cowden Richard Winckle Nathaniell Hancocke Robert Holden Richard Bolt John Friend John
Sharpe Edward Alsop John Foster Richard Bayly Esquiers John Forth Dannet Forth Aldermen Richard Powell
Robert Staneere Joshua Beale Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p148">[Monmouth<ref idref="n75">75</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p149">For Monmouth Charles Lord Herbert of Ragland James Herbert Gentleman Sir Baynham Throckmorton (<ref idref="n81">81</ref>) Sir
Edward Morgan (<ref idref="n81">81</ref>) Sir Charles Kemeys (<ref idref="n81">81</ref>) Sir Trevor Williams (<ref idref="n81">81</ref>) Sir Thomas Morgan [Baronets<ref idref="n81">81</ref>] Sir George Probert
Knight William Morgan Es&bhoqesq; Edward Lewis Edmond Thomas Trevor Williams Henry Probert Edward Progers Thomas
Lewis Charles Van James Herbert John Arnold Thomas Morgan of Lammuny Thomas Folio Collonell Progers
William Kemeys Edmond Morgan of Penloynsarth Thomas Morgan of Penrose Herbert Evans David Lewis Charles
Price Charles Hughes William Herbert Henry Milbourne Edmond Gamege Edmond Jones Henry Baker William
Jones Richard Lister George Kemis of Lanvare Esquiers Roger Oates Nicholas Kemeis Collonell William Morgan
John Mathewes Walter Rumsey Thomas Pritchard Charles Milbourne John Walter of Peirsfeild Edward Williams
Roger Williams Thomas Herbert Capell Hanbury Thomas Jones of Hurst William Blethin Thomas Isaacke James
Morgan John Rumsey Phillip Cicill William Herbert Barrister at Law Esquiers Trevor Morgan of Bedwelty Gent.
Edward Kemeys of Berthley Henry Chambers John Lewis of Upton Hill David Morgan of Llanwenarth Walter Evans
of Llangottocke (<ref idref="n82">82</ref>) Lewis Morgan Robert Gunter John Walter of Howick John Grenoph John Katchmey John Rumsey
of Wollesnewton Walter Jones of Megar Charles Morgan of Llangattocke Linwed Gent. George Kemeis Rowland
Williams William Williams of Carlion John Bird John Flere William Lewis of Llanellyn Walter Adley Rodericke
Guin Henry Rumsey Ezra Waters Thomas Powell Robert Jones Nicholas Parker Thomas Morgan of Riscah Andrew
Probert Herbert Jones George Harris Thomas Jones of Treathin William Evans Gentlemen The Maior of Monmouth
for the time being The Maior of Newport for the time being Phillip Jones James [Jones<ref idref="n83">83</ref>] James Prichard Francis
Spalding John Curr Thomas Springet Thomas Wroth Daniell Price Charles Williams Giles Morgan Theophilus
Reynolds Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p150">[County of Northampton<ref idref="n84">84</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p151">For the County of Northampton Obryan Viscount Cullen of the Kingdome of Ireland Henry Lord Obryan Baron
of Ibrican of the same Kingdome. William Lord Fitzwilliams of the same Kingdome Sir Francis Compton George
Mountague Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Crew Knight Robert Spencer Es&bhoqesq; Sir Richard Rainsford Knight one of the Justices
of the Kings Bench Sir Justinian Isham Sir Roger Norwich Sir Samuell Danvers Sir William Farmour Baronets
Sir Edward Nicholas Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Griffin Sir John Robinson Sir William Wake Sir John Holman
Baronets Sir William Fleetwood Sir John Bernard Sir William Haslewood Knights Sir James Langham Knight and
Baronet Sir Edward Alston John Beaumont Miles Fleetewood Edward Griffin Francis Lane Henry Stafford George
Clerke William Alston John [Parkhurst<ref idref="n85">85</ref>] William [Harbord<ref idref="n83">83</ref>] Goddard Pemberton John Browne Edward Hales
Thomas Chubnall [Esquiers<ref idref="n86">86</ref>] George Wake Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Lawrence Manley William Chestes William Saunders
Thomas Trist Thomas Elmes Toby Cheney Thomas Catisby Richard Rainsford Samuell Trist William Washbourne
[Esquiers<ref idref="n86">86</ref>] Sir William Craven Knight Sir Heneage Finch Knight and Baronet His Majestyes Attourney Generall and
Sir Francis North Knight His Majestyes Sollicitor Generall Sir Vere Fane Knight Devereux Knightley Es&bhoqesq; Sir William
Langham Knight Sir John Cartwright William Tate George Tresham Edward Harbey junior William Adams John
Colly Henry Benson Richard Saltenstall Maximilian Emersley Edward Palmer John Creswell Henry Edmund Robert
Clerke William Buckby Es&bhoqesq; Sir William Pargister Sir Samuell Clerke [Kn[igh]ts<ref idref="n87">87</ref>] Tanfeild Mulsho Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Pickering
Baronet Bryon [Johnson<ref idref="n88">88</ref>] Anthony Shugburgh Walter Kirkham Michaell Woodhall John Thornton John Willoughby
John Bagshaw William Warner of Lubnam William Lisle Christopher Thursby Andrew Lane Francis Morgan
Alexander Eakens Thomas Rhoane Thomas Jennisan William Ward John Lluyn George Delavall William Leavins
Thomas Neale Nicholas Steuart John Gardiner John Wiseman Es&bhoqesq; The Maior of Northampton for the time being
John Braffeild Richard Massingburgh Francis Pickmer Joseph Sergant William Vaughan Hatton Farmer Joseph
Hensman John Howes Robert Ives Henry Flaxon The Maior of Higham for the time being The Bayliffe of
Daventree for the time being The Maior of Brackley for the time being Henry Lucas Thomas Dove John Bourne
Richard Butler Edmond Sawyer Jeremiah Dove Salathiell Lovell John Bridges William Thursby John Hanbury
Richard Rives Francis Crane Thomas Cole William Puge Georges Quarles Es&bhoqesq; Edward Mountague William
Mountague Es&bhoqesq; Her Majestyes Attourney Generall Henry Edmonds Es&bhoqesq; Joseph Hanes Phillip Lord Viscount Wenman
of the Kingdome of Ireland.</para>
			<para id="p152">[Nottingham<ref idref="n84">84</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p153">For the County of Nottingham and the Towne and County of the same Henry Earle of Ogle Patricius Viscount
Chaworth of the Kingdome of Ireland Anchitell Gray William Pierpoint Arthur Stanhop William Byron Esquiers
Sir Francis Mullineux Knight and Baronet Sir Francis Leeke Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Williamson Sir
William Hickman Sir Edward Nevill Knights Francis Leeke Robert Pierpoint Cecill Cooper Francis Sandis John
Grubham How William Palmes Thomas Perkins William Cartwright John Thornaugh William Leeke William
Sacheverell William Stanhop Charles Hutchingson Thomas Marshall William Skevington Peniston Whalley Francis
Stringer George Nevill Arthur Warren senior Arthur Warren junior Thomas Charlton senior Rason Mellish Anthony
Gilby Thomas Wowen John Millington John [Rouston<ref idref="n89">89</ref>] Samuell Sandys senior John Yarborough Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke
James Lane John Nevill Gentlemen, The High Sheriffe for the County of Nottingham for the time being, The
Maior of Nottingham for the time being The Bayliffes of East-Redford for the time being John Thynne Thomas
Shipman [Gentlemen<ref idref="n90">90</ref>] The Maior of Newarke for the time being Edward Ward Mathew Jennison Samuell Ellis
Anthony Collingwood John Douglasse William Welby [Godard<ref idref="n90">90</ref>] Dye John Gerton senior Gent. Daniell Earle Thomas
Lewis Jarvis Piggot Esquiers Sir Scroope Grubham How Knight William Cartwright of Normanton Richard Slater
John Digby Rowland Dand John Dand William Cartwright junior John Hacker of Flintham John Hacker of Trowell
Henry Plumtree Richard Mansfeild Harvey Staunton Thomas Charlton junior George Gregory Thomas Rossell
Lindley of Skegby Esquiers Robert Thoroton Doctor in Phisick Peter Broughton William Newton
Garvas Holland Anthony Tate Charles Lacock George Chamberlaine Gentlemen Ralph Edge Christopher Hall
William Greaves John Parker Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p154">[County of Norffolke<ref idref="n84">84</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p155">For the County of Norffolke Sir Edward Turner Knight Lord Cheife Baron of His Majestyes Exchequer Thomas
Lord Richardson Baron Cramond of the Kingdome of Scotland Lord Fitzwilliams of the Kingdome of Ireland
Sir Edmond Bacon Sir John Hobart Sir Phillip Woodhouse Sir Edward Barkham Sir John Hollond Sir Robert
Paston Sir Augustine Palgrave Sir John Potts Sir Robert Kempe Sir Jacob Astley Sir Edward Ward Sir Henry
Deerham Sir William Cooke Sir William Doyley Sir Peter Gleene Sir Francis Bickley Sir Thomas Garrett Sir
John Pettus Sir William Adams Baronets Edward Progers Sir John Knivet Sir John Bennet Sir Christopher
Calthorp Knights of the Bath Sir Charles Herbord Sir Allen Apsley Sir William Doyley junior Sir Nevill Catlin
Sir Thomas Meadow Sir John Bladwell Sir Robert Baldock Sir William Rant Knights Herbert Astley Deane of
Norwich Robert Cooke Sir John Davis Knight Robert Walpoole John Potts William Windham Thomas Hollond
William Cooke Roger Potts Thomas Townshend Lestrange Calthropp Philip Harbord John Hubbard Robert Long
Roger Spilman Edward Barber Esquiers William de Gray Robert Suckling Francis Guybon William Rant Francis
Bacon Thomas Bacon Robert London Oliver Neve Thomas Gaudy of Claxton Robert Day Edmund Doyly John
Herbert Suckling Jay Francis Lane Jacob Preston Phillip Bedingfeild Humphrey Bedingfeild Robert Gawsell
Anthony Fisher Robert Houghton Robert Coney Francis Bell Charles Wrenn Laurence Oxburrough Richard
Godfrey Nicholas Rookwood Edmond Britiffe [Simon Brittiffe<ref idref="n92">92</ref>] Thomas Berney of Swarson John Anguish John
Fisher Robert Tyrrell of Wilton Christopher Crow Munford Spilman Clement Spilman Leonard Mapes Edward
Ward Lemuel Shouldam Edward de Grey Anthony [Duary<ref idref="n93">93</ref>] Nicholas Wilton Hatton Berners Thomas Thursby
Francis Thursby George Townshend Gascoyne Wild of Bracon Leonard Googe John Warner Anthony Freeston.
Francis Cory Christopher Jay Clement Sterne John Cocke Thomas Browne of Elsing Thomas Corey Thomas
Talbott Robert Buxton Thomas Wright of Ovington William Brantwaighte William Cropley William Armiger of
North-Crake Nicholas Hamond John Le-Strange Edmond Woodhouse Thomas Richmond William Marsham Esquiers
Do&bholigct;or Owen Hughes Peter Daymond M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Harby Richard Marriet John Richmond of Headingham Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p156">[Kings Lynne<ref idref="n94">94</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p157">For the Towne of Kings Lynne The Maior for the time being Henry Ferrour Es&bhoqesq; Seth [Howley<ref idref="n95">95</ref>] Thomas
Greene Benjamin Holly Henry Bell Thomas Robinson Edmond Abbot Daniell Goodwin Mathias Twelves John
Hamond Symon Taylor Edward Bromley Arthur Evelyn Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p158">[Great Yarmouth<ref idref="n94">94</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p159">For Great Yarmouth Sir Thomas Meadow Sir James Johnson Sir George England Knights Thomas Pufflet John
Cubit Richard Jarmin John Hall Abraham Castell Thomas Gooch Nathaniel Ashley John Rowe John Woodroffe
Edmond Thaxter Arthur Bacon William Huntington Peter Caulier Thomas Cooper Mitchell Mew Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p160">[Thetford<ref idref="n94">94</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p161">For Thetford The Maior for the time being Sir John Hollond Baronet Sir Phillip Woodhouse Baronet Sir Allen
Apsley Knight Sir Joseph Williamson Knight William Cropley Es&bhoqesq; Burrey Martin Robert Tyrrell. John Grine
Hatterset.</para>
			<para id="p162">[City of Norwich<ref idref="n94">94</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p163">For the Citty of Norwich The Maior for the time being Thomas Lord Richardson Sir John Hobart Knight and
Baronet Sir Thomas Browne Knight Francis Cory Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Francis Bacon Christopher Jay Herbert Astley
Deane of Norwich Henry Watts John Rayley Bernard Church John Man John Salter Richard Wenman John
Osborne John Croshold The two Sheriffes for the time being Augustine Briggs Thomas Wisse Robert Bendish
Richard Cold ham John Lawrence Henry Herne Francis Norris Mathew Markham John Manser Henry Wood
Henry Watts junior Richard Wenman junior Thomas Thaxer Thomas Chickering Aldermen John Hobart Francis
Norris Thomas Bacon Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p164">[Northumberland<ref idref="n94">94</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p165">For the County of Northumberland Henry Earle of Ogle Edward Lord Morpeth Ralph Grey of Chillingham
Collonell Edward Grey Sir William Fenwicke Sir Ralph Delavall (<ref idref="n96">96</ref>) Sir Cuthbert Heron [Baronets<ref idref="n96">96</ref>] Sir William
Forster Sir George Dowing Sir Richard Stote Collonell Edward Villiers Ralph Jennison Daniell Collingwood Thomas
Forster William Strother Ralph Heabron William Widdrington John Clarke John Salkeild Thomas Bewick
William Delavall of Dissington John Ridley of Hardriding Nicholas Whitehead William Warren Robert Widdrington
of Haxley John Fenwicke Robert Delavall Humphrey Mitford Robert Mitford John Grey Thomas Burrell of Browne
Parke The Bayliffe of Morpeth for the time being Thomas Collingwood of Rile.</para>
			<para id="p166">[Berwicke upon Tweede<ref idref="n94">94</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p167">For the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweed Sir Richard Stote Recorder Elias Pratt The Maior for the time being
Edward Grey Daniell Collingwood Thomas Watson Ralph Hebron Marke Scott M<emph type="p">r</emph> Winloe M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edmiston James
Cotterell M<emph type="p">r</emph> Counton Joseph Jackson Edward Nelson Roger Weddell Stephen Jackson.</para>
			<para id="p168">[Towne of Newcastle<ref idref="n94">94</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p169">For the Towne of Newcastle upon Tyne The Maior for the time being Sir John Marley Sir Francis Anderson Sir
Robert Shaftoe Recorder Sir Richard Stote Marke Milbanke Anthony Isaackson John Emerson William Blacket
Henry Maddison Henry Brabant Thomas Davison William Carr Ralph Grey John Clerke Robert Morley Es&bhoqesq;
John Blackston Edward Villiers and the Sheriffe for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p170">[Oxon<ref idref="n97">97</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p171">For the County of Oxon Phillip Lord Wenman Viscount Tuam Henry Lord Cornbury Phillip Lord Wenman
James Herbert Es&bhoqesq; Sir William Coventry Sir Anthony Cope Sir Thomas Spencer Sir Thomas Penniston Sir William
Walter Sir Compton Reede Sir William Glynn Sir Edmond Fettiplace Sir Francis Wenman Sir Litleton Osbaldston
Sir Anthony Craven Sir Robert Jenkinson Sir Thomas Chamberlaine Sir John Robinson Barronet Sir Thomas
Clayton Warden of Mertin Colledge Sir John Holman Barronet Sir William Fleetwood Sir Tymothy Terrell Sir
Edmond Bray Sir Thomas Typping Sir Edward Norris Sir Henry Jones Sir Allen Apsley Sir George Croke Sir
Phillip Harcourt Sir Edward Hungerford Knight of the Bath Sir Richard Temple Sir John Doyley Sir Thomas Cobb
Baronet Sir Llewellin Jenkins Sir William Coventry Broome Whorwood Es&bhoqesq; Richard Croke William Cope James
Hyde Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Anthony Libb Vincent Barrey Henry Alnutt John Stone Francis Martin John Clarke
William Lenthall William Dormer John Cartwright Henry Heylin Es&bhoqesq; George Chamberlaine William Cartwright
Arthur Jones Henry Alworth Do&bholigct;or of Law William Walter David Walter one of the Groomes of His Majestyes
Bedchamber Richard Halloway Councellour at Law Robert Dormer Reynald Bray William Bayley Thomas Hoard
John Croke Samuell Sandys Junior Es&bhoqesq; Charles Holloway Sergeant at Law George Cole Es&bhoqesq; Charles Holloway
Thomas Coventry Do&bholigct;or Mathew Skinner Robert Wither Steward of New Colledge William Gannocke George
Woodward M<emph type="p">r</emph> Sheppard of Roleright Robert Perrot junior Edward Vernon John West William Oakley Esquire
William Wright John Wickham M<emph type="p">r</emph> (<ref idref="n98">98</ref>) Blague of Coggs John Gore Es&bhoqesq; James Perrot junior of Northly John Gunne
Es&bhoqesq; Bartholimew Harris (<ref idref="n99">99</ref>) Richard Stevens Gent. Edward Warcup (<ref idref="n100">100</ref>) Thomas Worwood (<ref idref="n100">100</ref>) Richard Powell
[Esquiers<ref idref="n99">99</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Lenthall George Pudsey (<ref idref="n100">100</ref>) William Whitlocke (<ref idref="n100">100</ref>) Bartholimew Hall [Esquiers<ref idref="n100">100</ref>] Henry Hall
Gent. Robert Knolles (<ref idref="n101">101</ref>) Thomas Coghill [Esquiers<ref idref="n100">100</ref>] Puton Crocke Gent. Robert Parsons; (<ref idref="n99">99</ref>) Gilbert Jackson
[Gentlemen<ref idref="n99">99</ref>] The Major of Woodstocke for the time being, The Maior of Banbury, The Warden of Henley, The
Bayliffes of Burford and Chipping Norton, and the Cheife Magistrates to act in their severall Corporations onely.</para>
			<para id="p172">[University of Oxford<ref idref="n97">97</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p173">For the University of Oxford The Vice [Chauncellours<ref idref="n102">102</ref>] and Pro&bholigct;ors for the time being Sir Thomas Clayton
Knight Do&bholigct;or Thomas Yates Do&bholigct;or Thomas Barlow Do&bholigct;or Robert Say Do&bholigct;or John Fell Do&bholigct;or Thomas James
Do&bholigct;or Tully Do&bholigct;or John Wallis Do&bholigct;or Ralph Bathurst Do&bholigct;or James Hyde Do&bholigct;or Clarke Do&bholigct;or John Lamphere
Do&bholigct;or Lyddall Richard Holloway Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Tudor Mathew Loveday Richard Plydall John Hopkins Thomas
Rowney Gent. M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Withers.</para>
			<para id="p174">[Citty of Oxford<ref idref="n97">97</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p175">For the Citty of Oxford The Maior of the said Citty for the time being Broome Whorwood Esquire, Francis
Wenman Richard Croke Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Sir Anthony Cope George Lowe Es&bhoqesq; Sir Sampson White Knight William
Wright (<ref idref="n99">99</ref>) Roger Griffin (<ref idref="n99">99</ref>) William Bayly (<ref idref="n99">99</ref>) John Harris Gent. Aldermen John Lamb John Townsend Francis
Greenaway William Cornish Francis [Heywood<ref idref="n103">103</ref>] John Zouch William Walker and Anthony Hall Gentlemen,
John Paynton Gentleman Towne-Clerke Robert Whorwood and Peter Langston Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p176">[Rutland<ref idref="n97">97</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p177">For the County of Rutland Bennet Lord Sherrard Henry Noell and Phillip Sherrard Esquiers Sir Thomas
Mackworth and Sir. Abell Barker Baronets Sir Thomas Fanshaw George Benion Es&bhoqesq; Richard Wingfeild of Tickingcote
Samuell Browne Christopher Browne Edward Paulkner and Andrew Noell Esquiers William Colby Gent. Anthony
Palmer Robert Mackworth Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p178">[Salop<ref idref="n97">97</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p179">For the County of Salop William Pierpoint Richard Newport and Andrew Newport Esquiers Sir Henry Litleton
Sir Henry Fredericke Thynne Sir Humphrey Briggs Sir William Whitmore Sir John Corbet Sir Francis Lawley Sir
Vincent Corbet Sir Richard Corbet Sir Francis Edwards Sir Edward A&bholigct;ion Sir Henry. Vernon Sir Thomas Litleton
and Sir Clement Clarke Baronets Sir Thomas Whitmore Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Herbert Sir John Weld Sir
Job Charlton Sir Tymothy Litleton Sir William Childe Sir Timothy Turnor Sir John Trevor Sir Richard Mason Sir
Thomas Jones and Sir Samuell Baldwin Knights Leveson Gore Richard Screven Richard Fowler Francis Charlton
Charles Manwaring Francis Thornes Francis Forrester Richard Lister Edward Kineston of Oatley Edward Kineston
of Aberclee Roger Kineston Thomas Baldwin Charles Baldwin Phillip Prince Thomas Owen of Londover John
Wolrich Thomas Thornes Richard Herbert John Walcott Thomas Whitmore Thomas Thynne George Weld George
Ludlow Thomas Rocke William Owen Somerset Fox Robert Corbett of the Hall of Hussey John Coates William
Oakley Edmund Wareing of Owldbury Robert Leighton Adam Oatley Thomas Walcott Robert Cressett Robert
Owen Roger Pope Thomas Lloyed Richard Creswell John Lacon William Williams Vincent Edwards Thomas
Oateley Litleton Powis Thomas Crumpe George Whitmore Richard More John Newton Thomas Kinersley of Badger
William Cotton Thomas A&bholigct;ion William Jones of Sandford Thomas Hill Thomas Ireland Henry Griffiths Edward Vernon
Henry Davenport Henry Mitton of Shipton Rowland Nicholls Edward Luttige Es&bhoqesq; Corbett of Stanerdine
Richard Cowling Thomas Smalman James Becke Es&bhoqesq; Owen Barton Roger Evans Richard Pope Lingen Toppe
Rockley Prince Thomas Owen of Dinthurst Thomas Latchard Richard Charlton Henry Spratt Thomas Lochier John
Wood Thomas Jobber Henry Langley Richard Corbett The Maior of Salopp for the time being The Bayliffes of
Ludlow Bridgenorth Wenlocke and Bishops-Castle for the time being Thomas Cornwall Es&bhoqesq; Bevis Lloyd Daniell
Wicherley Francis Smith Robert Smith Herbert of Wootton John Tayler John Whitacre Richard Clarke
Samuell Lloyd Richard Tayler Arthur Hinkes Alexander Midleton George Hosier Roger Gough Edward Owen
Roger Griffiths Gosnall Edward Wollaston Richard Davis of Ludlow Thomas Jones of Sheete Thomas
Mason of Rockley Richard Wareing Andrew Hill Richard Pritchard Roger Harris Robert Vernon Richard Davis
of Whitchurch William Gravenor Richard Jenkins John Stannier Henry Powell Rowland Midleton William Owen
of Whitle Edward Pooley John Bright.</para>
			<para id="p180">[Stafford<ref idref="n104">104</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p181">For the County of Stafford Sir Thomas Wilbraham Sir Edward Bagott Sir Edward Litleton Sir Charles Woolsey
Sir Walter Wrotesley Sir Francis Lawley Baronet Sir Bryan Broughton Sir Theophilus Biddolph Knights and Baronets
Sir John Wirley Sir Thomas Whitgreve Sir Rowland Oliver Sir Henry Archbole Knights Randolph Egerton Henry
Grey Walter Chetwind Edward Litleton William Snead Robert Milward George Digby Edward Mainwaring Brome
Whorwood Robert Levison Thomas Lane Richard Dyott Walter Litleton William Chetwind Charles Cotton Richard
Congreave Edward Vernon Thomas Kinnersley John Swinfin Ralph Sneid Edwyn Skrinshier Henry Vernon Rowland
Cotton Daniell Watson Charles Agard Francis Wightwicke Jonathan Woodnoth John Pyott Thomas Rudiard Edward
Arablaster George Parker Henry Gough Edward Birch William Whitby John Noble Nicholas Hurte Edward Mooreton
John Whiteall William Parker Ferrers Fulke Esquiers The Maior of Stafford and Newcastle under Lyne for the
time being The Bayliffes of Tamworth for the time being William Trafford Walter Fowler Zachariah Babington
Thomas Palmer Thomas Bagnald Thomas Scott Richard Bracegirdle Thomas Rugeley Thomas Villers Leicester
Barber Sampson Birch Timothy Edge John Felton Sir John Bowyer Knight William Ward Esquire George Legg.</para>
			<para id="p182">[Lichfeild<ref idref="n104">104</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p183">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Lichfeild [Sir<ref idref="n105">105</ref>] Simon Martin Bayliffe The Bayliffe and Sheriffe for the
time being Sir Theophilus Bydulph Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Archbold Knight Richard Dyott Walter Litleton
Daniell Watson Thomas Minors Esquiers William Wythey James Allen John Rawlins Thomas Caterbanke and
William Jesson Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p184">[Somersett<ref idref="n104">104</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p185">For the County of Somersett Edward Seymour Es&bhoqesq; Speaker of the honourable House of Commons Sir Francis
Roll Knight High Sheriffe of the County Maurice Viscount Fitzharding Francis Lord Hawley John Lord Digby
Francis Pawlet Es&bhoqesq; Sir Edmond Windham Knight Marshall [Sir<ref idref="n105">105</ref>] John Sydenham Baronet Sir William Porteman
Sir Hugh Smith Knights of the Bath and Baronets Sir William Windham Knight and Baronet Sir John Wroth
Baronet Sir John Coventry Sir Edward Hungerford Sir Francis Popham Knights of the Bath Sir George Horner
Sir Thomas Bridges Sir William Bassett Sir Thomas Gore Sir Edward Phillips Sir John Mallet Sir Stephen Foxe
Sir George Norton Sir James Hayes Sir John Churchill Sir John Coppleston Knights Edward Phillips George Speake
Ralph Stawell Peregrine Palmer Francis Windham Edward Gorges William Hellyar Edward Nevill Edward Berkley
Maurice Berkley de Yarlington Thomas Windham de Witham Esquiers Thomas Windham William Bull Henry Bull
John Dodington John Strachey Henry Bull of Midsummer-Norton John Buckland Thomas Warr Robert Hunt
Thomas Piggott Henry Waldron John Harrington Halswell Tynt William Lacy Warwicke Bampfeild Edward Bampfield
William Strode Edward Strode Thomas Strode de Maxerton Edward Clarke Henry Henley George Horner Edward
Court Richard Jones Henry Carrant John Fox Robert Hawley John Hunt Anthony Pawlet William Speake John
S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albans Henry Light Peter Roynon William Haxboard George Stedman John Prawse William Coward William
Thynne Richard Morgan William Clerke Esquiers Richard Musgrove Copleston Horton Humphrey Sydenham
Edward Fripp Richard Crosse William Orange Richard Launsdowne Charles Staynings and Joseph Langton.</para>
			<para id="p186">[Citty of Wells<ref idref="n104">104</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p187">For the Citty of Wells The Maior for the time being, The Recorder Nicholas Niblet John Day John Davidge
John Davis Francis Simmons James Clutterbucke Maurice Berkley Gent.</para>
			<para id="p188">[Towne of Bridgewater<ref idref="n104">104</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p189">For the Towne of Bridgewater The Maior for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p190">[Citty of Bath<ref idref="n104">104</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p191">For the Citty of Bath The Maior for the time being, The Recorder Walter Gibbs Henry Chapman Robert Pearce
Doctor of Phisicke John Masters Gent.</para>
			<para id="p192">[Citty of Bristoll<ref idref="n107">107</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p193">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll The Maior and Sheriffes for the time being Sir Robert
Atkins Knight of the Bath and one of the Justices of the Common Pleas Sir John Knight Sir Robert Cam Knight
and Baronet Sir Humphrey Hooke (<ref idref="n108">108</ref>) Sir Thomas Langton [Knights<ref idref="n108">108</ref>] John Lauford Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Stephens
Alderman Sir Robert Yeamans Knight and Baronet John Knight (<ref idref="n109">109</ref>) John Hicks [Esquiers<ref idref="n109">109</ref>] Richard Streamour
Aldermen Ralph Ayliffe William Crabb Richard Crump John Lloyd Joseph Creswicke Richard Harte Robert
Aldworth Thomas Jennins William Colson Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p194">[Southampton<ref idref="n107">107</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p195">For the County of Southampton Charles Lord S<emph type="p">t</emph> John of Basing William Russell Edward Noell Esquiers Sir
Robert Howard Knight Sir George Carteret Knight and Baronet Sir Robert Worsley. Sir Kingsmill Lucy Sir John
Norton Sir Hugh Stewkley Sir William Lewis Sir Robert Dillington Sir William Meux Sir Thomas Bad, Sir
Nicholas Steward Sir Andrew Henley Sir Mundeford Brampston Sir John Oglander Sir Tamworth Reresby Baronets
Sir Robert Holmes Sir Thomas Higgons Sir Robert Henley Sir Richard Knight Sir Stephen Fox Sir Francis Rolle
Sir James Woresly Sir Edward Woresly Sir John Clobery Sir Charles Windham Knights William Smith Es&bhoqesq; High
Sheriffe Richard Norton Thomas Neale Lawrence Hyde Henry Wallop Thomas Knowlis Richard Lucy John Leigh
Esquiers James Halsell Charles West Thomas Jervis John Richards Captaine George Legg Henry Whitehead George
Pitt Leonard Bilson Richard Cobbe John Hooke Thomas Cole of Lisle Phillip Leigh James May Richard Compton
Londowicke Lewis John Woolveridge Benjamin Rudyard Roger Gallop Francis Tilney Henry Bromfield Arthur Bold
Edward Norton William Wither Edward Hooper of Hurne Court Francis Dickins John Stewkley White Tichborne
Bartholimew Price Daniell Kingsmill John Kingsmill Henry Tulse Thomas Edmonds Robert Oxenbridge Robert
Goffe Richard Love Peter Bettersworth William Stephens Henry Doyley Edward Cooke John Fawlkenor John Mari
Esquiers Richard Bishop Arthur Tayler Henry Perrin William Stanley John Pawlin Gabriell Whistler John Deane
William Wall Henry Kelsey Henry Goddard Richard Ayliffe Edward Hyde John Dingley: John Mathew Thomas
Knight Thomas Urrey of Gatcombe David Urrey of Freshwater John Smith John Rives Edward Pile William
Stanley William Tulse (<ref idref="n109">109</ref>) Robert Richbell [Esquiers<ref idref="n109">109</ref>] The Maior of Portsmouth for the time being Hugh
Salisbury Phillip James Aldermen of the same William Hussey and William Goddard Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p196">[Winchester<ref idref="n107">107</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p197">For the Citty of Winchester The Maior of the said Citty for the time being Thomas Wavell Thomas Muspratt
Nicholas Purdue Edmond Fifield William Tayler William Cradocke Aldermen of the said Citty.</para>
			<para id="p198">[Southampton<ref idref="n107">107</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p199">For the Towne and County of Southampton The Maior for the time being William Stanley Robert Richbell
Thomas Cornelius James Clungeon Henry Pitt Richard White Aldermen of the said Towne and County John Speede
of the same Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke The Maior of Newport The Maior of Yarmouth The Maior of Basingstoke and
The Bayliffes of Andover for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p200">[Suffolke<ref idref="n107">107</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p201">For the County of Suffolke Lionell Lord Huntingtower Sir John Duncombe Knight Chauncellour of the Exchequer
Walter Devereux Es&bhoqesq; Sir Charles North Sir Edmond Bacon Sir Henry Felton Sir Robert Kempe Sir Henry Bacon
Sir William Spring Sir John Castleton Sir Thomas Cullum Sir [Sir<ref idref="n107">107</ref>] Jervice Elwice Sir [Robert<ref idref="n110">110</ref>] Darcie Sir Robert
Cordall Sir William Doyley Sir Thomas Barnadiston Sir Phillip Parker Sir Henry North Sir John Duke Sir Robert
Brooke Baronets Sir Charles Gaudy Sir George Reeve Sir Thomas Allen Knights and Baronets Sir Nicholas Bacon
Sir John Knivet Sir John Bennet Knights of the Bath Sir Phillip Parker Sir John Pettus Sir John Pooly Sir Thomas
Harvey Sir John Winife Sir Nevill Catelin Sir John Hanmer Sir William Bloys Sir Algernoon May Sir Thomas Smith
Sir Jeffery Burwell Sir Phillip Meadows Sir Thomas Meadowes Sir Francis Theobalds Knights John Harvey Treasurer
to Her Majesty Edward Proger Thomas Glemham Thomas Holland Thomas Walgrave senior Thomas Walgrave
junior John Cordall John Southerby William Gipps Clement Higham Benjamin Cutler of the Chauntry William
Bloys John Wright Francis Warner Thomas Stewart Robert Wright Thomas Wright Joseph Brand John Playters
Lionell Playters John Cole Robert Marryot John Bence of Kingsfeild William Stiles John Rouse Henry Coppinger
Do&bholigct;or Thomas Arris Francis Barker Thomas Dade John Scrivener Robert King John Lambe Edward North
William Acton Thomas Allen Robert Butts Thomas Butts William Rivett Thomas Golding Francis Burwell William
Some senior Charles Cornwallis Edward Plum Edward Mann Edward Clench Richard Kirby Thomas Turill Thomas
Edger Reinold Williams Allen Cotton Thomas Vesy Charles Vesy Phillip Haward William Gouch Framlingham Gaudy
Anthony Gaudy Ptolomy Talemach William Germy Henry Parker Thomas Bacon John Breame of Ash John Spencer John
Bedingfield Edmond Bedingfeild William Glover Thomas Day Richard Vesy Henry Edger Samuell Kirridge William
Somes junior Edmond Sheppard William Culham Edmond Gardiner Robert Browning Henry Stebbing John Brooke
Paul Buckenham John Thurston Thomas Edger junior Do&bholigct;or John [Kivet<ref idref="n111">111</ref>] Doctor Owen Hughes William Duncombe
Stephen Morley Baptist May Thomas Jerman (<ref idref="n109">109</ref>) Samuell Alston Phillips Wallis Esquiers The
Maior of Sudbury for the time being Sir Robert Cordall Baronet Thomas Walgrave John Cordall Do&bholigct;or Butcher
Joseph Woods John Cooke Daniell Cooke Catesby Towne Clerke John Warner Samuell Cabecke Gent.
The Bayliffes of Dunwich for the time being Sir John Pettus Knight William Wood Es&bhoqesq; John Benefice Thomas
Tokely Thomas Grey Thomas Goddard Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p202">[Ipswich<ref idref="n112">112</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p203">The Bayliffes of Ipswich for the time being William Bloys John Wright Thomas Edger Recorder Nicholas
Phillips Miles Wallis Luke Gore Gilbert Linfeild William Cullam Charles Wright and Robert Clarke Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p204">[S<emph type="p">t</emph> Edmonds Bury<ref idref="n112">112</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p205">For the Burrough of Saint Edmonds Bury The Aldermen for the time being John Southerby Recorder Sir
Thomas Harvey Knight Thomas Holland (<ref idref="n113">113</ref>) William Duncombe [Esquiers<ref idref="n113">113</ref>] Richard Gipps of Horningu Thomas
Goddard James Cobb Francis Browne Robert Sharpe Mathew Warren Samuell Hustler and Thomas Burrowes Gent.</para>
			<para id="p206">[Aldburrough<ref idref="n112">112</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p207">For the Burrough of Aldburrough The Bayliffes for the time being Sir John Holland Baronet John Bence Es&bhoqesq;
Thomas Ellyot John Browne Thomas Wall Ralph Rabbitt Walter Garfoote and Alexander Osborne Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p208">[Burrough of Orford<ref idref="n112">112</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p209">For the Burrough of Orford The for the time being Walter Devereux Es&bhoqesq; Sir Allen Brodericke
Knight Thomas Hastings Joseph Hastings Francis Mace James Coppin and Edward Ewen Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p210">[Surrey<ref idref="n112">112</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p211">For the County of Surrey and Burrough of Southwarke James Burton Es&bhoqesq; High Sheriffe of the County of
Surrey Charles Earle of Ancram of the Kingdome of Scotland Francis Lord Aungier of the Kingdome of Ireland,
Lord Huntingtowre Sir Edward Thurland one of the Barons of the Exchequer. Francis Coventry Es&bhoqesq; Sir Henry Capell
Knight of the Bath Sir Walter S<emph type="p">t</emph> Johns (<ref idref="n114">114</ref>) Sir Anthony Vincent (<ref idref="n114">114</ref>) Sir Adam Browne (<ref idref="n114">114</ref>) Sir Thomas Trevoire (<ref idref="n114">114</ref>) Sir
William More (<ref idref="n114">114</ref>) Sir Marmaduke Gresham (<ref idref="n114">114</ref>) Sir Richard Stydolfe (<ref idref="n114">114</ref>) Sir Robert Long (<ref idref="n114">114</ref>) Sir Edward Bromfeild(<ref idref="n114">114</ref>)
Sir John Werden (<ref idref="n114">114</ref>) Sir Phillip Mathewes [Baronets<ref idref="n114">114</ref>] Sir George Freeman Knight of the Bath Sir John Nicholas Knight
of the Bath Sir William Terringham Knight of the Bath Sir Edmond Bowyer Sir Charles Howard Sir William Haward
Sir Thomas Nott Sir Thomas Bludworth Sir Thomas Clarges Sir Robert Parkhurst Sir Richard Hatton Sir Allen
Brodericke Sir Nicholas Carew Sir Edward Bish Sir William Hoskins Sir Cirill Wiche Sir Thomas Forster Sir
James Austin Sir Richard Mason Sir Dawes Wymondsold Sir John Plott Sir Dennis Gawden Sir Purbecke Temple
Knights Arthur Onslow Henry Hildierd Bernard Greenfield George Chute Edward Evelin William Mountague
junior Roger James Christopher Buckle George Evelin [senior<ref idref="n114">114</ref>] John Scott William Ellyott Anthony Thomas
Thomas Dalmahoy James Zouch Vincent Randyll John Holmeden John Dawes George Browne Ambrose Browne
Anthony Bowyer Edward Thurland George Evelin of Blechingley George Evelin of Wootton junior Denzill Onslow
John Weston of Ockham William Muschampe George Smith John Thynne George Garth Thomas Turges Mathew
Carleton Roger Duncombe George Duncombe George Woodroffe George Vernon Thomas Brend James Gresham
John Thynne White Tichburne William Harvey [Stephen<ref idref="n115">115</ref>] Harvey James Freeman Edward Freeman William
Lenthall Samuell Rous John Highlord Samuell Howland Walter Howland Charles Good Captaine Robert Coke
Thomas Lee Peter Hussey Captaine Clarke of Sheene Richard Heath Do&bholigct;or John Windebanke John Wight John
Byne of Camberwell Edward Gresham Sygismond Stydolfe Edward Trapps Mathew Andrewes John Parker Thomas
Sidderfin George Holman George Turner Thomas Arden Rowland Jewks Henry Byne John Heather John Jordan
Ellis Crispe William Angell John Jones of London Thomas Jenner James Oast James Clarke Henry Haughton
Francis Gerrard Richard Dalton Samuell Wall Giles Dunstar William Haukins John Glynn Shem Bridges Anthony.
Covert Esquiers George Smith of Wandsworth William Brownlough Richard Mountany Richard West M<emph type="p">r</emph> Lloyd
of Stretham John Chelsham Thomas Benson Sir Edmond Wyndham Sir James Butler M<emph type="p">r</emph> Pepys of Merton-Abbey
Somerset Draper Richard Coldham of Downfarm George Coldham of Waverly The Maior of Guildford for the
time being Richard Creswell Caleb Westbrooke Richard Symms John Spencer John Childe Francis Knight John
Reave of Farnham James Reading William Castles Thomas Locke William Cannon John Wilkinson William Hickox
Richard How Peter Rich Captaine Price Peter Delanoy Edward Ball George Meggott Jacob May John Butler
Tobias Solby Abraham Hubbard Richard Holman Gentlemen William Haward Es&bhoqesq; Stephen Moseley Edward
Woodward William Branbrugh.</para>
			<para id="p212">[Sussex<ref idref="n112">112</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p213">For the County of Sussex Charles Lord Buckhurst John Tufton Richard Tufton Thomas Tufton Esquiers Sir
John Pelham Sir William Culpeper Sir Cecill Bishop Sir Adam Browne Sir James Bowyer Sir John Covert (<ref idref="n116">116</ref>) Sir
William Thomas Sir John Stapeley Sir John Fagg (<ref idref="n116">116</ref>) Sir Denny Ashburnham Sir Anthony Shurley Sir William Wilson
Baronets Sir William Morley Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Woodcocke Sir Thomas Nutt Sir George Courthopp
Sir Henry Peckham Sir Nicholas Pelham Sir James Moreton Knights George Parker Thomas Sackvile Henry Goreing
senior Henry Goreing junior William Garraway Nisill Rivers Richard Bridger Edward Mitchelbourne Thomas
Midleton junior Robert Fagg Anthony Feaversfield John Eversfeild Edward Eversfeild Edward Blaker (<ref idref="n117">117</ref>) Henry West
Miles Cooke Esquires Edward Chowne John Gratwicke William Stracy John Backshall Gent. John Alford Thomas
Midleton senior Simon Smith John Midleton Esquires John Mitchell John Machell Bray Chowne Gent. Oliver
Weekes Robert Palmer William Palmer Thomas Garroway Esquires Henry Edmonds Richard Nash Thomas Paine
Francis Mose Christopher Coles Richard Mills Gentlemen William Westbrooke Ralph Mills John May Richard
May Robert Anderson Thomas Bestworth Esquires Thomas Palmer Richard Cooper Thomas Young John Peckham
Thomas Peckham Richard Young Gent. Thomas Grey John Steward Henry Shelley John Millington Walter Dobell
Peter Courthop Esquires Edward Traiton John Oliver William Lane Thomas Beard Nicholas Sell win Gentlemen
Henry Bishop William Spence William Kempe Sackvile Graves William Dyke John Baker senior John Baker junior
William Morley Edward Pollhill Roger Shoiswell Walter Everden Thomas Frewen Robert Fowle Edward Shephered
Esquires John Fuller Peter Farnden John Busbridge John Dyne John Dunke Thomas Bromfeild junior Gent. Thomas
Bromfeild senior Thomas Collins Peircy Goreing Henry West Nicholas Leicet William Peckham Henry Peckham
Esquires The Maior of Arundell The Maior of Chrichester John Chele senior John Chele junior Lawrence Alcock
John Cooke William Hardum Joseph King Gent. Christopher May Es&bhoqesq; Mathew Young Gent. William Westbrook
Gent. Phillip Packer Es&bhoqesq; Sir Nicholas Stroud The Maior of Hasting The Maior of Rie The Maior of Winchelsea
The Bayliffe of Seaford for the time being and The Bayliffe of Peversey for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p214">[Warwicke<ref idref="n118">118</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p215">For the County of Warwicke Sir Francis Compton Knight Fulke Grevill Thomas Coventry Charles Leigh Esquiers
Sir Robert Holt Sir Richard Temple Sir Henry Puckering alias Newton Sir Edward Boughton Sir Clement Fisher
Sir Roger Burgoigne Sir John Knightley Sir Herbert Price Sir Thomas Norton Sir Theophilus Biddulph Sir John
Hales Sir Fuller Skipwith Sir William Bromeley Knight of the Bath Sir Charles Adderley Sir Charles Lee Sir
William Palmer Sir Arthur Caley Sir William Underhill Sir Richard Hopkins Sir Richard Bishop Sir John Clopton
Sir William Throckmorton Knights Richard Nudigate Sergeant at Law Richard Lucy John Ferrars Thomas Archer
John Bridgeman Orlando Bridgeman Richard Nudigate Esquires William Somerville Seabret Reppington Harvey
Baggott John Lisle Henry Pudsey John Rouse William Purefoy Richard Boughton of Bilton Richard Verney senior
of Kingston Richard Verney junior of Kingston Henry Ferrars William Combes Thomas Marryot Thomas Rawlins
Charles Newsham Hastings Ingram Thomas Wagstaffe George Devereux William Bath of Witton Charles Bentley
Humphrey Jennyngs Thomas Corben George Sacheverell Richard Hopkins John Newsham Thomas Temple James
Prescott Henry Shugburgh Es&bhoqesq; Henry Parker William Loggins Henry Mathews The Maior of Warwicke for the
time being The Maior of Stratford for the time being The Bayliffes of Tarnworth for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p216">[Coventry<ref idref="n118">118</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p217">For the County of the Citty of Coventry The Maior for the time being Sir Clement Fisher Sir Thomas Norton
Sir John Hales Baronets Sir Richard Hopkins Sergeant at Law Sir Robert Townesend Sir Arthur Caley Sir William
Jesson Knights Richard Hopkins Henry Greene Esquires John Woolridge William Jolliffe Joseph Chambers Julius
Billers James Nayler Nathaniell Harriman Aldermen Robert Beake and Thomas Wagstaffe Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p218">[Worcester<ref idref="n118">118</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p219">For the County of Worcester M<emph type="p">r</emph> Secretary Coventry M<emph type="p">r</emph> Coventry Sir John Packington Sir Henry Litleton Sir
Francis Russell Sir Edward [Ceabright<ref idref="n119">119</ref>] Sir William Keyh Sir James Rushout Sir Thomas Cookes Baronet Sir Henry
Herbert Sir Rowland Berkley Sir John Winford Sir John Talbot Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir John Hanmer (<ref idref="n120">120</ref>) Sir
John Barnaby Sir Francis Wynnington Knights Collonell Samuell Sandis John Packington Edward Rowse Samuell
Sandys junior Sherrington Talbot Thomas Savage Thomas Savage junior of [Elmey-Castle<ref idref="n121">121</ref>] James Pitts Robert
Berkley Francis Finch Edward Carew Joseph Walsh Thomas Childe Henry Townshend John Nanfan Thomas Streets
Edward Dingley Leonard Simpson Litleton Clent Richard Vernon Charles Cornwallis Edward Parteridere William
Sheldon of Broadway Walter Savage Thomas Jolliffe Thomas Simons Thomas Foley senior Thomas Foley junior
Phillip Parsons Anthony Crump Henry Evett William Wasborne William Hancocke John Charlett Thomas Watson
of Bengworth Henry Spiller William Ligon Henry Jeffryes Brome Whorwood Phillip Brace. senior Phillip Brace
junior Thomas Bushell Thomas Haslewood of Wick Es&bhoqesq; Francis Sheldon Thomas Stephens John Bearcroft
Bridges Nanfan Thomas Chetle of the Walhouse senior Thomas Vernon Robert Foley Henry Parker Gerrard Dannett
Thomas Turvey Richard Dowdeswell Martin Sandys Humphrey Perrot junior Es&bhoqesq; Garratt of Aunton
Gentlemen Higgins James Thomas Barker The Maior of Evesham for the time being The Bayliffes of Droitwich
for the time being The Bayliffes of Bewdley for the time being Anthony Langston John Sandys Mathew Skinner
Doctor of Phisicke.</para>
			<para id="p220">[Citty of Worcester<ref idref="n119">119</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p221">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester The Maior, Aldermen and Sheriffe for the time being
Sir John Packington Baronet Collonell Samuell Sandys Sir Rowland Berkley Knight Thomas Streete Thomas
Vernon Thomas Harris Robert Wilde Esquires Richard Bedowes Henry Taylor John Bearcroft William Norris
Humphry Tyrer William Swift Gent.</para>
			<para id="p222">[Wilts<ref idref="n122">122</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p223">For the County of Wilts Edward Seymour Es&bhoqesq; Speaker to the honourable House of Commons Henry Lord
Colraine Henry Viscount Cornbury Anthony Lord Ashley Edward Howard Es&bhoqesq; Sir Robert Howard Knight Sir
Walter S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Sir Robert Button Sir Seymour Pile Sir Giles Escourt Sir Richard Grobham-How Sir Robert Long
Sir George Grobham-How Sir Walter Erneley Sir Giles Tooker and Sir Walter Long Baronets Sir John Coventry Sir
Edward Hungerford Sir John Nicholas Sir Francis Popham Sir Edward Bainton Knights of the Bath Sir John Evelin
Sir John Talbott Sir Edward Poole Sir George Hungerford Sir Thomas Estcourt Sir Thomas Ivy Sir John Weld Sir
Henry Cocker Sir Thomas Mompesson Sir John Ernle Sir Stephen Fox Sir Richard Harrison Phillip Howard Es&bhoqesq;
Edmund Pile Thomas Hum Gentlemen Sir Joseph Ash Baronet Sir John S<emph type="p">t</emph> Law Sir Edward Lowe Knights Thomas
Thynne James Mountague George Pitt Edward Ernle Richard Lewis George Cooper Francis Wroughton John Plydall
William Glanville John Hall Henry Clarke William Jourdan James Long William Eyre William Brunker William
Ducket Ralph Freeke George Ayliffe Thomas Estcourt Henry Hungerford Giles Hungerford Thomas Bennett
George Bond Edmund Warnford Thomas Mompesson Robert Hyde Bernard Pawlet William Ash Alexander
[Thistlewaite <ref idref="n123">123</ref>] Maurice Beckland Oliver Calley Thomas Lambert John Harrison John Windham Es&bhoqesq; John Smith
de Tydworth John Long Richard Aldworth Gilbert Raleigh John Collins George Lowe Jeffery Daniell Edward
Goddard de Standen William Willoughby Christopher Willoughby Thomas Gore William Trenchard Richard
Estcourt George Johnson Giles Eyre senior Samuell Eyre William Swanton Henry Clerke junior Giles Eyre
junior Thomas Halls Thomas Chamberlaine George Ivy Nevill Masklyn Robert Drew John Bowles Robert Chaundler
John Topp Thomas Pile Peter Dove Joseph Stockman Thomas Hungerford Oliver Nicholas Richard Powle Henry
Wallis Edmond Webb John Danvers John Ash Michaell Ernle Samuell Ash Thomas Gerrard of Swindon Richard
Davy George Parry Thomas Clerke Edward Nott John Mervin William Chaffin William Thynne William Norborne
John Hawkins John Mompesson Richard Holt Francis Hill Lawrence Swanton Edward Goddard junior de Ogborne
Abiotin Stokes Charles Tooker Benjamin Gifford John Fitzherbert John Bennet Gabriell Ashley John Brooke
Robert Challoner William Herst Charles Yorke Ephrim Westle Richard Geene Robert Hippesley John Young
John Metwin Richard Poore John Jacob Thomas Dennet senior Walter Dowse Mathew Bennett William Hewes
Giles Lybcot Thomas Dove William Chap[h<ref idref="n124">124</ref>]man William Levett John Bigg George Sadler William Grinfeild
Jonathan Rogers M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Nicholas M<emph type="p">r</emph> Hancocke with [the<ref idref="n122">122</ref>] Maiors of Wilton and Devizes and Marleburrough
for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p224">[Citty of Sarum<ref idref="n122">122</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p225">For the Citty of Sarum Robert Jones Gent. Maior and The Maior for the time being Sir Thomas Mompesson
Sir Stephen Fox Knights William Swanton Recorder Edward Edmunds Maurice Greene Thomas Gardiner John
Joyce Thomas Williams, Edmund Macks Christopher Cardiner James Bennett Giles Naish Aldermen George Low
George Vennard Richard Davis Richard Holt William Hearst Gabriell Ashley Thomas Harris Francis Hill
John Stevens.</para>
			<para id="p226">[Westmerland<ref idref="n122">122</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p227">For the County of Westmerland Thomas Tufton Es&bhoqesq; Sir Phillip Musgrave Sir William Dalston Sir George
Fletcher Sir Richard Sandford Sir John Lowther [Sir John Lowther<ref idref="n124">124</ref>] Baronets Sir Thomas Strickland Knight
Richard Musgrave Es&bhoqesq; Sir Christopher Musgrave [Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>] <ref idref="n124">124</ref>John Dalston Es&bhoqesq; James Bellingham Daniell Flemming
Thomas Sandford Richard Brathwake Robert Hilton John Otway Thomas Brathwaite Edward Wilson Henry Wilson
Thomas Fletcher Lancelot Matchell Christopher Dalstons Esquires Thomas Gabetis Thomas Sands John Fisher
Richard Duckett Gentlemen, The Maiors of Appleby and Kendall for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p228">[Yorke<ref idref="n122">122</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p229">For the West Rideling in the County of Yorke George Viscount Castleton Charles Lord Clifford Henry Lord
Fairfax Lord S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Conyers Darcy Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Osborne Sir Henry Goodricke Sir Richard Mauleverer Sir
John Reresby Sir John Hay Sir John Armitage Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir William Ingleby Sir Solomon Swaile Sir
William Robeby Sir Godfrey Copley Sir Edmond Wynne Sir John Jackson Sir Thomas Slingsby Sir George Cooke
Sir William Franckland Sir John Bennett Baronets Sir Thomas Wharton Sir Jervase Cutler Sir John Hewley Sir
Thomas Wenthworth Sir William Wentworth Sir John Dawney Sir William Lowther Sir Francis Goodricke Sir
Edmond Jennings Sir Christopher Clapham Sir Ralph Knight Sir Thomas Yarbrough Knights John Ramsdon of Biram
Richard Hutton Thomas Mauleverer Walter Hawkesworth Welbury Norton Ambrose Pudsey William Palmes John
Vavasour Sandford Nevill Francis Nevill Walter Calverley John Bole Henry Eyre Doctor in Phisicke John Savill of
Midley John Wentworth of Wolley Bradwardine Tyndall Francis Foljombe John Vincent Willoughby Rokeby Major
Francis Reresby William Lowther John Bilby Richard Washington William Ha[m]mond John Boynton Thomas
Yarbrough Walter Lister William Fairfax Henry Stapleton Arthur Ingram William Stockdale William Drake Inglebert
Leeds Cuthbert Wade Richard Weston John Stanhope of Grimston William Ellis Charles Osborne Tobias Jenkins
George Aystable Robert Harrison John Adams of Scansby John Stanhop Roger Portington John Clarke Edward
Lewis John Garland Henry Atkinson Francis White Thomas Lister of Bawtree John Adams of Rokeles Thomas
Haber John Otway Miles Stanley Doyley Gowre Thomas Fawkes Henry Hich Jonathan Jennyngs Henry Edmunds
Robert Benson John Ashton John Lister Thomas Parker Johnson of Scatebourne Lionell Copley senior
Lionell Copley junior Henry Marsden William Drake Henry Slingsby Esquiers John Preston Robert Walter George
Fothergill Christopher Drisseild Charles Richards Richard Albrough John Atkinson Henry Redshaw William Laughton
John Laughton Lawrence Wharton Henry Cooke Captaine John Atkinson William Roundle Thomas Gill John
Mattrum John Hatfeild George Westby William Beckwith John Slyman John Batty George Rayson Edward
Shepheard The Maior of Rippon The Maior of Doncaster The Maior of Pontefra&bholigct; The Maior of Leedes for the
time being.</para>
			<para id="p230">For the North Rideing in the said County of Yorke Charles Lord S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Conyers D'Arcy (<ref idref="n125">125</ref>) Marmaduke D'Arcy (<ref idref="n125">125</ref>)
James D'Arcy [Esquiers<ref idref="n125">125</ref>] Sir Thomas Osborne Sir Christopher Wivill Sir Hugh Cholmeley Sir [Christopher<ref idref="n126">126</ref>]
Mauleverer Sir Metcalfe Robinson Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir Solomon Swaile Sir Henry Stapleton Sir Thomas Slingsby Sir
David Fowlis Sir William Frankland Sir John Lowther Sir John Napier Sir Roger Langley Sir William Caley Sir George
Marwood Sir Richard [Gralime<ref idref="n127">127</ref>] of Nunnington Sir Richard [Gralime<ref idref="n127">127</ref>] of Norton Sir Christopher Wandesford Sir
William Chator Sir James Pennyman Sir John Hotham Baronets Sir Thomas Strickland Sir John Howley Sir William
Dalton Sir Edward Challenor Sir John Dawney Sir Phillip Monkton Sir Robert Layton Sir Joseph Craddocke Knights
William Wivill William [Lason <ref idref="n128">128</ref>] Gower William Gower Henry Marwood William Caley John How John Beverley.
Roger Beckwith Thomas Rokeby Brian Laton Roger [Tabott<ref idref="n127">127</ref>] John Dodsworth of Wallas Hugh Cholmley Richard
Peirce Barrington Bourchier Henry Calverley Edward Croft Thomas Robinson Anthony Frankland Major Norton
Thomas Norton of Langthorne Christopher Norton William Weddall Serjeant Turner Isaac Fairfax Humphrey
Wharton Robert Wharton William Asquith John Wivill of Olgerly John Gibson Edward Hutchinson of Wickham
Leonard [Gralime<ref idref="n127">127</ref>] Francis Drisseild Charles Tankred Thomas Jackson William Feilding William Palmes [John.<ref idref="n130">130</ref>]
Heblethwaite William Robinson Edward Trotter Anthony Lowther Hugh Bethell James Morley Tymothy Mauleverer
Thomas Hazle William Thompson Thomas Worsley Captaine Leonard Robinson William Metcalfe Walter Lister
John Colston Thomas Wayt Henry Crolland Charles Bellasis Charles Allanson John Chapman Roger Lee William
Dawson William Trueman Francis Cummin Robert Bushell Thomas Lastalls Thomas Bodsworth of Barton Thomas
Gill Charles Layton Tristram Fish Timothy Ford Walter Bethell Christopher Percy-Hay, The Maior of Richmond
and the Bayliffes of Scarborough for the time being, John Blackston Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p231">East Rideing in the said County of Yorke Charles Lord Clifford Charles Lord S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Sir John Hotham Sir
Francis Boynton Sir Robert Hilyard Sir Watkenson Pailer Sir Thomas Rudston Sir Henry North Sir John Legard
Sir Henry S<emph type="p">t</emph> Quintin Sir William Strickland Baronets Sir Phillip Monkton Sir Thomas Dangell Sir Thomas Remington
Sir Hugh Bethell Sir Francis Cobb Sir William Cobb Sir Ralph Warton Sir Edward Barnard Sir Michaell Warton
Sir Mathew Peirson Sir Henry Thompson Sir Jonathan Atkins Knights Tobias Jenkins Michaell Warton Robert Ruck
Durand Hotham John Lister Henry Holmes Christopher Hillyard John Vavasour William Osbaldeston William Grimston
Robert Southaby Richard Robinson Thomas Crompton William Gee senior William Gee junior Richard Legard
William Boynton Stephen Thompson Walter Bethell William Thompson Robert Constable Richard Thompson
Henry Hillyard senior John Stapilton John Heron Henry Portington Phillip Saltmarshe John Clerke William S<emph type="p">t</emph> Quintin
James Moyser Thomas Fesbett John Aeroyde Hugh Bethell James Heblethwaite Marmaduke Constable Richard
Remington Thomas Strickland Mathew Alered Esquires William Blunt William Lowings Francis Bushell John
Belton Ralph Higdom Richard Graham Robert Hollis Thomas Langley Ellis Cowper Edward Grey Robert Prickett
Timothy Remington Gentlemen, The Maior of Beaverley and The Maior of Headdon for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p232">[Citty of Yorke<ref idref="n131">131</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p233">For the Citty of Yorke and the County of the same The Lord Maior The Aldermen and Sheriffes for the
time being Henry Lord Fairfax of the Kingdome of Scotland Sir Thomas Osborne Sir Metcalfe Robinson Sir
Thomas Slingsby Sir Richard Maleverer Sir Roger Langley Sir Henry Goodricke Sir George Reeves Sir John
Hewley Baronets John Turnor Sergeant at Law Do&bholigct;or Burwell Henry Stapleton Joseph Scott Charles Allanson
John Tompson Richard Ethrington Tobias Jenkins James Moyser William Fairfax Thomas Robinson Thomas Hutton
John Swaile Phillip Prince William Raundall Thomas Hesket John Brooke George Aisliby Phillip Herbert M<emph type="p">r</emph> Suansdale
Richard Tenant Anthony Walker Es&bhoqexc; M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Hillery M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Hillary M<emph type="p">r</emph> Waller M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Fairfax M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry
Parsons M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Langley.</para>
			<para id="p234">[Kingston Upon Hull<ref idref="n131">131</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p235">For the Towne and County of Kingston upon Hull The Maior for the time being William Foxley William
Ramsden Christopher Richardson George Crowle Richard Wilson William Skinner Richard Frank Anthony Lambert
Humphry Duncalfe George Aiklam Daniell Hoare Aldermen Anthony Gilby (<ref idref="n125">125</ref>) Andrew Murrell [Esquires<ref idref="n125">125</ref>] The
Sheriffe for the time being Christopher Hildiard Es&bhoqesq; The Wardens of Trinity House for the time being Edmund
Popple John Lister John Rogers John Feild John Perkins Gentlemen Robert Hollis Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p236">[WALES<ref idref="n132">132</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p237">[Anglesey<ref idref="n132">132</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p238">The County of Anglesey Robert Lord Bulkeley Viscount Cassells of the Kingdome of Ireland Thomas Bulkley
Esquires Sir Hugh Owen Baronet Nicholas Bagenall Es&bhoqesq; Pierce Lloyd senior Richard Bulkley John Robinson Pierce
Lloyd junior Richard Mericke John Griffith of Llanvaithly Robert Roberts Es&bhoqesq; William Williams Thomas Holland
David Lloyd-Llidiard William Bulkley of Brinddy Conisby Williams Cornelius Weringden Es&bhoqesq; Owen Hughes
John Owens of Penrhose Edward Wynne Rowland Whitts Howell Lewis Henry Jones Esquires Henry Davies
William Williams of Treardder William Lewis Edward Price of Trevadog John Wood John Owen Hugh Williams
David Williams William Roberts of Caere Owen Williams Richard Edwards John Hughes John Williams John
Prichard William Griffith Richard Hughes The Maior of Bumorris for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p239">[Brecon<ref idref="n132">132</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p240">For the County of Brecon Sir William Leuis and Sir Herbert Price Baronets Sir [Edward<ref idref="n133">133</ref>] Price Edward Proger
Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Streete Es&bhoqesq; Justice of Assise Sir Walter Williams Baronet William Morgan of Therrow Thomas Price
and Thomas Lane Esquires Thomas Mansell Esq[uire] of Penderry Hugh Powell Henry Proger Edward Games and
John Jeoffreys Esquires Henry Williams of Cabalva William Le Hunt Es&bhoqesq; Lewis Morgan His Majestyes Attourney
Generall Walter Vaughan Es&bhoqesq; John Stedman Samuell Prichard Thomas Williams of Abercinlayes Henry Rumsey
William Morgan of Newton Esquires Do&bholigct;or Thomas Williams John Williams of Condee James Watkins Henry
Steadman and John Gwynn Esquires Doctor John Morgan of Llangenny David Morgan of Lawenarth and David Gwinne
of the Parke Gent. Rees Price Es&bhoqesq; William Lloyd of Wernos Edward Williams of Waringin Jasper Milward and
Thomas Bowen Esquires Richard Williams of Aberbrame John Powell of Brecknocke Es&bhoqesq; Henry Williams of
Llangunnedor Lewis Gunter David Jenkins of the Therrow John Gunter John Morgan of Werno Jeffrey Jeffreys
of Lliwell William Lloyd of Llangamath William Bowen junior Howell Powell Edmund Jones Recorder of Brecon
William Sanders Charles Roberts Richard Jones and William Phillips of Brecknock, The Bayliffe and the two
Aldermen for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p241">[Cardigan<ref idref="n132">132</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p242">For the County of Cardigan Sir Richard Price of Gogartham Baronet Edward Vaughan of Transcoed [Esq&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n134">134</ref>]
Erasmus Lloyd of Ystradtiloe (<ref idref="n135">135</ref>) James Phillips of Cardigan Hector Phillips and Thomas Lewis late of Cumaven
[Esquiers<ref idref="n134">134</ref>] Thomas Jenkins of Vardrey [Warkin<ref idref="n136">136</ref>] Lloyd of Werne Thomas Jones of Llanvayre Walter Lloyd
Nicholas Lewis and Richard Herbert late of Lanina Esquires John Vaughan of Llanlery John Price of Randyr
Thomas Jones of Llingary Thomas Lewis of Cardigan and Abell Griffith Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p243">[Carmarthen<ref idref="n132">132</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p244">For the County of Carmarthan John Lord Vaughan Altham Vaughan Sir Henry Vaughan Knight Sir Edward
Mansell Sir Sackvill Crow Baronets Sir Rice Rudd Sir Ralph [Bank<ref idref="n137">137</ref>] Sir William Russell Sir Francis Cornwallis
Knight Walter Rice Walter Vaughan of Llanelly Rowland Gwinne of Glanbraen William Gwinne of Taliaris
Nicholas Williams of Rhidodin John Vaughan of Dertlis Richard Vaughan of [Tacicold<ref idref="n138">138</ref>] Christopher Midleton John
Vaughan of Placegwin, Owen Brigstock John Powell of Llanurda Thomas Lloyd of Berlandowith John Williams
of Abercothy Phillip Vaughan of Frinsaran Morgan Jones of Trigib Esquires Richard Gwinne of Wempas John
Evans Thomas Davis of Newton Roger Manwaring Es&bhoqesq; Walter Morgan Gentleman Jarvies Jones of Dulacothy
Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Jones Gent</para>
			<para id="p245">[Towne of Carmarthan<ref idref="n132">132</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p246">For the Towne of Carmarthan The Maior for the time being John Lord Vaughan Altham Vaughan Sir Henry
Vaughan Knight John Vaughan of Dertlis John Vaughan of Plasegwin Walter Vaughan of Kanelly Esquires
Thomas Jones (<ref idref="n139">139</ref>) Dawkin Gough (<ref idref="n139">139</ref>) John Scurlock (<ref idref="n139">139</ref>) Thomas Binon (<ref idref="n139">139</ref>) George Lewis (<ref idref="n139">139</ref>) John Oakley (<ref idref="n139">139</ref>) William
Brigstocke [Aldermen<ref idref="n139">139</ref>] John Williams Es&bhoqesq; Robert Lewis the younger (<ref idref="n139">139</ref>) Richard Thomas [Aldermen<ref idref="n139">139</ref>] Edward
Jones Gent.</para>
			<para id="p247">[Carnarven<ref idref="n132">132</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p248">For the County of Carnarvan Robert Lord [Viscount<ref idref="n134">134</ref>] Buckley of the Kingdome of Ireland Robert Roberts (<ref idref="n135">135</ref>)
Thomas Buckley [Esquires<ref idref="n135">135</ref>] Sir Richard Wynne Sir Roger Mostin Sir Robert Williams Baronets Sir Richard Lloyd
Sir Thomas Jones Sergeant at Law Knights Cornelius Vermuyden Es&bhoqesq; Kenricke Eyton Thomas Mostin Nicholas
Bagnall William Griffith William Owen Griffith Vaughan Hugh Winne Thomas Vaughan John Wynne of Melas
Thomas Wynne Robert Coytmore Hugh Williams William Buckley Griffith Bodurda Edmund Glynne John Wynne
of Berthaur Thomas Madrin John Wynne of Tyhwynne Richard Anwell John Glynne Thomas Glynne Richard
Gruffith Robert Hookes Owen Wynne Thomas Wynne of Glascoed Richard Kiffin William Pritherigh John Winne
of Peniurth Herbert Gruffith Robert Wynne of Keselgivarch William Wynne of Pengwerne Robert Wynne of
Llannor William Williams Hugh Bodurda William Spicer [<ref idref="n140">140</ref>] Thomas of Carnarven Esquires William</para>
			<para id="p249">Arthur Owen Parry Richard Edwards Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p250">[Denbigh <ref idref="n141">141</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p251">For the County of Denbigh Edward Morris High Sheriffs Sir Richard Wynne Sir John Salisbury Sir Thomas
Midleton Sir Thomas Powell Sir William Meredith Sir Thomas Trevour Sir Evan Lloyd Baronetts Sir Richard
Lloyd Sir John Carter Sir Robert Agburough Sir John Wynne Sir John Trevor Sir Thomas Jones Sergeant at
Law and Sir William Neile Knights William Owen William Salisbury Hugh Wynne John Wynne Mutton Davis
Kadwalleder Wynne Edward Thelwell William Price Kenricke Eyton Thomas Vaughon John Robinson Bevis
Lloyd John Thelwall John Edisbury Charles Midleton John Midleton Eubile Thelwell John Jeffreys Richard
Midleton of Llanselin Edward Brereton William Williams Owen Thelwell Gabriell Goodman, Humphrey Hughes
of Brintanger William Parry David Morris Owen Wynne .Charles Goodman Humphrey Lloyd of Berse Mathew
Price Robert Power John Puleston John Lloyd of Bodidrist Francis Manley John Lloyd Llanivis Hedd Lloyd
William Vaughan of Bronhilog Hugh Roberts William, Jones Ellis Lloyd Placengion and John Chambers Esquires
Robert Wynne of Garthewynne Howell Lloyd James Thelwall Thomas Lloyd of Berse Meredith Wynne Captaine
Thomas Yale John Williams of Carwedfinidd Edward Lloyd of Placmaddock Ellis Lloyd of Egglwisig Morris
Williams of Llanverras Eubule Lloyd of [Plaheniha<ref idref="n142">142</ref>] John Lloyd of Wickwer The two Aldermen and two Bayliffes
of Denbigh Roger Midleton Edward Davis Robert Roberts and Foulke Davies Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p252">[Flint<ref idref="n141">141</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p253">For the County of Flint Sir Thomas Hanmer Sir John Salisbury Sir [Robert<ref idref="n143">143</ref>] Mostin and Sir William Glynne
Baronets Sir John Hanmer and Sir John Trevor Knights Thomas Mostin Thomas Ravenscroft Mutton Davis Thomas
Lloyd William Price Kendricke Eyton William Humner Robert Whitley Roger Whitley Peter Griffith Thomas
Griffith William Griffith John Eyton Pierce Pennant John Parry Edward Pennant Edward Ravenscroft William
Mostin Ellis Young John Mostin John Brougton Thomas Humphryes John Salisbury Ellis Evans Thomas Whitley
Charles Jones Edward Lloyd Thomas Cratchley Owen Barton Edward Evatt Edward Morgan and John Hughes
Esquires Luke Lloyd junior Walter Clapton Peter Peirce John Lloyd Owen Wynne and John Salisbury of Erbistog
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p254">[Glamorgan<ref idref="n141">141</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p255">For the County of Glamorgan Charles Lord Herbert of Ragland Robert Lord Lisle Sir Richard Lloyd Knight
Thomas Streete Esquire His Majestyes Justice of the Great Sessions Sir Edward Mansell Baronet Sir Edward
Stradling Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Thomas Baronet Sir John Awbery Knight and Baronet Sir Charles
Kemis Baronet Sir Lionell Jenkins Knight Judge of the Admiralty and Prerogative Bussy Mansell Robert
Thomas Edmund Thomas William Herbert of Swanzey Thomas Lewis Edward Lewis John Awbery Edmond
Lewis Herbert Evans David Mathews Phillip Jones Thomas Mathew Richard Bassett Edward Mathew of Abramen
Thomas Basset of Llanvythen Thomas Carne Humphrey Windham David Jenkins Francis Gwynne Evan Seyes
Sergeant at Law [William Basset Doctor of Law<ref idref="n144">144</ref>] John Windham Richard Lougher Phillip Hobby John Greenuph
William Thomas of Llanbradock David Evans Thomas Evans John Lluellyn John Carne Richard Seyes Charles
Bowen Miles Button Esquires Lyson Evans Rowland Dawkins George Williams George Lucas Robert Bidder
Thomas Lougher of Cornely William Bassett of Llandemore Thomas Mansell of Penrice Richard Jenkins of
Pantinowell Robert Popkins Roger Powell of Enys-Glin Richard Seys of Boverton Martin Button Thomas Stradling
John Van Esquires Edward Jenkins of Cowbridge Gentleman Captaine Thomas Morgan Thomas Mansell (<ref idref="n145">145</ref>) Edmund
Gamag William Thomas of Ruperry Edward Mansell of Hentlas Thomas Stradling junior Esquires James Gwin
Thomas Lewis of Roth Mansell Stradling Edward Thomas Lewis Thomas James Turbervill Iltid Nicholl Thomas
Gibbon Gent. William Awbery of Pencard George Morgan of Istred Edmond Thomas of Orchard [Esquires<ref idref="n145">145</ref>]
Jeremiah Dawkins Thomas Rees of Llanfa George Bowen Gentlemen Cradocke Wills Arthur Yeomans Bayliffes of
Cardiffe Edward Mansell.</para>
			<para id="p256">[Merioneth<ref idref="n141">141</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p257">For the County of Merioneth [Nathan<ref idref="n146">146</ref>] Jones Es&bhoqesq; High Sheriffe Sir Richard Wynne Baronets Sir Richard Lloyd
and Sir John Wynne Knights William Salisbury William Owen William Price Griffith Vaughan of Corsygedall
Edward Vaughan Hugh Naney Lewis Anwell John Pugh Vincent Corbett John Lloyd Roger Mostyn Owen
Wynne Griffith Lloyd Lewis Owen William Vaughan of Caithle John Naney Howell Vaughan of Vaner. Edmund
Mericke Humphry Hughes Owen Eyton Richard Anwill Ellis Edwards John Morgans Morris Williams and John
Mashmore Esquires Richard Naney John Owen of Havodowyll Griffith John Lewis Evan Lloyd of Rhrwygoch
and William Humphreys.</para>
			<para id="p258">[Mountgomery<ref idref="n141">141</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p259">For the County of Mountgomery Henry Herbert Andrew Newport Esquires Sir. Richard, Corbett Sir Mathew
Price Sir Henry Herbert Sir John Whitterong Sir Charles Lloyd Sir Thomas Jones Sir. Richard Masons Richard
Owen of Rusaisin Edward Vaughan of Gloydiart Edward Vaughan of Gwernygoe: Richard Herbert John Pugh
Edward Lloyd of Birth-Lloyd Robert Leighton William Oakeley George Devereux Es&bhoqesq; Roger Moystin Edmond
Wareing Mathew Price of Parkes Francis [Bull<ref idref="n147">147</ref>] Thomas Corbett Thomas Wynde Arthur Wenor Mathew Morgan
Thomas Maurice David Powell Richard Stedman Athelnstan Owen Francis Fitzherbert John Mathews Richard
Mittor William Eyton Robert Leigh Charles Herbert of Aston John Whittingham John Kiffin Edward Lloyd of
Mathravall Esquires David Maurice Gent Thomas Mason William Williams Richard Griffith of Sutton Esquires
John Okeley Edward Whittingham Captaine John Lloyd Thomas Hudson Gent. John Williams Es&bhoqesq; Edward Evans
of Rhidicarrow Humphrey Nicholas Vincent Pierce Gent. Edward Price of Glarmakley Humphry Griffiths Esquires
Evan Vaughan Richard Bower Evan Evans of Coome Christopher Annell James Penrhin Hugh Davies Trewilan
Edward Herbert Lodowicke Lewis John Bright of Mellington Meredeth Lloyd of Brinellen John Lloyd of Cowney
Ellis Lloyd James Banner Henry Griffiths of Benthall Morgan Evan's Nicholas Wareing William Penrhin Arthur
Vaughon John Edwards of Flanvarie Ellis Morgan William Biggs Gentlemen Edward Barret Es&bhoqesq; Richard Herbert
of Kerry Gentleman Evan Glynn David Price Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p260">[Haverford West<ref idref="n148">148</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p261">For the Towne and County of Haverford West Sir Fredericke Hyde Robert Prust Maior for the time being
Lewis Barron Alderman John Williams Alderman and William Browne Alderman John Thomas Es&bhoqesq; Thomas
Cozens Alderman Thomas Bowen Alderman Richard Crowler Alderman William Williams (<ref idref="n149">149</ref>) Richard Jones (<ref idref="n149">149</ref>) John
Lloyd Mercer John Bateman [Gentlemen<ref idref="n149">149</ref>] Richard Williams Sadler.</para>
			<para id="p262">[Pembrooke<ref idref="n148">148</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p263">For the County of Pembrooke Sir Erasmus Phillips (<ref idref="n150">150</ref>) Sir John Stepney (<ref idref="n150">150</ref>) Sir Hugh Owen [Baronets<ref idref="n150">150</ref>] Sir Herbert
[Berrot<ref idref="n151">151</ref>] Knight Sir Fredericke Hyde Arthur Owen Es&bhoqesq; Rowland Langhorn senior Lewis Barlow William Scouerfield
Esquires Lewis Wogan of Boulstan Essex Meyricke Lewis Wogan of Wiston Hugh Bowen William Phillips
Rowland Langharne junior William Mordaunt Thomas Corbett William Wogan Thomas Phillips Esquires Thomas
Lloyd Thomas Bowen of Troloyne John Williams of Gumferston Isaac Lloyd Arthur Owens of Johnstone John
Owens of Trocoone Griffith Davis James Bowen James Lloyd Morris Wogan Thomas Jones John Mathias William
Meare Esquires William Owen, of Henllys John Ellyott and William Lloyd of Trowent Gentlemen Arthur Langharne
John Owen of Prusully Hugh Langharne Jenkin Vaughan John Wogan of Selliham Gent Thomas Symmins William
Warren William Williams of Saint Florence Walter Cuney Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p264">[Towne of Pembrooke<ref idref="n148">148</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p265">For the Towne of Pembrooke Sir Fredericke Hyde The Maior for the time being William Hinton (<ref idref="n152">152</ref>) Walter Cuney (<ref idref="n152">152</ref>)
Mathew Bowen (<ref idref="n152">152</ref>) Francis Dawes (<ref idref="n152">152</ref>) John Hinton (<ref idref="n152">152</ref>) Francis Rogers (<ref idref="n152">152</ref>) George Meare (<ref idref="n152">152</ref>) Robert Meus [Aldermen<ref idref="n152">152</ref>]
George Powell Gent. and William Cozens Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p266">[Towne of Tenby<ref idref="n148">148</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p267">For the Towne of Tenby Sir Fredericke Hyde The Maior for the time being David Palmer (<ref idref="n152">152</ref>) Devereux Hammond (<ref idref="n152">152</ref>)
James Lloyd Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p268">[Radnor<ref idref="n148">148</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p269">For the County of Radnor Sir Edward Harley Knight of the Bath Sir Richard Lloyd (<ref idref="n153">153</ref>) Sir Robert Harley Knight
Richard Fowler James Price John Walcot Thomas Corbett Henry Williams Thomas Harley Samuell Powell Edward
Davyes Thomas Lewis of Harpton Griffith Jones Thomas Lewis of Manaughtee Henry Probert Richard Crowther
Robert Cutler [Robert<ref idref="n154">154</ref>] Vaughan of Pentecarac Edward Price of Presteigne Charles Lewis Herbert Weston James
Beck Sergeant at Armes Henry Stedman Hugh Powell John Richards John Walsam John James Esquires John
Fowler Jonas Stevans William Taylor Francis Richards Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>II. Commissioners to meet on or before the 23rd April;</head>
			<para id="p270">
				<emph type="i">may divide themselves.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p271">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the severall Commissioners aforesaid shall meete together at the
most usuall and common place or meeting within each of the said Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and
Places respe&bholigct;ively on or before the twenty third day of Aprill now next ensueing, And the said C&bhooov;missioners
or soe many of them as shall be present at the said first generall meeting or the major part of them are hereby
authorized and required to putt this present A&bholigct; in execution according to the best of their Judgements and
discretions and shall then if they see cause subdivide and distribute themselves soe into lesser numbers as two or
more of the said Commissioners may be appointed for the service of each Hundred or other Division and as
may best conduce to the carrying on of His Majestyes Service hereby required.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>III. Commissioners at their Meeting to set down in Writing what Number of Commissioners shall act in each Division, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p272">And for the more effe&bholigct;uall performance thereof Bee it ena&bholigct;ed and declared [Tha<ref idref="n155">155</ref>] the Commissioners at their
aforesaid first generall meeting or the major part of them shall agree and sett downe in writeing who and what
number of the said C&bhooov;missers shall act in each of the said Divisions or Hundreds to the end that there be noe
failer in any part of the due execution of the Service by this Act required.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>IV. Commissioners in their several Divisions to cause the Proportions charged to be equally assessed, and to appoint Assessors,</head>
			<para id="p273"><emph type="i">Duty of such Assessors.</emph></para>
			<para id="p274">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid That the Commissioners within the severall
Divisions or Hundreds or any two or more of them are hereby authorized and required to cause the said severall
proportions charged on the respe&bholigct;ive Divisions and on every parish and place therein for the said eighteene
moneths Assessment to be equally assessed and taxed and to appoint two or more Assessors in each parish or
place for the perfe&bholigct;ing thereof who are hereby required with all care and diligence to assesse the same equally
by a pound rate upon all Lands Tenements Hereditaments Annuityes Rents Parks Warrens Goods Chattells Stocke
Merchandize Offices (other then Judiciall and Military Offices and Offices relateing to the Navy under the Command
of the Lord High Admirall and Offices within His Majestyes Household) Tolls Proffitts and all other Estates both
reall and personall within the Limitts, Circuits and Bounds of their respe&bholigct;ive parishes and places.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>V. &pound;206, 458. 6s. 8d. to be paid to Receiver General 3d June 1673.</head>
			<para id="p275">&pound;206, 458. 6s. 8d. Second Payment, 3d Sept 1673. &pound;206, 458. 6s. 8d. Third quarterly Payment, 3rd Dec. 1673.; &pound;206, 458. 6s. 8d. Fourth quarterly Payment, 3rd March 1673. &pound;206, 458. 6s. 8d. Sixth and last quarterly Payment, 3rd June 1674.; &pound;206, 458. 6s. 8d. Sixth and last quarterly Payment, 3d Sept. 1674.</para>
			<para id="p276">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower
hundred fifty eight pounds six shillings and eight pence being the first of the said six quarterly payments hereby
imposed shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid into the Receiver Generall of the said severall Countyes
who shall be appointed by His Majestie and who are hereby required to transmitt or cause the same to be paid
into His Majestyes Receipt of his Exchequer on or before the third day of June in the yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred seaventy and three, and the Summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred fifty
eight pounds six shillings and eight pence being the second of the said quarterly payments on or before the third
day of September in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and three, and the Summe of
Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred fifty eight pounds, six shillings and eight pence being the third of
the said quarterly payments on or before the third day of December in the Yeare of our Lord one thousand six
hundred seaventy and three, and the Summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred fifty eight pounds
six shillings and eight pence being the fowerth of the said quarterly payments on or before the third day of March
in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and three, and the Summe of Two hundred and
six thousand fower hundred fifty eight pounds six shillings and eight pence being the fifth of the said quarterly
payments on or before the third day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and
fower, and the Summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred fifty eight pounds six shillings and
eight pence being the sixth of the said quarterly payments on or before the third day of September in the yeare
of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and fower.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VI. Assessors to deliver Copy of Assessment to the Commissioners, who are to sign and seat Two Duplicates thereof, and to deliver one to Collector, whom they are to nominate, with a Warrant for the Colle&bholigct;ion.</head>
			<para id="p277">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to deliver a Schedule of Sums assessed to Receiver General, who is to transmit the same to the Exchequer.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p278">And for the compleating of the whole Summe charged upon the same and to the end the aforesaid Summes
charged upon the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places may be equally and
indifferently assessed according to the true intent of this A&bholigct; and the money duely colle&bholigct;ed and true accompt
theirof made The said Assessors are hereby required to deliver one Copy of their respe&bholigct;ive Assessments fairely
written and subscribed by them unto the said Commissioners and the said Commissioners or any two or more
of them are hereby ordered and required to signe and seale two duplicates of the said Assesments and the one
of them to deliver or cause to be delivered to one or more honest and responsible person or persons to be
colle&bholigct;or or colle&bholigct;ors which the said Commissioners are hereby authorized to nominate and appoint for each
parish or place with Warrant to the said Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors to colle&bholigct; the said Assesment payable as aforesaid
soe as the said severall Summes may be paid in to the said Receivers Generall, and by them into the Receipt of
His Majesties Exchequer at the respe&bholigct;ive times aforesaid, and the said Commissioners are hereby required to
deliver or cause to be delivered a Schedule or note containing the particular Summes assessed upon each parish
or place to the Receiver Generall of each County, Citty Towne or Place respe&bholigct;ively to be by him the said
Receiver Generall transmitted into the Kings Remembrancers Office in the Exchequer, which the said Receiver
Generall is required to performe accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VII. Money received by Colle&bholigct;ors to be paid to Receiver General or his Deputy, who shall give Notice to Commissioners of such Payment. Receipt of Receiver General to be a Discharge.</head>
			<para id="p279">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authoritie aforesaid That the money received by the said
Colle&bholigct;ors within the respe&bholigct;ive Divisions or Hundreds shall from time to time be duely paid to the ReceiverGenerall or his Deputy or Deputyes to be appointed under his hand and seale whereof notice under the hand
and seale of the Receiver Generall shall be given unto the Commissioners or any two of them within the respe&bholigct;ive
Divisions or Hundreds within ten dayes after the first Generall Meeting and soe from time to time within ten
dayes after every death or removall of any Deputy if any such shall happen, and the Receipt of such Receiver
Generall his Deputy or Deputyes or any one of them shall be a sufficient discharge unto every such Colle&bholigct;or</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>VIII. Colle&bholigct;ors to pay Monies received by them to Receiver General or his Deputy, who is to transmit such Monies to the Exchequer. Salary to Receiver General 2nd. in the Pound in case he hath returned. Duplicate of Assessment into Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p280">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the particular Colle&bholigct;ors are hereby required to pay in all and
every the Summes soe received by them unto the said Receivers-Generall aforesaid or their deputy or deputyes,
for payment whereof the said Colle&bholigct;ors shall not be oblidged to travell above ten miles from the place of their
habitations, which said Receivers Generall are hereby required forthwith to transmitt or (<ref idref="n156">156</ref>) cause to be paid the
Moneyes by them received into the Receipt of His Majestyes Exchequer, And the said Lord Treasurer is hereby
authorized to allow the said Receiver-General I of each County, Citty and Towne respectively in case he hath
returned up as aforesaid a duplicate of the Assesment of each parish or place in the County Citty or Towne for
which he is appointed Receiver-Generall a Sallary for his paines not exceeding two pence in the pound upon the
clearing of his accompt, which duplicate soe to be returned into the Kings Remembrancers Office in the Exchequer
is intended to containe noe more then the Summes in grosse to bee colle&bholigct;ed by each Colle&bholigct;or and the severall
names of the said Colle&bholigct;ors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>IX. Colle&bholigct;ors allowed 3d. in the Pound;</head>
<para id="p281"><emph type="i">to be detained out of the last Payment. Allowance of one penny in the Pound to Commissioners' Clerks.</emph></para>
			<para id="p282">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the Colle&bholigct;ors of each parish or place which shall be
appointed by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall upon the colle&bholigct;ion of the whole summe appointed to be colle&bholigct;ed by them
and payment theirof as is hereby and before appointed have and receive for their paines in colle&bholigct;sing and paying
the moneyes three pence in the pound, which the said Colle&bholigct;ors are impowered to detaine out of the last payment
of the money of their severall and respe&bholigct;ive quarterly payments And the said Receivor Generall upon the receipt
of the whole Assesment of the County Citty or Towne for which he is appointed Receiver Generall in case he
hath received the severall duplicates of each parish or place therein and not otherwise shall allow and pay according
to such warrant as shall be in that behalfe given by the Commissioners or any three of them one penny in the
pound for the Commissioners Clerkes for their paines in faire writeing the Assesments Duplicates and Copies.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>X. Persons charged refusing, &amp;c, to pay.</head>
			<para id="p283">
				<emph type="i">Distress. Colle&bholigct;ors may break open Doors in the Day-time, and upon Warrant from Commissioners may break open any Chest, &amp;c. to call in Constables, &amp;c. who are to aid Colle&bholigct;ors. Questions upon such Distress to be determined by Commissioners. Persons not paying, or conveying away Goods, &amp;c. Commissioners may imprison, except Peers. Tenants may pay the Rate and dedu&bholigct; out of Rent. Landlord to allow such Dedu&bholigct;ion.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p284">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that if any person shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to pay any summe of money
whereat be shall be, rated and assessed that then it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Colle&bholigct;ors or
any of them who are hereby authorized and required thereunto to leavy the Summe assessed by distresse and sale
of the Goods of such [person<ref idref="n157">157</ref>] soe refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing to pay dedu&bholigct;ing the Summe assessed and reasonable
charges of destraining and restore the overplus to the owner thereof, and to breake open in the day time any
house, and upon Warrant under the hands and seales of two or three of the said C&bhooov;missers any Chest Trunke
Box or other things where any such goods are, and to call to their assistance the Constables Tythingmen and
Headburroughes within the Countyes Cittyes Townes and Places where any refusall, negle&bholigct; or resistance shall be
made, which said Officers are hereby required to be aiding and assisting in the premisses as they will answere
the contrary at their perills. And if any question or difference happen upon takeing of such distresses betweene
the partyes distressed or distrained the same shall be ended and determined by the said Commissioners or any two
or more of them. And if any person or persons shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to pay his or their assesment, or convey
his or their goods or other personall estate whereby the summes of money soe assessed cannot be leavyed according
to this A&bholigct;, then the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any two or more of them are hereby authorized to imprison
the person except a Peere or Peeres of this Realme and him and them in prison to detaine and keepe untill
the moneys soe assessed and the charges for the bringing in the same be paid and satisfyed and noe longer And the
severall and respe&bholigct;ive tennants or tennants of all houses and lands which shall be rated by vertue of this Act
are hereby required. and authorized to pay such summe or summes of money as shall be rated upon such houses
or lands and to dedu&bholigct; out of the rent soe much of the said rates as in respe&bholigct; of the said rents of every such
house and lands the landlord should or ought to pay and beare. And the said landlords both mediate and
immediate according to their respe&bholigct;ive interests are hereby required to allow such dedu&bholigct;sions and payments upon
the receipt of the residue of the rents.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XI. Tenant paying to be acquitted to Amount of Payment.</head>
			<para id="p285">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may settle Difference between Landlord and Tenant as to Rate.; Persons over-rated may complain (within Six Days after Demand) to Commissioners; In case Proportions of Rate not fully assessed, or Persons not of Ability, or upon Empty House; or if Assessments not paid to Receiver General or Deputy; Commissioners, Assessors, &amp;c. are to re-assess.; Such new Assessment to be made, &amp;c. as the former Assessment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p286">And it is ena&bholigct;ed and declared That every tennant paying the said Assesment shall be acquitted and discharged
for soe much Money as the said Assesments shall amount unto as if the same had beene a&bholigct;ually paid unto such person
or persons unto whome his rents should have beene due and payable And if any difference shall arise betweene
Landlord and Tennant or any other concerning the said rates the said severall Commissioners or any two or more
of them in their severall Divisions shall and have hereby power to setle the same as they shall thinke fitt And
if any person or persons shall finde him or themselves aggreived in that the Assessors have overrated him or
them and shall within six dayes after demand made of the summe of money assessed on him or them complaine
to two or more Commissioners whereof one of the C&bhooov;missers who signed or allowed his or their Assesment to
be one, the said Commissioners or any two or more of them shall have and have hereby power within twelve
dayes after the demand of the Assesment as aforesaid to relieve such person or persons and to charge the same
on such other person or persons as they shall see cause, and in case the proportions sett by this A&bholigct; upon all
and every the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Townes and Places shall not be fully assessed levyed and paid according
to the true meaning thereof or that (<ref idref="n158">158</ref>) any of the said Assesments shall be rated and imposed upon any person
not being of ability to pay the same, or upon any empty or void house or land where the same cannot be
colle&bholigct;ed or levyed, or that through any wilfulnes, negligence or mistake or accident the said Assesment charged
upon each County, Citty Towne or Place by vertue of this A&bholigct; happens not to be paid to the Receiver-generall his
deputy or deputyes'of the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes as in this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed That then [in<ref idref="n159">159</ref>] all and every such
cases the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners Assessors and Colle&bholigct;ors aforesaid and every of them respe&bholigct;ively
are hereby authorized and required to assesse or reassesse or cause to be assessed or reassessed leavyed and paid
all and every such summe and summes of money upon the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Townes and Places or upon
any the Divisions Hundreds and Parishes therein as to the said Commissioners or such number of them as by
this A&bholigct; are authorized to cause the first Assesment hereby required to be made shall seeme most agreeable to
equity and justice, the said new Assesment to be made colle&bholigct;ed and paid in such manner and by such meanes as
in this A&bholigct; for this Assesment is declared and directed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XII. Persons not executing A&bholigct;, Commissioners may fine;</head>
			<para id="p287">
				<emph type="i">To be levied by Distress.; and paid to Receiver General and by him into Exchequer.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p288">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid that if any person or persons shall wilfully
negle&bholigct; or refuse to performe his or their duty in the due and speedy execution of this present A&bholigct; the said
respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any three or more of them have hereby power to impose on such person or persons
soe refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing their dutyes such fine or fines as to them shall be thought fitt and to cause the
same to be levyed by distresse and sale of his and their goods. Provided that noe fine to be imposed by any of
the said Commissioners shall for any one offence exceede the summe of twenty pounds, and that all fines that
shall be imposed by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be paid to the respective Receivers Generall and by them to the
Receipt of His Majestyes Exchequer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIII. Colle&bholigct;or negle&bholigct;ing to pay, or detaining Monies, Proceedings by Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p289">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners so proceeding to appoint a general Meeting of Commissioners, Notice thereof.; Colle&bholigct;ors not paying, Proceedings by Commissioners.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p290">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That if any Colle&bholigct;or that shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; be appointed for
the receipt of any summe or summes of money thereby to be assessed shall negle&bholigct; or refuse to pay any summe
or summes of money which shall by him be received as aforesaid and to pay the same as in and by this A&bholigct; is
dire&bholigct;ed and shall detaine in his or their hands any money received by them or any of them and not pay the
same as by this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed the Commissioners of each County Citty or Towne respe&bholigct;ively or any two or
more of them in their respe&bholigct;ive Divisions are hereby authorized and impowered to imprison the person and seize
and secure the estate both reall and personall of such Colle&bholigct;or to him belonging or which shall descend or come
into the hands or possession of his heires executors or administrators wherever the same can be discovered and
found, And the said Commissioners who shall soe seize and secure the estate of any Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors shall
be and are hereby impowered to appoint a time for the generall meeting of the Commissioners of such County
Citty or Towne and there to cause publique notice to be given at the place where such meeting shall be appointed
ten dayes at least before such generall meeting; and the Commissioners present at such generall meeting or the
major part of them in case the moneys detained by any Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors be not paid or satisfyed as it
ought to be according to the dire&bholigct;ions of this A&bholigct; shall and are hereby impowered and required to sell and
dispose of all such estates which shall be for the cause aforesaid seized and secured or any part of them,
and satisfie and pay such County and place the summe that shall be soe detained in the hands of such Colle&bholigct;or
or Colle&bholigct;ors and returne the overplus, dedu&bholigct;ing necessary charges to such colle&bholigct;or or colle&bholigct;ors their heires
executors and administrators respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XIV. At Expiration of Times for quarterly Payments Commissioners are to call Colle&bholigct;ors before them, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p291">
				<emph type="i">and in case of Failure Commissioners to cause same to be levied and paid.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p292">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that at the expiration of the respe&bholigct;ive times in this A&bholigct; prescribed
for the full payment of the said quarterly Assesments the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any two of
them within their Division and Hundred shall and are hereby required to call before them the Colle&bholigct;ors within
each respe&bholigct;ive Division and Hundred to examine and assure themselves of the full and whole payment of the
particular summe and summes of money charged upon the same Division Hundred and every Parish and Place
therein and of the due returne of the same into the hands of the Receivers-generall their deputy or deputyes or
the said County Citty Towne and Place respe&bholigct;ively and by such Receivers-generall into the Receipt of His Majestyes
Exchequer to the end there may be noe failer [in the payment<ref idref="n160">160</ref>] of any part of the Assesment by vertue of this
A&bholigct; to be assessed and paid nor any arrears remaine chargeable upon any the said Countyes Cittyes Townes or
Places respe&bholigct;ively and in case of any failer in the premisses the said Commissioners or any two of them are
hereby to cause the same to be forthwith leavyed and paid according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XV. On Questions respe&bholigct;ing Assessments, &amp;c. in which Commissioners concerned, they have no Voice.</head>
			<para id="p293">And it is hereby enacted and declared That in case any controversie arise concerning the said Assesment or the
dividing apportioning or payment thereof which concerns any the Commissioners by this A&bholigct; appointed, that the
Commissioners soe concerned in the said Controversie shall have noe voice but shall withdraw at the time of the
debate of any such controversie untill it be determined by the rest of the Commissioners.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVI. Privileged Places; or Persons, &amp;c. not exempt from Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p294">
				<emph type="i">Fee-farm and other Rents, Annuities, &amp;c. liable; Tenants to pay proportionably.; Indemnified.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p295">And bee it hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That noe priviledged place or person Body Pollitique or Corporate
within the Countyes Cittyes and Townes aforesaid shall be exempted from the said Assesments and Taxes and that
they and every of them and alsoe all Fee Farme Rents and all other manner of Rents payments summes of money
Annuityes issueing out of any lands within Citty or County shall be lyable towards the payment of every summe
by this A&bholigct; to be taxed and leavyed And all the tennants of every Fee-farme Rent, other rent summes of money
or annuityes aforesaid are hereby dire&bholigct;ed and authorized to pay them proportionably according to the rates and
assesments by this A&bholigct; appointed and dire&bholigct;ed, and all such tennants shall be hereby saved and kept harmelesse
by authority of this A&bholigct; from any further payment of such portion of any such rent rents summes or annuityes
either to the Exchequer or to any other person or persons to whome any such rent rents summes of money or
annuityes as aforesaid should or ought to be paid to all intents and purposes whatsoever as fully and as amply
as if they had paid the same into the Exchequer or to any person or persons to whom the same is reserved or
become due.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVII. Provison for the Colleges in the Two Universities the Colleges of Windsor, Eton, Winchester, and Westminster, and for Hospitals, in respe&bholigct; of Scites of the Colleges, &amp;c. and for Lands belonging to Christ's Hospital and other Hospitals.</head>
			<para id="p296">Provided that nothing contained in this A&bholigct; shall be extended to charge any Colledge or Hall in either of
the Universityes or the Colledge of Windsor, Eaton, Winton or Westminster or any Hospitalls for or in respe&bholigct;
of the Scites of the said Colledges or Halls or Hospitalls nor any Master Fellow or Scholler of any such Colledge
or Hall or in any other Free Schooles or any Reader Officer or Minister of the said Universityes Colledges or
Schooles or of any Hospitalls or Almes-houses for or in respe&bholigct; of any Stipend Wages or Proffitt whatsoever ariseing
or growing due to them in respe&bholigct; of the said severall places and imployments in the said Universityes Colledges
Schooles Hospitalls or Almes houses nor to charge any of the houses or lands belonging to Christs-Hospitall Saint
Bartholomews Bridewell Saint Thomas and Bethlehem Hospitall in the Citty of London and Burrough or Southwarke
or any of them for or in respe&bholigct; of any rents or revenues payable to the said Hospitalls being to be received and
disbursed for the immediate use and releife of the poore in the said Hospitalls. Provided that noe tennants that
hold or enjoy any Lands or houses by lease or other Grant from any of the said Hospitalls doe claime and
enjoy any freedome exemption or advantage by this A&bholigct; but that all the houses and lands which they soe hold
shall be rated and assessed for soe much as they are yearely worth over and above the Rents reserved and payable
to the said Hospitalls.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XVIII. Persons having a House in one Parish, &amp;c. and Goods in another to be charged for such Goods, &amp;c. where they dwell.</head>
			<para id="p297">Provided alsoe that where any person inhabiting within the Citty of London hath his dwelling house in
one of the parishes or wards therein and hath any goods wares or merchandices in one or more of the other
parishes or wards within the same that then such person shall be charged taxed and assessed for such his goods
or merchandize in the parish or ward where he dweleth and not elsewhere in the said Citty.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XIX. No Clause in this A&bholigct; to extend to lessen the Rate.</head>
			<para id="p298">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to account to Treasury, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p299">Provided neverthelesse That noe Clause or Provisoe in this A&bholigct; shall extend to the, lessening or abatement of
the full summe by this A&bholigct; appointed to bee taxed leavyed and paid but that the same be fully assessed
taxed leavyed colle&bholigct;ed and paid in the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes and Townes aforesaid in such
manner and forme and to such uses as herein before is mentioned and declared And that the severall and
respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners and every of them shall from time to time give a true and perfe&bholigct; accompt of all their
doeings and proceedings in the execution of this A&bholigct; to the said Lord Treasurer or to other such person as his
Majestie shall appoint.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XX. Proceedings in case the assessing by Pound Rate shall be found to obstru&bholigct; the speedy bringing in of the Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p300">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared that in case the way (<ref idref="n161">161</ref>) or manner of assessing by a
pound rate shall prove any way prejudiciall or obstru&bholigct;ive to the said speedy bringing in of the Assesment or
any part thereof appointed by this A&bholigct; that then and in all such cases the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any two
of them are hereby authorized to order and dire&bholigct; their respe&bholigct;ive Assessors who are hereby required to proceede
accordingly to assesse the respe&bholigct;ive Summs charged on the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes and Burroughes Townes
and Places mentioned in this A&bholigct; according to the most just and usuall way of rates held and pra&bholigct;ized in such
Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and places respe&bholigct;ively Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof
contained in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXI. Proviso for Contra&bholigct;s between Landlords and Tenants as to Payment of Taxes.</head>
			<para id="p301">Provided alwayes That nothing in this A&bholigct; contained shall be construed to alter change determine or make
void any Contra&bholigct;s Covenants or Agreements whatsoever between the Landlord and Tennant touching the payment
of Taxes and Assesments Any thing herein before mentioned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXII. Places used to be assessed to pay and be assessed in such County, &amp;c. as heretofore.</head>
			<para id="p302">Provided alwayes and Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid That for the avoiding
of all obstru&bholigct;ions and delayes in colle&bholigct;ing the Summes by this A&bholigct; to be rated and assessed, all places
Constablewicks Divisions and Allotments which have used to be rated and assessed shall pay and be assessed in
such County Hundred Rape and Wapentake as the same hath heretofore beene usually assessed in and not
elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIII. In A&bholigct;ions for executing A&bholigct;. General Issue.</head>
			<para id="p303">
				<emph type="i">Treble Costs.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p304">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion Plainte Suite or Information shall be
commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in execution
of this A&bholigct; such person or persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall and may pleade the generall issue not
guilty, and upon any Issue joyned may give this A&bholigct; and the speciall matter in evidence, and if the Plaintiffe
or Prosecutor shall become nonsuite, or forbeare further prosecution or suffer a discontinuance, or if a Verdi&bholigct;
passe against him, the defendants shall recover their treble costs for which they shall have the like remedy as in
any case where costs by the Law are given to defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXIV. Proviso for a Decree in Chancery respe&bholigct;ing Suits between the Counties of Salop and Stafford, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p305">Provided alwayes that nothing in this A&bholigct; shall extend or be construed to invalidate a Decree lately made in
the High Court of Chauncery for quieting of Suits betweene the Countyes of Salop and Stafford and for the
setleing all future payments to be imposed on certaine Lands in Sheriffe-Hales with the County of Salop, and for
exempting the said Lands from paying hereafter with the County of Stafford, but that the said Decree shall
remaine in such (and noe other) force as it did before the makeing of this A&bholigct;. Any thing herein to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXV. Receivers General and their Deputies to give Acquittances to Colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
			<para id="p306">
				<emph type="i">Such Acquittance to be a Discharge.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p307">Provided alwaies and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authorise aforesaid That the severall Receivers Generall which
shall be appointed according to this A&bholigct; their deputy or deputyes shall from time to time at every payment
appointed thereby give unto the severall Colle&bholigct;ors within their respe&bholigct;ive Precin&bholigct;s upon the payment of the whole
summe due at such times of payment from their respe&bholigct;ive parishes Constablewicks or Places within each of their
Colle&bholigct;ions severall Acquittances under their hands without takeing any thing for the same, and that in like
manner at every time of payment appointed by this A&bholigct;, the Receiver Generall of each County his deputy or
deputyes shall give unto the severall Colle&bholigct;ors aforesaid upon the payment of the whole summe due for their
Parish or Place respe&bholigct;ively at each time of payment aforesaid Severall Acquittances under their hands and seales
without takeing any thing for the same, Which said Acquittances of the Receiver Generall his deputy or deputyes
shall be a full and perfe&bholigct; discharge to the Colle&bholigct;ors, And the said Acquittances of the Receiver Generall his
deputy or deputyes shall be a sufficient discharge to the Colle&bholigct;ors and to such parish or place respe&bholigct;ively and
to every person charged within the said Colle&bholigct;ors Charge against His Majestie his heires and successors for the
summe or summes of money soe acquitted.</para>
		</section>
<section id="s27">
<head>XXVI. Where Lands, &amp;c. unoccupied and no Distress found, Colle&bholigct;ors, Constables, &amp;c. may enter and distrain.</head>
<para id="p308"><emph type="i">Proceedings thereon.</emph></para>
<para id="p309">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That in case any Lands or Houses in any Parish Place or
Constablewicke shall [be<ref idref="n162">162</ref>] unoccupyed and noe distresses can be found on the same by reason whereof the said
Parish Place or Constablewicke are forced to pay and make good the Tax assessed upon such Land lying
unoccupyed that then it shall and may be lawfull at any time after for the Colle&bholigct;ors Constable or Tythingman
of the said Parish, Place or Constablewicke for the time being to enter and destraine upon the said Lands or
Houses when there shall be any distresse thereupon to be found, and the distresse and distresses being the proper
goods of the Owner or any claiming any estate interest or proffitt under him if not redeemed within fower dayes
by payment of the tax and charge of the distresse to sell rendering the overplus to the owner or owners of such
distresse And the said Colle&bholigct;or Constable or Tythingman is hereby enjoyned to distribute the money raised by
the said distresse or sale theirof proportionably to the partyes who contributed to the taxe of the said unoccupyed
Lands.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVII. Where Woodlands assessed and no Distress had, Colle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. may enter and cut Wood, &amp;c. growing.</head>
			<para id="p310">
				<emph type="i">Buyer may sell, rendering Overplus to Owner</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p311">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That where any Wood-Lands shall be assessed and noe distresse can be
had that in such case it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Colle&bholigct;or Constable Headburrough or Tythingman
by warrant under the hands and seales of two or more of the Commissioners of that Hundred or Division at
seasonable times of the yeare to cutt and sell to any person or persons soe much of the Wood growing on the
Wood-lands soe assessed as will pay the Assessment or Assessments soe behinde and unpaid and the charge incident
thereunto, and that it shall and may be lawfull for the person and persons and his Assignes to whome such wood
shall be soe sold, to sell, cutt downe, dispose and carry away the same to his owne use rendering the overplus
(if any be) to the owner, Any Law to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXVIII. Proceedings where Assessment Charged on Property not distrainable.</head>
			<para id="p312">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that where any Tax or Assessment shall be charged [or laid]
upon any Tythes Tolls Proffitts of Markets Faires or Fishery or other annuall Proffitts not destrainable in case the
same shall not be paid within fifteene dayes after such Assessment soe charged or laid and demanded then it shall
be lawfull to and for the Colle&bholigct;or Constable or other Officer thereunto appointed by warrant under the hands
and seales of any two or more of the Commissioners authorized by this A&bholigct; to seise take and sell soe much of
the said Tythes Tolls and other Proffitts soe charged as shall be sufficient for the leavying of the said Tax and
Assessment and all charges occasioned by such non payment thereof rendering the overplus to the Owner if any be.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXIX. Three Commissioners for Middlessex and Westminster may appoint Assessors;</head>
			<para id="p313">
				<emph type="i">who are to ascertain and rate the Value of Offices, and to return the same to the Commissioners, &amp;c. and to deliver their Surveys subscribed to the Commissioners, &amp;c. before the Second, General Meeting.; Commissioners at such Meeting to cast up the Revenue of the County, &amp;c. and proportion Charge.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p314">And whereas the County of Midlesex and Citty of Westminster are raised in the monethly Assesments by
reason of the new buildings lately ere&bholigct;ed and that Offices are made chargeable towards the payment of such
Assesments To the end that and equall rate may be made and imposed upon the severall Divisions Parishes and
Hamletts within the said County and Citty Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by this present Parlyament and the authority thereof
That the said C&bhooov;missioners appointed for the said County and Citty of Westminster or any three of them shall if
they shall thinke it fitt, cause two or three of the honest and able Inhabitants in the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Parishes
Towneshipps and Places within the said County and Citty to be named and appointed Assessors, who (or any two
of them) are to ascertaine and rate the yearely value and proffitt of all Offices belonging to the Courts at
Westminster and other Offices chargeable by this A&bholigct; towards the payment of the said summe sett upon the said
County and Citty and all Towneshipps Parishes and Places for which they are appointed Assessors and to returne
the same to the said Commissioners or to such person or persons as shall be appointed to receive the same which
said Assessors are to deliver in their severall Surveyes perfe&bholigct;ed and subscribed by them unto the said
Commissioners or unto such person or persons as shall be appointed by them or any three of them to receive
the same two or three dayes at the least before the second generall meeting of the said Commissioners to the
end that the said Commissioners may deliver in all the severall Surveyes to be made throughout the said County at
the [said<ref idref="n163">163</ref>] second generall meeting at which said generall meeting the said Commissioners or the major part of
them then present shall upon view and perusall of the said severall Surveyes cast up the true Revenue and yearely
Proffitts of the whole County Citty and Offices aforesaid to the end that an equall pound rate may be apportioned upon
every Office chargeable by this A&bholigct; Division Hundred Towneshipp and Parrish according to the proportion and
summe of money charged upon the said County and City by vertue of this present A&bholigct; which the said
Commissioners or the major part of them then and there assembled are by vertue of this A&bholigct; authorized and
appointed to proportion and make accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXX. Proviso for the ancient Rights of Peers, Clergy, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p315">Provided alwayes That nothing herein contained shall be drawne into example to the prejudice of the auntient
rights belonging to the Lords Spirituall and Temporall or Clergy of this Realme or unto either of the Universityes
or unto any Colledges Schooles Almeshouses Hospitalls or Cinque Ports.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXI. For Three Years, &amp;c. when Corn is at the Price herein mentioned Persons shipping for Exportation to bring a Certificate of Quantity and Quality of Corn on Oath to the Commissioners, &amp;c.</head>
<para id="p316"><emph type="i">and thereupon; and upon Bond given not to reland the same Corn, &amp;c.; to receive the Bounties herein mentioned without Fee; and upon Certificate of Corn being duly landed, Bond to be delivered up to Exporter to be cancelled without Fee; and Commissioners, &amp;c. discharged.</emph></para>
			<para id="p317">And to the end that all Owners of Land whereupon this Taxe principally lyeth may be the better enabled to pay
the same by rendering the labours of the [husbandmen<ref idref="n164">164</ref>] in raising corne and graine more valuable by exportation
of the same into forreigne parts which now is already at a very low rate and that the Nation in generall may
have her stocke increased by the returns thereof Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that for the space of three yeares from
the first day of this Session of Parlyament and from thenceforward to the end of the next Session of Parlyament
when Mault or Barley (Winchester Measure) is or shall be at twenty fower shillings a quarter, Rye thirty two
shillings a quarter and Wheater forty eight shillings a quarter or under in any Port or Ports of this Kingdome or
Dominion of Wales every Merchant or other person who shall putt on Shipboard in English Shipping (the Master
and two thirds of the Marriners at least being His Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s) any sorts of the corne aforesaid from any
such Ports where the rates shall not then be higher then as aforesaid with intent to export the said Corne to
parts beyond the Seas, every such merchant or other person shall bring a Certificate in writeing under his or their
hands containing the quantity and quality of Corne soe shipped to the Farmers Commissioners Colle&bholigct;ors or other
persons appointed or to be appointed by His Majestie his heires or successors to colle&bholigct; the dutyes and rates
ariseing by Customes within any such Port and upon proofe made of any such Certificate by one or more credible
persons upon their oathes which oathes the said Commissioners or other persons are hereby authorized and required
to administer, and upon bond given by every such Merchant or other person in the Summe of Two hundred
pounds at the least for every hundred Tunns of Corne soe shipped and soe proportionably, that the said Corne
(danger of the Seas excepted) shall be exported into parts beyond the Seas and not be againe landed in the
Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales the Islands of Guernsey or, Jersey or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede
every such Merchant soe shipping off any of the aforesaid Corne and giveing Certificate and bond as aforesaid
shall have and receive from such Farmers Commissioners Colle&bholigct;ors or other persons in any port respe&bholigct;ively where
the same Corne shall be soe shipped for every quarter of Barley or Mault ground or unground two shillings and
six pence, for every quarter of Rye ground or unground three shillings and six pence, for every quarter of
Wheate ground or unground five Shillings, which Summe or Summes every such Commissioner Farmer or other
persons are hereby authorized and required upon demand by such Exporter to make present payment of accordingly
without takeing or requireing any thing for custome or any fee or reward for corne soe loaden to be exported,
or for soe much graine as shall be exported in any shipp wherein any other goods shall be shipped Any Law
Statute or Usage in any wise to the contrary notwithstanding. And upon Certificate returned under the Common
Seale of the Cheife Magistrate in any place or places beyond the Seas, or under the hands and seales of two
knowne English Merchants upon the place that such Corne was there landed, or upon proofe by credible persons
that such Corne was taken by Enemies or perished in the Seas, the examination and proofe thereof being left to
the judgement of such Commissioners Farmers or other persons, which proofe being made or certificate delivered to
such person or persons respe&bholigct;ively as tooke bond as aforesaid the said bond shall be delivered up to such Importer
or his order to be cancelled without any fee for the same, and the moneys by any such Commissioners Farmers
Colle&bholigct;or or other person soe paid in obedience to this A&bholigct; shall be accepted [of<ref idref="n165">165</ref>] in his or their Accompts as
soe much paid to His Majestie, and he and they is and shall be discharged thereof accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXII. Receivers General certifying Arrears due where Monies have been received.</head>
			<para id="p318">
				<emph type="i">Penalty to Party.; Penalty to His Majesty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p319">And for the better preventing of such unjust vexations as might bee occasioned by such persons as shall be
appointed Receivers Generall of any of the Summes of money granted by this A&bholigct;, And to the intent that the
said Receivers Generall may returne a true accompt into His Majestyes Court of Exchequer of such Summes of
money as shall be received by them and every of them their and every of their deputy and deputyes Bee it
further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any [such<ref idref="n165">165</ref>] Receiver Generall shall returne or certifie into
the said Court any Summe or Summes of money to be in arreare or unpaid after the same hath beene received
either by such Receiver Generall or his deputy or deputyes or any of them, or shall cause any person or persons
to be sett insuper in the said Court for any Summe or Summes of money that hath beene soe received, That
then every such Receiver Generall shall forfeite to every person and persons that shall be molested vexed or
dammaged by reason of such unjust Certificate returne or setting insuper treble the damages that shall be thereby
occasioned, The said damages to be recovered by a&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in which noe Essoigne
Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager in Law shall be allowed nor any more then one imparlance and shall alsoe forfeite to His
Majestie his heires and successors double the summe that shall be soe unjustly certified or returned or cause to
be sett insuper.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Esq&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Purbeck <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Cholmondley.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Barront <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Delves Barron <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="
n12" number="6">Barron<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Cholmondsley Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">Gent. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">Wilfrid <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">Elvaston <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">Calmady <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">Fusse <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">Goulston <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">Silas Tithus <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">Stanley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">Crosby <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">Barronett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">Knight <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">Keete <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41">Hudd <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n42" number="42">Bunce <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n43" number="43">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n44" number="44">Gent.1 <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n45" number="45">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n46" number="46">Alderman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n47" number="47">Chisnwall <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n48" number="48">Otway <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n49" number="49">Dobson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n50" number="50">Gentlemen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n51" number="51">Gentleman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n52" number="52">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n53" number="53">Baronet <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n54" number="54">Barr<emph type="p">ti</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n55" number="55">Barron<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n56" number="56">Barron<emph type="p">tt</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n57" number="57">Knight <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n58" number="58">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n59" number="59">Es&bhoqesq;<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n60" number="60">Barronets <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n61" number="61">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n62" number="62">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n63" number="63">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n64" number="64">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n65" number="65">Knight <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n66" number="66">Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n67" number="67">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n68" number="68">King <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n69" number="69">Serjant <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n70" number="70">his <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n71" number="71">Law <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n72" number="72">Carey <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n73" number="73">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n74" number="74">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n75" number="75">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n76" number="76">Rober <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n77" number="77">Blank in Original.</note>
			<note id="n78" number="78">Griffiths <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n79" number="79">Lockier <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n80" number="80">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n81" number="81">Baronett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n82" number="82">Gentlemen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n83" number="83">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n84" number="84">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n85" number="85">Packhurst <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n86" number="86">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n87" number="87">Knight <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n88" number="88">Jansan <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n89" number="89">Roulston <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n90" number="90">Gentleman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n91" number="91">Gothard <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n92" number="92">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n93" number="93">Drury <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n94" number="94">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n95" number="95">Hawley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n96" number="96">Barronett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n97" number="97">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n98" number="98">Blank in Original.</note>
			<note id="n99" number="99">Gentleman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n100" number="100">Esquire; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n101" number="101">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n102" number="102">Chancello<emph type="p">r</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n103" number="103">Heyward <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n104" number="104">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n105" number="105">Mr <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n106" number="106">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n107" number="107">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n108" number="108">Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n109" number="109">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n110" number="110">Thomas <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n111" number="111">Rivett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n112" number="112">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n113" number="113">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n114" number="114">Barronett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n115" number="115">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n116" number="116">Barronetts <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n117" number="117">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n118" number="118">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n119" number="119">Seabright <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n120" number="120">Knights <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n121" number="121">Elmely Castle <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n122" number="122">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n123" number="123">Thistlethwaite <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n124" number="124">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n125" number="125">Esq[uire] <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n126" number="126">Richard <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n127" number="127">Grahme <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n128" number="128">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n129" number="129">Talbott <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n130" number="130">James <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n131" number="131">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n132" number="132">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n133" number="133">Richard <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n134" number="134">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n135" number="135">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n136" number="136">Watkin <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n137" number="137">Banks <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n138" number="138">Taricold <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n139" number="139">Alderman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n140" number="140">William <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n141" number="141">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n142" number="142">Placviha <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n143" number="143">Roger <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n144" number="144">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n145" number="145">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n146" number="146">Nathaniell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n147" number="147">Buller <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n148" number="148">
				<emph type="i">O</emph> omits.</note>
			<note id="n149" number="149">Gentleman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n150" number="150">Barronet <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n151" number="151">Perrott <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n152" number="152">Alderman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n153" number="153">Knt <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n154" number="154">Thomas <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n155" number="155">that <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n156" number="156">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n157" number="157">Persons <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n158" number="158">if <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n159" number="159">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n160" number="160">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n161" number="161">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n162" number="162">lye <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n163" number="163">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n164" number="164">Husbandman. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n165" number="165">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


