<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47453" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1672</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IV. An A&bholigct; for repeale of a Clause in a former A&bholigct; to prohibit Salesmen from selling Fatt Cattell. [Rot. Parl. 25 C. II. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 22 &amp; 23 C. II. c. 19. &sect;2.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">22 &amp; 23 C.II. c. 19. &sect;2. repealed. ; Exception.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; made this p&bhopcrl;sent Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; to prevent Fraudes in the buying and
selling of Cattell in Smithfeild and elsewhere (amongst other things) It is ena&bholigct;ed That noe Jobber Salesman
or other Broker or Fa&bholigct;or, who doe [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] shall commonly buy or sell Cattell for others be allowed or imployed
either for buying or selling any Fatt Cattell other [then<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Swine or Calves by or for any Butcher or other person
or persons whatsoever within fowerscore miles of the Cittyes of London and Westminster upon paine of the
Forfeiture of the vallue of the said Cattell soe bought or sould [by<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] him or them as aforesaid to be paid by the
Owner of such Cattell, And upon further paine That all and every person and persons takeing upon him or them
to use or exercise the said imployment of a Jobber or Broker, or of a Salesman or Fa&bholigct;or for the buying and
selling of Cattell contrary to the said A&bholigct;, shall forfeite for every such offence the vallue of all such Cattell soe
bought or sould or exposed to sale by him or them as aforesaid, But for that the said Clause in the said A&bholigct;
contained is found by experience to be very prejudiciall to the sale of the Cattell of this Realme, and a great
inconvenience and discouragement to those that feede the said Cattell in their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, who by reason
thereof are forced to make Journeyes up in their owne persons to London, or to send others purposely for that
imployment, which commonly taketh up and wasteth all or the greatest part of the Proffitt or Gaine that they
make of their said Cattell, Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie and by and with, the
advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and
by the authoritie of the same That the said Clause and all and singular Penaltyes in the said A&bholigct; relateing
thereunto, soe farr forth as the same doe or may any wayes concerne Salesmen or Fa&bholigct;ors imployed by Feeders
or Farmers, but not as the same doe concerne Salesmen or Fa&bholigct;ors imployed by Butchers, Jobbers or Brokers
shall be and doe stand repealed, and be utterly null and void to all intents and purposes whatsoever.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">for <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


