<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47459" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1672</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for reviveing the Judicature for d?termination of Differences touching Houses burnt downe and demolished
by reason of the late Fire, which happened in London, and for rebuilding of the Navy Office. [Rot. Part, 25 C. II. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that 18 &#x0026; 19 C. II. c. 7. (19 C. II. c.2.) had expired, and had been revived by 22 C. II. c. 11. which had also expired; and that many Houses remained unbuilt.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Judicature for Determination of Differences occasioned by the Fire, continued until 25th Feb. 1675</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an A&bholigct; lately passed in the nineteenth yeare of his Majestyes Raigne entituled An A&bholigct; for ere&bholigct;ing
a Judicature for determination of Differences touching Houses burnt downe and demolished by reason of the
late Fire which happended in London; which said A&bholigct; expired upon the last day of December in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred sixty eight, And by another A&bholigct; made in the two and twentyeth yeare of his
Majestyes Raigne entituled An additionall A&bholigct; for rebuilding the City of London, uniteing the Parishes, and rebuilding
of the Cathedrall and Parochiall Churches within the said City, was revived with additionall authority to the
said Judicature, which said last additionall A&bholigct; expired upon the twenty nineth of September one thousand six
hundred seaventy and one. And whereas there are yet remaining nine hundred Tofts of Ground of Houses burnt
downe and demolished in the said late great Conflagration, and a considerable number of other which were burnt
downe and demolished by reason of a Fire which happened and begunn in his Majesties Navy-Office scituate in
Seething-Lane London on the twenty nineth day of January last past, the rebuilding whereof may be much expedited
by the determination of the Differences, which are or may be betweene the Landlords and Tennants of the said
Houses soe burnt or demolished respe&bholigct;ively, Bee it therefore enacted by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with
the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled
and by the authoritie of the same That the Judicature ere&bholigct;ed by the said two severall A&bholigct;s and all and every
the powers and authorities thereby given to the Justices of the [Courts of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the Kings-Bench and Common Pleas and
Barons of the Coife of the Exchequer for the time being; or any three or more of them, and all other matters
and things therein contained touching the said Judicature shall from henceforth stand and be revived untill the
twenty fifth day of February one thousand six hundred seaventy five, Any clause, matter or thing in the said
A&bholigct;s contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The King's Surveyor to employ so much Ground near the Navy Office lately burnt, as shall be set out.</head>
			<para id="p3">And to the end that his Majestyes Navy-Office in the rebuilding thereof may be inlarged and made more
commodious for his Majestyes use, and better secured from the dangers and casualties of Fire, and that some
convenient distance, intervall and circuit of Ground may be left betweene the said Office and any other Houses
that are or may be contiguous thereunto Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That his Majestyes
Surveyor Generall shall and may and is hereby impowered to employ such places and portions of Ground of the
Houses lately burnt downe and demolished adjacent to the said late Navy-Office as by and with his Majestyes approbation
shall before the first day of May one thousand six hundred seaventy and three be sett out and adjudged necessary,
for the ornament, enlargement, security and conveniencie of the said Office.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Satisfaction to Owners for the same Ground.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">In what Cases the Lord Mayor and Court of Aldermen to impannel a Jury; Verdict of the Jury, Judgement of the Mayor, &#x0026;c. and Payment of the Money awarded, conclusive against the Owners, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p5">And to the intent that reasonable satisfa&bholigct;ion may be given to the Owners and others haveing any Estate or
Interest in the Grounds of the houses lately burnt downe and demolished, and places which shall be sett out to
bee taken and employed for the ornament, security and conveniency of the Navy-Office aforesaid, the said Surveyour
Generall and such other persons shall bee impowered and appointed by his Majestie in that behalfe shall and may
treate and agree with the Owners and others interessed therein; And in case of wilfull refusall or any such disability.
or impediment as in the aforesaid A&bholigct;s are mentioned or other incapacity whatsoever as the Owners thereof or others
interessed therein shall delay or be disabled to treate and agree, the Lord Maior and the Court of Aldermen of
the Citty of London shall and are hereby impowered, authorized and required to cause a Jury to be impannelled
in such manner and forme as by the aforesaid A&bholigct;s is directed and appointed ; soe as noe two of the said Jurrors
(soe to be appointed) shall come out of the same Ward to adjudge and assesse what recompence and satisfa&bholigct;ion
in any or every of the cases aforesaid ought to be awarded and given to the respe&bholigct;ive Owners and others
interressed in the Ground and Places soe sett out to be taken and imployed for the use or purpose aforesaid in
pursuance of this A&bholigct;, according to such their respective Estates and Interests; and the Verdi&bholigct; of such Jury in
that behalfe to be taken and the Judgement of the said Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen of London thereupon
and the payment of the money soe awarded and adjudged at or in the Office of the Chamberlaine of the City of
London, there to remaine by the space of six moneths for the Owners or others interessed therein as aforesaid,
and after that time to be paid unto them by the said Chamberlaine upon demand, if that within that time there,
shall not arise any Controversie touching the payment thereof by reason of different Claimes made thereunto, shall
be binding and conclusive to and against the Owners and all others haveing, (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) claimeing, or to claime any Estate,
Right, Title or Interest of, in, to or out of the same, their Heires, Executors, Administrators, Successors or Assignes,
and every of them, and shall be a full authoritie for his Majestie, his Heires and Successors to cause the same to
be converted to and for the use and purpose aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. In case of Controversy concerning the Division of the Money for the Ground, Court of Judicature, on Petition within Six Months after the Verdict, to determine.</head>
			<para id="p6">And in case any Controversie shall arise betweene any person or persons Bodies Pollitique or Corporate or his
or their Assignes or Under-tenants or other persons claiming any Estate, Right, Title or Interest in Law or Equity,
Trust, Charge or Incumbrance of or in the said places or grounds soe to be purchased or converted as aforesaid,
who shall find him or themselves aggreived for or by reason that the said money soe given in satisfa&bholigct;ion for the
said places or ground is not or, shall not be equally or indifferently apportioned according to the true value of his
or their Interests in the said places or grounds, that then the said Justices of the Courts of the Kings-Bench and
Common Pleas and Barons of the Coife of the Court of Exchequer for the time being or any three or more of
them sitting together at the same time and place upon the petition of the said partie or parties greived, to be
preferred to any one of them within six moneths after the said verdict soe had and given, and not after, are
hereby authorized to heare and finally determine the same, and to order and award such Destribution of the
money soe paid unto the Chamberlaine as aforesaid to the said person or persons Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate
respe&bholigct;ively, according to his and their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Interests in the same, in such manner and forme as
the said Justices and Barons or any three of them may determine any Differences or Demands which have or shall
arise betweene any Landlord or Tenant touching repairing or rebuilding any of the Houses burnt downe or
demolisht by the late Fire afor&eacute;said by vertue of the said A&bholigct;s or either of them:</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Court of Judicature may determine Differences between Landlord and Tenant concerning Houses demolished in Seething Lane.</head>
			<para id="p7">And whereas some Differences are and may arise betweene Landlords and Tenants of the severall Houses lately
burnt or demolished in Seething-Lane, London aforesaid; Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That
the said Judges and Barons or any three or more of them bee, and are hereby authorized and impowered to [heare and
<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
determine all such Cases for all such Houses and Tenements as fully and amply, and in like manner to all intents
and purposes as they could or might heare and determine any the like Differences by vertue of both or either of
the A&bholigct;s aforesaid, and all Decrees and Orders in such Cases to be made shall binde and be obeyed by all parties
therein concerned accordingly.</para>
			<para id="p8">ITEM queda? Petitiones privatas personas concernentes (in se formam A&bholigct;us continentes) exhibite fuerunt predi&bholigct;o
Domino Regi in Parliamento &bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o, quor? Tituli subscribuntur (videlicet)</para>
			<para id="p9">1. An Act for the Setlement of the Re&bholigct;ory of Chudleigh in the County of Devon upon Thomas Lord Clifford
and others.</para>
			<para id="p10">2. An Act to enable James Earle of Salisbury to lett Leases of certaine Lands and Tenements for any terme
not exceeding forty yeares.</para>
			<para id="p11">3. An Act to enable the Deane and Chapter of the Cathedrall Church of Bristoll to exchange their Vicaridge
of Berkley in the County of Gloucester with George Lord Berkley for his Re&bholigct;ory of Saint Michaells in Sutton
Bonnington in the County of Nottingham.</para>
			<para id="p12">4. An Act to enable the Trustees of Sir William Hanham Baronet deceased to sell Lands to pay his debts
according to his owne dire&bholigct;ion in his Life time, and for management of the estate of Sir John Hanham an infant
dureing his minority.</para>
			<para id="p13">5. An Act to confirme Articles of Agreement made upon the marriage of Sir William Rich Baronet.</para>
			<para id="p14">6. An Act for the confirming of an Award made by Sir Orlando Bridgeman Knight and Baronet late Lord
Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the ending of all differences in the family of Sir Thomas Woolrich Knight
and Baronet deceased and to enable John Woolrich Esquire and his heires to execute the powers in the said Award
mentioned.</para>
			<para id="p15">7. An Act for transferring the Interest of a terme of yeares in certaine Mannours and Lands late of Sir Robert
Berkley Knight deceased and payment of Portions appointed to his Grand-children.</para>
			<para id="p16">8. An Act for confirmeing Agreements made betweene Sir Ralph Bancks Sir John Hanham Baronet Ellis Bethell
Thomas Mackrell, Richard Warland and John Edwards by their Guardians, and diverse other persons.</para>
			<para id="p17">9. An Act for explaining and declareing the extant of an exception in a Deed therein named.</para>
			<para id="p18">10. An Act for enabling Robert Bellamy to sell Lands for the payment of his Debts.</para>
			<para id="p19">11. An Act for the naturalizing of Phillip Lloyed Gentleman.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>Anno 27&deg; CAROLI, II. A.D. 1675.</head>
			<para id="p20">(<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) ACTS passed on the 9th of June 1675 in the 27th Yeare of the Reigne of K'g Charles y<emph type="p">e</emph> 2d. in the
Session begun the 13 of Aprill 1675. 27&deg; Car. II. being the 13th Session of the Parliament begun the
8th of May 1661 in the 13th Yeare of his Reigne.</para>
			<para id="p21">1. An Act for granting a licence to His Highnes Prince Rupert Duke of Cumberland for one and thirty yeares.</para>
			<para id="p22">2. An Act to enable Sir Francis Compton to make Sale of the Mannor of Hammerton in the County of
Huntington.</para>
			<para id="p23">3. An Act for the naturalization of Theodore Russell and others.</para>
			<para id="p24">4. An Act to enable Charles Cotton Es&bhoqesq; to sell Lands for payment of debts and raiseing Portions for Younger
Children.</para>
			<para id="p25">5. An Act for enabling Trustees to sell Lands in the Counties of Glamorgan &#x0026; Monmouth, for the Payment
of the Debts of William Lewis Es&bhoqesq; deceased, and the Debts and Legacies of Edward Lewis Es&bhoqesq; deceased his Son.(<ref idref="n5">5</ref>)</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Taken from the Long Calendar at the Parliament Office.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">There is no Roll in Chancery for this Session; and no A&bholigct;s appear at the Parliament Office as Public A&bholigct;s; and the above
Five A&bholigct;s only appear there as Private A&bholigct;s.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


