<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47454" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1672</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An A&bholigct; for the Kings Majestyes most Gratious, Generall and Free Pardon. [Rot. Parl. 25 C. II. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">A Pardon of all Crimes to all Subje&bholigct;s;Pains of Death, &#x0026;c.; not hereafter excepted before and unto 25th March 1673.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Charles R.<br/>
The Kings Majestie most gratiously considering the dutyfull affe&bholigct;ions and faithfull hearts of his most loyall
and obeidient Subje&bholigct;s, and understanding that his good Subje&bholigct;s have many and sundry wayes by the
Lawes and Statutes of this Realme fallen into the danger of diverse great Penalties and Forfeitures, and that the
Persons and Fortunes of his Subje&bholigct;s doe lye open to manifold inconveniencies and may be questioned for severall
matters and things in his Majestyes Courts both Ecclesiasticall and Temporall Is of his Princely and mercyfull
Disposition most gratiously inclined to extend unto them his generall and free Pardon, and that in a more bountyfull
manner then hath beene accustomed. His Majestie most assuredly trusting That all his Subje&bholigct;s by this his Clemency
and indulgent Grace and Favour to them will be the rather moved and induced from henceforth more carefully
to observe his Highnesse Lawes and Statutes and to continue in their Loyall and due Obedience to his Majestie.
And therefore his Majestie is well pleased and contented That it be ena&bholigct;ed by authoritie of this present
Parlyament, And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by authoritie of the same in manner and forme following. That is to say, That
all and every the said Subje&bholigct;s aswell Spirituall as Temporall of this his Highnesse Realme of England, Dominion
of Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede their Heires, Successors Executors and Administrators of them
and every of them and all and singular Bodyes in any manner of wise corporated Cittyes, Burroughes, Shires,
Rideings, Hundreds, Lathes, Rapes, Wapentakes, Townes, Villages, Hamblets and Tythings and every of them and
the Successor and Successors of every of them shall be by Authority of this present Parlyament acquitted, pardoned,
released and discharged against the Kings Majesty his Heires and Successors and every of them of and from all
manner of Treasons, Felonies, Mispresions of Treason, Treasonable or Seditious Words or Libells, Misprisions of
Felony, Seditious and unlawfull Meetings and Conventicles, and, all Offences whereby any person may be charged
with the penalty and danger of Premunire, And all Stampings and Coynings of Farthings, Halfe-pence, Pence,
Two-pence, or such like small Moneys to be used in common payments, without any lawfull authoritie derived
from his Majestie, and all utterings thereof in ordinary payments, as currant Money, And alsoe of, and from all
Ryotts, Routs, Offences, Contempts, Trespasses, Entryes, Wrongs, Deceites, Misdemeanors, Forfeitures, Penaltyes
and Summes of Money, paines of Death, paines. Corporall and paines Pecuniary, and generally of and from all
other Things, Causes, Quarrells, Suites, Judgements and Executions in this present A&bholigct; not hereafter excepted nor
foreprized, which may be or can be by his. Highnesse in any, wise or by any meanes pardoned, before and unto
the five and twentyeth day of March, in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy three, to any
the Subje&bholigct;s or Bodyes Corporate aforesaid.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The Pardon to be as good as if all things were particularly named;and the King's Subje&bholigct;s not to be sued, &#x0026;c. for any Matter done, &#x0026;c. against the Crown before the said 25th March 1673.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Exception.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And alsoe the Kings Majestie is contented that it bee ena&bholigct;ed by authoritie of this present Parlyament And bee
it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie of the same That this is free Pardon shall be as good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law to
every of his said Subje&bholigct;s Bodyes Corporate and others before rehearsed in, for and against all things which be
not hereafter in this present A&bholigct; excepted and foreprized, as the same Pardon should have beene if all Offences,
Contempts, Forfeitures, Causes, Matters, Suites, Quarrells, Judgements, Executions, Penalties and all other things
not hereafter in this present A&bholigct; excepted and foreprized, had beene particularly, singularly, specially and plainly
named, rehearsed and specifyed, and alsoe pardoned by proper and expresse words and names in their kinds,
natures and qualities by words and termes thereunto requisite to have beene putt in and expressed in this present
A&bholigct; of Free Pardon. And that his said Subje&bholigct;s nor any of them, nor the Heires Executors or Administrators of
any of them, nor the said Bodyes Corporate and others before named and rehearsed nor any of them, be or
shall be sued, vexed or unquieted in their Bodyes, Goods, Chattells, Lands or Tenements for any manner or
Matter, Cause, Contempt, Misdemeanour, Forfeiture, Trespasse, Offence, or any other thing suffered, done or
committed or ommitted before the said five and twentyeth day of March against his Majestie, his Crowne, Dignity
Prerogative, Lawes or Statutes, but onely for such Matters, Causes and Offences as be rehearsed, mentioned or
in some wayes touched in the Exceptions of this present A&bholigct; to be foreprized and excepted and for none other;
Any Statute or Statutes, Lawes, Customes or Usages heretofore had made or used to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Grants of all Forfeitures incurred before said 25th March, to the Subje&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Exception.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And the Kings Majestie of his bounteous Liberality by the authoritie of this present Parlyament granteth and freely
giveth to every of his Subje&bholigct;s [and to<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] every of the said Bodyes Corporate and others [before<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] rehearsed and
every of them all Goods, Chattells, Debts, Fines, Issues, Proffitts Amerciaments, Forfeitures and Summes of Money
by any of them forfeited, which to his Majestie doe or shall belong or appertaine by reason of any Offence,
Contempt, Trespasse, Entry, Misdemeanour, Matter, Cause or Quarrell suffered, done or committed by them or
any of them before the said five and twentyeth day of March which be not hereafter in this present Act foreprized
and excepted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Grants or Executions upon Forfeitures how far of Force.</head>
			<para id="p7">And bee, it ena&bholigct;ed neverthelesse That all Grants thereof or of any part thereof made by any such as have
soe forfeited the same, and are hereby restored as aforesaid, and all Executions thereof or of any part thereof
had against any such after such forfeiture thereof committed or made, shall be of such force and effe&bholigct; as if noe
such forfeiture had beene had or made and of noe other, The same forfeiture or any thing before in this A&bholigct;
to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Any Person may plead this Pardon ;</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Fee.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the Kings Subje&bholigct;s, and all and singular Bodies Corporate and
others before rehearsed may by him or themselves or by his or their Deputie or Deputyes or by his or their
Attourney or Attourneys according to the Lawes of this Realme pleade and minister this present A&bholigct; of Free Pardon
for his or their discharge, of and for any thing that is by vertue of this present A&bholigct; pardoned, discharged, given
or granted without any Fee or other thing paying to any person or persons for Writeing or Entry of the Judgements
or other Cause concerning such Plea, Writeing or Entry, but onely sixteene pence to be paid to the Officer or
Clerke that shall enter such Plea Matter or Judgement for the partyes discharge in that behalfe, Any Law, Custome
or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Pardon to be expounded most beneficially for the Subje&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p10">And furthermore the Kings Majestie is contented and pleased that it be ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid
That this his said Free Pardon by the generall Words, Clauses and Sentences before rehearsed shall be reputed,
deemed, adjudged, expounded, allowed and taken in all manner of Courts of his Highnesse and elsewhere most
beneficiall and available to all and singular his said Subje&bholigct;s Bodyes Corporate and others before rehearsed, and
to every, of them in all things not in this present A&bholigct; excepted or foreprized without any ambiguity, question or
other delay whatsoever it shall bee to be made, pleaded, obje&bholigct;ed or alleadged by the Kings Majestie his Heires
or Successors or his or any of their Generall Auttourney or Attourneys or by any person or persons for his Majestie
or any of his Heires or Successors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Officer of the Courts making out Process for things pardoned;</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">or Sheriff taking or withholding things pardoned; Penalty &pound;10. and Treble Damages and Costs, and such Process void.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p12">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any Officer or Clerke of any of his Majestyes
Courts commonly called the Chauncery, Kings Bench, Common Pleas or Exchequer, or any other Officer or Clerke
of any other of his Majestyes Courts within this Realme at any time after the last day of this present Session
Parlyament make out or write out any manner of Writts, Processe, Summons or other Precepts whereby any of
the said Subje&bholigct;s or of the Bodyes Corporate or others before rehearsed or any of them shall be in any wise
arreasted, attached, distrained, summoned or otherwise vexed inquieted or greived in his or their Bodies, Lands,
Tenements Goods or Chattells or any of them for or because of any manner of thing pardoned or discharged
by vertue of this A&bholigct;, or if any Sheriffe or Escheator or any of their Deputy or Deputyes or any Bayliffe or other
Officer whatsoever by colour of his or their Officer or otherwise after the said last day of this present Session of
Parliament doe leavy, receive, take or withhold of or from any person or persons any thing pardoned or discharged
by this A&bholigct;, that then every such person soe offending, and thereof lawfully convi&bholigct;ed or condemned by any sufficient
Testimony, Witnesse [and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Proofe shall yeild and pay for recompence thereof to the party soe greived or offended
thereby his or their treble Dammages besides all Costs of the Suite, and shall alsoe forfeite and loose to the Kings
Majestie for every such Offence Ten pounds; And neverthelesse all and singular such Writts, Processe and Precepts
soe to be made for or upon any manner of thing pardoned or discharged by this present A&bholigct; of Free Pardon
shall be utterly void and of noe effe&bholigct;.</para>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Exceptions; High Treasons, &#x0026;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">Excepted and alwayes foreprized out of this Generall and Free Pardon all and all manner of High Treasons and
other Offences committed or done by any person or persons against the Kings Majestyes most Royall Person and
all Conspiracies and Confideracies traiterously had committed or done by any person or persons against his Majestyes
most Royall Person.</para>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Treasons out of the Realm, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p16">And alsoe excepted all and every manner of Treasons committed or done by any person or persons in the Parts
beyond the Seas or in any other Place out of this Realme, and alsoe all Suites, Punishments, Executions Paines
of Death, Forfeitures and Penalties for or by reason or occasion of any the Treasons and Offences before excepted.</para>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Forging Great Seal, &#x0026;c. and diminishing the Coin.; Misprisions of Treason</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And alsoe excepted out of this Free Pardon all Offences in foreging and false counterfeiting the Kings Majestyes
Great or Privy Seale, Sigle Manuall or Privy Signet or of any the Moneys currant within this Realme, and alsoe
all Offences of unlawfull diminishing any of the said Moneys by any way or meanes whatsoever contrary to the
Lawes and Statutes of this Realme, and all Misprisions and Concealments of the Treasons before excepted, and all
abetting, aiding, comforting and procureing of the same offences or any of the said Treasons before excepted.</para>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Murders, Petit Treasons, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p20">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all manner of voluntary Murders, Petit Treasons and wilfull Poysonings
done or committed by any person or persons and all and every the Accessaries to the same Offences or any of
them before the said Offences committed.</para>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Piracies, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p22">And alsoe excepted and foreprized out of this Generall Pardon all Piracies and Robberies done upon the Seas,
and all and every procureing or abetting any such Offenders and the comforting and receiving of them or any
of them or of any Goods taken by way of Piracy or Robbery upon the Seas as aforesaid.</para>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Burglaries, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p24">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all Burglaries committed or done in any Dwelling-house or Houses and
all Accessaries to any the said Burglaryes before the same Burglary committed.</para>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Buggery.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p26">And alsoe excepted the detestable and abominable Vice of Buggery committed with Mankinde or Beast.</para>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">Rapes.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p28">And alsoe excepted all Rapes and Carnall Ravishments of Women.</para>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">Taking away Women.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p30">And alsoe excepted all Ravishments and wilfull takeing away or marrying of any Maid, Widdow or Damsell
against her will or without the assent or agreement of her Parents or of such as then had her in custodie; and
alsoe all offences of aiding, comforting, procuring or abetting any such Ravishment, wilfull takeing. or marrying
had, committed or done.</para>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">Perjury, Subornation, counterfeiting Deeds, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p32">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all Offences of Perjury and the subornation of Witnesses and the offences
of forging and counterfeiting any false Deeds Escripts or Writeings, and all offences of forging or counterfeiting
any Examinations or Testimonies of any Witnesse or Witnesses tending to bring any person or persons into
danger of his life and all procureing and counselling or any such forgeings or counterfeitings had, made, committed
or done.</para>
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">Forfeitures, &#x0026;c. for which Action has been brought as herein mentioned.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p34">And alsoe excepted all Forfeitures and other Penalties and Proffitts now due accrued and grown, or which, shall
or may be due accrew or grow to the Kings Majestie by reason of any Offence, Misdemeanour or Contempt or
other a&bholigct; or deed had, suffered, committed or done contrary to any A&bholigct;, Statute or Statutes or contrary to the
Common Lawes of this Realm, and whereof, or for the which any A&bholigct;ion, Bill, Plaint or Information at any time
within six yeares next before the thirteenth day of February in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
seaventy two have beene commenced or sued in any of his Majestyes Courts at Westminster and was then and
there depending and remaining to be prosecuted, or whereupon any Verdi&bholigct;, Judgement or Decree is already given or
entred, other then such [Information<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] as shall be then and there depending for stamping and coyning of Farthings,
Halfe-pence, Pence, and such small Money as aforesaid, or for uttering the same.</para>
			<para id="p35">
				<emph type="i">Informations concerning Bridges, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p36">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all Informations and other Proceedings depending concerning any common
High wayes or Bridges and all Issues returned upon any Processe concerning the same since the five and twentyeth
day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and three.</para>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">Embezzling the King's Goods, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p38">And alsoe excepted all Offences in takeing away, imbezilling or purloyning any of the Kings Majestyes Goods,
Moneys; Chattells, Jewells, Armour, Munition, Stores, Navall Provisions, Shipping, Ordnance or other Habiliments
of Warr;</para>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">Breach of Covenant, &#x0026;c. with the King.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p40">And alsoe excepted all Conditions and Covenants and all Penalties, Titles and Forfeitures of Condition or Conditions,
Covenant or Covenants accrued or grown to the Kings Majestie by reason of the Breach and not performing of any
Covenant or Condition whatsoever.</para>
			<para id="p41">
				<emph type="i">Incest; Simony, &#x0026;c. for which Suit depending the First Day of the Session.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p42">And alsoe excepted all Offences of Incest, Simony or Dilapidations for which any Suite is or was depending upon
the first day of this Session or Parliament.</para>
			<para id="p43">
				<emph type="i">First Fruits, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p44">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all First-fruits and Tenths, Pensions, Procurations, Synodalls and other
payments out of any Ecclesiasticall Promotion or Benefice.</para>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">Concealment of Duties.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p46">And alsoe excepted out of this Free Pardon all and every the Summes of Money and Dutyes following, and
the concealements or wrongfull detainments thereof (that is to say) of any Custome or Subsidy, Excise, Hearth-money,
Imposition upon Wines or other Liquours, Impositions upon Proceedings at Law, Dutyes ariseing by Wine-Licences
or the Post-Office or any other Taxes, Assesment, Duty or Imposition due to the Kings Majestie, or given by any
A&bholigct; of Parliament and all arreares thereof, and all Forfeitures ariseing thereby, or for the Non-payment thereof
and all Corruptions and Misdemeanours of any Officer or Minister of, in, or concerning the same, and all Accounts
and Suites whatsoever to be had, made or prosecuted for the same, and all Concealments, Fraudes and Offences,
by which his Majestie hath beene deceived, and not truely answered of or for the same.</para>
			<para id="p47">
				<emph type="i">Debts, &#x0026;c. excepted by 12 C.II. c. 11.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p48">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all Debts, Dutyes, Summes of Money, Accounts, Obligations, Recognizances
and other Securityes which by a former A&bholigct;, entituled, An A&bholigct; of Free and Generall Pardon, Indemnity and Oblivion
doe therein stand excepted, and are not yet answered and paid or otherwise discharged.</para>
			<para id="p49">
				<emph type="i">Taking away Goods, Rents, &#x0026;c. forfeited to the King.
			Rents, &#x0026;c. of Traitors, &#x0026;c.; Rents, &#x0026;c. of Temporalties in the King's Hands.; Arrearages due from Faumers of the Revenue</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p50">And alsoe excepted all and every manner of takeing from the Kings Majestie any Goods or Chattells forfeited
unto him by reason of any Treason, Petit Treason, Murder or Felony heretofore committed or done. And alsoe
all and every manner of takeing from the Kings Majestie the Issue, Rents, Revenues or Proffitts or any Mannours,
Lands Tenements or Hereditaments which were of any Traitor, Murderer, Felon, Clerke or Clerks attainted or
any of them. And alsoe all and every manner of takeing from the Kings Majestie the Issues, Rents, Revenues
and Proffitts of any Mannours, Lands, Tenements or Hereditaments, parcell of the Possessions of any Bishoprick,
the Temporalaties whereof upon the said five and twentyeth day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred sixty three, or at any time since were or of right ought to have beene in his Majestyes hands.</para>
			<para id="p51">
				<emph type="i">Arrearages due from Farmers of the Revenue.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p52">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all Arrearages of Rent due from any Farmer of any part of his Majesties
Revenue ariseing by Customes, Excise or Hearth-Money or Impositions upon Proceedings at Law, and all
Arrearages of Fee-farme Rents or other Rents due to his Majestie.</para>
			<para id="p53">
				<emph type="i">Accounts of Collectors, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p54">And alsoe excepted all and singular Accompts of all and every Colle&bholigct;or and Colle&bholigct;ors, Commissioners
Treasurers or Receivers who have received or colle&bholigct;ed any [Subsody,<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Custome, Subsidy of Tonnage or Poundage,
additionall Duty, Prize-goods or other things grown due or happening since the said five and twentyth day of
March in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred sixtie and three, and all Accompts of every other
person whatsoever that ought to be accomptant to the Kings Majestie for or in respe&bholigct; of any Receipt or other
charge which hath growne since the said five and twentyeth day of March, and the Heires, Executors, Administrators
and Sureties of every such person that ought to accompt for all things touching onely the same accompts, And
all and singular arrearages of accompts and untrue accompts made or rendred since the said five and twentyeth
day of March, and all Impetitions, Charges, Seizures, Suites, Demands and Executions which may or can be
had of or for any such accompt or accompts or any arrearages of the same.</para>
			<para id="p55">
				<emph type="i">Recognizances of Receivers, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p56">And alsoe except all Recognizances Obligations and other Securities given or enterd into by any Receiver,
Reeve, Bayliffe, Colle&bholigct;or or other Accomptant in the Court of Exchequer and their Sureties and their Accompts
respe&bholigct;ively and all other Recognizances and Obligations whatsoever conditioned for the payment of Money.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Recognizances, &#x0026;c. forfeited and not forfeited, as herein mentioned, and Specialties to the Crown, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p57">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; shall not extend or be construed to pardon or discharge
any Recognizance or Obligation not yet forfeited, nor to pardon or discharge any forfeited Recognizance or
Obligation or any other Forfeiture or Penaltie whereof the Farmers of his Majestyes Customes or, Excise or the
Farmers of any other part of his Majestyes Revenue ought to receive any benefitt or advantage, nor to pardon or
discharge any Debt due by Recognizance, Obligation or other Specialty to any other person or persons indebted
to his Majestie, and which hath beene duely seized in aid of his Majesties Debt, nor to pardon or discharge any debt
due by Recognizance, Obligation, Condemnation or otherwise whereupon any Enstalment or Seizure hath beene
at any time heretofore made, upon which Enstalment or Seizure any thing is, or at any time since the said five
and twentyeth day of March hath beene answered and paid to his Majestyes Use, nor to pardon or discharge
any Penalties, Forfeitures or Summes of Money due or accrued to his Majestie by reason of any A&bholigct;, Statute or
Statutes; which Forfeitures Penaltyes and Summes of Money since the said five and twentyeth day of March be
converted into the nature of debt by any Judgement, Order Decree or by the Agreement or the offender or
offenders; or [have<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] beene estalled or any Seizure made for the same, and upon such Seizure or Estalment any
thing answered or paid to his Majestyes Use Since the said five and twentyeth day of March in the yeare of our
Lord one thousand six hundred sixty and three.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Proviso for Recognizances for Appearance, &#x0026;c. forfeited, since 25th March.</head>
			<para id="p58">Neverthelesse it is hereby declared That all Obligations and Recognizances forfeited since the said five and
twentyeth day of March for Non-appearance in any Court or other place whatsoever, or for not keeping the
Peace, or not being of the Good behaviour shall be clearely pardoned and discharged.</para>
			<para id="p59">
				<emph type="i">Further Exception. Issues, &#x0026;c. lost</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p60">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all Issue Fines and Amerciaments lost, imposed or assessed since the
said five and twentyeth day of March one thousand six hundred sixty and three being totted, leavyed or received
by any Sheriffe, Under Sheriffe, Bayliffe, Minister or other Officer to or for the Kings Majesties use or behoofe
before the last day of this present Session of Parlyament.</para>
			<para id="p61">And alsoe excepted all Issues Fines and Amerciaments lost, imposed or assessed since the said five and twentyth
day of March affeered, taxed, sett, estreated or entred severally or particularly touching or concerning any one
or more persons joyntly or severally above the summe of six pounds.</para>
			<para id="p62">
				<emph type="i">Issues, &#x0026;c. returned, &#x0026;c. within a Year before this Parliament.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p63">And alsoe excepted all Issues, Fines and Amerciaments returned, affeered, taxed, sett or entred severally or
perticularly in any Court of Record at Westminster at any time within the space of one whole yeare before the
first day of this present Session of Parlyment.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Proviso for other Fines and Issues.</head>
			<para id="p64">And yet neverthelesse all other Fines, as well Fines pro Licentia concordandi as other sett, taxed, estreated or
entred before that time, and alsoe all Issues and Amerciaments aswell reall as others within any Liberties or
without being sett, taxed, estreated or entred before the time aforesaid, and which severally and perticularly extend
to or under the Summe of six pounds and not above, whether they be estreated or not estreated, or whether
they be turned into debt or not turned into debt, and not being totted leavyed or received by any Sheriffe
Under-Sheriffe Minister or other Officer to or for the Kings Majestyes use or behoofe before the first day of
this present Session of Parlyament shall be freely, clearely and plainely pardoned and discharged against the Kings
Majestie his Heires and Successors by force of this present A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Estreats of Fines, &#x0026;c. hereby pardoned already estreated to be delivered into the Pipe Office.</head>
			<para id="p65">
				<emph type="i">Sheriffs and other Accountants may petition for Allowance of Fines, &#x0026;c. without Fee.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p66">And yet neverthelesse all Estreats of such Fines, Issues and Amerciaments as be now pardoned by this A&bholigct;
and which be already estreated forth of the Court of Exchequer, and be remaining in the hands of the Sheriffe,
Under Sheriffe, or Bayliffe for colle&bholigct;ing of the same Fines, Issues and Amerciaments shall upon the Returne of
the same Estreats be duely and orderly charged and delivered by Scrowes into the Office of the Pipe in the Court
of [the<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Exchequer as heretofore hath beene accustomed, to the intent that thereupon order may be taken that his
Majestie may be truely answered all such Fines, Issues and Amerciaments not by this A&bholigct; pardoned and which any
Sheriffe, Under Sheriffe, Bayliffe or other Officer or Minister hath received or ought to answere by force or
colour of any such Estreate, Processe or Precept to him or them made for the leavying thereof. And yet
that notwithstanding all and every Sheriffe and Sheriffes and other Accomptant upon his or their Petition, or
Petitions to be made for the allowance of any such Fines Issues and Amerciaments as by this A&bholigct; are pardoned
shall have all and every [such<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] his and their Petition allowed in his and their Accompt and Accompts without
paying any Fee or Reward to any Officer Clerke or other Minister for the makeing, entering or allowing of any
such Petition or Petitions Any Usage or Custome to the contrary hereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Further Exception. King Charles the First's Murderers, excepted by 12 C. II. c. 11. and the two Persons appearing upon the Scaffold with Vizors, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p67">
				<emph type="i">This Act not to heal Disabilities.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p68">Provided alwayes, That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to pardon, discharge or give any benefitt whatsoever unto
any person or persons who are by Name particularly excepted out of the said former A&bholigct; of Free and Generall
Pardon, Indempnity and Oblivion for their execrable Treason and horrid Murther of his Majestyes Royall Father
of glorious memory, nor to those two persons or either of them who being disguised by Frocks and Vizors
appeared upon the Scaffold at the time when the said Murder was committed, Nor shall this present A&bholigct; give or
restore any abilitie or capacitie to take any Office or imployment to such person or persons who in and by the
said former A&bholigct; are made incapeable to beare any Office Ecclesiasticall, Civill or Military within this Realme of
England or Dominion of Wales, or of serveing as a Member in Parlyament, But all and every such person and
persons shall remaine and continue under all and every the Disabilityes and Incapacityes by the said former A&bholigct;
imposed, Any thing in this present A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>Further Exception of Persons who have accepted any Office contrary to 12 Car. II. c. 11.</head>
			<para id="p69">Nor shall this A&bholigct; extend to pardon discharge or give any benefitt to any person or persons who if they shall
after the first day of September one thousand six hundred and sixty accept or exercise any Office Ecclesiasticall,
Civill or Military or any other publique imployment within England, Wales or the Towne of Berwicke upon
Tweede are by the said former A&bholigct; to stand and be as if he or they had beene totally by name excepted out
of the said former A&bholigct;, but all and every such persons shall if they accept any Office or imployment contrary to
the tenour of the said former A&bholigct; be out of this A&bholigct; wholly excepted and foreprized.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIII. Persons disabled from bearing Offices liable to be Sheriffs.</head>
			<para id="p70">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That notwithstanding the said Disability by this or the said former A&bholigct;,
any of the said persons soe disabled by either of the said A&bholigct;s shall and may bee lyable and chargeable with the
Office of Sheriffe of any County in case it shall be his Majestyes pleasure to impose the same.</para>
			<para id="p71">
				<emph type="i">Persons attainted of Rebellion, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p72">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all such persons as be and remaine still attainted or condemned by A&bholigct;
of Parlyament, or otherwise of or for any Rebellion or leavying of Warr [or of or for any Conspiricy of any
Rebellion or leavying of Warr<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] within this Realme or any other his Majestyes Dominions, and all such persons
who are attainted or outlawed of, or for any other Treason, Petit Treason, Murder, wilfull poysoning or Burglary
and all Executions therefore.</para>
			<para id="p73">
				<emph type="i">Persons exiled, &#x0026;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p74">And alsoe excepted out of this Pardon all such persons who by vertue of any former A&bholigct; of this present
Parlyament are by expresse name exiled or made lyable to any other paines, penaltyes or disabilities whatsoever.</para>
			<para id="p75">
				<emph type="i">Persons who have desired Transportation.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p76">And alsoe excepted all such persons who after Convi&bholigct;ion or Attainder of, or for any manner of Felony have
desired to be transported into any of his Majestyes Forreigne Plantations.</para>
			<para id="p77">
				<emph type="i">Persons formerly excepted out of 12 Car. II. c. 11. and punished by any subsequent A&bholigct;.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p78">And alsoe excepted all such persons, who being excepted out of the said former A&bholigct; of Generall Pardon,
Indempnity and Oblivion have had any paines or penalties imposed upon them by any subsequent A&bholigct; of
Parlyament.</para>
			<para id="p79">
				<emph type="i">Persons imprisoned by Command of His Majesty or Privy Council.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p80">And alsoe except out (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) of this Pardon all such persons who upon the first day of this present Session of Parlyament
were in prison within the Tower of London or within the prison of the Marshalsea, or in the prison of the Fleete
or in the prison of the Gatehouse, or elsewhere in any part of his Majesties Dominions, or otherwise restrained of
Liberty by expresse Commandment or Dire&bholigct;ion of his Majesty or any of his Majestyes Privy Councill.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XIV. Capias Utlagatum to be sued out at the Suit of the Plaintiff.</head>
			<para id="p81">
				<emph type="i">The Defendant to sue out a Scire facias to have his Pardon allowed.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p82">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for all
and every Clerke and all other Officers of the Kings Courts to award and make Writts of Capias utlagatum at
the Suite of the party Plaintiffe against such Persons outlawed as be pardoned by this A&bholigct; to the intent to compell
the Defendant or Defendants to make answere to the Plaintiffe or Plaintiffes at whose Suite he or they were outlawed;
and that every person soe outlawed shall sue a Writt of Scire facias against the party or partyes at whose Suite he
or they were outlawed, before this Pardon in that behalfe shall be allowed to him or them that were soe outlawed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XV. Proviso respecting Outlawries upon Cap. ad sat.</head>
			<para id="p83">Provided alsoe and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That this A&bholigct; of Generall Pardon shall not in any
wise extend to any person outlawed upon any Writt of Capias ad satisfaciendum, untill such time as the party soe
outlawed shall satisfie or otherwise agree with the partie at whose Suite he was soe outlawed or condemned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVI. This A&bholigct; of Pardon may be given in Evidence.</head>
			<para id="p84">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That every person or persons hereby pardoned may pleade
the Generall Issue without speciall pleading of this Pardon; and give this A&bholigct; of Pardon in Evidence for his discharge,
and that the same shall be thereupon allowed and the advantage thereof had as fully to all intents and purposes as
if the same had beene fully and well pleaded, and in such manner as any Justice, of Peace, Constable or other
Officer questioned for matters a&bholigct;ed by them as Officers may have advantage of the matter of their Justification
upon the Generall Issue by them pleaded by the Lawes and Statutes of this Realme.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVII. Good as well against the King's Grantee as against the King.</head>
			<para id="p85">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That this present Pardon shall be of as good force and
effe&bholigct; to pardon and discharge all and singular the Premisses above-mentioned and intended to be pardoned and
discharged as well against such person or persons Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate as doe or shall claime the same
by or under any Letters Patents Lease or Grant made by the Kings Majestie or any his Predecessors as against the
Kings Majestie himselfe.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Informations <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Subsidy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">out <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


