<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47466" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act for the Naturalizing of Children of his Majestyes English Subje&bholigct;s borne in Forreigne Countryes during the late Troubles. [Rot. Parl. 29 C. II. p. 2. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that many Persons had been obliged to reside Abroad, and that it might become difficult to prove the Occasion of their Residence.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Certain Persons herein named, and all other Persons born out of the King's Dominions, between 14th June 1641 and 24th March 1660, and whose Fathers or Mothers were natural born Subjes, declared natural-born Subjects</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas during the late unhappy Troubles in England which began in the yeare of our Lord one thousand
six hundred forty one and continued untill the time of his Majestyes most happy Restauration diverse of
his Majestyes English Subje&bholigct;s as well of the Nobility as others did either by reason of their attendance upon his
Majestie or for feare of the then Usurped Powers reside in parts beyond the Seas out of his Majestyes Dominions
and [it<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] may hereafter become difficult to make proofe of the occasion of such their residence, Now for preventing
of all Disputes and Questions that may arise whether the Children of such his Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s of this Realme
are Naturall borne Subje&bholigct;s of our Soveraigne Lord the King and to expresse a due sence of the merit of all
such Loyall persons as out of their duty and fidelity to his Majestie and his Father of Blessed Memory did foregoe
or were driven from their Native Country. Bee it declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by
and with the consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled
and by the authoritie of the same That Charles Gerard and Elizabeth Gerard Children of the Right Honourable
Charles Lord Gerard of Brandon Trever Wheler and Dorothy Elizabeth Wheeler Children of Sir Charles Wheler
Baronet [Anne Ravenscroft the Wife of Edward Ravenscroft of Bretton in the County of Flint Esquire one of
the Daughters of Sir Richard Lloyd Knight deceased borne at Calice in France<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and all other persons who at any
time betweene the fourteenth day of June in the said yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred forty one and
the foure and twentyeth day of March in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred and sixty were borne
out of his Majestyes Dominions and whose Fathers or Mothers were Naturall borne Subje&bholigct;s of this Realme are
hereby declared and shall for ever be esteemed and taken to all Intents and Purposes to be and to have beene the
Kings Naturall borne Subje&bholigct;s of this Kingdome and that the said Children and all other Persons borne as
aforesaid and every of them are and shall be adjudged reputed and taken to be and to have beene in every respe&bholigct;
and degree Naturall borne Subje&bholigct;s and free to all intents purposes and constru&bholigct;ions as if they and every of them
had beene borne in England.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. and enabled to take Titles of Honour, Lands, and other Rights and Privileges, as if born or English Parents within this Kingdom.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Such Persons to receive the Sacrament and take the Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy as herein mentioned; and have Proof thereof by Certificate and Witnesses</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authoritie aforesaid That the Children and all other persons
as aforesaid and every of them shall be and are hereby enabled and adjudged able to all intents constru&bholigct;ions and
purposes whatsoever as well to demand as to have and enjoy any Titles of Honour Mannours Lands Tenements
and Hereditaments and all other Priviledges and Immunityes belonging to the Leige People and Naturall Subje&bholigct;s
of this Kingdome and to make his or their resort or pedigree as Heire to his their or any of their Auncestors
Lyneall or Collaterall by reason of any Descent Remainder Reverter Right or other Title Conveyance Legacy or
Bequest whatsoever which hath may or shall descend remaine revert accrue come or grow unto the said Children
or the persons borne as aforesaid or any of them as alsoe to have and enjoy all Mannours Lands and Tenements
or other Hereditaments by way of Purchase or Gift of any person or persons whatsoever as alsoe to prosecute
pursue maintaine avow and justifie all and all manner of Actions Suites and Causes and all other things to doe
as lawfully liberally freely and fully as if the said Children and the persons borne as aforesaid and every of them
had beene and were borne of English Parents within this Kingdome or as any other person or persons borne within
this Kingdome may lawfully in any wise doe, Any Law A&bholigct; Statute Provision Custome or other thing whatsoever
had made done promulged proclaimed or provided to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding. Provided
alwayes That noe Person other then the persons expressely named in this A&bholigct; shall have any benefit thereby except
such person shall within seaven yeares next ensueing receive the Sacrament of the Lords Supper and within one
moneth next after such receiving the Sacrament take the Oathes of Alleigiance and Supremacy in some of his
Majestyes Courts at Westminster and deliver into the Court at the same time a Certificate of such his receiveing
the said Sacrament and then make proofe thereof by Witnesses to be examined viva voce upon Oath.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. otherwise no Benefit of this Act.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That noe person or persons other then the persons expressely named in this A&bholigct;
shall have any benefitt thereby untill he or they shall have received the Sacrament and made proofe thereof by
Certificate and Witnesses and taken the said Oathes in manner aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proof of Qualification may be made by Witnesses viv&acirc; voce;</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">and thereupon have Certificate enrolled.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">And for the better manifestation and proofe of such qualifications as may entitle any person to the benefitt of
this A&bholigct; which in processe of time may be very hard to be proved Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That any person haveing
received the Sacrament and made proofe thereof by Certificate and Witnesses and taken the said Oathes within the
time aforesaid in any of his Majestyes Courts in manner aforesaid shall and may be admitted to make proofe of
such his qualification in the said Court by Witnesses viva voce to be examined upon Oath and if he shall make
proofe thereof to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said Court he shall thereupon have a Certificate thereof under the Seale of
the said Court to be likewise enrolled in the said Court and for ever after upon shewing such Certificate or Enrollment
thereof every such person shall have full benefitt of this Law as if he had beene therein expresly named.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


