<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47463" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for prevention of Frauds and Perjuryes. [Rot. Parl. 29. C. II. p. 2. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Parol Leases and Interests of Freehold, &amp;c. to have the Force of Estates at Will only</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For prevention of many fraudulent Pra&bholigct;ices which are commonly endeavoured to be upheld by Perjury and
Subornation of Perjury Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and
consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the
authoritie of the same That from and after the fower and twentyeth day of June which shall be in the yeare of
our Lord one thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven All Leases Estates Interests of Freehold or Termes of
yeares or any uncertaine Interest of in to or out of any Messuages Mannours Lands Tenements or Hereditaments
made or created by Livery and Seisin onely or by Parole and not putt in Writeing and signed by the parties soe
makeing or creating the same or their Agents thereunto lawfully authorized by Writeing, shall have the force and
effe&bholigct; of Leases or Estates at Will onely and shall not either in Law or Equity be deemed or taken to have any
other or greater force or effe&bholigct;, Any consideration for makeing any such Parole Leases or Estates or any former
Law or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Except Leases not exceeding Three Years, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">Except neverthelesse all Leases not exceeding the terme of three yeares from the makeing thereof whereupon,
the Rent reserved to the Landlord dureing such terme shall amount unto two third parts at the least of the full
improved value of the thing demised.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. No Leases or Estates of Freehold or Copyhold, &amp;c. to be granted or surrendered but by Writing signed.</head>
			<para id="p4">And moreover That noe Leases Estates or Interests either of Freehold or Terms of yeares or any uncertaine
Interest not being Copyhold or Customary Interest of in to or out of any Messuages Mannours Lands Tenements
or Hereditaments shall at any time after the said fower and twentyeth day of June be assigned, granted or surrendred
unlesse it be by Deed or Note in Writeing signed by the party soe assigning granting or surrendring the same
or their Agents thereunto lawfully authorized by writeing or by a&bholigct; and operation of Law.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. No A&bholigct;ion against Executors, &amp;c. upon a special Promise, or upon any Agreement, or Contra&bholigct; for Sale of Lands, &amp;c. unless Agreement, &amp;c. be in Writing and signed.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That from and after the said fower and twentyeth day of
June noe A&bholigct;ion shall be brought whereby to charge any Executor or Administrator upon any speciall promise to
answere damages out, of his owne Estate or whereby to charge the Defendant upon any speciall promise to answere
for the debt default or miscarriages of another person or to charge any person upon any agreement made upon
consideration of Marriage or upon any Contra&bholigct; or Sale of Lands Tenements or Hereditaments or any Interest in
or concerning them or upon any Agreement that is not to be performed within the space of one yeare from the,
makeing thereof unlesse the Agreement upon which such A&bholigct;ion shall be brought or some Memorandum or Note
thereof shall be in Writeing and signed by the partie to be charged therewith or some other person thereunto
by him lawfully authorized.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Devises of Lands to be in Writing and signed and attested by Three or Four Witnesses.</head>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That from and after the said fower and twentyeth day
of June all Devises and Bequests of any Lands or Tenements deviseable either by force, of the Statute of Wills
or by this Statute or by force of the Custome of Kent or the Custome of any Burrough or any other perticular
Custome shall be in Writeing and signed by the partie soe deviseing the same or by some other person in his
presence and by his expresse dire&bholigct;ions and shall be attested and subscribed in the presence of the said Devisor
by three or fower credible Witnesses or else they shall be utterly void and of none effe&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. How the same Devise to be revocable.</head>
			<para id="p7">And moreover noe Devise in Writeing of Lands Tenements or Hereditaments nor any Clause thereof shall at
any time after the said fower and twentyeth day of June Be revocable otherwise then by some other Will
or Coddicill in Writeing or other Writeing declareing the same or by burning cancelling teareing or obliterating
the same by the Testator himselfe or in his presence and by his dire&bholigct;ions and consent but all Devises and
Bequests of Lands' and Tenements shall remaine and continue in force untill the same be burnt cancelled torne or
obliterated by the Testator or his dire&bholigct;ions in manner aforesaid or unlesse the same be altered by some other
Will or Codicill in Writeing or other Writeing of the Devisor signed in the presence of three or fower Witnesses
declareing the same, Any former Law or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Declarations or Creations of Trusts of Lands to be in Writing signed.</head>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That from and after the said fower and twentyeth day
of June all Declarations or Creations of Trusts or Confidences of any Lands Tenements or Hereditaments shall be
manifested and proved by some Writeing signed by the partie who is by Law enabled to declare such Trust or
by his last Will in Writeing or else they shall be utterly void and of none effe&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for Trusts arising, transferred or extinguished by Implication of Law.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alwayes That where any Conveyance shall bee made of any Lands or Tenements by which a Trust
or Confidence shall or may arise or result by the Implication or Constru&bholigct;ion of Law or bee transferred or
extinguished by an a&bholigct; or operation of Law then and in every such Case such Trust or Confidence shall be of
the like force and effe&bholigct; as the same would have beene if this Statute had not beene made. Any thing herein
before contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Assignments of Trusts shall be in Writing.</head>
			<para id="p10">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all Grants and Assignments of any Trust or Confidence shall likewise be in
Writeing signed by the partie granting or assigning the same [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] by such last Will or Devise or else shall likewise
be utterly void and of none effe&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Lands, &amp;c. of Cestui que Trust liable to the Judgments, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">and held free from the Incumbrances of the Persons seized in Trust. Trust shall be Assets by Descent</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That from and after the said fower and twentyeth day
of June it shall and may be lawfull for every Sheriffe or other Officer to whome any Writt or Precept is or
shall be dire&bholigct;ed at the Suite of any person or persons of for and upon any Judgement Statute or Recognizance
hereafter to be made or had, to doe make and deliver Execution unto the partie in that behalfe sueing of all such
Lands Tenements Re&bholigct;ories Tythes Rents and Hereditaments as any other person or persons be in any manner of
wise seised or possessed [or hereafter shall be seised or possessed<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] in Trust for him against whome Execution is soe
sued like as the Sheriffe or other Officer might or ought to have done if the said partie against whome Execution
hereafter shall be soe sued had beene seised of such Lands Tenements Re&bholigct;ories Tythes Rents or other Hereditaments
of such Estate as they be seized of in Trust for him at the time of the said Execution sued. Which Lands
Tenements Re&bholigct;ories Tythes Rents and other Hereditaments by force and vertue of such Execution shall accordingly
be held and enjoyed freed and discharged from all Incumbrances of such person or persons as shall be soe seised
or possessed in Trust for the person against whome such Execution shall be sued. And if any Cestuy que Trust
hereafter shall dye leaveing a Trust in Fee simple to descend to his Heire, there, and in every such case such
Trust shall be deemed and taken and is hereby declared to be Assetts by descent and the Heire shall be lyable
to and chargeable with the Obligation of his Auncestors for and by reason of such Assetts as fully and amply as
he might or ought to have beene if the Estate in Law had descended to him in possession in like manner as the
Trust descended, Any Law Custome or Usage to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. But Heir shall not by reason thereof become chargeable of his own Estate.</head>
			<para id="p13">Provided alwayes That noe Heire that shall become chargeable by reason of any Estate or Trust made Assetts
in his hands by this Law shall by reason of any kinde of Plea or confession of the A&bholigct;ion or suffering Judgement
by Nient dedire or any other matter bee chargeable to pay the Condemnation out of his owne Estate but Execution
shall be sued of the whole Estate soe made Assetts in his hands by descent in whose hands soever it shall come
after the Writt purchased in the same manner as it is to be at and by the Common Law where the Heire at
Law pleading a true Plea Judgement is prayed against him thereupon. Any thing in this present A&bholigct; contained to
the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Estates pur auter vie devisable;</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">and to be Assets in the Hands of the Heir; and where no special Occupant, to go to Executors.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p15">And for the amendment of the Law in the particulars following Bee it further ena&bholngs;ed by the authorise
aforesaid That from henceforth any Estate per auter vie shall be deviseable by a Will in writeing signed by the
party soe deviseing the same or by some other person in his presence and by his expresse dire&bholngs;ions attested and
subscribed in the presence of the Devisor by three or more Witnesses, and if noe such Devise thereof be made
the same shall be chargeable in the hands of the Heire if it shall come to him by reason of a speciall Occupancy
as Assetts by descent as in case of Lands in Fee simple And in case there be noe speciall Occupant thereof it
shall goe to the Executors or Administrators of the partie that had the Estate thereof by vertue of the Grant and
shall be Assetts in their hands.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Recital of Mischiefs arising from the Relation of Judgments to the First Day of the Term, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">The Day of signing any Judgment to be entered on the Margin of the Roll without Fee:</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p17">And whereas it hath beene found mischievous that Judgements in the Kings Courts at Westminster doe many
times relate to the first day of the Terme whereof they are entred or to the day of the Returne of the Originall
or fileing the Baile and binde the Defendants Lands from that time although in trueth they were acknowledged or
suffered and signed in the Vacation time after the said Terme whereby many times Purchasers finde themselves
agrieved Bee it enacted by the authorise aforesaid That from and after the said foure and twentyeth day of June
any Judge or Officer of any of his Majestyes Courts of Westminster that shall signe any Judgements shall at the
signeing of the same without Fee for doeing the same sett downe the day of the moneth and yeare of his soe
doeing upon the Paper Booke Dockett or Record which he shall signe which day of the moneth and yeare shall
be alsoe entred upon the Margent of the Roll of the Record where the said Judgement shall be entred.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. And such Judgments as against Purchasers shall relate to such time only.</head>
			<para id="p18">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That such Judgements as against Purchasers bona fide for valueable consideration of Lands
Tenements or Hereditaments to be charged thereby shall in consideration of Law be Judgements onely from such
time as they shall be soe signed and shall not relate to the first day of the Terme whereof they are entred or
the day of the Returne of the Originall or fileing the Baile Any Law, Usage or Course of any Court to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Writs of Execution to bind the Property of Goods but from the time of their Delivery to the Officer.</head>
			<para id="p19">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That from and after the said fower and twentyeth day of
June noe Writt of Fieri facias or other Writt of Execution shall binde the Property of the Goods against whome
such Writt of Execution is sued forth but from the time that such Writt shall be delivered to the Sheriffe Under
Sheriffe or Coroners to be executed, And for the better manifestation of the said time the Sheriffe Under Sheriffe
and Coroners their Deputyes and Agents shall upon the receipt of any such Writt (without Fee for doeing the
same) endorse upon the backe thereof the day of the moneth [or<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] yeare whereon he or they received the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. In what Cases only Contracts for Sales of Goods for &pound;10 or more to be binding.</head>
			<para id="p20">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That from and after the said fower and twentyeth day
of June noe Contra&bholigct; for the Sale of any Goods Wares or Merchandises for the price of ten pounds Sterling
or upwards shall be allowed to be good except the Buyer shall accept part of the Goods soe sold and a&bholigct;ually
receive the same or give some thing in earnest to bind the bargaine or in part of payment, or that some Note
or Memorandum in writeing of the said bargaine be made and signed by the partyes to be charged by such
Contra&bholigct; or their Agents thereunto lawfully authorized.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. The Day of Enrolment of Recognizances to be set down;</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">and Lands in the Hands of Purchasers bound from that time only.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p22">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the day of the moneth and yeare of the Enrollment
of the Recognizances shall be sett downe in the Margent of the Roll where the said Recognizances are enrolled,
and that from and after the said fower and twentyeth day of June noe Recognizance shall binde any Lands Tenements
or Hereditaments in the hands of any Purchasor bona fide and for valueable consideration but from the time of
such Enrollment, Any Law Usage or Course of any Court to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. No Nuncupative Will good where Estate exceed &pound;30 in Value;</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">unless proved by Three Witnesses on Oath, and made; in last Sickness of Testator, and where he had been resident Ten Days or more ; Exception.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p24">And for prevention of fraudulent Pra&bholigct;ices in setting up Nuncupative Wills which have beene the occasion of
much Perjury Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That from and after the aforesaid fower and twentyeth
day of June noe Nuncupative Will shall be good where the Estate thereby bequeathed shall exceede the value of
thirty pounds that is not proved by the Oathes of three Wittnesses (at the least) that were present at the makeing
thereof, nor unlesse it be proved that the Testator at the time of pronounceing the same did bid the persons
present or some of them beare wittnesse that such was his Will or to that effe&bholigct;, nor unlesse such Nuncupative
Will were made in the time of the last sicknesse of the deceased and in the House of his or her habitation or dwelling
or where he or she hath beene resident for the space of ten dayes or more next before the makeing of such Will
except where such person was surprized or taken sick being from his owne home and dyed before he returned to
the place of his or her dwelling.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. No Testimony to be received after Six Months. Exception.</head>
			<para id="p25">And bee it further ena&bholngs;ed That after six monethes passed after the speaking of the pretended Testamentary
words noe Testimony shall be received to prove any Will Nuncupative except the said Testimony or the substance
thereof were committed to writeing within six dayes after the makeing of the said Will.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Probates of Nuncupative Wills.</head>
			<para id="p26">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That noe Letters Testamentary or Probate of any Nuncupative Will shall passe
the Seale of any Court till fowerteene dayes at the least after the decease of the Testator be fully expired, Nor
shall any Nuncupative Will be at any time received to be proved unlesse Processe have first issued to call in the
Widow or next of kindred to the deceased to the end they may contest the same if they please.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. In what Cases only Wills of Personal Estate may be revoked or altered by Parol.</head>
			<para id="p27">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That noe Will in writeing concerning any Goods or Chattells or Personall Estate
shall be repealed nor shall any Clause Devise or Bequest therein be altered or changed by any Words or Will
by word of mouth onely except the same be in the life of the Testator committed to writeing and after the
writeing thereof read unto the Testator and allowed by him and proved to be soe done by three Wittnesses at
the least.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Proviso for Soldiers and Mariners Wills.</head>
			<para id="p28">Provided alwayes That notwithstanding this A&bholigct; any Soldier being in a&bholigct;uall Military Service or any Marriner
or Seaman being at Sea may dispose of his Moveables, Wages and Personall Estate as he or they might have
done before the makeing of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Proviso for the Jurisdi&bholngs;ion of Courts granting Probate.</head>
			<para id="p29">And it is hereby declared That nothing in this A&bholigct; shall extend to alter or change the Jurisdi&bholigct;ion or Right
of Probate of Wills concerning Personall Estates but that the Prerogative Court of the Archbishop of Canterbury
and other Ecclesiasticall Courts and other Courts haveing Right to the Probate of such Wills shall retaine the
same Right and Power as they had before in every respe&bholigct; subje&bholigct; neverthelesse to the Rules and Directions of
this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. 22 &amp; 23 C.II. c.10. Husbands not compellable to make Distribution of the Personal Estates of their Wives.</head>
			<para id="p30">And for the explaining one A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament entituled An A&bholigct; for the better setleing of Intestates
Estates Bee it declared by the authority aforesaid That neither the said A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall
be construed to extend to the Estates of Feme-Coverts that shall dye Intestate, but that their Husbands may
demand and have Administration of their Rights Credits and other Personall Estates and recover and enjoy the
same as they, might have done before the makeing of the said A&bholigct; .</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


