<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47468" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for confirming and perpetuating Augmentations made by Ecclesiasticall Persons to small Vicarages and
Curacies.[Rot. Parl. 29 C. II. p. 2. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Augmentations payable since 1st June, 12 Car. II. and hereafter, to continue during the Estate upon which they are reserved, and afterwards; Remedy for the same</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas diverse Arch Bishops Bishops Deanes and Chapters and other Ecclesiasticall persons in obedience
to his Majestyes Letters beareing date the first day of June in the twelfth yeare of his said Majestyes
Raigne and out of a pious care to improve poore Vicarages and Curacies where the endowment thereof was found
too small to afford a competent maintenance to those that serve the Cure have since his Majestyes happy Returne
upon their renewing of Leases of Re&bholigct;ories or Tythes impropriate or appropriate made or may hereafter make
diverse Reservations beyond the auntient Rent to the intent the same should or might become payable to the said
Vicars or Curates in augmentation of their endowments which have beene for the most part enjoyed accordingly
But in reguard that such Reservations were not made to the Vicars or Curates or if they were noe convenient
remedy could be had by such Vicars or Curates for the recovery thereof and they were not at the time thereof
capeable of takeing any Interest to their owne use whereby the said Provisions will depend upon the good pleasure
of the Successors and may in time be disappointed. For the establishment thereof Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in
this present Parlyament assembled and by the authority of the same That all and every Augmentation of what
nature soever granted reserved or agreed to be made payable or intended to be granted reserved or made payable
since the said first day of June in the twelfth yeare of his said Majestyes Raigne or which shall at any time hereafter
be granted reserved or made payable to any Vicar or Curate or reserved by way of increase of Rent to the
Lessors but intended to be to or for the use or benefitt of any Viccar or Curate by any Arch-Bishop Bishop Deane
Provost Deane and Chapter Arch-Deacon Prebendary or other Ecclesiasticall Corporation person or persons whatsoever
soe makeing the said Reservation out of any Re&bholigct;ory Impropriate or Portion of Tythes belonging to any Arch-Bishop
Bishop Deane Provost Deane and Chapter or other Ecclesiasticall Corporation person or persons shall be deemed
and adjudged to continue and be and shall for ever hereafter continue and remaine as well dureing the continuance
of the Estate or Terme upon which the said Augmentations were granted reserved or agreed to be made payable
as afterwards in whose hands soever the said Re&bholigct;ories or Portion of Tythes shall be or come, which Re&bholigct;ories
or Portion of Tythes shall be chargeable therewith whether the same be reserved againe or not, and the said
Vicars and Curates respe&bholigct;ively are hereby adjudged to be in the a&bholigct;uall possession thereof for the use of themselves
and their Successors and the same shall for ever hereafter be taken received and enjoyed by the said Vicars and
Curates and their Successors as well dureing the continuance of the Terme or Estate upon which the said Augmentations
were granted reserved or agreed to be made payable as afterwards, and the said Vicars and Curates shall have
remedy for the same either by Distresse upon the Re&bholigct;ories Impropriate or Portions of Tythes charged therewith
or by A&bholigct;ion of Debt against that person who ought to have paid the same his Executors or Administrators,
Any disability in the person or persons Bodyes Politicke or Corporate soe granting or any disability or incapacity
in the Vicars or Curates to whome or to or for whose use or benefitt the same are granted or intended to be
granted, The Statute of Mortmaine or any other Law, Custome or other matter or thing whatsoever to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Augmentations exceeding one Moiety of yearly Value not confirmed.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes That noe future Augmentation be confirmed by vertue of this A&bholigct; which shall exceede one
moyety of the cleare yearely value above all Reprises of the Re&bholigct;ory Impropriate out of the which the same
shall be granted or reserved.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Augmentation Leases where to be entered.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Fee for entering. Such Entry how to be attested ; to be a Record and Evidence at Law</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And to the end the said Vicars and Curates may the better make appeare the certainty of the said Augmentations
Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That every Arch-Bishop Bishop Deane and Chapter respe&bholigct;ively on or
before the nine and twentyeth Day of September next comeing shall cause every Lease or Grant whereon any
such Augmentation is made to be fairely entred in a Booke of Parchment to be kept by their respe&bholigct;ive Registers
for that purpose. And every Deane Arch-Deacon Prebendary or other Ecclesiasticall person respe&bholigct;ively shall cause
every Lease or Grant whereon any such Augmentation hath beene made by himselfe his Predecessor or Predecessors
to be entred in the said Booke to be kept by the Register of the Bishop of the Diocesse, for the entering
whereof noe Fee shall be paid nor any thing demanded save onely a reasonable Reward to the Clerke for
entering the same not exceeding five shillings, which said Entry being examined by the respective Arch-Bishop
Bishop or Deane and by them respe&bholigct;ively attested in the said Booke to be a true Copy of the Originall Lease
or Grant and that the Augmentation in the same was intended for such use shall be as a Record a true Copy
whereof proved by Witnesses to be a true Copy shall be deemed taken adjudged and expounded to be good
and sufficient Evidence in the Law whereupon the said Vicars and Curates respe&bholigct;ively shall and may by vertue of
this A&bholigct; from time to time recover the benefitt of such Augmentation.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Agreements for Augmentations to be entered likewise.</head>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That where any Arch-Bishop Bishop Deane and Chapter
or any other Ecclesiasticall Corporation or Person whatsoever upon the renewing or granting any Lease or Estate
have made any Agreement for an Augmentation for the Vicar or Curate and such Augmentation hath for any
time beene accordingly paid although the said Agreement is not expressed or mentioned in the said Lease or Grant
every such Ecclesiasticall Person shall cause the substance of such Agreement to be entred in the said Booke to
remaine for a memoriall of it to perpetuity.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Such Augmentation so entered to continue for the Benefit of Vicar and Curate as if reserved by the Lease.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Augmentations to be construed as charitable Uses.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That such Augmentation soe entred shall likewise continue and be for ever hereafter
good and available in the Law for the benefitt of the Vicar or Curate for whome it was intended and their
Successors as well against the Arch-Bishop Bishop or other Ecclesiasticall Corporation or Person who agreed for
the same and his and their Successors as against every other person enjoying the said Re&bholigct;ories or Portions of
Tythes intended to be charged therewith in the same manner and for which they shall have the same remedy
as they should or ought to have by vertue of this A&bholigct; if the same had beene mentioned and reserved in and
by the Lease. And if any question shall hereafter arise concerning the validity of such Grants or any other matter
or thing in this A&bholigct; mentioned and contained such favourable constructions and such further remedy if need be
shall be had and made for the benefitt of the Vicars and Curates as heretofore have beene had and made or may
be had for other charitable Uses upon the Statutes for charitable Uses.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. New Leases without express Continuance of the Augmentations, void.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That if upon the Surrender Expiration
or other Determination of any Lease wherein any such Augmentation as aforesaid hath beene or shall be granted
any new Lease of the Premisses or any part thereof shall hereafter be made without expresse continuance of the
said Augmentation every such new Lease shall be utterly void to all intents and purposes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for a Lease of the Parsonage of Stourton.</head>
			<para id="p10">[Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be construed to invalidate
alter or make void one Lease beareing date the nineteenth of O&bholigct;ober one thousand six hundred seaventy and six
made by the Deane and Chapter of Yorke of the Parsonage and Tythes of Stourton in the County of Nottingham
wherein there is an Augmentation of six and thirty pounds per annum reserved and made due and payable to the
Vicar of Stourton aforesaid but that the said summe of six and thirty pounds be alwayes paid to the Vicar and
his Successors accordingly, Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. And for a Lease of St. Evall in Cornwall.</head>
			<para id="p11">[Provided That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be construed to invalidate alter or
make void one Lease lately made by the Deane and Chapter of Exon unto Arthur Sprey Esquire of the Tithesheafe of the Parish of Saint Evall in the County of Cornwall whereon there is an Augmentation of twenty
pounds per annum already made due and payable to the Vicar of the said Parish dureing the said Lease but that
the said summe of twenty pounds be alwayes paid to the Vicar and his Successors accordingly Any thing in this
A&bholigct; contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


