<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47471" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677 &amp; 1678</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for raising Money by a Poll and otherwise to enable His Majestie to enter into an a&bholigct;uall Warr against
the French King and for prohibiting severall French Commodities. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) [Rot. Parl 29 &amp; 30 C. II]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">Most Gratious Sovereigne<br/>
WEE Your Majestyes most obedient and loyall Subje&bholigct;s the Commons now in Parliament assembled being
sensible that Your Majestie finds it highly neccessary to make a Warr against the French King for the
Defence of Your Majestyes Kingdomes and lessening the Power of the said King And that the Wealth and Treasure
of this Nation hath beene much exhausted by the Imporatation and Consumption of the French Commodities herein
after mentioned Doe most humbly present unto Your Majestie a Free Gift of severall Summes of Money for the
Use and Service of a Warr against the French King to be levyed in such manner as hereafter is expressed and
doe beseech Your Majestie to accept thereof and that it may be ena&bholigct;ed And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Commons
in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That all and every Person and Persons
Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate Guilds or Fraternityes within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or
Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede haveing any personall Estate either in such Debts oweing to them within this
Realme or without which he or they doe not account and estate as desperate over and besides such just Debts
as he she or they shall bona fide owe or in ready moneys shall yield and pay unto His Majestie for every Hundred
pounds in such Debts and ready moneys the Summe of Twenty shillings to be assessed imposed levyed and colle&bholigct;ed
in manner herein after mentioned.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Public Officers, &amp;c. (Exception) to pay 23. in the Pound of the Profits of their Offices.</head>
			<para id="p2">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons Commissioner
or Commissioners haveing useing or exerciseing any Office Place or publicke Imployment whatsoever (such persons
who are or shall be in Muster and Pay at Land or Sea for or in respe&bholigct; of such their Pay onely excepted) and
all and every their Deputyes Agents Clerks Secondaryes Substitutes and other their inferiour Ministers and Servants
whatsoever shall pay unto His Majestie the summe of Two shillings out of every Twenty shillings which he or
they doe receive in one yeare by vertue of any Salaries Fees Proffitts Perquisites or other Advantages to him
or them accrewing or by reason or occasion of their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Commissions Offices Agencies and
Imployments the said summe of Two shillings out of every Twenty shillings to be assessed imposed levyed and
colle&bholigct;ed in such manner as herein after is mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Penfions, &amp;c. from Government to pay 3s. in the Pound.</head>
			<para id="p3">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every other person and persons haveing
or claiming to have any Pension or yearely Stipend or Annuity issueing or payable out of any part of his Majestyes
Revenue exceeding Twenty pounds per Ann? shall pay unto his Majestie the summe of Three shillings out of
every Twenty shillings by the yeare soe given or granted as aforesaid to be assessed imposed levyed and collected
in such manner as is here in after mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Judges, Serjeants at Law, Counsellors, Advocates, &amp;c. and Persons pra&bholigct;ising Physic, to pay 2s. for every 20s.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Servant's to pay is. for every 20s.; except for Board Wages.; Every Person to pay is above the other Rates, (Except Persons receiving Alms, and certain Persons under 16 Years.)</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Judges and other persons haveing any judiciall
Office or other Office or Place of proffitt, And all Serjeants at Law Councellors Attourneys Sollicitors and
Scriveners And all Advocates Proctors and Publick Notaries And all and every person and persons pra&bholigct;ising the
Art of Phisicke shall pay unto His Majestie the summe of Two shillings out of every Twenty shillings which he
or they doe receive by his or their respe&bholigct;ive Salaries Offices Pra&bholigct;ices or Professions in one yeare, And all and
every Servant which at the time of the execution of this A&bholigct; shall receive Wages for his her or their Service
shall pay unto His Majestie the summe of Twelve pence for every Twenty shillings by the yeare which shall
be due or payable to him her or them for his her or their Wages except for Board Wages. And all and every
person and persons of what Age Sex or Condition soever shall pay unto His Majestie the summe of One shilling
over and above the rates charged upon them by this A&bholigct; except such Persons as shall receive Almes of the
Parish where they dwell and their Children being under the age of Sixteene yeares at the time of the execution
of this A&bholigct;, And except all Children being under the age of Sixteene yeares of all day Labourers and of all
Servants in Husbandry and of all other persons who by reason of their poverty are exempted from contributing
to the charge of Church and Poore, And alsoe except all Children being under the age of Sixteene yeares of
such who hath fower or more Children and is not worth in Lands Goods and Chattells the summe of Fifty
pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Rates of Payment by Peers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Duke resident in the Kingdom &pound;50; Marquis &pound;40; Earl &pound;30 ; Viscount &pound;20 ;Baron &pound;20; eldest Son of a Duke, &pound;30; younger Son of a Duke &pound;25; eldest Son of a Marquis, &pound;25; younger Son of a Marquis, &pound;20; eldest Son of an Earl, &pound;20; younger Son of an Earl, &pound;15; eldest Son of a Viscount, &pound;17. 10s.; younger Son of a Viscount, &pound;13. 6s. 8d.; eldest Son of a Baron, &pound;15; younger Son of a Baron, &pound;12; Baronet &pound;15; Knight of the Bath &pound;15; Knight Bachelor &pound;10; King's Sergeant at; Law &pound;20; other Sergeants &pound;15; Esquire &pound;5; Gentleman 20s,; Widow to pay the Third Part of Rate on her late Husband's Degrees.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained That all and every person and persons who at the time of the
Execution of this A&bholigct; shall be of the severall Rankes and Degrees hereafter mentioned shall, to the purpose
aforesaid contribute and pay the severall summes of money hereafter in this A&bholigct; sett downe and appointed that
is to say, Every person of the Degree of a Duke of England Scotland or Ireland inhabiting and resideing within
this Kingdome shall pay the summe of Fifty pounds, Every person of the Degree of a Marquesse of any of the
said three Kingdomes inhabiting and residing within this Kingdome shall pay the summe of Forty pounds,
Every person of the Degree of an Earle of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting and resideing within
this Kingdome the summe of Thirty pounds Every person of the Degree of a Viscount of any of the said
three Kingdomes and inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome the summe of Five and twenty pounds,
Every person of the Degree of a Baron of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting and resideing within
this Kingdome the sum of Twenty pounds, Every eldest Sonne of a Duke of any of the said three Kingdomes
and inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome being of the Age of Sixteene yeares the summe of Thirty
pounds, Every younger Sonne of a Duke of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting and resideing within
this Kingdome being of the age of Sixteene yeares the summe of Twenty [five<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] pounds, Every eldest Sonne of
a Marquesse of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome being of the
age of Sixteene yeares the summe of Twenty five pounds Every younger Sonne of a Marquesse of any of the
said three Kingdomes and inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome being of the age of Sixteene yeares
the summe of Twenty pounds, Every eldest Sonne of an Earle of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting
and resideing within this Kingdome being of the age of Sixteene yeares the summe of Twenty pounds, Every
younger Sonne of an Earle of any of the said Three Kingdomes and inhabiting or resideing within this Kingdome
being of the age of Sixteene yeares the summe of Fifteene pounds, Every eldest sonne of a Viscount of any
of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome being of the Age of Sixteene
yeares the summe of Seaventeene pounds ten shillings Every younger sonne of a Viscount of any of the said
three Kingdomes and inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome being of the age of Sixteene yeares the
summe of Thirteene pounds six shillings and eight pence, Every eldest sonne of a Baron of any of the said
three Kingdomes inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome and being of the age of Sixteene yeares the summe
of Fifteene pounds, Every younger Sonne of a Baron of any, of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting and
resideing within this Kingdome being of the age of Sixteene yeares the summe of Twelve pounds, Every
person of the Degree of a Baronet of any of the said three Kingdomes or of Nova Scotia and inhabiting and
resideing within this Kingdome the summe of Fifteene pounds, Every person that is a Knight of the Order of
the Bath inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome the Summe of Fifteene pounds, Every person who is a
Knight Batchelor inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome the Summe of Ten pounds, Every Serjeant at
Law being the Kings Serjeant the summe of Twenty pounds and every other Serjeant at Law the summe of
Fifteene pounds, Every person of the Degree of an Esquire or soe reputed or owning or writeing himselfe
such inhabiting or resideing in his Kingdome and being of the age of Sixteene yeares the summe of Five
pounds, Every Gentleman or reputed Gentleman or owneing or writeing himselfe such above the age of Sixteene
yeares inhabiting or resideing in this Kingdome the summe of Twenty shillings, Every Widow respe&bholigct;ively
according to her Husbands Degree shall pay the third part rated by this A&bholigct; upon that Degree of which the
Husband of such Wife was in his life time.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Gentleman having an Estate of &pound;300 or more, to pay 20s. though an Infant.</head>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That every Gentleman haveing an Estate of the value of Three hundred pounds
or more shall be charged with the summe of Twenty shillings though he be a Minor under the age of One
and twenty yeares. And noe Gentleman not haveing such an Estate and shall thereof make Oath before any
two or more of the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners shall be charged with the said summe of Twenty shillings in respe&bholigct;
of his Title.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Archbishop &pound;50; Bishop &pound;20; Dean &pound;10; Archdeacon &pound;2. 10s. Canon and Prebendary, except Sole Prebendary, and not rated at above &pound;30, &pound;2. 10s; Doctor of Divinity, Law, and Physic, &pound;5;</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Persons holding Two Benefices, &amp;c. &pound;5.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p10">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained That all and every the person and persons within the Kingdome of
England Dominion, of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede who at the time of the execution of this
A&bholigct; shall be of the severall Orders Rankes or Degrees hereafter mentioned shall to the purpose aforesaid pay
the severall summes of money hereafter in this A&bholigct; sett downe and appointed (that is to say) Every person of
the Order and Degree of an Archbishop shall pay the summe of Fifty pounds Every person of the Order and
Degree of a Bishop the summe of Twenty pounds, Every person of the Degree of a Deane. of any Cathedrall
or Collegiate Church shall pay the summe of Ten pounds, Every person of the Degree of an Archdeacon shall
pay the summe of Fifty shillings, Every person of the Degree of a Canon or Prebendary of any Cathedrall or
Collegiate Church excepting such sole Prebendary who is a sole Corporation and his Prebend not rated in the
Exchequer at above Thirty pounds shall pay the summe of Fifty Shillings, Every person of the Degree of a
Do&bholigct;or of Divinity, Law or Phisick shall pay the summe of Five pounds, Every person holding two or more
Benefices haveing Cure of Soules which shall amount together to the cleare yearely value of One hundred and
twenty pounds shall pay the summe of Five pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for D.D. not haveing Benefice, and for Widows of Ecclesiastical Persons.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwayes That noe Do&bholigct;or of Divinity not haveing any Benefice or Ecclesiasticall Preferment shall be
charged for his Title or Dignitie of Do&bholigct;or by vertue of this A&bholigct;, nor the Widdow of any Ecclesiasticall person
shall be charged for the third part according to the Title or Dignity of her late Husband.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Merchants of London not free &pound;10; Merchants and Traders holding a House of &pound;30; per Annum in London 10s; Members of East India Company 20s. in the Hundred for Shares; Members of the Guinea Company the like.</head>
						<para id="p12">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained That the severall persons hereafter mentioned resideing and inhabiting
within this Kingdome shall pay the severall summes of money hereafter in this A&bholigct; respe&bholigct;ively sett downe and
charged on them (that is to say) Every Merchant tradeing in the Port of London and resideing within the said
Citty or Ten miles thereof and not being free of the said Citty shall pay the summe of Ten pounds And every
Merchant or, other person whatsoever useing any Trade or manuall Occupation and holding a House of Thirty
pounds per Ann&bhouov; within the Citty of London and Weekly Bills of Mortality shall pay the summe of Ten
shillings Every Member of the East India Company shall pay for his Share or Shares which he hath in the
joynt Stocke of the said Company Twenty shillings for every Hundred pounds according to the first Capital of
the said Stocke, Every Member of the Guynea Company shall pay for his Share or Shares which he hath in
the joynt Stocke of that Company Twenty shillings for every Hundred pounds according to the first Capitall of
the said Stocke to be paid by the Governours and Treasurers of the said East India and Guynea Companies
and to be dedu&bholigct;ed at their next Dividend.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Alien Merchants &pound;10.</head>
			<para id="p13">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the Authority aforesaid That every Merchant Stranger resideing
within this Kingdome shall pay the summe of Ten pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Commissioners under 29 Car.II. c. I. to put this Act in Execution.</head>
			<para id="p14">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That for the better assessing, ordering, and levying of
the severall summes of money soe as aforesaid limitted and appointed to be paid for the more effe&bholigct;uall putting
of this present A&bholigct; in Execution that all and every the persons named and appointed by one A&bholigct; of this present
Session of Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; for raising the summe of Five hundred eighty fower thousand nine hundred
seaventy eight pounds two shillings and two pence halfe penny for the speedy building Thirty Shipps of Warr to be
Commissioners for putting the said A&bholigct; in execution shall alsoe be Commissioners for putting in execution this
present A&bholigct; and the Powers therein contained within all and every the severall Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes
and Places for which by the said former A&bholigct; they are appointed Commissioners.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Commissioners for the County of Lincoln to a&bholigct; for the City. ; General Meeting of Commissioners 12th April 1678;</head>
<para id="p15">
<emph type="i">to dire&bholigct; Precepts to Inhabitants, Constables, &amp;c. to attend; and thereupon the Commissioners to read, &amp;c. the Rates openly; and prefix other Days for bringing in Certificates of Names, &amp;c. of Persons residing within certain Limits,; together with the Assessment; Penalty.; and also return the Names of Persons to be Colle&bholigct;ors.; Parish answerable for their Payment to Receiver General.; Certificates and Assessments returned to Commissioners 10th May 1678; and thereupon Commissioners to; issue Warrants, &amp;c. for colle&bholigct;ing the Assessment; and Colle&bholigct;ors to demand Payment accordingly, within Six Days after Receipt of Warrant, and to levy and pay same 12th June 1678; and if not then paid, Distress upon Colle&bholigct;or.</emph></para>
			<para id="p16">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That the Commissioners for the County of Lincolne named and appointed in the said last
mentioned A&bholigct; shall be Commissioners alsoe for the Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne to execute therein
all the Powers and Dire&bholigct;ions of this present A&bholigct; as likewise of the said last mentioned A&bholigct;. Which said
Commissioners in order to the speedy Execution of this A&bholigct; shall in their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes
Townes and Places meete together at the most usuall or common Place of Meeting within each of the said
Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places respe&bholigct;ively at or before the Twelfth day of Aprill which shall
be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy eight And the said Commissioners or soe many of
them as shall be present at the first Generall Meeting or the major part of them may by their Consents and
Agreements divide as well themselves as other the Commissioners not then present for the Execution of this A&bholigct;
in Hundreds Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Wards Townes and other Places within their Limitts priviledged or not
priviledged in such manner and forms as to them shall seeme expedient and shall dire&bholigct; their several or joynt
Precept or Precepts to such Inhabitants High Constables Petty Constables Bayliffes and other like Officers and
Ministers and such Number of them as they in their discretions shall thinke most convenient to be Presenters
and Assessors requireing them to appeare before the said Commissioners at such time and place as they shall
appoint not exceeding Eight dayes. And at such their Appearances the said Commissioners or soe many of them
as shall be thereunto appointed shall openly reade or cause to be read unto them the Rates in this A&bholigct; mentioned
and openly declare the effe&bholigct; of their Charge unto them and how and in what manner they ought and should
make their Certificates according to the Rates aforesaid and shall then and there prefix another day to the said
persons to appeare before the said Commissioners and bring in their Certificates of the Names and Sirnames
Qualities Degrees and Titles of all and every the persons dwelling or resideing within the limitts of those places
with which they shall be charged and of the Substances and Values of every of them in Moneys, Debts,
Annuall Fees, Salaries, Perquisites Wages Proffitts, Emoluments and other Things chargeable by this A&bholigct;, together
with the Assesment of the respe&bholigct;ive Rates thereby imposed on each particular person according to the Rules and
Dire&bholigct;ions thereof without Concealment, Love, Favour, Dread or Malice upon paine of forfeiture of any summe
not exceeding Five pounds to be levyed as by this A&bholigct; is appointed and shall then alsoe returne the Names of
two or more able, and sufficient persons within the limitts and bounds of those parishes or Places where they
shall be chargeable respe&bholigct;ively as aforesaid to be Colle&bholigct;ors of the Moneyes due to his Majestie by this A&bholigct;, for
whose paying unto the Receiver Generall to be appointed by his Majestie, his Deputie or Deputyes in manner
following, such Moneyes as they shall be charged withall, the Parish or Place by who me they are soe imployed
shall be answerable; which Certificates and Assesments shall be ascertained and returned in to the Commissioners
at or before the Tenth day of May which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy
eight and upon the delivery and returneing in of such Certificates or Assesments unto the said Commissioners
they or any two or more of them shall forthwith issue out and deliver their Warrants or Estreates to such
Colle&bholigct;ors as aforesaid for the speedy colle&bholigct;ing and leavying of the said Assesments and all moneyes and Rates
due thereupon according to the intent and subsequent dire&bholigct;ions of this present A&bholigct;, of all which the said Colle&bholigct;ors
are hereby required to make demand of the partyes themselves or at the places of their last abode within six
dayes after the receipt of such Warrants or Estreats and to levy and pay in the same on or before the Twelfth
day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy eight at such place as the Commissioners shall appoint unto
the respe&bholigct;ive Receiver Generall his Deputy or Deputyes who are hereby impowered and required to call upon
and hasten the Colle&bholigct;ors to the said payment, and after the said Twelfth day of June to levy by Warrant under
the Hands and Seales of any two or more of the Commissioners upon the Colle&bholigct;or by distresse such summe
and summes of money as he hath received and as ought by him to have beene paid and is not paid by reason
of his failer in doeing his duty according to the dire&bholigct;ion of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Duplicate of Sum charged within every Hundred, &amp;c. to be returned into the Exchequer under the Hands and Seals of Commissioners before 12th July 1678.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Appeals to be first determined, and like Duplicates delivered to Receivers General, and Money paid before 10th Aug. 1678.; Commissioners may examine Presenters of Certificate, and if they have Cause to suspe&bholigct; that Property is of greater Value than represented, then to proceed against the Parties.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p18">And bee it en&bholigct;ed That a true Duplicate of the whole summe charged within every Hundred, Lath, Wapentake,
Parish Ward or Place rated and assessed in pursuance of this A&bholigct; without nameing the persons shall under the
Hands and Seales of two or more of the Commissioners thereunto appointed be returned into his Majestyes
Exchequer before the [Twelfth<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] day of July which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
seventy eight (all Appeales being first determined) and that like Duplicates be alsoe in convenient time made
out and delivered unto the Receivers Generall, soe as every of them may be duely charged to answere their
res&bholigct;ive Coll&bholigct;ions and Receipts and that the money thereupon due be paid into his Majestyes Exchequer before
the Tenth day of August which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy eight
and upon returne of any such Certificate the said Commissioners or any three or more of them shall and may
if they see cause examine the Presenters thereof. And if the said C&bhooov;mmissioners or any three or more of them
within the severall Limits shall at the time of the delivery of the Certificates or six dayes after have certaine
knowledge or vehemently suspe&bholigct; that any person or persons who ought to be mentioned in the said Certificates
is or are omitted or that any person or persons in the said Certificate mentioned is or are of a greater value
or Estate then in the said Certificate is mentioned, the said Commissioners or any Three or more of them shall
have power to warne such person or persons to appeare before them at a Day and Place prefixed to be examined
touching their Substance and Value or touching other matters which may any wayes concerne the Premisses and
if the person or persons warned to be soe examined shall negle&bholigct; to appeare not haveing a reasonable excuse
for such his Default, every person soe makeing Default shall pay unto his Majestie double the summe of the
Rate he should or ought to have been sett at.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Commissioners may inquire, but not on Oath, into the Value of Property assessed, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p19">And moreover the said Commissioners or any three or more of them shall have power by all lawfull wayes
and meanes without Oath to examine and enquire into the Value and Substance of such persons as are soe
chargeable by this A&bholigct; and to sett such Rate or Rates upon every such person or persons as shall be according
to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Receiver General 2d, in the Pound. Colle&bholigct;or 3d.</head>
			<para id="p20">And the said Receiver Generall shall have an allowance of Two pence in the Pound for all Moneys which
shall be by him paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer. And that every Colle&bholigct;or shall have Three pence in
the Pound for what Money he shall pay to the Receiver Generall his Deputy or Deputyes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Commissioners Clerks 2d. per Pound.</head>
			<para id="p21">And for the carefull writeing and transcribeing the said Warrants Estreates and Duplicates in due time Bee it
further ena&bholigct;ed That the Commissioners Clerkes who shall respe&bholigct;ively performe. the same shall by Warrant under
two or more of the Commissioners Hands have and recieve from the respe&bholigct;ive Recievers Generall their Deputy
or Deputyes Two pence in the Pound of all such Moneys as he shall have recieved by vertue of such Warrants
and Estreats who is hereby appointed and allowed to pay the same accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Persons assessed refusing to pay on Demand, Officer may distrain; Proceedings thereon.</head>
			<para id="p22">And if any person or persons shall refuse to pay the severall summe and summes and proportions appointed by
this A&bholigct; for such person to pay upon demand made by the Officer or Colle&bholigct;or of the Place according to the
Precept or Estreats to him delivered by the said Commissioners it shall and may be lawfull to and for such
Officer or Colle&bholigct;or who are hereby thereunto authorized and required for non payment thereof to distraine the
person or persons soe refuseing by his or their Goods or Chattells and the Distresse soe taken to keepe by the
space of fower dayes at the Costs and Charges of the Owner thereof, and if the said Owner doe not pay the
summe of money due by this A&bholigct; within the said fower dayes then the said Distresse to be appraised by three
or two of the Inhabitants where the said Distresse is taken and there to be sold by the said Officer for payment
of the said money and the overplus comeing by the said Sale (if any be) over and above the charges of takeing
and keeping the said Distresse to be immediately restored to the owner thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Persons assessed not paying in 20 Days, and where no sufficient Distress, Party imprisoned in the Common Gaol without Bail.</head>
			<para id="p23">And if any person or persons assessed by this A&bholigct; shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to pay the summe or summes soe
assessed by the space of Twenty dayes after demand as aforesaid where noe sufficient Distresse can or may be found
whereby the same may be levyed, in every such case three or more of the Commissioners by this A&bholigct; appointed
for any such Citty County or Place are hereby authorized by Warrant under their Hands and Seales to committ
such person or persons to the Common Goale, there to be kept without Baile or Mainprize untill payment shall,
be made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Persons aggrieved by Rate, &amp;c. may complain to Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to meet to hear Complaints.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p25">And if any person certified assessed or rated finde him or her selfe agrieved with such assessing or rateing
and doe within Ten dayes after demand thereof made, complaine to the Commissioners the said C&bhooov;mmissioners or
any two or more of them whereof one of the Commissioners who signed (or allowed<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) his or her Rate to be one
shall and may within, fourteene dayes next after such Complaint perticularly examine the person soe complaining
upon his or her Oath of his or her Personall Estate aforesaid and upon due examination or knowledge thereof
abate defalke increase or inlarge the said Assesment, and the same soe abated increased or inlarged shall be
estreated by them into the Exchequer in manner aforesaid, and to that end the said Commissioners are hereby
required to meete together for the determining of such Complaints and Appeales accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Officers rated where their Office executed;</head>
			<para id="p26"><emph type="i">other Persons, not being Householders, &amp;c. and Servants, where they live</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That every person rated for his Office shall be rated and pay for [the<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] said Office
in the Place where the said Office is executed and every person to be otherwise rated shall be rated and the summe
or summes on him or her sett and levyed at such places where he or she and with his or her Family shall be
resident at the time of the execution of this A&bholigct;, and that all persons not being Householders nor haveing a
certaine place of Abode and all Servants shall be taxed at the place where they are resident at the time of the
execution of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. If Persons having several Mansions be doubly charged,</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">how such Persons discharged.; Persons out of the Realm rated at last Place of Abode.; Persons escaping from Taxation charged at double Value.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p29">Provided alwayes That if any person haveing severall Mansion Houses or Places of Residence shall be
doubly charged by vertue of this A&bholigct;, that upon Certificate made by two or more of the Commissioners for the
County Citty or Place (which Certificate the said Commissioners are required to give without Delay, Fee or
Reward) of his or their last personall Residence under their Hands and Seales of the summe or summes there
charged upon him or them, or in what capacity or respe&bholigct; he or they were soe charged and upon Oath made of
such Certificate before the Commissioners to whome such Certificate shall be tendred, which Oath the said
Commissioners are hereby authorized to administer then the person and persons soe doubly charged shall (for soe
much as shall be soe certified) be discharged in every other County, Citty or Place. And if any person at the time of
the assessing shall be out of the Realme such person shall be rated where such person was last abideing within
the Realme, And if any person that ought to be taxed by vertue of this A&bholigct; by changeing his place of residence
or by Fraude or Covin shall escape from the Taxation and not be taxed and the same proved before the
Commissioners or two of them or two Justices of the Peace of the County where such person dwelleth or resideth
at any time within Six moneths next ensueing after such Taxe made every [such<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] person that shall soe escape from the
said Taxation and Payment shall be charged upon proofe thereof at the double Value of soe much as he should
or ought to have beene taxed by the A&bholigct;, the said double Value upon Certificate thereof made into the
Exchequer by the Commissioners or Justices before whome such proofe shall be made to be leavyed of the Goods
Lands and Tenements of such persons towards the Supply aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Commissioners may assess other Commissioners and Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p30">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Commissioners which shall be within any County or Place within their
respe&bholigct;ive Limitts or the major Part of them shall taxe and assesse every other Commissioner joyned with them,
and the Commissioners within their Division shall assesse every Assessor within their Division and as well all
summes upon every the said C&bhooov;missioners and Assessors as the Assesments made and presented by the Presenters
as aforesaid shall be written estreated levyed and gathered as it should and ought to have beene as if the said
C&bhooov;mmissioners had not beene named Commissioners.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Peers to be rated by Persons herein named.</head>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">Not subje&bholigct; to Imprisonment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p32">[Provided neverthelesse That all and every the Peeres who are to be rated by vertue of this A&bholigct; for their Offices or
Personall [Estate<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] shall be rated by Arthur Earle of Anglesey Lord Keeper ;of the Privy Seale Christopher Duke
of Albemarle Charles Marquesse of Winchester Henry Earle of Arlington Lord Chamberlaine of His Majestyes
Household Anthony Earle of Kent William Earle of Derby Theophilus Earle of Huntingdon William Earle of
Bedford Charles Earle of Dorsett and Midlesex John Earle of Bridgewater James Earle of Northampton Oliver
Earle of Bolingbrooke Charles Earle of Berkshire Thomas Earle Rivers Heneage Earle of Winchelsea Henry Earle
of Clarendon Arthur Earle of Essex John Earle of Bath Charles Earle of Carlisle William Earle of Craven Robert
Earle of Aylisbury Anthony Earle of Shaftsbury Thomas Viscount Fauconberg George Viscount Hallifax Francis
Viscount Newport Richard Lord Archbishop of Yorke Henry Lord Bishop of London Nathaniell Lord Bishop of
Durham George Lord Bishop of Winchester Seth Lord Bishop of Salisbury Edward Lord Bishop of Carlisle John
Lord Bishop of Rochester Peter Lord Bishop of Bath and Wells John Lord Bishop of Chester George Lord Berkley
Robert Lord Ferrars Phillip Lord Wharton Forde Lord Grey of Werke William Lord Mainard John Lord Bellases
Charles Lord Gerrard of Brandon Charles Lord Cornwallis George Lord Delamer and John Lord Fretchevile or any
Five of them and not otherwise and shall not be subje&bholigct;ed to the Imprisonment of his or their persons Any
thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Taxes of Peers to be received by a Colle&bholigct;or nominated by them.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided alsoe and it is hereby declared That the severall Rates and Taxes to which the Lords and Peeres
of this Realme shall be lyeable by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be received by a Colle&bholigct;or to be nominated by the
Peeres which said Colle&bholigct;or shall cause the same to be paid into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer at Westminster
upon, or before the aforesaid Tenth Day of August One thousand: six hundred seaventy and eight.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Proviso for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey, and Guernsey.</head>
			<para id="p34">Provided That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to the Inhabitants of Scotland Ireland Jersey. or Guernsey for or
concerning any such personall Estate as aforesaid which they or any other to their use have within the Places
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Assessors and others appointed by Commissioners negle&bholigct;ing Duty; Penalty not exceeding &pound;20. for any one Offence; to be certified into Exchequer, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p35">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any Assessor Colle&bholigct;or Receiver or other person appointed by the
Commissioners shall wilfully negle&bholigct; or refuse to performe his duty in the due and speedy execution of this present
A&bholigct; the said respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any three or more of them may and shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; impose
on such person or persons soe refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing their dutyes any Fine not exceeding the Summe of
Twenty pounds for any one offence, the same to be levyed and certifyed as aforesaid into His Majestyes Court
of Exchequer and charged upon the respe&bholigct;ive Recievers Generall amongst the rest of the Rates aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Commissioners to require Accounts from Receiver General, and in case of Failure Money to be levied.</head>
			<para id="p36">And the said C&bhooov;mmissioners or any two or more of them may or shall from time to time call for and require
an Account from the respe&bholigct;ive Receivers Generall of all the Moneyes received by them of the said Colle&bholigct;ors and
of the payment thereof into His Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer according to the dire&bholigct;ion of this A&bholigct; and in case
of any failer in the Premisses the said Commissioners or any two or more of them are hereby required to cause
the same to be forthwith leavyed and paid according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. If any Controversy concerning Rates, Proceedings.</head>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">Questions to be determined by Two or more Commissioners.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p38">And in case of any Controversie ariseing betweene the said Commissioners concerning the said Rates or
Assessments the Commissioners that shall be concerned therein shall have noe voice but shall withdraw during the
debate of such Controversie until it be determined by the rest of the Commissioners and all questions and differences
that shall arise touching any of the said Rates Taxes Assessments or Leavyes shall be heard and finally determined
by two or more of the Commissioners upon complaint thereof to them made by any person or persons thereby
grieved without further trouble or Suite in Law.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Receivers General to give Acquittances to Colle&bholigct;ors gratis.</head>
			<para id="p39">And the said Receiver Generall his Deputy or Deputyes shall give Acquittances gratis to the said Colle&bholigct;ors for
all Moneyes of them recieved in pursuance of this A&bholigct;, which Acquittances shall be a full Discharge to the said
Colle&bholigct;ors respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Colle&bholigct;ors to deliver to Receivers General a Schedule of Names, &amp;c. of the Persons rated making Default; to be returned in to the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p40">And the said Colle&bholigct;ors shall make and deliver to the said Recievers Generall their Deputy or Deputyes a
perfe&bholigct; Schedule fairely written in Parchment under their Hands and Seales signed and allowed by any Two or
more of the respe&bholigct;ive C&bhooov;mmissioners containing the Names Sirnames and Places of Abode of every person .as well
Peere as Commoner within their respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;ion that shall make defaults of payment of any of the S&bhouov;mes
that shall be rated or assessed on such person by vertue of this A&bholigct; and the Summe and Summes charged on
every such person the same to be by him returned into His Majestyes Exchequer whereupon every person soe
makeing default of payment may be charged by Processe of the Court according to the course thereof in that
behalfe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Proviso against Double Charge in respe&bholigct; of Titles.</head>
			<para id="p41">Provided always and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That noe person shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; be doubly charged for or in
respe&bholigct; of severall [Honours<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Honours or Degrees but that every such person shall be charged and assessed for such
Title Honour or Degree onely as is highest rated by this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Letters Patent from the Crown, Privileges, &amp;c. or Non obstantes, not to exempt from Payment of Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p42">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Letters Patents granted by the Kings Majestie
or any of His Royall Progenitors or to be granted by His Majestie to any person or persons Cittyes Burroughs
or Townes Corporate within this Realme of any manner of Liberties Priviledges or Exemptions from Subsidies
Tolls Taxes Assesments or Aids shall be construed or taken to exempt any person or persons Citty Burrough or
Towne Corporate or any the Inhabitants of the same from the Burthen and Charge of any. S&bhouov;me or Summes of
Money granted by this A&bholigct;, And all Non obstantes in such Letters Patents made or to be made in barr of any
A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s of Parlyament for the Supply., or Assistance of His Majestie are hereby declared to be void and of
none effe&bholigct; Any such Letters Patents Grants or Charter or any Clause of Non obstante or other matter or thing
therein contained or any Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Constables, &amp;c. to aid in executing Warrants, &amp;c. of Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p43">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That all Constables Headburroughs Tythingmen and other His Majestyes
Officers shall and are hereby required and enjoyned to be respe&bholigct;ively aideing and assisting in the execution of
this A&bholigct; and to obey and execute such Precepts or Warrants as shall be to them dire&bholigct;ed in that behalfe by the
respe&bholigct;ive C&bhooov;mmissioners hereby appointed or any two or more of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. Persons lending Money on Credit of A&bholigct;, not exceeding &pound;300,000, to have Tallies of Loan, and Orders for Repayment.</head>
			<para id="p44">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the authoritie aforesaid That all and every person and persons who
shall lend any Moneyes not exceeding Three hundred thousand pounds in the whole to your Majestie upon the
credit of this A&bholigct; and pay the same into the Receipt of the Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally of
Loane strucke for the same and an Order for his Repayment beareing the same Date with his Tally, in which
Order shall be alsoe contained a Warrant for payment of Interest for Forbearance after the Rate of Seaven
Pounds per Cent? per Ann? for his Consideration to be paid every Three months untill the repayment of his
Principall.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. Persons furnishing Navy or Ordanance with Goods, on Certificate thereof to have Warrants for Payment.</head>
			<para id="p45">And that all person and persons who shall furnish Your Majestie Your Officers of the Navy or Ordnance with
any Wares Goods Shipps Vi&bholigct;ualls or any other Necessaries for the Service aforesaid shall upon Certificate of the
Commissioners and Officers of the Navy or of the Master or C&bhooov;mmissioners and Officers of the Ordnance or some
of them without delay forthwith have' made out to them Warrants or Orders for the payment of the moneyes due
or payable unto them which Certificates the said Officers of Your Navy Commis?sers and Officers of the Ordnance
shall make without Fee Charge or Delay.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Orders for Repayment of Money lent, and Orders signed by Treasury; to be registered in course.</head>
			<para id="p46">And that all Orders for repayment of money lent shall be registred in course according to the date of the
[Talley<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] respe&bholigct;ively. And that all Orders signed by the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer of the Exchequer for
payment of Moneyes for Goods Wares Vi&bholigct;ualls and other Necessaries furnished to Your Majestie Your Officers
Master or Commissioners as aforesaid shall be registred in course according to the time of bringing to the Office
of the Auditor of Receipt the Certificates above mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. Orders signed by Treasury to be entered in course.</head>
			<para id="p47">And that all Orders soe signed for payments dire&bholigct;ed by His Majestie shall be entred in course according to
their respe&bholigct;ive dates and none of the sorts of Orders above-mentioned either for Loanes of Money Supplyes of
Wares, Goods, Vi&bholigct;ualls or other Necessaries or by specially Dire&bholigct;ion shall have preference one before another but
shall all be entred in their course according to the dates of the Talleys the times of bringing their Certificates
and the dates of the Orders for payments dire&bholigct;ed by his Majestie as they are in point of time respe&bholigct;ively before
each other.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. Persons to be paid in course, as their Orders stand entered.</head>
			<para id="p48">And that all and every person and- persons shall be paid in course according as their Orders shall stand entred
in the said Register Booke, be it Orders for payments dire&bholigct;ed by His Majestie or of Moneyes lent or for
Wares Commodities Shipps Vic?tualls or other Necessaries furnished as aforesaid soe as that the Person Native or
Forreigner his Executors Administrators and Assignes who shall have his Warrant or Order Warrants or Orders
first entred in the said Booke of Register shall be taken and accounted as the first person to be paid upon the
moneyes to come in by vertue of this A&bholigct; and he or they that shall have his or their Warrants or Orders Warrant
or Order next entred shall be taken and accounted to be the second person to be paid and soe successively and
in course.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. Monies raised by Assessments to be liable in the like Order.</head>
			<para id="p49">And that the moneys to come in by this A&bholigct; shall be in the same order lyeable to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said
respe&bholigct;ive partyes their Executors Administrators or Assignes successively without preference of one before another
and not otherwise and not be divertible to any other Use Intent or Purpose whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. No Fees to be taken for providing or making Registers, Entries, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p50">
				<emph type="i">Penalty, Treble Damages and Costs of Suit, and Officer demanding, &amp;c. Fee to lose his Place.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p51">And that noe Fee Reward or Gratuity dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly be demanded or taken of any Your Majestyes
Subje&bholigct;s for provideing or makeing of any such Books Registers Entryes View Search or Certificate in or for
payment of money lent or the Interest thereof or for payment of any Money upon any Order upon any Contra&bholigct;
for Wares and Goods furnished to the use of Your Majestyes Navy and Ordnance as aforesaid by any of Your
Majestyes Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputyes on paine of payment of treble Damages to the party grieved
by the party offending with Costs of Suite, or if the Officer himselfe take or demand any such Fee or Reward
then to loose his Place alsoe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Undue Preference by Officer.</head>
			<para id="p52">
				<emph type="i">A&bholigct;ion by Party grieved, and Loss of Place.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p53">And if any the undue preference of one before another shall be made either in point of Registry contrary to the
true meaning of this A&bholigct; by any such Officer or Officers then the party offending shall be lyeable by A&bholigct;ion of
Debt or on the Case to pay the value of the Debt Damages and costs to the party grieved and shall be forejudged
from his Place or Office.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. The like as to Deputy.</head>
			<para id="p54">And if such preference be unduely made by any his Deputy or Clerke without dire&bholigct;ion or privity of his Master
Then such Deputy, or Clerke [onely<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] shall be lyeable to such A&bholigct;ion Debt Damages and Costs and shall be for ever
after uncapeable of his Place or Office.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>XLIII. Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller offending, liable to Forfeiture, and Deputies to A&bholigct;ion,</head>
			<para id="p55">And in case. the Auditor shall not dire&bholigct; the Order or the Clerke of the Pells record or the Teller make payment
according to each persons due place and Order as aforedire&bholigct;ed Then he or they shall be judged to forfeite and
their respe&bholigct;ive Deputyes and Clerks herein offending to be lyeable to such A&bholigct;ion Debt Damages and Costs in such
manner as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>XLIV. Penalties, &amp;c. how to be recovered.</head>
			<para id="p56">All which said Penaltyes Forfeitures Damages and Costs to be incurred by any of the Officers of the Exchequer
Navy or Ordnance or any their Deputyes or Clerks shall and may be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or
Information in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion Priviledge
Wager of Law Injun&bholigct;ion or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise granted or allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>XLV. What not to be interpreted undue Preference where Tallies brought the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p57">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby declared That if it happen that severall Tallyes of Loane or Certificates
for Wares delivered or Orders for payments dire&bholigct;ed by Your Majestie as aforesaid beare date or be brought the
same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be registred Then it shall be interpreted noe undue preference which
of those he enters first soe he enters them all the same day.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>XLVI. The like Ena&bholigct;ment when Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, and Teller pay subsequent Orders when first demanded.</head>
			<para id="p58">Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpreted any undue Preference to incurr any Penalty in point of Payment
if the Auditor dire&bholigct; and the Clerke of the Pells record and the Teller doe pay subsequent Orders of persons that
come and demand their Money and bring their Orders before other persons that did not come to demand their
Money and bring their Order in their course soe as there be soe much Money reserved as will satisfie their
orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon Loane being to cease from the
time the Money is soe reserved and kept in Bank for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>XLVII. Persons having Money due to them may assign their Interest in Warrants, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p59">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee.; Assignee may assign, and Assignor not to release, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p60">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every person or persons to whome any money
shall be due by vertue of this A&bholigct; after Warrant or Order entred in the Booke of Register aforesaid for Payment
thereof his Executors Administrators or Assignes by Indorsment of his Order or Warrant may assigne and transferr
his Right Title Interest and Benefit of such Warrant or Order or any part thereof to any other which being
notifyed in the Office of the Auditor. of the Receipt aforesaid and an Entry and Memoriall thereof alsoe made in
the Booke of Registry aforesaid for Warrants (which the Officers shall upon request without Fee or Charge
accordingly make) shall entitle such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the Benefit thereof
and Payment thereon, and such Assignee may in like manner assigne againe and soe toties quoties and afterwards
it shall not be in the power of such person or persons who have made such Assignements to make void release
or discharge the same or any the Moneys thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>XLVIII. In A&bholigct;ions, &amp;c. for executing A&bholigct;,</head>
			<para id="p61">
				<emph type="i">General Issue.; Treble Costs.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p62">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion Plaint Suite or Information shall be
commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in
execution of this A&bholigct; such person or persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall or may pleade the Generall
Issue Not guilty, and upon any Issue joyned may give this A&bholigct; and the Speciall matter in Evidence and if the
Plaintiffe or Prosecutor shall become Nonsuite or forbeare further prosecution or suffer Discontinuance or if a
Verdi&bholigct; passe against him the Defendant and Defendants shall recover their treble Costs for which they shall have
the like remedy as in any Case where Costs by the Law are given to Defendants</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>XLIX. Parents, &amp;c. of Infants making Default, to pay.</head>
			<para id="p63">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained That the respe&bholigct;ive Parents Guardians and Tutors of every person
under the age of one and twenty yeares shall upon default of payment by such person and upon demand pay
what is due and payable by this A&bholigct; for every such person resideing in their Family or under their Tution and
not exempted as before herein is mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s50">
			<head>L. Lodgers, &amp;c. to be taxed at Place of Residence.</head>
			<para id="p64">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That all persons not being Householders nor haveing a certaine place of abode and all Servants
shall be taxed at the place where they shall be resident at the time of the Execution of this A&bholigct; and not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s51">
			<head>LI. The times and manner in which Colle&bholigct;ors to pay Monies Colle&bholigct;ed by this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p65">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Moneyes due and payable by this A&bholigct; shall be
paid by the particular Colle&bholigct;ors of the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cityes Burroughs Townes Parishes and Places who
shall colle&bholigct; the same unto such Receiver Generall as shall by His Majestie be appointed to receive the same or to the
Deputy or Deputyes of such Receiver Generall to be appointed under his Hand and Seale whereof notice shall
be given by the Receiver Generall unto the Commissioners or any two of them within their respe&bholigct;ive Divisions
within Ten dayes after the first Generall Meeting and soe from time to time within Ten dayes after every death
or removeall of any Deputy if any such shall happen, and the Receipt of such Receiver Generall his Deputy or
Deputyes or any one of them shall be a sufficient Discharge unto every such Colle&bholigct;or.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s52">
			<head>LII. Not obliged to travel above 10 Miles to make Payments.</head>
			<para id="p66">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the perticular Colle&bholigct;ors for payment of any summes by them received unto such
Receiver Generall or his Deputy shall not be obliged to travel I above Ten miles from the place of their Habitations.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s53">
			<head>LIII. Receiver under any former A&bholigct; not having accounted not to be Receiver under this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p67">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;500.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p68">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any person haveing been a Receiver
of any money due upon any A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s passed before the begining of this present Session of Parlyament and
not haveing accompted for all the moneys by him received and to be accompted for upon such A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s shall
be appointed Receiver for any the moneys due upon this A&bholigct; and shall intermedle therein every such person shall
forfeite the summe of Five hundred pounds to be recovered by any person or persons that will sue for the same.
in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or other Information wherein noe
Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion Wager of Law Ayde Prier Priviledge Injun&bholigct;ion or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise prayed
granted or allowed nor any more then one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s54">
			<head>LIV. Receiver General, within One Month, to give Commissioners a Receipt for Monies received by him;</head>
			<para id="p69">
				<emph type="i">such Receipt to be a Discharge of the Hundred, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p70">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every Receiver Generall from time to time within
the space of one Moneth next after he shall have received the full summe that shall be charged upon any
Hundred or Division for each particular Payment that is to be made to such Receiver General by vertue of this
A&bholigct; shall give to the Commissioners that shall a&bholigct; in such Hundred or Division a Receipt under his Hand and Seale
acknowledgeing his receipt of the full summe charged upon such Hundred or Division for such particular Payments,
which Receipt shall be a full Discharge of such Hundred or Division for such particular Payments both against
his Majestie his Heires and Successors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s55">
			<head>LV. Receivers General certifying Arrears where none due, or unduly setting insuper.</head>
			<para id="p71">
				<emph type="i">Penalty to the Party; Penalty to the King.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p72">And for the better preventing of such unjust vexations as might be occasioned by such persons as shall be
appointed Receivers Generall of any of the Summes of Money granted by this A&bholigct;, and to the intent the said
Receivers Generall may returne a true Account into his Majestyes Court of Exchequer of such Summes of Money
as shall be received by them and every of them their and every of their Deputy, and Deputyes Bee it further
ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any such Receiver Generall shall returne or certifie into the said
Court any Summe or Summes of Money to be in arreare [and<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] unpaid after the same have beene received either
by such Receiver Generall or by his Deputy or Deputyes or any of them or shall cause any person or persons
to be sett insuper in, the said Court for any Summe or Summes of Money that hath beene soe received That then
every such Receiver Generall shall forfeite to every person and persons that shall be molested vexed or damaged
by reason of such unjust Certificate, Returne or setting in super treble the Damages that shall be thereby occasioned
the said Damages to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in which noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion
or Wager of Law shall be allowed nor any more then one Imparlance and shall alsoe forfeite to his Majestie
his Heires and Successors double the Summe that shall be soe unjustly certified or returned or caused to be
sett in super.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s56">
			<head>LVI. Money lent under this A&bholigct; not to be rated.</head>
			<para id="p73">Provided alwayes That noe Summe of Money which shall be lent unto his Majestie upon the Securitie of this
present A&bholigct; at the rate of Seaven pounds per Cent shall be rated or assessed by vertue of this A&bholigct; Any thing
herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s57">
			<head>LVII. Commissioners not liable to Penalties of 25 Car. II. c. 2.</head>
			<para id="p74">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Commissioner or Commissioners or any other
Officer that shall be imployed in the Execution of this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall be lyeable for or
by reason of their a&bholigct;ing or proceeding as Commissioners by vertue of this A&bholigct; to any of the Penalties mentioned
in an A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for preventing Dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants for not takeing the
Oaths or Declaration in the said A&bholigct; expressed in case such Commissioner or Commissioners Officer or Officers
have before that time taken the said Oathes and subscribed the Declarations in the recited A&bholigct; mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s58">
			<head>LVIII. Monies colle&bholigct;ed under this A&bholigct; (Exception) to be applied for the Use of a War against the French King.</head>
			<para id="p75">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Moneyes colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid by vertue
of this A&bholigct; (except the Allowances-therein made to the respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;ors Clerks and Receivers Generall and
the usuall Fees of the Officers of the Exchequer and what shall be issued thence for the Repayment of Loanes
made in pursuance of this A&bholigct; into the Exchequer and Interest for the same) shall be applyed and appropriated
and are hereby appropriated for the Use and Service of a Warr against the French King and to noe other intent
use or purpose whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s59">
			<head>LIX. Colle&bholigct;ors of Parishes, &amp;c. keeping Monies in their Hands, or unduly paying away the same.</head>
			<para id="p76">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5.; Receiver General or Deputy unduly paying Monies received under this A&bholigct;.; Penalty &pound;500.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p77">And for the more effe&bholigct;uall doeing thereof and that the said Moneyes hereby given may be applyed to the Use
and Service aforesaid Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed And it is ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any Colle&bholigct;or
of any Parish or Place shall keepe in his Hands any part of the money by him colle&bholigct;ed for any longer time
then is by this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ed (other then the allowance made unto him by this A&bholigct;) or shall pay any part thereof
to any person or persons other then the Receiver Generall of such County or Place or his Deputy that every such
Colle&bholigct;or shall forfeite for every such Offence the summe of Five pounds. And in case any Receiver Generall
or his Deputy shall pay any part of the Moneys paid to him or them by any Colle&bholigct;or by vertue of this A&bholigct; to
any person or persons whatsoever other then the Receipt of his Majestyes Exchequer and that at or within the
respe&bholigct;ive times limitted by this A&bholigct; or in case such Receiver Generall shall pay any part of the said Moneys by
any Warrant of the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer or either of them or Commissioners of the Treasury for the
time being or upon any Talley of Pro or Talley of Anticipation or other way or device whatsoever whereby to
divert or hinder the a&bholigct;ual payment thereof into the Receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid That such Receiver
Generall shall for every such offence of himselfe or his Deputy forfeite the summe of Five hundred pounds to him
or them that shall, sue for the same in any Court of Record by Bill Plaint or other Information wherein noe
Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager in Law is to be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s60">
			<head>LX. Treasury not to dire&bholigct; any Warrant for Payment of</head>
			<para id="p78">
				<emph type="i">Monies other than into the Exchequer, nor for striking of any Tally of Pro, or Anticipation.; Teller not to throw down any Bill, &amp;c. till he shall have received Money.</emph></para>
			<para id="p79">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer or
Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being or any of them doe not dire&bholigct; any Warrant to any of the
said Colle&bholigct;ors or Receivers Generall or their Deputyes for the payment of any part of those Moneyes to any
person or persons other then into the Receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid nor shall they or any of them dire&bholigct;
any Warrant to the Officers of the Exchequer for the strikeing of any Talley of Pro or Talley of Anticipation,
nor doe any other matter or thing whereby to divert the a&bholigct;uall payment of the said Moneys into the Receipt
of the Exechequer, Nor shall the Officers of the Exchequer dire&bholigct; or strike or record the strikeing of any Talley
of Pro or Talley of Anticipation upon any of the said Moneys upon any Account or Warrant whatsoever. Nor
shall any Teller throw downe a Bill whereby to charge himselfe with any of the said Moneyes untill he shall have
a&bholigct;ually received the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s61">
			<head>LXI. Treasury not to sign Warrants, &amp;c. for Money, except for a War against the French King, or Repayment of Loans upon this A&bholigct;</head>
			<para id="p80">
				<emph type="i">the like as to Officers of the Exchequer.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p81">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer or
either of them or the Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being doe not signe any Warrant or Order or
doe any other matter or thing for the issueing of any of the said Moneys out of the Exchequer for any use or
service whatsoever other then for the use and service of a Warr against the French King or for the repayment
of Loanes upon the credit of this A&bholigct; or Interest of the same as by this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed, nor shall the Auditor of
the Receipt draw any Order for the issueing of any part of the said Moneyes to any person or persons whatsoever
for any use or service other then the use and service of a Warr against the French King or for the repayment
of Loanes and Interest for the same as aforesaid nor shall he dire&bholigct; or the Clerke of the Pells record or the
Teller make payment of any of the said. Moneys by vertue of any Warrant or upon any Order or other way or
device whatsoever other then for the uses aforesaid and to be soe mentioned and expressed in such Warrant and
Order.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s62">
			<head>LXII. Loans under this A&bholigct; appropriated to a War against the French King.</head>
			<para id="p82">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Loans upon the Credit of this A&bholigct; be and
are hereby appropriated to the use and service of a Warr against the French King nor shall they [be issued out of
the Exchequer to any other Intent or Purpose whatsoever nor by any other Warrant .or Order but wherein it is
expressed that the same is for the use and service of a Warr against the French King.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s63">
			<head>LXIII. Treasurer of the Navy, and Treasurer of the Ordnance, to keep Monica apart;</head>
			<para id="p83">
				<emph type="i">Regulations for Treasurer of the Navy and Ordnance, and Treasurer and Paymaster of the Land Forces issuing and paying Monies.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p84">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Treasurer of the Navy Treasurer or
Paymaster of the Ordnance and Treasurer [and <ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Paymaster of the Land forces and every other Person to whome any
of the Moneys colle&bholigct;ed or paid by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be issued upon Account (of whome good Security
shall be first taken) or to whome any of the Loanes had upon this A&bholigct; shall be issued upon Account shall keepe
all such Moneys paid to them respe&bholigct;ively distin&bholigct; and apart from all other Moneys and that the said Treasurer
of the Navy Treasurer or Paymaster of the Ordnance issue and pay the same by Warrant of the principall Officers
and Commissioners of the Navy and principall Officers of the Ordnance respe&bholigct;ively or three or more of them and
mentioning and expressing that it is for the use and service of a Warr against the French King [And that the
Treasurer or Paymaster of the Land forces doe not issue or pay any of the said Moneys but by Warrant expressing
that the same is for the Ufe and Service of a Warr against the French King [and that noe other person or persons
whatsoever to whome any Loans upon this A&bholigct; or Moneys ariseing thereby shall be paid upon Account doe issue
or make use of the same to any Intent or Purpose whatsoever other then for the Use and Service of a Warr
against the French King.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s64">
			<head>LXIV. And for Commissioners, &amp;c. of the Navy, Bills, as to signing Navy Bills, &amp;c. for issuing such Money.</head>
			<para id="p85">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Principall Officers and Commissioners of
the Navy and Principall Officers of the Ordnance and such person or persons as doe signe the Warrants to the
Treasurer or Paymaster of the Land Forces or to any other person or persons receiving any of the said Moneys
upon account shall not signe any Navy Bill or Warrant or doe any other a&bholigct; or thing for the issueing and paying
any of the said Moneys to any use intent or purpose whatsoever other then for the Use and Service of the said
Warr and to be soe expressed in the said Navy Bill or Warrant.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s65">
			<head>LXV. Officers appointed to receive Monies misapplying same;</head>
			<para id="p86">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p87">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That if any of the Officers or other persons aforesaid shall
after receipt of any of the said Moneys divert or misapply the same or any part thereof by vertue of any Warrant
from the Lord Treasurer for the time being or other superior Officer contrary to the true intent and meaning of
this A&bholigct; That then such Officer or Officers soe diverting or misapplying the said Money shall forfeite the like Summe
soe diverted or misapplyed which said Forfeiture shall be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information
in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall
be allowed, one Moyety of which Forfeiture soe to be recovered shall be to the Informer [or him that shall sue
for the same<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] and the other Moyety thereof to be distributed to the Poore of the Parish where such Offence shall
be committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s66">
			<head>LXVI. Officers of Exchequer or Navy misapplying Monies;</head>
			<para id="p88">
				<emph type="i">Loss of Office and Incapacity.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p89">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any Officer or Officers mentioned in this A&bholigct;
or in any wise belonging to the Exchequer Navy Ordnance or Land Forces or other person receiving any of
the said Moneyes upon Account shall wittingly and wilfully offend against this Law or any Clause thereof by
diverting or misapplying any of the Moneys colle&bholigct;ed or paid by vertue of this A&bholigct; or any Loane had thereupon
contrary to the true intent and meaning of this said A&bholigct; That for any and every such Offence such Officer and
Officers [and<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] other person receiving any of the said Moneys upon Account, soe offending shall forfeite his Office
and Place and is and are hereby disabled and made incapeable to hold or execute the said Office or any other Office
whatsoever for the future.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s67">
			<head>LXVII. No Stay of Prosecution in A&bholigct;ion for Penalties.</head>
			<para id="p90">Provided alsoe and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That noe stay of Prosecution upon any Command Warrant Motion Order
or Dire&bholigct;ion by Non vult ulterius prosequi shall be had made admitted received or allowed by any Court whatsoever
in any Suite or Proceeding by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information or otherwise for the Recovery of all or any
the Paines Forfeitures or Penaltyes upon any person or persons by this A&bholigct; infli&bholigct;ed or therein mentioned or for or in
order to the Convi&bholigct;ion or Disability of any person offending against this Law.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s68">
			<head>LXVIII. Auditor of Exchequer to transmit to the House of Commons Account of Monies paid, Loans, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p91">
				<emph type="i">Treasurer of Navy, &amp;c. to give a like Account.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p92">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the Auditor of the Receipt of the Exchequer for
the time being shall transmitt to the Commons in Parlyament assembled an Account of all the Moneys paid into the
Exchequer by vertue of this A&bholigct; and of all Loanes thereupon and to whome the same are issued and paid and by
whose Warrant and for what uses And that the Treasurer of the Navy Treasurer or Paymaster of the Ordnance and
Treasurer or Paymaster of the Land Forces and every other person or persons to whome any of the said Moneys shall
be paid upon Account shall in like manner give an Account to the Commons in Parlyament assembled of soe much
of the said Moneys as shall be by them and (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) every of them respe&bholigct;ively received and to whome the same are issued
and paid by them respe&bholigct;ively and by whose Warrant and for what Uses.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s69">
			<head>LXIX. Limitation of Prosecution.</head>
			<para id="p93">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That noe person to be prosecuted for any Offence by diverting or misapplying
any Moneys contrary to the intent and meaning of this A&bholigct; shall be prosecuted thereupon by any Plaint Bill A&bholigct;ion
Suite or Information unlesse such Bill Plaint A&bholigct;ion Suite or Information be exhibited and commenced between the
time of the Offence committed and the end of Six monthes after the Account of the Moneys to be levyed or paid
by this A&bholigct; shall be given and transmitted to the Commons in Parliament assembled as by this A&bholigct;, is ordained and
provided.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s70">
			<head>LXX.</head>
			<para id="p94">
				<emph type="i">French Goods not to be imported for Three Years, &amp;c. from 20th March 1677.; Such Importation declared a common Nuissance. ;Goods and Ships, &amp;c. to be forfeited and seized.; Information to be exhibited and prosecuted.; No Writ of Delivery to be granted until Cause determined; Upon what Evidence Jury to decide; If Jury return a Verdi&bholigct; of French Goods; Judgement to be immediately passed, &amp;c.; that such Goods be destroyed; and Penalty on Importers, and on Persons having such Goods in Custody.; First Offence; Second Offence after Convi&bholigct;ion for First Offence.</emph>
			</para>
<para id="p95">And forasmuch as it hath beene by long Experience found that the Importing of French Wines Brandy Linnen
Silke Salt and Paper and other Commodities of the Growth Produ&bholigct; or Manufa&bholigct;ure of the Territories and Dominions
of the French King, hath much exhausted the Treasure of this Nation, lessened the Value of the Native Commodities
and Manufa&bholigct;ures thereof and caused great detriment to this Kingdome in generall Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the
Authoritie aforesaid' That from and after the Twentyeth of March One thousand six hundred seaventy seaven Noe
French Wine Vinegar Brandy Linnen Cloath Silks Salt (<ref idref="n17">17</ref>). Paper or any Manufa&bholigct;ures made of or mixed with Silke
Threade Woole Haire Gold or Silver or Leather being of the Growth Produ&bholigct; or Manufa&bholigct;ure of any the Dominions
or Territories of the French King shall dureing the terme of three yeares to be accounted from the said Twentyeth
day of March or before the end of the first Session of Parlyament next after the expiration of the said Three yeares
be brought in by Land or shall be imported in any Shipp or Shipps Vessell or Vessells [whatsoever<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] into any Port Heaven
Creeke or other place [whatsoever<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] of the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede
or Isles of Jersey Guernsey Alderny Sarke or Isle of Man from any [Place or Port<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] whatever either mixt or unmixt with
any Commodity of the Growth or Produ&bholigct; of any other Nation Place or Country whatsoever, And that all and every
Importation and Importations or vending or selling or uttering or retailing of any French Wines Brandy Linnen Silks
Salt or Paper or other Commodities imported contrary to this A&bholigct; or any of them shall be and is hereby declared
and adjudged to be a common Nusance to this Kingdome in generall and to all His Majestyes subje&bholigct;s thereof, And
that if any Wines Brandy Linnens Silks Salt or Paper or other [Commodities<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] whatsoever shall be imported contrary to
this A&bholigct; the same soe imported in whose hands or custody or in what place soever they shall or may be seized found
or kept as alsoe all and every Shipp and Shipps Vessell and Vessells in which they be or were imported whether such
Shipp or Shipps Vessell or Vessells be laden or unladen shall and may be forthwith stayed by any person or persons
whatsoever untill search can be made of such Shipp or Vessell and the Goods imported contrary to this A&bholigct; be
carryed into His Majestyes Warehouse in the Port where such Shipp shall be and an Information thereof shall the next
Terme or sooner be exhibited into His Majestyes Court of Kings Bench or Exchequer and all the Judges and Barons
of the said respe&bholigct;ive Courts of Kings Bench and Exchequer are hereby required and stri&bholigct;ly injoyned to cause due
prosecution in the said respe&bholigct;ive Courts of every such Information and not to grant any Writt of Delivery or Restitution
for such Goods or any of them on any Security or Pretence whatsoever, untill the Cause shall be finally determined
in Law by or upon the Verdi&bholigct; of a Jury of twelve of such persons who are of knowne Experience to be returned by
the Sheriffe which jury upon the tast or view of any Wines Brandy Linen, Silks Salt or Paper or other Commodities
seized or stayed as aforesaid or upon proofe before them made shall and may judge the quality and value thereof and
whether any of the Wines Brandy Silks Linnen Salt or Paper or other Commodities soe seized and which of them
were of the Growth Produ&bholigct; or Manufa&bholigct;ure of any the Dominions or Territories of the French King or were imported
contrary to this A&bholigct; and in what Shipp or Shipps Vessell or Vessells the same was or were imported and by whome
the same was imported or vended retailed or sold and in whose Custody they were at the time when the said Seizure
or Stay was made and [wher<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] the said Wines Brandy Linnens Silks Salt or Paper or other Commodityes or any of
them or any part of them or any of them were of the Growth Produ&bholigct; or Manufa&bholigct;ure of any of the Territories [or
Dominions<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] of the French King And in case the said Jury shall finde and returne their Verdi&bholigct; upon their Oathes
that the Wines Brandy Linen Silks Salt or Paper or other Commodityes soe seized or stayed or any of them or
any part of them or any of them were of the Growth Produ&bholigct; or Manufa&bholigct;ure of any of the Dominions or Territories
of the French King that then im&bhomov;ediately Judgement shall be passed upon the Goods, soe found; and the Judgement
executed accordingly (to witt) That all such Wines and Brandyes soe found whether single or mixed shall in the
open Field or Streets neere the place where they were soe seized be there staved and the said Wines and Brandyes
there spilt upon the ground and the said Linens Silke Salt or Paper and other Co&bhooov;modities soe found by the said

Jury shall be publickly burnt and destroyed in the open Field or Streets neere the place where they were soe
seized And moreover every person and persons that shall have imported the same shall forfeite the full value
thereof And every person and persons in whose custody the same shall be found at the time of such Seizure
or Stay or that shall sell utter or retaile within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of
Berwicke upon Tweede or the Isles of Jersey Guernsey Alderney Sarke or Isle of Man any Wines Brandy Linen
Silks Salt or Paper or other Commoditie imported contrary to this A&bholigct; shall for the first Offence forfeite the full
value thereof and for the second offence after Convi&bholigct;ion for such first Offence shall forfeite the full value thereof
and shall alsoe stand and be disabled and incapeable in Law to exercise any Trade or beare or execute any Office
or Imployment for or concerning or relateing to the Colle&bholigct;ion or Managery of the Customs or any part of his
Majestyes Revenue one Moyety of all which said Forfeitures shall be to the Use of the Poore of the Parish where
the Goods soe as aforesaid prohibited to be imported shall be first landed or seized and the other Moyety to the
Informer to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of his Majestyes Courts of Record
wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion Priviledge Injun&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be granted prayed admitted or allowed
nor any more then one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s71">
			<head>LXXI. If such French Goods be brought into any English Port by His Majesty's Ships as Reprisal, &amp;c. the same not to be landed, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p96">
				<emph type="i">Penalty; Being adjudged Prize, to be exported.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p97">And if any French Wines Brandy Silke Linen Salt or Paper or other Commodities of the Growth Produ&bholigct; or
Manufa&bholigct;ure of any of the Territories or Dominions of the French King prohibited by this A&bholigct; shall be brought
into any of the Ports Havens or Creeks of the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede or Isles of Jersey Guernsey Alderney Sarke or Isle of Man by any of his Majestyes Shipps or Vessells
or by any private Man of Warr as Reprisall or Rescue the same shall not be landed or putt on Shore on any
pretence whatsoever nor retailed sold uttered or kept within the Kingdome. of England Dominion of Wales or Towne
of Berwicke upon Tweede or the Isles of Jersey Guernsey Alderney Sarke or Isle of Man under the same Penalties
and Forfeitures as abovesaid to be recovered and disposed of as aforesaid but being adjudged good Prize shall be
exported againe to any Forreigne Market in the same Shipp or Vessell.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s72">
			<head>LXXII. Such Goods found vended, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p98">
				<emph type="i">may be seized in any Custody, and like Information and Judgement and Penalties as before mentioned.; Onus probandi of Growth, &amp;c. of Goods, on Owner, Seller, &amp;c.; In Default of such Proof, Judgement for Destru&bholigct;ion of Goods and Recovery of Penalties.; Informers delaying, &amp;c. Prosecution; Penalty &pound;500.; Officers, Sheriffs, &amp;c. to be aiding in Execution of A&bholigct; Commissioners. &amp;c. of Customs not to allow Warrants for Delivery, &amp;c. of such Goods, other than to the King's Warehouses, till Judgement had.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p99">And if any French Wines Brandy Silke Linen Salt or Paper or other Commodity of the Growth Produ&bholigct; or
Manufa&bholigct;ure of any of the Territories or Dominions of the French King prohibited by this A&bholigct; whether they be
single or mixt with any Commodity of the Growth or Produ&bholigct; of any other Nation Country or Place or at what
time soever they have beene or shall be imported shall at any time dureing the said terme of three yeares and
after the First day of May which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and nine
be found vended sold retailed or uttered within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede or Isles of Jersey Guernsey Alderney Sarke or Isle of Man the same shall and may be seized by any
person or persons whatsoever in whose possession or custody soever they shall or may be found and like Information
thereof and Judgement and Execution for the Destru&bholigct;ion of them shall be had made and given as if they had been
imported contrary to this A&bholigct; And moreover every person in whose custody they shall be found after the said first
day of May or that shall vend sell retaile or utter the same after the said First day of May shall incurr the Forfeitures
and Penalties aforesaid to be [recovered<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] &amp; disposed of in manner aforesaid, And if any Question Dispute or Doubt
shall arise whether any of the Wines Brandy Silke Linen Salt or Paper or other C&bhooov;modities seized sold found or
uttered as aforesaid or any part thereof either single or mixt were of the Growth Produ&bholigct; or Manufa&bholigct;ure of any
of the Territories or Dominions of the French King or were imported contrary to this A&bholigct; the Proofe shall be
incumbent onely upon the Importer Claimer Owner Proprietor Seller and Retailer respe&bholigct;ively and not upon the
Informer, and for default of such Proofe that then a Judgement thereupon shall be given for the destru&bholigct;ion of
such Wines Brandy Silks Linen Salt and Paper and other Commodities and for recovery of the aforesaid Forfeitures
and Execution of such [Judgement<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] shall be immediately granted and awarded according to the true intent and meaning
of this A&bholigct; without any stay or delay whatsoever And if any Informer shall by Fraude or Collusion desist or delay
the prosecution of the Condemnation of any such Wines Brandy Silke Linen Salt or Paper or other' Commodity as
aforesaid after Seizure or Stay of the same he shall for every such offence upon due Convi&bholigct;ion thereof forfeite the
summe of Five hundred pounds to be recovered as aforesaid one moyety whereof shall be to the use of the Poore
of the Parish wherein such Informer had beene usually resistant when such Seizure or Stay was made and the other
moyety to him that shall informe against him And all Customers Searchers and other Officers belonging to the
Customs and all Sheriffes Maiors Bayliffes Constables and other Officers shall be and are hereby stri&bholigct;ly enjoyned
and required to be aiding and assisting in the due Execution of this A&bholigct; in reference to French Wines Brandyes
Silk Linen Salt Paper and Commodities which are to be destroyed as aforesaid and noe Commissioner or Commissioners
Customer Survey our Generall or Surveyor or other Officer relateing to the Customs shall' signe suffer or allow of
any Warrant Free Warrant or Order for passing or Delivery of any Goods prohibited by this A&bholigct; either to any
person or into any place whatever other then into one of His Majestyes Warehouses there to remaine in safe custody
untill a Judgement in Law upon or touching the said Goods be given and passed according to the true intent and
meaning of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s73">
			<head>LXXIII. Surveyors, Land Waiters, &amp;c. not to deliver such Goods other wise than as before mentioned.</head>
						<para id="p100">
				<emph type="i">Such Goods brought to the King's Warehouses to be registered, and Register produced at Trial; Goods not to be delivered out of Warehouse till Judgment had.</emph></para>
<para id="p101">Nor shall any Surveyour of the Land waiters or Surveyor of the Tyde waiters or Kings waiter or Land
waiter or other Officer whatsoever relateing to the Customs either' by vertue colour or pretext of any Warrant
or Order whatsoever take up or deliver any of the Goods prohibited by this A&bholigct; and carry them or suffer them
to be carryed to any other place then one of His Majestyes Warehouses there to remaine untill a Judgement in
Law upon or touching the said Goods be given and passed according to the true intent of this A&bholigct;, And all; such
Goods soe as aforesaid brought into any of His Majestyes Warehouses together with the time, when they were soe
brought in and the time of their Delivery out of the said Warehouses shall by speciall Dire&bholigct;ion of the Commissioners
or other Cheife Officers that shall have the Managery Dire&bholigct;ion or Colle&bholigct;ion of the Customs be registred in a Booke
to be kept for that purpose onely and to be produced at any Tryall that shall be had for and in order to the
Condemnation or Destru&bholigct;ion of the said Goods or touching the unlawfull importing thereof or for the Recovery
of any Forfeiture or Penalty incurred by reason of the importing of such Goods contrary to this A&bholigct;, nor shall
such Goods be delivered out of any of the said Warehouses by any Officer whatsoever relateing to the Customs
untill a Judgement in Law shall have been given and passed upon or touching the said Goods according to the
true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s74">
			<head>LXXIV. Persons not Shopkeepers selling such Goods.</head>
			<para id="p102">
				<emph type="i">Penalty and Imprisonment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p103">And forasmuch as the Commodityes and Manufa&bholigct;ures of the Dominions of the French King prohibited by this
A&bholigct; are often sold by persons not being Shopkeepers Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any
person not being a Shopkeeper shall from and after the said First day of May One thousand six hundred and
seaventy nine be found selling or exposeing to sale or to have sold any of the Commodities or Manufa&bholigct;ures soe
prohibited as aforesaid according to the Dire&bholigct;ions of this A&bholigct; being thereof lawfully convi&bholigct;ed shall over and above
the Penaltyes aforesaid suffer Twelve moneths Imprisonment without Baile or Maineprize.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s75">
			<head>LXXV. Penalties how to be levied.</head>
			<para id="p104">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That all Penaltyes and Forfeitures to be incurred for any Offences against
this A&bholigct; for which there is noe way of levying therein before prescribed or appointed shall be levyed by Warrant
of any two or more of the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners of the Division or Place where any such Offence was or shall
be committed by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of the Offender rendering the Overplus to the Owner thereof
after a Dedu&bholigct;ion of reasonable Charges for destraining the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s76">
			<head>LXXVI. Commissioners in Counties at General Meetings to cause Duplicates of Sums charged on each Hundred to be written, and to subscribe and deliver the same to the Sheriff, and by him to the Exchequer before 1st Nov. 1678.</head>
			<para id="p105">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Commissioners in every County at a Generall Meeting to be by them
appointed after all Appeales shall be first determined shall cause Duplicates of the whole summe charged within
every Hundred Lath Wapentake Parish Ward or Place rated and assessed in such County in pursuance of this A&bholigct;
without nameing the persons to be fairely written in Parchment and ascertained under two or more of their Hands
respe&bholigct;ively to each Duplicate and the same soe by them subscribed and ascertained shall be joyntly and together
delivered to the Sheriffe of such County and be by him transmitted to the Exchequer at or before the first day
of November One thousand six hundred and seaventy eight.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">In the Calendar at the Chapel of the Rolls this A&bholigct; is entered as N.degree; 1., but there is no Number on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Twentyeth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">his <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Estates <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Titles <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Tallies <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">1 or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">1 or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">inserted in the Margin of the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">1 and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">whatever <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">whatsoever. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">Port or Place <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">Comoditie <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">whether <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">Judgements <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


