<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47477" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677 &amp; 1678</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act for repealeing certaine words in a Clause in a former A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for enlargeing and repaireing 
of Common Highwayes. [Rot. Parl. 30C. II. p.1. nu.5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 14 (13 &amp; 14) C.II.c.6.&pound;&sect;8;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that the said A&bholigct;, by reason of the Words "for Hire" therein, had not been of good Effe&bholigct; The said Words repealed.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; of Parlyament made in the Fowerteenth yeare of His Majestyes Raigne entituled An A&bholigct; for
enlargeing and repaireing of Common Highwayes it is provided that noe Traveling Wagon Wain Cart or Carriage
wherein any Burthens Goods or Wares are or shall be drawne for hire (otherwise then is therein excepted) shall
at any time travell be drawne or goe in any publique Highwayes or Roads with above seaven Horse beasts whereof
six shall draw in paires and not with above eight Oxen or six Oxen and two Horse beasts nor shall at any time
carry above Twenty hundred weight betweene the first of O&bholigct;ober and the first of May nor above Thirty hundred
weight from the first of May to the first of O&bholigct;ober nor above five Quarters of Wheate Meale Meslin Rye
Peas Beanes and Tares nor above eight Quarters of Barley Malt or Oates and after that proportion under such
penalties as by the said A&bholigct; is expressed which A&bholigct; by reason of those words For hire hath not that good effe&bholigct;
which was expe&bholigct;ed many pretending that they carry not for hire but the Goods and Wares they carry are their
owne and many A&bholigct;ions have beene brought by colour thereof against such persons as have endeavoured to putt
the said Law in execution and others discouraged from doeing their duty therein For remedy whereof Bee it
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That [these<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
words For hire in the said A&bholigct; expressed shall from henceforth stand void and be repealed to all intents and
purposes whatsoever.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">those <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


