<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47470" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for the better repairing and maintaining the Piere of Great Yarmouth.[Rot. Parl. 29 C.II. p. 2. nu, 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 22 Car. II. c. 2.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Corporation may levy Duty on Coals, Corn, &amp;c.; The Powers of 22 C.II. c.2. except &sect;9, 10. revived.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; made in this present Parlyament entituled An A&bholigct; for Repaire of the Haven and Pieres
of Great Yarmouth Power was given to the Bayliffes Aldermen Burgesses and Commonalty of the said
Burrough in Common Councill assembled to leavy such summes of money as they should thinke fitt not exceeding
twelve pence upon every Chaldron of Coles (Winchester Measure) and every Last of Wheate, Rye Barley Mault
or other Grain, and for every Weigh of Salt and every Tunn of any other Goods and Merchandizes whatsoever
(Fish onely excepted) unladen in the said Haven with diverse Powers Limitations and Provisoes as by the said A&bholigct;
may appeare whereby the said Pieres then much in decay have beene repaired soe that the power of the said
A&bholigct; will soone determine. And whereas the like decay cannot be prevented without a constant Charge, To the
end therefore that the said Haven and Pieres (in which the good and benefit not onely of the said Towne but of
the Countyes and parts adjacent are highly concerned) may at all times hereafter be preserved maintained and kept
in good reparation Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and
consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the
authoritie of the same. That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Bayliffes Aldermen Burgesses and
Commonalty in Common Councill assembled for seaven yeares from and after the expiration and determination of
the powers in the said former A&bholigct; to leavy such summe and summes of money as they shall think fitt from time
to time not exceeding six pence upon every Chaldron of Coles (Winchester Measure) and every Last of Wheate
Rye Barley Mault or other Graine and for every Weigh of Salt and every Tunn of any other Goods and
Merchandices whatsoever (Fish onely excepted) which shall be unladen in the said Haven, Which said summe
and summes of money soe levyed shall be expended in and for the maintenance of the said Haven and Pieres and for
noe other use or purpose whatsoever, For the better observation whereof all the Powers Limitations and Dire&bholigct;tions
in the said former A&bholigct;t are hereby revived confirmed and enacted except the last Clause of the said former A&bholigct;t
Provideing That if by the Annuall Imposition the Pieres should be repaired within lesse then ten yeares That
then the said Imposition should cease. Which said Clause is not intended to be hereby revived, Excepting likewise
such Clauses as doe dire&bholigct;t and appoint perticular dayes and times in the said A&bholigct;t expressed for the meeting of
Commissioners for makeing a contract and for inspe&bholigct;ting and takeing the Accompts.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners how to be chosen;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and how often to meet.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">Which dayes and times being now past Bee it ena&bholigct;ed That at the Quarter Sessions to be holden for the
Countyes of Suffolke and Norffolke next after the five and twentyeth day of December next ensueing and likewise by
the Corporations of the Citty of Norwich and Towne of Yarmouth such number of Commissioners shall be
Chosen in such manner as in the said former A&bholigct; is directed, which said Commissioners shall meete once every
yeare or oftner if occasion shall require at the said Towne of Great Yarmouth there to view the said Piere and inspe&bholigct;t
the Accompts of all the moneys expended thereupon according to the power given in the forementioned A&bholigct;t.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Commencement of A&bholigct;, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p5">This A&bholigct; to commence and take effe&bholigct; from the five and twentyeth day of March One thousand six hundred
seaventy and eight, at which time the powers of the said former A&bholigct;t as to the charge of twelve pence therein
mentioned are to cease and determine.</para>
			<para id="p6">ITEM qued&amacr; Petitiones privatas Personas concernentes (in se forman A&bholigct;tus continentes). exhibite fuerunt &bhopcrl;di&bholigct;to Domino
Regi in Parliamento p&bhopcrl;di&bholigct;to, Quarum Tituli subscribuntur videlicet.</para>
			<para id="p7">1. An Act to enable Robert Earle of Manchester to sell Lands for Payment of his Debts and for setleing other
Lands of a greater valew in lieu of those appointed to be sold.</para>
			<para id="p8">2. An Act for re&bholigct;ifying a Mistake in a generall Setlement of the Lord Mainards Estate upon the Marriage of
his Sonne.</para>
			<para id="p9">3. An Act to enable the Right Honourable the Lady Mary Mordant to make Sale of her Interest in the Mannour
of Blechingley and diverse Lands in the County of Surrey notwithstanding her Minority.</para>
			<para id="p10">4. An Act for Payment of the Debts of Charles late Lord Viscount Kilmorey of the Kingdome of Ireland and for
raising of Portions for Byron Nedham and Charles Nedham two of his Younger Sonnes.</para>
			<para id="p11">5. An Explanatory and Supplement all Act for the better enableing Sir Francis Compton to make Sale
and dispose of the Mannour of Hamerton or any part thereof in the County of Huntington.</para>
			<para id="p12">6. An Act to enable Sir Edward Hungerford Knight of the Bath to make Leases for yeares of Hungerford House
in the Strand in the Parish of Saint Martins in the Fields in the County of Midlesex and of certaine Houses and
Tenements thereunto adjoyning.</para>
			<para id="p13">7. An Act to enable Herbert Awbrey and his Trustees to sell Lands for payment of his Debts.</para>
			<para id="p14">8. An Act for setleing a Maintenance on the Vicar of Alhallowes in the Towne of Northampton.</para>
			<para id="p15">9. An Act to enable Thomas Barkley Esquire and his Trustees to sell Lands for Payment of the Debts of the
said Thomas Barkley and raising Portions for his younger Children.</para>
			<para id="p16">10. An Act for naturalizing of Alice Rushout Daughter of Sir James Rushout Baronet.</para>
			<para id="p17">11. An Act for Naturalization of Jacob David and others.</para>
			<para id="p18">12. An Act for the Naturalization of Peter Reneu and others.</para>
			<para id="p19">13. An Act to enable Trustees to sell Lands for Payment of the Debts of Edward Standish Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p20">14. An Act to enable the Sale of certaine Lands in Winterborne Whitechurch in the County of Dorsett lately
belonging to Lawrence Squibb Esquire deceased.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


