<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47476" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677 &amp; 1678</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IV. An A&bholigct; for the further Reliefe and Discharge of poore distressed Prisoners for Debt.[Rot. Parl. 30 C. II. p. 1. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 22 &amp; 23 C. II.c.20.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Persons being in Prison for Debt, &amp;c. on 29th May 1678, in the Cases herein mentioned, released</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament made in the Two and twentyeth and Three and twentyeth
yeares of the Raigne of our Soveraigne Lord King Charles the Second intituled An A&bholigct; for Reliefe and
Release of poore distressed Prisoners for Debt, Provision hath beene made for Releife and Release of such Prisoners
as were in Prison for Debt or Damages upon the Fourteenth day of Aprill One thousand six hundred seaventy
and one in such way and manner as in the said A&bholigct; is provided and declared Notwithstanding which the persons
of such Prisoners have not beene discharged of their Imprisonments the words Debt or Damages mentioned in the
said A&bholigct; being construed doubtfull as not warranting the Discharge of any Prisoner unlesse charged in Execution
For Explanation whereof and to supply other Defe&bholigct;s which have obstru&bholigct;ed the good ends and purposes of the
said A&bholigct; Bee it now ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of
the same That all persons being in Prison upon the Nine and twentieth day of May One thousand six hundred
seaventy and eight being the Anniversary day of his Majestyes Birth and happy Restauration for Debt or Damages
or for or upon any A&bholigct;ion or A&bholigct;ions or upon any mean-processe for Debt Account or Trespasse upon the Case
which A&bholigct;ions by Prosecution of Law may be Judgements for Debt or Damages or who have Judgements entred
upon Record against them or are charged in Execution or imprisoned upon Attachments for Debt or upon
Outlawryes before or after [Judgements<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] for Debts or upon any other Processe whatsoever issueing out of any Court
of Law or Equity for the Cause of Debt or Damages or Costs onely whether the said persons were in prison upon
the said Fowerteenth day of April One thousand six hundred seaventy and one and have taken the Oath in the
said A&bholigct; mentioned or have beene committed to Prison since that time who shall take the Oath in the said recited
A&bholigct; mentioned shall and may be released and discharged from their Imprisonments in such way and manner as
such as were in Prison for Debt or Damages upon the said Fourteenth day of Aprill One thousand six hundred
seaventy and one by the former A&bholigct; were or might have beene in case the said Debt and Damages had beene
ascertained by Judgement</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Justices of Peace to execute the said A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">The said A&bholigct; to be construed beneficially to Prisoners</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And all Justices of the Peace within their severall Countyes and Divisions are hereby authorized and impowered
to putt in Execution all such Powers Dire&bholigct;ions and Authorities for the full Release and Discharge of such persons
as were in Prison on the said Fowerteenth day of Aprill One thousand six hundred seaventy and one as aforesaid
and of all such other persons as have beene since that time committed to Prison and are in Prison on the said
Nine and twentyeth day of May as aforesaid as the said former A&bholigct; hath made and provided for the Release
and Discharge of such who were in Prison for Debt or Damages upon the said Fowerteenth Day of Aprill One
thousand six hundred seaventy and one and every Clause Matter and Thing in the said former A&bholigct; contained shall
be construed and taken to the benefitt and advantage of such as shall be in Prison upon the said Nine and
twentyeth day of May One thousand six hundred seaventy and eight as fully and amply as by the said A&bholigct; it
ought to have beene for the Benefit and Discharge of such as were in Prison on the said Fowerteenth day of Aprill
One thousand six hundred seaventy and one</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Recital of 22 &amp; 23 C. 11. c. 20. &sect;4.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Weekly Allowance to be paid to Prisoner and not to Keeper, &amp;c.; Prisoner not discovered in Three Months to have any Estate, discharged by Two Justices</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And whereas by the said former A&bholigct; it is provided That if any Creditor shall insist to have his Debtor continued
in Prison after he hath taken the said Oath and will allow him a weekly Maintenance to be appointed by the
Justices of the Peace not exceeding Eighteene pence the weeke the same Prisoner shall continue and be detained
in Prison Bee it now ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That such weekly Allowance shall be paid to the Prisoner
himselfe and not to the Goale-Keeper or any other person for him and if within the space of Three moneths after
such weekly Allowance by any Creditor noe Estate of the Prisoner shall be discovered or made out before Two
Justices of the Peace of that County and Division where the said Prisoner is kepte in Prison then the said Prisoner
shall forthwith be discharged by Warrant under the Hands and Seales of any Two Justices of the Peace of the
same County and Division where the said Prisoner shall be soe in Prison to the Keeper of such Prison in that
behalfe dire&bholigct;ed as fully and amply as if such Prisoner had beene discharged by the Justices of the Peace at their
Quarter Sessions as in the said recited A&bholigct; is mentioned and that then and from thenceforth the said weekely
Allowance shall cease and determine as if the same had never beene made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Prisoners freed by this and the former A&bholigct;, free from Chamber Rent, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">And all Prisoners by this present A&bholigct; or by the said former A&bholigct; freed and discharged from their Imprisonments
are hereby acquitted and discharged of and from the payment of Chamber Rent and all and every (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Fee and Fees
due to the Goaler or Keeper of such Prison or Prisons in any manner or wise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Prisoner discharged, not again to be charged for the old Debts;</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">nor by any other Person to whom he gave Notice of Application for Discharge.; Prisoner shewing Duplicate of Discharge may retain an Attorney; Proceedings thereon against Prisoner, and his 
Lands, Goods, &amp;c.; Proviso for Wearing Apparel, &amp;c. to the Value of &pound;10; and for Discharge of Prisoner.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Prisoner discharged out of Prison by vertue
of this present A&bholigct; or by vertue of the said recited A&bholigct; shall at any time hereafter be imprisoned for or by reason
of any Debt or Damages or any summe or summes of money contra&bholigct;ed or growne due to or recovered by any
person or persons at whose Suite the said Prisoner did then stand charged in any Prison or any other person or
persons to whome such Prisoner did give notice under the Hand and Seale of some Justice of the Peace of the
same County City or Place the space of forty dayes before the time of his Discharge of his intention to receive
the benefit of this A&bholigct; and of the way and course he intended to take for obtaining the same before the time of
their Discharges as aforesaid But that upon any Arrest for such Debt Damages or Summes of Money it shall or may
be lawfull for them shewing a Duplicate of their Discharge under the Hands and Seales of the Justices of the
Peace by whome they were discharged or of any Two of them or of such Justices of the Peace in case such
Prisoner be discharged after an allowance of Maintenance by the Creditor for Three Moneths as aforesaid which
the said Justices are hereby required to give to every Prisoner soe by them discharged to retaine an Attourney
to appeare for them and file Common Baile to every such A&bholigct;ion and pleade thereunto soe that the Plaintiffe if
he please may recover and enter Judgement against such Prisoner to be executed and levyed upon the Lands
Tenements Goods and Chattells of such Prisoner soe discharged as aforesaid his or her Wearing Apparell Furniture
for his or her Dwelling house the said Furniture not exceeding Ten pounds in value and necessary Tools for his
or her Trade and. Occupation onely excepted but not upon the Person of the Prisoner the persons of such
Prisoners being hereby for ever freed and discharged from Imprisonment for any Debt Trespasse upon the Case Duty
Summe or Summes of Money or thing thereunto relateing contra&bholigct;ed or due before the time of their discharge
haveing had notice as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Sheriff or Gaoler refusing, &amp;c. to discharge Prisoner;</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;20. and Punishment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p11">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That in case any Sheriffe Goaler and Keeper of Prison shall refuse
and delay to bring and discharge and sett at Liberty any Prisoner or Prisoners according to the Order of the
Justice or Justices of the Peace made in pursuance of this A&bholigct; or of the said former recited A&bholigct; Every such
Goaler Sheriffe [and<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Keeper of Prison shall forfeite and pay to such Prisoners (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) detained contrary to such Order the
summe of Twenty pounds to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record and shall
alsoe be subje&bholigct; to such Fine and Punishment as the said Justices of the Peace shall upon Complaint thereof to
them made order and award</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. On A&bholigct;ion of Escape, &amp;c. against Sheriff or Gaoler;</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">General Issue; Double Costs.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p13">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That upon any A&bholigct;ion of Escape or other Suite brought
or to be brought against any Justice of the Peace Sheriffe Goaler or Keeper of Prison for any thing done in
obedience to this A&bholigct; it shall and may be lawfull to and for any such Justice of the Peace Sheriffe Goaler and
Keeper of Prison to plead the Generall Issue and give this A&bholigct; in Evidence which shall be a good and sufficient
Discharge and shall save harmelesse every such Justice of the Peace Sheriffe Goaler or Keeper of Prison pleading
the same And if the Plaintiffe in any such A&bholigct;ion shall be nonsuited or Verdi&bholigct; passe against him the Defendant
shall have double Costs to be taxed by the Court where such A&bholigct;ion is brought.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Discharge of Prisoner not a Discharge of Surety.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That the Discharge of any, person or persons by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall
not amount unto or be construed to free or discharge any other person or persons joyntly or severally bound for
or lyable to answere or satisfie the said Debt or any part thereof either as Principall or Surety but that such other
person or persons shall be lyable to answere the said Debt and Damages in such manner to all intents and
purposes as they were before the discharge of such Prisoner</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Prisoner discharged to have been Six Months imprisoned.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided alsoe That noe person shall be discharged by this A&bholigct; that hath not or shall not before such Oath
made have remained in Prison by the space of Six Moneths.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Debtor for more than &pound;500 to one Creditor, not discharged.</head>
			<para id="p16">Provided alsoe That noe person by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be discharged out of Prison who shall stand
charged in Execution with more then the Summe of Five hundred pounds to any one person Principall Money
and Damages</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. If Parent, &amp;c. of Ability, Creditor not bound to make weekly Allowance to Prisoner.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided alsoe That noe Creditor insisting to have his Debtor continued in Prison shall be bound to make
any Weekly Allowance for the Subsistance of the Prisoner where the Father Mother Sonne or Daughter or other
person who by the Lawes of this Realme are bound to maintaine him in discharge of the Parish if he were at
large are of sufficient Ability to maintaine such Prisoner.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Creditor of Debtor, being a Day Labourer, &amp;c. may have his Debtor removed to public Work-house within 20 Miles, and kept to Labour.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Creditor to contribute only so much above Profit of Labour as shall be requisite to maintain Debtor, Proviso if Profit of Labour exceed Maintenance.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p19">Provided alsoe and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That if any Creditor insisting to have his Debtor continued in Prison and
ordered to make Allowance towards his Maintenance shall desire to have his Debtor being a person formerly
useing any Handycraft or Day labour removed to any Publique Worke house there to be kept at hard Labour
and shall within One weeke next after notice of such Order for makeing Allowance at his owne proper Costs and
Charges cause such Prisoner by Habeas Corpus and Committment or other Order to be removed to any Publique
Worke-house in the same County where the said Prison is or within Twenty miles distance of the said Prison
That then such Prisoner soe removed to the said Workhouse shall and may be there held to Labour suitable to
his ability and the Creditor or Creditors shall afterwards contribute towards his Maintenance onely such Summe
as over and above the proffitt of his Labour shall be requisite to maintaine him to be ascertained by the Two
next Justices of Peace And in case the proffitt of his Labour shall exceede the value of his Maintenance one
moyety of the overplus shall goe towards the payment of his Debts for which he remaines in Execution the other
moyety shall be paid to the hands of the said Prisoner the said moyetyes to be distributed accordingly by the
Two next Justices of the Peace</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. After continuing in Workhouse Two Years, Prisoner discharged.</head>
			<para id="p20">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That after any person shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; have continued at any Workhouse
by the space of Two yeares he is then to be discharged from his Imprisonment and enjoy the full benefitt of
this Law</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Powers to Judge, &amp;c. to commit Prisoner to Workhouse.</head>
			<para id="p21">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That any Judge of such Court whereto such Debtor is a Prisoner or the two next Justices
of the Peace to such Workehouse shall and may have power to committ such Debtor being brought before him
or them by Habeas Corpus or Order under the Hands and Seales of such Two Justices unto any Worke house
within the County where such Prison is there to remaine according to this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Prisoner released, found or suspe&bholigct;ed to have Goods, &amp;c. above Allowance by this or former A&bholigct;</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Exception; and not paying his Debts.; Oath may be again tendered, and on Refusal Prisoner remanded.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p23">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That if any Prisoner that shall be released by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall
at any time afterwards be found or suspe&bholigct;ed by any of his Creditors to have in ready Money Goods or Chattells
in his owne hands and possession or in the hands of any others to his or her use or in Trust for him or her
in value over and above what he or she is allowed by this or the said former A&bholigct; to have [or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] then such Goods
in his Shop or Worke house as he shall have beene credited or trusted with since the time of his Discharge and
for what he shall be really indebted at the time of [his<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] makeing such Oath and he or she will not or doe not,
upon convenient Demand pay his or her Debt or Debts therewith as farr as the same will reach That then and
in such case at the request of any Creditor the said Oath shall be tendered to him or her againe by any
Justice of the Peace in this A&bholigct; before impowered to administer the [said<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Oath for Discharge of Prisoners or by
any Judge of the Court wherein there is Judgement against him which he or she refuseing to take shall be remanded
to Prison in Execution for such Debt or Debts Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Proviso for Persons in Execution for Penalty before 29th May 1678.</head>
			<para id="p24">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to any person or persons in Execution for any Fine on him or
her imposed for any Offence committed before the said Nine and twentyeth day of May One thousand six hundred
seaventy and eight.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Persons detained upon Meane Process.</head>
			<para id="p25">Provided that such person or persons as is or are detained in Prison upon any Meane Processe if it shall be
desired by any Creditor before any Justice of the Peace to whome such Prisoner hath applyed for his Discharge
shall forthwith give a Warrant to some Attourney to appeare or file Common Baile for him or them in the Court
out of which the said Meane Processe issued and to receive a Declaration at the Plaintiffes Suite and that such
Prisoner shall thereupon have the full benefit of this Law as to the Liberty of his Person against his said
Imprisonment upon the said Meane Processe and against any Judgement or Execution that shall be had against
him in that Suite and against any other Suite that shall be brought against him for the same Matter[and<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] cause
of A&bholigct;ion to all intents and purposes as fully and beneficially as if he had beene charged in Execution at the (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>)
Plaintiffes Suite before the Nine and twentyeth of May One thousand six hundred seaventy and eight but such
Prisoner upon Meane Processe shall in case of his refusall to give such Warrant of Attourney lose the whole
benefitt of this Law.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Aliens how far not to have Benefit of this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p26">Provided alwayes That noe Merchant Stranger or other Alien or Forreigner that hath beene arrested and is
in Prison on any A&bholigct;ion or Suite for or by reason of any Debt or other Engagement contra&bholigct;ed or entred into
beyond the Seas shall have any benefitt by this A&bholigct; but that all and every such Merchant Stranger or
other Alien or Forreigner shall and may be detained in Prison and proceeded against as if this A&bholigct; had never
beene made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Prisoner not to be discharged till Disclosure of his, Effe&bholigct;s on Oath.</head>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">Schedule thereof to be made before Justices, and by them returned to Sessions; Proceedings thereon.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p28">Provided alwayes That noe Prisoner shall be discharged by vertue of this A&bholigct; untill he shall before the Justices
of the Peace who are by this A&bholigct; impowered to discharge him declare upon his Corporall Oath (which Oath the
said Justices are hereby appointed to administer) what Effe&bholigct;s are belonging to him or what Debt or Debts are
then oweing to him within any of His Majestyes Dominions or elsewhere and by whome, and for what cause
and upon what Security, of all which a Schedule shall be made in the presence of such Justices and subscribed
by the Prisoner and shall be by such Justices returned to the next Sessions there to be kept for the better
Information of the Creditors of such Prisoner who or such of them as will joyne may thereupon sue for
such Debts or soe much thereof as will reasonably satisfie them in the Name of the Prisoner and after
the same recovered and received to render the overplus (their owne Debts and Charges first dedu&bholigct;ed) to the
Prisoner.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Perjury.</head>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">Punishment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p30">Provided alwayes (and to deterr all persons who are by the charitable intention of this A&bholigct; to be relieved
from abuseing the Favour hereby to them intended) That if any person who shall in pursuance of this A&bholigct;
take his Oath for any of the purposes hereby appointed shall forsweare or perjure himselfe Then such person
being thereof lawfully convi&bholigct;ed shall beyond and over and above the Penalties which may by the Law now in
being be infli&bholigct;ed suffer Imprisonment for the space of Seaven yeares without Baile or Maineprise.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Judgment <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">soe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


