<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47487" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1680</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER II. An A&bholigct; prohibiting the Importation of Catle from Ireland.; [Rot. Parl. 32 C. II.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 18 (18 &amp; 19) C. II. c. 2.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">18 (18 &amp; 19) C. II. c. 2. to be revived and continued for ever</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an A&bholigct; of Parlyament was made in the eighteenth yeare of the Raigne of our Soveraigne Lord
the King that now is intituled An A&bholigct; against importing Cattell from Ireland and other parts beyond
the Seas and Fish taken by Forreigners, which was to continue untill the end of seaven yeares and from
thence to the end of the first Session of the next Parlyament which is now expired. And forasmuch as by
long experience the said Law hath beene found to be very beneficiall to this Kingdome Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the
Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the
Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That the said A&bholigct; and every
Clause Article and Thing therein contained together with the additions and alterations herein after mentioned and
expressed shall from and after the second day of February which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God one
thousand six hundred and eighty be revived continue and remaine and is hereby revived and continued in force to
all intents constru&bholigct;ions and purposes for ever.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Any Person may seize Irish Cattle and Goods imported contrary to 18 (18 &amp; 19) C. II. c. 2.</head>
			<para id="p3">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That not onely the Constables Officers and Inhabitants
mentioned in the aforesaid recited A&bholigct; but any and every other person and persons whatsoever shall and may take
and seize in any place or places whatsoever the Cattell and Goods imported contrary to the said recited A&bholigct; and
that all and every such person and persons that shall seize as aforesaid shall from time to time have the benefit
and advantage hereafter given by this A&bholigct; to any Seizor or Seizors whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Seizor to cause the Cattle, &amp;c. to be killed.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">How distributed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And to prevent all fraudulent Seizures Sales and Compositions to be made by any person or persons
whatsoever in any Parish or Place whatsoever where any great Cattell Sheepe or Swine shall be imported or
found contrary to this or the A&bholigct; aforesaid and to make the Prohibitions therein more effe&bholigct;uall Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the
authoritie aforesaid That all and every the respe&bholigct;ive Seizor or Seizors of such Cattel Sheepe or Swine shall within
six dayes after Convi&bholigct;ion and Forfeiture thereof cause the said Cattel Sheepe and Swine to be killed and the
Hides and Tallow of such great Cattel Sheepe and Swine shall be and remaine to the use of the said Seizor or
Seizors and the remainder of the said great Cattel Sheepe and Swine shall be forthwith distributed amongst the
Poore of the said Parish by the Churchwardens and Overseers of the Poore there or some of them upon notice
thereof to be given them or any of them by such Seizor or Seizors as aforesaid any thing in the said former
Law or any other Law to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Seizors, Church. wardens, &amp;c. negle&bholigct;ing;</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Penalty; levied by Distress; For Want of Distress, Imprisonment for Three Months</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That in case the said Seizor or Seizors or the Churchwardens and Overseers of the
Poore shall faile in their respe&bholigct;ive Dutyes in the Execution of this A&bholigct; they and every of them respe&bholigct;ively
shall forfeite the summe of forty shillings for every one of the great Cattell and ten shillings for every Sheepe
or Swine which should have beene killed and distributed as aforesaid one moyety thereof to the Poore of the said
Parish and the other moyetie to the Informer the same to be levyed by distresse and sale of the Goods and
Chattells of the person or persons soe offending by Warrant under the Hand and Seale of any Justice of the
Peace of the said County or Place where the said Offence shall be committed upon confession of the Party view
of the said Justice or Oath thereof made before such Justice by one or more credible Witnesse or Witnesses
other then the Informer Which Oath the said Justice hath hereby power to administer rendring the overplus to
the Owners thereof necessary Charges of distraining being first dedu&bholigct;ed, And for want of such Distresse the
said Offender or Offenders to be committed to the common Goale of the said County or Place there to remaine
for the space of three monthes without Baile or Mainprize.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Importation of Stock Fish and live Eels.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided alwaies and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That neither this A&bholigct; nor any other A&bholigct;.
whatsoever heretofore made shall either hinder or be construed to extend to hinder the Importation of Stockefish
or live Eeles into this Kingdome of England but that it shall and may be lawfull to and for all and every person
and persons whatsoever to import into this Kingdome of England any Stock-fish or live Eeles as aforesaid Any
thing in this A&bholigct; or any other Law Statute Usage or Custome to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Mutton or Lamb imported, or exposed to Sale, subje&bholigct;ed to former Penalties.</head>
			<para id="p9">And whereas the present Lawes doe not sufficiently provide against the Importation of Mutton and Lambe out
of Ireland and other parts beyond the Seas into this Kingdome but that great quantities thereof are dayly imported
and sold to the great losse and prejudice of this Kingdome Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid
That from and after the said second day of February noe Mutton or Lambe shall be imported into this Kingdome
from the Kingdome of Ireland or any forreigne parts And all Mutton or Lamb imported from Ireland or beyond
the Seas or that shall be exposed to sale within this Kingdome shall be subje&bholigct; to the like Seizures and the
Importers and Sellers thereof respe&bholigct;ively to the like penalties as are provided or appointed in any former Law
against any Importer or Seller or Importation of any Beefe, Porke or Bacon from the Kingdome of Ireland or
any forreigne parts Any thing in this or any former Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Butter and Cheese imported from Ireland and exposed to Sale, subje&bholigct; to</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Penalties as for Importation, &amp;c. of Beef, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And whereas the present Lawes doe not sufficiently provide against the Importation of Butter and Cheese out
of Ireland into this Kingdome but that great quantities thereof are dayly imported and sold to the great losse
and prejudice of this Kingdome Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That from and after the said
second day of February noe Butter or Cheese shall be imported into this Kingdome from the Kingdome of Ireland
And all Butter and Cheese imported from Ireland or that shall be exposed to sale within this Kingdome shall be
subje&bholigct; to the like Seizures and the Importers or Sellers thereof respe&bholigct;ively to the like penalties as are provided
or appointed in any former Law against any Importer or Seller or Importation of any Beefe Bacon or Porke from
the Kingdome of Ireland or any forreigne parts Any thing in this or any former Law or Statute to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Seizure may be in any Parish into which Cattle removed.</head>
			<para id="p12">And for the more effe&bholigct;uall execution of this and the aforesaid A&bholigct; Bee it further enacted by the authoritie
aforesaid That if any great Cattell Sheepe or Swine shall be once or oftner seized in persuance of this or the aforesaid
A&bholigct; and afterwards either by permission connivance negligence or otherwise shall be removed into and found alive
in any Parish or place within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede
other then such Parish or place wherein they shall have beene respe&bholigct;ively seized That then the said Cattell Sheepe
and Swine shall be lyable to like Seizure and the Seizor and Poore of the Parish or Place have like benefitt
and advantage and the Cattell Sheepe and Swine be forfeited and the proofe be incumbent upon the Owner as if
such Cattell had never before beene seized.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. English Cattle driven or intermixed with Irish Cattle to be seized as Irish.</head>
			<para id="p13">And whereas diverse persons on purpose to discourage others from makeing Seizure of Irish Cattell have
intermixed some few English or other Cattell in droves of Irish Cattell and soe created many vexatious and chargeable
Suites against those that have seized Irish Cattel in pursuance of the aforesaid A&bholigct; Bee it further enacted by the
authoritie aforesaid That if any English or other Cattell driven or intermixed with Irish Cattell shall be seized
together with them such Cattel soe intermixed and seized shall be deemed Irish Cattel and shall be subje&bholigct; to
like forfeiture and be ordered and disposed of in all respe&bholigct;s as if they were Irish Cattel and imported contrary
to this and the aforesaid A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Proviso for Cattle in England before 2d Feb. 1680.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided That nothing in this A&bholigct; shall be construed to extend to the Forfeiture or Seizing any Cattel that
are or shall be in England before the said second day of February.</para>
			<para id="p15">Item qu&aelig;d&amacr; Peti&bhocotil; privat pso&ntilde; concerne&ntilde; (in se form&amacr; A&bholigct;us contine&ntilde;) exhibit fuit p&bhotcrl;di&bholigct;o D&ntilde;o Regi in Parliamento
p&bhotcrl;dict cujus Titulus subscribitur (vizt)</para>
			<para id="p16">An Act for re&bholigct;ifying severall Errors and Mistakes in the Marriage Setlement of Sir Charles Hoghton Baronet.</para>
			<para id="p17">End of the Statutes of King charles the second.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


