<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47483" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1679</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for granting a Supply to His Majestie of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred sixtie two
pounds seaventeene shillings and three pence for paying off and disbanding the Forces raised since the Nine
and twentyeth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy seaven. [Rot.Parl. 31. C.II. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Grant of &pound;206,4.62.173.3d.; &pound;34,410. 98. 6&frac12;d. by the Month for Six Months, in the several Counties,&amp;c. and Proportions herein mentione</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Most Gracious Soveraigne<br/>
Wee Your Majestyes most loyall and obedient Subje&bholigct;s the Commons now in Parlyament assembled
considering the great unnecessary Charge and Burthen and the many Inconveniencies to this Kingdome
which Your Majestie sustaines by the Continuance of the Forces raised since the Nine and twentyeth of September
One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven and those brought since that time into this Kingdome from Forreigne
Service from beyond the Seas and being desireous to enable Your Majestie to pay and disband the same Doe
freely chearfully and unanimously present unto Your Majestie for the Ends and Purposes aforesaid the Summe of
Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred sixty two pounds seaventeene shillings and three pence which wee
beseech Your Majestie to accept of as a Testimony of our great Care for the Safety of Your Majestyes Person
and the Peace and Prosperity of the Kingdome, And that it may be ena&bholigct;ed and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings
most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the
Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the Summe of Thirty
fower thousand fower hundred and ten pounds nine shillings and six pence halfe penny by the moneth for Six
monthes the First of the said monethes begining from the Twenty fowerth day of February in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and nine shall be assessed taxed levyed and paid by Two Quarterly
Payments in the severall Countyes Cityes Burroughes Townes and Places within England and Wales and the
Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede according to the Rules and Proportions following. That is to say, For each
Moneth of the said Six Moneths.</para>
		<para id="p3">For the County of Bedford the summe of Fower hundred forty eight pounds eight shillings ten pence
halfe-penny.</para>
		<para id="p4">For the County of Berks the summe of Five hundred sixty six pounds three shillings three pence halfe-peny.</para>
		<para id="p5">For the County of Buc?s the summe of Sixe hundred fifty seaven pounds thirteene shillings two pence
halfe-peny.</para>
		<para id="p6">For the County of Cambridge the summe of Five hundred and ten pounds.</para>
		<para id="p7">The Isle of Ely the summe of One hundred seaventy fower pounds eighteene shillings and eleaven pence
halfe-peny.</para>
		<para id="p8">The County of Chester the summe of Three hundred seaventy three pounds eighteene shillings and seven
pence.</para>
		<para id="p9">The Citty and County of the Citty of Chester the summe of Twenty six pounds fourteene shillings and
two pence.</para>
		<para id="p10">The County of Cornwall the summe of Seaven hundred and seaventy pounds nine shillings one peny
halfe-peny.</para>
		<para id="p11">The County of Cumberland the summe of Eighty fower pounds three shillings one halfe-peny.</para>
		<para id="p12">The County of Derby the summe of Fower hundred thirty one pounds fower shillings and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p13">The County of Devon the Summe of One thousand six hundred and fowerteene pounds nineteene shillings and
seaven pence.</para>
		<para id="p14">The Citty and County of the Citty of Exon the summe of Fifty eight pounds three shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p15">The County of Dorset the summe of Six hundred seaventy two pounds five shillings two pence halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p16">The Towne and County of Poole the summe of Five pounds nine shillings and ten pence.</para>
		<para id="p17">The County of Durham the summe of One hundred sixty one pounds eighteene shillings fower pence halfe peny.</para>
		<para id="p18">The County of Yorke with the Citty and County of the, Citty of Yorke and Towne and County of Kingston
upon Hull the summe of One thousand seaven hundred thirty fower pounds twelve shillings and seaven pence.</para>
		<para id="p19">The County of Essex the summe of One thousand five hundred forty nine pounds fower shillings and
five pence.</para>
		<para id="p20">The County of Gloucester the summe of Nine hundred and fower pounds five shillings one penny halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p21">The Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester the summe of Nineteene pounds fowerteene shillings.</para>
		<para id="p22">The County of Hereford the summe of Five hundred sixtie five pounds sixteene shillings eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p23">The County of Hertford the summe of Six hundred seaventy two pounds eighteene shillings one penny
halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p24">The County of Huntington the summe of Three hundred and sixteene pounds seaventeene shillings and one
penny.</para>
		<para id="p25">The County of Kent with the Citty and County of the Citty of Canterbury the summe of One thousand six
hundred' sixty three pounds nine shillings and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p26">The County of Lancaster the summe of Five hundred and three pounds six shillings and nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p27">The County of Leicester the summe of Five hundred forty two pounds seaven shillings one penny halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p28">The County of Lincolne with the Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne the summe of One thousand two
hundred eighty seven pounds eleaven shillings.</para>
		<para id="p29">The Citty of London with the Liberty of Saint Martins le Grand the summe of Two thousand one hundred forty
five pounds fifteene shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p30">The County of Midlesex with the Citty and Liberty of Westminster the summe of One thousand five hundred
and twenty pounds and five shillings.</para>
		<para id="p31">The County of Monmouth the summe of One hundred ninety five pounds.</para>
		<para id="p32">The County of Northampton the summe of seaven hundred and six pounds nineteene shillings and one penny.</para>
		<para id="p33">The County of Nottingham with the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham the summe of Fower
hundred thirty six pounds fowerteene shillings.</para>
		<para id="p34">The County of Norffolke the summe of One thousand six hundred eighty five pounds six shillings.</para>
		<para id="p35">The Citty and County of the Citty of Norwich the summe of Ninety pounds.</para>
		<para id="p36">The County of Northumberland with the Townes of Newcastle and Berwicke upon Tweede the summe of One
hundred eighty six pounds seaven shillings and ten pence.</para>
		<para id="p37">The County of Oxon the summe of Five hundred sixty seaven pounds fifteene shillings fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p38">The County of Rutland the summe of One hundred and twenty pounds fower shillings five pence halfe-penny.</para>
		<para id="p39">The County of Salop the summe of Six hundred and one pounds seaventeene shillings and one penny.</para>
		<para id="p40">The County of Stafford the summe of Fower hundred twenty six pounds five shillings and ten pence.</para>
		<para id="p41">The Citty and County of the Citty of Litchfield the summe of Six pounds and ten shillings.</para>
		<para id="p42">The County of Somerset the summe of One thousand three hundred eighty five pounds fifteene shillings and
fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p43">The Citty and County of the Citty of Bristow the summe of Ninety nine pounds fowerteene shillings and
two pence.</para>
		<para id="p44">The County of Southampton with the Towne and County of Southampton and the Isle of Wight the summe
of One thousand ninety fower pounds fowerteene shillings and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p45">The County of Suffolke the summe of One thousand six, hundred forty nine pounds five shillings and fower
pence.</para>
		<para id="p46">The County of Surrey with the Burrough of Southwarke the summe of Seaven hundred ninety eight pounds
ten shillings and; one penny.</para>
		<para id="p47">The County of Sussex the summe of Nine hundred and ten pounds thirteene shillings and ten pence
halfe-penny.</para>
		<para id="p48">The County of Warwicke with the Citty and; County of the Citty of Coventry the summe of Five hundred
ninety six pounds fower shillings fower pence halfe-penny.</para>
		<para id="p49">The County of Worcester the summe of Five hundred twenty six pounds nineteene shillings six pence.</para>
		<para id="p50">The Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester the su[m]me of Twenty seaven pounds fowerteene shillings and
nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p51">The County of Wilts the summe of Nine hundred eighty three pounds eight shillings nine pence halfe peny.</para>
		<para id="p52">The County of Westmorland the summe of Fifty eight pounds.</para>
		<para id="p53">The County of Anglesey the summe of Sixty two pounds sixteene shillings and ten pence.</para>
		<para id="p54">The County of Brecon the summe of One hundred forty one pounds five shillings two pence three farthings.</para>
		<para id="p55">The County of Cardigan the summe of Fifty two pounds seaventeene shillings ten pence three farthings.</para>
		<para id="p56">The County of Carmarthen the summe of One hundred thirty six pounds three shillings and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p57">The County of Carnarvan the summe of Seaventy three pounds six shillings one penny.</para>
		<para id="p58">The County of Denbigh the summe of One hundred and eleaven pounds fifteene shillings and three pence
halfe peny.</para>
		<para id="p59">The County of Flint the summe of Fifty nine pounds eight shillings eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p60">The County of Glamorgan the summe of One hundred eighty nine pounds eight shillings and eleaven pence.</para>
		<para id="p61">The County of Merioneth the summe of Fifty pounds eight shillings and one halfe-penny.</para>
		<para id="p62">The County of Montgomery the summe of One hundred thirty eight pounds six shillings and one penny.</para>
		<para id="p63">The County of Pembrooke the summe of One hundred sixtie three pounds five shillings.</para>
		<para id="p64">The Towne and County of Haverford-West the summe of Seaven pounds eleaven shillings eight pence halfe-penny.</para>
		<para id="p65">The County of Radnor the summe of Eighty seaven pounds three shillings and fower pence.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Commissioners named; with Powers as under 29 C. II. c. I.</head>
		<para id="p66">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the persons hereafter named shall be Commissioners of and for
the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes, Burroughs, Townes and Places hereafter named, and they and every
of them shall have and execute the like Powers and Authorities Rules and Dire&bholigct;ions touching the better assessing,
distributeing, colle&bholigct;ing leavying receiveing and paying the said Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred and
sixty two pounds seaventeene shillings and three pence in as large and ample manner as are limitted ena&bholigct;ed
dire&bholigct;ed and appointed to the Commissioners in one A&bholigct; of Parlyament made in the Nine and twentyeth yeare of
the Kings Majestyes Raigne Entituled An A&bholigct; for raiseing the summe of Five hundred eighty fower thousand nine
hundred seaventy eight pounds two shillings and two pence halfe penny for the speedy building Thirty Shipps of
Warr. That is to say.</para>
		<para id="p67">For the County of Bedford</para>
		<para id="p68">The Right Honourable William Lord Russell Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Bedford and one of
His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Thomas Lord Bruce Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of
Aylisbury Edward Russell Es&bhoqesq; Sir George Carteret Sir John Duncombe Baronets Charles Leigh Es&bhoqesq; Sir John
Napier Sir John Cotton Sir John Burgoyne Sir Rowland Alston Sir Anthony Chester Sir Humphry Winch Sir
Humphrey Monox Sir S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Charnocke Sir Stephen Anderson Sir William Gostwicke Sir John Osborne Baronets,
Sir William Palmer Sir William Beecher Sir George Blundell Sir Francis Wingate Sir William Francklin Knights.
Pawlet S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Oliver Luke John De la Fountaine Thomas Hillersdon William Duncombe Francis Dives Thomas
Browne William Dyer Thomas Palmer Villiers, Charnocke Richard Stone St John Thompson Senior William
Butler John Keeleing George Abbott senior George Edwards Brooke Bridges John Harvey William Spencer John
Coppin William Gery Walter Carew Gayus Squire Robert Mountague Humprey Fish John Vaux John Neale
John Cockayne John Ventres Robert Crompton Robert Awdley Samuell Bedford Edmond Gardner William Farrer
Mathew Dennis Richard Orlibeare Jasper Edwards Richard Edwards William Foster William Daniell John Smith
St John Thompson junior Henry Mountague Esquires William Symcocks Thomas Halfepenny senior Nicholas
Granger Thomas Halfe penny junior Gentlemen Francis Dodsworth John Ashburnham Charles Duncombe Ironsides
Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p69">For the Towne of Bedford.</para>
		<para id="p70">The Maior for the time being The Right Honourable William Lord Russell Sonne and Heire apparent to the
Earle of Bedford and one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Thomas Lord Bruce Sonne and
Heire apparent to the Earle of Aylisbury Sir John Napier Sir Humphrey Winch Sir Humphrey Monox Baronets
Sir William Beecher Knight Pawlet St John Esquire Sir William Francklyn Knight Robert Awdley Edmond
Gardiner Robert Russell John Ashburnham Charles Fleetwood William Foster Brooke Bridges Esquires Thomas
Cristy William Berket John [Beaumon<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] William Scott Gentlemen Alderman Crawley Paul Coble John Spencer
Gentlemen Alderman Symon Berkett Alderman Francis Berkett John Eastern Gentleman John Pemberton Gent.
Alderman Faldone senior Alderman Smith.</para>
		<para id="p71">For the County of Berks</para>
		<para id="p72">Henry Earle of Sterling of the Kingdome of Scotland Charles Earle of Ancram of the Kingdome of Scotland
Sir George Carteret Vice-Chamberlaine to His Majestie Sir Humphrey Forester Sir John Stonehouse Sir Henry Henn
Sir Henry Winchcombe Sir Thomas Draper Sir Thomas Clergis Sir Edmond Fettiplace Baronets Sir William Rich
Sir Anthony Craven Sir Henry Purefoy Baronets Sir Henry Fane Knight of the Bath Sir Robert Pye Sir William
Craven Sir William Jones His Majestyes Attourney Generall Knights Sir William Kendricke Baronet Sir Thomas
Dolman Sir Richard Harrison Sir Algernon May Sir Giles Hungerford Sir William Armorer Sir Edward Norris Sir
William Paule Knights Robert Packer Edward Mansfield Richard Nevill George Porter Thomas Hobby William
Chiffinch John Deane Richard Southby senior Richard Aldworth Edward Fettiplace Thomas Vachell Francis Piggott
Esquires Sir Robert Sawyer Knight John Kingsmill Edward Keate Captaine Edward Gerrard of Midiam William
Trumball Do&bholigct;or of Lawes William Nelson Hungerford Dunch Major Dunch Esquires John Blagrave Thomas
Fettiplace Samuell Brightwell William Willimott Thomas Goodlocke Humphrey Hyde John Finch Paul Colton
William Barker of Hurst Henry Pro&bholigct;or Edmund Wiseman Thomas Hussey Francis Hungerford Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke
William Ball Henry Nevill Esquires Roger Draper John Breeden John Wildeman Esquires John Hippesley Benjamin
Ruddier Thomas Meddlicott Richard Southby Junior John Southby junior Richard Hyde of Blagrave John Loder
Esquires Thomas Holt Serjeant at Law John Bygg of Hurst Esquire Richard Winwood Thomas Staples [Esquire<emph type="p">1</emph>]
Thomas Seymour Richard Brotherwicke William Angell John Collins Henry Due Collonell Charles Gerrard of
Lamborne Richard Fincher William Hammersley Esquires Phillip Weston Richard Lightffoote Gentlemen William
Offley Charles Perrett Do&bholigct;ors of Law Henry Barker Esquire John Whitwicke Robert Leigh Samuell Starkey Richard
Pount John Howse Scorey Barker John Hersey William Smith John Stone Esquire, James Smith Symon Smith
Charles Whitacre William Cherrey Es&bhoqesq; Richard Palmer Esquire Richard Brickenden Giles Hamley George Blagrave
John Topham John Peacocke Nicholas Hyde Thomas Southby John Blandy Esquires John Due. Bartholomew
Tipping Esquire George Keat John Hearon John Saunders of Shipon cum Stoford Bolton James Robert Lee Esquire
John Byggs John Whitfield James Hexon Edmond Eyre John Powney Roger Knight John Topham of Windsor
Richard Peirce William Bowles Bartholomew Yeate Nathan Knight Valentine Croome George Bishopp of Bray
Gentleman The Maior of Reading, The Maior of Abingdon, The Maior of Windsor, The Maior of Wallingford
The Maior of Newberry for the time being Moses Slade of Wallingford Ray man Es&bhoqesq; Richard Jennings
Es&bhoqesq; Captaine Robert Reeves Reynald Povay Es&bhoqesq; Edmund Pye Thomas Hoard Esquires John Plumer Es&bhoqesq; John Jones
Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Timothy Eman Alexander Blagrave James Hayes Thomas Harrison Samuell Howse
Sawyer junior Sebastian Lyford Gent..</para>
		<para id="p73">For the County of Bucks</para>
		<para id="p74">Charles Earle of Ancram in the Kingdome of Scotland Edward Viscount Larimer Sonne and Heire apparent to
Thomas Earle of Danby Phillip Lord Waynman Viscount Tuen in the Kingdome of Ireland, Thomas Wharton
Esquire Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir Thomas Tyrrell Sir John Borlace Sir Anthony
Chester Sir Thomas Proby Sir William Bowyer Sir William Smith Sir Ralph Verney Sir William Drake Sir Henry
Andrewes Sir Humphrey Winch Sir Thomas Lee Sir Dennis Hampson Sir Peter Tyrrell Baronets Sir William
Terringham Sir Richard Ingoldesby Sir Robert Gayer Knights of the Bath Sir Francis Weynman Sir Richard Piggott
Sir Robert Cleyton Sir Robert Crooke Sir Thomas Clargis Sir Roger Hill Sir John Trevor Sir John Tompson
Sir John Busby Sir George Jefferies Sir Cesar Cranmer Sir Thomas Cleyton Knights Daniell Finch Charles Cheney
Thomas Waller Edmond Waller senior Edmond Waller junior William Penn Edmond West Brett Norton Thomas
Hackett John Duncombe of Great Brickhill Simon Bennet Robert Lovet Thomas Barrenger Edward Lee Edward
Backwell Thomas Butler William Serjeant junior Edward Nicholas of Hitcham Thomas Farrer senior Thomas
Farrer junior John Risby Roger Price Knightley Purefoy Thomas Nappier Richard Hampden John Borlace Thomas
Lewes Robert Tomkins Edward Baldwyn John Witherengs Thomas Saunders of Haddenham George Russell
William Jepson Richard Winwood Richard Greenvile Budd Wayes Bazill Brent William Hill John Hampden Thomas
Stafford Bernard Turney Christopher Egleton Francis Terringham Robert Dormer John Loggins Thomas Piggott
Joseph Alston Henry Bertie Thomas Doyley John Hobart George Wyan William Clever William Abraham Nicholas
Salter junior Thomas Lewes senior Henry Seymour Robert Stiles John Grubb John Greene Joseph Mainard Thomas
Owen Andrew Duffeild Edmond Mellicott Marmaduke Darrell Edmond Varney Edmond Darrell William Coleing
John Dormer William Farrer junior Francis Knowles Simon Mayne William Fleetewood Henry Herbert Edward
Bate William Bowyer junior William Bowyer Senior William Busby Richard Meade Edward Manfeild Esquires
George Evelyn Henry Summer Joseph Halnes Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p75">For the Towne of Buckingham.</para>
		<para id="p76">The Bayliffe for the time being Edward Viscount Latimer Sonne and Heire apparent to Thomas Earle of Danby
Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir William Smith Sir Peter Tyrell Baronets Sir John Busby
Knight John Risley Edward Bate Edmond Varney Edmund Andrewes Edmund Darrell junior Hugh Ethersey
Esquires John Rogers John Grove William Robinson William Hartley Pelham Sandwell George Dancer Walter Alnutt.</para>
		<para id="p77">For the Towne of Wickham</para>
		<para id="p78">The Maior for the time being Charles Ellyott Edward Bedder Henry Bigg Samuell Wells Alexander Parmum
John Wheeler Jonathan Randoll.</para>
		<para id="p79">For the County of Cambridge.</para>
		<para id="p80">William Lord Allington of the Kingdome of Ireland Richard Lord Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland, The
Right honourable Sir Thomas Chichley Knight Master Generall of the Ordnance and one of His Majestyes most
Honourable Privy Councill, Sir Thomas Hatton Sir John Cotton Sir Thomas Willis Sir Henry Pickering Sir Thomas
Slater Sir Levinus Bennett Sir George Downeing Sir Robert Cotton Baronets Gerrard Russell Edward Parthericke
John Willis John Cotton Francis Buller Thomas Steward Phillip Cotton John Millicent Roger Rant Jeffery Knightwryall
Gardner John Clarke William Layer Thomas Duckett Roger Pepys Mildmay Dowman Terrell Dolton
William Ayliffe Thomas Bucke Daniell Martin Edward Pickering Henry Slingsby John Pepis Do&bholigct;or of Law William
Russell Richard Cutts Christopher Hatton John Childe Samuell Clerke William Manniston Ralph Pemberton Samuell
Fortrey junior Talbert Pepis John Holman John Rant Haynes Barley Samuell Desborow Robert West Butler
of Barnewell Roger Stotewill John Folkes William Eversdon Richard Bury Robert Dorrington Robert Swayne John
Bennett of Abbington Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p81">For the Isle of Ely</para>
		<para id="p82">The Right Honourable William Lord Russell sonne and heire apparent to the Earle of Bedford and one of His
Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Richard Lord Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Thomas Chichley
Knight Master Generall of the Ordnance and one of His Majestyes most Honourable (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Sir John Norton Sir Lyonell
Walden Gerrard Russell Edward Parthericke William Colvile Thomas Steward Anthony Fisher William March
Thomas Towers Charles Wren William Wren Robert Hampson William Balam Henry Hitch Do&bholigct;or of Law
Thomas Edwards Roger Jenings, Francis Underwood Haynes Barley Hugh Underwood Peter Dimond John Fincham
Richard Reade Henry Goodricke Edward Parthericke junior Ralph Pemberton Robert Swaine Maximilian Walsham
Edmond Williamson Samuell Fortrey junior George Farewell junior Sigismond Trafford Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p83">For the University and Towne of Cambridge.</para>
		<para id="p84">The Vice-Chauncellor of the University for the time being The Maior of the Towne for the time being William
Lord Allington of the Kingdome of Ireland [The Right Honourable<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Sir John Chichley Knight Master Generall of the
Ordnance and one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Sir Thomas Page Sir Thomas Exton James
Vernon Joseph Beaumont Do&bholigct;or of Divinity Cudworth Francis Turner John Eachard Thomas Watson
Nathaniell Coga Do&bholigct;ors of Divinity John [Board<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Do&bholigct;or of Law Robert Brady Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke John Goslin
Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Roger Pepys Robert Wright Nicholas Jacob Esquires Nathaniell Crabb Robert Muriell Samuell
Newton Owen Mayfield Edward Miller Andrew Hart Thomas Ewin Francis Jermin Aldermen of the Towne of
Cambridge Sir Thomas Slater Baronet Edward Stoyt Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Robert Twelves Do&bholigct;or of Law Samuell
Moody Esq&bhoqesq; Edward Storey Gent..</para>
		<para id="p85">For the County of Chester</para>
		<para id="p86">Robert Lord Cholmondley of the Kingdome of Ireland(<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) William Lord Brereton of the Kingdome of Ireland Charles
Gerrard Henry Booth Thomas Nedham Esquires Sir Thomas Grosvenor Sir Thomas Wilbraham Sir Thomas Delves
Sir Willoughby Aston Sir Thomas Powell Sir Robert Leicester Sir Thomas Manwareing Sir Richard Brookes Sir
Thomas Bellott Sir Peter Pynder Sir Peter Standley Baronets Sir Robert Cotton Knight and Baronet Sir Phillip
Egerton Sir Jeffery Shackerley Sir Peter Brookes Sir John Arderne Sir John Trevor Sir John Crew Knights Peter
Venables Baron of Kinderton John Crew Collonell Thomas Leigh senior Collonell Thomas Leigh junior Richard
Leigh of Lyme Thomas Cholmondley Richard Leigh William Venables Nathaniell Booth Thomas Mostyn of Beeston
William Williams Edward Leigh Randoll Dodd Peter Wilbraham Roger Wilbraham William Marbury Edward Warren
John Leigh John Manwareing of Badeley Edward Glegg Edward Minshell Edward Jodrell William Lawton Thomas
Delves John Daniell Roger Whitley Thomas Leigh of Lyme Edward Lutwich Edward Dove of Duddon Esquires
John Warren William Davenport Thomas Whitley Robert Pickering Robert Cholmondley of Holford Thomas Daniell
Peter Leigh of Boothes Henry Manwaring Roger Manwaring Thomas Minshall Ralph Wilbraham Richard Walthall
Anthony Eyre William Cotton Henry Davies John Davies John [Hurreston<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Thomas Dutton Thomas Bunbury Edward
Downes John Ward John Davenport of Wydford Leftwich Oldfeild William Stopford Hugh Grosveour Edward
Wright John Starkey of Wrenbury Thomas Hollingshead Esquires Phillip Ward Thomas Swettenham of Swettenham
Thomas Swettenham of Hateley Christopher Berron Gentlemen Do&bholigct;or Wainwright Greenhough
Bispham.</para>
		<para id="p87">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester.</para>
		<para id="p88">The Maior for the time being William Williams Esq&bhoqesq; Recorder Sir Thomas Grosvenour Baronet Richard Bird
Randall Oulton William Streete Robert Murrey William Wilson Gawen Hudson Thomas Simpson Richard Wright
Henry Lloyd John Maddox Robert Caddick William Harvey William Ince William Wilme George Manwareing Peter
Edwards Aldermen Sir Robert Williams Sir Peter Pynder Baronets Sir Phillip Egerton Sir James Bradshaw Knights
Henry Brooke Pusey Brooke Ralph Whitley Kenricke Eaton Edward Lutwich John Brerewood George Booth Thomas
Swynton Esquires The Sheriffes for the time being Nathaniell Williamson William Wright John Anderson Gent.</para>
		<para id="p89">For the County of Cornwall.</para>
		<para id="p90">Bernard Greenvile Robert Robertes John Arundell Hender Robertes Francis Robertes James Mohun Esquires Sir
Bourchier Wrey Sir Jonathan Trelawney Sir John Carew Sir Viell Vivion Sir John Coriton Sir William Godolphin
Baronets Sir Peter Killegrew Knight and Baronet Sir Nicholas Stanning. Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir John
St Awbin Sir William Morris Baronets Sir Richard Edgecombe Knight of the Bath Sir John Arundell Sir Joseph
Tredenham Sir James Smith Sir John Godolphin Sir Walter Moyle Sir John Molsworth Knights Collonell John
Trelawney Charles Trevanian Hugh Boscawen Samuell Rolles Sydney Godolphin William Boscawen John Seynt
Awbin Jonathan Rashleigh Francis Trefusis John Ellyott Francis Buller John Buller John Trelawney John Coriton
Daniell Ellyott John Tanner William Scawen Edmond Prideaux Walter Kendall Joseph Sawle Thomas Dorrell
Nicholas Glynn Edward Boscawen John Vivian Thomas Vivian Edward Herle John Connock Humphrey Nichols of
Penvos William Courtney Arthur Fortescue Nicholas Courtney Edward Ellyott Richard Ellyott William Mohun
Edward Nosworthy senior Edward Nosworthy junior John Prideaux John Rashley Esquires Richard Trevanion of
Verrian Richard Scobell Gentlemen John Kendall Esquire Charles Trevanion of Goran Gent John Treffry Francis
Calmady Richard Erisey Esquires Charles Kendall Gent. Ambrose Manaton Nicholas Herle Esquires Arthur Spry
James Prayed William Painter Humphrey Courtney John Blyth Charles Grills Robert Hoblin Francis Grills Richard
Hoblin George Robinson William Bond William Keigwin Esquires Arthur Painter Gentleman John Polewheele John
Penrose Collonell William Godolphin Thomas Piper Richard Kelliowe John Pendarvis Richard Pendarvis Charles
Boscawen Thomas Waddon Ezekiell Arundell Edward Harris James Erisey Thomas Coke William Arscott Lewes
Tremayne Thomas Achim Samuell Ennis John Fowell Henry Erisey Anthony Chinowith William Silley Humphrey
Borlace Nathaniell Moyle Thomas Kendall Christopher Bellott Thomas Carew Samuell Langford John Verman
Humphrey Lower John Billing Phillip Mayowe John Arundell of Duloe Esquires John Barrett of Killigreene Gent.
Thomas Penhallow Richard Williams John Williams Esquires Stephen Robbins of Winnoe Gentleman John Murth
Humphrey Langford James Bond of Earth Nicholas Wills Samuell Cabells Jonathan Trelawney of Coldruneck George
Spry Esquires Abell French Gent. John Cotton Hugh Jones Edward Kneebone junior Gent. John Pierce of Dewsto
Hugh Tonkin of Trevownance Walter Vincent Charles Vivian Esquires Thomas Kelley John Courtney Thomas Hicks
of Kerries Gentlemen, Hugh Trevanion William Symons Esquires Thomas Cossen Robert Pearse Gent. John Tregagle
John Waddon Esquires John Hichens Walter Norris Gent. William Blyth Robert Rowse Esquires Francis Seint
Awbin William Coryton Esquires Sampson Veale Gent. Edmond Phillips John Glynn Esquires Charles Trevanian of
Crege Edward Hoblin Gentleman John Nicholl of Litlewood William Trevisa Esquires Sampson Mannaton of Manaton
Thomas Hawkey Henry Gregor Gentlemen The Maior for the time being of Lanceston Bodmin Loytwithiell and
Truroe.</para>
		<para id="p91">For the County of Cumberland</para>
		<para id="p92">Edward Lord Morpeth Sonne and Heire apparent to Charles Earle of Carlisle Sir Richard Musgrave of Edenhall
Sir Richard Graham Sir William Dalston Sir George Fletcher Sir John Lowther of Lowther Sir John Lowther of
Whitehaven Sir William Pennington Sir Richard Musgrave of Haton Baronets Sir Joseph Williamson Sir Wilfred
Lawson Sir Phillip Howard Sir John Dalston Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir John Ballentine Knights Wilfred Lawson
Esquire High Sheriffe Ferdinando Hudleston John Lamplugh Daniell Fleming Richard Lamplugh Robert Carleton
John Aglionby Orlando Gee William Musgrave Thomas Denton Richard Jolson Thomas Dalston Henry Dacre
Thomas Warwicke Anthony Hutton Richard Pahilkson William Blenerhasset Christopher Richmond Miles Pennington
Darcey Curwen Edward Stanley Henry Foster Leonard Dykes Henry Broham Henry Salkeild William Orfeer
William Fielding Henry Fletcher John Ponsonby Andrew Hudleston William Briscoe Esquires Captaine Joseph
Hudleston Bazill Fielding John Briscoe Richard Eglesfeild Richard Lowry of Cockermouth Gentlemen The Maior of
Carlisle for the time being.</para>
		<para id="p93">For the County of Derby</para>
		<para id="p94">The Right Honourable William Lord Cavendish Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Devonshire and one of
His Majesties most Honourable Privy Councill Sir Thomas Grisley Sir John Courzon Sir John Gell Sir Francis
Burdett Sir John Harper Sir Robert Coke Sir Henry Every Sir William Boothby Baronets Sir Francis Leake Knight
and Baronet Sir Samuell Sleigh Sir Gilbert Clerke Sir Edward Abney Knights Sir Nicholas Wilmott Knight Serjeant
at Law Sir Simon Degg Sir John Shore Knights Anchitell Grey John Ferrers German Pole. John Coke Henry Gilbert
Henry Cavendish George Vernon Robert Burdett John Burdett Willoughby Grey William Fitzherbert John Agard
Charles Cotton John Stephenson Henry Milward John Mundey Phillip Gell George Pole Robert Coke William
Eyre Francis Revell Robert Wilmott Cornelius Clarke Christopher Horton Gilbert Thacker John Allen John Stanhope
Thomas Milward Francis Leake John Curzon Francis Burton Walter Horton Francis Barker Edward Pegg Samuell
Saunders John Morewood John Spateman John Every William Allestrey Henry Mellor Nicholas Wilmott Thomas
Gladwin Samuell Holden Samuell Hallows Anthony Fitzherbert John Low of Denbigh Low of Alderwasley
Henry Keyes Robert (<ref idref="n7">7</ref>) Agney William Bage Walter [Wolsey<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Henry Kendall John Smithson William Hopkinson
Thomas Eyre Adam Eyre Henry Balgey Robert Wandoll Andrew Clayton Robert Haywood Hugh Bateman Edward
Osborne Esquires The Maior of Derby for the time being Humphrey Yates Policarpus Dakin James Ward John
Dalton John Brookehouse Edward Walker George Blackewell Samuell Goodwin Joseph Parker Gentlemen The Maior
of Chesterfeild for the time being Richard Clarke Peter Dowker Thomas Britland.</para>
		<para id="p95">For the County of Devon.</para>
		<para id="p96">The Right Honourable William Lord Russell Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Devonshire and one of
His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill The Right Honourable Edward Seymour Esquire one of His Majestyes
most Honourable Privy Councill Sir William Courtnay Baronet Edward Russell Esquire Sir Edward Seymour Sir
Peter Prideaux Sir George Chudleigh Sir Francis Drake Sir Amos Pollard Sir Courtney Poole Sir Coplestone
[Bampfeild<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Sir Arthur Northcote Sir Walter Young Sir Hugh Ackland Sir John Drake Sir Henry Carew Sir William
Morris Sir Peter Fortescue Sir Arthur Harris Sir Thomas Putt Sir Nicholas Slanning Sir Peter Leare Baronets Sir
John Rolle Sir Richard Edgecombe Sir Simon Leach Sir Henry Vane Knights of the Bath Sir Henry Carew Sir
John Mainard Sir Peter Ball Sir Henry Ford Sir John Trevor Sir James Smith Sir John Mallett Sir William
Waldrond Sir Thomas Bury Sir Hugh Piper Sir Thomas Carew Sir William Bastard Sir Nathaniell Herne Knights
Samuell Rolle Peter Prideaux George Chudley Francis Courtney John Pole John Roll John Northcott of Uton
John Basset Richard Strode Mathew Halls Edmond Parker John Courtney Mathew Hale Nicholas Morrice Richard
Coffin John Harris Richard Duke William Bragge Josias Calmady senior Nicholas Dennis Edmond Walrond John
Tanner Henry Northleigh Richard Bevis Arthur Harris John Drake of Iveybridge John Bury of Colditon Elizeus
Crimes Joseph Drake William Lacy John Cloberry William Trevild William Eveligg John Harris of Wortham
Bampfeild Rodd Phillip Harris of Tomington Hugh Vaughan Ambrose Manaton James Calwoodleigh Henry Carew
Thomas Shepcott John Worth Martin Rider Thomas Pyne Phillip Harris of Hayne Warwicke Pollexfen Arthur
Pyne Robert Pollexfen Thomas Reynell John Kelland senior John Upton John Kelland junior John Sparke William
Stowell Richard Hillersdon Samuell Foote George Treby Josias Calmady junior Gilbert Yard of Bradleigh Jonathan
Rashleigh John Chichester of Hall John Fry of Yarley Richard Duke senior Gideon Heydon John Croker William
Savery John Gifford of Brightby George Carew Samuell Sainthill Samuell Tanner Thomas Weare Richard Lee
John Chichester of Widworth John Ashford John Blewet John Raymond Elias Bartlett Arscott Bickford Thomas
Drew Edmond Prideux of Ford Leonard Yeo Jonathan Prideux Henry Steevens James Cllifford John Beere of
Berescoembe Roger Pomerey John Hale Roger Wallacombe Sebastian Isaac James Huish Richard Ducke Edward
Yard Edward Lovett Bartholimew Gidley Aaran Baker John How James Rodd William Drake of Yarbury John
Vaughan William Bogan Henry Fry John Arscott Arthur Tremaine John Kelley Sampson Hele Richard Langworth
John Steere Arscott Bickford John Fortescue William Langford William Putt Phillip Champernowne Shilston Calmady
Jonathan Sparke John Sparke William Jenings William Fortescue Rowland Whiddon Thomas Wood junior Edward
Fortescue Phillip Shepcott Anthony Salter John Willoby John Davy of Canontring John Davy of Ruxford Richard
Shapley Rawlin Mallock Henry Worth Henry Chichester Hugh Stofford Thomas Beare of Huntson John Quash
John Garland John Quick Nicholas Courtney Edmond Pollexfen Arthur Ackland Arthur Champernoone John
Bidgood Ambrose Roope Thomas Walker Henry Blackalter Henry Trosse James Fortescue Henry Bennet William
Upton Richard Founds Samuell Serle Esquires George Fortescue William Cotton Andrew Friend Charles Strode
John Munion Joseph Elford John Martin Robert Burgoyne Andrew Horseman Isaac Tillard William. Symons The
High Sheriffe for the time being The Maiors of Plymouth Barnstable Totnesse Tiverton Torrington Dartmouth and
Plimpton for the time being.</para>
		<para id="p97">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Exon</para>
		<para id="p98">The Right Honourable Edward Seymour Esquire one of His Majesties most Honourable Privy Councill The Maior
for the time being Sir James Smith Sir John Mallet Sir Thomas Carew Knights Henry Gaudy Thomas Walker
George Tuthill William Glyde Malachy Pyne Isaac Mowditt Chrisopher Bradridge John Parr The Sheriffe for the
time being The Receiver for the time being Andrew Quash John Snell Malachy Pyne junior John Glanvile John
Tremaine Councellors at Law John Bidgood Nicholas Hele John Waterhouse Edmond Davye Doctors of Phisicke
George Leach John Cholwich Nicholas Brookeing Thomas Brookeing Robert Hutchings Hurnphrey Levermore John
Elwill John Starr junior Joseph Mowditt John Mayne Thomas Tucker Abraham Trowt Merchants.</para>
		<para id="p99">For the County of Dorsett.</para>
		<para id="p100">Anthony Lord Ashley Sonne and Heire apparent of Anthony Earle of Shaftesbury Sir Hugh Windham Knight
one of the Justices of His Majesties Court of Common Pleas Sir Francis Holles Knight Sir William Portman
Knight Sir John Morton Sir Nathaniell Napier Baronets Sir John Nicholas Knight of the Bath Sir John Strode
Sir Winston Churchill Sir George Strode Knights Thomas Strangewayes Esquire Thomas Freke Esquire John
Tregonwell of Milton John Tregonwell of Anderston Esquires Thomas Browne Robert Napper George Hulford
Edward Meller James Long Wadham Strangewayes Henry Butler William Uvedall William Okenden Robert
Coker Henry Whitacre George [Reeves<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Robert Culliford Robert Seymour Anthony Ethricke John Rives
James Gould Thomas Chaffe Thomas Chafin Robert Williams William Strode Thomas Earle, Thomas Bainard
George Savage John Hoskins Michaell Harvey John Hurding Nathaniell Highmore Hugh Hodges William Floyre
John Gould Henry Henley Thomas Bennett Henry Constantine George Strangewayes John Still John Lawrence
John Ironside William Bowles John Hardy Richard Greene Thomas Turbervile Seamour Bowman John Cradocke
Joseph Seward John Churchill William Churchill Robert Oxenbridge Francis Mohun George Stile Edward St Low
Robert Fry senior Richard Swaine Joseph Hussey Henry Bower Robert Fry William Frampton Giles Frampton
William Hull Richard Broadripp Richard Fownes John Larder Henry [Heming<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Nicholas Hardy John Bishop Simon
Agarton Arthur Fookes Andrew Etricke Thomas Radford George Dawbeny senior Bullen Rymes John Richards
John Abington Nicholas Gould William Wayte Richard Henvile Nicholas Browne John Gallop Bonham Strangewayes
Gerrard Wood John Eastment Henry Trenchard George Strode of Slape John Michaell Doyley Michaell Robert
Freke Thomas Gallop of Stroude George Gigger Robert Bishopp Thomas Plucknet George Spencer William
Bull Robert Henning William Harvey Gregory Alford.</para>
		<para id="p101">For the Towne and County of Poole.</para>
		<para id="p102">Anthony Lord Ashley Sonne and Heire apparent of Anthony Earle of Shaftesbury Thomas Chaffin Henry Trenchard
Esquires The Maior for the time being [Anthony Etricke Esq&bhoqesq; Recorder The Sheriffe of the said Towne for the
time being<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] William Orchard John Carter Nicholas Efford Moses Durrell Isaac Hart Allen Skutt William Streete
Henry Jubber Thomas Young Willis Merchants.</para>
		<para id="p103">For the County Palatine of Durham.</para>
		<para id="p104">Nicholas Conyers Esquire High Sheriffe of the County Sir John Otway Knight Temporall Chauncellor Richard
Lord Lumley of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Ralph Cole Sir James Clavering Sir Thomas Liddell Sir Robert
Eden Sir William Blacket Baronets Sir Gilbert Gerrard Baronet Sir George Vane Sir Francis Anderson Sir Joseph
Craddocke Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir Henry Calverley Sir Ralph Carr Knights John Tempest Henry Lidle Henry
Lambton William Bellases Christopher Vane John Clavenng Francis Bowes William Bowes John Parkhurst Thomas
Craddocke William Blakiston William Stroder Nicholas Cole Ralph Davison Thomas Fetherstonhalgh Cuthbert
Carr William Tempest Humphrey Wharton John Morland Thomas Carnaby Esquires Master Duke Allison Miles
Stapleton George Morland Christopher Sanderson Clement Fulthorp Thomas Bellingam William Lambton Robert
Wharton Baldwin Pitt John Jennison Thomas Wright John Jefferson James Mickelton William Davison William
Orde of Beete John Fulthorpe John Jenkins William Lilbourne Henry Ewbancke Esquires Michaell Hall Gentleman
The Maior of Durham for the time being The Maior of Stockton for the time being Master Alderman Hall
Master Alderman Ducke Captaine Henry Barnes Master Walter Etricke Master Robert Smith Master William Wilson
Master Pexall Foster Master James Cooke Master Robert Jackson Master Thomas Watson of Berwicke Thomas
Hall Esquire Thomas Allenson [Gentlemen<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Mr William Midford Mr Midleton.</para>
		<para id="p105">For the County of Yorke The West Rideing of the said County.</para>
		<para id="p106">Charles Lord Clifford Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Burlington George Viscount Castleton of the
Kingdome of Ireland Edward Lord Latimer Sonne and Heire apparent of Thomas Earle of Danby Henry Lord
Fairefax of the Kingdome of Scotland Conyers Darcey Esquire Sir Henry Goodricke Sir Thomas Maleverer Sir John
Reresby Sir John Kay Sir Thomas Armitage Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir William Ingleby Sir Godfrey Copley Sir
Edmond Wynn Sir Thomas Slingsby Sir George Cooke Sir William Franckland Baronets Sir Thomas Wharton Sir
Gervas Cutler Sir John Hewley Sir John Dawney Sir William Lowther Sir William Wentworth Sir Edmond Jennings
Sir Christopher Clapham Sir Henry Thompson Sir Ralph Knight Sir Thomas Yarbrough Sir Richard Weston Sir
John Boynton Sir. William Dalston Sir Jonathan Jenings Sir Patience Ward Knights Phillip Wharton Thomas Fairefax
Richarn Hutton Christopher Tankred John Ramsden Sir Walter Hawksworth Welbury Norton William Palmes
Francis Nevill Denzell Onslow Walter Calverley Henry Eyre Sir James Long Baronet John Savile John Wentworth
Bradwardin Tindall Francis Touljombe Thomas Vincent Willoughby Rokeby Francis Rersby William Lowther James
Stockdale John Brilby Richard Washington William H&bhoaovm;ond Thomas Yarbrough Walter Lister Henry Stapleton
Arthur Ingram William Stockdale William Drake Inglebert Leeds Thomas Fairfax of Menston Cuthbert Wade John
Stanhope William Ellis Charles Osborne Tobias Jenkins John Adams John Goodricke Roger Portington John Clarke
John Garland Francis White John Lister George Thornhill Thomas Haber senior Ralph Lowther Miles Stanley Richard
Beaumont Thomas Fawkes Henry Hitch William Roundle Henry Edmonds Thomas Gill Thomas Parker Thomas
Dodson John Hatfield William Johnson Thomas Lister Lyonell Copley William Farrer Henry Marsden William
Beckwith William Drake Henry Slingsby Francis Batty Thomas Jackson George Fothergill Thomas Craven Thomas
Haber junior Jonathan Jennings Christopher Driffield Thomas Dawney John Ashton Richard Aldbrough Henry
Arthington Everingham Cressey Thomas Rokeby Thomas Hasseltine Richard Sterne Thomas Wilkinson Anthony
Hetcher John Lawson Lawrence Wharton Charles Richard Henry Cooke Esquires Walter Lacocke George Rason
Wilfrid Lawson Cuthbert Chambers John Atkinson Richard Atkinson Gentlemen The Maior of Rippon for the
time being The Maior of Doncaster for the time being The Maior of Pontefra&bholigct; for the time being The Maior of
Leeds for the time being Richard Graham Francis Styreing Richard Roads Symon Warranor Gentlemen John
Fountaine Thomas Ward Esquires William Dawson.</para>
		<para id="p107">For the North Rideing in the said County of Yorke.</para>
		<para id="p108">Edward Lord Morpeth Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Carlisle Conyers Darcey Nicholas Sanderson
Marmaduke Darcy Esquires Sir Christopher Wivill Sir Hugh Cholmley Sir Metcalfe Robinson Sir Gilbert Gerrard
Sir Thomas Slingsby Sir David Foulis Sir William Franckland Sir John Lowther Sir Watkinson Payler Sir John
Nappier Sir William Caley Sir George Marwood Sir Richard Grahme of Nunington Sir Richard Grahme of
Norton Sir Christopher Wandesford Sir James Pennyman Sir James Long Sir John Hotham Sir John Brooke
Sir Thomas Pennyman Baronets Sir Hugh Bethell Sir John Hewley Sir Marmaduke Dalton Sir Robert Peyton
Sir Gervas Elwes Sir Edward Challoner Sir John Dawney Sir Phillip Howard Sir John Dalston Sir Henry
Thompson of Marston Sir Henry Calverley Sir Barrington Bourchier Sir Robert Layton Knights Serjeant Turner
James Darcy Phillip Darcy William Wivell William Leveson Gower Henry Marwood William Caley John
Beverley Roger Beckwith Roger Talbott John Dodworth of [Warlis<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Richard Peirse Barrington Bourchier George
Smithson senior George Smithson junior Robert Watters of Cundall Francis Wivill Henry Guy Edward Croft
William Thompson John Gibson senior Anthony Franckland Richard Shutleworth Constable Bradshaw Thomas
Gower William Gower Humphrey Wharton Edward Hutchinson Reynald Grahme Charles Tankred Richard Sterne
William Palmes Christopher Darcy Francis Thompson James Heblethwaite Thomas Hasle William Robinson James
Mountaigne Edward Trotter Anthony Lowther John Ayscough John Lowther Timothy Maleverer Henry Thompson
Thomas Worsley William Metcalfe Walter Lister Thomas Wayte Henry Crosland Charles Bellasis John Wivill
Constable Bradshaw Mathew Anlaby Thomas Lassells Thomas Craddocke Walter Bethell Robert Wharton Esquires
John Gibson junior Isaac Fairfax Thomas Wakefeild George Norton William Fielding James Morley John Chapman
Roger Lee John Sampson William Trueman Thomas Fairfax Thomas Langley Thomas Jackson of Nunington
Phillip Prince Towers Driffeild John Hill senior John Hill junior Robert Bushell Richard Ward George Smalwood
Isaac Newton John Thomlinson Christopher [Peardhah<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] John Nary Robert Willy Gentleman Do&bholigct;or Smith of Easby
[The Maior of Easby<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] The Maior of Richmond for the time(<ref idref="n17">17</ref>) The Bayliffes of Scarborough for the time being and
Tristam Fish and [Timoty<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] Ford for Scarborough aforesaid.</para>
		<para id="p109">For the East Rideing in the said County of Yorke.</para>
		<para id="p110">Charles Lord Clifford Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Burlington Henry Lord Fairfax of the Kingdome
of Scotland Sir John Hotham Sir Francis Boynton Sir Robert Hilliard Sir Watkinson Pailer Sir Thomas Rudston
Sir John Legard Sir Henry S<emph type="p">t</emph> Quintin Sir Thomas Strickland Sir Gilbert Gerrard Baronets Sir Thomas Daniell
Sir Thomas Remington Sir Hugh Bethell Sir William Cob Sir Ralph Wharton Sir Henry Thompson Sir Edward
Bernard Sir Michaell Warton Sir Mathew Peirson Sir Stephen Thompson Knights Michaell Warton Sir John Hewley
Knight Tobias Jenkins Robert Bucke Durand Hotham George Dawney John Lister Christopher Hilliard William
Osbaldiston William Thompson John Hotham Henry Thompson Robert Southabby Richard Robinson Captaine
Tomlinson Thomas Crompton Francis Tompson William Gee William Boynton Henry Guy Walter Bethell Robert
Constable Richard Thompson Richard Thompson junior John Stapilton Phillip Saltmarsh John Clarke William
Saint Quintin James Moiser Thomas Hesketh William Bethell James Heblethwaite Richard Remington Mathew
Alured Esquires Thomas Alured Thomas Langley William Bernard William Blunt William Lewins Tobias Hodgson
Edward Gray Ralph Higdon Richard Grahme Robert Hollis Ellis Cooper Robert Prickett William Ramsden
Esquires The Maior of Beverley for the time being The Maior of Headon for the time being Sir Joseph Ash
Baronet Richard Osbaldiston Esquire Gregory Creyke Esquire Edmond Howson Gentleman Edward Barnard
Esquire.</para>
		<para id="p111">For the Citty of Yorke and County of the same</para>
		<para id="p112">The Lord Maior for the time being The Aldermen for the time being The Sheriffes for the time being Sir
Thomas Slingsby Baronet Sir John Hewley Sir Stephen Thompson Knights John Turner George Prickett Thomas
Rokeby James Moyser Henry Stapilton Thomas Hesletine Esquires Sir John Brooke Baronet Thomas Hutton
William Roundell Richard Sterne Esquires Robert Waller Phillip Prince John Swaile Walter Lacocke Gentlemen
Henry Watkinson Do&bholigct;or of Lawes.</para>
		<para id="p113">For the Towne and County of Kingston upon Hull.</para>
		<para id="p114">The Maior and Aldermen for the time being The Recorder for the time being Lemuell Kingdon Esquire The
Sheriffe of the said Towne and County for the time being Christopher Hilliard Robert Hollis Esquires The Wardens
of Trinity-House for the time being Will : Ramsden Merchant Edmond Popple John Lister John Field Robert
Mason Will: Hayes Gentlemen Anthony Iveson Andrew Rakes Robert Bernard Gilead Gough Robert Legard
Phillip Seaman Will: Legard William Carleton John Blanchard William Idle Thomas Clayton Joseph Ellis Hugh
Fodle Thomas Coates Richard Grey.</para>
		<para id="p115">For the County of Essex</para>
		<para id="p116">Rob: Bertie Bainister Mainard Rich : Barrett Will: Mainard Esquires Sir Harbotle Grimston Master of the
Rolls Sir William Scroggs Lord Cheife Justice of England Sir John Barrington Knight and Baronet Sir John
Cotton Sir William Appleton Sir Benjamin Ayliffe Sir Francis Massam Sir William Hicks Sir Andrew Jenour Sir
Will: Wiseman Sir Thomas Knightingall Sir Richard Everard Baronets Sir Capell Luckin Knight and Baronet
Sir Thomas Abdy Knight and Baronet Sir William Wiseman Knight and Baronet Sir Martin Lumley Sir Francis
Lawley Sir John Abdy Sir Gervas Elwes Sir Benjemin Wright Sir James Rushout Sir Thomas Garrett Sir Edward
Smith Sir Phillip Mathews Sir Robert Smith Sir Thomas Rich Baronets Sir Francis Leake Knight and Baronet
Sir Rich : Browne Knight and Baronet Sir John Brampston Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Litleton Sir William
Adams Sir Josiah Childe Baronets Sir Henry Clerke Sir Richard Wiseman Sir Anthony Browne Sir Mundeford
Brampston Sir Thomas Meeres Sir Richard Everard Sir John Shaw Sir William Hicks junior Sir Thomas Fanshaw
Sir William Holcroft Sir Gobart Barrington Sir Eliab Harvey Sir Edward Turner Sir Edward Farmer Sir Marke
Guyon Sir Thomas Midleton Sir John Peake Sir Michaell Hicks Sir James Smith Sir Richard Piggett Sir Robert
Rich Sir Robert Cleyton Sir Francis Brampston Knights Trestram Conyers Serjeant at Law Samuell Grimston
Richard Somers Thomas Meade Robert Cheeke Thomas Cheeke Peter Soames Henry Mildmay John Wroth
Robert Clerke Oliver Raymond Thomas Argoll John Symonds William Glascocke John Fanshaw John Lemott
Honeywood Thomas Bowes John Morris Aurelius Piercie Wiseman William Dawtice William Mainard of Walthamstow
John Tindall Thomas Luther Thomas Turner John Turner William Humphreville John Penington Thomas Robertes
Will: Appleton John Bernours Esquires Robert Wood Do&bholigct;or of Law Richard Kerby William Commins Edward
Bullocke John Higham Robert Bateman Francis Mildmay Thomas Smith Robert Mildmay senior Robert Mildmay
junior Henry Wight Samuell Hare Alexander Prescott William Pert John Everard Brabazon Aylemer Thomas
Weeley William Vernon Henry Glascocke William Palmer Cuthbert Martine Roger James Francis Bradbury
Henry Ayliffe Giles Dent Richard Stanes William Gore Mundeford Brampston Anthony Gobbolt John Eldred
junior John Eldred senior Anthony Knightbridge Samuell Reynolds George Scott William Nutt John Rotheram
John Marshall George Dashwood George Walton James Milbourne William Lingwood Richard Rich Richard
Luther William Webb John Cooke of Chesholl Robert Sheffeild Charles Hancocke Edward Rudge Thomas Kiny
Thomas Talcott Thomas Bland George Gent Edward Passhall Robert Cole Francis Leeke William Wade Hoynes
Burley Zachariah Gee Orlando Gee George Jeames William Harris John Refney Jeremiah Lacy, Thomas Cullom
Henry Southcott Richard Collins Richard Godbolt Charles Wale Richard Hyde Edward Thorowgood John Austine
Josuah Gallard Thomas [Dawtree<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] John Greene Gamaliell Cappell Samuell Vincent John Parsons John Kirke Ralph
Griffeild Francis Thompson William [Motfinfield<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Mott Councellour at Law John [Pashall<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] Esquires Thomas
Stringer Nathaniell Rich Waldron of Noleshill Kempt of Spainshall John Barnish John
Tendring of Rivenhall William Scott Edward Stubbings William Cloyton Martine Carter Nicholas Jekill Timothy
Felton George Wale John Sarle of Eping Charles Wale [<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] Walden John Marshall Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p117">For the Burrough of Maulden.</para>
		<para id="p118">Phillip Rawling Samuell Pond Gentlemen Bayliffes Sir William Wiseman Knight and Baronet Alderman Sir John
Brampston Knight of the Bath High Steward Mondeford Brampston Esquire Recorder Anthony Brampston Esquire
Abell Fawkes Gentleman Robert Jennings Gentleman William Vernon Esquire John Cockerill Gentleman Aldermen
Sir Richard Wiseman Knight Robert Page Thomas Coe Peter Robjent Michaell [Cooker<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Ezekiell Finch John
Harreson Gentlemen Christopher Jaggard Thomas Futt William Allen John Pond John Helmes John Sparhawke
Capitall Burgesses.</para>
		<para id="p119">For the Burrough of Colchester</para>
		<para id="p120">Sir Harbotle Grimston Baronet Master of the Rolls and Steward Sir Walter Clarges Baronet Samuell Regnolds
Thomas Talcott William Mott John Shaw John Reyner Ralph Creffeild Henry Lambe William Moore Jonathan
Merry William Flanner George Hammon Nathaniell Lawrence Esquires Joseph Thurston Thomas Ruse John
Rebow Andrew Fromantell Thomas Greene Samuell Mott and Alexander Hindmers Gentlemen Sir John Shaw
Knight Sergeant at Law.</para>
		<para id="p121">For the County of Gloucester</para>
		<para id="p122">The Honourable William Gregory Serjeant at Law Speaker of the House of Commons Charles Lord Herbert
of Ragland Sonne and Heire apparent to the Marquesse of Worcester John Lord Viscount Scudamore of the
Kingdome of Ireland John Lord Viscount Tracy of the Kingdome of Ireland William Viscount Downes of the
Kingdome of Ireland Sir Robert Atkins Knight of the Bath one of His Majesties Justices of the Court of Common
Pleas George Mountague Esquire Sir Charles Berkley Sir Henry Capell Knights of the Bath Sir William Coventry
Knight Henry Powle Esquire Sir Bainham Throckmorton Knight and Baronet Sir William Hicks Sir Richard Ashfield
Sir Henry Fredericke Thynne Sir Richard How Sir Richard Francklin Sir William Juxon Sir William Kyte Sir
Francis Russell Sir John Guise Sir John Newton Sir John Furse Sir Richard Cox Sir Robert Cann Sir Ralph
Dutton Sir Thomas Price Sir Edward Bathurst Baronets Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath Sir William Catchmaid
Sir Edmond Bray Sir Robert Southwell Sir Michaell Hicks Sir Thomas Stephens Sir Thomas Overbury Sir Gabriell
Lowe Sir Robert Atkins junior Sir John Poynts Sir Scroope How Sir Duncome Colchester Sir Fleetwood Dormer
Sir Robert Guning Knights Evan Seys Sergeant at Law John Grabham Howe Henry Norwood Thomas Thynne
Richard How William Cooke Thomas Master John Winter Thomas Escourt Reginald Bray Robert Codrington
William Trye Miles Sandys Robert Codrington junior John Higford John Dennis John Bridgeman John Chamberlaine
William Bourchier Thomas Chester Nathaniell Stephens John Stephens Robert Pleydell William Leidgh William
Stratford Thomas Horton George Pitt John Sackvile John Delabere Thomas Barrow Edward Rich Anthony
Samback Benjamin Barrett Thomas Jennings Thomas Vele William Stratford William Cope William Morgan David
Williams Robert Bromage Theophilus Leigh Thomas Marryot William Selwin John Smith Miles Rattur Andrew
Barker James Stephens John Buise Robert Loggan John Meredeth Richard Baudgh. Thomas Smith Philip Shepheard
Richard Norwood Robert Oldsworth William Oldsworth John Robbins Edward Smith William Guyse James George
Rowland Wood Joseph Knight Thomas Stephens of [Lipgard<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] junior William Woseley Henry Symes John Dowle
Christopher Cole John Holmes Paul Foley James Hawkins William Player Poole Paunchfoote William Hale John
Langley Nicholas Vele Thomas Cutler James Thinne Henry Brett Esquires Francis Creswicke John Seymour Thomas
Rawlins Joseph Creswicke Henry Heylin John Coles John Stafford William Dowdeswell Henry Izard Thomas Browne
of Cortslaen Richard Browne John Browne of Norton Robert Lingen John Hunger Samuell Astrey Hugh Browne
Richard Jones of Hanham Richard Hart Paul Dowdswell Thomas Wise John Driver John Driver junior Edward
Nott junior William Banister John Pates William Gouglis Edmond Maddocke John Pryor Edward Matcher Christopher
Woodyard Thomas Pyrke George Bond Thomas Nanfan Conway Whitterne John Dobbins Robert Porter The
Bayliffes of Tewksbury for the time being Sergeant Rawlins Andrew Wansleyes Henry Dighton Esquire John
Marriett Robert Lingon the younger Gentlemen William George Theophilus Leigh Paull Dodwell William Guyse
of Ablodscourt Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p123">For the Citty and County of the City of Gloucester.</para>
		<para id="p124">The Honourable William Gregory Serjeant at Law Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons John
Wagstaffe Maior of the said Citty and the Maior for the time being Evan Seyes Serjeant at Law William Cooke
Esquire Sir ?uncombe Colchester Knight Robert Fielding Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke Henry Norwood William Selwin
Capell Hanbury George Brett William Capell Thomas Browne Esquires Henry Fowler William Russell Aldermen
John Powell Esquire Anthony Arnold Lawrence Singleton James Stephens Thomas Pierce Gentlemen John Gittins
John Rogers Thomas Aram John Webb Robert Halford Aldermen Thomas Lugg Nicholas Webb William Scudamore
Toby Langford William Hodges Robert Longden Francis Singleton Daniell Leysons Thomas Lloyd Thomas Pury
Thomas Snell Gentlemen Benjamin Hyett, Thomas Milles Sheriffes and the Sheriffes for the time being.</para>
		<para id="p125">For the County of Hereford</para>
		<para id="p126">The Honourable William Gregory Sergeant at Law Speaker of the House of Commons John Lord Viscount
Scudamore of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir John Kyrle Sir William Powell Sir John Morgan Sir John Scudamore
Sir John Holman Sir Herbert Crofts Sir Thomas Williams Sir Bennet Hoskins Baronets Sir Edward Harley Knight
of the Bath Sir Thomas Hanbury Sir Job Charleton Sir John Barnaby Sir Herbert Perrett Knights Sir John Payne,
The Right Honourable Sir John Ernley Knight Chauncellor of the Exchequer and one of His Majestyes most
Honourable Privy Councill Sir John Hoskins Sir Francis Winington Knights Udall Tomkins High Sheriffe of the
said County Thomas Thynne Thomas Cornwall of Staplcton Castle Somerset Fox Francis Charleton Thomas Price
Humphrey Cornwall John Birch Herbert Westphaling Thomas C&bhooov;ningsby of Hampton Court Wallop Brabbason
Walter Pye Robert Pye John Scudamore of Kenchurch Herbert Awbery Richard Reede Thomas Cox James Pitts
Edward Cornwall John Skipp Edward Freeman Richard Hopton Bridstocke Harfford Paul Foley. Thomas Geeres
Humphrey Baskervile John Arnold Henry Milbourne John Barnaby of Brockhampton John Booth of Letton
William Lambe John Nourse Robert Rodd George Skipp Marshall Bridges Younger Cooke Thomas Baskerville of
Earsley Francis Pember of Elsden Edwin Skinnester Richard Williams of Cathalva Ambrose Elton Thomas Delahay
of Urrisha Francis Pember of Newport Thomas Duppa Richard Barnaby of Brockhampton Robert Cornwall John
Darnell Ferdinando Gorges Bridstocke Harfford Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke James Lloyd of Kingston John Vaughan of
Hargest John Williams John Parrey of Dewlasse Thomas Delahay of Alterianis Edward Jones of Langwarne James
Gregory Will: Daresey senior Esquires James Rawlins Bennet Hoskins of Pennython William Guillim of Langston
George Carver of Buttus Samuell Birch of Whitbourne Anthony Rowden Nicholas Walwin Richard Walwyn of
Hellens Martin Sandis of Cradley John Booth of Branton Gentlemen Lemuell Kingdon Jeremiah Bubb Richard
Guillam Robert Dobbins Esquires William Mathews Gent. William Dancy of Litle Hereford Esquire William
Westphaling Gent. Herbert Masters Esquire Thomas Howorth of Whitehouse Gent Thomas Wigmore Gent Thomas
Berrington of Bishopstone John James Higgons James John Kirle of Rosse Esquires William Broome Gent. John
Goodier of Burrop Esquire Essex Sherbourn Edward Broughton of Kington Thomas Carpenter of Tylington
Gentlemen Edward Lloyd of Batch Esquire Henry Hyett Francis Geores of Garmons Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p127">For Lemster</para>
		<para id="p128">The Bayliffe of the Burrough of Lemster for the time being John Dutton Colt James Pitts Esquires John
Tomkins Peter Dancer Gent. William Bowdler Esquire John Powell James Hereford Esquire John Whittington of
Hampton William Bassell of Ledbury James Winstone of Blackmore John Carver of Upton William Bridges
Gentlemen Giles Bridges of Wilton Esquire John Whittington of Lemster Edward Hayes Sampson Edwards of
Lemster Gentlemen Richard Marrot Thomas Bridges of Bosbury James Good Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p129">For the Citty of Hereford</para>
		<para id="p130">The Honourable William Gregory Serjeant at Law Speaker of the House of Commons The Maior for the time
being John Lord Viscount Scudamore of the Kingdome of Ireland Bridstocke Harfford Paul Foley Herbert
Westphaleing Thomas Price Esquires Bridstocke Harfford Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Robert Symonds Thomas Homes
Thomas Clerke Thomas Panard Do&bholigct;or John Harfford Thomas Bond Hugh Rodd Thomas Symonds Edward Rodd
Richard Williams Roger Bolcock John Cooke William Maylerd Abraham Seward Richard Wadley Thomas Mathewes
John Abrahall James Price Lyson Thomas Nicholas Philpotts senior John Rodd John Williams senior Edmond Weaver
Richard Goure, Thomas Clarke junior John Barnes Gent..</para>
		<para id="p131">For the County of Hertford</para>
		<para id="p132">Sir Harbotle Grimston Master of the Rolls Sir Richard Francklin Knight and Baronet Sir John Mounson
Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Leventhorpe Sir John Reede Sir Richard Spencer Sir John Wittewrong Sir Richard
Anderson Sir Jonathan Keate Sir John Awstin Sir William Gostwicke Sir Robert Joselin Sir Richard Atkins Sir
William Lemon Sir Benjamin Maddox Sir Edmond Anderson Baronets Sir Phillip Boteler Knight of the Bath Sir
John Gore Sir Francis Boteler Sir Henry Blount Sir William Glascocke Sir Edward Alson Sir Francis Leigh Sir
Charles Cesar Sir Henry Tulse Sir John Watts Sir Humphrey Gore Sir Thomas Byde Sir William Litton Sir John
Boteler Sir Charles Cleaver Sir Robert Viner Sir Ralph Ratcliffe Sir Robert Dacres Sir Robert Peyton Sir Benjamine
Titchbourne Sir George Walker Henry Mounson Samuell Grimston Sylas Tytus William Hale Thomas Lewis John
Garrard Thomas Doewra Andrew Fountaine Richard Harrison Richard Francklin Ralph Freeman Thomas Priestly
Thomas Pope Blount James Wittewrong Mathew Bluck Richard Goulston Henry Guy Thomas Weeden Thomas
Cowley James Goulston William Edmonds Nicholas Miller Skinner Byde Thomas Arris Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke George
Cooper Edward Atkins Arthur Palter Henry Baldwin Francis Shalcrosse Thomas Stanley Thomas Moncke Thomas
Chatterton Edward Wingate John Gape senior Thomas Carpenter Daniell Sheldon Thomas Atkins Perkins
Thomas Field George Nodes George Loe Edward Watts Richard Crofts Thomas Halsey James Willimot Edward
Chester William Hutchinson John King Edward Briscoe senior Edward Briscoe junior William Greenhill Charles
Blount William Cotton Henry Childe John Eccleston Edmond Smith John Briscoe Ralph Gore Robert Robotham
John Fotherley Edmond Prideaux Thomas Nicholl of Bushey Thomas Saunders Henry Chauncey Anthony Farringdon
John Weatherhead George Hadley George Throckmorton Marmaduke Rawden senior Henry Dunstar William Nuce
Reeves of Aston Josuah Lomax John Ellis Thomas Aram Henry Meaux Marmaduke Rawden junior
Francis King Rowland Litton George Nedham Thomas Bird Thomas Arris Alexander Weld William Pecke Humphrey
Hall William Crowley John Pigott Esquires Maior of Hertford for the time being.</para>
		<para id="p133">For the Towne of Saint Albans.</para>
		<para id="p134">William Marston Maior Sir Harbotle Grimston (<ref idref="n25">25</ref>) Master of the Rolls Samuell Grimston Thomas Pope Blount John
Gape Esquires Do&bholigct;or Arris Sir John Simpson Recorder Robert Robatham Charles Blount William Cotton Anthony
Farrington Esquires Thomas Cowley John New John Doggatt Thomas Hayward William Oxten Thomas Eccleston
John New junior Aldermen John Ellis Josuah Lomax Esquires Thomas Arris Robert Pemberton John Gape junior
Lewis Montgomery Stephen Adams Thomas Crosfeild Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p135">For the County of Huntingdon.</para>
		<para id="p136">Ralph Montague George Montague Sydney Wortley Esquires Sir Francis Compton Knight Sir John Cotton. Sir
John Hewett Sir Thomas Proby Sir John Bernard Baronets Sir Nicholas Pedley Sir Lionell Walden Knights Robert
Appreece John Cotton John Stone Silas Tytus John Dryden Charles Cesar Esquires Alderman Backwell Nicholas.
Pedley Lyonell Walden Richard Naylor John Ferrar John Trice Anthony Hamond John Bigg Richard Elmes Castell
Sherrard Esquires Richard Winde Symon Mason junior William Naylor Robert Clarke John Mason William Moseley
Robert Caveney Gentlemen William Conyers Thomas Audley Lewis Ethwingthon Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p137">For the Towne of Huntington.</para>
		<para id="p138">Sydney Wortley Esquire Sir John Cotton Sir John Bernard Baronets Sir Nicholas Pedley Sir Lyonell Walden
Knights The Maior for the time being Nicholas Pedley Lyonell Walden Esquires William Fulwood Do&bholigct;or in
Phisicke Samuell Pont Richard Astre James Facreside William Dowse Aldermen.</para>
		<para id="p139">For the County of Kent</para>
		<para id="p140">Phillip Viscount Strangford of the Kingdome of Ireland Lewis Watson Esquire Sir Vere Fane Knight of the
Honourable Order of the Bath John Tufton Richard Tufton Sackvile Tufton Esquires Sir Thomas Twisden Sir
William Wilde one of the Justices of the Kings Bench Sir Phillip Howard Knight Sir William Twisden Sir Edward
Hales Sir Henry Palmer Sir Richard Meredith Sir Edward Deereing Sir Thomas Peyton Sir Oliver Butler Sir Norton
Knatchball Sir John Tufton Sir John Raney Sir Robert Hales Baronets William Viscount Downe of Ireland Sir
Stephen Leonard Sir Humphrey Miller Sir John Marsham Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir John Bancks Sir William
Honeywood Sir Robert Bernham Sir Thomas Pierce Sir Nathaniell Powell Sir John Austin Sir Thomas Selyard Sir
Anthony Archer Sir Henry Oxenden Knight and Baronet Sir James Oxenden Sir Francis Clarke Sir Thomas Godfrey
Sir Thomas Engham Sir Phillip Warwicke Sir John Darrell Sir Thomas Scott Sir Thomas Culpeper Sir Theophilus
Biddulph Baronet Sir William Wiseman Knight and Baronet Sir James Rushout Sir William Boreman Sir Bernard
Hyde Sir William Swan Baronet Sir Robert Filmer Baronet Sir John Heath Attourney of the Dutchy of Lancaster
Sir Thomas Hardresse His Majestyes Serjeant at Law Edward Hale of Tunstall Esquire John Strode Esquire
Leiutenant of Dover Castle John Boyse of Fredvill Thomas Hales of Beakborne John Cropley Thomas Crispe of
Queakes Thomas Hardresse Walter Breames Christopher Vane James Masters of Langden Esquires James Masters
of Yokes Thomas Turner William Rooke Henry Oxenden of Brookes Herbert Randolph Nicholas Tooke of
Goddington Henry Thornhill of Allanty Thomas Knatchball James Brockman Edward Hales Richard Hulse John
Nayler Robert Lewkner Peter Hamond John Moyle of Buckwell Zouch Brockman Phillip Warwicke Thomas Flood
Anthony Irby Esquire Edward Gresham Sir George Curtis Thomas Knatchball Richard Wilkinson Thomas Mun
Ralph Bufkin Walter [Franckin<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] Richard Marsh Thomas English Thomas Harlackenden Captaine John Clarke
Richard Duke William Maddox The Maior of Rochester for the time being Richard Manley Esquire Sir Richard
Head Baronet John Boys Esquire John du Boys Sir Charles Bickerstaffe Knight Francis Barrell Serjeant at Law Sir
Thomas Stiles Baronet Sir Arnold Breames Thomas Marley Thomas Brewer Samuell Boise Phillip Packer George
Polhell Henry Gilborne Marke Cotle Esquires John Hyde Sir William Hooker Knight Norton Curtis Edward Curtis
Robert Heath Francis Heath John Eveling Sir Eliab Harvey Knight Thomas Papillon of Acreridge William Swan
Thomas Selyard Christopher Allison Esquires Ralph Petley John Bridger Francis Farnaby George Gifford Paul
Epps Robert Clerkson Sir John Williams Humphrey Withwicke Sir Anthony Maney Thomas Petley Esquire John
Sydney James Thurbone Sir John Henden Knight Sir Robert Honeywood Knight William Hamond of Saint Albane
Esquire William Campion Sir Purbecke Temple Edward Grace Gentleman William Dyke Esquires Thomas Andrewes
Edward Gulston Reynald Peckham Edward Short Robert Austin Richard Breton Sir Henry Boswell Knight
Mr Henry Sandis Sir Percivall Hart Edward Manning Esquire Sir John Shaw Baronet Michaell Chidwicke Piercy
Goreing Roger Paine Esquire Sir Robert Faunce Knight Sir Nicholas Strode Archibald Clincard Edward Deereing
William Kingsley Edwin Wyatt Cresheld Draper George Duke Esquire Samuell Plumer John Cooke Sir Francis
Leigh Thomas Fane Esquire [Sir<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] Julius Deeds Charles Wheeler John Marsham Esquires Mr Thomas Gombledon John
Plummer Esq&bhoqesq; Henry Frere Esquire Thomas Gifford Edward King Richard Mathewes John Conney Henry Sherman
Bartholimew Gentlemen Francis Leake Esquire James Codd Thomas Hooper Esquire Edmond Steed of
Bidenden William Ash Esquire Sir John Cutler Knight and Baronet Peter Godfrey Esquire The Bayliffe of Rumney
Marsh for the time being John Bugen The Ependiters of Rumney Marsh for the time being John Bloome Henry
Parker George Cooper Esquires The Maior of Maidstone for the time being Christopher May James Cripps James
Paine John Murall Gentlemen Sir John Fagg Baronet Roger Twisden Daniell White Esquires Francis Withens, Sir
Phillip Honeywood John Smith of Chaell Esquire Captaine Gracian Linch Captaine Courtop John Ady Christopher
Mason Richard Hopkins Esquire Paul Barrett Esq&bhoqesq; William Lambard Richard Bettenson John Thurborne William
Hugeson Gideon de Laune Nathaniell Darrell John Percivall Robert Cage Mathew Tomlinson John Butler Edward
Nutt Esquires Nicholas Cooke Gent. Thomas Brett of Wye Sir Thomas Culpeper of Ailesford Henry Marsh Jeffery
Boise Edward Boise Thomas Toke Samuell Short John Cason Esquire Peter Lancaster John Maskall Thomas Napleton
D<emph type="p">r</emph> William Jacob James Bate George Elcocke Thomas Fitch Esquires Nicholas Miller Stephen Leonard Esquire
William Watton Peter Courthop Gentlemen Robert Gibbon Edward Deereing John Whitfield Robert Smith Esquire
Anthony Nowers Wortley Whorwood Charles Bargrave Samuell Curtis John Lemott Honeywood Esquire George
Atkins Gent. Sir Thomas Robarts Baronet Edward Diggs Esquire William Boise John Relfe William Peachy Gent.
Thomas Dyos Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
		<para id="p141">For the Citty and County of Canterbury.</para>
		<para id="p142">The Maior for the time being Sir Edward Master Knight Sir Thomas Hardresse His Majestyes Serjeant at Law
Recorder Edward Hales Esquire William Jacob Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke Vincent Denne Thomas Turner Paul Barrett
William Mann Edward Nutt Esquires Captaine Hilles Beverton Esquire Thomas Elwin Captaine William
Watson John Lott Aldermen Thomas Enfield Israell Jacob Edward Hyrst John Bridges Gentlemen William Rooke Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
		<para id="p143">For the Towne and Port of Sandwich</para>
		<para id="p144">The Maior for the time being John Thurburne Water Bayliffe James Thurburne Esquire Phineas Eldwood John
Verrier Jeffery Wells Jeffery Sackett Peter Nowell Edward Fellowes Bartholimew Combes John Haward Sir James
Oxenden.</para>
		<para id="p145">For the Towne and Port of Dover.</para>
		<para id="p146">The Maior for the time being Walter Breames Esq&bhoqesq; William Stokes John Matson Do&bholigct;or John Golder George
West William Richards John Bullocke Nicholas Cullen Charles Valey Nathaniell Denee Fredericke de Vincke Simon
Yorke Thomas Tyddeman Esquire Thomas Scott John Ford Thomas Rayworth Abraham Stocke Edward Lowell
Thomas Underdowne.</para>
		<para id="p147">For the Towne and Port of Rumney.</para>
		<para id="p148">The Maior for the time being Peter Lancaster Thomas Brett John Mascall John Hunt Thomas Freebody Thomas
Durrant Daniell Gadsby William Ward.</para>
		<para id="p149">For the Towne and Port of Hith.</para>
		<para id="p150">The Maior for the time being Robinson Beane Julius Deeds Esquire William Knight Elias Bassett George
Thurburne Henry Read John Brewer.</para>
		<para id="p151">For the Towne of Fordwich.</para>
		<para id="p152">The Maior for the time being Thomas Norton Samuell Short James Baron Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
		<para id="p153">For the Towne of Feversham</para>
		<para id="p154">The Maior for the time being Robert Watson Esquire Marke Trouts Thomas Southerest Thomas Napleton Simon
Steede Thomas Lowthon Joseph Edwards Master Waterman.</para>
		<para id="p155">For the Towne of Folkeston.</para>
		<para id="p156">The Maior for the time being Edward Francklin Miles Jacob Captaine Jenkin.</para>
		<para id="p157">For the Towne of Lidd</para>
		<para id="p158">The Bayliffe of Lidd for the time being John Bateman John Barton William Sudell Henry [Porter<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] William Glover
Humphrey Lee.</para>
		<para id="p159">For the Towne of Tenderden</para>
		<para id="p160">The Maior for the time being Sir Edward Hales Robert Austin Esquire Edward Short Peter Short junior John
Plummer Samuell Curtis Charles Bargrave.</para>
		<para id="p161">For the County of Lancaster.</para>
		<para id="p162">Sir Robert Carr Knight and Baronet Chauncellor of the County Palatine of Lancaster Charles Earle of Ancram
of the Kingdome of Scotland Charles Gerrard Esquire William Spencer senior Esquire Henry Booth Esquire Sir
Charles Houghton Sir John Molineux Sir Robert Bindlos Sir Ralph Ashton of Whaley Sir Ralph Ashton of Midleton
Sir Richard Standish Baronets Sir Roger Bradshaw senior High Sheriffe of the County Palatine of Lancaster Sir
Peter Brooke Sir John Arderne Sir Jeffery Shackerley Sir Thomas Stringer Sir Edward Chisenhall Sir Jervas Elwes
Sir John Otway Sir Roger Bradshaw junior Knights Edward Rigby Serjeant at Law Thomas Hesketh Richard
Kirkby Richard Harrison Roger Nowell Edward Fleetewood Christopher Bannester Henry Farrington James Holt
Thomas Preston Lawrence Raresthron Nicholas Towneley John Parker of Extwisley Daniell Fleming Curwin Rawlinson
Miles Dodding William Kirkby Thomas Braddyll Alexander Rigby of Midleton Alexander Rigby of Layton Alexander
Rigby of Aspull Thomas Norris Christopher Parker Henry Sclatter Richard Leigh Richard Fleetewood of Rossall
Peter Bold Alexander Nowell Thomas Powler Edward Herle John Halsted of Banckhouse Adam Byrom Robert
Hesketh James Duckenfield John Entwisle John Risley Jeffery Holcroft Edward Ogle Henry Houghton John Ashton
William Hutton Thomas Greenhalgh William Helme of Kirsley Richard Shutleworth Richard Atherton William
Spencer [senior<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] Edward Wilson senior Edward Wilson junior The Maior of Lancaster for the time being Thomas
Cole Christopher Carus Esquires William Fleming William Knipe John Hodgson George Tomlinson Thomas Foster
Josua Partington William Waller Francis Medcalfe John Kirkby Gentlemen Edward Warren junior John Warren
Alexander Johnson Esquires The Maior of Preston for the time being George Pigot Christopher Greenfield Thomas
Pallen Thomas Whittingham Esquires William Langton Gentleman Captaine Ralph Langworth George Sharples
James Lowde Thomas Hodgkinson Thomas Winckley Gentlemen Do&bholigct;or Cuerden William Wall John Kellett
William Lemmon Luke Hodgkinson Gentlemen Thomas Parker George Halstead Richard Ashton of Cuerdall Ralph
Livesy Christopher Wilkinson Thomas Lacy Thomas Holden Henry Marsden Esquires The Bayliffes of Clitherowe
for the time being Edward Rishton William Apleton Peers Starkey William Crombock John Lister William Yates
Abraham Townley Robert Hammond Nicholas Cownliffe Ambrose Barcroft Gentlemen Richard Brooke Hugh Cooper
John Crosse Stephen Radley Peter Adlington Esquires Edward Diccenson William Wilson of Timley Gentlemen
Edward Dobson John Ashhurst Edward Hyrle, Will: Bancks William Daniell Esquires The Maior of Wigan for
the time being The Maior of Leverpoole for the time being Silvester Richmond Oliver Lyme John Chandler
Thomas Bricksteth John Bretherton Paul Moreau Robert Roper Nicholas Fezakerley Thomas Turner Alexander.
Radcliffe John Widdowes Richard Moleneux of Hawkley Thomas Johnson Peter Lurting James Vernon Gentlemen.
Alexander Butterworth Leonard Edgerton John Hartley Edward Moseley James Lightboone Esquires William Hulme
of Davis Hulme Esquire Oswald Moseley Roger Kenion Ralph Browne William Worthington James Chetham of
Jurton James Chetham of Smedley Edward Osbaldeston John Hopwood Thomas Leven Richard Holte Esquires
Ralph Eddowes William Lee John Birch of Urdsall Richard Persivall Thomas Williamson Thomas Wright Leonard
Nowell Arthur Ashton Edward Robinson Gentlemen John Asheton Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
		<para id="p163">For the County of Leicester.</para>
		<para id="p164">Rowland Browne Esquire High Sheriffe of the County of Leicester Thomas Lord Beaumont of the Kingdome of
Ireland The Honourable John Gray Esquire Sir George Villiers Bennet Lord Sherrard of the Kingdome of Ireland
Sir Wolstan Dixie Sir Lewis Palmer Sir Henry Hudson Sir John Lowther Sir Edward Smith Sir Henry Beaumont
Sir Thomas Hesilrigge [Sir Thomas Barton<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] Sir Thomas Meeres Baronets Sir William Hartopp Sir William Ellis. Sir
William Halford Sir Thomas Dolman Knights Thomas Caldicott John Hartopp John Crew Samuell Cotton William,
Beaumont John Stafford William Whaley Roger Roe Christopher Packe William Skevington Phillip Sherrard William
Villiers William Faunt Jeffery Palmer Richard Lister John de la Fountaine Richard Brudnell William Woleston
Beaumont Dixie Richard Verner Thomas Boothby [William Boothby<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] Thomas Babington Henry Kendall Saint John
Bennet John Hackett William Stayely William Cole Thomas Pochin William Streete Walter Budings Stanhope
Whaley George Pochin Henry Hastings George Ashby Jeremiah Dove Nathan Wright George Hewitt Cassibulan
Burton William Bale Esquires William Trimnell Theophilus Bernard Richard Bradgate Henry Farnham John
Bainebrigg John Fowler Gentlemen Mathew Johnson Alexander Hansell John Needham Richard Roberts Esquires
Francis Needham Robert Bernard Thomas Hood Francis Chamberlaine William Bainbrigge John Benskin John
Barwell Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p165">For the Burrough of Leicester.</para>
		<para id="p166">Phillip Abney Maior and the Maior for the time being John Cley Francis Noble William Alsop William
Southwell Andrew Freeman William Deane Robert Hartshorne George Beckett Edmond Sutton Aldermen John
Herrick Edward Palmer senior Edward Browne William Major Lawrence Carter William Billers Robert Somerfield
John Daintree Mathew Simons Jonathan Cooke William Warburton senior James Ludlam senior [Thomas Wrightman
John Morris<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] Doctor John Harrison Nathaniell Tapper William Ward Marmian Gee Edward Billers.</para>
		<para id="p167">For the County of Lincolne and for the Citty of Lincolne and the County of the said City.</para>
		<para id="p168">George Lord Viscount Castleton of the Kingdome of Ireland Robert Lord Willoughby Sonne and Heire apparent
of the Earle of Lindsey Bennett Lord Sherrard of the Kingdome of Ireland Robert Pierpoint Peregrine Bertie
Richard Bertie Charles Bertie Sir Robert Carr Knight and Baronet Chauncellour of the Dutchy and County
Palatine of Lancaster Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath William Mountague Lord Cheife Baron Sir John
Munson Sir Thomas Hussey Sir John Newton Sir John Browneloe Sir Robert Markham Sir William Hickman
Sir Richard Rothwell Sir Christopher Wray Sir Humphrey Winch Sir Carr Scroope Baronets Sir William Ellis
Serjeant at Law Sir William Ellis Baronet [Sir Richard Cust Baronet<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] Sir John Bennet Knight of the Bath Sir
Thomas Meeres Knight Sir John Moreton Sir Edward Ascough Sir Henry Massingbeard Sir Thomas Skipwith
Serjeant at Law Sir Drayner Massingberd Sir William Yorke Sir Charles Dimmocke Sir Christopher Clapham
Sir Christopher Nevell Sir Edmond Turner Knights Sir Henry Heron Knight of the Bath Sir William Humble
Baronet Sir Anthony Irby Knight Henry Savile Esq&bhoqesq; Henry Mounson William Hyde Rutland Sanderson Thomas
Hatcher William Marwood William Godfrey Charles Pelham Charles Sanderson William Broxholme Henry Fane
William Lister Richard Ryley Thomas Farmer Edward Payne John Sanders Redmaine Burrell William Welby
Lister Tighe John Newton Francis Stringer Anthony Palmer Charles Bawdes Pury Cust Esquires The Maior Six
senior Aldermen and Recorder of the Citty of Lincolne for the time being The Maior of Grimsby for the
time being The Maior of Boston for the time being The Alderman of Grantham for the time being The Maior
of Stamford for the time being The Warden of Lowth for the time being Sir John Oldfield Baronet Edward
Curtis of Stamford John Palmer senior of Stamford Gentlemen Montague Cholmley William Troloppe William
Savill Stephen Rothwell Peregrine Bucke Richard Pell George Sanderson Stephen Mason George Healy Thomas
Cox Thomas Ellis Ludrington of Brassebrigg John Browne of Laughton Robert Sleeford Esquires
John Cocke of Skendle by Thorpe Darcy Stanhope George Farmery Edward Turney Robert Sanderson Marmaduke
Dorrell William Fitzwilliams George Newell George Midlemore Charles Woolley Christopher Pym Thomas Hall
Francis Grantham Vincent Grantham Christopher Berisford Bevercotes Cornwallis Anthony Ayrr John Butler John
Eley George Nevill George Whichcott Bishop John Jay Francis Corie of Sutton Cooley
of Dinnington Gambling of Moulton Henry Hall of Dinnington Henry Stone Anthony Williams
Robert Lameing Thomas Harrington Esquires Miles Long Augustine Caudron Cornelius Hall Edward Browne
Gentlemen Anthony Irby Esquire Samuell Browne John Bolt William Wilson John Dimpson Adlard Welby David
Boneale Henry Burrell Esquire Bevill Wimberley Israell Jackson Richard Calcroft of Grantham Richard Milner
Richard Cracroft John Tooley Gentlemen Richard Holley of Grantham Nathaniell Hobson Bishop of
Heniswell Lake of Norton Charles Harvey of Norton William Howell Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Edward
Sturton Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke John Shaw Gentleman William Dickenson John Burton of Spalding John Eeley
Edward Melthorpe John Boswell Charles Newcomen George Knight George Lucas Esquire Sigesmond Trafford
Charles Radley William Thompson of Roxham John Towne of Sudbrooke George Langton [Christopher Clayton
[and<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] James Langton<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] Gilbert Standish of Durrington Robert Fisher William Popell John Smith William Hooton
William Marwood junior Robert Sands Thomas Coventry James Harrington William Hall of Lincolne Nicholas
Smith Francis Ascoughe Thomas Ascoughe John Treeston George Fairfax Robert Perkins of Grantham John
Rossiter John Greene senior Ashton of Grantham Captaine Topham of Deeping Saint James Robert
Hurst Edward Webb Councellor at Law William Byfield Joseph Edmonds Esquire Thomas Tulston of Cathorpe
Gilbert Berry William Leach of Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p169">For the Citty of London</para>
		<para id="p170">The Right Honourable Sir James Edwards Lord Maior and the Lord Maior for the time being Sir William
Wilde Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Chiverton Knight and Alderman Sir Thomas Allen Knight and Baronet
Sir John Fredericke Knight Sir John Robinson Knight and Baronet Sir John Lawrence Sir Thomas Bludworth
Sir William Turner Sir George Waterman Sir Robert Hanson Sir William Hooker Knights and Aldermen [Sir
Robt Viner Kn<emph type="p">t</emph> &amp; Bar[one]t Sir Joseph Sheldon Sir Tho: Davis Sir Francis Chaplin Kn<emph type="p">ts</emph> &amp; Aldermen<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] Sir George
Jeffereys Knight Recorder and the Recorder for the time being Sir Robert Clayton Sir Patience Ward Sir John
Moore Sir William Pritchard Sir Henry Tulse Sir James Smith Sir Nathaniell Herne Sir Robert Jefferyes Sir John
Shorter Sir Thomas Gould Sir, William Rawstorne Knights, and Aldermen Sir Richard Howe Sir John Chapman
Knights and Sheriffes and the Sheriffes of the same Citty for the time being Sir John Lethulier Sir John Peake
Sir Thomas Stampe Sir William Thompson Sir Theophilus Biddulph Sir Thomas Player Knights Sir Josiah Childe
Sir Nicholas Crispe Baronets Sir Thomas Meres Sir Samuell Bernardiston Sir Eliab Harvey Sir John Cope Sir
Thomas Clarges Sir Phillip Mathews Sir John Trevor Sir Robert Wiseman Sir Lyonell Jenkins Sir Thomas
Exton Sir Francis Pemberton Sir Edward Waldoe Knights William Trumball Do&bholigct;or of the Lawes Sir Richard
Lloyd Knight Do&bholigct;or of Lawes William Love John Jolliffe Henry Dunstar John Morris John Jones John Bence
Thomas Papillon Erasmus Smith James Hayes John Nicholls John Jefferyes John Bathurst Edward Turgis John
Dubois Thomas Pilkinton James Hublon Francis Warner William Williams Humphrey Cliffe Alam Cliffe Charles
Thorold Ralph Box Marke Cotle John Lane John Fitz Nicholas Charleton Edward Backwell John Wise Richard
Hawkins Thomas Lewes Thomas Hunt George Keate John Crispe William Wilkinson Thomas Farmin Nathaniell
Letton Henry Collier William Wogan Samuell Franckin Walter Lapp Gervase Price Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p171">For the County of Midlesex</para>
		<para id="p172">The Right Honourable William Lord Russell Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Bedford and one of
the Lords of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill William Lord Cavendish Sonne and Heire apparent
to the Earle of Devonshire and one of the Lords of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill William
Lord Allington of the Kingdome of Ireland, The Honourable Daniell Finch Esquire Sir Harbotle Grimston Baronet
Master of the Rolls Sir Robert Carr Knight and Baronet Chauncellour of the Dutchy of Lancaster George
Mountague Esquire Henry Coventry Esquire Principall Secretary of State Sir Robert Atkins Knight of the Bath
one of His Majestyes Justices of the Common Pleas Sir John Mainard Knight one of His Majestyes Sergeants at
Law Sir Will: Roberts Sir Francis Gerrard Knights and Baronets Sir Thomas Litleton Sir Joseph Ash Baronets
Sir John Cutler Knight and Baronet Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir Thomas Wolstenholme Sir Phillip Mathews Sir John
Parsons Sir Paul Whichcott Baronets Sir John Wynn Knight and Baronet Sir William Cooper Baronet Sir John
Bennet Knight of the Bath Sir Richard Fisher Baronet Sir Goddard Nelthorp Baronet Sir Richard Fisher Baronet
Sir Robert Payton Sir John Talbott Sir Thomas Player Sir William Poultney Sir Thomas Allen Sir Thomas
Byde Sir Thomas Escourt senior Sir Thomas Escourt junior Sir Thomas Chambers Sir Robert Hanson Sir
Clement Armiger Sir William Bowle Sir Thomas Stringer Sir William Waller Sir Charles Pitfield Sir Charles
Harboard Sir Charles Lee Sir Lancelott Lake Sir Thomas Clerges Sir John Trevor Sir John James Sir William
Powell Sir John Pye Sir James Rushout Sir Edward Abney Sir Miles Heneage Sir John Masters Sir Nicholas
Crispe Sir Nathaniell Herne Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir Richard Blake Sir (<ref idref="n35">35</ref>) William Turner Sir John Elwayes Sir
Edward Brett Knights George Pitts Charles Cheney Francis Crawley Henry Barker William Barker George Walsh
Samuell Bucke John Wilkinson Thomas Hayter James Southern Nicholas Raynton Ralph Hawtry George Dashwood
Thomas Row Thomas Robinson Humphrey Wirley Samuell Grimston James Clitherowe Edmond Warcupp John
Honor John Walker senior John Walker junior Charles Umfrevile Orlando Gee Thomas Harris Thomas Rider
Roger Gillingham Charles Blount Henry Hawley John Walstenholme Anthony [Krike<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] William Gulston Thomas
Harriot Thomas Johnson John Swanley Thomas Lewis James Hoare junior Stewart Foster William Walter Scory
Barker John Baldwin Ralph Palmer Maximilian Beard Thomas Coppin Christopher Yate Thomas Cheeke Francis
Rogers William Northee Richard Bayly Nicholas Stanley Joseph Keeble Henry Johnson John Robarts Thomas
Knight Arnold Browne Simon Midleton John Greene Charles Gerrard Bridstocke Harford Paul Bows Charles
Porter Ambrose Phillipps John Trenchard William Rawlinson George Hutchinson Jermin Ireton William Wogan
Richard Peacocke Nicholas Townley Samuell Vincent Thomas Winford Robert Weft William Parkins John Cary
Richard Dunton John Hawtry Richard Adams William Goldesbrough Esquire Clerke to the Honourable the
House of Commons Henry Reynell Leonard Hamond Chr: Blake Peter Sabbs Rich: Morley Tho: Owen Daniell
Waldoe Edward Waldoe Richard Harrison Simon Smith Roger Stoughton George Day John Pulford Erasmus
Smith John Jolly John Lloyd of Edgeware Anthony Collins Henry Collins William Northee Ellis Lloyd Thomas
Lewis Edmond Draper Henry Devenish Robert Forsett Abraham Nalson Roger Gardiner Henry Slingsby Justinian
Pagitt John Hutchinson Rowe of Shacklewell Francis Brand Will: Page Will: Prettiman Edw:
Wilford senior Paul Nicholl Peter Vandputt Rich: Spicer Henry Trenchard Ralph Halsall Collonell John Birch
John Halsall Rich: Neltrop Joseph Alston John Robinson John Barnes Tho: Clitherowe Christopher Clitherow
George Sittwell Ralph Bucknall George Nodes Thomas Austin William Marsh John Owen John Wildman Edward
Byde Nicholas Archbold Do&bholigct;or Nicholas Barboon Gray Alderman Thomas Neale John Byfeild Thomas
Casse Richard Cheney Thomas Englesfield John Searle John Haynes Thomas Winter Thomas Henslow Walter
Moyle John Bathurst Josuah Galliard William Avery Josuah Beale Henry Hodges Charles Good Robert Hampton
William Hastings Jervice Price Edmond Walter junior James Cardrow Brooke Bridges Thomas Lewis of the
Spitle Nicholas Gardiner John Parsons Robert Thornhill Thomas Gardiner John Baker Charles Nott William
Robarts Theophilus Birkenhead Esquires John Short Thomas Jackson John Nicholl of Mimns Thomas Nicholl
of Hendon John Biscoe Edward Kemsall Thomas Wood John Nicholl of Cowley William Sedgewick John Carter
John [Indee<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] Thomas Bucknell Richard Holt Merchant Richard Potter John Cane John Memley
Haley of the Bury Arthur Blyth William Thomson John Hardestey Edward Wilford junior Thomas Wratton
John Kirton John Slater William Bannfield Francis Barham Gregory Page Thomas Grimble George Hooper
Henry Dixon Robert Nicholl of Edgeware Henry Johnson junior Thomas Partridge Giles Butler Allen Parsons
Randoll Nicholl of Dolestreete William Browne of Hammersmith William Bird Merchant John Byfeild John Hennins
Thomas Jackson John Page Charles Morgan and Roger Gardner Richard Gwin John Holman Gent..</para>
		<para id="p173">For the Citty of Westminster and the Liberties thereof.</para>
		<para id="p174">The Right Honourable William Lord Cavendish Sonne and Heire apparent of the Earle of Devonshire and
one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Charles Lord Clifford Sonne and Heire apparent to the
Earle of Burlington George Mountague Esquire Sir John Nicholas Sir Joseph Williamson Sir Allen Apsley Sir
Thomas Litleton Sir Charles Cotrell Sir John Bennet Sir Edward Hungerford Sir Phillip Warwicke Sir Michaell
Heneage Sir Robert Howard Sir Robert Carr Sir Phillip Howard Sir Phillip Mathewes Sir Robert Peyton Sir
William Waller Sir John Trevor Sir William Poultney Sir Stephen Fox Sir Thomas Clarges Sir Peter Collidon
Sir Theodore de Vaux Henry [Powle<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] Esquire one of His Majestyes Privy Councill Sir Edward Brett Sir Walter
Clarges Sir John Cotton Sir Charles Harbord Sir Francis Holles Sir Thomas [Meeres<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] Sir George Downeing Sir
John Talbott Sir Thomas Mompesson Sir Anthony Irby Sir Cyrill Wich Sir John Cutler Sir Richard Malon Sir
Robert Filmer Sir Richard Temple Sir Robert Pye Sir Richard Graham Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir William
Orpe Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir William Boreman Sir Winston Churchill Sir Robert Southwell Clerke of His
Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Sir Phillip Lloyd Sir Christopher Wren Sir William Walter Sir
James Hayes Sir Richard Blake Sir Edward Graves The Honourable Lawrence Hyde Esquire one of the Lords
Commissioners of the Treasury Sir John Harvy Esquire William Bridgeman Do&bholigct;or Sydenham Edwin Sandys
[William<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] Walter Phillip Packer John Wilkinson William Herbert Bernard Grindvile John Tregonwell Samuell
Pepis Christopher Vane Reynald Graham Thomas Thynne Nicholas Cortney Hugh Boscowen Edmond Warcupp
Richard Pewman Alexander Strode Mathew Locke Henry Progers John Browne John Stroud Edward Boscowen
George Legg Francis Lucy Henry Herbert Roger Higgs Edward Griffin John Currence Do&bholigct;or Warner Thomas
Lucy Esquires George Forewell Hugh May John Birch James Dewy Humphrey Wurley senior Thomas Bayles
Do&bholigct;or Samuell Barrows Thomas Morris Walter Brideall Ellis Lloyde Bevis Lloyde Simon Smith John Man
Richard Paget Michaell Bridgehouse Lancelot Thornton Hugh Squire Charles Hinton John Baines Captaine Hugh
Bohey Humphrey Worley junior John Russell Thomas Hayewood William Wardour Edward Clerke Robert
Harcourt John Walker Thomas Russell Ambrose Scudamore Do&bholigct;or Barwicke David Lloyd Richard Smitle
Nicholas Baxter Thomas Crumpe John Ball Do&bholigct;or John Clerke Bartholimew Vermuden Henry Slingsby William
Blake John Chasse George Cooper William Morgan Henry Shalcrosse William Bookeley Ralph Marshall John
Lugg Richard Wheeler Richard Bull John Minchen John Leeson Michaell Arnoll George Plucknet Nicholas
Edlyn Morris Hunt Richard Mill Thomas Tyndall Thomas Warner John Greene Nehemiah Arnold Henry Simons
Miles Michaell Richard Harding Christopher Sheene William Wheeler Peter Griffith Charles Campaine William
Austin John Fister Samuell Bate George Browne Thomas Butler Edmond Doyle John [Loyier<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] Robert Blayne
Thomas Symmons Robert Newman Arthur Dryer Robert Whitte William Williams John Dunn John Snell Edward
Younger Henry Becke and Giles Masters Gentlemen Nathaniell Houghton Esquire William Hawkins Henry Aldrige
Robert Pott and James Smitleby Gentlemen George Bennitt Richard Maye Daniell Finch Sir Tho: Daniell Will:
Thursby Tho: Gilbert and Arthur Sparkes Esquires Samuell Vincent Josuah Drayner and Francis Gwyne Gentlemen
John Tomlinson Francis Stephens John Lawrence John Loveing Morrice Hunt Gent. Symon Smith Merchant
Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke, Richard Bayles of Westminster Charles Knott of Saint Clements Dane
Gentlemen Thomas Owen Esquire Richard Stephens Charles Morgan Gent. Richard Baile Albian Chaire Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p175">For the County of Monmouth</para>
		<para id="p176">Charles Lord Herbert of Ragland Sonne and Heire apparent to the Marquisse of Worcester Sir Baynham
[Throckmorton<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] Baronet Sir Edward Morgan Sir Charles Kemys Baronets Sir Trevor Williams Baronet Sir John
Morgan Baronet William Morgan Richard Lewis Edward Morgan Trevor Williams Henry Probert Esquires Thomas
Lewis Charles Vann William Kemys James Herbert John Arnold Edward Progers Charles Progers Thomas Morgan
John Carey David Lewis Thomas Folio Charles Price Edmond Morgan Esquires Collonell William Morgan Thomas
Morgan William Herbert Richard Lister Henry Milborne Edmond Jones Henry Barker Roger Oates William Jones
Esquires Nicholas Kemish Edmond Gamage Ralph Bucknell Charles Milborne Thomas Pritchard Rowland Gwyne
Roger Williams George Keyms John Williams John Morgan John Price Capell Hanbury Trevor Morgan Thomas
Harbert Thomas Jones John Walter Thomas Hughes Phillip Cecill John Rumsey James Morgan Rowland Pritchard
William Herbert Rodericke Gwyne Esquires Morgan Chambers William Blethin Edward Kemys John Lewis
David Morgan Walter Evans Robert Gunter Lewis Morgan John Walter John Ketchmay George Kemys Charles
Morgan William Williams John Rumsey Rowland Williams Gentlemen John Bird John Fleare William Lewis
Walter Aldy Robert Jones Nicholas Parker Phillip Morgan Trevor Probert Charles Williams Isaac Tomkins Giles
Morgan Theophilus Reynolds James Jones John [Carr<ref idref="n43">43</ref>] Charles Morgan Henry Morgan William Jones Hugh James
of Saint Maughanes Walter Cecill George Harris Richard Jones John Jones John Wroth Henry Morgan Herbert
Williams Christopher Price Roger Williams James Harris Hopkin Vaughan William Herbert William Powell John
Harris Leonard Merwicke Richard Vaughan Morgan Thomas Isaac Williams Charles Baker John Watkins William
Evans Thomas Jones Richard Roberts Herbert Jones Francis Williams Thomas Springett John Gwillim Francis
Pritchard William Powell Nathaniell Rogers Gentlemen John Scudamore Esq&bhoqesq; Walter Scudamore Thomas Patricke
James Williams James Hughes Martin Boothby William George Gent. Edward Perkins Gent. Thomas Williams
Gent. The Maior of Monmouth for the time being The Maior of Newport for the time being The Port Reve
of Uske for the time being and The Bayliffe of Abergavenny for the time being Captaine Wolsley John Morgan
Gent..</para>
		<para id="p177">For the County of Northampton.</para>
		<para id="p178">Bryen Viscount Cullen of the Kingdome of Ireland Lord Huntingtower of the Kingdome of Scotland William
Lord Fitzwilliams of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir William Mountague Lord Cheife Baron Ralph Mountague Esquire Sir
Francis Compton Knight George Mountague Esquire Sir Thomas Crew Knight Sir Roger Norwich Sir Samuell Danvers
Sir John Egerton Sir William Farmer Sir Edward Nicholas Sir John Robinson Sir William Wake Sir Hugh Chumley
Sir Charles Shugburrough Sir Lewis Palmer Sir James Langham Sir John Holman Sir John Pickerine Sir Thomas
Samwell Baronets Sir Edward Griffin Sir William Haslewood Sir William Langham Sir Edward Alston Sir William
Craven Sir Samuell Clerke Sir Edmond Bray Knights Sir Roger Cave Sir Rice Rudd Sir Robert Dryden Baronets
Philip Lord Waynman of the Kingdome of Ireland Robert Apreece Daniell Finch Edward Griffin Francis Lane
junior Henry Stafford Richard Ransford John Parkhurst William Herbert John Browne; Lawrence Maudley Thomas
Trist William Saunders Thomas Elmes Tobias Chauncey Thomas Catsby Samuell Trist William Washbourne
Devereux Knightley William Tate John Hampden Edward [Harvey<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] William Adams of Welton Richard Saltonstall
Edward Palmer John Creswell Henry Edmonds George Clerke Robert Clerke William Bugby Bryan Janson
John Woodhall John Willoughby William Lisle William Warner Christopher Coe Christopher Thursby George
Leaffeild John Bagshaw Andrew Lant Francis Morgan Miles Fleetewood Thomas Hacke Robert Pemberton Thomas
Ward John Lyne Nicholas [Studard<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] Francis(<ref idref="n46">46</ref>) Saint Jones Jeremiah Dove William Leven Samuell Templer John
Bridges John Hanbury John Thornton John Combs Edgar Farmer Francis Crane Francis Arundell John Gardner
Tryan Thomas Andrewes Robert Hesleridge Gerrard Gore Goddard Pemberton Ekins
of Weston Joseph Hames William Adams of Charleton Edward Ladkins Bathurst of Howthorp
Benson of Tocester Richard Butler The Maior of the Towne of Northampton for the time being
John Brafield John Friend William Kimboll Gentlemen Edward Knighton Salathiell Lovell The Maior of Higham
for the time being The Bayliffe of Daventree for the time being Valentine Shugburgh Richard Shugburgh of
Farthingoe The Maior of Brackley for the time being Henry Lucas Doctor Skinner John Bourne Richard Plowman
William Thursby George Quarles Richard Willowby Edward Stratford Edmond Bacon Bernard Walcote Thomas
Newton Robert Fruen Gentlemen Thomas Pilkington Merchant.</para>
		<para id="p179">For the County of Nottingham</para>
		<para id="p180">Patricius Viscount Chaworth of the Kingdome of Ireland The Honourable Anchitell Grey Arthur Stanhope Will:
Byron Robert Pierpoint Esquires Sir John Mollineux Sir Thomas Williamson Sir William Hickman Sir John
Newton Baronets Sir Francis Leeke Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Nevile Knight and Baronet John Grubham
How John Lindley Charles Stanhope Charles Hutchinson John Thornhagh Will: Sandys Francis Sandys Esquires
Sir Scroope How Sir Ralph Knight Knights John Digby Thomas Perkins William Godfrey Harvey Staunton Francis
Stringer Thomas Charleton senior Peniston Whalley Esquires Thomas Lewes William Cartwright of Ossington
Richard Slater Lancellot Rowleston Henry Plumtree Esquires Richard Mansfield Edward Bigland Gilbert Millington
George Gregory William Palmes Darcey. Mollineux William Pinckney William Clerkson George Nevill Thomas
Shipman. John Musters Thomas Russell Phillip Pendocke Reason Mellish Francis Jessop John Millington Esquires
The Maior of Newarke for the time being The Bayliffes of Retford for the time being Edward Ward Mathew
Jennison Samuell Ellis Gentlemen George Lascelles Arthur Warren Clifton Rodes William Lane Esquires Peter
Broughton John Rolston John Yarborrow Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke William Wymondsold William Savile Esquires Robert
Newton John Hacker of Trowell Henry Halfehide John Clerkson Anthony Tate Thomas Porter of Binckham
Thomas Dickenson William Fowler Robert Westbrooke Gentlemen Thomas Wawen Thomas Marshall George Pole
Hacker of Fincham William Gray John Dand Samuell Sandys Esquires William Cartwright of Normanton
Esquire Samuell Staples Tempest Brighouse Henry Walter John Baines Robert Sherbrooke Lawcocke
Thomas Barrett John Newton Thomas Bristow Ralph Edge John Trueman Thomas Porter of Blyth William
Wharton Gent. William Stanhope Gervase Pigott Charles Lawcocke Anthony Gilby Mountague Wood Edward
Phinney Esquires John White Esquire William Gelstrop of Whatton John Kerchevill Gent..</para>
		<para id="p181">For the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham.</para>
		<para id="p182">The Maior and Aldermen for the time being The Honourable Robert Pierpoint Charles Hutchinson Henry Plumtree
Edward Bigland George Gregory Samuell Staples Richard Slater James Savewell Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p183">For the County of Northumberland</para>
		<para id="p184">Henry Earle of Ogle Sonne and Heire apparent to the Duke of Newcastle Edward Lord Morpeth Sonne and
Heire apparent to the Earle of Carlisle Sir John Fenwicke Sir Ralph Delavall Sir Cuthbert Heron Sir William
Blacket Sir Thomas Lorraine Baronet Sir George Downeing Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Horsley Sir Ralph
Jennison Sir Richard Stote Knights Cuthbert Heron Utricke Whitfield John Grey Daniell Collingwood John
Blackstone Edward Villers William Strother Ralph Hebron William Lilborne Thomas Bewicke Francis Blake Robert
Mitford Francis Addison Thomas Collingwood John Ridley James Howard Henry Ogle William Widrington John
Forster of Cornwall Robert Jennison William Ogle John Shaftoe William Carnaby Robert Delavall Nicholas Whitehead
Edmond Craster William Armorer William Fenwicke Esquires William Delavall George Delavall William Carr John
Forster of Etherson Thomas Burrell Patricius Crow Tristram Fenwicke Robert Fenwicke of Bywell Edward
Collingwood William Strother of Grindor Rigg Gentlemen</para>
		<para id="p185">For the Towne and County of Newcastle upon Tyne.</para>
		<para id="p186">Mathew Jeffreson Maior Sir James Clavering Baronet Sir William Blacket Baronet Sir Francis Anderson Sir
Robert Shafto Recorder Sir Ralph Carr Knight Sir Ralph Jennison Knight Sir Richard Stote Knight Henry Maddison
Henry Brabant Timothy Davison Robert Roddam George Morton Nathaniell Johnson Aldermen Nicholas Fenwicke
Sheriffe John Watson Robert Jennison William Lilburne John Blackiston Henry Jennison Michaell Blacket Anthony
Isaacson Esquires William Huntley Robert Fenwicke William Bales Abraham Drake Henry Hargraves Ralph Fell
John Phillipson Robert Wetwang John Squire Edward Freeman Nicholas Ridley Benjamin Davison Edward Greene
John Vary Marke Dover Richard Hutchinson Anthony Spenceley Ralph Rogerson William Blackett Francis Anderson
Gent..</para>
		<para id="p187">The Burrough of Berwicke upon Tweede</para>
		<para id="p188">John Lucke Maior for the time being Ralph Grey Esquire Thomas Watson James Cutterall Andrew Moore
Aldermen Elias Pratt Marke Scott Stephen Jackson Gentlemen Daniell Collingwood Esquire William Strother senior
William Strother junior Esquires Sir John Fenwicke Baronet Sir Richard Scott Knight The Bayliffes for the time
being Ralph Hebron Esquire Master Richard Windloe Roger Weddell Edward Nealson Selby senior
Selby junior Ferdinand Forster Anthony Compton Robert Watson George Watson Edward Ord
Edward Salkeld Gentlemen John Rushworth Esq&bhoqesq;</para>
		<para id="p189">For the County of Norffolke</para>
		<para id="p190">William Lord Fitzwilliams of the Kingdome of Ireland Henry Lord Richardson of the Kingdome of Scotland
William Paston Esquire Sir Robert Howard Sir William Coventry Knights Sir Edmond Bacon Sir John Hobart Sir
Phillip Woodhouse Sir Edward Barkham Sir John Holland Sir Augustine Palgrave Sir Roger Potts Sir Robert
Kempe Sir Jacob Astley Sir Edmond Bacon of Gillingham Sir Edward Ward Sir Henry Deereham Sir William
Cooke Sir William Doyley Sir Peter Gleane Sir Francis Bickley Sir Thomas Garrard Sir John Pettus Sir William
Adams Sir John Mordaunt Baronets Sir Christopher Calthrope Knight of the Bath Sir Charles Harboard Knight
His Majestyes Surveyour Generall Sir Joseph Williamson Sir Nevile Catlin Sir Thomas Allen Knights Sir Thomas
Hare Baronet Sir Thomas Meadows Sir John Bludwell Sir Robert Beldocke Sir William Kant Sir James Johnson
Knights John Harvey Robert Walpoole Will: Windum Thomas Holland William Cooke Esquires Sir Roger Pratt
Knight Thomas Townesdend Phillip Harbord William Harbord John Harbord John Hobart Robert Long William
de Grey Robert Suckling John Barney John Pell Francis Guybon William Rant John Jay Francis Bacon Edward
Ward James Host Simon Taylour John Turner Augustine Briggs Richard Huntington Esquires James Hobard
Thomas Bacon Robert London Oliver Neve Thomas Gaudy Robert Day Edmond Woodhouse Edmond Doyley
Suckling Jay Francis Lane Jacob Preston Thomas Peirson Phillip Bedingfeild Thomas Say John Greene of Bradenham
Anthony Fisher Robert Houghton Robert Coney Francis Bell Charles Wren Lawrence Oxborough Ralph Earle
Thomas Knivett Richard Godfrey Nicholas Rookwood Simon Brittiffe John Anguish Christopher Crow Mumford
Spilman [Leonard<ref idref="n47">47</ref>] Spilman Leonard Mapes Edmond de Grey Christopher Bedingfeild Nicholas Wilton John Fisher
Hatton Barners Thomas Thursby Francis Thursby Clipsby Gribon George Townsend Gascoigne Weld Leonard
Gouch Le Grose of Crostwicke John Warner Anthony Freeston John Hauton Clement Horne John
Cocke Thomas Browne Thomas Cory Thomas Talbott John Buxton Thomas Wright William Branthwaite William
Cropley Gabriell Armiger John Thurston John Le Strange Thomas Richmond Esquires Peter Diamond Richard
Barrey junior John Norris William Barker Henry Farrer Edmond Osborne Francis Creamer George Ward Henry
Heynes Edward Beedle Thomas Bransby Robert Suckling junior Robert Wood Gardiner Hewett John Paynell
John Knivett Thomas Wood Richard Marriott John Richmond Esquires Do&bholigct;or Owen Hughes Richard Browne
John Aid Henry Marsham John Mingay Thomas Weld Anthony Buther Thomas Weld William Sydley Israell
Long Robert Doughty John Garnish John Blofeild Henry Negoes John Garnish Isaac Preston Hugh Harvey
Edward Le Strange Isaac Mootham Edward Leigh Roger Pepis Samuell Vincent [Esquires<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] Ralph Peirson Gent.
James Ward Nicholas Stileman Esquires Roger Jenings James Fountaine [Esqires<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] Francis [Dulgate<ref idref="n49">49</ref>] Arthur
King of Tilney Richard Trice Gent. Robert Wardell Gent. Do&bholigct;or Pepper Page Thomas Buller
Esquires William Williamson Charles [Tunior<ref idref="n50">50</ref>] junior Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p191">For the Towne of Great Yarmouth</para>
		<para id="p192">The Bayliffe for the time being Sir Thomas Meddow Knight Sir James Johnson Knight George England Esquire
John Woodrofe Abraham Castle Edmond Thexter John Hall Richard Huntington Peter Cantier Michaell Mew
George Ward Samuell Fenn Thomas England Benjamin England Nicholas Cuttin John Robins Samuell Fuller
Nathaniell Symonds Aldermen.</para>
		<para id="p193">For the Citty and County of Norwich.</para>
		<para id="p194">The Maior for the time being Francis Bacon Esq&bhoqesq; Recorder John Norris Esquire Steward William Paston
Jehosophat Davy Bernard Church John Mann Thomas Wisse Henry Wood John Lawrence Augustine Briggs Robert
Bendish Henry Herne John Manser Henry Watts Thomas Chickring John Rithers Esquires Henry Crow Marke
Cockrey John Low Robert Freeman Hugh Bokenham Francis Gardner Leonard Osborne William Helwis Nicholas
Helwes Jeremiah Vyn William Parmenter Aldermen Henry Brady Simon Wissiter Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p195">For the Towne of Kings Lynn.</para>
		<para id="p196">Benjamin Holles Henry Bell Thomas Robinson Edmond Abbott Daniell Goodwin Simon Taylor Edward Bramley
Arthur Evelin John Turner Esquires Giles Bridgeman William Bassett Thomas Fenn Edmond Tassell Aldermen
Percivall Harwicke Robert Thorowgood Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p197">For the Towne of Thetford</para>
		<para id="p198">The Maior for the time being Thomas Povey Esquire Recorder Sir John Holland Barronet Sir Thomas Garrard
Baronet Sir Phillip Woodhouse Baronet Sir Joseph Williamson Knight William Harbord Esquire Burage Martin
John Thurston William Cropley Esquires Robert Tyrrell Wormley Hettersell Thomas Gouch Principall Burgesses.</para>
		<para id="p199">For the County of Oxford</para>
		<para id="p200">Lord Viscount Falkland of the Kingdome of Scotland Phillip Lord Wenman Viscount Tuan of the Kingdome of
Ireland Henry Bertie Esquire Sir William Coventry Knight Sir John Burlace Sir Thomas Spencer Sir William
Walter Sir Compton Read Sir William Glyn Sir Edmond Fettyplace Sir Francis Wenman Sir Litleton Osbaldeston
Sir Anthony Craven Sir Robert Jenkinson Sir Thomas Chamberlaine Sir John Holman Sir Richard Temple Sir
John Doyley Sir Thomas Cob Sir John Cope Sir Fairemeadow Peniston Sir Phillip Harcourt Sir William Rich
Baronets Sir Edward Hungerford Knight of the Bath Sir Edward Norreys Sir Timothy Tyrrell Sir Edmond Bray Sir
Thomas Tipping Sir George Crooke Sir Allen Apsley Sir James Hayes Sir Nicholas Pelham Sir Thomas Woodcock Sir
Thomas Row Knights Nicholas Whitten Broome Whorwood Robert Dormer Esquires Charles Holloway Serjeant at Law
Richard Crooke Serjeant at Law Charles Perrot Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Richard Wenman Richard Lyb Vincent Barry John
Hampden Edward Barry John Stone Henry Alnutt Francis Martin John Clerke William Barker William Lenthall.
Esquires Sir John Lenthall Kn<emph type="p">t</emph> Francis Clerke William Dormer William Barber Henry Heiling George Chamberlaine
Reginald Bray Thomas Horde William Bayly John Croke Samuell Sandys junior Thomas Coventry William
Gannocke Robert Perrott John Gower Edmund Warcupp and Robert Warren Esquires Richard Powell Nicholas
Bowell Nicholas Baynton George Pudsey John Nurse William Whitlocke Tavernor Harris Henry Hall of Hardingers
Thomas Coghill Alexander Denton Robert Huntington Thomas Wise Esquires James Hyde Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke
Henry Aldworth Doctor of Law Arthur Jones William Sheppard Charles Holloway Richard Holloway Serjeant at Law
Mathew Loveday William Oakley John West William Wright Humphrey Wickham John Gun Samuell Trotman John
White Sebastian Smith Edmond Gregory James Paul Esquiers Thomas Teddar John Blagrave Esquires Nathan
Knight Esquire Mathew Skinner Do&bholigct;or of Physicke William Blake Esq&bhoqesq; John Parson James Perrott Esquires
Bartholimew Harris William Stonehouse George Woodward John Wickham Thomas Cleyton Robert Withers
Robert Whorwood John Cary Robert Parsons Thomas Rowney Charles Sparke Richard Stephens Gilbert Jackson
John Irons Robert [Magott<ref idref="n51">51</ref>] Richard Hinton Gentlemen The Maior of Woodstocke for the time being The Maior
of Banbury for the time being The Warden of Henley of Thames for the time being The Bayliffes of Chippingnorton.
for the time being The Bayliffes of Burford for the time being The Bayliffes of Whitney for the time being Adam.
Springhall Gentlemen Nathaniell Brookes of Backbrooke Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p201">For the University of Oxford</para>
		<para id="p202">Do&bholigct;or John Nicholas Vice Chauncellor Heneage Finch Esquire His Majestyes Sollicitor Generall Do&bholigct;or John.
Wallis Do&bholigct;or Tho: Yate Do&bholigct;or Henry Clerke Do&bholigct;or Thomas James Do&bholigct;or John Lloyd Do&bholigct;or Gilbert Ironside
Do&bholigct;or Henry Smith Do&bholigct;or Timothy Houghton Do&bholigct;or Thomas Bourchier Do&bholigct;or John Lamphire Do&bholigct;or Thomas
Elyot Do&bholigct;or John Edisbury The Pro&bholigct;ors for the time being Master Benjamin Cooper Master Richard Witt
Master John Haslewood Master John Crosse Master Richard Hopkins.</para>
		<para id="p203">For the Citty of Oxford</para>
		<para id="p204">The Maior for the time being Sir Sampson White Sir Edward Norreys Sir Francis Wenman Sir John Cope
Knights Richard Crooke Serjeant at Law Recorder of the Citty Broome Whorwood Esquire William Wright
William Bayly John Townesend Thomas Fifeild Alderman John Lambe Francis Grenaway William Cornish William
Walker. Esquires Tobias Browne William Morrall Thomas Eustace Thomas Tisdale Charles Holloway Esquires John
Paynton Towne Clerke Robert Whorwood Charles Harris Gent. George Lowe. Esquire.</para>
		<para id="p205">For the County of Rutland</para>
		<para id="p206">The Right Honourable Bennet Lord Sherrard of the Kingdome of Ireland The Honourable Edward Noell Esquire
Sonne and Heire apparent to the Right Honourable Baptist Viscount Campden Phillip Sherrard Esquire Sir Thomas
Mackworth Sir Abell Barker Baronets Sir Thomas Fanshaw Knight William Palmes John Wingfield Christopher
Browne Richard Verney Samuell Browne Edward Faukener Androw Noell Charles Halford Thomas Barker Bennet
Sherrard William Hyde Anthony Palmer Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p207">For the County of Salop</para>
		<para id="p208">Richard [Newort<ref idref="n52">52</ref>] Andrew Newport (<ref idref="n53">53</ref>) [Sir Henry Fredericks<ref idref="n54">54</ref>] Sir Humphry Briggs Sir William Whitmore Sir
Roger Harris Sir Francis Lawley Sir Vincent Corbett Sir John Corbett (<ref idref="n55">55</ref>) Sir Francis Edwards Sir Edward A&bholigct;on Sir
Thomas Vernon Sir Clament Clerke Baronets Sir Thomas Jones one of His Majestyes Justices of the Kings Bench
Sir Thomas Whitmore Sir John Weld Sir Job Charleton Sir John Trevor Sir Richard Mason Sir Samuell Baldwin
Sir Lacon Childe Sir Robert Owen Knights Gervase Pierpoint Thomas Thynne William Levison Gower Richard
Screven Richard Fowler Francis Charleton of [Apleby<ref idref="n56">56</ref>] Charles Manwareing John Walcott Francis Forrester Robert
Leighton Richard Lister Thomas Lister Arthur Weaver Edward Kinaston of Adbrightcley Edward Kinaston of Oateley
Thomas Bawdwin Phillip Prince Henry Langley Thomas Burton Adam Ottley Somersett Fox Francis Charleton
Henry Herbert William Forrester John Woolrich Francis Berkley George Weld Tho: Rocke Roger Kinaston
Robert Corbett of Lee John Coates William Oakeley Edmund Warring of Woolbury Tho: Walcott Robert Cressett
Phillip Bentall Daniell Wicherley Robert Owen Roger Pope Thomas Lloyd Richard Creswell John Leighton John
Lacon Will: Williams Vincent Edwards Tho: Ottley Litleton Powis Richard Moore John Newton Richard
Carew Roger Whitley Thomas Kinnersley of Badger William Cotton Thomas Cotton of Pully. Humphrey Brigges
William Jones of Sandford Thomas Hill Thomas Ireland William Hanmer Edward Leighton Edward Kerry Edward
Whichcott Edward Vernon Henry Davenport Samuell Langley of Brosely Rowland Nicholls Rowland Hunt Henry
Mitton George Cline Thomas Corbett of Stanwardine Humphrey Cornwall Thomas Cornwall Edward Agborough Bevis
Lloyd Roger Evans William Herbert of Wooton Robert Clowes Thomas Vernon Richard Cowling John Corbett of
Newton John Seaverne Thomas Smalman James Becke Richard Pope Arthur Ward George Lluellin Richard Prince
William Adams John Wood Thomas Jobber John Edwards of Rorington Richard Corbett Thomas Langley Edward
Luttwich Thomas Edwards William Charleton Henry Powell John Powell Esquires The Maiors of Salop and Owstry
The Bayliffes of Ludlow Bridgenorth Bishops Castle and Wenlocke for the time being Francis Smith Robert Smith
John Taylor of Rodington Ralph Hareing George Hosier John Whitacre Samuell Lloyd Thomas Mason Alexander
Midleton Arthur Hincks Edward Gosenell John Langley of the Amyes Edward Owen of Cundover Roger Griffiths
Richard Wareing Edward Woolaston Robert Vernon John Woodhouse Adam Wareing John Fowler of Whitechurch
Richard Deves William Walter John Latham William [Howler<ref idref="n57">57</ref>] Richard Jenkins John Slaniers Edward Powell John
Bright Rowland Midleton William Owen of Whitley Edward Poully William Dansy Walter Bagott Thomas Hawkes
William Griffithes William Grosvenor Richard Davies Richard Bradley Richard Ridley William Bridgen Samuell
Bowdler John Edwards of the Heath Gent. Edward Lloyd of Llanvardoe Robert Clive Owen Barton Morgan Wynne
Edward Jenings John Whitmore Esquires John Huxley Thomas Hinckes Esquires William Crumpton William Jones
George Chambers Edward Owen Christopher [Braan Roger<ref idref="n58">58</ref>] Trevor Francis Harris John Kenett Darniell Wicherley
Richard Lloyd Henry Bigges Edward Donne Richard Cleeveley Kenricke John Hill and Robert Wood
Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p209">For the County of Stafford</para>
		<para id="p210">Sir Thomas Wilbraham Sir Walter Bagott Sir Edward Litleton Sir Henry Litleton Sir John Bowyer Sir Charles
[Molsley<ref idref="n59">59</ref>] Sir Thomas Bellat Sir Francis Lawley Baronets Sir Bryan Broughton Sir Theophilus Biddulph Knights and
Baronets Sir John Wirley Sir Rowland Oakeover Sir Thomas Whitgrave Sir Henry Archbold Sir Henry Gough
Knights William Ward Randolph Egerton Henry Grey Walter Chetwind William Levison Gower Thomas Thynne
Edward Litleton Michaell Biddulph John Offley William Snead Edward Manwaring George Legg Broome Worwood
Robert Levison George Vernon Thomas Lane William Chetwind John Every Phillip Foley Charles Cotton Richard
Congreave Jonas Grosvenor Edward Vernon Thomas Kinnersley senior William Crompton John Swinfen Ralph Sneyd
Edwin Skrimshire Henry Vernon Charles Skrimshire John Coates Thomas Kinnersley junior Daniell Watson John
Agard Francis Wightwicke Walter Aston Jonathan Woodnott Thomas Rudiard Thomas Orme William Parker Edward
Arablaster Edward Birch William Whitby Michaell Noble Nicholas Hart John [Whitehall<ref idref="n60">60</ref>] Ferrers Fulke William
Turton Peter Walburton John Bagnall Thomas Whitby William Trafford Zachariah Babington Mathew [Kelbelt<ref idref="n61">61</ref>]
Mathew Flyer John Turton John Leigh Esquires Thomas Palmer Thomas Scott Thomas Rugley Thomas Villers
Leister Barbour Sampson Birch Timothy Edge John Felton Gentlemen The Maiors of Stafford and Newcastle under
Lyne for the time being The Bayliffes of Tamworth for the time being Nicholas Parker Charles Baynton William
Midleton Ralph Wood Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p211">For the City of Litchfield.</para>
		<para id="p212">The two Bayliffes and Sheriffes for the time being Sir Theophilus Biddulph Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Archbold
Knight Sir Henry Litleton Baronet Michaell Biddulph Esquire John Babington Esquire Mathew Dyott Sampson Pott
John Rathbone John Rawlins Ralph [Minotts<ref idref="n62">62</ref>] William Jesson Francis Bayley senior Charles Harrison Edward
Wilson Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p213">For the County of Somersett.</para>
		<para id="p214">The Lord Viscount Fitzharding of the Kingdome of Ireland The Lord Hawley of the Kingdome of Ireland The
Right Honourable Edward Seymour Esquire one of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Francis Pawlett
Esquire Sir William Portman and Sir Hugh Smith Knights of the Bath and Baronets [Sir William Windham Sir
Halsewell Tint Sir Thomas Windham Baronets<ref idref="n58">58</ref>] Sir John Coventry Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Bridges Knight
Sir Edward Hungerford Knight of the Bath Sir William Bassett Sir Edward Phillips Knights Sir Francis Rolle Sir
Edmond Windham Sir John Mallett Sir Stephen Fox Sir John Churchill Sir Humphrey Sydenham Sir James Hayes
Knights Ralph Stawell Thomas Thynne Edward Phelipps George Speake Peregrine Palmer George Horner Edward
Gorges John Carew of Crocombe Edmond Windham Edward Berkley John Smith Hugh Tent William Wogan
Thomas Windham of Witham William Hillier Thomas Warre Robert Hunt Henry Bull of Shapwicke John Pigott
William Lacy the elder John Harrington Henry Waldron George Doddington of Doddington Henry Bull of
Midsummer Norton Warwicke Bampfield William Strode Edward Strode William Lacy the younger Edward Clarke
Robert Hawley Henry Henley Thomas Strode senior Thomas Strode junior Edward Courte Richard Jones Edmond
Carrant John Hunt Peter Royner William Speake John Saint Albans Henry Light William Harbord John Prowse
Thomas Ledgingham John Bayly Chauncellour of Wells William Coward George Stedman Thomas Jennings George
Longe Thomas Mompesson Hugh Tynte Richard Morgan William Harbyn William Clarke Humphrey Sydenham
of Dulverton Richard Musgrave Copleston Horton Richard Newman Richard Crosse William Orange John Hody
Henry Bridges Joseph Langton Richard Landsdowne Charles Steyning George Doddington of Horsington Anthony
Stocker junior Thomas Sanders Edward Hobbs John Wyne George Clarke Esquires Sir George Norton Knight
Francis Luttrell John Hall John Every Baldwin Mallett John Speake Thomas Palmer Francis Vaughan Benham
Strangewayes John Trenchard George Musgrave Thomas Syderfin Roger Sydenham Mathew Pitt Thomas [Blaynard<ref idref="n63">63</ref>]
of [Bagden<ref idref="n64">64</ref>] Edward Coward Gilbert Bourne William Catford Robert Cannon John Burland Edward Thunstone
Robert Chute James Webb Henry Bonner Thomas Jennings William Turner William Proctor Merchants George
Baconobb Lanibord Fitzhead Netlescome William Brewer Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p215">For the Citty of Wells.</para>
		<para id="p216">The Maior for the time being William Coward Esquire Recorder Nicholas Weblett John Davies John Davidge
John Day William Salmon.</para>
		<para id="p217">For the Citty of Bath</para>
		<para id="p218">The Maior for the time being Edward Nevill Esquire Recorder Robert Chapman Benjamin Baber John Bush John
Masters Walter Gibbs Henry Chapman William Bush Walter Hicks Robert Haward Robert Peirce Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke.</para>
		<para id="p219">For the Towne of Bridgewater</para>
		<para id="p220">The Maior for the time being Sir John Mallet Recorder Francis Harvey Humphrey Stere Edward Sealey William
Macy John Lyneing Robert Balch George Crane Thomas Bare Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p221">For the County and City of Bristoll.</para>
		<para id="p222">Sir John Lloyd Knight Maior and the Maior of the said City for the time being Sir Robert Atkins one of His
Majestyes Justices of the Common Pleas Recorder Sir Robert Canne Knight and Baronet Sir John Knight Sir Robert
Yeomans Baronet John Lamford John Hickes Christopher Griffith Richard Streamer Ralph Olliffe William Crabb
Richard Crumpe Esquires The Sheriffes for the time being William Colston Joseph Creswicke Henry Gough William
Willett Humphrey Litle Richard Hart Thomas Day Thomas Earle Edward Young John Cooke John Cecill Samuell
Wharton Edward Feilding George Lane Henry Glisson Henry Merriott William Downeing John Moore William
Jackson William Clutterbucke.</para>
		<para id="p223">For the County of Southampton.</para>
		<para id="p224">Edward Noell Lieutenant of the County William Lord Russell Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Bedford
James Lord Annesley Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Anglesey Sir John Norton Sir Hugh Stewkley Sir
Richard Edgecombe Knight of the Bath Sir Robert Dillington Sir William Meux Sir Thomas Badd Knight and
Baronet Sir Nicholas Stuart Sir John Saintbarbe Sir John Oglander Baronets Sir Robert Holmes Sir Thomas
Higgens Sir Francis Rolle Sir Robert Henley Sir Richard Knight Sir James Worsley Sir Edward Worsley Sir John
Cloberry Sir Charles Windham Sir John Biggs Knights Francis Pawlett Richard Norton Thomas Gervois Henry
Wallop George Pitt Francis Tilney George Legg Lawrence Hyde Henry Whitehead Thomas Knollis John Lewkner
James May Leonard Bilson John Hooke Thomas Cole Benjamin Newland Roger Gallop Henry Bromfield White
Titchbourne Oliver Saint John Henry Tulse Richard Ayliffes William Withers John Faulkner Roger Clavell William
Stevens John Leigh John Paulin Gabriell Whistler John Deane John Smith Edward Dillington John Button Richard
Love of Gretham Francis Dickins John Dingley Robert Goffe Peter Bettesworth William Smith Richard Cobb Robert
Richbell Daniell Kingsmill Richard Holt John Kingsmill Edward Hooper Henry Dawley Francis Morrison Esquires
Charles Foster Francis Morley William Gulson James Rudyard Henry Bromfeilde Ralph Hastings William Pitt
William Drake Thomas Urry of Gatcombe Benjamin Newland George Duke George Browne Henry Perrin Thomas
Dowse of Brooke John Mathews Richard Richards Richard Bishop Robert Rolle Thomas Edmonds Edward Pile
Thomas Knight William Guidott William Goddard John Venables John Reeves Robert Leigh Thomas Urry of
Freshwater William Bunckley of Saint Ellins Bartholimew Bulkley senior John Burrard Peter Blake Joseph Hinchman
Esquires The Maior of Portsmouth for the time being Thomas Wills Phillip James Nicholas Hedger Saint John
Steventon Nicholas Peirson Gent. The Maior of Newport The Maior of Yarmouth The Maior of Baseingstoake and the
Bayliffe of Andover for the time being.</para>
		<para id="p225">For the City of Winchester.</para>
		<para id="p226">The Maior for the time being Sir John Cloberry Knight John Warner William Taylor Thomas Muspratt Edward
Fifeild William Craddock Thomas Wavell Godson Penton William Horwood Aldermen of the same Richard Harris
Recorder Ellis Mew Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p227">For the Towne and County of Southampton</para>
		<para id="p228">The Maior for the time being Roger Gallop Recorder Robert Richbell Benjamin Newland William Stanley James
Crosse Edward Dormer Jacob Ward Thomas Cornelius Richard White Thomas Clutterbooke John Speede Edward
Richards Alexander Hill.</para>
		<para id="p229">For the County of Suffolke</para>
		<para id="p230">Lyonell Lord Huntingtowre of the Kingdome of Scotland Walter Devereux Esquire Sir Edmond Bacon Sir Henry
Felton Sir John Holland Sir Robert Kempe Sir Henry Bacon Sir John Barker Sir William Spring Sir Willoughby Deux
Sir John Castleton Sir Henry North Sir Thomas Cullum Sir William Doyley Sir Gervase Elwes Sir Robert Cordell
Sir Robert Brooke Sir John Duke Sir Phillip Parker Sir Samuell Bernardiston Sir Thomas Bernardiston Sir John Rouse
Sir Robert Reeves Baronets Sir Charles Gawdy and Sir Thomas Allen Knights and Baronets Sir Nicholas Bacon
Knight of the Bath Sir John Duncombe Sir John Pettus Sir John Pooley Sir Thomas Harvy Sir George Wemue Sir
Nevill Catlin Sir John Hanmer Sir Thomas Smith Sir Jeoffery Burwell Sir Francis Theobalds Sir Phillip Meadowes Sir
Thomas Meadowes Sir Charles Crofts Read Sir Phillip Skippon Sir William Soame Sir John Coell Master of Chauncery
Sir Richard Gibbs Sir John Peake and Sir Joseph Brand Knights John Harvey Treasurer to her Majestie William
Crofts Edward Progers John Platers Thomas Holland William Duncombe Adam Felton Thomas Jermin John Cordell
Dudley Cullum Gervase Elwes Thomas Walgrave John Robinson Thomas Bedingfeild Thomas Glenham Henry Pooley
Thomas Coell Thomas Allen John Wright of Ipswich John Bence of Rinsfeild Edmond Tyrrell Henry Parker John
Thirston Giles Bernardiston Benjamin Cutler of the Chauntry William Pooley Maurice Shelton William Soame Richard
Norton Francis Warner Edmond Warner Henry Warner Reginald Williams Edward Hubbard Thomas Robinson of
Kentwell Lumley Robinson Robert Russell Gerrard Russell William Glascocke Lyonell Plaiters Francis Barker
Thomas Dade Robert Gurdon John Sotherby Thomas Shelley John Clerke Samuell Clerke William Gipps John
Cornwallis John Hodges Henry Johnson Edward Man Hamond Lestrainge John Scrivenor Robert King William Acton
Edward North William Rivett Richard Cooke Thomas Salter Thomas Bright Clement Higham Thomas Edgar William
Gooch William Gibbes Samuell Gibbs Thomas Blackerby Robert Maltiward [Tho: Golding Jeffery Malteward<ref idref="n65">65</ref>] Thomas
Wright Henry Edgar Barnaby Bowtell Lawrence Rowse Mathew Leman John Leman Joseph Hull William Glover
Thomas Bacon John Breame of Ash John Beddingfeild Henry Stebbing William Guavas Francis Harvey and Thomas
Tont Esquires Edmond Bedingfeild John Spencer Phillip Gourden Thomas Vesy Allen Cotton Edmond Plomb
Robert Plomb Stephen Morley Benjamin Tany John Hall Charles Cocke Edward Bence Thomas Roper William
Brand of Polstead Richard Vesey Edmond Sheppard Edmond Gardiner Robert Browneing Paul Buckenham Richard
Cutts Esquires William Cullum William Cooke Robert Meene Thomas Hayes Adam Budle Nicholas Bragg Joseph
Beaumont John Lambe John Beaumont Thomas Darcy John Hill Phillip Haward John Jermey John Gurdon Robert
Sparrow Thomas Smith John Buxton Thomas Colvell alias Covell and Thomas Rivett Robert Maidstone Framlingham
Gaudy Edward Bohun Bassingborne Gaudy Robert Duke Ptollimy Talmach Charles Gaudy Thomas Mighills James
Wild Samuell Pacy Gentlemen Wentworth Garnish Esquire John Porter junior Gentleman Anthony Friston Gerrard
Russell Esquires Wickstead Weld John Gurling Henry Johnson junior William Coe Gentleman Samuell Baker Thomas
Barker Esquires John A&bholigct;on James Colthrope William de Gray Edmond Jenny Robert Naunton Roger Kerrington
Jacob Garrard Edward Alpe Tyrrell Prettiman Robert Myn Thomas Leman John Blomfeild Ambrose Kerrington
Esquires Joseph Crane Gent..</para>
		<para id="p231">For the Towne of Sudbury</para>
		<para id="p232">The Maior of Sudbury for the time being Sir Gervas Elwes Sir Robert Cordell Baronets Gervas Elwes Esquire
John Catisby John Cooke Joseph Wood Daniell Cooke John Gibbon Richard Hubbert Gentlemen Do&bholigct;or Butcher
William Harell John Fothergell Benjamin Carter Samuell Pannell senior Coxe Richard Waite junior.</para>
		<para id="p233">For the Towne of Dunwich</para>
		<para id="p234">The Bayliffes of Dunwich for the time being Sir Phillip Skippon Knight Thomas Allen John Boneface Thomas
Tookley Thomas Grey Thomas Goddard Henry Bedingfeild Samuell Driver Jonas Munnings Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p235">For the Towne of Ipswich</para>
		<para id="p236">The Bayliffes of Ipswich for the time being John Wright Gilbert Linfeild Esquires Thomas Edgar Recorder Charles
Wright Henry Gosnord John Pimberton Lawrence Stistead Richard Phillips Robert Clerke Gent..</para>
		<para id="p237">For the Towne of St Edmonds-bury</para>
		<para id="p238">The Alderman for the time being Sir John Duncombe Sir Thomas Harvey Knights William Duncombe Thomas
Holland Thomas Shelley Esquires John Sotheby Recorder Thomas Coell [James<ref idref="n66">66</ref>] Clarke Esquires James Cobb Francis
Browne Robert Sharpe Mathew Warren Thomas Hustler Nicholas Batley Martin Spenceley Gentlemen Sir Thomas
Culham Baronet John Rotherham Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
		<para id="p239">For the Towne of Aldburrough</para>
		<para id="p240">The Bayliffes for the time being Sir Richard Haddocke Knight Henry Johnson Esquire John Bedingfeild Recorder
John Browne John Woodruffe Thomas Wall John Bence John Burrowes Alexander Osborne Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p241">For the Towne of Orford</para>
		<para id="p242">The Maior for the time being Lyonell Lord Huntingtower of the Kingdome of Scotland Sir John Duke Baronet Sir
Charles Gaudy Knight and Baronet Henry Parker Henry Parker junior Esquires Thomas Hastings Joseph Hastings
Edward Edwin Thomas Johnson Copin Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p243">For the County of Surrey.</para>
		<para id="p244">Anthony Bryan Esquire High Sheriffe for the County Charles Earle of Ancram of the Kingdome of Scotland
Francis Earle of Longford of the Kingdome of Ireland, Lord Huntingtower of the Kingdome of Scotland James
Lord Annesley Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Anglesey Sir Edward Thurland one of the Barons of
the Exchequer Bernard Greenvile Francis Coventry Esquires Sir Henry Capell Knight of the Bath Sir Walter St
John Baronet Sir Thomas Whitmore Sir Fr: Vincent Sir Adam Browne Sir Will: Moore Sir Marmaduke Gresham
Sir Nicholas Staughton Sir Edward Bromfeild Sir Phillip Mathews Baronets Sir William Terringham Knight of the
Bath Sir John Nicholas Knight of the Bath Sir William Morley Knight of the Bath Sir Edmond Bowyer Sir
William Haward Sir Thomas Foster Sir Richard Mason Sir(<ref idref="n67">67</ref>) Thomas Bludworth Sir Nicholas Carew Sir William
Haskins Sir Stephen Leonard Sir Allen Brodericke Sir Thomas Clarges Sir Edward Evelin Sir Mathew Andrewes
Sir Henry Tulse Sir Edward Bish Sir Robert Knightley Sir John Shorter Sir James Butler Sir Robert Clayton
Sir Richard How Sir Robert Hatton Sir James Rushout Sir Edward Winter Knights William Mountague Esquire
Francis Howard Ambrose Browne junior of Bechworth Castle Arthur Onslow George Evelin of Wootton George
Chute senior Christopher Buckley Will; Elyot Edward Prodgier Thomas Dalmahoy Edward Harvey Roger James
George Evelin of Nutfeild James Zouch Ralph Freeman Thomas Turgis John Lewkner Richard Onslow Deane
Goodwin Anthony Thomas Edward Gresham Segismond Stidolfe John Weston of Ockham Edward Thurland
George Woodroffe George Vernon Anthony Bowyer Denzell Onslow James Gresham Peter Rich Ambrose Muschampe
Phillip Hildeyard George Smith John Thynne William Haward Robert Cooke Edward Woodward Daniell Sheldon
William Vanburgh Stephen Harvey Samuell Rous Marke Hildesley Thomas Lee George Chute junior James Clerke
Peter Hussey Richard Heath Henry Byne of Casholton Samuell Howland Walter Howland Francis Brend Thomas
Jenner John Covert In wood Thomas Arden Thomas Newton John Jorden John Parker Henry Byne
John Heather Phillip Rawleigh John Burgoyne John Morris John Mountenay Ralph Halsey John Glynne John
Sands Esquires John Glyde Ellis Crispe Tho: Bridges Tho: Moore of Egham Tho: Barker Rich: Garth John
Thynne junior Edmond Sherman William Hatton Francis Buller James Reading Francis Gerrard William Hawkins
Robert Gavell Richard Dalton Robert Moore of Egham John Lugg Captaine William Perry Esquires The Maior
of Gildford for the time being Francis Darrington John Wight Thomas Foster Richard Coldehan of Downe
Farme Esquires John Freeman Richard Hutton Peter Daniell Joseph Cooleing Thomas Syderfin Esquires John
Childe Richard Sims John Spencer William Hill of Guldeford Gentlemen John Grant William Casteele Esquires
Thomas Locke Richard Haleman Nicholas Fenn Thomas Benson Gentlemen Henry Thompson Esquire John Bind
of Camberwell George Smith Robert Wilson Gentlemen William Salmon John Snell Symon Smith Edward Ball
Gentlemen The Bayliffes of Farnham for the time being Walter [Halchor<ref idref="n68">68</ref>] of Croydon Cutler of Yewell
George Wrath Rich White of Farnham John Gainsford senior John Gainsford junior John Halfall Thomas Evans
Thomas Caustin John Turner John Terrey John Cooper Rich: Jewell of Nutfeild Ralph Drake William Hester
Joseph Reeve John Page Gervase Locke Jonadab Balaam William Worneham John Mason William Pigott Gentlemen
Anthony Smith Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke of Kingston William Hatton White Titchborne Esquire George Coleham of
Waverley Gentleman Mr George Osborne.</para>
		<para id="p245">For the County of Sussex</para>
		<para id="p246">John Tufton Richard Tufton Thomas Tufton William Ashburnham Esquires Sir John Pelham Sir Cecill Bishop
Sir Adam Browne Sir Henry Ge[e<ref idref="n69">69</ref>]reing Sir William Thomas Sir John Stapdley Sir John Fagg Sir Denny Ashburnham
Sir Anthony Sherley Sir William Wilson Sir Robert Parker Sir Thomas Duke Sir Richard Ashfeild Baronets Sir
William Mooreley Knight of the Bath Sir Nicholas Stroude Sir Thomas Woodcocke Sir George Courthop Sir
Nicholas Pelham Sir James Norton Sir Christopher Conyers Knights Thomas Pelham Thomas Sackvile John
Lewkner Walter Bartlet Robert Edmonds William Board Henry Goreing John Ashburnham Nisell Rivers Percy
Goreing Robert Fagg William Mooreley Richard Bridger Edward Nicholbourne Richard Onslow Thomas Midleton
Anthony Eversfeild John Alford Simon Smith Robert Palmer William Westbrooke Ralph Mills Thomas May
Richard May Robert Anderson James Butler Thomas Smith John Steward Thomas Gray Henry Shelley Harburt
Stapeley Richard Sherley John Millington Walter Dobell Peter Courthop Thomas Beard Edward Selwin Henry
Bishop John Spena Sackvile Graves William Duke Edward Payne John Baker senior Edward Polhill Richard
Payne Roger Shoyswell Robert Fowle Thomas Fruen John Busbridge Thomas Peirce Thomas Collins Nicholas
Towneley William Peckham Joseph King Christopher May Phillip Packer Timothy Burrell Esquires Nicholas
Eversfeild Edward Chowne John Gratwicke William Sorasse John Backshall senior John Backshall junior John
Mitchell Robert Mitchell Bray Chowne John Machell William Palmer Thomas Garraway Thomas Gratwicke John
Cumber Richard Nash Francis Mose Walter Cole Thomas Betsworth Thomas Palmer Esquires Richard Cooper
Thomas Young George Gunter Thomas Bickley Richard Peckham John Peckham of Crockerhill Thomas Peckham
William Lane John Oliver John Baker junior Edward Sheppard John Fuller Peter Farden Peter Gott Thomas
Briggs Robert Johnson William Young John Cobden Edward Dine Thomas Mouns Thomas Bromfeild senior
Thomas Bromfeild junior John Cheale senior John Cheale junior Lawrence Alcocke John Cooke Peter Farnden
Thomas Burrell Gentlemen The Maior of Chichester The Maior of Arundell The Maior of Hastings The Maior
of Rye The Maior of Winchelsea for their times being The Bayliffe of Seaford The Bayliffe of Pevensey The
Bayliffe of Midhurst for their times being Oliver Weekes Peregrine Palmer Francis Dorrington Jeffery Amhurst
Esquires William Peatchy of Petsworth John Petsworth John Polhill of Frenches Henry Apesly [John Langford
George Alfred<ref idref="n70">70</ref>] William Elson senior William Elson junior Gent. William Burrey Thomas Gunter Captaine Penford
John Braman John Farrington Rich: Farrington Orlando Gee Rob: Austin Barnham Dobell Humphrey Fowle
Alexander Farmer William Kempe Thomas Henshaw Robert Heath Apsley Newton Esquires John Stone senior
John Stone junior George Mills John Higgambottom Nicholas Best William [Baker<ref idref="n71">71</ref>] Henry Byne John Smith of
Waldron John Gee Thomas Paller George Goreing Edward Staker Peter Guard William Pechey Conyers
Richardson Richard [Helmes<ref idref="n72">72</ref>] Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p247">For the County of Warwicke</para>
		<para id="p248">Charles Lord Clifford Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Burlington William Lord Allington of the
Kingdome of Ireland Lord Digby of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Francis Compton Knight Anchitell
Grey Thomas Coventry Charles Leigh Esquires Sir Robert Holt Sir Richard Temple Sir Henry Puckering alias
Newton Sir John Tufton [Sir Edward Boughton Sir John Mordant<ref idref="n73">73</ref>] Sir John Burgoine Sir Clement Fisher Sir Francis
Lawley Sir John Bridgeman Sir John Knightley Sir Thomas Price Sir Theophilus Biddulph Sir John Hubbond
Sir Thomas Norton Sir Thomas Dolman Sir Charles Wheeler Sir Orlando Bridgeman Sir Richard Nudigate Baronets
Sir William Bromley Knight of the Bath Sir Adderley Sir Charles Lee Sir Arthur Caley Sir William
Underhill Sir Richard Hopkins Sir John Clopton Sir Samuell Marrow Sir Andrew Hackett Sir Will: Jesson Sir
Josiah Childe Sir William Bishop Knights Thomas Thynne Robert Burdett Thomas Lucy John Ferrers Thomas
Arthur Sebret Kepington Richard Hopkins John Rowse Thomas Fisher Francis Fisher Richard Boughton of Bilton
Richard Verney senior of Kingston John Coomes Walter Chetwin Ardin Bagot Henry Ferrers Thomas Rawlins
Charles Newsham Hastings Ingram Thomas Wagstaffe John Chamberlin John Newsham Thomas Corbin Fredericke
Blewston Adolphus Oughton senior George Devereux Henry Greene Basill Fielding Thomas Fetherston Richard
Shugburgh Henry Parker William Coleman Arden Adderley Humphry Jenings George Sacheverill Edward Bentley
James Prescott William Loggins Richard Eedes Nathaniell Stoughton [Richard<ref idref="n74">74</ref>] Hinton Henry Mathews Esquires
Thomas Marriott John Stratford Esquires William Perkins John Snell Thomas Keite John Ludford Esquires Thomas
Millard Edward Harvey William John Rugley William Bolton The Maior of Warwicke for the time
being The Maior of Stratford for the time being The Bayliffes of Tamworth for the time being.</para>
		<para id="p249">For the City and County of the City of Coventry.</para>
		<para id="p250">The Maior for the time being Sir Clement Fisher Sir Thomas Norton Baronets Sir Richard Hopkins Serjeant at
Law Sir Arthur Caley Sir Robert Townsend Sir William Jesson Knights Richard Hopkins John Dugdale Robert
Beake Humphry Lowe Henry Greene Edward Taylor John Bowater Esquires William Jelliffe Joseph Chambers
James Nailor Ralph Phillips Nathaniell Harryman John Woodbridge Aldermen Thomas Wagstaffe Henry Smith
Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p251">For the County of Worcester</para>
		<para id="p252">Master Secretary Coventry Tho: Lord Folliott of the Kingdome of Ireland Other Windsor Esquire John Coventry
Esquire Sir John Packington Sir Henry Litleton Sir Francis Russell Sir Edward Seabright Sir William Kyte Sir
Thomas Cookes Baronets Sir James Rushout Knight and Baronet Sir Rowland Berkley Sir John Winford Sir John
Talbott Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir John Barnaby Sir Francis Winnington Knights Collonell Samuell Sandys
John Packington Samuell Sandys junior Thomas Savage senior Thomas Savage junior Henry Herbert James Pitt
Henry Jefferies William Bromley Robert Berkley Edward Carew Joseph Walsh Thomas Childe Henry Townsend
senior Richard Couling William Swift Thomas Streete Serjeant at Law Edward Dingley Leonard Simpson Litleton
Clent Thomas Vernon of Astwood Richard Lygon Edward Parteridge William Sheldon Walter Savage Thomas
Jolliffe Thomas Simons Giles Parsons Anthony Sambage Henry Bromley of Upton Henry Townsend junior Phillip
[Poley<ref idref="n75">75</ref>] Henry Winford Higens James Capell Hanbury Thomas Harris Robert Foley Goddard Carter Edmond
Lechmore Henry Evett William Washborne Henry Spiller Thomas Watson William Lygon Broome Whorwood
Thomas Bushell Nicholas Barnaby Francis Sheldon Thomas Haslewood Thomas Stevens John Bearcroft Bridges
Nanfan Thomas Vernon Henry Parker Gerrard Dannett Martin Sandis Richard Nash Thomas Turvey William
Dowdeswell Richard Dowdeswell Thomas Barker Marke Dingley Thomas Foley Esquires Humphrey Perrott junior
John Newport John Clutton William Garrett Kemp Harwood Thomas Martin senior Edward Feild senior Gentlemen
The Bayliffes of Droitwich for the time being The Maior of Evesham for the time being The Bailiffe of Bewdley
for the time being.</para>
		<para id="p253">For the City and County of the City of Worcester.</para>
		<para id="p254">The Maior Aldermen and Sheriffes for the time being Sir John Packington Baronet Collonell Samuell Sandys
Sir Francis Winington Knight Sir Rowland Berkley Knight Thomas Streete Serjeant at Law Thomas Vernon Esquire
Richard Beddow Henry Taylor John Bearcroft William Norris William Swift Nicholas Baker Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p255">For the County of Wilts.</para>
		<para id="p256">The Right Honourable Richard Lord Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland Henry Lord Coleraine of the same
Kingdome Anthony Lord Ashley Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Shaftesbury Thomas Herbert Edward
Howard The Right Honourable Edward. Seymour and Henry Powle Esquires Sir John Ernle Knight Chauncellor
of the Exchequer of His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Sir Walter Saint John Sir John Button Sir
William Estcourt Sir Richard Grubham How Sir Seymour Pile Sir Joseph Ash Sir Walter Ernle Sir Walter Longe
Sir James Long Sir George Speeke Baronets Sir John Coventry Sir Edward Hungerford Sir John Nicholas and
Sir Edward Baynton Knights of the Bath Sir John Evelin Sir John Talbott Sir George Hungerford Sir Thomas
Mompesson Sir Thomas Estcourt the elder Sir Thomas Estcourt the younger Sir Stephen Fox Sir Richard Harrison
Sir Henry Coker Sir Mathew Andrewes Sir Francis Chaplin Sir Giles Hungerford Sir John Saint Low Sir Edward
Loe Knights Thomas Thinne George Pitt Lawrence Hyde Richard Lewis Henry Saint John Richard How George
Cooper Francis Wroughton the elder Robert Hyde Francis Pile John Pleydell William Glanvile John Hall William
Eyre William Brounker William Duckett Ralph Freake George Ayliffe Thomas Bennet George Bond Edmond
Warnford Edward Nicholas of Maningford Thomas Mompesson Bernard Pawlett William Ash Alexander Thistlewaite
Maurice Bocland Oliver Calley Thomas Lambert John Harrison Walter Ernle Charles Fox John Windham John
Smith of Tidworth Richard Aldworth Charles Rawleigh John Collins George Low Jeffery Daniell Edward Goddard
of Standen Thomas Gore William Trenchard William Hodges George Johnson Giles Eyre the elder Samuell Eyre
William Swanton Henry Clerke the younger Giles Eyre the younger Thomas Chamberlaine Giles Estcourt John
Scroope Nevill Maskline Francis Goddard Robert Drew John Bowles Thomas Penruddocke Robert Chaundler
Thomas Pile Peter Dove John Hungerford Oliver Nicholas Henry Wallis Edmond Webb Richard Chaundler John
Danvers John Deane Edward Nott John Ash Michaell Ernle Samuell Ash Thomas Goddard of Swinden Thomas
Clerke John Mervin William Chaffin Thomas Chaffin John Norden William Norbourne John Hawkins Henry
Webb John Mompesson Francis Hill Lawrence Swanton Edward Goddard of Ogborne Abian Stoakes Charles
Tooker Benjamin Gifford John Fitzherbert Thomas Bennett Edmond Hungerford Gabriell Ashley John Brooke
William Hearst John Wallis of Westwood Charles Yorke Ephraim Westley William Brounker Richard Greene
John Hippesley John Young Hope Long Thomas Harris Richard Poore John Jacob Thomas Dennett the elder
Francis Stonehouse Robert Foyle Richard Goddard Mathew Bennett Chr: Willoughby Chr: Pitt Edward Duke
George Duke of Sarum George of Lake Henry Chivers Thomas Long Giles Litcott Thomas Dove Edward Nicholas
Thomas Chitle James Lynch Anthony Hungerford John Wadman Robert Compton William Hewes Walter Norborne
Charles Danvers Walter Grubb Henry Skillin William George William Willoughby William Barker Nathaniell
Knight and John Bigg Esquires David Thomas Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke James Bennett James Georges Walter Perkin
of Lishill William Levett John Bigg George Sadler William Grinfeild Michell Beach Richard Hunt William
Gauntlett John Gauntlett William Turner Nicholas Elliott Edward Hoburrough James Phipps Thomas Mitchell
Thomas Rolt John Bennett Hitchcocke of White Parish Jona[than<ref idref="n76">76</ref>] Rivett Peregrine Thistlewaite Nicholas
Greene Thomas Goddard of Rudloe John Yerbury John Curle William Ivy Walter Greene Thomas Stump John
Smith the younger Nathaniell Trotman Charles Bowles John King Edward Dobney Charles Rayman
Hancocke Christopher Potticor and Jonathan Rogers Gentlemen with the Maiors of Wilton and the Devizes and
Marleburrough for the time being.</para>
		<para id="p257">For the Citty of New Sarum.</para>
		<para id="p258">James Harris Maior and The Maior for the time being William Swanton Esquire Recorder Sir Thomas Mompesson
Knight Alexander Thistlewaite Esquire Giles Eyre Esquire Deputy Recorder Edward Edmonds Thomas Cutler senior
William Viner senior Thomas Williams Christopher Gardiner James Bennett William Smith John Priaulx Thomas
Keynton Giles Nash and Oliver Shergold Aldermen David Thomas Doctor of Phisicke John Windham William
Hearst Thomas Chaffin James Harris Francis Hill Gabriell Ashley and Lawrence Swanton Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p259">For the County of Westmorland</para>
		<para id="p260">John Tufton Richard Tufton Esquires Sir Richard Musgrave Sir William Dalston Sir George Fletcher Sir John
Lowther of Lowther Sir John Lowther of Sockebridge Baronets Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir John Otway Knights
John Dalston James Bellingam Allen Bellingham Knight of the Shire Anthony Lowther Daniell Fleming Richard
Lowther Robert Hilton Edward Wilson William Sandford William Fleming Henry Wilson Thomas Fletcher Thomas
Hilton Christopher Dalston Christopher Phillipson Roger Moore Edward Musgrave Lancelott Mawchell Thomas Gebetis
Esquires Thomas Lamplugh John Fisher Esquires George Fothergill Robert Brathwaite Christopher Teasdell James
Bird Reynald Dobson Gentlemen The Maiors of Apleby and Kendall for the time being.</para>
		<para id="p261">For the County of Anglesey</para>
		<para id="p262">Robert Lord Bulkley Viscount Cassells of the Kingdome of Ireland Richard Bulkley Thomas Bulkley Henry
Bulkley Esquires Sir Hugh Owen Sit Roger Mostin Baronets Nicholas Bagnall John Glynn John Robinson William
Meyricke John Griffith Llanvachley Robert Roberts William Williams Thomas Holland David Lloyd Lloydiart
William Bulkley Conisby Williams Owen Hughes John Owen Pencoes Edward Wynne Rowland White Howell Lewis
Esquires Henry Jones Henry Davies John Price Robert Parry John Owen Llanvaithly Thomas Mostin Hugh Williams
David Williams William Robarts Caeree Owen Williams John Hughes William Griffith Richard Edwards Gentlemen
The Maior of Beaumaris for the time being.</para>
		<para id="p263">For the County of Brecon</para>
		<para id="p264">Thomas Bulcott Esquire High Sheriffe of the said County Charles Lord Herbert of Ragland Sonne and Heire
apparent to the Marquesse of Worcester Sir Walter Williams Baronet Sir Thomas Williams Baronet William Morgan
of Therow Esquire Richard Williams Esquire Thomas Lane Esquire John Ashburnham Esquire Rowland Gwynne
Esquire John Jefferies Esquire Lewis Morgan Esquire Edward Proger Esquire Thomas Mansell Esquire Edmond
Jones Esquire William Le Hunt Thomas Lewis Marmaduke Lloyd Thomas Walker Thomas Williams Walter Vaughan
Guynne Vaughan Hugh Powell William Morgan of Newton John Williams John Stedman Edward Games Henry
Proger Richard Guynne Marmaduke Guynne Daniell Williams Walter Williams Jasper Meller James Watkins Edward
Williams Robert Lucy John Walbiefe Thomas Bowen Rees Penry Walter Williams Henry Williams of Langonider
Henry Rumsey John Morgan Barzailli Jones William Vaughan John Gunter Rees Price John Guynne John Waters
Lodowicke Lewis Phillip Parry Edward Herbert Esquires Henry Vaughan Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Lewis Jones William
Morgan of Longeney William Bowen senior Lewis Gunter Lluellin Jenkins Charles Powell Thomas Williams of
Abercamlais junior Samuell Pritchard Samuell Williams William Saunders Hugh Powell of Glynn William Lloyd
Thomas Price of Glynn John Powell of Penkelley Richard Williams of Aberbrane Morgan Price William Lloyd of
Llandhewircoom William Jones of Hepstey Richard Jones Gentlemen Godfrey Harcourt Hugh Penrey Coroners.</para>
		<para id="p265">For the Towne of Brecon</para>
		<para id="p266">John Waters Esquire and The Bayliffe for the time being James Jones Esquire Recorder or the Recorder for
the time being John Jefferies Esquire William Philips [Towne Clerke<ref idref="n77">77</ref>] Rees Penry Lodowicke Lewis Esquires William
Thomas Richard Jones John Price Saunder Saunders Howell Williams Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p267">For the County of Cardigan</para>
		<para id="p268">Edward James Esquire High Sheriffe of the said County Sir Thomas Price of the Lodge Baronet Edward
Vaughan of Transcoed He&bholigct;or Phillips of Cardigan Morgan Herbert of Havod Thomas Price of Lanfread Hugh
Griffith of Urglaugh James Jones of Abermaid Walter Lloyd of Almarch Erasmus Lloyd of Mabus Thomas Lloyd
of Castell Howell Thomas Lloyd of Richo Arthen Thomas Powell of Lechweth Diris Thomas Lewis of Coedmore
Watkin Lloyd of Wern Newith Thomas Lloyd of Bromeith Cornelius Lebrune of Nant Eos John Lewis of Girnos
Thomas Jenkins of Dyffrin Lynod John Lloyd of Kilgwin John Williams of Abernantbican John Herbert of
Gagartham Morgan Lloyd of Greene Grove Thomas Knowles of Unisheare Esquires Richard Lloyd of Mabus
Francis Vaughan John Price of Randhir Richard Lewis of Pantiridin Morgan Lloyd of Foes Heleg Gentlemen
The Maior of Cardigan for the time being James Lloyd Esq[uire] John Morris Mathew Griffiths Arthur Bateman Henry
Stedman He&bholigct;or Morgan Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p269">For the County of Carmarthen</para>
		<para id="p270">John Lord Vaughan Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Carbery Altham Vaughan Esquire Ralaigh Mansell
Esquire High Sheriffe of the said County Sir Edward Mansell Sir Sackvile Crow Sir Rice Rudd Sir William Russell
Baronets Sir Rice Williams Baronet Richard Vaughan of Taracoed Walter Vaughan of Llanally John Ashburnham
John Vaughan of Court Derlisk John Vaughan of Place Gwynn William Guynn Rowland Guynn of Taliaris
Thomas Lloyd of Porlandowill Owen Bridgestocke of Llandaby William Bridgestock of [Llightoony<ref idref="n78">78</ref>] Christopher
Midleton Richard Jones of Tregibb William Wogan John Powell Edward Vaughan of Penybanck Richard Bloome
Thomas Williams of Talley Richard Vaughan of Derlis James Jones of Delacothy William Bevans of Penycoyd
Richard Gwynne of Guempa Roger Manwairing Walter Midleton John Lloyd of Llanlowthog John Morgan Griffith
Lloyd Richard Brett John Williams of Aberchoy Thomas Lloyd of Alti Cadnow Thomas Gwynn of Kanordy
Esquires James Prothero of Hawkesbrooke Christmas Vaughan John Lloyd of Frood William Brigstocke of Castle
Piggin Arthur Guynne of Pyod Charles Phillips of Lletty Garriard John Evans of Treventy Francis Price of
Llaneddy Henry Owen of Glaswalt Jonathan Scurlock Thomas Davis of Newton Owen Bowen Hugh Jones of
Llanelly William Williams of Ystradwralt Henry Vaughan of Trimsaran Walter Morgan Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p271">For the Towne of Carmarthen</para>
		<para id="p272">The Maior for the time being John Lord Vaughan Sonne and Heire apparent to the Earle of Carbery of the
Kingdome of Ireland Altham Vaughan Esquire John Lloyd Towne Clerke Walter Vaughan of Llanelley Esquire
John Vaughan of Court Derlles Richard Vaughan Esquire of the same John Vaughan of Placegwyn Thomas Jones
Dawkins Goffe Richard Thomas Robert Lewis John Oakley Thomas Bynon William Brigstock John Williams
Richard Lee Aldermen Henry Vaughan Jonathan Scurlocke Martin Bynon Edward Jones David Jones George Lewis
Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p273">For the County of Caernarvan</para>
		<para id="p274">Robert Lord Viscount Bulkley of the Kingdome of Ireland Lord Willoughby Richard Bulkley Robert
Roberts Thomas Bulkley Esquires Sir John Wynne Sir Roger Mostin Sir Robert Williams Baronets Sir Robert Owen
Knight Thomas Mostin Nicholas Bagnall William Griffith of Llyne Griffith Vaughan Robert Wynn Thomas
Vaughan John Wynne Robert Coytmore Griffith Wynn Hugh Williams William Bulkley John Wynn Barthaer
Thomas Madrin John Wynne Tu Guyn Richard Anvill John Glyn Conisby Williams Richard Griffith Robert Hookes
Owen Wynn Richard Kiffin William Pricherch Lewis Merricke Robert Wynn William Wynn Llananda Holland
Williams Hugh Bodurda Thomas Wynn William Glynn Randall Wynn William Wynn of Wern Esquires William
Archer Hugh Lewis Owen Barry Richard Edwards William Lloyd Robert Gethin John Owen Hugh Owen William
Griffith of Madrin Issa Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p275">For the County of Denby</para>
		<para id="p276">Hedd Lloyd Esquire High Sheriffe of the said County Sir John Wynn Knight and Baronet Sir John Salisbury
Sir Walter Baggot Sir Thomas Powell Sir Thomas Midleton Sir Evan Lloyd Baronets Sir Roger Mostin Knight and
Baronet Sir William Neale Sir Thomas Jones one of His Majestyes Justices of the Kings Bench Sir Robert Agburrough
Sir John Trevor Sir Kenrick Eaton and Sir Robert Owen Knights Thomas Powell Thomas Carter John Wynn John
Trevor of Trevalin John Langford Edward Vaughan of Lloydiarth John Robinson Mutton Davis Edward Brereton
Cadwallider Wynn John Thelwall Euble Thelwall William Williams Thomas Vaughan John Jeffreys Robert Wynn
of Bertsha William Price David Maurice of Pennyboate Edward Maurice of Llorraine Rich: Midleton of Chirke
Charles Midleton Francis Manley Owen Wynn William Parry Bevis Lloyd Owen Thelwall Mathew Price Robert
Price of [Gooler<ref idref="n79">79</ref>] Josuah Edisbury William Lloyd of Halton John Midleton Charles Goodman Richard Lloyd of
Segroyt Roger Mostin of Brimbo Hugh Roberts John Dolben John Maesmore Peirce Foulkes of Meriadocke John
Price of Vaynall Hugh Meridith Robert Wynn of Lanidlas John Lloyd of Bodidrist John Lloyd of Gwreech Thomas
Holland Yale of Yale William Vaughan of Bronhilogg William Jones Peter Foulkes of [Erviat<ref idref="n80">80</ref>] John
Chambers Richard Parry Thomas Rosandall Ellis Lloyd of Ruabon Edward Lloyd of Place Maddocke and Jasper
Peake Esquires Robert Wynn of Garthewin Howell Lloyd Euble Lloyd Robert Turbridge Thomas Lloyd of
Wrexam Edward Williams Robert Holland Ellis Sutton David Lloyd of Croes Onnen Henry Vaughan of Glynn
John Lloyd of Rossa John [Griffiths<ref idref="n81">81</ref>] John Edwards and Thomas Powell of Stansti Thomas Griffith Captaine Robert
Gething Owen Lloyd of Wickwer Thomas Lloyd of Keven John Lloyd of Brinn Lliciar William Morris of
Kenevy Braick John Winn of Venitid Thomas Pritchard David Lloyd of Llangollenvechan John Maddox John
Ashpoole John Midleton and John Powell of Llandernogg Edward Chambers David Williams Edwards
of Holt Parke Robert Cowley Captaine Robert Gething William Mores Richard Lloyd of Lanninus Humphrey
Wynne Robert Griffith of Brimbo The two Aldermen and two Bayliffes of Denbigh for the time being Edward
Davies Robert Roberts Foulke Davies Thomas Roberts Robert Edwards of [Psalyollin<ref idref="n82">82</ref>] Edward Lloyd of Dwyvaen
Robert Winn of Llangum David Lloyd of Kum and Rodericke Lewis Gentlemen The Maior of Holt for the
time being.</para>
		<para id="p277">For the County of Flint</para>
		<para id="p278">Edward Lloyd Esquire High Sheriffe of the said County Sir John Salsbury Sir John Hanmer Sir Thomas Grosvenor
Sir Evan Lloyd Sir Roger Mostin Sir [Evan<ref idref="n83">83</ref>] Glinn Baronets Sir John Trevor Sir Kenricke Eyton Sir Saint John.
Gwillim Knights William Hanmer John Trevor Thomas Mostin Thomas Lloyd Thomas Pindar William Price Thomas.
Hanmer Thomas Carter Robert Whitley Mutton Davies George Hope Roger Whitley Thomas Humphreys William.
Williams John Midleton Kenricke Eyton John Price Owen Wynn John Salsbury senior John Salsbury junior Piers
Pennant Charles Jones Thomas Eyton Thomas Edwards Peter Wynn Richard Parry Thomas Whitley Ralph Whitley
Thomas Griffith of Caervis Walter Clapton John Broughton Thomas Evans John Winn of Gopp William Griffith
Thomas Griffith of Mannereh Edward Morgan Ellis Young Thomas Whitley Edward Mostin Edward Evatt Thomas
Cratchley William Lloyd Luke Lloyd George Winn Owen Barton Edward Ravenscroft Jasper Peck John Lloyd of
Wellington Esquires John Whitley John Lloyd of Knolton John Griffith of Quibyr Josias Jones John Powell of
Kelstrim Edward Wynne Robert Lloyd of Caergurle Thomas Price Roger Williams Luke Lloyd junior William
Phillips John Mathews Robert Griffith of Pengwern William Rutter William Butler John Lloyd of Wickner Roger
Jones Peter Pritchard Gentlemen Robert Conway and Griffith Williams Esquires.</para>
		<para id="p279">For the County of Glamorgan</para>
		<para id="p280">Charles Lord Herbert of Ragland Sonne and Heire Apparent to the Marquisse of Worcester Thomas Streete
Serjeant at Law and Owen Winn Esquire His Majestyes Justices of the Great Session Thomas Gibbon Esquire
High Sheriffe of the said County Sir Edward Mansell Sir Edward Stradling Sir Robert Thomas Sir Charles Kemys
Sir John Awberry Barronets Sir Leoline Jenkins Knight Evan Seyes Serjeant at Law William Morgan Richard Lewis
John Ashburnham Thomas Lewis Richard Bassett William Herbert Humphrey Windham David Jenkins John
Windham David Mathew Thomas Carne Thomas Stradling senior Collonell Thomas Stradling Lieutenant Collonell
Carne Major Humphrey Windham Francis Winn Oliver Jones John Avan Martin Button Richard Langhorne
William Thomas Edward Lewis John Bowen David Evans Walter Evans Bussy Mansell Marmaduke Gibbs Rowland
Dawkins Edmond Gamadge William Herbert Edmond Thomas Richard Seys William Seys George Bowen Miles
Mathew Captaine Edward Mathew Edward Mansell Thomas Mansell Thomas Mansell of Penrice Esquires Edward
Thomas Lewis Thomas Miles Button James Gwinn Thomas Bassett of Lanveythin Thomas Bassett of Bolston John
Price of Court Carney Jeremiah Dawkins Robert Bidder Thomas Price of Pengllwingare Leyson Evans George
Williams William Seys of Rheding Edward Carne of Cornetowne Thomas Longhor of Cownley Richard Jenkins
of Pantinawell James Turbervill Edward [Turberill<ref idref="n84">84</ref>] Edward Powell George Lucas William Awbrey of Pencoed Roger
Powell of Enar Glynn Iltid Nicholl Gentlemen John Llewellin Edmund Parker Corroners Thomas Williams
Benjamin Browne Esquires Bayliffes of [Cordiffe.<ref idref="n85">85</ref>]</para>
		<para id="p281">For the County of Merioneth</para>
		<para id="p282">Robert Winn of Mascanieth High Sheriffe of the said County Sir John Winn Knight and Baronet Sir John
Salusbury Baronet Sir Thomas Midleton Baronet Sir Roger Mostin Baronet Sir Robert Owen Knight Thomas
Mostin Griffith Vaughan William Price Owen Salusbury Edward Vaughan Owen Wynn of Glynn John Lloyd of
Maesy Pandy Richard Anwill William Pugh Lewis Owen William Williams of Glascoed Vincent Corbett Jenkin
Vaughan of Caethly John Vaughon of Caergay John Wynn Owen Wynn of Mellay William Parry Ellis Young
John Lloyd junior Humphrey Hughes Owen Anwell John Lloyd of Ruedock Richard Mostin Richard Anwell John
Wynn of Comin Nathaniell Jones Hugh Tudor John Maesmore Griffith Lloyd of Mayce Pandy Lewis Lewis Edmond
Merricke Esquires Owen Eyton John Price Oliver Thomas William Vaughan of Caergay [Evan Evans Anthony
Thomas<ref idref="n86">86</ref>] Richard Anwell William Williams William Humphreys of Maerdie Griffith Vaughan of Dolmie Vinlin
Robert Price of Iskarnetha Robert Ellis Edward Winn Evan Lloyd of Rhiwgoch John Lloyd of Kevenvaice John
Lewis of Festiniogg John Lloyd of Ukon Robert Vaughon of Kironooch Lewis Owens of Havodtowell Maurice
Jones of Hendoor Ellis Davis William Owens John Morgan Gent..</para>
		<para id="p283">For the County of Mountgomery</para>
		<para id="p284">John Williams Esquire High Sheriffe of the said County Andrew Newport Esquire Sir Richard Corbett Sir John
Price Sir John Whitterong Sir Francis Lawley Baronets Sir Thomas Jones Sir Richard Mason Knights George
Devereux Edward Vaughan of Lloydiarth Edward Vaughan of Guernigo Will: Pugh of Matthaverne Edward Lloyd
of Berth Lloyd Edward Kenaston Robert Leighton William Oakley Richard Mostin of Doley Coeslin Richard Owen
of Rinsafen Edmund Wareing Henry Blaney Mathew Price of Parke Robert Owen of the Woodhouse David Morris
of Pennybont Sidney Godolphin of Broniarth Thomas Winde Arthur Weaver Arthur Weaver junior William Williams
Mathew Morgan John Mathews Edmond Lloyd of Trefnant David Powell Vincent Peirce Richard Stedman Rowland
Hunt Richard Miton John Wynn of Dolearthin Thomas Lloyd of Trowscord Esquires Thomas Thynne of Garth
William Eyton Robert Lee Thomas Morris of Treveddride Gentlemen Charles Herbert of Aston Charles Ninoe
Edward Lloyd of Matharavall Rowland Owen of Kinlooth Humphrey Lleyth John Lloyd of Llanhaven
Edward Price of Glumeheley Edward Barrett Richard Herbert of Kerrey Evan Glynn Esquires William Kiffin
Richard Glin of Guistride Thomas Mason John Oakley Thomas Hodson Edward Evans of Phiedgcarow Edward
Evans junior Evan Vaughan of Castlethinawh Sydney B&umacr;ller Evan Vaughan of Llantwilling Evan Evans of Cumy
Anett Hugh Davies of Colfrin Robert Price of Llanwelling Edward Herbert Richard Evans junior John Bright of
Mithington Meredith Lloyd of Breynellers Samuell Lloyd of Llantmichwood Edward Cun Rees Lloyd of Conney
Richard Ingram of Llanidlos John Wilson Richard Davies of Llenhilva William Penrin Arthur Vaughan Robert
Kenaston Evan Bowen of Colfrin John Thomas Llanvaire John Edwards Oliver Jones William Biggs William Mathews
of Guernedee Evan Jones John Reade John Griffiths of Glanhaverin Humphrey Jones of Poole Thomas Parry William
Pierce Daniell Whittingham Nicholas Wareing George Robinson Griffith Robinson Price Clunne Charles Jones of
Leighton John Vaughan of Mivod Humphrey Lloyd of Goitree William Lloyd of Finant Roger Trevor Morris Lloyd
of Henblaste William Derwas Robert Evans of Llandirinio James Hanmer Robert Owen Gentlemen Henry Herbert
Francis Buller junior John Edwards of Rerington Esquires Edmond Jones of Llanvellen Nathaniell Kinaston Gent.
The Bayliffe [for<ref idref="n87">87</ref>] the Towne of Mountgomery for the time being George Llewelin Esquire Richard Owen junior of
Rhusason Edward Whittingham Roger Jones, Humphrey Jones of Garthmall David Price of Penstrowed William
Price of Gwestyd Lewis Price Henry Vaughan Edward Browne Randle Owen.</para>
		<para id="p285">For the County of Pembrooke.</para>
		<para id="p286">Sir Erasmus Phillips Sir John Stepneth Sir Hugh Owen Sir John Barlow Barronets Sir Herbert Perret Knight
Francis Phillips High Sheriffe of the said County Essex Merrick Lewis Parlow Arthur Owen Rowland Langhorne
Hugh Bowen He&bholigct;or Phillips Lewis Wogan of Boulston John [Owen of Treroone William Scurfeild Lewis<ref idref="n88">88</ref>] Wogan of
Wiston Griffith Dawes Thomas Howard Walter Midleton William Phillips William Wogan John Cannon William
Mordant David Williams Thomas Lloyd John Elliott Arthur Langharne Thomas Lort Thomas Owen Nathaniell
Powell John Thomas Richard Phillips John Barlow James Lloyd Griffith Hawkewell Henry Walter James Ap Rice
John Williams George Bowen Nicholas Adams Hugh Langharne William Owen David Morgan John Mathias William
Warren Lewis John William Meare David Morris Esquires George Lort Richard Cuney William Foard Thomas
Simmons John Phillips of Trelewellin William Bourne of Williamston Thomas Edwards John Wogan James
Langharne Reignald Howell Thomas Jones Jenkin Jones John Jordan John Meyrrick John Owen of Parshills Captaine
William Williams John Lewis William Skyrme William Lloyd of Trewent Thomas Jones of Panty Derry Gwin
Vaughan John Bell William Jones John Childe Robert Chambers The Maior of Pembrooke for the time being
Mathew Bowen George Powell Francis Rogers Gentlemen The Maior of Tenby for the time being Henry Jones
Devereux Hammond James Lloyd Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p287">For the Towne and County of Haverford West.</para>
		<para id="p288">John Williams Esquire Maior Edward Hughes Gentleman Sheriffe Sir Hugh Owen Sir Erasmus Phillips Sir John
Barlow Sir John Stepneth Baronets Sir Herbert Perrott Knight Lewis Wogan of Wiston Lewis Wogan of Boulston
Arthur Owen Thomas Cozens William Wogan Thomas Haward John Thomas Esquires John Barlow Gentlemen
Thomas Bowen John Bateman Lewis Barron and Robert Prust Aldermen Thomas Cozens John Fowler Benjamin
Twineing Thomas Wilkins George Lewis and Vincent Powell Gentlemen.</para>
		<para id="p289">For the County of Radnor</para>
		<para id="p290">Sir John Morgan Baronet Sir Edward Harley Knight of the Bath Thomas Vaughan Esquire High Sheriffe of the
said County Richard Fowler Henry Walcott Richard Williams Morrice Wynn Thomas Lewis senior Thomas Lewis
of Monaighty Thomas Hughes Rowland Gwinn Samuell Powell Thomas Harley Henry Probert Mathew Price
John Fowler Robert Lucy Bristock Harford Griffith Jones senior Edward Freemen Edward Price Nicholas Taylor
William Probert John James Edward Davies Nicholas Meredith James Lloyd John Walsam Thomas Lewis junior
Herbert Weston Marmaduke Grimes Hugh Powell Robert Cutler Thomas Howard Griffith Jones junior John Davies
Thomas Corbett Lewis of Headwall Esquires John Probert Henry Bull William Taylor John Lewis
Lloyd Weston Walter Vaughan Thomas Lewis Jeremiah Powell Thomas Powell Evan Vaughan. Edward Phillips
Gabriell Taylor Jonas Stephens Francis Richards William Morgan Evan Bowen Thomas Williams Thomas Griffith
Nehemiah Kitleby The Bayliffe of New Radnor and two Aldermen for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Commissioners to meet in the several Counties, &amp;c. on or before the 4th March 1679.</head>
		<para id="p291">
			<emph type="i">and may subdivide themselves</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p292">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the severall Commissioners aforesaid shall meete together at the
most usuall and common Place of Meeting within each of the said Countyes Cityes Burroughes Townes and
Places respe&bholigct;ively on or before the Fourth day of March One thousand six hundred seaventy and nine And the
said Commissioners or soe many of them as shall be present at the said First Generall Meeting or the major
part of them are hereby authorized and required to putt this A&bholigct; in Execution according to the best of their
Judgements and Discretions and shall then if they see cause subdivide and distribute themselves into lesser Numbers
as Three or more of the said Commissioners may be appointed for the Service of each Hundred or other Division
and as may best conduce to the carrying on of His Majestyes Service hereby required.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Commissioners at their Meeting to appoint Receiver General.</head>
		<para id="p293">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the Commissioners at their aforesaid first Generall Meeting or the major part
of them shall and are hereby authorized and required to nominate and appoint under their Hands and Seales an
honest able and responsible Person to be Receiver Generall for each County City or Division respe&bholigct;ively takeing
sufficient Security from such Receiver Generall in the Kings Name for His Majestyes Use.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. Receiver General to give Commissioners a Receipt for Monies received by him from them.</head>
		<para id="p294">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every Receiver Generall from time to time within
the space of one moneth next after he shall have received the full Summe that shall be charged upon any
Hundred or Division for each perticular Payment that is to be made to such Receiver Generall by vertue of
this A&bholigct; shall give to the Commissioners that shall a&bholigct; in such Hundred or Division a Receipt under his Hand
and Seale acknowledgeing his Receipt of the full Summe charged upon such Hundred or Division for such
particular Payment which Receipt shall be a full Discharge of such Hundred or Division for such particular
Payment against His Majestie His Heires and Successors</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. &pound;103, 231, 8s. 7&frac12;d. to be paid to Receiver General 24th May 1680.</head>
		<para id="p295">
			<emph type="i">&pound;103, 231. 8s. 7&frac12;d. Second Payment, 24th Aug. 1680.; Commissioners to deliver a Schedule of Sums assessed to Receiver General, to be transmitted by him to the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p296">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the summe of One hundred three thousand two
hundred thirty and one pounds eight shillings and seaven pence halfe penny being the first of the said two
quarterly Payments hereby imposed shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid unto the Receiver. Generall of the
said severall Countyes and Places on or before the Fower and twentieth day of May One thousand six hundred 
and eighty and the summe of One hundred three thousand two hundred thirty and one pounds eight shillings and
seaven pence halfe penny being the second of the said two quarterly Payments on or before the Fower and
twentyeth day of August in the said Yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and eighty. And the said
Commissioners are hereby required to deliver or cause to be delivered a Schedule or Note containeing the particular
Summes assessed [on<ref idref="n89">89</ref>] each Parish or Place to the Receiver Generall of each County City Burrough Towne or
Place respe&bholigct;ively to be by him the said Receiver Generall transmitted into the Kings Remembrancers Office in
the Exchequer within fifteene dayes after he shall have received the same</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. Money received by Colle&bholigct;ors to be paid to Receiver General, who is to give Notice to Commissioners of such Payment.</head>
		<para id="p297">
			<emph type="i">Receipt of Receiver General to be a Discharge</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p298">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authority aforesaid That the money received by the Colle&bholigct;ors
within the respe&bholigct;ive Divisions or Hundreds shall from time to time be duely paid to the Receiver Generall or to
his Deputy or Deputies to be appointed under his Hand and Seale whereof notice under the Hand and Seale of
the Receiver Generall shall be given [to<ref idref="n90">90</ref>] the Commissioners or any two of them within the respe&bholigct;ive Divisions
or Hundreds within Eight dayes after the first Generall Meeting and soe from time to time within Eight dayes
after every Death or Removeall of any Deputy if any such shall happen, and the Receipt of such Receiver
Generall his Deputy or Deputyes or any of them shall be a sufficient Discharge unto every such Colle&bholigct;or.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. Particular Colle&bholigct;ors to pay to Receiver General, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p299">
			<emph type="i">Not obliged to travel above Ten Miles for Payments.; Salary to Receiver General, &amp;c.; Regulations as to returning Duplicate of Assessment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p300">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the particular Colle&bholigct;ors are hereby required to pay in all and
every the Summes soe received by them unto the said Receivers Generall aforesaid or their Deputy or Deputies
for payment whereof the said Colle&bholigct;ors shall not be obliged to travell above Ten miles from the places of their
Habitations which said Receivers Generall are hereby required forthwith to transmitt or cause to be paid the
moneys by them received into the Receipt of the Exchequer And the Lord High Treasurer or Lords
Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being or any three or more of them are hereby authorized and
required to allow the said Receiver Generall of each County City and Towne respe&bholigct;ively in case he hath
returned up as aforesaid a Duplicate of the Assesments of each Parish or Place in the County City or Towne
for which he is appointed Receiver Generall a Salary for his Paines not exceeding Two pence in the Pound
upon the clearing of his Accompt which Duplicate soe to be returned into the said Receipt of the Exchequer is
to containe noe more then the Summes in grosse to be colle&bholigct;ed by each Colle&bholigct;or and the severall Names of
the said Colle&bholigct;ors</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>IX. Allowance to Colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
		<para id="p301">
			<emph type="i">Colle&bholigct;ors may detain Allowance.; Allowance to Commissioners' Clerks to be paid by Receiver General</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p302">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the Colle&bholigct;ors of each Parish or Place which shall be
appointed by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall upon Colle&bholigct;ion of the whole Summe appointed to be colle&bholigct;ed by them
and Payment thereof as is hereby before appointed have and receive for their Paines in colle&bholigct;ing and paying the
moneyes Fower pence in the Pound which the said Colle&bholigct;ors are impowered to detaine out of the last Payment
of the money of their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Two Quarterly Payments And the said Receiver Generall upon the
Receipt of the whole Assesment of the County City or Towne for which he is appointed Receiver Generall in
case he hath received the severall Duplicates of each Parish or Place therein and not otherwise shall allow and
pay according to such Warrant as shall be in that behalfe given by the said Commissioners or any three or more
of them One penny in the Pound for the Commissioners Clerkes for their Paines in faire Writeing the Assesments
Duplicates and Copies.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s10">
		<head>X. Places to be assessed as heretofore.</head>
		<para id="p303">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid That for the avoiding of
all Obstru&bholigct;ions and Delayes in colle&bholigct;ing the Summes by this A&bholigct; to be rated and assessed all Places Offices
Constablwicks Divisions and Allotments shall pay and be assessed in such County Hundred Place Rape Division
or Wapentake according to the like Proportions and Distributions in respe&bholigct; to this present Assesment as they were
assessed and taxed by the said recited A&bholigct;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s11">
		<head>XI. Receiver General and their Deputies to give Acquittances to Colle&bholigct;ors. without Fee.; such Acquittances to be a Discharge.</head>
		<para id="p304">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the severall Receivers Generall which
shall be appointed according to this A&bholigct; their Deputy or Deputyes shall from time to time at every Payment
appointed thereby give unto the severall Colle&bholigct;ors within their respe&bholigct;ive Precincts upon the Payment of the whole
Summe due at such times of Payment from their respe&bholigct;ive. Parishes Constablewicks or Places within each of
their Colle&bholigct;ions severall Acquittances under their Hands without takeing any thing for the same and that in
like manner at every time of Payment appointed by this A&bholigct; the Receiver Generall of each County his Deputy
or Deputyes shall give unto the severall Colle&bholigct;ors aforesaid upon the Payment of the whole Summe or any
part thereof due for their Parish or Place respe&bholigct;ively at each time of Payment aforesaid severall Acquittances
under their Hands and Seales without takeing any thing for the same which said Acquittances of every respe&bholigct;ive
Receiver Generall his Deputy or Deputyes shall be a sufficient Discharge to the Colle&bholigct;ors and to such Parish
and Place respe&bholigct;ively and to every Person charged within the said Colle&bholigct;ors Charge against His Majestie His
Heires and Successors for the Summe or Summes of Money soe acquitted.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s12">
		<head>XII. Treasury authorized, as herein mentioned, to issue Money granted by this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p305">
			<emph type="i">Persons lending Money on the Credit of this A&bholigct; to have Tally and Order for Repayment.; Interest at &pound;8 per Cent. per Ann</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p306">And whereas it will be necessary for the more speedy disbanding and paying off the said Forces soe raised
That Money should be borrowed upon the Credit of the said Two hundred six thousand fower hundred sixty
two pounds seaventeene shillings and three pence given by this A&bholigct; And that the issueing and paying thereof
out of His Majestyes Exchequer may be with the most Expedition for the Ends aforesaid Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the
Authoritie aforesaid That the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer of the Exchequer for the time being or the
Lords Commissioners of the Treasury now or for the time being or any Three or more of them shall and are
hereby authorized by Order or Warrant under their Hands without any Privy Seale or other Warrant from the
King his Heires or Successors to issue the Money by this A&bholigct; granted to such Person and Persons and according
to such Rules Orders and Dire&bholigct;ions as are hereby dire&bholigct;ed and appointed and not otherwise And that all and
every Person and Persons who shall lend any Money to His Majestie upon the Credit of the aforesaid Summe
of Two hundred six thousand fower hundred sixty two pounds seaventeene shillings and three pence and pay
the same into the Receipt of the Exchequer shall immediately and by vertue hereof have a Tally of Loane for
the same and an Order for Repayment beareing the same Date with the Tally with a Clause therein inserted for
the Payment of Interest for such money at the rate of Eight pounds per Centum by the yeare to be paid every
Three moneths untill the Repayment of the Principall which Order of Loane shall be in these words mutatis
mutandis that is to say</para>
		<para id="p307">
			<emph type="i">Form of Order of Loan</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p308">Order is by us taken this day of by vertue of an A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for granting
a Supply to His Majestie of Two hundred and six thousand foure hundred sixty two pounds seaventeene
shillings and three pence for paying off and disbanding the Forces raised since the Nine and twentyeth of
September One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven That you deliver and pay of such His Majestyes
Treasure as remaines in your Charge of the Summe of Two hundred six thousand fower hundred sixty two
pounds seaventeene shillings and three pence ariseing by vertue of the said A&bholigct; unto
or his Assignes the Summe of in Repayment of soe much Money by him lent unto His
Majestie upon the Credit of the said Summe of Two hundred six thousand fower hundred sixtie two pounds
seaventeene shillings and three pence and paid into the Receipt of His Majestyes Exchequer the said
day of as by a Tally leavyed at the Receipt of the Exchequer beareing Date the same day appeares
together with the Interest thereof at the rate of Eight pounds per Cent? per Ann? at the end of every Three
moneths untill the repayment of the Principall And these together with his or her Acquittance or the Acquittance
of his or her Assignee or Assignes shall be your Discharge therin.</para>
		<para id="p309">
			<emph type="i">If sufficient Money not advanced to pay Commission Officers what shall be due to them, Commissioners to give a Debenture on the Treasury for Payment, with Interest at &pound;8 per Cent. payable Quarterly</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p310">And that in case there shall not be money enough advanced by Loane to pay the Commission Officers what
shall be to them due upon stateing their Accompts the Commissioners appointed by this A&bholigct; for disbanding the
said Forces or any one or more of them are hereby authorized and required to give to (<ref idref="n91">91</ref>) the said Officers a
Certificate or Debenter under their or any of their Hands and Seales dire&bholigct;ed to the Lord Treasurer or Lords
Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being who shall thereupon by vertue of this A&bholigct; without any Privy
Seale or other Warrant from His Majestie His Heires or Successors give or cause to be given to every such
respe&bholigct;ive Officer or Officers an Order for the Payment of the Summe soe certified together with Interest for the
same after the rate of Eight pounds per Centum per Annum to be paid Quarterly from the day of the Date
of such Order untill the Payment of the money due thereupon.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s13">
		<head>XIII. If Money due for quartering Officers, &amp;c. cannot be paid, Commissioners to give a like Debenture on the Treasury, with Interest at &pound;8 per Cent. payable Quarterly.</head>
		<para id="p311">And in case the persons to whome money shall be due for Quartering of Officers or Souldiers or any of them
cannot be paid at the time of stateing the Accounts of the Debts due to such Persons by reason of the deficiency
of advance of Money by Loane as aforesaid the said Commissioners or any one or more of them are hereby
authorized and required to give to every of the said Persons or any other by them or any of them sufficiently
entrusted a like Certificate or Debenter under their or any of their Hands and Seales directed to the Lord
Treasurer or Lords Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being who shall thereupon by vertue of this
A&bholigct; without any Privy Seale or other Warrant give or cause to be given to such Person or Persons an Order
for the Payment of the summe soe certifyed together with Interest for the same after the rate of Eight pounds
per Centum per Annum to be paid Quarterly from the day of the date of such Order untill the payment of the
Money due thereupon.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s14">
		<head>XIV. After disbanding, Commissioners to make up an Account of Deductions for Clothing out of Pay, &amp;c.; and to distribute what shall remain unpaid, and make Certificate thereof to the Treasury, who shall thereupon order Payment, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p312">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That after the Forces shall be a&bholigct;ually disbanded the Commissioners for disbanding
the Forces or any two or more of them shall make up an Account with the Paymaster of the said Forces of all
such summes of Money as have beene by him dedu&bholigct;ed for Cloathes out of the pay of the Souldiers before the
First day of September last past together with [an<ref idref="n92">92</ref>] Account of what shall be by them the said Commissioners
since that time dedu&bholigct;ed from any Officer or Souldier for Cloathes and of what shall then appeare to them to
remaine unpaid to any person that furnished the same shall make a proportionable distribution to such person or
persons and make a Certificate or Debenter thereof to the Lord Treasurer or Lords Commissioners of the Treasury
for the time being in manner as aforesaid who shall thereupon by vertue of this A&bholigct; as aforesaid dire&bholigct; the
like Order for payment to such Person or Persons without any Clause for payment of Interest to be in such
Order inserted.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s15">
		<head>XV. Commissioners may examine and adjust Accounts with Officers and Persons who have delivered Clothes to Soldiers hereby discharged, and deduct what shall appear due, and make Certificate thereof.</head>
		<para id="p313">
			<emph type="i">Quarters of Soldiers being first discharged; the said Accounts to be stated before disbanding, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p314">And whereas there are severall Persons that have delivered Cloathes or other Necessaries to the Souldiers (by
this A&bholigct; to be discharged) for which they have the severall Officers Receipts for the same but have not as yet
obtained from the respe&bholigct;ive Officers Assignements upon the Paymaster Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the said
Commissioners or any two or more of them shall and may have power to examine adjust and make up the
Accompts as well with the respe&bholigct;ive Officers as with such Person or Persons before such Officers shall receive
their respe&bholigct;ive Orders and that what shall appeare to be really and bona fide due shall be dedu&bholigct;ed by the said
Commissioners and distributed to such Person or Persons and make such Certificate as aforesaid of the same as
if they had obtained Assignements from the respe&bholigct;ive Officers upon the Paymaster and in like manner the said
Commissioners shall dedu&bholigct; and keepe in their hands all such summe and summes of Money as shall appeare to
the said Commissioners under the hand of any Souldier to be due to his Officer and to pay the same to such
Officer the Quarters of such Souldier being first paid off and discharged according to such dire&bholigct;ion onely as
the Officer hath given to the Innekeeper or Landlord soe as the said Accompts betweene the Officer and Soldier
be stated before the day of disbanding and soe as such dedu&bholigct;ion shall be made onely out of the Pay due to
such Souldier and not out of the free guift hereby given.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s16">
		<head>XVI. Orders for Repayment of Loan entered according to Date of Tally.</head>
		<para id="p315">
			<emph type="i">Orders for Payment of Officers to be registeredin Course.; Persons to be paid in Course as their Orders stand entered.; Monies raised by Assessments to be liable in the same Order.; No Fee for providing or making Books, &amp;c. or for Payment of Money lent.; Penalty.; Punishment.; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty.Undue Preference by Deputy; Penalty, Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller not making Payments in due Order; Penalty.How all such Penalties shall be recovered</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p316">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That all Orders for the repayment of Loanes on this A&bholigct; shall be entred
according to the dates of the respe&bholigct;ive Tallyes of Loane And all Orders for payment of Commission Officers
of the Army and the discharge of Quarters and payment for Cloathes shall be registred in course according to
their respe&bholigct;ive dayes and times of bringing thereof and none of the Orders abovementioned shall have preference
one before another but shall be entred in their Course according to the dates of [their<ref idref="n93">93</ref>] said Tallyes and the times
of bringing their other Orders as they are in point of time respe&bholigct;ively before each other And that all and every
person and persons shall be paid in Course according as their Orders shall stand entred in the said Register
Booke soe as that the Person Native or Forreigner his Executors Administrators and Assignes who shall have his
Order or Orders first entred in the said Booke of Register shall be taken and accounted as the first person to
be paid upon the Two hundred six thousand fower hundred sixty two pounds seaventeene shillings three pence
to come in by vertue of this A&bholigct; [And he she or they that shall have his her or their Order or Orders next
entred shall be taken and accounted to be the second person to be paid and soe successively and in course And
that the two hundred six thousand fower hundred sixty two pounds seaventeene shillings three pence to come in
by vertue of this A&bholigct;<ref idref="n94">94</ref>] shall be in the same Order lyeable to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said respe&bholigct;ive Partyes their
Executors Administrators or Assignes successively without preference of one before another and not otherwise and
not to be divertible to any other use intent or purpose whatsoever and that noe Fee or Reward or Gratuity dire&bholigct;ly
or indire&bholigct;ly be demanded or taken of any of your Majeftyes Subje&bholigct;s for provideing or makeing any such Bookes
Registers Entryes View Searches or Certificate in or for Payment of money lent or the Interest thereof or for
Payment of any money upon any Order by any of your Majestyes Officer or Officers their Clerkes or Deputyes on
paine of payment of Treble Damages to the party grieved by the partie offending with costs of Suite or if the
Officer himselfe take or demand any such Fee or Reward then to loose his Place alsoe And if any undue
preference of one before another shall be made either in point of Registry or of Payment contrary to the true
meaning of this A&bholigct; by any such Officer or Officers then the partie offending shall be lyable by A&bholigct;ion of Debt
or on the case to pay the value of the Debt Damages and Costs to the partie grieved and shall be forejudged from
his Place or Office, And if such preference be unduely made by any his Deputy or Clerke without dire&bholigct;ion
or privity of his Master then such Deputy or Clerke onely shall be lyable to such A&bholigct;ion Debt Damages and
Costs and shall be for ever after incapeable of his Place or Office And in case the Auditor shall not dire&bholigct; the
Order or the Clerke of the Pells record or the Teller make Payment according to each persons due Place and
Order as afore-dire&bholigct;ed then he or they shall be adjudged to forfeite and their respe&bholigct;ive Deputyes and Clerkes
herein offending to be lyeable to such A&bholigct;ion Debt Damages and Costs in manner as aforesaid all which said
Penalties Forfeitures Damages and Costs to be incurred by any of the Officers of the Exchequer or any their
Deputyes or Clerks shall and may be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of his
Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion Priviledge Wager of Law Injun&bholigct;ion
or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise granted or allowed.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s17">
		<head>XVII. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date the same Day.</head>
		<para id="p317">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby declared That if it happen that severall Tallyes of Loane beare date or be
brought the same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be registred then it shall be interpreted noe undue
preference which of those he enters first soe he enters them all the same day.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s18">
		<head>XVIII. Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded, no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Orders.</head>
		<para id="p318">Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpreted any undue preference to incurr any penalty in point of Payment
if the Auditor dire&bholigct; and the Clerke of the Pells record and the Teller doe pay subsequent Orders of persons
that come and demand their money and bring their Order before other persons that did not come to demand
their money and bring their Order in their course soe as there be soe much money reserved as will satisfie
their Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon Loane or Orders being to
cease from the time the money is soe reserved and kept in Bancke for them.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s19">
		<head>XIX. Orders for Payment of Monies may be assigned by Indorsement.</head>
		<para id="p319">
			<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee.; Assignee may in like manner assign</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p320">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every person or persons to whome any money
shall be due upon the Two hundred six thousand fower hundred sixty two pounds seaventeene shillings and three
pence given by vertue of this A&bholigct; after Order entered in the Booke of Register aforesaid for Payment thereof
his Executors Administrators or Assignes by Endorsement of his Order may assigne and transferr his Right Title
Interest and Benefitt of such Order or any part thereof to any other which being notified in the Office of the
Auditor for the Receipt aforesaid and an Entry and Memoriall thereof alsoe made in the Booke of Registry
aforesaid for Orders which the Officers shall [upon request<ref idref="n95">95</ref>] without Fee or Charge accordingly make shall entitule
such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the Benefitt thereof and Payment thereon, And such
Assignee may in like manner assigne againe and soe toties quoties and afterwards it shall not be in the power
of such person or persons who have made such Assignements to make void release or discharge the same or any
the moneys thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s20">
		<head>XX. Commissioners not liable to Penalties of 25 C. II. c. 2. for executing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p321">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Commissioner or Commissioners or any other
Officer that shall bee imployed in the Execution of this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall be lyable for
or by reason of their a&bholigct;ing or proceeding as Commissioners by vertue of this A&bholigct; to any of the Penalties
mentioned in an A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for preventing dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants, for not
takeing the Oathes or Declaration in the said A&bholigct; expressed, in case such Commissioner or Commissioners Officer
or Officers have before that time taken the said Oathes and subscribed the Declaration in the recited A&bholigct;
mentioned.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s21">
		<head>XXI. Monies levied under this A&bholigct;, (Exception). to be appropriated to the paying and disbanding the Forces, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p322">
			<emph type="i">Doing, &amp;c. any A&bholigct; to divert or misapply Monies; Premunire, 16 R. II. c.5.; and incapable of Pardon</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p323">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all moneyes herein before named and mentioned
colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid by vertue of this A&bholigct; into the Receipt of the Exchequer as well upon Loane as otherwise
except the Allowances therein made to the respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;ors Clerkes and Receivers Generall and the usuall Fees
of the Officers of the Exchequer and to the Commissioners hereby appointed for disbanding the said Forces and
what shall be issued thence for the repayment of Loanes and payment of Orders made in persuance of this A&bholigct;
in manner aforesaid, upon the Credit of the said Two hundred and sixe thousand fower hundred sixty two pounds
seaventeene shillings and three pence shall be applyed &amp; appropriated and are hereby appropriated to and for the
speedy and compleate paying and disbanding the Forces Officers and Souldiers by this A&bholigct; appointed to be disbanded
and the necessary Charges for doeing thereof and to noe other Intent Use or Purpose whatsoever And any person
or persons that shall advise frame contrive countersigne or putt in execution any Commission A&bholigct; Order Warrant
or Command whatsoever for diverting or misapplying any of the Money hereby granted to His Majestie to any
other Intent Use or Purpose whatsoever then the Uses Intents and Purposes by this A&bholigct; limitted &amp; appointed he
or they soe offending shall incurr and sustaine the Paines Penalties and Forfeitures limited ordained and provided
in and by the Statute of Provision and Premunire made in the Sixteenth yeare of King Richard the Second and
shall from thenceforth be disabled dureing his life to sue or impleade any person in any A&bholigct;ion reall or personall
or to make any Gift Grant Conveyance or other disposition of any his Lands Tenements Hereditaments Goods
or Chattells which he hath to his owne use either by A&bholigct; executed in his life time or by his last Will or
otherwise or take any Gift Conveyance or Legacie to his owne use and bee incapeable of any Ease or Pardon from
his Majestie his Heires or Successors of the said Penalties Forfeitures and Disabilities or any of them.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s22">
		<head>XXII. Commissioners for disbanding the Forces to take Account of Monies received and paid by Paymaster of the Land Forces.</head>
		<para id="p324">
			<emph type="i">The said Account and of Money hereby granted to be given to the Commons in Parliament, within Three Months after disbanding</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p325">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Commissioners for disbanding the Forces or any Two
or more of them are hereby authorized and required to take an Accompt of the Treasurer or Paymaster of the
Land Forces of all moneyes by him received and paid for the use of or to the said Forces raised since the said
Nine and twentyeth day of September One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven or any of them or any
contingent Charges in reference thereunto which the said Paymaster is hereby injoyned to make and deliver upon
Oath to the said Commissioners within Ten dayes After the disbanding of the said Forces and the said Commissioners
or any Two or more of them are hereby impowered to administer the said Oath to the said Paymaster, for the
makeing and perfe&bholigct;ing the same, And the said Account as alsoe the Account of the Money hereby granted to
his Majestie shall be given to the Commons assembled in Parlyament of this or any succeeding Parlyament within
Three moneths after the said Forces shall be disbanded and all Charges incident thereunto paid and discharged if
a Parlyament shall then be sitting or in the next approaching Session that shall happen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s23">
		<head>XXIII. Colle&bholigct;or keeping Money in Hand, or paying to Person other than Receiver General.</head>
		<para id="p326">
			<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5.; Receiver General or Deputy paying Monies other than into the Exchequer; Penalty &pound;500</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p327">And for the more effe&bholigct;uall doeing thereof and that the said moneys hereby given may be applyed to the use
and service aforesaid Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed And it is ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any Colle&bholigct;or
of any Parish or Place shall keepe in his hands any part of the said money by him colle&bholigct;ed for any longer time
then is by this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ed (other then the allowance made unto him by this A&bholigct;) or shall pay any part thereof
to any person or persons other then the Receiver Generall of such County or Place or his Deputy That every
such Colle&bholigct;or shall forfeite for every such Offence the summe of Five pounds And in case any Receiver Generall
or his Deputie shall pay any part of the moneyes paid to him or them by any Colle&bholigct;or by vertue of this A&bholigct;
to any person or persons whatsoever other then into the Receipt of the Exchequer And that at or within the respe&bholigct;ive
times hereby limitted such Receiver Generall shall for every such Offence of himselfe or his Deputy forfeite the
Summe of Five hundred pounds to him or them that shall sue for the same in any Court of Record by Bill Plaint
or other Information wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law is to bee allowed.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s24">
		<head>XXIV. Officers and Soldiers of the Regiments herein mentioned to be paid and disbanded.</head>
		<para id="p328">And for the more certaine speedy and effe&bholigct;uall disbanding of all the said Forces raised or brought over from
forreigne parts into this Kingdome since the Twenty nineth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy
and seaven Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the severall Officers and Soldiers of the Regiment of
Horse and [of<ref idref="n96">96</ref>] the Regiment of Foote now or late of James Duke of Monmouth The severall Officers and
Soldiers of the Regiment of Dragoons now or late of His Highnesse Prince Rupert Duke of Cumberland,
Of the Regiment of Dragoons (<ref idref="n97">97</ref>) of Lewis alias Louis Earle of Feversham otherwise called The Royall Regiment,
Of the Regiment of Dragoons now or late of Sir John Talbot Knight The severall Officers and [Soldies<ref idref="n98">98</ref>]
of the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Regiments of Foote now or late of William Lord Allington of the Kingdome of
Ireland Collonell Henry Sidney Sir Thomas Slingsby Sir Lionell Walden Sir Charles Wheeler Collonell George
Legg consisting of Eight Companies and Collonell Thomas Stradling The two Foote Companyes now or late
commanded by Captaine John Wharton and Captaine Thomas Denton being part of the late Regiment of Edward
Lord Morpeth Sonne and Heire apparent of the Earle of Carlisle The two Foote Companies now or late of Sir
Henry Goodricke and Sir Jonathan Jennings being part of the late Regiment of the said Sir Henry Goodrick,
The two Companies now or late commanded by Captaine John Shaftoe and Captaine William Collingwood being
part of the late Regiment of Sir John Fenwicke The two Foote Companies now or late commanded by Major
Henry Collier and Captaine Henry Jeyne being part of the late Regiment of Collonell Edward Villers The two
Companies now or late commanded by Captaine John Boys and Captaine John Cox being part of the late Regiment
of Henry late Lord O Bryen of the Kingdome of Ireland The severall Officers and Souldiers of the severall and
respe&bholigct;ive Troops of Granadeers now or late commanded by Captaine Henry Carr Captaine John Staples and
Captaine Thomas Row The severall Officers and Soldiers of the Six Foote Companies of Granadeers now or late
commanded by Captaine John Daniell Captaine William Rigg Captaine John Gibbs Captaine John Bristow Captaine
George Wingfeild and Captaine Charles O-hara The additionall Adjutant and Twenty fower Serjeants of the
Regiment now or late commanded by Collonell John Russell, The additionall Adjutant and the severall Officers and
Soldiers of the Eight additionall Companies in the Regiment of Foote of the Earle of Craven now or late
commanded by Captaine Thomas Talmash Captaine Robert Saincleere Captaine Thomas Sillyard Captaine Simon
Parry Captaine Robert Brett Captaine Humphrey Okeover Captaine David Ogleby and Captaine Francis Newport
And alsoe the Twelve additionall Serjeants and Fower hundred and eighty Soldiers raised and distributed into the
other Twelve Companies of the same Regiment videlicet One Serjeant and Forty Soldiers in each Company
since the Nine and twentyeth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven The additionall Adjutant
and the severall Officers and Souldiers of the Eight additionall Companies in the Regiment of Foote now or
late of Sir Charles Litleton Knight commonly called The Regiment of His Royall Highnesse The Duke
of Yorke now or late commanded by Captaine Thomas Whally Captaine James Fortry Captaine Charles
Herbert Captaine Charles Churchill Captaine Francis Iszard Captaine Edward Harris Captaine John Parker
and Captaine Samuell Scudamore And alsoe the Twelve additionall Serjeants Twelve Drummers and Five
hundred and seaventy Soldiers raised and distributed into the other Twelve Companies of the said
Regiment viz<emph type="p">t</emph> One Serjeant One Drummer and Fifty Souldiers for each Company excepting Major Darrells
Company to whome there were Twenty onely added raised since the Nine and twentyeth of September One thousand
six hundred seaventy and seaven The additionall Adjutant and the severall Officers and Souldiers of the Eight
additionall Companies in the Regiment of Foote now or late of The Earle of Mulgrave now or late commanded
by Captaine Charles Hillyard Captaine Charles Mannering Captaine John Richardson Captaine Ralph Delavall
Captaine Gilbert Cornwall Captaine William Wheeler Captaine Francis Collingwood and Captaine Edward Fitz
Patrick And alsoe Twelve additionall Serjeants Twelve Drummers and Six hundred Souldiers raised and distributed
in the other Twelve Companies of the same Regiment viz<emph type="p">t</emph> One Serjeant One Drummer and Fifty Souldiers in
each Company since the said Nine and twentyeth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven
The severall Officers and Souldiers of the Troope of Horse now or late commanded by Captaine Will Wind now
or late in the Island of Jersey The severall Officers and Souldiers of the Six Foote Companies now or late of
John Lord Fretchville Sir John [Rereby<ref idref="n99">99</ref>] Sir Robert Hilliard Sir Ralph Wharton Captaine William Godolphin and
Captaine Robert Pollard The Adjutant Provost Marshall Chaplaine Chirurgions Mate and Eightie Souldiers raised
and distributed into the Regiment of Horse now or late of Awbrey de Vere Earle of Oxford viz<emph type="p">t</emph> Ten Souldiers
to each of the Troops in the said Regiment since the Nine and twentyeth of September One thousand six hundred
seaventy and seaven The additionall Two and twenty Serjeants Two and twenty Drummers and Eleaven hundred
Soldiers raised and distributed since the Nine and twentyeth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy and
seaven into the Two and twenty Non-regimented Garrison Companies of Foote hereafter mentioned That is to say
Into the Company now or late of Edward Lord Morpeth aforesaid in Carlisle, The Company now or late of Sir
Francis Leake at Gravesend The two Companies now or late of Christopher Lord Hatton and Captaine William
Sheldon at Guernsey The two Companies now or late of James Duke of Monmouth and Collonell Anthony Gilby
at Hull The Companies now or late of Sir Thomas Morgan Knight and Baronet and Captaine Thomas Germain
at Jersey The Company now or late of Richard Lord Arundell of Trerice at Pendennis The Companies now or
late of Collonell George Legg Captaine Oliver Nicholas Captaine John Lee Captaine George Howston and Sir
Roger Strickland at Portsmouth The two Companies now or late of John Earle of Bath and Sir Hugh Piper at
Plymouth The Company now or late of Collonell Edward Villers at Tinmouth The three Companies now or late of
Sir John Robinson Sir Thomas Chichley and Collonell David Walter in the Tower of London The two Companies
now or late of Sir Robert Holmes and Lieutenant.[Collonell<ref idref="n100">100</ref>] James Halsell in the Isle of Wight videlicet One
Serjeant and one Drummer and Fiftie Souldiers in each Company The additionall Towne Major Chaplaine
Chirurgion and Marshall to the Garrison of Plymouth The additionall Chirurgion to the said Isle of Wight The
additionall Chirurgion to the Garrison of Hull The additionall Chirurgion in the Isle of Guernsey The additionall
Chaplaine for the Garrison of Shernesse and The additionall Chaplaine and Chirurgion for the Island of Jersey
raised and added since the Nine and twentyeth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven
And all other His Majestyes Regiments Forces Troops and Companies or parts of Regiments Troops and Companies
Officers and Souldiers whatsoever whether in Garrison or out of Garrison within the Kingdome of England Dominion
of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede and the Isles of Guernsey or Jersey which have beene raised
listed or mustred within this Realme or the Places aforesaid since the said Nine and twentieth of September One
thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven or since that time brought over into this Realme from Forraigne Parts
be forthwith paid off disbanded and discharged.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s25">
		<head>XXV. Names of Commissioners appointed; to a&bholigct; according to Instructions; to meet and execute A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p329">
			<emph type="i">Treasury to issue Warrants for Payment of Debentures, &amp;c.; Colonels, &amp;c. to give due Obedience to Precepts, &amp;c of Commissioners for paying and disbanding the Forces</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p330">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That Sir Gilbert Gerrard Baronet Collonell Roger
Whitley Collonell John Birch and Sir Thomas Player Knight shall be and are hereby constituted and appointed
Commissioners for that purpose and shall a&bholigct; therein according to the Rules Orders Dire&bholigct;ions and Instru&bholigct;ions
hereafter expressed and shall meete together the next day after the Royall Assent to this A&bholigct; given in the Place
called the Inner Court of Wards at Westminster to beginn to putt this A&bholigct; in Execution and the Lord Treasurer
and Vice-Treasurer or Lords Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being or any three or more of them
are hereby authorized and required to issue their respe&bholigct;ive Warrants or Orders as aforesaid for the payment of
such Certificates or Debenters as shall be by the said Commissioners for disbanding or any one or more of them
from time to time to them or any three or more of them respe&bholigct;ively dire&bholigct;ed and to such person or persons as
shall be in the said Certificates or Debenters respe&bholigct;ively mentioned And according to the Rules Orders Dire&bholigct;ions
and Instru&bholigct;ions herein limitted and dire&bholigct;ed for paying and disbanding the said Forces and all and every the
Collonells and Officers of the said Forces the Commissary Generall of the Musters and all the respe&bholigct;ive Muster
Masters by them deputed and the Paymaster of the Guards and Forces and all other persons concerned in the
Rules and Instru&bholigct;ions by this A&bholigct; given are hereby required to give due Obedience to all Precepts Rules and
Dire&bholigct;ions as the said Commissioners or any one or more of them or any person or persons by them one or
more of them thereunto authorized shall from time to time in order to the paying and disbanding of the Forces
as aforesaid make dire&bholigct; and appoint.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s26">
		<head>XXVI. Commissions of General Officers (Exception) void.</head>
		<para id="p331">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the severall Commission and Commissions of all Generall
Officers of the Army other then the Generall Staffe Officers dated since the Nine and twentyeth day of September
One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven are hereby declared to be void to all intents and purposes
whatsoever.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s27">
		<head>XXVII. All other Officers, &amp;c. by this A&bholigct; ordered to be disbanded, are to be disbanded according to the Rules herein mentioned.</head>
		<para id="p332">
			<emph type="i">Treasury, on Receipt of Debenture, to grant Warrant for Pay.; Paymaster not to pay until Deduction for Clothes, as herein mentioned.; Officers to produce to Commissioners Acquittances</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p333">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all other the Officers Souldiers and Forces by this A&bholigct;
to be disbanded shall be paid off and disbanded according to the Rules [Orders<ref idref="n101">101</ref>] Dire&bholigct;ions and Instru&bholigct;ions
hereafter following That is to say That the Commissioners for disbanding the Forces or any two or more of
them shall order the Paymaster of the Army to make and deliver to them or any two or more of them
within two dayes after the Royall Assent to this A&bholigct; given an Account of what money shall bee then due
on the Muster of September last to all or any of the Officers and Souldiers of the severall Regiments Troops
and Companies raised since the said Twenty ninth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy seaven
and upon the Receipt of the said Account the said Commissioners or any two or more of them shall make out
a Certificate or Debenter of the summe or summes of money due upon the said Muster dire&bholigct;ed to the said
Lord Treasurer or Lords Commissioners of the Treasury or any three or more of them [&amp; the ?d Lord Treasurer
or Lords C&bhooov;n?s or any three or more of them<ref idref="n101">101</ref>] are hereby injoyned upon Receipt of such Certificate or Debenter
to grant their Warrant or Order in manner as aforesaid for the Payment thereof to the said Paymaster who shall
not pay the same to any of the said Officers untill he shall have made dedu&bholigct;ions for Cloathes to the First of
November last which Officers shall produce to the said Commissioners or any one or more of them Acquittances
for the full Discharge of all money due for Quarters from the said First day of September to the said First day
of November from the person or persons to whome the same is or shall be due attested by the Constable or
Cheife Magistrate of the Place before any money be paid to any such Officer by the said Commissoners for or
upon any subsequent Muster.</para>
		<para id="p334">
			<emph type="i">No Commissioned Officer to have his Accounts made or receive Pay after 1st April 1679</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p335">That noe Commission Officer either of Horse Foote Dragoons or Granadeers now to be disbanded shall have
his or their Accounts made up or receive any Pay for longer time then to the First day of Aprill One thousand
six hundred seaventy nine exclusive and noe Generall Officer of the Field shall have any Pay as a Generall
Officer by vertue of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		<para id="p336">
			<emph type="i">Soldiers after 31st May</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p337">That noe Souldier whether Horse, Foote Granadeer or Dragoons under the Degree of a Commission Officer
shall have his or their Accounts made up nor receive any Pay for any longer time then to the last day of May
next following exclusive.</para>
		<para id="p338">
			<emph type="i">Regulation as to Pay, &amp;c. of Officers of disbanded Regiments.</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p339">That noe Officer whose Regiment Troope or Company is already disbanded shall have his Accounts dated or
receive any Pay other then as Captaine of such Troope or Company which are now left undisbanded and
heretofore were part of Regiments already disbanded as aforesaid.</para>
		<para id="p340">
			<emph type="i">Paymaster General and Commissary of Musters to draw up Account of Monies due to disbanded Officers and Soldiers</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p341">That the Pay master Generall and Commissary of the Musters shall forthwith draw up an Account in a Booke
or Bookes of all Moneys due to any Officer or Souldier now to be disbanded according to the Musters of them
taken from the First of November to the First of Aprill One thousand six hundred seaventy nine and likewise
an Account of all Moneys due to the Non Commission Officers and Souldiers from the said First day of Aprill
inclusive to the First day of May next following exclusive.</para>
		<para id="p342">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners at time of disbanding, to call over Officers and Soldiers by the Book.; Only those who appear or account for Absence to be paid</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p343">That the Commissioners appointed by this A&bholigct; for disbanding the said Forces shall at the time and place of
disbanding call over every Officer and Souldier by the said Booke or Bookes soe drawne up by the said Pay-master
and Commissary and soe many of the said Officers and Souldiers as shall then and there appeare (and noe other)
except such as they shall be fully satisfyed by good proofe are absent by reason of death sicknes or otherwise,
shall have what Moneyes by the said Muster Rolls and Bookes thereupon made shall appeare to be to them due,
the Quarters for every such Officer and Souldier first dedu&bholigct;ed and alsoe the money for him or them respe&bholigct;ively
due for Cloathes.</para>
		<para id="p344">
			<emph type="i">Troops nearest to London to be first disbanded</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p345">That the Forces whether Horse Foote Dragoons or Granadeers that lye nearest to London shall be first
disbanded and according to that Rule for all the rest of the Forces now to be disbanded.</para>
		<para id="p346">
			<emph type="i">Forces to be disbanded where quartered, &amp;c.; Notice of disbanding</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p347">That all the aforesaid Forces shall be disbanded in the Places where they shall be quartered at the time of
their disbanding or within such a distance as the persons to whome money shall be due for their Quarters may
reasonably come, of which place and the time of disbanding notice shall be given some reasonable time beforehand
at the discretion of the Commissioners appointed to disband the said Forces.</para>
		<para id="p348">
			<emph type="i">Money due for Quarters to be defalked out of Pay.; Colonel, &amp;c. to ascertain Sums due</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p349">That there shall be defalked out of the Pay of every Officer and Souldier soe much money as shall be made
appeare to the Commissioners to be due from every such Officer and Souldier for his or their Quarters at the
time of their disbanding And for the more speedy dispatch of this Service every Collonell Captaine or other Officer
whose Troope or Company shall be concerned in paying for their Quarters shall doe their utmost endeavour to
ascertaine the summes that shall be soe due against the day and time of their disbanding.</para>
		<para id="p350">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners may authorize Persons to disband Troops</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p351">That in case any Troope or Company shall lye at such a distance as the Commissioners cannot with conveniency
disband them in soe short a time as is desired in every such case the Commissioners or any two of them are
hereby authorized under their Hands and Seales to dire&bholigct; some able and sufficient persons to disband them
according to the Rules and Instru&bholigct;ions herein contained.</para>
		<para id="p352">
			<emph type="i">Notice of disbanding to be given by Commissioners to Officers of Ordnance; Receipt by Ordnance for Arms delivered up</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p353">That notice be given by the Commissioners appointed for disbanding the Forces to the Officers of the Ordnance
at what time and place such Forces shall be disbanded to the intent that fitt persons may be appointed by the
said Office to receive such Armes and Ammunition as shall be delivered up at the time of their disbanding for
which Armes and other things in particular soe delivered up a Receipt shall be then given by the person deputed
by the said Office of the Ordnance to receive the same unto the Collonell or other Superiour Commission Officer
that shall be soe disbanded which Arms and Ammunition shall be delivered up before the Commissioners or any
of them signe any Certificate or Debenter as aforesaid for the paying any of the Forces then to be disbanded.</para>
		<para id="p354">
			<emph type="i">Clothes, Swords, &amp;c. allowed to disbanded Soldiers; and to Commission Officers</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p355">That at the time and place where any such Forces shall be disbanded every Foote Souldier shall march away
with his Cloathes, Sword, Belt and Snapsacke onely and every Horseman below the degree of a Commission
Officer with his Horses, Sadles, Bridles Cloathes Swords and Belts onely and all Commission Officers shall march
away with such Horses and Armes and other Accoutriments whatsoever as were not received out of his Majestyes
Stores and all other Armes shall be then delivered up as is before dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
		<para id="p356">
			<emph type="i">Officers or Soldiers refusing to be disbanded, &amp;c. Proceedings</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p357">That if any Officer or Souldier hereby appointed to be disbanded shall refuse to give obedience thereunto or
disswade others from disbanding he or they shall forfeite their whole Arreares and be forthwith secured and
proceeded against according to Law.</para>
		<para id="p358">
			<emph type="i">Sheriffs, &amp;c. to be aiding</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p359">That all Sheriffes and all other his Majestyes Officers in every County be aiding and assisting to the
Commissioners appointed for disbanding the Forces if thereunto required by the Commissioners or any one or
more of them.</para>
		<para id="p360">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners to give Passes to disbanded Soldiers</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p361">That one or more of the Commissioners for disbanding the Forces doe under his or their Hands and Seales
give Certificates or Passes gratis at the time of disbanding to every Private Souldier whether Horse or Foote
that shall desire them of his faithfull Service and that he or they may peaceably travell to their severall places
of their last abode when he or they entred into this Service, at which place every such Soldier shall be received
as an Inhabitant Any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<para id="p362">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners may divide themselves</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p363">That for the more speedy and effe&bholigct;uall paying and disbanding of the said Forces the said Commissioners may
divide themselves if they shall thinke fitt and any one or more of the said Commissioners shall and have
hereby full power to pay off and disband the said Souldiers according to the Rules and Dire&bholigct;ions appointed by
this A&bholigct;.</para>
		<para id="p364">
			<emph type="i">Soldiers that were Apprentices to be received by their Masters, &amp;c. who are to allow the Time; and on Refusal Master to deliver up Indentures.</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p365">That such Souldiers as were Apprentices at the time of their being entertained in any Troope or Company
shall upon such Certificate be recieved againe into the Service of the Master or Mistresse to whome they were
bound as Apprentices and such Master or Mistresse is to allow the time of their being Soldiers upon their
Indentures as if they had continued in such their Service and if the time of their Apprentiships be expired they
shall be admitted to the Freedome of the respe&bholigct;ive Corporation City Company or Towne to which their respe&bholigct;ive
Service former Residence or Indenture related and in case such Master or Mistresse doe refuse to admitt such
Apprentice they shall deliver up their Indentures and all Bonds and Security in reference thereunto.</para>
		<para id="p366">
			<emph type="i">Disbanded Soldiers being paid to repair to their Habitations.</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p367">That every Officer or Souldier soe disbanded and haveing the money to him or them soe made appeare to be
due paid or secured unto him or them or their Order and haveing Certificates delivered them by one or more
of the Commissioners as is before dire&bholigct;ed shall forthwith repaire from the place of their respe&bholigct;ive disbanding to
their owne habitations or places of abode.</para>
		<para id="p368">
			<emph type="i">Allowances to Commissioners to be paid by Warrant from Treasury.</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p369">That the Commissioners that is to say Sir Gilbert Gerard Baronet Colonell Roger Whitley Colonell John Birch
and Sir Thomas Player Knight shall have and receive for their Paines and Charges for themselves and servants
and all necessaries for this Service Two pence in the pound and noe more out of all such money as shall be
issued by vertue of this A&bholigct; and for the Uses therein expressed which the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer
or Lords Commissioners of the Treasury or any Three or more of them are hereby authorized and required by
their Warrant or Order to cause to be paid to the said Commissioners respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p370">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners to pay to disbanded Soldiers 10s. as a free Gift, over and above Pay</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p371">That for the subsistance of every Foote Souldier or Foote Granadeer under the Degree of a Co&bhooov;mission Officer
and to the end that they may quietly and peaceably goe to their severall places of abode without doeing any
prejudice to the Country the Commissioners nominated and appointed by this A&bholigct; for disbanding the Forces are
immediately after such Foote Souldiers shall be by them disbanded to pay to every such Souldier or their Order
ten shillings as a free Gift over and above their respe&bholigct;ive Pay due to them at the time of their disbanding to
the ends aforesaid.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s28">
		<head>XXVIII. Commission Officers, &amp;c. exercising Command over disbanded Men, or endeavouring to continue any of the said disbanded Regiments together;</head>
		<para id="p372">
			<emph type="i">Premunire 16 R. II. c. 5. and disabled to sue, and otherwise as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p373">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every Commission Officer and Officers who shall exercise any power
or authority over the Souldiers in their respe&bholigct;ive Regiments Troops or Companies after such Officer or Officers
shall be paid off and disbanded by the said Commissioners or any one or more of them or by any person or
persons by them or any one or more of them thereunto authorized and every person or persons that shall advise
frame contrive countersigne or putt in execution any Proclamation Commission A&bholigct; Order or Command whatsoever
for continueing together any of the said Regiments Troops or Companies or parts of Regiments Troops or
Companies after they shall be paid off and disbanded as aforesaid he or they soe offending shall incurr and
sustaine the paines penalties and forfeitures limitted ordained and provided in and by the Statute of Provision and
Premunire made in the Sixteenth Yeare of King Richard the Second and shall from thenceforth be disabled
dureing his life to sue or impleade any Person in any A&bholigct;ion reall or personall or to make any Gift Grant
Conveyance or other Disposition of any his Lands Tenements Hereditaments Goods or Chattells which he hath
to his owne use either by A&bholigct; executed in his life time or by his last Will or otherwise or to take any Gift
Conveyance or Legacie to his owne use and none of the said Souldiers or Non Commissioned Officers paid off
and disbanded as aforesaid shall after the space of Fower and twenty houres after such disbanding continue together
above Ten in Company.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s29">
		<head>XXIX. Recital that several Officers and Soldiers who ought to have been disbanded pursuant to 30 C. II. c. 1. continued in Arms, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p374">
			<emph type="i">Indemnity to such Officers and Soldiers,; on their disbanding pursuant to this A&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p375">And forasmuch as severall Officers and Souldiers who ought to have beene disbanded by vertue and in pursuance
of an A&bholigct; made in the Thirtyeth yeare of His Majestyes Raigne entituled An A&bholigct; for granting a Supply to His
Majestie of Six hundred nineteene thousand three hundred eighty eight pounds eleaven shillings and nine pence
for disbanding the Army and other uses therein mentioned, did continue longer in Armes then the time therein
limitted for their disbanding and some of them after such time limitted for their disbanding recruited and supplyed
their respe&bholigct;ive Troops and Companies with Souldiers Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all such
Officers and Souldiers and every of them are hereby indempnifyed acquitted and discharged against the Kings
Majestie His Heires and Successors and every of them of and from all Offences of which they may be charged
for continueing in Armes as aforesaid or being mustred in any Troope or Company after their respe&bholigct;ive times
for disbanding in the said A&bholigct; limitted and alsoe for their illegall and undue Quartering or exa&bholigct;ing Money for
Subsistance or Quarters of or from any Inneholder Vintner Vi&bholigct;ualler Alehousekeeper or other Person or Persons
whatsoever and none of the said Officers or Souldiers shall be at any time hereafter impeached in Body Lands
or Goods for any thing by them done or executed contrary to the laste recited A&bholigct; soe as such Officers and
Souldiers doe disband and separate themselves according to the purporte true intent and meaneing of this A&bholigct;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s30">
		<head>XXX. Recital of 30 C. II. c. 1. &sect; 35.; and that the same was mistaken.</head>
		<para id="p376">
			<emph type="i">&pound;103,231. 8s. 7&frac12;d. to be assessed as if the said Mistake had not been made</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p377">And whereas by the said last recited A&bholigct; it is dire&bholigct;ed That the summe of One hundred and three thousand
two hundred thirty one pounds eight shillings and seaven pence halfe penny being the First of the Fower
Quarterly Payments of the summe of Fower hundred and twelve thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds
fowerteene shillings and six pence thereby granted shall bee assessed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid unto the Receivers
Generall of the severall Countyes therein named who shall be appointed by His Majestie on or before the Fower
and twentyeth day of May One thousand six hundred seaventy and eight which was mistaken it being intended
that the same should have beene assessed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid on or before the Fower and twentyeth day
of May One thousand six hundred seaventy and nine Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said
summe of One hundred and three thousand two hundred thirty one pounds eight shillings seaven pence halfe-peny
shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid to the Receivers Generall of the severall Countyes in the said A&bholigct;
mentioned on or before the Fower and twentyeth day of May One thousand six hundred seaventy and nine in
such manner as the same ought to have beene done if noe such mistake had beene made Any thing in the said
A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s31">
		<head>XXXI. Where A&bholigct;ions, &amp;c. commenced against Persons executing A&bholigct;, they may plead the General Issue, and recover Treble Costs on Nonsuit, &amp;c. of Plaintiff.</head>
		<para id="p378">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any A&bholigct;ion Suite Plaint or Information shall be commenced or prosecuted
against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in execution of this A&bholigct; such person
or persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall or may pleade the Generall Issue Not Guilty, and upon any
Issue joyned may give this A&bholigct; and the speciall matter in Evidence and if the Plaintiffe or Prosecutor shall become
Nonsuite or for beare further prosecution or suffer discontinuance or if a Verdi&bholigct; passe against him the Defendant
and Defendants shall recover their treble Costs for which they shall have the like remedy as in any case where
Costs by Law are given to Defendents.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s32">
		<head>XXXII. No Officer, &amp;c. to quarter Soldiers on any Subje&bholigct; without his Consent, and any Subje&bholigct; may refuse to quarter Soldiers.</head>
		<para id="p379">And whereas by the Lawes and Customes of this Realme the Inhabitants thereof cannot be compelled against
their wills to receive Souldiers into their Houses and to sojourne them there Bee it declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the
Authoritie aforesaid That noe Officer Military or Civill nor any other person whatever shall from henceforth
presume to place quarter or billet any Souldier or Souldiers upon any Subje&bholigct; or Inhabitant of this Realme of any
degree quality or profession whatever without his consent And that it shall and may be lawfull for every such
Subje&bholigct; and Inhabitant to refuse to sojourne or quarter any Souldier or Souldiers notwithstanding any Command
Order (<ref idref="n102">102</ref>) or Billetting whatever.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">Beaumont <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">Privy Councell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">Boord <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">Lord Colchester <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n7" number="7">Hurleston <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n8" number="8">Ashton James <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n9" number="9">Woolsley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n11" number="11">Ryves <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n12" number="12">Henning <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n14" number="14">Gentleman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n15" number="15">Watlis <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n16" number="16">Pearcyhay <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n17" number="17">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n18" number="18">being <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n19" number="19">Timothy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n20" number="20">Dowtree <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n21" number="21">Mottfinsfeild <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n22" number="22">Pascall <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n23" number="23">no blank in <emph type="i">Original</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n24" number="24">Cooper <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n25" number="25">Lippyard <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n26" number="26">Barronett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n27" number="27">Francklin <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n28" number="28">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n29" number="29">Potter <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n30" number="30">junior <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n31" number="31">Burton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n32" number="32">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n33" number="33">John Morrice Thomas Whightman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n34" number="34">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n35" number="35">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n36" number="36">S<emph type="p">r</emph>
			<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n37" number="37">Kecke <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n38" number="38">Inder <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n39" number="39">Powell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n40" number="40">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n41" number="41">Edmund <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n42" number="42">Lockier <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n43" number="43">The Name appears to be meant for "Throckmorton;" but the Roll is in part obliterated; it is Throckmorton in the Original A&bholigct;.</note>
		<note id="n44" number="44">Curr <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n45" number="45">Harby <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n46" number="46">Steward <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n47" number="47">S. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n48" number="48">Clement <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n49" number="49">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n50" number="50">Dusgate Gent.<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n51" number="51">Turner <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n52" number="52">Mayott <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n53" number="53">Newport <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n54" number="54">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n55" number="55">Sir Henry Littleton Sir Henry Frederick Thinne <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n56" number="56">Sir Richard Corbett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n57" number="57">Apley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n58" number="58">Fowler <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n59" number="59">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n60" number="60">Wolsley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n61" number="61">Whitehall <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n62" number="62">Kelbett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n63" number="63">Minors <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n64" number="64">Baynard <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n65" number="65">Blagden. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n66" number="66">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n67" number="67">John <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n68" number="68">Sir <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n69" number="69">Hatcher <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n70" number="70">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n71" number="71">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n72" number="72">Blaker <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n73" number="73">Holmes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n74" number="74">S<emph type="p">r</emph> John Mordant S<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Boughton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n75" number="75">Edward <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n76" number="76">Foley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n77" number="77">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n78" number="78">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n79" number="79">Laghtoony <emph type="i">O.</emph>
		</note>
		<note id="n80" number="80">Geeler <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n81" number="81">Eriviat <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n82" number="82">Griffith <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n83" number="83">Plasyollin <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n84" number="84">William <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n85" number="85">Turbervill.</note>
		<note id="n86" number="86">Cardiffe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n87" number="87">Anthony Thomas Evan Evans <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n88" number="88">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n89" number="89">upon <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n90" number="90">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n91" number="91">every of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n92" number="92">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n93" number="93">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n94" number="94">annexed to the Roll in a separate Schedule.</note>
		<note id="n95" number="95">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n96" number="96">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. Omits.</note>
		<note id="n97" number="97">now or late <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n98" number="98">Souldiers <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n99" number="99">Reresby <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n100" number="100">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n101" number="101">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n102" number="102">Warrant <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


