<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE index SYSTEM "../dtd/index.dtd">
<index id="47499" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Index</title>
	<subtitle>N</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>N</head>
		<entry>
			<head>
				<key>Naturalization</key>
			</head>
			<table id="t1">
				<tr>
					<td cols="3"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<th>Statute</th>
					<th>Page</th>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For the Naturalization of Children of His Majesty's English Subjects born in Foreign Countries.</td>
					<td>29 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 6.</td>
					<td>847</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Certain Persons herein named, and all other Persons born out of the King's Dominions between 14th June 1641 and 24th March 1660, and whose Fathers or Mothers were natural-born Subjects, declared natural-born Subjects.</td>
					<td>&sect;1.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>And enabled to take Titles of Honour, Lands, and other Rights and Privileges, as if born of English Parents within this Kingdom.</td>
					<td>&sect; 2.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Such Persons to receive the Sacrament and take the Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy as herein mentioned, and have Proof thereof by Certificate and Witnesses.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Otherwise no Benefit of this Act (Exception.)</td>
					<td>&sect; 3.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proof of Qualification may be made by Witnesses <emph type="i">viva voce</emph>; and thereupon Certificate enrolled.</td>
					<td>&sect; 4.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<head>
				<key>Navy</key>
			</head>
			<table id="t2">
				<tr>
					<td cols="3"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<th>Statute</th>
					<th>Page</th>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For the encouraging and increasing of Shipping, &amp;c.</td>
					<td>12 
<emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 18.</td>
					<td>246</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>No Goods shall be imported to or exported from Plantation, &amp;c. in Asia, Africa, or America but in English Ships, and Master and Three Fourths of Mariners English &mdash;Penalty.<br/>
						<emph type="i">Foreign-built Ships, though owned and manned by English (Exception), not deemed English Ships</emph>, 13 &amp; 14 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 11. &sect; 6.; <emph type="i">see, as to Ships in the Greenland Trade</emph>, 4 <emph type="i">W. &amp; </emph>
						<emph type="i">M. c</emph>. 17. &sect; 22.; <emph type="i">but that Trade laid open</emph>, 1 
<emph type="i">Ann: Stat</emph>. 1. 
<emph type="i">c</emph>. 16.&mdash; 
<emph type="i">See</emph> 10 
<emph type="i">G. I. c</emph>. 16.&mdash; 12 
<emph type="i">G. I. c</emph>. 26. &sect; 7. 
<emph type="i">but which appear to be expired. No Goods whatever to be imported in Ships, although registered as British Ships, unless so navigated</emph>, 34 
<emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 68. &sect; 1. 
<emph type="i">Who shall be deemed English (British) Masters and Mariners</emph>, 34 
<emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 68. &sect; 6. 
<emph type="i">As to Importations of Spanish Wool</emph>, 39 
<emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 98. &sect; 1. 
<emph type="i">Who shall be deemed British and Irish Masters and Mariners</emph>, 42 
<emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 61. &sect; 7. 
<emph type="i">And during War, Three Fourths of the Crews of Irish Trading Vessels and Privateers may be Foreigners</emph>, 42 
<emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 61. &sect; 10, 12. 
<emph type="i">So as to Merchant Ships in general returning Home</emph>, 43 
<emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 64. &sect; 1.</td>
					<td>&sect; 1.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>. </td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Admirals, &amp;c. empowered to seize and bring in as Prize all Ships offending.</td>
					<td>12 
<emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 18. &sect;1.</td>
					<td>246</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proceedings in case of Condemnation.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Aliens exercising the Occupation of Merchants or Factors in Plantations&mdash;Penalty.</td>
					<td>&sect; 2.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Governors of Plantations to take Oath to perform the afore-mentioned Clauses&mdash;Neglecting so to do, removed.<br/>
						<emph type="i">This Section explained and enforced</emph>, 7 &amp; 8 
<emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 22. &sect; 4. 
<emph type="i">Naval Stores may be purchased by Commissioners of the Navy on board Neutral Ships brought into Port by the King's Ships</emph>, 29 
<emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 34. &sect; 38. 
<emph type="i">Altered as to Aliens residing in any Place in the West Indies surrendered to His Majesty</emph>, 34 
<emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 42. &sect; 6. 
<emph type="i">So as to any Place surrendered generally</emph>, 37 
<emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 63. &sect; 5.&mdash;45 
<emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 32. &sect; 5.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>247</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Goods of Asia, Africa, or America not to be imported but in English Ships, and manned as aforesaid&mdash;Penalty.<br/>
						<emph type="i">See as to Treaty of Commerce with Portugal</emph>, 51 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 47.</td>
					<td>&sect; 3.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
Goods of Foreign Growth or Manufacture (<emph type="i">a</emph>), to be imported only from the Places of their said Growth, &amp;c. or from those Parts where they have been usually first shipped (<emph type="i">b</emph>)&mdash;Penalty.<br/>(<emph type="i">a</emph>) <emph type="i">Thrown Silk no Manufacture within the Meaning of this Act</emph>, 2 <emph type="i">W. &amp; M. Sess</emph>. 1. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 9. <emph type="i">Italian Organzined Thrown Silk may be imported in any Vessels from Places in Amity during the Continuance of Hostilities</emph>, 43 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 155. &sect; 1.
(<emph type="i">b</emph>) <emph type="i">It should seem this is meant to be explained as to Goods the Growth or Production of Africa, Asia, or America, manufactured in Foreign Parts</emph>, 19 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 48. &sect; 1. <emph type="i">but the Section is not correctly recited there, and see as to Importation of American Drugs</emph>, 7 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 8. &sect; 12.&mdash;51 <emph type="i">G.III. c</emph>. 47.&mdash;53 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 155. &sect; 7.</td>
					<td>12 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 18. &sect; 4.</td>
					<td>247</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>All Ling, Stockfish, &amp;c. Oil, &amp;c. Whalefins, &amp;c. imported, not caught in Vessels of the Proprietors themselves, &amp;c. shall pay double Aliens' Custom.</td>
					<td>&sect; 5.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>No Goods to be carried from One Port of England to another in the Vessel of any Alien, (Exception) and of which the Master and Three Fourths of the Mariners are not English&mdash;Penalty.</td>
					<td>&sect; 6.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Abatement, &amp;c. in the Book of Rates allowed only where the Master and Three Fourths of the Mariners be English</td>
					<td>&sect; 7.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proviso for Sickness, &amp;c.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Goods of the Growth or Manufacture of Muscovy or Russia and of the Turkish Empire (<emph type="i">a</emph>), and other Goods herein mentioned, to be imported in English Ships and manned as aforesaid&mdash;Exception&mdash;Penalty (<emph type="i">b</emph>).<br/> (<emph type="i">a</emph>) <emph type="i">As to the Trade from Persia through Russia, see</emph> 14 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 36. (<emph type="i">b</emph>) <emph type="i">As to Goods from Holland, see</emph> 14 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 11. &sect; 23. <emph type="i">As to Timber and the other enumerated Articles, see</emph> 22 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 78. &sect; 3, 4. <emph type="i">As to Goods herein mentioned being of European Growth and Manufacture generally</emph>, 27 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 19. &sect; 10.</td>
					<td>&sect; 8.</td>
					<td>248
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>What Goods deemed Aliens' Goods and to pay Aliens' Duties.</td>
					<td>&sect; 9.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>In what Case and by what Means Foreignbuilt Ships shall be deemed English Ships.<br/>
						<emph type="i">See further</emph> 13 &amp; 14 <emph type="i">Car. c</emph>. 11. &sect; 6.</td>
					<td>&sect; 10.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Oath of Purchase of such Ship for a valuable Consideration and other Particulars.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>On Oath taken, Certificate under Hand and Seal of Officer.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Officer to keep Register of Certificates, and return Duplicates to Customs in London.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Officers of the Customs allowing Privilege to any Foreign-built Ship, until Certificate or Proof, &amp;c.</td>
					<td>&sect; 11.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Governors of Plantations, &amp;c. suffering Foreign-built Ships to load or unload without Certificate&mdash;Penalty.<br/>
						<emph type="i">Altered as to Foreign Ships purchased for Privateers</emph>, 6 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 37. &sect; 1.</td>
					<td>12 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 18. &sect; 11.</td>
					<td>248 
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proviso for Goods of the Streights or Levant.<br/>
						<emph type="i">Repealed as to the Importation of Raw Silk and Mohair Yarn, of the Product or Manufacture of Asia</emph>, 6 <emph type="i">G. I. c</emph>. 14.</td>
					<td>&sect; 12.</td>
					<td>249
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proviso for Importation of East India Commodities as to Growth.<br/>
						<emph type="i">Further Regulations</emph>, 37 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 117. &sect; 1. <emph type="i">and see</emph> 53 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 155. &sect; 7.</td>
					<td>&sect; 13.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proviso for Goods imported from Spain, Portugal, Azores, Madeira, or Canary Islands.</td>
					<td>&sect; 14.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proviso for Bullion and Goods taken by Way of Reprisal.</td>
					<td>&sect; 15.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proviso concerning Corn, Salt, and Fish of Scotland, and for Seal Oil of Russia.</td>
					<td>&sect; 16.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>The Duty payable upon Goods in French Ships, and on their taking in and setting on Shore Passengers.</td>
					<td>&sect; 17.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>How long to continue.<br/>
						<emph type="i">Enforced, and Penalty added</emph>, 13 &amp; 14 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 11. &sect; 24.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Sugars, Tobacco, &amp;c. of the Growth of Plantations, &amp;c. in America, Asia, or Africa, to be shipped only to English Dominions&mdash;Penalty.</td>
					<td>&sect; 18.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ships sailing from England, Ireland, or Wales to English Plantations, Bond, according to Tonnage, with Sureties, to bring Goods there loaded into England, &amp;c.</td>
					<td>&sect; 19.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ships coming from any other Port to the Plantations, Governors to take such Bond, or Certificate that such Bond has been given in England&mdash;Penalty.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>250
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Governors to return Bonds taken twice yearly to Customs in London.<br/>
						<emph type="i">This Section repealed as to the Word "Ireland" in such Bonds</emph>, 22 &amp; 23 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 26. &sect; 11.; <emph type="i">but that Section repealed</emph>, 20 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 10. &sect; 3. <emph type="i">during the Continuance of that Act. As to Security in the Case of Molasses and Syrups of the Plantations</emph>, 4 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 15. &sect; 23.; <emph type="i">and as to Security generally at American Ports</emph>, 6 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 52. &sect; 30. <emph type="i">As to Time limited for producing Certificates of bonded Ships having discharged Goods</emph>, 15 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 31. &sect; 4. <emph type="i">This Act confirmed</emph>, 13 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 14. <emph type="i">Persons sued for executing this Act may plead the General Issue</emph>, 13 &amp; 14 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 11. &sect; 17. <emph type="i">The Penalties</emph>, &amp;<emph type="i">c</emph>. <emph type="i">of this Act extended to Rice and Molasses</emph>, 3 &amp; 4 <emph type="i">Ann. c</emph>. 5. &sect; 12. <emph type="i">to Copper Ore</emph>, 8 <emph type="i">G. I. c</emph>. 8. &sect; 22.; <emph type="i">to Salt</emph>, 4 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 19. &sect; 1.
<emph type="i">and to Rum or other Spirits shipped in any British Colony</emph>, &amp; <emph type="i">c</emph>. <emph type="i">in America, and carried to the isle of Man</emph>, 5 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 39. &sect; 5. <emph type="i">This Act ratified, except as to Sugars exported from American Colonies</emph>, 12 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 30 &sect; 1.; <emph type="i">as to Sales of British-built Ships to Foreigners</emph>, 13 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 26.
<emph type="i">For the Extension of this and other Acts therein mentioned to the Trade between Colonies in America and the West indies and Ireland</emph>, 20 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 10. <emph type="i">East India Ships considered as British-built</emph>, 21 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 65. &sect; 33.; <emph type="i">and see Regulations as to Built of Ships</emph>, 27 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 19. &sect; 10. <emph type="i">And as to further Regulations as to Trade with America</emph>, 37 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 97. &sect; 1&mdash;22.; <emph type="i">and Ships of Country in Amity may import and export Goods to and from India, subject; to Regulations as therein mentioned</emph>, 37 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 117.
<emph type="i">The Trade to and from Malta may be regulated by Orders in Council, notwithstanding this Act</emph>, 41 <emph type="i">G. III. (U. K.) c</emph>. 103. <emph type="i">Regulations as to Goods therein enumerated</emph>, 43 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 153. <emph type="i">As to Trade to Cape of Goods Hope</emph>, 46 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 30. &sect; 1.&mdash;48 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 105. <emph type="i">Indemnity to importers and Exporters into and from the West India Islands and conquered Territories</emph>, 46 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 53. <emph type="i">His Majesty empowered, by Order in Council, to permit Importation of Naval Stores from Places in Amity, in Ships however navigated</emph>, 47 <emph type="i">G. III. </emph>
						<emph type="i">Sess</emph>. 2. <emph type="i">c</emph>. 27. <emph type="i">Goods from Portuguese South America may be imported in Portugues Ships</emph>, 48 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. II.
<emph type="i">Subjects of the United Provinces permitted to trade with certain Colonies as therein mentioned, notwithstanding this Act</emph>, 54 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 72.; <emph type="i">but that Act is repealed by</emph> 56 <emph type="i">G. III. </emph>
						<emph type="i">c</emph>. 91. &sect; 10. <emph type="i">Trade and Commerce with French Colonies may be regulated by the King in Council not withstanding this Act</emph>, 55 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 146. <emph type="i">and Goods may be re-exported from Malta and Gibraltor to the United Kingdom, subject to such Regulations and in Vessels of such Tonnage as prescribed by Stat</emph>. 53 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 155.&mdash;57 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 36. &sect; 9. <emph type="i">notwithstanding this Act</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For establishing Articles and Orders for regulating and Government of the Navy, &amp;c.</td>
					<td>13 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 9.</td>
					<td>311
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>The Articles which are to be observed.</td>
					<td>&sect; 1.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Provisoes touching the Powers of the Lord Admiral.<br/>
						<emph type="i">This Act repealed</emph>, 22 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 33. &sect; 1.</td>
					<td>&sect; 3.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For confirming an Act, intituled, An Act for encouraging and increasing of Shipping and Navigation, &amp;c.</td>
					<td>13 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 14.</td>
					<td>316</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Statutes 12 Car. II. c. 18. c. 32. c. 36. c.34. c. 13. c. 6. and 12 Car. II. pr. P. 253. confirmed, and declared to have the full force of Acts or Parliament.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>317
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For providing Carriage by Land and by Water for the Use of His Majesty's Navy and Ordnance.</td>
					<td>14 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 20.</td>
					<td>413
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Carriages, Horses, &amp;c. may be taken for the Service of the Navy or Ordnance, on Notice to Two or more neighbouring Justices, who shall issue Warrants to Places within 12 Miles.</td>
					<td>&sect; 1.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Rate of Recompence.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Admiralty, Commissioners of the Navy, Master and Lieutenant of the Ordnance, may impress Ships, Hoys, &amp;c. for the Service.</td>
					<td>&sect; 2.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Rates of Hire.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>If not agreed, to be settled by Trinity House of Deptford Strond.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Persons refusing to furnish Carriages, Ships, &amp;c. or after they have undertaken, neglecting, &amp;c. the same; on Conviction by Oath of Officer or Two other Witnesses&mdash;Penalty, to be levied by Distress.</td>
					<td>&sect; 3.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proviso respecting Length of Journey and Continuance in Employment.</td>
					<td>&sect; 4.</td>
					<td>414
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Justices, or Persons appointed by Admiralty, &amp;c. taking Gift to spare any Person, or charging Persons not liable, or impressing more Carriages than necessary&mdash;Penalty &pound;10.</td>
					<td>&sect; 5.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Persons not empowered impressing Carriages, Horses, Ships, &amp;c.&mdash;Punishment as by Stat. 12 Car. II. c. 24.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>In what Case certain Ships, Hoys, &amp;c. not liable.</td>
					<td>&sect; 6.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Continuance of Act.</td>
					<td>&sect; 7.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proviso for extra Allowance for Carriage of Timber within the Division of the New Forest.<br/>
						<emph type="i">This Act continued for Seven Years</emph>, 1 <emph type="i">Jac. II. c</emph>. 11. &sect; 1.&mdash;4 &amp; 5 <emph type="i">W.</emph> &amp; <emph type="i">M. c</emph>. 24. &sect; 1. <emph type="i">and for Seven Years, from Sept</emph>. 1700. 11 &amp; 12 <emph type="i">W. III. c</emph>. 13. &sect; 1. <emph type="i">but now expired</emph>.</td>
					<td>&sect; 8.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>To prevent Disturbances of Seamen, and to preserve the Stores belonging to His Majesty's Navy.</td>
					<td>16 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 5. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
					<td>520
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Certain Officers may punish Disturbances by Seamen and others relating to the Navy Service, by Fine or Imprisonment.</td>
					<td>&sect; 1.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>May discharge Penalty, or for Non-payment thereof imprison.</td>
					<td>&sect; 2.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Fines paid to the Clerk of the Chest.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>May bind to good Behaviour.</td>
					<td>&sect; 3.</td>
					<td>521
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>May inquire concerning embezzling of Stores and Ammunition, and search for the same, and imprison until Recognizance entered into.</td>
					<td>&sect; 4.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Two Officers may proceed.</td>
					<td>&sect; 5.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Continuance of Act, Two Years, &amp;c.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>To prevent Disturbances of Seamen, and preserve Stores belonging to the Navy.</td>
					<td>18 &amp; 19 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 12. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
					<td>615
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Jurisdiction of Treasurer</td>
					<td>&sect; 1.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Commissioners of the Navy to punish Offenders&mdash;Fine and Imprisonment.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Power of Committal.</td>
					<td>18 &amp; 19 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 12. &sect; 1.</td>
					<td>615
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>How Fines to be applied.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>616
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Commissioners, &amp;c. may bind to good Behaviour.</td>
					<td>&sect; 2.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Commissioners, &amp;c. may search for Ammunition, &amp;c. embezzled&mdash;Punishment of Offenders.</td>
					<td>&sect; 3.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Officers to exercise the Power given by this Act in any Franchise.</td>
					<td>&sect; 4.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Executors of Seaman shall pay but 12d. for proving the Will.</td>
					<td>&sect; 5.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Taking larger Fee&mdash;Penalty &pound;10.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Continuance of Act, Two Years, &amp;c.</td>
					<td>&sect; 6.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>For the Revival of Stat. 18 &amp; 19 Car. II. c. 12.</td>
					<td>22 &amp; 23 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 23. <emph type="i">exp</emph>.</td>
					<td>741
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>The said Act, except &sect; 5, continued.</td>
					<td>&sect; 1.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Where the Value of the Stores embezzled is under 20s., Treasurer of the Navy, &amp;c. may convict and impose Penalty, which may be levied by Distress&mdash;If not sufficient Distress, Imprisonment.</td>
					<td>&sect; 2.</td>
					<td>742
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Power to Treasurer, &amp;c. to grant Warrant to enter any Ship in the Day-time, and search for stolen Goods&mdash;Contents of Warrant.</td>
					<td>&sect; 3.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>In case of Resistance the Persons deputed may enter and break open Hatches and take the Goods.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proviso respecting undue Seizures.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Personating Seamen, &amp;c. in the Presence of Commissioners or Paymaster, in order to receive Money due to Seamen, &amp;c.&mdash;Punishment.</td>
					<td>&sect; 4.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Counterfeiting the Hands of Treasurer, &amp;c. of the Navy, or producing a counterfeit Ticket&mdash;Committed, or to find Surety.</td>
					<td>&sect; 5.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Power to Treasurer, &amp;c. of the Navy to administer an Oath.</td>
					<td>&sect; 6.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>A general Liberty given to the said Treasurer, &amp;c. to execute their Power.</td>
					<td>&sect; 7.</td>
					<td>743
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Only 5s. to be paid for the Probate of any Will, or granting Letters of Administration of the Estate of any Person dying in the Pay of His Majesty's Navy, except the Estate be &pound;20 or upwards&mdash;Penalty &pound;10.</td>
					<td>&sect; 8.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Stat. 22 Car. II. c. 5. confirmed.</td>
					<td>&sect; 9.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Powers given by this Act may be executed by Lord High Admiral.</td>
					<td>&sect; 10.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>No double Punishment.</td>
					<td>&sect; 11.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.
</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Continuance of Act, 7 Years, &amp;c.</td>
					<td>&sect; 12.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<sub>
				<emph type="i">See</emph> Ships.</sub>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<head>
				<key>Needle-work</key>
				<emph type="i">See</emph> Lace.</head>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<head>
				<key>Newcastle</key>, Port of</head>
			<table id="t3">
				<tr>
					<td cols="3"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<th>Statute</th>
					<th>Page</th>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
Act for Admeasurement of Keels and Boats carrying Coals.</td>
					<td>30 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 8.</td>
					<td>891</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<head>
				<key>New Forest</key>
				<emph type="i">See</emph> Naby.</head>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<head>
				<key>Non-Conformists</key>
			</head>
			<table id="t4">
				<tr>
					<td cols="3"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<th>Statute</th>
					<th>Page</th>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
For restraining Non-Conformists from inhabiting in Corporations.</td>
					<td>17 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 2.</td>
					<td>575</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Persons in Holy Orders not having declared their Assent to the Matters required in Stat. 14 Car. II. c. 4. to take the Oath in this Act mentioned.</td>
					<td>17 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 2. &sect; 1.</td>
					<td>575</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Persons preaching in Conventicles not to come within Five Miles of any Corporation&mdash;Sending Members to Parliament (Exception) before they have taken said Oath&mdash;Penalty &pound;40.</td>
					<td>&sect; 2.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Such Persons, or those not frequenting the Established Church, not to teach in any Public or Private School, &amp;c.&mdash;Penalty &pound; 40.</td>
					<td>&sect; 3.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Two Justices may commit Offenders charged on Oath, unless they make and subscribe Oath and Declaration.</td>
					<td>&sect; 4.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Proviso for Persons served with Process.<br/>
						<emph type="i">This Act repealed</emph> 52 <emph type="i">G. III. c</emph>. 155. &sect; 1.</td>
					<td>&sect; 5.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<head>
				<key>Norfolk and Norwich</key>
				<emph type="i">See</emph> Stuffs.</head>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<head>
				<key>Northampton</key>, Town of</head>
			<table id="t5">
				<tr>
					<td cols="3"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<th>Statute</th>
					<th>Page</th>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
For rebuilding of.</td>
					<td>27 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 1.</td>
					<td>798</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<head>
				<key>Northern Counties and Borders</key>
			</head>
			<table id="t6">
				<tr>
					<td cols="3"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<th>Statute</th>
					<th>Page</th>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
For preventing Theft, &amp;c. upon the Northern Borders of England.</td>
					<td>14 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 22.</td>
					<td>417</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>From Michaelmas 1662 for 5 Years, Justices in Sessions may make Order for charging the Inhabitants for the Safeguard of the said Counties.</td>
					<td>&sect; 1.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>The Amount above which the said Counties are not to be charged.</td>
					<td>&sect; 2.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Quarter Sessions may appoint Persons to have the Command of a certain Number of Men, and may issue Warrants for levying Money for the Safeguard of the said Counties.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>May be levied by Distress.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Justices may hear Complaints against Persons refusing to obey Act, and may bind over such Persons.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Justices may appoint Treasurers to receive such Monies, and may agree with Persons to be employed in the said Service.</td>
					<td>&sect; 3.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Persons employed in the Border Service corruptly forbearing to discover or apprehend Moss Troopers&mdash;Disability&mdash;Imprisonment.</td>
					<td>&sect; 4.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Justices may moderate Charge.</td>
					<td>&sect; 5.</td>
					<td>418</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Continuance of Act, 5 Years</td>
					<td>&sect; 6.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Statutes 4 Jac. I. c. 1. 7 Jac. I. c.1. revived.</td>
					<td>&sect; 7.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Clergy taken away or Transportation.<br/>
						<emph type="i">This Act continued for Seven Years from the above Expiration</emph>, 18 &amp; 19 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 3.&mdash;29 &amp; 30 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 2. <emph type="i">and by several subsequent Acts, and last until</emph> 1<emph type="i">st Sept</emph>. 1744, <emph type="i">by</emph> 6 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 37. &sect; 7. <emph type="i">and together with that Act made perpetual</emph>, 31 <emph type="i">G. II. c</emph>. 42. &sect; 1.</td>
					<td>18 &amp; 19 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 3. &sect; 2.</td>
					<td>598</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Statutes 14 Car. II. c. 22. 18 &amp; 19 Car. II. c. 3. continued for Seven Years, &amp;c.</td>
					<td>29 &amp; 30 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 2. &sect; 1.</td>
					<td>864</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Quarter Sessions of the said Counties to take Security of Persons employed in the Border Service for the Preservation of said Counties.</td>
					<td>&sect; 2.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Stolen Goods to be entered in Books to be kept in Market Towns within Fortyeight Hours after the same are stolen.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
					<td>
						<emph type="i">Ib</emph>.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Quarterly Sessions yearly, or every Two Years, in open Court, to appoint Persons for the said Service.</td>
					<td>&sect; 3.</td>
					<td>865</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Persons so employed to receive the Sacrament, and deliver Certificate to the next Quarter Sessions, and take the Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy, and subscribe the Declaration of Stat. 25 Car. II. c. 2. &sect; 8.<br/>
						<emph type="i">See Note to</emph> 14 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 22. <emph type="i">which seems also to apply to this Act</emph>.</td>
					<td>29 &amp; 30 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 2. &sect; 4.</td>
					<td>865</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<head>
				<key>Norway</key>
			</head>
			<table id="t7">
				<tr>
					<td cols="3"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<th>Statute</th>
					<th>Page</th>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Free Trade to.</td>
					<td>25 <emph type="i">Car. II. c</emph>. 7. &sect; 8.</td>
					<td>793</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<head>
				<key>Nuncupative Wills</key>
				<emph type="i">See</emph> Frauds and Perjuries.</head>
		</entry>
	</section>
</index>

