<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47199" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1625</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An A&bholigct;e for the ease in the obtayning of Licenses of Alienacion, and in the pleading of Alienacions with License, or of pardons of Alienacions without License, in the Court of Exchequer and elsewhere.[Rot. Parl. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Licences of Alienation shall be general.</head>
		<para id="p1">THAT the King&bholngs; Tenures, which are a principall flower of the Crowne, may not be concealed, and yet that the
Tenant&bholngs; of the King may not be unnecessarily charged, Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament,
That from and after the end of this &bhopcrl;sent Session of Parliament, all Licenses of Alienacion to be had and obtayned,
other then uppon raysing of uses by force of any Deed, from or out of the estate of the Covenanter, shalbe generall
to alien without expressing any uses.</para>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Fee to Officer for drawing, &amp;c. Alienations with Licence, and Pardon of Alienation without Licence.</head>
<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">Penalty on Officer taking greater or other Fee, 5s. for every 1d. received beyond or other than 30 s</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed; that from and after the end of this &bhopcrl;sent Session of Parliament, there shalbe paid to the
Tresurers Remembrancer in the Court of Exchequer, which now is, or at any tyme hereafter shalbe, or to any other in
any other Court or place in what office theise Pleading&bholngs; are or shalbe, and to his or their Clarke, or any under them,
for the drawing, pleading, entring, finishing, and discharging of an Alienacion with Licence, or of a pardon of Alienacion
without Licence, and the uses of the same in such cases onely, where the subje&bholigct; by the Lawes and Statutes of this
Realme ought to pleade, the s&bhooov;me of [thirtie shilling&bholngs;<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] and no more. And if the Tresurers Remembrancer for the
tyme being, or any other Officer by himselfe or his Clarke, or any other &bhopubr;son whatsoever, shall at any tyme or tymes
from and after the end of this &bhopcrl;sent Session of Parliament, exa&bholigct;, take, or receive any other or greater Fee, reward,
gratuitie or s&bhooov;me of mony, dire&bholigct;lie or indire&bholigct;lie uppon any colour or &bhopcrl;tence whatsoever, for the causes aforesaid, or
any of them, or for any thing thereunto belonging, That the offender therein contrary to the true meaning of this A&bholigct;e
shall forfeit and lose to the partie greived, the s&bhooov;me of five shilling&bholngs; for every penny, which he shall receive beyond or
above, or other then the s&bhooov;me of [thirtie shilling&bholngs;<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] before mentioned: such forfeitures to be recovered by the partie
greived by Information or A&bholigct;ion of Debt, to be brought in the Court&bholngs; of King&bholngs; Bench, or C&bhooov;mon Pleas, at the
ele&bholigct;ion of the plaintiffe, wherein no Priviledge, &bhopubrc;teccion, Inhibicion, or Injunccion, Ley Gager, or Essoine shalbe
allowed to the Defendant.</para>
</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Officer offending disqualified.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed, That every Officer, Clarke, or other Minister of the said Court of Exchequer, which
at any tyme after the end of this &bhopcrl;sent Session of Parliament shall offend therein, and be thereof duly convi&bholigct;ed, shalbe
from thenceforth utterlie disabled to be or contynue an Officer or Clarke, or to have any imployment in the said Court
of Exchequer, or any other Court of Justice.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">xxvi s. viii d. <emph type="i">King's Printer's Copy</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


