<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47197" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1625</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Acte for punishing of divers abuses c&bhooov;mitted on the Lord&bholngs; day called Sunday.[Rot. Parl. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Profanation of the Lord's Day;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">No Meetings for Sports by People out of their own Parishes, nor Bearbaitings, &amp;c. within them on the Lord's Day.; Penalty, 3 s. 4 d. leviable by Distress; or in Default, Punishment by the Stocks.; Limitation of Prosecution.; Proviso for Ecclesiastical Jurisdi&bholigct;ion.; Continuance of A&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">FORASMUCH as there is nothing more acceptable to God then the true and sincere Service and worshipp of him
according to his holy Will, and that the holy keeping of the Lord&bholngs; day, is a principall part of the true Service
of God, which in very many places of this Realme hath beene and now is &bhopubrc;faned and negle&bholigct;ed by a disorderlie sort
of people, in exercising and frequenting Bearebaiting, Bullbaiting, Enterludes, co&bhomov;on Playes, and other unlawfull
exercises and pastimes upon the Lord&bholngs; day; And for that many quarrell&bholngs; bloodshedd&bholngs; and other great inconveniences
have growen by the resort and concourse of people going out of their owne Parishes to such disordered and
unlawfull exercises and pastimes negle&bholigct;ing Divine service both in their owne Parishes and elswhere, Be it ena&bholigct;ed by
the King&bholngs; most Excellent Majestie, the Lord&bholngs; Spirituall and Temporall, and the C&bhooov;mons in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament
assembled, and by the Authoritie of the same, That from and after fortie dayes next after the end of this Session of
Parliament, there shalbe no meeting&bholngs; assemblies or concourse of people out of their owne Parishes on the Lord&bholngs; day
within this Realme of England, or any the Dominions thereof, for any sport&bholngs; or pastimes whatsoever; nor any
Bearebaiting, Bullbaiting, Enterludes c&bhooov;mon Playes or other unlawfull exercises or pastimes used by any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons
within their owne Parishes, and that every &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons offending in any the &bhopcrl;misses, shall forfeit for every offence
three shilling&bholngs; foure pence, The same to be employed and converted to the use of the poore of the Parish where such
offence shalbe c&bhooov;mitted, And that any one Justice of the Peace of the Countie, or the cheife Officer or Officers of
any Cittie Borough or Towne corporate where such offence shalbe c&bhooov;mitted uppon his or their view, or confession of the
partie, or proofe of any one or more witnesse by oath, which the said Justice or cheife Officer or Officers shall by
vertue of this A&bholigct; have authoritie to minister, shall fynde any &bhopubr;son offending in the &bhopcrl;misses, the said Justice or cheife
Officer or Officers, shall give warrant under his or their hand and Seale to the [Constables<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] or Churchwardens of the
Parishe or Parishes where such offence shalbe c&bhooov;mitted to levie the said penaltie so to be assessed, by way of distresse
and sale of the good&bholngs; of every such offendor, rendring to the said offenders the overplus of the monie raised of the
said good&bholngs; so to be sold, And in default of such distres, that the partie offending, be set publiquelie in the stock&bholngs; by
the space of three houres; And that if any man be sued or impeached for execucion of this Lawe, he shall and may
pl&eacute;ad the generall issue, and give the said matter of Justificacion in evidence. Provided that no man be impeached by
this A&bholigct;, except he be called in question within one moneth next after the said offence c&bhooov;mitted. Provided also, that
the Ecclesiasticall Jurisdiccion within this Realme, or any the Dominions thereof, by vertue of this A&bholigct; or any thing therein
conteyned, shall not be abridged, but that the Ecclesiasticall Court may punish the said offences, as if this a&bholigct;e had
not bene made: This A&bholigct; to contynue untill the end of the first Session of the next Parliament, and no longer.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">Constable <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


