<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47203" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1625</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act, that this Session of Parliament shall not determyne by his Majesties Royall assent to this and some other A&bholigct;es. [Rot. Parl. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">The Kinges most Excellent Majestie taking into his gracious and princelie consideracion, the many and weightie
businesses, which in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament have bene begun, most whereof yet depend unfinished, And
considering the &bhopcrl;sent daunger by the increase of the Sicknesse, and the inconveniencie of the season, and other
important reasons, that do necessarilie require a speedie adjournement of the Parliament at this tyme, before soe manie
and great affaires can be deliberatelie, and maturelie concluded and determined: And to take away all doubt, whether
his Majesties Royall assent unto one or more A&bholigct;&bholngs; of Parliament, will not be a determinacion of this &bhopcrl;sent Session,
His Majestie is well pleased, that it may be ena&bholigct;ed,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The King's Royal Assent to this and other A&bholigct;s shall not determine this Session.</head>
			<para id="p2">And be it ena&bholigct;ed by Authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, That his Majestie at his good pleasure may before the
Adjournement of this Parliament, either in &bhopubr;son or by his C&bhooov;mission, or l[ia]res Patent&bholngs; as to him shall seeme
good, give his Royall assent unto such, and so many Billes purporting A&bholigct;&bholngs; of Parliament, having by the assent
of the Lord&bholngs; Spirituall and Temporall and C&bhooov;mons passed in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, as to his most Excellent
Majestie shalbe found expedient, And that notwithstanding such assent to any such Bills, or to this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;, this
&bhopcrl;sent Session of Parliament shall not thereby determine; but the same to be adjourned, as to his Majestie shalbe
found requisite, for the generall good and welfare of this Kingdome,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Matters depending to continue.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">All Statutes which are to have continuance until the End of the present Session are to remain in force.; Proviso if the present Session determine by Dissolution</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And that all Billes and matters whatsoever, depending in the same Parliament, not fully determined or ena&bholigct;ed
before such Adjournement, shall remaine and contynue in the same state and plight, as they are, or shalbe the day
of the said Adjournement: And that all Statut&bholngs; and A&bholigct;&bholngs; of Parliament, which are to have contynuance unto the
end of this &bhopcrl;sent Session, shall be of full force after the said Adjournement, untill this &bhopcrl;sent Session be fully
ended and determined. And if this Session shall determine by dissolucion of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, then all the
A&bholigct;&bholngs; aforesaid, shalbe contynued untill the end of the first Session of the next Parliament: And all Statutes and
A&bholigct;&bholngs; of Parliament, which before the said Adjournement shall passe by his Majesties Royall assent, shalbe put in
execucion ymediatelie after fortie daies after the said Adjournement, notwithstanding that by the wordes or letter of
the said A&bholigct;&bholngs;, or any of them they be lymitted to take effe&bholigct; or be put in execucion, from, or at any tyme after
the end of this &bhopcrl;sent Session.</para>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Rot. Parl. nu. 8.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">An Acte for the setling and confirmacion of Coppihold Estates and Customes of the Tennts in base tenure of the
Mannor of Cheltenham in the Countie of Glouc[ester] and of the Mannor of Asheley otherwise called Charleton Kings
in the said Countie being holden of the said Mannor of Cheltenham according to an agreement thereof made
betweene the King&bholngs; most excellent Majestie being then Prince of Wales Duke of Cornewall and of Yorke and
Earle of Chester Lord of the said Mannor of Cheltenham and Giles Grevill Esquire Lord of the said Mannor of
Asheley and the said Coppiholders of the said severall Mannors.</para>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Rot. Parl. nu. 9</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">An Acte for the enabling and confirmacion of an agreement or composicion made betweene the King&bholngs; Majesties
C&bhooov;missioners of Revenue, his Majestie then being Prince of Wales Duke of Cornewall and Earle of Chester
on his Majesties behalfe and his Majesties Coppiholders of his Highnes Mannor of Macclesfeild in the Countie of
Chester and of a Decree made in the Court of Exchequer at Chester for the &bhopubr;fe&bholigct; creacion and confirmacion of
certaine Land&bholngs; and Tenements Parcell of the said Mannor to be Coppihold and customary Land&bholngs; according to
the tenor of the same Decree.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


