<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47209" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1627</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the establishing of the Estates of the ten[a]nts of Bromfeild and Yale in the Countie of Denbigh and of the Tenures Rents and Servics thereuppon reserved according to a late Composicion made for the same with the Kings most Excellent Majestie then Prince of Wales.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Lordships and Manors of Bromfield and Yale forfeited to the Crown.</head>
		<para id="p1"><emph type="i">Inheritance of the Tenants questioned by the Crown.; Commission of Survey, 4 Eliz.; Composition between the Crown and the Tenants.; Surrender by the Tenants to the Crown.; Leases thereupon from the Crown to the Tenants.; The aforesaid Composition questioned, and Proceedings thereon in Exchequer Chamber whereby the said Composition was confirmed.; Grant to the King, then Prince of Wales, of the said Lordships, &amp;c. by Letters Patent 18 Feb. 14. Jac. I</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">In most humble manner doe beseech your most Excellent Majestie your true and loyall Subject&bholngs; the Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs;
of the Lordshipps of Bromfeild and Yale in your Highnes Countie of Denbigh, That whereas the Lordshipp&bholngs;
and Mannors of Bromfeild and Yale within the Countie of Denbigh in or about the tenth yeare of the Raigne of
King Henry the seaventh were forfeited and came to the Crowne of England by the attainder of Sir William
Stanley Knight, Before which time the Tennant&bholngs; of the said Lordshipps or Mannors had tyme out of minde of man
held and enjoyed divers Messuages Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; and Hereditament&bholngs; being part and parcell of the said
Lordshipps and Mannors clayming to hold the same to them and their heires by Coppie of Court Rolle and to have
therein a customarie estate of inheritance by and under certaine yearelie Rent&bholngs; Customes and Services, And the
said Messuages Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; and Hereditament&bholngs; then were and by all the time aforesaid had bene by the
Custome of the said Mannors discendable unto the heires of every such Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt and the Widowes of such Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs;
were therein endowable and endowed for terme of their lives as of land&bholngs; of inheritance. And likewise from and
after the said forfeiture and after such c&bhooov;ming of the said Lordshipps and Mannors unto the Crowne, the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs;
in like sort and manner claymed and peaceablie and quietlie held and enjoyed their Messuages Landes Tenement&bholngs;
and Hereditament&bholngs; so holden of the said Lordshipps or Mannors to them and their Heires by Coppie of Court
Rolle without any question suite eviccion or interrupcion untill about the begynning of the Raigne of the late
Queene Elizabeth of famous memorie. Att or about which tyme the said estates of the Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs;of the said
Lordshipps or Mannors were on the behalfe of the said late Queene questioned and &bhopcrl;tended not to be estates of
Inheritance, and besides the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; in generall were questioned for and concerning a certaine yearelie Rent
of one hundred and five pounds within the said Lordshipps &bhopcrl;tended and alleadged to have bene therein withdrawne and
decayed within the time incurred from and after the Raigne of King Edward the third or thereabout&bholngs;, And thereuppon
a C&bhooov;mission issued in the fourth yeare of the Raigne of the said late Queene for surveying of the said Lordshipps
and Mannors and reviving of the said rent, uppon which C&bhooov;mission although it could not be discovered by any
matter of record or otherwise which of the said Messuages Land&bholngs; or Tenement&bholngs; were liable or chargeable to or with
the said yearelie rent of one hundred and five pounds soe &bhopcrl;tended to have bene decayed, yet by &bhopubr;swasion [of<emph type="p">1</emph>] the
then C&bhooov;missioners a Composi&bhocotil;n was then had and made by and betweene the said C&bhooov;missioners on the behalfe of
the said late Queene and the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; That they the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; should surrender and relinquish their said
Customary Estates of Inheritance and revive the said decayed Rent of one hundred and five pound&bholngs; Ann&bhouov; and
also pay unto the said late Queene for a Fine the s&bhooov;me of eight hundred pound&bholngs; of lawfull mony of England, And
that for and in consideration thereof the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; their Heires and Assignes should have good firme and &bhopcrl;petuall
Estates in their said Messuages Lands Tenement&bholngs; and Hereditaments by Leases successivelie to be made unto
them from forty yeeres to forty yeeres for ever. In pursuance and &bhopubr;formance of which agreement and Composi&bhocotil;n
the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; did relinquish and surrender their said Customarie Estates of Inheritance charged their said Messuages
Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; with the said Rent of one hundred and five pounds &bhopubr; Ann&bhouov; which hath ever sithence been
accordinglie payd, and paid to the said late Queene the said Fine of eight hundred pounds, And severall Leases
were thereuppon alsoe made unto the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; from the said late Queene of their said severall and respe&bholigct;ive
Messuages Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; and Hereditament&bholngs; for fortie yeares with a Covent<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; from the said late Queene in
every of the said Leases conteyned for the renewing of the same Leases from time to time uppon expiracion surrender
or otherwise for like Terme and Rent, paying onelie two yeares old Rent for a Fine for such new Lease, And the
said Agreement and Composicion was firmelie and inviolablie holden and kept during the reigne of the said late Queene:
and howsoever as well during that time as in the beginning of the raigne of our late Soveraigne Lord King James
of famous memorie the said Composicion were questioned and sought to be impeached by some who had obtayned
Graunt&bholngs; of part of the said Mannors uppon &bhopcrl;tence that the said Coven<emph type="p">a</emph>nt did not binde the Crowne yet uppon
severall Suit&bholngs; thereuppon in His Majesties Court of Exchequer Chamber severall Decrees were there had and made,
whereby the said Composicion was ratified and confirmed and the said Coven<emph type="p">a</emph>nt holden and decreed to be reall and
to binde the Crowne and all others clayming any Estate in the said Lordshipps or Mannors from or under the
Crowne whereby the said estate of the Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; aforesaid were againe setled in peace and quiett and so by them
holden and enjoyed and new Leases were from time to time made unto the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; by and from the said late
King according to the Composicion aforesaid untill the said late King in and by his Highnes Letters Patent&bholngs; sealed
with the Great Seale of England bearing date at Westminster the eighteenth day of Februarie in the fourteenth
yeere of his said late Majesties raigne of England did give and graunte unto your Majestie being then Prince of Wales
amongest other things the said Lordshipps Mannors Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; of Bromfeild and Yale. To have and
to hold to your Majestie being Prince and to your Heires King&bholngs; of England in augmentacion and increase of the
lands and possessions of the principalitie of Wales and of your Highnes being Prince, and by the said l[ia]res Patents
did unite and annex the said Lordshipps and Mannors, and willed and declared the same to be united and annexed
to the said Principalitie.</para>
		<para id="p3"><emph type="i">The aforesaid Composition again questioned.; Agreement and Composition by the Tenants for Estates to them from the Prince of Wales for &pound;10,000</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">After which time that is to saie in or about the twentith yeare of the said late King&bholngs; raigne the said
Composicion and agreement so as aforesaid made in the fourth yeere of the raigne of the said late Queene was
againe questioned by the C&bhooov;missioners of the Revenue of your Majestie then Prince of Wales so as the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs;
could not obtaine any new Leases of the &bhopcrl;misses to be made unto them for the Termes and under the Coven<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; and
Agreement&bholngs; contayned in the said Composicion nor for any longer Terme then onelie for three lives or one and
thirtie yeares, and that also for an Arbitrarie Fine to be paid for such Leases and uppon the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; refusall
so to accept the same, some of their Land&bholngs; after the expiracion of their Leases were by your Majesties said
C&bhooov;missioners graunted and passed away to others whereby much trouble and suite was like to have ensued. For
&bhopcrl;vencion whereof the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; at length compounded with the said C&bhooov;missioners and agreed to give and pay unto
your Majestie then Prince of Wales the s&bhooov;me of Ten thousand pound&bholngs; or thereabout&bholngs;for estates to be made unto
them and their Heires of and in their severall Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; to be holden in Fee Farme by and under the
Rent&bholngs; and Services formerlie reserved due or payable for the same For which said great s&bhooov;me of mony the said
Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; have no other benefitt then onelie the quieting and setling of their Estates and a discharge of the foresaid
Fine of Two yeares old rent payable uppon the new taking of any Lease of the &bhopcrl;misses, which by the expiracion of
the said Leases by effluxion of time was to be payable but once in forty yeares there being uppon the said last
mencioned Composicion reserved unto your Majestie your Heires and Successors all other rents and services whatsoever
formerlie due or payable for the same.</para>
		<para id="p5"><emph type="i">Performance and Execution of such Agreement and Composition secured by Letters Patent; Tenor thereof</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">And for the better &bhopubr;formance and execucion of the said last mencioned composicion and to the end that there
might be there uppon a firme and sure estate in Fee Farme made unto the said Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nt&bholngs; of their severall and respe&bholigct;ive
Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; your Majestie then Prince of Wales by your Highnes &bhoalias;res Patent&bholngs; under your then great
Seale bearing date the fourth day of Januarie in the two and twentith yeere of his said late Majesties raigne of England
Did give graunt and surrender back the said Lordshipps Mannors and other the &bhopcrl;misses to the said late King as in
and by the said l[ia]res Patent&bholngs; relacion being thereunto had more plainelie appeareth. And afterward&bholngs; in further
pursuance and execucion of the said last mencioned Composicion at the request and nominacion of your Majestie
then Prince of Wales the said late King&bholngs; Majestie by his Highnes l&bhoalias;res Patent&bholngs; bearing date at Westminster the
seaven and twentith day of Januarie in the two and twentith yeare of his said Raigne of England for the consideracions
in the same l[ir]res Patent&bholngs; mencioned Did give and graunte unto Sir Henrie Hobarte Knight and Baronett late
cheife Justice of the C&bhooov;mon Pleas and then your Highnes Chauncellor Sir James Fullerton Knight then Master of
your Highnes Ward&bholngs; and Liveries Sir John Walter Knight then your Highnes Attorny generall and now Cheife
Baron of your Majesties Court of Exchequer and Sir Thomas Trevor Knight then your Highnes Sollicitor generall
and now one of the Barons of your Majesties said Court of Exchequer the said Lordshipps Mannors Towneshipps
Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; of Bromfeild and Yale in the said Countie of Denbigh with all and singuler the right&bholngs;
members and Appurten<emph type="p">a</emph>nces thereof. To have and to hold the same unto the said Sir Henry Hobart Sir James
Fullerton Sir John Walter and Sir Thomas Trevor and their heires and assignes, To be holden of the said late King
his heires and successors as of the Mannor of Eastgreenwich in the Countie of Kent by Fealtie onelie in free and
c&bhooov;mon Soccage and not in Capite nor by Knight&bholngs; service And to the end that the said Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; and
Hereditament&bholngs; might be the better assured and conveyed unto your said Subject&bholngs; according to the purport and true
meaning of the said last mencioned Composicion, our said late Soveraigne Lord in and by the said l&bhoalias; res patent&bholngs; Did
give and graunt unto the said Patentees and their heires and assignes full free lawfull and absolute power and
authoritie without ympeachment from time to time. To give graunt or alien all and singuler the &bhopcrl;misses or any
part thereof parcell of the said Lordshipps and Mannors as much as should seeme best to the said Patentees their
Heires and Assignes for the tyme being to any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons their Heires and Assignes in Fee Farme for such
yearelie Rents and services of and uppon the same Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; and Hereditament&bholngs; to be reserved as to the
said Patentees their heires and assignes for the time being should seeme fitt, To be holden of the same Patentees their
Heires and Assignes as of the said Lordshipps and Mannors or any of them respe&bholigct;ivelie, whereunto the said Land&bholngs;
Tenement&bholngs; and Hereditament&bholngs; so to be given graunted or aliened severallie and respectivelie did belong and
appertaine in free and c&bhooov;mon Soccage and not in Capite nor by Knight&bholngs; service, as in and by the said last recited
l&bhoalias;res Patent&bholngs; more at large appeareth.</para>
		<para id="p7"><emph type="i">The last above mentioned Letters Patent confirmed.</emph></para>
		<para id="p8">May it therefore please your most excellent Majestie at the humble suite and peticion of your said Subje&bholigct;&bholngs; That
it may be ena&bholigct;ed by your Majestie by and with the assent of the Lord&bholngs; Spirituall and Temporall and the C&bhooov;mons
in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled, And be it enacted by the authoritie of the same, That the said l[ia]res Patent&bholngs; before
recited to be made to the said Sir Henry Hobart Sir James Fullerton Sir John Walter and Sir Thomas Trevor and
their Heires and every Guift Graunt Power Authoritie Clause Article and Sentence therein contayned shalbe ratified
and confirmed by the Authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament and shall for ever hereafter be and remaine and shall be
reputed taken and adjudged to be and to have been good &bhopubr;fect and effectuall in the Law for all thing&bholngs; therein
contayned according to the true intent and meaning of the same. The annexacion and uniting of the said &bhopcrl;misses
to the said Principalitie of Wales by the said first recited l&bhoalias;res Patent&bholngs; or any thing Clause or Sentence in the said
l&bhoalias;res Patent&bholngs; mencioned or contayned or any other matter causeor thing whatsoever to the contrary thereof in any
wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<para id="p9"><emph type="i">Former Grants, &amp;c. and Grants to be made within Two Years by Patentees confirmed.</emph></para>
		<para id="p10">And be it likewise ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, That all Guift&bholngs; Graunt&bholngs; and Alienacions alreadie made
or at any time within two yeares now next ensuing to be made by the said Patentees or the Survivor or Survivors
of them or by the Heires or Assignes of them or the Survivor of them of any Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; or Hereditament&bholngs;
in the said l[ia]res Patent&bholngs; comprised and all Tenures Rent&bholngs; and Services reserved by or uppon the same Guift&bholngs; Graunt&bholngs;
and Alienacions and every of them, So that the Rent&bholngs; and Services formerlie due or payable for the same be
thereuppon reserved shalbe ratified and confirmed by the Authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament and shalbe and remaine
and shalbe reputed taken and adjudged to be good &bhopubr;fect and effe&bholigct;uall in the Law for all thing&bholngs; therein contayned
according to the true intent and meaning of the same and of the said l&bhoalias;res Patent&bholngs; made and graunted to the said
Sir Henry Hobart Sir James Fullerton Sir John Walter and Sir Thomas Trevor and their Heires, The annexacion
and uniting of the said Lordshipps Mannors Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; of Bromfeild and Yale with the Appurten<emph type="p">a</emph>nc&bholngs;
to the said Principalitie of Wales or any other matter cause or thing whatsoever to the contrary thereof in anywise
notwithstanding, And that all and every &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons to whome any such Guift Graunt or Alienacion hath bene
or within the tyme aforesaid shalbe made and his and their Heires and Assignes shall and may have hold and for ever
enjoy the Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; and Hereditament&bholngs; so to him or them given graunted or aliened as is aforesaid under
and uppon the severall Rent&bholngs; and Services thereby reserved or to be reserved and according to the intent and true
meaning of the said Guift&bholngs; Graunt&bholngs; and Alienacions without any Impeachment Let or Disturbance of or by your
Highnes your Heires or Successors or of or by the said Patentees their Heires or Assignes or any of them or of
or by anie &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons lawfullie clayming by from or under your Majestie or the said Patentees or any of them.</para>
		<para id="p11"><emph type="i">General Saving other than to the King and the Patentees.</emph></para>
		<para id="p12">Saving neverthelesse to all and every &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons bodies Pollitique and Corporate their Heires and Successors
Executors and Administrators and every of them other then your most excellent Majestie your Heires and Successors
and other then the said Patentees their Heires and Assignes all such Estat&bholngs; Possessions Right Entryes Condicions
Titles and Demaund&bholngs; whatsoever as they or anie of them had shall may or ought to have of in to or out of the said
Mannors Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; and &bhopcrl;misses or any of them in such and the same Estate degree manner and forme to
all intent&bholngs; and purposes as if this A&bholigct; had not bene made.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">1 of of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>

