<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47200" pubid="351" publish="true">
<title>Charles I, 1625</title>
<subtitle>Chapter IV. An Acte for the further restraint of Tipling in Innes, Alehouses, and other Vi&bholigct;ualling Houses. [Rot. Parl. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>Recital of 21 Jac. I. c. 7. &sect; 2. extending Penalties of I Jac. I. c. 9. &amp; 4 Jac. I. c. 5. to all Persons whatever found tippling in Inns, &amp;c.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">Penalties of Stat. I Jac. I. c. 9. extended to Inn-keepers permitting tippling by Persons not Inhabitants.</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">WHEREAS in the last Parliament, it was ena&bholigct;ed, that if any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons wheresoever his or their habitacion,
or abiding be, should after be found, uppon view or his owne confession, or proofe of one witnesse, to be
tipling in any Inne Alehouse, or Victualling house, such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons should be thenceforth adjudged and construed to
be within the Statutes of the first and fourth yeares of the late King&bholngs; Majesties reigne, King James of famous memory:
The one intituled, An A&bholigct; to restraine the inordinate haunting of tipling in Innes Alehouses, and other Vi&bholigct;ualling
Houses: And the other intituled, An A&bholigct;e to represse the odious and loathsome sinne of drunkennesse, as if he or they
had inhabited and dwelled in the Citie, Towne corporate, Markett towne, Village or Hamlett, where the Inne,
Alehouse, or Victualling house was or should be, where he or they should be so found tipling, should incurre the
like penaltie, and the same to be in such sort levied and disposed, as in the said A&bholigct; is expressed, concerning such
as there inhabite, but no punishment by any, or either of the said A&bholigct;es, or by any other Statute, is infli&bholigct;ed uppon the
Innekeeper, Alehousekeeper, or Vi&bholigct;ualler that &bhopubr;mitts [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] suffers such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons not there inhabiting to tipple in
his Inne, Alehouse, or Vi&bholigct;ualling House: For remedy whereof, be it ena&bholigct;ed, That every Innekeep, Alehousekeep, and
other Vi&bholigct;ualler, that at any tyme after the end of this Session of Parliament, shall &bhopubr;mitt and suffer any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons,
not inhabiting in the Cittie, Towne corporate, Markett Towne, Village, or Hamlett, where such Inne, Alehouse, or
Vi&bholigct;ualling House is, or shalbe, to tipple in the saide Inne, Alehouse, or Vi&bholigct;ualling House, contrary to the true intent
of any, or either of the said former Statutes, the said Innekeeper, Alehousekeeper, and Vi&bholigct;ualler so offending, shall
incurre the same penaltie, and in such manner to be proved, levied, and disposed, as in the former Statute of the first
yeare of his said late Majesties Raigne, is appointed for &bhopubr;mitting such to tipple as dwell in the same Cittie, Towne
corporate, Markett Towne, Village, or Hamlett.</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Tavern-keepers declared to be within the A&bholigct;.</head>
<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed, That the Keepers of Tavernes, and such as doe sell Wine in their houses, and doe
alsoe keepe Innes, or Vi&bholigct;ualling in their houses, shalbe taken to be within the said two former Statutes, and also
within this Statute.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


