<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47208" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1627</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act for Contynuance and Repeale of divers Statuts.[ Rot. Parl. nu. 7]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>1 Eliz. c. 17. except a Proviso for certain River Rents to the Crown.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">13 Eliz. c. 20. with Additions, &#x0026;c. thereto by 14 Eliz. c. 11. 18 Eliz. c. 11. 43 Eliz. c. 9</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament that one A&bholigct;e made in the first yeare of the Raigne of
the late Queene Elizabeth entituled An A&bholigct;e for the &bhopcrl;servacion of Spawne and Frye of Fish except the Proviso
in the said A&bholigct; mencioned that the same A&bholigct;e shall not extend to the Rivers of Tweed nor Waters or Rivers whereof
the Queene was aunswered of any yearelie Rent or Proffitt nor to Farmers Owners or Occupiers of the Rivers of Wye
Uske and other Rivers in the said proviso mencioned or conteyned, One A&bholigct; made in the thirteenth yeare of the Raigne
of the late Queene Elizabeth entituled An A&bholigct; touching Leases of Benefices and other Ecc&bhoalias;sticall Living&bholngs; with
Cure together with all and every Explanacions Addicions and Alteracions thereof or of any of them or to any of
them made by severall Statutes in the Fourteenth Eighteenth and three and Fortith yeares of Her said late Majesties
Raigne.</para>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">27 Eliz. c. 19.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p4">And one A&bholigct; made in the seaven and twentith yeere of the Raigne of the late Queene Elizabeth entituled An A&bholigct;
for the (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Peer and Cobb of Lyme Regis in the Countie of Dorsett.</para>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">3 Jac. I. c. 8. made perpetual.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p6">And one A&bholigct; made in the third yeare of the Raigne of the late King James entituled An A&bholigct; for the avoyding
of unnecessary delayes of execucions, Be by Authoritie of this Parliament made perpetuall and shall from henceforth
stand in full force and effe&bholigct; and be put in due execucion for ever hereafter.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. 21 Jac. I. c. 17. made perpetual.</head>
			<para id="p7">And be it also ena&bholigct;ed by the same Authoritie that one Statute made in the one and twentith yeare of the
Raigne of the late King James entituled An A&bholigct; against Usurie, which A&bholigct; was to contynue for the space of seaven
yeares from the foure and twentith day of June which then should be in the yeare of our Lord [God<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] one thousand
six hundred twentie and five and so to the end of the first Session of Parliament then next following be alsoe by
Authoritie of this Parliament made &bhopubr;petuall.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. 21 Hen. VIII. c. 12.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">3 &#x0026; 4 Edw. VI. c. 19. &sect; 1. 3.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that one A&bholigct; made in the one and twentith yeare of the
Reigne of the late King Henry the eight, entituled An A&bholigct; for the true making of Cables Halters and Ropes, And
that part of one A&bholigct; made in the Parliament holden at West&bhouov;m by &bhopubrc;ga&bhocotil;n the fourth Day of November and
contynued untill the first Day of Februarie next after in the third and fourth yeares of the Raigne of the late King
Edward the sixt, by which it is ordeyned and ena&bholigct;ed That no &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons after the tyme in the said A&bholigct;
mencioned shall sell againe live Cattell in the said A&bholigct; mencioned at or in the Market or Fayre wherein he bought
the same during the tyme of the same Fayre or Market under the paynes therein conteyned. And that no &bhopubr;son
being a Butcher and using the Craft or Mistery of Butchery shall at any time after the said feast buy any fat
Oxen Steers Ront&bholngs; Kine Heyfers Calves or Sheepe and sell or cause to be sold the same againe alive uppon paine
of forfeiture of every such Oxe Steere Ront Cowe Heifer Calves or Sheepe bargained or sold contrary to the
forme of that A&bholigct;.</para>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">3 &#x0026; 4 Ed. VI. c. 21; 21 Jac. I. c. 22.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p11">One other A&bholigct; made in the same Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; for the buying and selling of Butter and Cheese
together with one Statute made in the Parliament holden in the one and twentith yeare of the Raigne of the late King
James entituled An A&bholigct; for the explanacion of the Statutes made in the third fourth and fifth yeares of the Reigne
of the said late King Edward the sixth concerning the traders of Butter and Cheese.</para>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Certain Parts of 5 Eliz. c. 5. with all Additions, &#x0026;c. thereto by any Act in force the last Day of the Session 21 Jac. I</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And so much of an A&bholigct; made in the fifth yeare of the raigne of the late Queene Elizabeth intituled An A&bholigct;
touching certaine pollitique Constitucions made for the maynten<emph type="p">a</emph> nce of the Navie as is not repealed by any later
Statute, nor doth concerne the eating of Flesh or using of Fish uppon the Wednesday, Nor the transportacion of
Herring or other Sea Fish Nor freedome of Subsidie Custome or Tonnage for the same Nor transportacion of Corne
nor the &bhopubrc;hibiting the bringing into this Realme any Cod or [Ling<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] in Barrell&bholngs; or other Caskes together with all and
every other addicions explanacions and alteracions made thereunto or thereof or of any part thereof by anie Statute or
Statutes made sithence the making of the said last mencioned A&bholigct;, and in force the last day of the Session of Parliament
that was in the one and twentith yeare of the raigne of the late King James.</para>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">5 Eliz. c. 7</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">And one other A&bholigct; made in the said fifth yeare entituled, An A&bholigct; for avoyding divers forraine wares made by
handicraft&bholngs; men beyond the Seas.</para>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">8 Eliz. c. 10</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And an A&bholigct; made in the eight yeare of the raigne of the said late Queene Elizabeth entituled An A&bholigct;e for Bowyers
and the prises of Bowes.</para>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">13 Eliz. c. 21</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And one A&bholigct; made in the thirteenth [yeares<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of the raigne of the late Queene Elizabeth entituled An A&bholigct; that
Purveyers may take corne and vi&bholigct;uall&bholngs; within five miles of Cambridge and Oxford in certaine cases.</para>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">14 Eliz. c. 5. relating to the levying, &#x0026;c. of Gaol Money</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And so much of an A&bholigct; made in the fourteenth yeare of the raigne of the said late Queene Elizabeth entituled
An A&bholigct; for the punishment of Vagabond&bholigct; and releife of the poore and impotent as concerneth the taxing rating
levying and imploying of Gaole mony.</para>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">18 Eliz. c. 3. relating to Bastards, with a Proviso as to Execution of the said Act by Justices of Peace</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">And so much of an A&bholigct; made in the eighteenth yeare of the Raigne of the said late Queene Elizabeth entituled An
A&bholigct;e for setting the poore on worke and avoyding idlenesse, as concerneth Bastard&bholngs; begotten out of lawfull Matrimonie
with this that all Justices of the peace within their severall lymitt&bholngs; and &bhopcrl;cincts and in their severall Sessions may doe
and execute all thing&bholngs; concerning that part of the said Statute that by Justices of the Peace in the severall Counties
are by the said Statute lymited to be done.</para>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">18 Eliz. c. 20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And an A&bholigct;e made in the said eighteenth yere of the raigne of the said late Queene Elizabeth entituled An A&bholigct;e
for repayring and amending of the Bridges and Highwayes neere unto the Cittie of Oxford.</para>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">27 Eliz. c. 17. Pr</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">And one A&bholigct; made in the seven and Twentith yere of the Raigne of the said late Queene Elizabeth entituled,
An A&bholigct; for the good government of the Citie or Borough of Westminster (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>).</para>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">27 Eliz. cc. 14. 24</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">And two other A&bholigct; &bholngs; made in the said seven and twentith yeare of the Raigne of the said late Queene Elizabeth
the one intituled An A&bholigct; for reviving of a former Statute for the true making of Malt together with the Statute
by the said A&bholigct; revived, and the other intituled An A&bholigct; for the keeping of the Seabankes and Seaworkes in the
Countie of Norfolke.</para>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">31 Eliz. c. 8</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">And one A&bholigct; made in the one and thirtith yeare of the Raigne of the late Queene Elizabeth entituled An A&bholigct; for
the true gauging of vessell&bholngs; brought from beyond the Seas converted by Brewers for the utterance and sale of Ale
and Beere.</para>
			<para id="p32">
				<emph type="i">35 Eliz. cc. 10. 11</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p33">And two A&bholigct; &bholngs; made in the five and Thirtith yeare of Her said late Majesties Raigne, the one intituled An A&bholigct; for
the Reformacion of sondry abuses in Clothes called Devonshire Kersies or Douzens according to a Proclamacion of
the foure and thirtith yeare of Her said Majesties Raigne the other intituled An A&bholigct;e for the bringing in of Clapboard
from the part&bholngs; beyond the Seas and the restrayning of the transporting of Wine Caskes for the sparing and &bhopcrl;serving
of Timber within the Realme.</para>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">So much of 35 Eliz. c. 1. as hath not been since repealed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">And so much of one A&bholigct; made in the five and thirtith yeare of the Raigne of the said late Queene Elizabeth
entituled, An A&bholigct;e to retaine the Queenes Majesties subjects in their due obedience as hath not been since repealed
by any other Statute.</para>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">39 Eliz. c. 4. with the Provision annexed thereunto by 1 Jac. I. c. 25. &sect; 20 ;39 Eliz. c. 10. repealing 23 Eliz. c. 7; 39 Eliz. cc. 14. 16. 17</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">And the severall A&bholigct;e&bholngs; hereafter mencioned made in the nine and thirtith yere of the Raigne of the late Queene
Elizabeth That is to saie An A&bholigct; intituled An A&bholigct; for the punishment of Roagues Vagabond&bholngs; and sturdie Beggars
with the provision annexed thereunto by one A&bholigct; made in the first yeare of the raigne of the late King James entituled
An A&bholigct; for contynuing and reviving of divers Statut&bholngs; and for repealing of some others, An A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct;[for<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] increase of Marriners and for mainten<emph type="p">a</emph>nce of Navigacion repealing a former Act made in the three and twentith yeare of her said Majesties raigne bearing the same title, An A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; &bhopubrc;hibiting the bringing into the
Realme of forraine Card&bholngs; for Wooll, An A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; or restrayning the excessive making of Mault, An A&bholigct;
against lewd and wandering &bhopubr;sons &bhopcrl;tending to be Souldiers or Marriners.</para>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">43 Eliz. cc. 3. 6.; 43 Eliz. c. 2. with the Addition thereto by 1 Jac. I. c. 25. &#x0026;c. &sect; 23.; and with the further Addition herein mentioned as to the taking Parish Apprentices; and Overseers of the Poor, &#x0026;c. setting up Trades for setting the Poor on work.; 43 Eliz. cc. 10. 5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">And the severall A&bholigct;&bholngs; hereafter mencioned made in the three and fortith yeare of the raigne of the said late Queene
Elizabeth that is to saie An A&bholigct; entituled, An A&bholigct;e for the necessary releife of Souldiers and Marriners, An A&bholigct; entituled
An A&bholigct; to avoid trifling and frivolous Suit&bholngs; in Lawe in her Majesties Court&bholngs; at Westminster, An A&bholigct;e entituled An A&bholigct;e
for releife of the poore with the addicion thereunto made by an A&bholigct;e made in the first yeare of the raigne of the late
King James entituled An A&bholigct; for contynuing of divers Statut&bholngs; and for repeale of some others, and with this further
addicion. And be it ena&bholigct;ed That all &bhopubr;sons to whome the Overseers of the poore shall according to the said A&bholigct; binde
any children apprentices may take and receive and keepe them as apprentices: And also that the Churchwardens and
Overseers of the poore mencioned in the said A&bholigct; made in the said three and fortith yeare may by and with the consent of
two or more Justices of the Peace, whereof one to bee of the Quo[rum] within their respe&bholigct;ive limitt&bholngs; wherein shalbe more
Justices then one, and where no more shalbe then one with the assent of that one Justice of the Peace sett upp use
and occupie any Trade Misterie or Occupacion onelie for the setting on worke and better releife of the poore of the
Parish Towne or place of or within which they shalbe Churchwardens or Overseers of the poore any former Statute
to the contrary notwithstanding, An A&bholigct;e entituled An A&bholigct; for the true making and working of Woollen Cloath,
An A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; to &bhopcrl;vent Perjury and subordinacion of Perjury and unnecessary expence in Suit&bholngs; of Lawe.</para>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">1 Jac. I. cc. 7. 8;1 Jac. I. c. 22. save so far as repealed by 4 Jac. 1. c. 6.; 1 Jac. I. c. 18.; 1 Jac. I. c. 6.; 1 Jac. I. c. 31</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">And the severall A&bholigct;&bholngs; made in the first yeare of the Raigne of the late King James after mencioned, One [A&bholigct;
intituled<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] A&bholigct; for the Continuance and Explanacion of the Statute made in the nyne and thirtith yeare of the raigne
of the late Queene Elizabeth entituled An A&bholigct; for punishment of Roagues Vagabond&bholngs; and Sturdie Beggars An other
entituled An A&bholigct; to take away the benefitt of Clergie for some kinde of Manslaughter An other intituled An A&bholigct;
concerning Tanners Corriers Shoomakers and other Artificers occupying the cutting of Leather saving for such part thereof
as is repealed by one other A&bholigct; made in the fourth yeare of His said late Majesties Raigne of England in that behalfe.
An other intituled An A&bholigct; for the better execucion of the intent and meaning of former Statut&bholngs; made against shooting
in Gunns and for the &bhopcrl;servacion of the Game of Pheasant&bholngs; and Partriges and against the destroying of Hares with
Harepipes and tracing [of<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Hares in the Snowe, An A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for avoyding of deceit in selling buying or
spending corrupt and unwholesome Hoppes, An A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for explanacion of the Statute made in the
fift yeare of the late Queene Elizabeths Raigne concerning Labourers, An A&bholigct; for the charitable releife and ordering
of &bhopubr;sons infe&bholigct;ed with the Plague.</para>
	
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">3 Jac. I. c. 9;3 Jac. I. c. 10.; 3 Jac. I. c. 11.; 3 Jac. I. c. 13</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">And the severall A&bholigct; &bholngs; made in the third yeare of the Raigne of the late King James after mencioned, That is to
saie One intituled An A&bholigct; for releife of such as lawfullie use the Trade and Handicraft of Skinners, An other A&bholigct;
entituled An A&bholigct;e for the rating and levying of the charges for conveying of Malefa&bholigct;ors and Offendors to the Gaole,
Another A&bholigct; for transportacion of Beere over the Seas One other intituled An Act against unlawfull hunting and
stealing of Deere and Conies.</para>
			<para id="p44">
				<emph type="i">4 Jac. I. c. 11</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p45">And one Act; made in the fourth yeare of the raigne of the said late King James entituled An Act for the better
provision of Meadow and Pasture for the necessary mainten<emph type="p">a</emph> nce of Husbandry and Tillage in the Mannors Lordshipps
and Parishes of Merden &bhoalias; Manarden Boddenham Wellington Sutton S<emph type="p">t</emph> Michael[ia]l[ia]s Sutton S<emph type="p">t</emph> Nicholas Murton uppon
Lugg and the Parish of Pipe and everie of them in the Countie of Hereford.</para>
			<para id="p46">
				<emph type="i">7 Jac. I. c. 1;c. 4.; c. 11.; c. 12.; c. 13.; c. 18</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p47">And the severall A&bholigct;&bholngs; made in the seventh yeare of the Raigne of the said late King James [afore<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] mencioned
the one intituled An A&bholigct;e for the better execucion of Justice and suppressing of criminall Offenders in the North
part&bholngs; of the Kingdome of England Another intituled An A&bholigct; for the due execucion of divers Lawes and Statutes
heretofore made against Rogues Vagabond&bholngs; and sturdy Beggers and other lewd and idle &bhopubr;sons Another intituled
An A&bholigct;e to &bhopcrl;vent the spoile of Corne and Graine by untimely Hawking and for the better &bhopcrl;servacion of Pheasant&bholngs;
and Partridges One other intituled An A&bholigct; to avoid the double payment of debt&bholngs;, One other intituled, An A&bholigct; for
the explanacion of one Statute made in the second Session of that &bhopcrl;sent Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; against unlawfull
hunting of Deere and Conies And one other A&bholigct; intituled An A&bholigct; for the taking landing and carrying of Seasand for
the bettering of ground&bholngs; and for the increase of Corne and Tillage within the Counties of Devon and Cornewall.</para>
			<para id="p48">
				<emph type="i">That Part of 25 H. VIII. c. 11. which was repealed by 3 &#x0026; 4 Edw. VI. c. 7. but revived by 21 Jac. I. c. 28. &sect; 9</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p49">And that one part of the Statute made in the five and twentith yeare of the Raigne of the late King Henry
the eight, intituled An A&bholigct; for the destruccion of Wilde fowle, which was repealed by a latter A&bholigct; in the Parliament
holden in the third and fourth yeares of the Raigne of the late King Edward the sixt and revived in the Parliament
holden in the one and twentith yeare of the Raigne of the late King James.</para>
			<para id="p50">
				<emph type="i">1 M. Sess. 3. c. 5. revived by 21 Jac. I. c. 28. &sect; 10</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p51">And one A&bholigct; made in the first yeare of the Raigne of the late Queene Mary for and con&bhoccrl;ning the making repayring
and amendment of the C&bhooov;mon high Way and Cawsey in the Counties of Dorsett and Somersett betweene the
Townes of Shaftsbury and Sherborne in the said Countie of Dorsett and revived in the said one and twentith yeare.</para>
			<para id="p52">
				<emph type="i">21 Jac. I. c. 6;21 Jac. I. c. 18.; So much of 4 Jac. I. c. 2. as was in force on the last Day of the Session 21 Jac. I.; 21 Jac. I. c. 20.; c. 27.; continued until the End of the First Session of the next Parliament in Manner herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p53">And alsoe the severall A&bholigct;&bholngs; hereafter mencioned made in the said one and twentith yere of the Raigne of the late
King James, That is to saie An A&bholigct; ; intituled An A&bholigct; concerning Women convi&bholigct;ed of small felonies and one A&bholigct;
intituled An A&bholigct; for the continuance of a former Statute made in the fourth yeare of the Raigne of the said late King
James intituled An A&bholigct; for the true making of Wollen Clothes and for some addicions and alteracions in and to
the same together with so much of one A&bholigct; made in the said fourth yeere as was in force the last day of the Session
of Parliament holden in the said one and twentith yeare, and one other A&bholigct;e intituled An A&bholigct; to &bhopcrl;vent and reforme
&bhopubrc;fane swearing and cursing And one A&bholigct; intituled An A&bholigct; to &bhopcrl;vent the destroying and murdering of bastard
children by vertue of this Act shalbe and contynue untill the end of the first Session of the next Parliament in force
and effe&bholigct; as the same were the first day of the Session of Parliament holden in the first yere of the Raigne of our
Soveraigne Lord the King that now is.</para>
			<para id="p54">
				<emph type="i">1 Car. I. c. 1. continued until the End of the First Session of the next Parliament</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p55">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed that one Statute made in the said first yeare of his Majesties raigne that now is entituled
An A&bholigct; for punishing of divers abuses c&bhooov;mitted on the Lord&bholngs; day shall contynue (<ref idref="n10">10</ref>) untill the end of the first Session
of the next Parliament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Explanation, &#x0026;c. of said A&bholigct;&bholngs; by any new A&bholigct; of this Session, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p56">Provided neverthelesse that so much of every of the said A&bholigct;&bholngs; as by any new A&bholigct; &bhomtild;ade in this Session of
Parliament are or shalbe explayned altered or repealed shall for so much thereof from the end of this Session of
Parliament stand and be in force as by those other A&bholigct;&bholngs; shalbe ordayned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Exportation of Corn at certain Prices.</head>
			<para id="p57">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Custom and Poundage of Corn</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p58">Provided also and be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament That when the prizes of
corne or graines at the tymes havens and places, when and where the said corne or graine shalbe bought shipped
or loaden exceed not the rates hereafter following videl&bhoalias;t the quarter of wheat at Thirtie and two Shilling&bholngs; the
quarter, the quarter of Rye at twentie Shilling&bholngs;, the quarter of Pease and Beanes at sixteene shilling&bholngs;, the quarter
of Barley or Malt at sixteene shillings of currant English mony That then it shalbe lawfull for all and every
&bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons being Subject&bholngs; of the King&bholngs; Majestie his Heires and Successors, and borne within this Realme to
carry and transport of his owne and to buy to sell againe in markett&bholngs; and out of marketts&bholngs; ; and to keepe or sell or
carry and transport any of the said cornes and graines from the places where they shall be of such prises unto any
part&bholngs; beyond the Seas in amitie with His Majestie as Merchandise in Shipps Crayes or other vessell&bholngs; whereof any
English borne Subje&bholigct; or Subje&bholigct;&bholngs; then shalbe the owner or owners or the same to carry and sell in other places
within this Realme or Dominions thereof. Any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary hereof notwithstanding.
And that the King&bholngs; Majestie his Heires and Successors shall have and receive by the Customers and Officers of his
Port&bholngs; for the Custome or Pondage of every quarter of wheat to be transported by force of this Statute out of this
Realme two Shillings, of every quarter of other graine sixteene pence, which said severall s&bhooov;mes so to be had
and taken as Custome or Poundage shalbe in full Satisfaccion of all manner of Custome or Poundage for the said
Corne or Graine by any Constitucion Order Statute Law or Custome heretofore made used or taken for
transporting of any such manner of Corne or Graine or made in this &bhopcrl;sent Session of Parliament or hereafter
to be made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. The King's Proclamation may restrain Exportation of Corn.</head>
			<para id="p59">
				<emph type="i">Exporting contrary thereto.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p60">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, That the King&bholngs; Majestie his
heires and successors may at all tymes by his and their Writt of Proclamacion to be published generallie in the
whole Realme or in any of the Counties of this Realme where any Port&bholngs; are c&bhooov;maund that no &bhopubr;son shall by vertue
of this A&bholigct; transport or convey any manner of graine out of his Highnes Dominions generally or out of any speciall
Port&bholngs; to be in the said Proclamacion particulerlie named for such time as shalbe therein lymitted and appointed,
And it shall not be lawfull for any &bhopubr;son to carrie out any such graine contrary to the tenor of the said Proclamacion
uppon such paines and forfeitures as by the Lawes and Statut&bholngs; of this Realme are and have bene &bhopubrc;vided and ordained
in that behalfe, this A&bholigct;e or any thing therein contayned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Length, Breadth, and Weight of Welch Cottons.</head>
			<para id="p61">Provided also and be it ena&bholigct;ed That no &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons shall incurre any penaltie for want of length bredth
or weight of Welsh Cottons under the price of fifteene pence the yard or two shilling&bholngs; the Goad so as they be not
mixed with haire or other deceitfull stuffe nor for any others above that price except they shall be mixed as aforesaid
or shall shrinke above the rate of halfe a yard in twelve yard&bholngs; of length or weigh lesse then fourteene ounces the
yard or hold not full three quarters of a yard broad.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII.</head>
			<para id="p62">
				<emph type="i">16 Ric. II. c. 1. &sect; 2.; 16 Ric. II. c. 4</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p63">And be it also ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, That that part of one Statute made in the sixteenth yeare of
the raigne of the late King Richard the second by which it is ordeyned that no manner of Spicery after that it be
brought into the Realme shalbe carried out of the same Realme by Aliens nor by Denizen uppon paine of forfeiture
thereof: And one Statute made in the sixteenth yeare of the Raigne of the late King Richard the second concerning
Liveries.</para>
			<para id="p64">
				<emph type="i">20 Ric. II. c. 2</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p65">And one other Statute made in the twentith yeare of the raigne of the late King Richard the Second by which it is
ordeyned that no Valelett&bholngs; called Yeoman nor other of lesser estate then an Esquire shall use or beare any signe of
Livery called Livery of Company of any Lord within the Realme.</para>
			<para id="p66">
				<emph type="i">1 Hen. IV. c. 7</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p67">And one Statute made in the first yeare of the Raigne of the late King Henry the fourth concerning giving of
Liveries.</para>
			<para id="p68">
				<emph type="i">7 Hen. IV. c. 14</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p69">And one Statute made in the seaventh yeare of the Raigne of the late King Henry the fourth concerning giving of
Liveries.</para>
			<para id="p70">
				<emph type="i">13 Hen. IV. c. 3</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p71">And one other Statute made in the thirteenth yeere of the Raigne of the late King Henry the fourth concerning
giving of Liveries.</para>
			<para id="p72">
				<emph type="i">8 Hen. VI. c. 4</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p73">And one Statute made in the eight yeare of the Raigne of the late King Henry the sixt concerning Liveries.</para>
			<para id="p74">
				<emph type="i">8 Edw. IV. c. 2</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p75">And one Statute made in the eight yeare of the Raigne of the late King Edward the fourth concerning Liveries.</para>
			<para id="p76">
				<emph type="i">3 Hen. VII. c. 1. &sect; 1. as to Liveries; 3 Hen. VII. c. 12. repealed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p77">And so much of one Statute made in the third yeare of the Raigne of the late King Henry the seaventh concerning
the Starchamber as toucheth or concerneth the punishment of those that shall give or take Liveries, And one other
Statute made in the said third yeare concerning taking of Liveries by the King&bholngs; Officers and Farmers be from henceforth
Repealed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. 7 Jac. I. c. 20. continued until the End of the next Session.</head>
			<para id="p78">And be it also ena&bholigct;ed by authoritie of this Parliament, that one A&bholigct; of Parliament made in the seventh yeare
of the Raigne of the late King James intituled An A&bholigct; for the speedie recoverie of manie thousand Acres of Marsh
ground&bholngs; and other ground&bholngs; within the Counties of Norfolke and Suffolke latelie surrounded by the rage of the
Sea in divers part&bholngs; of the said Counties and for the &bhopcrl;vencion of the daunger of the like surrounding hereafter be
contynued and shall stand in force untill the end of the next Session of Parliament.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">mayntenance of the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Linges <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">yeare <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Not on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">for the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">intituled an <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8"><emph type="i">0</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">after <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">in force <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


