<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47201" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1625</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Acte for the confirmacion of the Subsidies graunted by the Clergie. [Rot. Parl. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Grant of Three entire Subsidies given by the Clergy of Canterbury.</head>
		<para id="p1">WHERE the Prelates and Clergie of the Province of Canterbury, for divers weightie consideracions, respecting
his Majesties extraordinary occasions, have lovinglie, and liberallie given and granted to the King&bholngs; most
Excellent Majestie, three whole and entire Subsidies of foure shilling&bholngs; in the pound, to be taken and levied, of all and
singular their promocions Spirituall within the same Province, at such dayes and tymes, and in such manner and forme,
and with such excepcions and provisions, as bee specified and delivered in a certaine instrument by them thereof
made, and delivered unto the King&bholngs; Majestie, under the Seale of the most reverend Father in God, George, now
Archbishop of Canterbury, and Primate of all England, which Instrument is now exhibited in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament to
be ratified and confirmed: the tenor whereof ensueth in theise word&bholngs;;</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Tenor of the Instrument;</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p3">Inclytissimo &amp; Serenissimo D[omin]o n[ostr]o Carolo, Dei gra Angl[ie] Scocie, Franc[ie];, &amp; Hib[ernie] Regi Fidei Defensori &amp; c.
Georgius divina providencia Cantuar Archiep[iscop]us, tocius Ang&bhoalias; Primas &amp; Metropolitanus, &bhopubrc;pensissimam subjec cionem, &amp; 
obedientiam, ac in eo, qui est Rex Regum, &amp; D[ominu]s dominanci&bhouov;, s&bhouov;mam felicitatem. Serenissime vere Majestati, &bhopubr;
publicum hoc instrumentum testatum facim[us], q[uo]d Prelati &amp; Clerus Provincie n[ostr]e Cantuariensis, in convoca&bhocotil;e, sive sacra
Synodo Provinciali, authoritate bris vri Regij ad nos dati in domo Capitulari Eccl[es]ie Cat[hedral]is S[anct]i Pauli London vicesimo
die mensis Junij Anno D[omin]i mi&bhoalias;imo sexcentesimo vicesimo quinto (ex continua&bhocotil;e &amp; &bhopubrc;roga&bhocotil;e ejusdem) inchoata &amp; 
celebrata, ac de die in diem, &amp; loco in locum, usq[ue] ad &amp; in o&bholigct;av&umacr; diem instantis Mensis Julij, anno &bhopcrl;d[ic]io post meridiem
eciam continuata &amp; &bhopubrc;rogata, in Eccl[es]ia Collegiata b[ea]ti Petri West&bhomov; eodem o&bholigct;avo die &bhopcrl;sentis mensis Julij legittime
congregati, &bhopubrc; quibusdam arduis &amp; urgentib[us] causis &bhopubr; nos, ejusdem Provincie Clero &bhopubrc;positis, ac in&bhotcrl; eos sedulo pensitatis,
tria integra Subsidia Magnificencie vre Regie, spontaneo, unanimiq[ue] consensu dederunt &amp; concesserunt (&bhopubrc;ut tenore
publici hujus Instrumenti plenius liquet) Majestatem eandem supplici&bhotcrl; obnixeque rogantes, ut hec eo tria Subsidia
benigne acci&bhopubr;e, ac equi boniq[ue] consule dignemini. Tenor vero &bhopcrl;d[i]cte concessionis se het in eum qui hic sequit[ur] modum.</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Prelates, &amp; c. of Province of Canterbury, assembled in Convocation,; grant Three whole Subsidies of 4s. in the Pound on all Spiritual Promotions</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p5">Most gracious Soveraigne, Your Majesties faithfull Subje&bholigct;&bholngs;, the Prelates and Clergie of the Province of Canterbury,
being called together by the Authoritie of your Highnes writt, and att this &bhopcrl;sent being orderlie assembled in a
Provinciall Synode, or Convocacion, maturelie considering with themselves that great and bounden dutie, which by the
rules of the Sacred Scripture they doe owe to your gracious Majestie their Soveraigne Lord, especially for your
&bhopubrc;fessed contynuance of the sincere preaching of the Gospell: And moreover as obedient Subje&bholigct;&bholngs;, well weighing the
singuler care which your Majestie hath, for the well guiding and governing of all that people, which is by God c&bhooov;mitted to
your charge; And not forgetting those great expences, whereat your Majestie now is, and hereafter is more like to be,
aswell for the honorable sustentacion of your Royall estate at home, and the necessary defence of this your Realme,
as alsoe for the more effe&bholigct;uall furtherance of your Majesties most Royall and extraordinary designes abroad, as a
speciall and significant testimonie of their great joy at your Majesties first entrance unto your Throne, have with one
agreement and unanimous consent, given and granted, and by theise &bhopcrl;sent&bholngs; doe give and graunte to your Highnes
your Heires and Successors three whole and entire Subsidies, of foure shilling&bholngs; in the pound, in manner and forme
as here followeth. That is to saie, That every Archbishopp, Bishopp, Deane, Archdeacon, Provost, Master of Colledge,
Prebendary, Parson, and Vicar, and every other &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons, of whatsoever name or degree, he or they be within
the Province of Canterbury, having or enjoying any Spirituall promocion or other temporall possession to the
same spirituall promocion annexed, now not divided, nor separated by Act of Parliament, or otherwise from the
possession of the Clergie shall pay to your Highnes your Heires and Successors, for every Pound that he may
yearelie receive and dispend by reason of the said Spirituall &bhopubrc;mocion the s&bhooov;me of foure shilling&bholngs; for every of the said
three Subsidies.</para>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">Benefices to be valued according to Taxation of the Tenth under 26 Hen. VIII. c. 3. but to pay Subsidy on 9-10ths only.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p7">And for the true and certaine value of all the &bhopubrc;mocions and every of them, whereof the payment of theise three
Subsidies shalbe made, the rate, taxacion, valuacion, and estimacion now remayning of Record in your Majesties
Court of Exchequer for the payment of a &bhopubr;petuall Disme or Tenth, granted unto King Henry the eight of worthie
memory, in the six and twentith yeare of his raigne, concerning such &bhopubrc;mocions as now bee in the possession of the
Clergie, shall onely be followed and observed, without making any other valuacion, rate taxacion, or estimacion, then
in the said Record is comprised. Provided alwaies, that forasmuch as the tenth parte of the said rate and valuacion
before mencioned, is yearelie paid to your Highnes for the said &bhopubr;petuall Disme or Tenth, so as there remaine
onelie nine part&bholngs; yeerelie to the Incumbent cleare theise three Subsidies of foure shilling&bholngs; of the pound, shalbe
understood and meant onelie of every full pound of the said nine part&bholngs;, and nothing for any other mony, not amounting
to a full .pound.</para>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">Manner and Form and Time of Payment of Subsidies; Fee to Receiver or other Officer</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p9">And your Prelates and Clergie doe also graunt, that theise three Subsidies of foure Shilling&bholngs;of the full pound, of
the nine part&bholngs; of the yearelie value of every Spirituall &bhopubrc;mocion aforesaid within the said province taxed as is aforesaid,
shalbe paid to your Majestie your heires and successors in manner and forme following, that is to saie, the first payment
and moytie of the first of theise three Subsidies, vide&bhoalias;, two shilling&bholngs;of every full pound, as [aforesaid<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to be due, at and
uppon the first day of December, which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God, One thousand six hundred twentie and
seaven, and the second payment and moitie of the first of the said three Subsidies videl[icet], two shilling&bholngs;of every full
pound as aforesaid to be due, att and uppon the first day of June which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand
six hundred twentie and eight. And the first payment and moytie of the second of the said three Subsidies, videl[icet], two
shilling&bholngs;of every full pound as aforesaid to be due at and uppon the first day of June then next and i&bhomov;ediatelie
following in the same yeare, and the second payment and moitie of the second of the said three Subsidies, videl[icet],
two shilling&bholngs;of every full pound as aforesaid, to be due att and uppon the first day of June then next and y&bhomov;ediatelie
following, which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God, one thousand six hundred twentie and nyne, and the first
payment and moytie of the third and last of the said three Subsidies, videl[icet], two shilling&bholngs;of every full pound as
aforesaid, to be due at and uppon the first day of December then next and y&bhomov;ediatelie following in the same yeare,
and the second and last payment, and moitie of the third and last of these three Subsidies, to be due at and uppon the
first day of June, which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God, one thousand six hundred and thirtie, to be delivered and
paid by such &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons as in this &bhopcrl;sent Graunte, shalbe appointed to have the Colleccion thereof, to the Lord
High Tresurer or Under Tresurer of England for the tyme being, or to such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons, and in such place or places,
as shall please your Highnes to appoint to be paid, videl[icet], The first payment of every of the said three Subsidies, which
shalbe due att and uppon the first day of December as aforesaid, to be made at or before the last day of February next
following every of the aforesaid dayes, when the said payment&bholngs; or moyties shalbe due, and the second payment of
every of the said three Subsidies, which shalbe due att and uppon the first day of June as aforesaid, to be made at or
before the last day of August next following after every of the aforesaid daies, when the said payment&bholngs; or moities
shalbe due, without paying any thing to the Receivor or to any other &bhopubr;son or officer to be assigned for the receipt
thereof, for any acquittance or other Discharge or Dispatch uppon any such payment or receipt of the said three
Subsidies or any-part thereof, but onelie foure pence, and that to the Clerke, for the writing of the Acquittance or
Discharge for every of the said payment&bholngs;.</para>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">Subsidy not payable for the Year in which First Fruits are paid.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p11">Provided alwaies, that no &bhopubr;son, which hereafter shalbe &bhopubrc;moted to any Benefice or spirituall &bhopubrc;mocion, and shall
compound with your Majestie, your Heires or Successors, for the first fruit&bholngs; of the same, from the first day of
December, which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six hundred twentie and seaven, and on
this side the first day of June, which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God, one thousand sixe hundred and thirtie,
shalbe contributorie or charged for the same Benefice or Promocion to your Highnes, your Heires or Successors, with
any Part of the said three Subsidies, during the first yeare after the tyme of any such compounding for his first fruit&bholngs;.</para>
		<para id="p12">
			<emph type="i">Archbishops, &amp; c. to be Colle&bholigct;ors.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p13">Item your Highnes said Prelat&bholngs; and Clergie doe graunt, that every Archbishopp, Bishopp, and (the See being
void) every Deane and Chapter of that See void, and none other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons shalbe Colle&bholigct;or of the said three
Subsidies within their &bhopubrc;per Dioces during the tyme appointed for the Payment of the said three Subsidies.</para>
		<para id="p14">
			<emph type="i">Colle&bholigct;ors offering Payment, Officer to receive the same within Four Days, and give Receipt to Colle&bholigct;or; 
Auditors to take Accounts and make Allowances.; Delaying, &amp; c. so to do,; Penalty &pound;10.; Imprisonment until Penalty paid.</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p15">And your said Prelates and Clergie doe most humblie beseech your Majestie, that it may be ena&bholigct;ed by your
Majestie and your high Court of Parliament, for the speedie payment of the said three Subsidies, and to avoid
delayes thereof, that when, and as often as any Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors, chargeable with the Colleccion of the
said three Subsidies, or any part thereof, or their or any of their Under colle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors, Deputie or
Deputies, or any of them, shall offer the Payment of the said three Subsidies, or of any part of them to the use
of your Majestie, your Heires [and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Successors, to any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons appointed to receive the same by your Highnesse,
or by your Lord High Treasurer, that the said &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons so appointed, shall within foure Daies next after such
appointment, receive, or cause to be received the Money soe offred to be paid, without any further delay, and deliver
one sufficient Bill, testifying the receipt thereof, to the said Colle&bholigct;or, or his Undercolle&bholigct;or or Deputie, uppon every
such particuler Payment. And that every such Auditor, as is, or shalbe appointed to take or receive the account of
any such Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors, or of their severall Undercolle&bholigct;ors or Deputies, shall within six daies, next after
request to him to be made, truly and indifferentlie take the said account, and make allowance as by this Graunte is
appointed, uppon paine that every such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons appointed to receive the same s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of money soe
offered, and every such Auditor shall lose and forfeit for every default or delay to be made to the Colle&bholigct;or or
Colle&bholigct;ors, Undercolle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors, Deputie or Deputies soe offering to make Payment or account, as is
aforesaid, the s&bhooov;me of ten pound&bholngs; of lawfull mony of England, the one moietie thereof to be to your Majestie, your
Heires and Successors, and the other moietie to the said Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors, Undercolle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors,
Deputie or Deputies so greived, the same to be paid uppon complaint to be made to the said Lord Tresurer, or
Undertresurer, or to the Lord Cheife Baron of your Majesties Court of Exchequer, who uppon such complaint shall
&bhopcrl;sentlie examine the matter, and fynding default shall c&bhooov;mitt the offender to Warde, there to remaine untill he shall
have paid the said severall s&bhooov;mes so forfeited.</para>
		<para id="p16">
			<emph type="i">Power to Colle&bholigct;ors to levy Subsidies; may account for the same as the King and Exchequer shall appoint, as Archbishops, &amp; c. account for the Tenth.; Archbishop, &amp; c. gathering and paying what they can, to be discharged for the rest.; Sixpence in the Pound allowed to Colle&bholigct;ors.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p17">And for the better levying and recovering of these three Subsidies, or any of them, your said Prelates and Clergie
doe likewise most humblie beseech your Majestie, that it may be ena&bholigct;ed by your Majestie, and your said High
Court of Parliament, in manner and forme following, That is to saie, That every Colle&bholigct;or of the said three Subsidies,
and of every part and parcell of them, and their lawfull Undercolle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors, Deputie or Deputies
may have full power and Authoritie to use all such waies and meanes and processe, as be &bhopcrl;scribed in the A&bholigct; of
&bhopubr;petuall disme for the Colleccion and levying thereof, and may make account of the same before the Lord High
Tresurer or Undertresurer of England, for the tyme being, or any other Officer by your Highnes or your Court
of Exchequer, to be appointed for the same, and in such place as your Majestie shall likewise assigne, in such
wise, and after such forme onelie, as the said Archbishopp and Bishops bee now charged to make accompt for the said
&bhopubr;petuall Disme and tenth: whereby is meant that the lacke and default of payment, of and for any Spirituall &bhopubrc;mocion
or &bhopubrc;mocions, shall onelie charge such incumbent or incumbents and such others as be bound to pay the same, And
that the Archbishopp, Bishopp, Deane and Chapter, gathering that which they can receive, and making payment
thereof, shall for the rest, not by them received, be discharged by their Certificate, to be made unto your Highnes
Court of Exchequer, for every of the aforesaid payment&bholngs;, which shalbe due uppon the first day of December in
any of the aforesaid yeares, at or before the last day of Februarie next and imediatelie following every of the aforesaid
daies, when every of the said payment&bholngs; shalbe due, And for every of the aforesaid payment&bholngs;, which shalbe
due uppon the first day of June, in any of the aforesaid yeares, at or before the last day of August, next and
ymediatelie following every of the aforesaid daies, when the said payment&bholngs; shalbe due, and that six pence of every
pound, wherewith the Colle&bholigct;or shalbe charged in this account clerelie to be paid into the Receipt of your Majesties
Exchequer, or into such other place as shall please your Highnes to appoint, shalbe allowed unto the said Colle&bholigct;or
uppon his account for the same at every of the aforesaid severall tymes of payment for the charges of the said
Colleccion, Portage, safe conveying and paying of the said three Subsidies.</para>
		<para id="p18">
			<emph type="i">Incumbents, &amp; c. being monished and not paying Subsidies; Proceedings.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p19">And moreover that it may be ena&bholigct;ed likewise, that after any payment of the said three Subsidies shalbe once
due by vertue of this Graunt, if any Incumbent of any Benefice or Promocion Spirituall, charged to the Payment
of any of the said three Subsidies or any part thereof, being at any tyme after that the same payment shalbe due
lawfullie monished, either &bhopubr;sonallie, or at his Dignitie, Stall, Church, or Mansion house, by the Archbishop or Bishop
of the Dioces, or his Undercolle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors, Deputie or Deputies, or by the Deane and Chapter (the
See being void) or by any of their Undercolle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors, Deputie or Deputies authorised in that behalfe
to appeare by himselfe or his Deputie at a certaine day and place of convenient distance to the said Incumbent, then
to be signified and &bhopcrl;fixed, and then and there to pay such parte of the said three Subsidies for his Benefice or
&bhopubrc;mocion spirituall or the whole, as then by virtue of this Graunt shalbe due, doe not either att the same day and
place soe to him signified and &bhopcrl;fixed, trulie content and paye, or cause to be contented [or<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] payed such Payment&bholngs; of
the said three Subsidies, as then by him shall be due to be paide unto the same Archbishopp or Bishop, or to his</para>
		<para id="p20">
			<emph type="i">Such Default to be certified into Exchequer.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p21">Undercolle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors, Deputie or Deputies, or to the Deane and Chapter of anie See being voide, or to
their Undercolle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors, Deputie or Deputies or to one of them, shewing sufficient deputacion from
the said Archbishop, Bishop, or Deane [or<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Chapter under his or their Seale in that behalfe [be<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] ready att the said
day and place soe signified and &bhopcrl;fixed, to receave anie payment of the said three Subsidies then due and openlie
demaunding the same, or els paie everie of the payment&bholngs;of the said three Subsidies given by this Graunt within fiftie
daies next after anie such &bhopcrl;fixed daies of warning at the furthest (so that open demand be made of every of the
said Paiments of the said three Subsidies in and at the saide place and day before &bhopcrl;fixed) That then everie Incumbent so
making defaulte of anie of the Payment&bholngs; aforesaid, which shalbe due from him for anie of the part&bholngs; of the said three
Subsidies as aforesaid after such Default thereof certified into your Majesties Exchequer in writing under the Seale
and hand writing of anie Archbishop, or Bishop, or the c&bhooov;mon Seale of the Deane and Chapter (the See being voide)
charged with the colleccio[n] of the said three Subsidies or anie part thereof soe that the said Certificate shalbe made
according to the forme hereafter expressed and exhibited into your Majesties said Court of Exchequer, vide&bhoalias; for
everie of the aforesaid paiements of the said three Subsidies, which shalbe due the firste day of December in anie
of the aforesaid yeeres att or before the laste day of Februarie next following everie of the aforesaid daies when everie
of the said paiements shalbe due, And for everie of the aforesaid payment&bholngs; which shalbe due upon the firste day
of June in anie of the aforesaide yeeres att or before the last daie of August next following everie of the aforesaid
daies, when everie of the saide payment&bholngs; shalbe due, as aforesaid shall forfeite and lose unto your Majestie your Heires
and Successors all the &bhopubrc;fitts which of that onlie Dignitie, Benifice or &bhopubrc;mocion, for the which he maketh such default
of payment and whereof such Certificate shalbe made, shall come grow and arise unto him (over and above the
Charges of serving the Cure and the annuall Tenth due to be paid out of his said Living) in one whole yeare next
after such Certificate made and delivered unto your Highnes Courte of Exchequer and there admitted in case the
said Incumbent shall soe long live And that everie such Certificate of anie such default of Paiement shalbe made
according to the tenor and effe&bholigct; ensuing, (mutatis mutandis,)</para>
		<para id="p22">
			<emph type="i">Form of Certificate of Default</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p23">Honorabilis &amp; egregijs viris D[omin]o Thesaurario &amp; Baronib[us] de S[caccar]io Illustrissimi D[omin]i n[ostr]i D[omin]i Caroli Dei g[rati]a Ang&bhoalias;
Scoc[iae] Franc[iae] &amp; Hib[er]nie Regis fidei Defensoris &amp; c. Vester humilis I. &bhopubr;missione Divinia L. Ep[iscop]us authoritate &amp; vigore
cujusdam a&bholigct;us Parliamenti, Anno Regni dci D[omi]ni Regis primo editi &amp; &bhopubrc;visi ad colligend &amp; levandum tria Subsidia
eidem D[omin]o Regi in eodem Parliamento &bhopubr; Prelatos &amp; Clerum Cantuarie &bhopubrc;vincie concessa vide&bhoalias; &bhopubrc; prima solu&bhocotil;e primi
Subsidij solvend primo die Decembris ultimo &bhopcrl;&bhotcrl;iti infra Dioces n[ostr]am L. duputatus &amp; [authoritatus<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] o&bhomov;imodam
reverenciam tantis viris debitam cum honore. Vris reverencijs ha[rum] serie a&bhonov;uncio &amp; &bhoccrl;tifico me &bhopcrl;fat E[piscopu]m modo quo
&bhopcrl;fertent deputat[um] &amp; [authoritatum<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] sufficient[er] &amp; cum o&bhomov;i diligencia requisivisse &bhopubr; N. O. Subcollect[orem] seu deputatum meum
in hac parte de quovis beneficio &amp; &bhopubrc;mo&bhocotil;e ecc&bhoalias;iastic in quadam Scedula &bhopcrl;sentib[us] annexa sp[er]ificatis, s&bhouov;mas solu&bhocotil;is dci
primi Subsidij &bhopcrl; dcis beneficijs &amp; &bhopubrc;mo&bhocotil;ib[us] debitas &amp; solvendas, dco primo die Decembris ultimo &bhopcrl;&bhotcrl;iti &bhopubrc;ut in eadem
Schedula &bhopcrl;sentib[us] annex plenius liquet &amp; apparet Sed dcas s&bhouov;mas ex causis in eadem Scedula allegatis reci&bhopubr;e non
potui. In cujus rei testimoniu[m] Sigillum meum &bhopcrl;sentib[us] apposui. Dat[um] die mensis Anno D[omi]ni.</para>
		<para id="p24">
			<emph type="i">Form of Schedule referred to in Certificate.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p25">The forme of which Schedule above mencioned ensueth.</para>
		<para id="p26">Civitas L. vel Decanatus de H. A. B. Re&bholigct;or vel Vicarius ibm monitus fuit apud &bhopcrl;dict die
mensis ultimo &bhopcrl;&bhotcrl;iti p N. O. Subcolle&bholigct;orem seu deputat meum ad solvend apud Ecc&bhoalias;iam de L. in
Co&bhomov; R. die mensis &bhopubrc;x[imi] sequen solu&bhocotil;em sive illam part dci primi Subsidij &bhopubr; ipsam debitam
primo die Decembris ultimo &bhopcrl;&bhotcrl;iti &bhopubrc; &bhopubrc;mo&bhocotil;e sua &bhopcrl;dica. Sed &bhopcrl;dcus A. B. nec apud Ecclesiam de L. &bhopcrl;dict
eodem die, nec alibi &bhopubr; quinquaginta dies postea, s&bhouov;mam &bhopubr; ipsam debitam (ut &bhopcrl;fert<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) solvit vel satisfecit,
neq[ue] dcam s&bhouov;mam de &bhopubrc;ficuis dce &bhopubrc;mo&bhocotil;is nec de bonis &amp; catallis dci A. B. aliquo modo levare sive reci&bhopubr;e potui.</para>
		<para id="p27">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for Tender of Payment by Incumbent, &amp; c. before Certificate exhibited into the Exchequer; Trial of Tender.; If Issue found for Incumbent, he to enjoy his Promotion</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p28">Provided allwaies that if anie &bhopubr;son or Incumbent chargeable by this A&bholigct; or graunt to anie payment of these
three Subsidies or anie part thereof shall proffer and tender payment of anie s&bhooov;me due to the Archbishop of Bishop,
or to the Deane and Chapter where the See is void, or to anie Undercolle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors Deputie or Deputies
of anie Archbishop Bishopp or Deane and Chapter aforesaid at anie time before the Certificate exhibited into the
Exchequer as is aforesaid that then notwithstanding the Certificate made as is aforesaid against anie such &bhopubr;son the
said Incumbent or &bhopubr;son, against whome the Certificate was so made shall and may averre the offer and tender of
his Payment as is aforesaid and of the same shalbe tryed either by sufficient witnesses before the Lord Treasurer
and Barons of the Exchequer or by the tryall of twelve men uppon anie issue thereuppon to be joyned betwixt the
said Incumbent and anie other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons that he or anie for him did offer and tender the Paiement of the
s&bhooov;me due as aforesaid, which being found for the Incumbent then evirie such Incumbent shall have and injoye his
Promocion or &bhopubrc;mocions still without forfeiture or losing to your Majestie your Heires or Successors anie the &bhopubrc;fitts
thereof and as though noe Certificate or default of anie such payment had bene made or exhibited, anie thing in this
&bhopcrl;sent Graunt or A&bholigct; to the contrarie notwithstanding.</para>
		<para id="p29">
			<emph type="i">Quietus est to Archbishops, &amp; c. being Colle&bholigct;ors; Fee for Quietus est.; Refusing, &amp; c. Quietus est or taking a larger Fee.; Penalty &pound;10.; Particular Acquittance by Colle&bholigct;or to Incumbent, &amp; c. a full Discharge in Law.; Acquittance before Certificate not good</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p30">And further that it may be ena&bholigct;ed likewise that every Archbishop and Bishop, and Deane and Chapter of every
See vacant, and other &bhopubr;sons chargeable to and with the Colleccion of theise three Subsidies within the said Province
of Canterbury shall and may have uppon every payment of the same three Subsidies made to the Lord High
Tresurer or Undertresurer of England for the tyme being, or to such other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons in place and places to
whome and where it shall please your Highnes, or your Court of Exchequer, to appoint for the receipt thereof at
every of the aforesaid tymes of payment, a sufficient acquittance discharge or Quietus est in Writing of the aforesaid
Lord High Tresurer or Undertresurer, or of such other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons, as either your Highnes or your said Court
of Exchequer shall assigne for the receipt thereof, or as heretofore in the like cases it hath been accustomed, the same
acquittance, discharge or Quietus est witnessing the receipt of so much of the same s&bhooov;me of the said three Subsidies
as shalbe so received, and every such acquittance, discharge, or Quietus est in writing subscribed with the name or
names of the Lord High Tresurer, or Undertresurer for the tyme being, or of such Auditor or other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons as it shall please your Highnes or your said Court of Exchequer to appoint for the same receipt, or of such others
as heretofore in like cases it hath beene used, shall and may be good and effe&bholigct;uall in the Lawe, and be also as
sufficient a discharge to all and every of the said Colle&bholigct;ors, to all such intent&bholngs; construccions and purposes, as if the
same were made by A&bholigct; of Parliament, And that every of the said Colle&bholigct;ors, shall pay but onelie three shillings
foure pence for every generall or finall acquittance discharge or Quietus est, for every payment of the said three
Subsidies, And if any &bhopubr;son so assigned, shall refuse or delay to make such a generall or finall acquittance, discharge,
or Quietus est for any payment of the said three Subsidies, or shall require or take for the same any more then
three shilling&bholngs;foure pence: Or if any other Officer of the Exchequer shall require and take of any Colle&bholigct;or or
Colle&bholigct;ors, or of his or their Undercolle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors, Deputie or Deputies, in respe&bholigct; of the Colleccion,
Payment or account of the said three Subsidies, or any Part thereof, or for expedicion, or for any other cause or
&bhopcrl;tence whatsoever concerning the same, any fees or s&bhooov;mes of money, other then are before in this &bhopcrl;sent Graunt
expressly allowed unto them, shall forfeit the s&bhooov;me of tenne pound&bholngs; of lawfull mony of England, to be paid and
recovered in like manner, and to the same uses as is before limited and expressed in this Graunt touching the like
Forfeitures of Receivers and Auditors. And also that every particular Acquittance, which uppon any Payment of
the said three Subsidies shalbe made by any Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors of the said three Subsidies, or of any payment
of them, or by his or their Undercolle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors Deputie or Deputies, in that behalfe, to any Incumbent
of any Benefice or &bhopubrc;mocion Spirituall, or to any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons contributory and chargeable to and with the said
three Subsidies or any part or payment of them, shall be good and effe&bholigct;uall in Lawe, and a full and sufficient discharge
to every such Incumbent, and other &bhopubr;son and his Benefice and &bhopubrc;mocion Spirituall, of and for all such s&bhooov;me and
s&bhooov;mes of mony, as by the same acquittance shalbe acknowledged to bee received, in respe&bholigct; of the same Benefice,
or &bhopubrc;mocion Spirituall, for any payment, or any part of the said three Subsidies: and that none acquittance of any
other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons, made before such Certificate, shall in any wise discharge any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubrc;mocion for any Part or
payment of his said Subsidies, nor of any paine penaltie or forfeiture specified in this Graunt.</para>
		<para id="p33">
			<emph type="i">Names of Undercolle&bholigct;ors, &amp; c. certified by Archbishop, &amp; c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p34">And to the intent it may be knowne to the Court of Exchequer, who be the Undercolle&bholigct;or or Undercolle&bholigct;ors
Deputie or Deputies of every such Archbishopp, Bishopp, or Deane and Chapter authorized to receive the same,
and to make acquittance thereof, every Archbishopp, Bishopp, and Deane and Chapter of any See being void, shall
yearelie together with their Certificates aforemencioned, certifie the names of every of the Undercolle&bholigct;ors or Deputies
to be appointed as is aforesaid.</para>
		<para id="p35">
			<emph type="i">Process not to issue within Twenty Days after Day prefixed for Payment; Fee to Colle&bholigct;or on Acquittance</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p36">Provided alwaies, that no Colle&bholigct;or of these three Subsidies, or of any part of them, shall use any &bhopubrc;cesse or
compulsorie meanes, or exa&bholigct; any Fees or s&bhooov;mes of monie for the same, or otherwise, of any &bhopubr;son for not paying the
said three subsidies or any Part thereof, at such certaine day and place as shall be by the Colle&bholigct;or, or his
Undercolle&bholigct;or or Deputie &bhopcrl;fixed, in case the said &bhopubr;son shall tender the same unto the Colle&bholigct;or or his Undercolle&bholigct;or
or Deputie within twentie daies next after such &bhopcrl;fixed day. And that the said Colle&bholigct;ors shall not by themselves
or any other take of any &bhopubr;son for the receipt of any severall payment of the said three Subsidies, and for his
acquittance thereuppon, any more then foure pence, by any colour or &bhopcrl;text whatsoever.</para>
		<para id="p37">
			<emph type="i">Spiritual Promotions, &amp; c. not chargeable to any other Subsidy</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p38">Provided alwaies, that no Spirituall &bhopubrc;mocions, nor any land&bholngs; possessions or revenues annexed to the same, being
charged by this Graunt of the Province of Canterbury, or any good&bholngs; or chattell&bholngs; growing being or renewing uppon
the same or elsewhere appertayning to the owners of the said Spirituall &bhopubrc;mocions, or to any of them, shalbe charged
or made contributorie to any Fifteene or Tenth, or to any other Subsidie alreadie graunted to your Highnes by the
Laitie or hereafter to be graunted during the tyme appointed by this graunt for the Payment of the said three
Subsidies.</para>
		<para id="p39">
			<emph type="i">Deans, Archdeacons, Prebendaries, &amp; c. of Cathedrals and Colleges, &amp; c. how chargeable.; Archbishop, &amp; c. to certify Portions chargeable and not chargeable into Exchequer</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p40">Provided also, that all Deanes, Archdeacons, Dignities, Masters, Wardens, and Prebendaries of all Cathedrall
and Collegiate Churches, and Colledges or any of them within the said Province shalbe [chargeable<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] with theise
three Subsidies for those possessions revenues, and &bhopubrc;mocions onelie, which to their severall promocions, dignities and
roomes are cleerelie and distin&bholigct;lie lymitted, and to their onelie use severed, thereof to pay (the tenth part being
dedu&bholigct;ed) for every and each of the said three Subsidies foure shilling&bholngs;of every full pound in manner and forme as
is above rehearsed. And that all those rent&bholngs; possessions proffitts porcions hereditament&bholngs; and Spirituall promocions
and every of them heretofore by your Highnes, or any of the King&bholngs;or Queenes of this Realme, or any other &bhopubr;son
or &bhopubr;sons whatsoever, given, graunted, bequethed, devised, or impropriated unto the said Cathedrall or collegiate
Churches or Colledges, or to any of them which any waies be assigned, imployed, or used, either for or towards
the yearelie mainten<emph type="p">a</emph>nce of Readers of Divinitie, Poore men, Schoolemasters, Ushers, Grammarians, Petie Canons,
Condu&bholigct;s, Vicars chorall, Singingmen, Choristers, Virgers, Sextons, or of any other necessarie or dailie Officers
or Ministers in such Cathedrall or Collegiate Churches or Colledges, or anie of them, or for or towards the
reedifying or repayring of any of the same Cathedrall or Collegiate Churches or Colledges, shall not be charged
with any part of theise three Subsidies: the certentie of which porcions aswell chargeable to theise three Subsidies,
as not chargeable in this behalfe, the Archbishopp or Bishopp of the Dioces, or (the See being void) the Deane and
Chapter or any other to whome the same shall or may appertaine, uppon due search and examinacion shall certifie
under his or their Seales into your Highnes said Court of Exchequer, at or before the severall daies aforesaid appointed
for the payment&bholngs; of the said three Subsidies.</para>
		<para id="p41">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for Spiritual Persons paying Pensions</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p42">Provided alwaies, that every Parson Vicar, or other Spirituall &bhopubr;son paying any Pension whereof no allowance is
made in the valuacion of his &bhopubrc;mocion or Benefice shall and may retaine to his owne use and releife so much of
every pound of every such Pension for every payment of these three Subsidies as he standeth charged by this Graunt
to pay for every Part and payment of these three Subsidies out of every pound for the whole valuacion of his
Spirituall &bhopubrc;mocion, any Coven<emph type="p">a</emph>nt, Graunt, or Bond to the contrarie notwithstanding.</para>
		<para id="p43">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for Lands, &amp; c. formerly granted for Obits, &amp; c. and come into the hands of King E. VI. under A&bholigct; 1 Edw. VI. c. 14</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p44">Provided also and your said Prelates and Clergie doe most humblie beseech your Highnes, that it may be ena&bholigct;ed
by your Majesties authoritie and your High Court of Parliament, that where certaine Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; Rent&bholngs;
Spirituall Promocions Tithes Pencions Porcions Fruit&bholngs; and other Hereditament&bholngs;, latelie belonging to divers Cathedrall
Churches and to other places and &bhopubr;sons Ecclesiasticall within the said Province of Canterbury, which were given
and assigned to be bestowed and spent in and on finding and maintayning of certaine Chauntries, Anniversaries,
Obites, Light&bholngs;, Lampes, and other like charges, intent&bholngs;, and purposes, of late came into the hand&bholngs; and possession
of the late King of famous memorie, Edward the sixt by force of a Statute thereof made in the first yeare of his
raigne as by the said Statute more plainelie appeareth, that the Cathedrall Churches, and the Bishopps, Deanes or
Presidents, and Chapters, and Prebendaries of the same, and all other places and &bhopubr;sons Ecclesiasticall and every of
them, to whome the said Land&bholngs; Rent&bholngs; and other the &bhopcrl;misses, or anie of them did latelie appertaine, shall not during
the tyme appointed by this Graunt for the payment of the said three Subsidies be charged to and with any payment
of Subsidie, of and for, that part and porcion of Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; Rent&bholngs; Spirituall &bhopubrc;mocions and other Hereditament&bholngs;,
or any of them whereunto the said late King by force of the said Statute was intituled or possessed of, nor of any
yerelie Rent&bholngs; or Payment&bholngs; going, out of the said Cathedrall Churches and other the Places and &bhopubr;sons Ecclesiasticall
aforesaid, And that deduccion and allowance thereof be made to them and every of them accordinglie, in and uppon
every payment of the said three Subsidies out of the whole taxacion valuacion and estimacion made for the payment
of the said &bhopubr;petuall Disme or Tenth remayning of Record in your Highnes Court of Exchequer as aforesaid for the
rate and porcion of Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; Rent&bholngs; Spirituall &bhopubrc;mocions and other Hereditament&bholngs;, and those yerelie
payment&bholngs; whereunto the said late King was intituled or possessed of, or which since the making of the said Statute,
by reason they have byn found as Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; Rent&bholngs; Tithes and other Hereditament&bholngs; concealed from the
said late King Edward the sixt, the late King Henry the eight, the late Queene Mary, the late Queene Elizabeth,
your late most Royall Father, or any of them, or from your Majestie, or otherwise are severed from the possessions
of the said Cathedrall Churches, and other the places and &bhopubr;sons aforesaid or of any of them by force of the Statute
premised or any otherwise.</para>
		<para id="p45">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for the Universities; Colleges of Windsor, Westminster, Eaton, and Winchester; ; Hospitals, Free Schools, &amp; c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p46">Provided also, that these three Subsidies graunted by the Clergie or any part of them, shall not be demaunded or
levied out of any Benefice, house of Student&bholngs; or Colledge scituate or sett within either of the Univ[er]sities of Oxford
or Cambridge or any Benefice Landes, or other revenues unto the said Univ[er]sities or either of them, or to any
house of Student&bholngs; or Colledge in any of the said Univ[er]sities united appropriated or appertayning, or out of any
Benefice Land&bholngs; or revenues of the Colledge of Windsor, or of the Colledge of Westminster, or of the Colledge of
Eaton neere Windsor, or of the Colledge called Saint Maries Colledge by Winchester founded by William Wickham
sometimes Bishopp of Winchester, or of any Hospitall&bholngs; Almehouses Grammer Schooles, or of any Church, Benefice,
or other, revenues to the said Colledges Hospitall&bholngs;, Almeshouses or Grammer Schooles, or to any of them annexed
appropriated or otherwise appertayning.</para>
		<para id="p47">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for Living&bholngs;not above &pound;6. 13. 4. yearly.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p48">Provided alwaies, That all Parsons, Vicars, and all other Ecclesiasticall &bhopubr;sons, whose Benefices are not above
six pound&bholngs; thirteene shilling&bholngs;foure pence by the yeere after the taxacion aforesaid, shall not be charged with these
three Subsidies, or any part of the same.</para>
		<para id="p49">
			<emph type="i">Living&bholngs; of &pound;8. and not above &pound;10. yearly Value, shall pay 6s. 8d. on each Subsidy; Vicarages under &pound;8. Incumbent not to be charged</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p50">Provided also that every Viccar, whose Benefice is eight pound&bholngs; or above, and not above ten pound&bholngs; by the
yeare, after the taxacion aforesaid, shall pay unto your Highnes your Heires and Successors six shilling&bholngs;and eight
pence at every payment of the said three Subsidies, at such times and to such &bhopubr;sons as is aforesaid, for his part of
the said three Subsidies, And if any Vicarage be under eight pound&bholngs; by the taxacion aforesaid, the Incumbent shall
not be charged with any part or payment of the said three Subsidies: And for the sure and true payment of these
three Subsidies graunted by your said &bhopcrl;lates and Clergie of the province of Canterburie, according to the tenor
purpose effe&bholigct; and true meaning of this &bhopcrl;sent Graunte, your said Prelates and Clergie most humblie desire your
Highnes, that this their said Gift, Graunt, and three Subsidies and every matter, s&bhooov;me of mony, Peticion, Clause,
&bhopubrc;visions, Reservacions and Sentences in this Instrument conteyned, concerning the said three Subsidies, may be ratified
established and confirmed by the authoritie of your Highnes Court of Parliament.</para>
		<para id="p51">In quo[rum] o[mn]i[u]m &amp; singulo[rum] &bhopubr;misso[rum] fidem &amp; testimonium, Nos Georgius Archiepus Cantuariensis antedcus has &bhopcrl;sentes
lras nras Testimoniales, sive hoc &bhopcrl;sens publicum Instrumentum ad humilem rogatum Prelato[rum] &amp; Cleri &bhopcrl;dict, Sigilli
nri appensione, ac signo no[m]i[n]e &amp; subscrip&bhocotil;e Johis Drake Notarij publici deputati Nichi Weston Registrarij n[ost]ri principalis,
jussim &amp; fecim c&bhooov;uniri. Datum dcio o&bholigct;avo die mensis Julij Anno Dni Mittimo sexcentesimo vicesimo quinto,
Regniq[ue] vri felicissimi Ang&bhoalias; Scocie Franci &amp; Hibn primo &amp; nre transla&bhocotil;is Anno decimo quinto.</para>
		<para id="p52">
			<emph type="i">Grant ratified by Parliament.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p53">Wherefore for the true and sure payment of the said Subsidies graunted by the said Prelates and Clergie of the
said Province of Canterbury according to the tenor effe&bholigct; and true meaning of the said Instrument, Be it ena&bholigct;ed
by the King&bholngs;most Excellent Majestie with the assent of the Lord&bholngs; Spirituall and Temporall, and the C&bhooov;mons in
this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled, and by the authoritie of the same, that the said Gift and Graunte, and every
matter s&bhooov;me of mony; peticion, &bhopubrc;vision, clause, and sentence in the same Instrument conteyned, shall stand and be
ratified established and confirmed by the authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Power to Colle&bholigct;ors to levy Subsidies by Authority of Censures of the Church and by Sequestration, Distress, &amp; c.</head>
			<para id="p54">And further be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, that every &bhopubr;son that shalbe appointed to the colle&bholigct;ing and
gathering of the said Subsidies, shall have [full<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] power and authoritie to levie take and &bhopubr;ceive the said Subsidies by
the Authoritie of the Censures of the Church, That is to saie, by Suspension, Exc&bhooov;municacion, or Interdiccion, and
also by Sequestracion of the fruites and proffitts of their Benefices and promocions Spirituall, in whose hand&bholngs; soever
they be, and to make sale of the same fruit&bholngs;, without danger of the Lawes of this Realme, or by distresse uppon
the possessions of the Farmers or occupiers of the Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; chargeable by the said Instrument, for or
to the payment of any s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of monie to be due by force thereof, or otherwise by the discrecion of the</para>
			<para id="p55">
				<emph type="i">Farmers paying for their Lessors may retain out of Rent.; Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p56">Colle&bholigct;or thereof. And that no Replevie, Prohibicion, or Su&bhopubr;sedeas, shall be allowed or obeyed for anie &bhopubr;sons
making default of the payment of the said Subsidies or any of them contrary to the tenor of the Graunt thereof,
untill such time as they have trulie satisfied and contented all such part and porcions as to them in that behalfe
appertayneth. And that every such Farmor and Farmors their Executors and Assignes that shall fortune hereafter
to be charged to or with the payment of the said Subsidies or anie part [of them,<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] shall by the Authoritie aforesaid
be allowed and retaine in his hand&bholngs; as much of his yearelie Rent and Farme as the s&bhooov;me which he shall fortune to
pay for his Lord or Leasour shall extend unto; (except that the said Farmor or Farmors their Executors or Assignes,
by the Lease and Graunt that they have of any part of the Landes Tithes Proffitts [and<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Tenement&bholngs; chargeable to
the said Subsidies or by force of any Coven<emph type="p">a</emph>nt or Article therein contayned, be bound and charged to pay the
same, and thereof to discharge the Leasor and Landlord during the terme mencioned in the said Lease.)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Subsidies may be levied by Distress on Farmers of Impropriations.</head>
			<para id="p57">
				<emph type="i">Sale of Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p58">And likewise, be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, That whereas divers Curates liable to
the Subsidies, being oftentymes removeable, doe serve aswell in divers Impropriacions beloingning to the Kings
Majestie, as in other Spirituall promocions belonging to other &bhopubr;sons, that for the speedy recoverie of the said
Subsidies it may be lawfull to the said Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors of the said Subsidies their Deputie or Deputies to levie
the said Subsidies uppon the Farmor or Farmors, or occupiers of all such Impropriacions or Spirituall &bhopubrc;mocions
by all censures of the Church aforesaid, and every of them, or by way of distresse of Tithes of the said Impropriacion
or Impropriacions and Spirituall &bhopubrc;mocions, or otherwise uppon the good&bholngs; and chattell&bholngs; of the said Farmor or Farmors
and Occupiers, in which case no inhibicion &bhopubrc;hibicion Replevin or other &bhopubrc;cesse awarded to the contrary shalbe
obeyed, any Lawes Statutes Priviledges or Customes to the contrary hereof heretofore made graunted or used or
hereafter to be made graunted or used to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding. And that it may be lawfull to
the Colle&bholigct;or and other Officers and Ministers of such Archbishop, Bishop, Deane and Chapter for not payment
of the said Subsidies, after the same shalbe due in or at any of the said tymes of payment, to prise and value the
said Distresse or Distresses by two indifferent neighbours by him to be chosen, and the Distresse and Distresses so
prised to sell and thereof to detaine so much mony as shall amount to the s&bhooov;me payable to the King&bholngs;most Excellent
Majestie with the reasonable charges also of the said Colle&bholigct;ors susteined in that behalfe, and the rest of the money
made of the said Distresse to be delivered and paid to the Owner and Occupier thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. How Lay Impropriators to be charged for their Spiritual and Temporal Possessions.</head>
			<para id="p59">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, that every lay &bhopubr;son having Spirituall &bhopubrc;mocion
chargeable by this A&bholigct;, and also having Temporall possessions Good&bholngs; Chattell&bholngs; and Debt&bholngs; charged to the said
Subsidies graunted in this Parliament by the Temporaltie, shalbe taxed charged and sett for his said Spirituall
&bhopubrc;mocions with the Clergie, and his Temporall possessions and Chattell&bholngs; reall with the Temporaltie, and not
otherwise, any thing before mencioned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. This A&bholigct; extended to the Subsidy of the Province of York.</head>
			<para id="p60">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, that all and every graunt and graunt&bholngs; of all and every
s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes of monie granted, or which hereafter shalbe graunted to the King&bholngs;Majestie by the Clergie of the
Province of Yorke, shalbe of the same strength force and effe&bholigct; in all thing&bholngs;, as the said graunt made by the said
Province of Canterbury, and shalbe taxed certified colle&bholigct;ed levied gathered and paied according to the tenor forme
and effe&bholigct; of this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; of Parliament to all intent&bholngs; construccions and purposes in such manner and forme as
though it were specially plainelie and particulerlie expressed and rehearsed in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; by expresse words
termes and sentences, in their severall natures and kindes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Provisions in the Grants of the Clergy declared valid.</head>
			<para id="p61">Provided alwaies, and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, that all &bhopubrc;visions before rehearsed, contayned or to
be contayned in the said Graunt of the Prelates and Clergie of the Province of Canterbury, and the like of the same
Provisoes contayned in the said Graunt of the Prelates and Clergie of the Province of Yorke, shalbe good and
effe&bholigct;uall, and to be observed and kept in every point and article according to the purport and true meaning of
the same.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">foresaid <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">and <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">being <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">authorizatus <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">authorizatum <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">charged <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">thereof <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


