<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47210" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1627</title>
	<subtitle>Capter VII. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) An Act for the confirmacion of the Subsidies graunted by the Clergie.[ Rot. Parl. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Grant of Five whole Subsidies.</head>
		<para id="p1">WHERE the Prelates and Clergie of the Province of Canterbury for divers weightie consideracions respe&bholigct;ing
his Majesties extraordinary occasions have lovinglie and liberallie given and graunted to the King&bholngs; most
Excellent Majestie five whole and entire Subsidies of foure shilling&bholngs; in the pound to be taken and levied of all
and singuler their &bhopubrc;mocions Spirituall within the same Province at such dayes and tymes and in such certaine manner
and forme and with such excepcions and &bhopubrc;visions as be specified and delivered in a certaine Instrument by them thereof
made and delivered unto the King&bholngs; Majestie under the Seale of the most reverend Father in God George now
Archbishopp of Canterbury and Primate of all England, which Instrument is now exhibited in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament
to be ratified and confirmed, The tenor whereof ensueth in theise word&bholngs;.</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Tenor of the Instrument.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p3">SERENISSIMO &amp; Excellentissimo in X[christ]o Principi &amp; D&ntilde;o n[ostr]o clementissimo D&ntilde;o Carolo Dei Gra Anglie Scocie
Francie &amp; Hib&ntilde; Regi Fidei Defensori &amp;c. Georgius &bhopubrc;videncia Divina Cantuar Archiep[scop]us tocius Anglie Primas &amp;
Metropolitanus &bhooov;nimodam obedienciam ac felicitatem &amp; sal[uta]tem in eo &bhopubr; quem Reges regnant &amp; Principes dnant<emph type="p">r</emph>.
Inclitissime vre Regie Majestati &bhopubr; &bhopubr;sens publicum instrumentum sive has lras nras testimoniales notum facim &amp;
significam qd Prelati &amp; Clerus Provincie
nre Cantuar in Sacra Synodo Provinciali sive convoca&bhocotil;e vigore &amp; authoritate
bris vri Regij nobis direct in Domo capitulari Eccl[es]ie vre Cath[edral]is Sancti Pauli London Decimo octavo die Mensis Marcij
Anno D&ntilde;i juxta cursum &amp; computa&bhocotil;em Eccl[es]ie Anglicane Mitimo sexcentesimo vicesimo septimo inchoata &amp; celebrata
ac de die in diem &amp; loco in locum usq[ue] ad &amp; in diem Mercurij septim[u]m videl[ice]t diem &bhopcrl;sentis Mensis Maij Anno D&ntilde;i
Mill[ess]imo sexcentesimo vicesimo octavo post Meridiem continuata ac &bhopubrc;rogata in Eccl[es]ia Collegiata B[ea]ti Petri Westm eodem
septimo die &bhopcrl;sentis Mensis Maij legittime congregati &bhopubr; quibusdam g<emph type="p">a</emph>vib[us] &amp; urgentib[us] causis &bhopubr; nos eis &bhopcrl;positis ac in&bhotcrl;
eos delib[er]a&bhocotil;e matura ponderatis &bhopubr; defensione Regno[rum] &amp; Domino[rum] vestro[rum] sed &amp; &bhopubr; eo[rum] eciam erga Regiam vram sublimitatem
obsequiosa observancia quinq[ue] spontanea ultronea &amp; voluntaria Subsidia vre Regie Magnificencie unanimi eo[rum] consensu
&amp; assensu dederunt &amp; concesserunt &bhopubrc;ut tenore &bhopcrl;sentis publici Instrumenti (seriem concessionis huiusmodi in se continentis)
plenius liquet &amp; apparet humili&bhotcrl; &amp; obnixe vre Regie Majestati supplicantes quatenus hec eo[rum] quinq[ue] Subsidia &bhopubrc; vra
consueta clemencia benigne accipiatis ac bene consul[ia]e g[ene]rose dignemini. Tenor vero dce concessionis de verbo in v[er]bum
sequit<emph type="p">r</emph> &amp; est talis.</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Five whole Subsidies of 4s. in the Pound on all Spiritual Promotions.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p5">Most gracious and most religious Soveraigne your Majesties faithfull Subjects the Prelates and Clergie of the
Province of Canterbury being called together by vertue of your Highnes Writt and orderlie assembled at this &bhopcrl;sent
in a Provinciall Synode or Convocacion well considering and maturelie weighing with themselves that dutie which by
the Sacred Word of God they doe owe unto your Majestie as to their true naturall and gracious Soveraigne Lord,
and that so much the more for the free passage of the holy Gospell amongest them which by Gods goodnes and
your meanes they enjoy beyond all other nacions, And knowing the incessant care and travaile of your Majesties
minde for the well governing of this great people c&bhooov;mitted by God to your charge, but most of all remembring the
manifold expences whereat your Majestie is, and is dailie like more and more to be both for the honorable support
of your Royall estate and for the necessary defence of this your Realme of England and your other Dominions
against so many so mighty and so combined enemies, who not onelie hate our &bhopubr;sons, but the verie Religion which
wee &bhopubrc;fesse; as a testimonie of their trulie loyall affeccion and most bounden service with one uniforme accord and
consent have given and graunted, and by their &bhopcrl;sents doe give and graunte to your Highnes your Heires and
Successors five whole and intire Subsidies of foure shillings in the pound in manner and forme following,
That is to saie, That every Archbishopp Bishopp Deane Archdeacon Provost Master of Colledge Prebendary
Parson and Vicar and every other &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons of whatsoever name or degree he or they be within the Province of
Canterbury having or enjoying any Spirituall Promocion or other Temporall possession to the same Spirituall
Promocion annexed now not divided nor seperated by Acte of Parliament or otherwise from the possession of the
Clergie shall pay to your Highnes your Heires and Successors for every pound that he may yearelie receive and
dispend by reason of the said Spirituall Promocion the s&bhooov;me of foure shillings for every of the said five Subsidies.</para>
		<para id="p6">
			<emph type="i">Benefices to be valued according to Taxation of the Tenth under 26 H. VIII. c. 3. but to pay Subsidy on 9.10th only</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p7">And for the true and certaine value of all the Promocions and every of them whereof the payment of theise five
Subsidies shalbe made the Rate Taxacion Valuacion and Estimacion now remayning of Record in your Ma[jes]ties Court
of Exchequer for the payment of a &bhopcrl;petuall Disme or Tenth graunted unto King Henry the eight of worthie memorie
in the six and twentith yeare of his Reigne concerning such &bhopubrc;mocion as now be in the possession of the Clergie shall
onelie be followed and observed without making any other Valuacion Rate Taxacion or Estimacion then in the
said Record is comprised. Provided alwaies, that forasmuch as the tenth part of the said Rate and Valuacion before
mencioned is yearelie paid to your Highnes for the said &bhopcrl;petuall Disme or Tenth, so as there remaine onelie nyne
parts yearelie to the Incumbent cleare, These five Subsidies of foure shillings of the pounds shall be understood
and meant onelie of every full pound of the said nyne parts and nothing for any other mony not amounting to
a full pound.</para>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">Manner and Form and Times of Payment. ; Fee to Receiver or other Officer.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p9">And your Prelats and Clergie doe alsoe graunt that theise five Subsidies of foure shillings of the full pound of
the nine parts of the yearelie value of every Spirituall promocion aforesaid within the said Province taxed as is aforesaid
shalbe payed to your Majestie your Heires and Successors in manner and forme following That is to saie, The first
payment and moytie of the first of theise five Subsidies videl[ia]t, two shillings of every full pound as aforesaid to be
due at and uppon the first day of December which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred
and thirtie, And the second payment and moytie of the first of the said five Subsidies, videl[ia]t two shillings of every
full pound as aforesaid to be due at and uppon the first day of June which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God One
thousand six hundred thirtie and one, And the first paym[en]t and moytie of the second of the said five Subsidies, videl[ia]t
two shillings of every full pound as aforesaid to be due at and uppon the first day of December then next and
i&bhomov;ediatelie following in the same yeare, And the second payment and moytie of the second of the said Five Subsidies,
videl[ia]t two Shillings of every full pound as aforesaid to be due at and uppon the first day of June then next and
ymediatelie following which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God, one thousand six hundred thirtie and two. And
the first payment and moytie of the third of the said five Subsidies, videl[ia]t, two Shillings of every full pound as
aforesaid to be due at and uppon the first day of December then next and imediatelie following in the same yeare.
And the second payment and moitie of the third of the said five Subsidies, videl[ia]t, two shillings of every full pound
at and uppon the first day of June then next and imediatelie following which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God
one thousand six hundred thirtie and three And the first payment and moytie of the fourth of the said five Subsidies,
videl[ia]t, two shillings of every full pound as aforesaid to be due at and uppon the first day of December then next
and ymediatelie following in the same yeare, And the second payment and moitie of the fourth of the said five Subsidies,
videl[ia]t, two shillings of every full pound as aforesaid to be due at and uppon the first day of June then next and
ymediatelie following which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six hundred thirtie and foure And
the first payment and moitie of the fift and last of the said five Subsidies, videl[ia]t, two shillings of every full pound
as aforesaid to be due at and uppon the first day of December then next and ymediatelie following in the same yeare,
And the second and last payment and moytie of the fift and last of these five Subsidies to be due at and uppon the
first day of June which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six hundred thirtie and five to be delivered
and paid by such &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons as in this &bhopcrl;sent Graunt shalbe appointed to have the Colleccion thereof to the
Lord high Treasurer or Undertreasurer of England for the tyme being or to such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons and in such
place or places as shall please your Highnes to appoint to be paid videl[ia]t, The first payment of every of the
said five Subsidies which shalbe due at and uppon the first day of December as aforesaid to be paid at or before the
last day of Februarie next following every of the aforesaid daies when the said payments or moyties shalbe due. And
the second payment of every of the said five Subsidies which shalbe due at and uppon the first day of June as
aforesaid to be made at or before the last day of August next following after every of the aforesaid daies when the
said payments or moyties shalbe due without paying any thing to the Receiver or any other &bhopubr;son or officer to be
assigned for the receipt thereof for any acquittance or other discharge or dispatch uppon any such payment or receit
of the said five Subsidies or any part thereof but onelie foure pence, and that to the Clerke for writing the Acquittance
or discharge of every of the said payments.</para>
		<para id="p10">
			<emph type="i">Subsidy not payable for the Year in which First Fruits are paid</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p11">Provided alwaies, that no &bhopubr;son which hereafter shalbe &bhopubrc;moted to any Benefice or spirituall promocion and shall
compound with your Majestie your Heires or Successors for the first fruits of the same from the first day of December
which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six hundred and thirtie and on this side the first day of
June which shalbe in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred thirtie and five shalbe contributary or
charged for the same Benefice or Promocion to your Highnes your Heires or Successors with any part of the said
five Subsidies during the first yeare after the tyme of any such compounding for his first fruits.</para>
		<para id="p12">
			<emph type="i">Archbishops, &amp;c. to be Collectors</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p13">Item your Highnes said Prelates and Clergie doe graunt, that every Archbishopp Bishopp (the See being void)
every Deane and Chapter of that See void and none other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons shalbe Collectors of the said five Subsidies
within their &bhopubrc;per Dioces during the tyme appointed for the Payment of the said five Subsidies.</para>
		<para id="p14">
			<emph type="i">Collectors offering Payment, Officer to receive Money within Four Days, and give Receipt to Collector</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p15">And your said Prelates and Clergie doe most humblie beseech your Majestie that it may be enacted by your Majestie
and your High Court of Parliament for the speedie payment of the said five Subsidies and to avoid delaies thereof
that when and as often as any Collector or Collectors chargeable with the Colleccion of the said five subsidies or of
any part of them or their or any of their Undercollector or Undercollectors Deputie or Deputies or any of them
shall offer the payment of the said five subsidies or of any part of them to the use of your Majestie your Heires
	<emph type="i">Auditors to take Account within Six Days after Request, and make Allowances.; Delaying, &amp;c. so to do, Penalty &pound;10.; Imprisonment until Penalty paid</emph>.
		or Successors to any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons appointed to receive the same by your Highnes or by your Lord high Tresurer
that the said &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons so appointed shall within foure daies next after such appointment receive or cause to
be received the mony so offred to be paid without any further delay and deliver one sufficient Bill testifying the
receipt thereof to the said Collector or his Undercollector or Deputie uppon every such particular payment. And that
everie such Auditor as is or shalbe appointed to take or receive the account of any such Collector or Collectors
or of their severall Undercollectors or Deputies shall within six daies next after request to him to be made trulie
and indifferentlie take the said account and make allowance as by this Graunt is appointed, uppon paine that
every such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons appointed to receive the same s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of mony so offred and every such Auditor
shall lose and forfeit for every default or delay to be made to the Collector or Collectors Undercollector or
Undercollectors Deputie or Deputies soe offering to make payment or account as is aforesaid the s&bhooov;me of ten pounds
of lawfull mony of England, the one moitie thereof to be to your Majestie your Heires and Successors and the other
moytie to the said Collector or Collector Undercollector or Undercollectors Deputie or Deputies so greived the
same to be paid uppon complaint to be made to the said Lord Tresurer or Undertresurer or to the Lord cheife
Baron of your Majesties Court of Exchequer who uppon such complaint shall &bhopcrl;sentlie examine the matter and
finding default shall c&bhooov;mitt the offendor to Warde there to remaine untill he shall have paid the said severall
s&bhooov;mes so forfeited.</para>
		<para id="p16">
			<emph type="i">Power to Collectors to levy Subsidy, and may account for the same as the King and Exchequer shall appoint, as Archbishops, &amp;c. account for the Tenth; 
Archbishops, &amp;c. gathering and paying what they can, to be discharged for the rest.; Sixpence in the Pound allowed to Collectors</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p17">And for the better levying and recovering of the said Subsidies or any of them your said Prelates and Clergie doe
likewise most humblie [beseech<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] your Majestie that it may be enacted by your Majestie and your said High Court of
Parliament in manner and forme following That is to saie That every Collector of the said Five Subsidies and of
every part and parcell of them and their lawfull Undercollector or Undercollectors Deputie or Deputies may have
full power and authoritie to use all such waies and meanes and &bhopubrc;cesse as be &bhopcrl;scribed in the Act of &bhopubr;petuall Disme
for the Colleccion and levying thereof and may make account of the same before the Lord High Treasurer or
Undertresurer of England for the tyme being or any other Officer by your Highnes or your Court of Exchequer
to be appointed for the same and in such place as your Majestie shall likewise assigne in such wise and after such
forme onelie as the said Archbishopp and Bishopps be now charged to make account for the said &bhopubr;petuall Disme
and tenth, Whereby is meant that the lacke and default of payment of and for anie Spirituall promocion or
promocions shall [onlie<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] charge such incumbent or incumbents and such others as be bound to pay the same. And
that the Archbishopp Bishopp Deane and Chapter gathering that which they can receive and making payment thereof
shall for the rest not by them received be discharged by their Certificate to be made unto your Highnes Court
of Exchequer for every of the aforesaid payments which shalbe due upon the first day of December in any of the
aforesaid yeares at or before the last day of Februarie next and i[m]mediatelie following every of the aforesaid daies
when every of the said payments shalbe due, And for everie of the foresaid payments which shalbe due uppon
the first day of June in any of the foresaid yeares at or before the last day of August next and imediatelie following
every of the aforesaid daies when the said payments shalbe due, and that six pence of every pound wherewith the
Collector shalbe charged in his account clerelie to be paid into the Receipt of your Majesties Exchequer or into
such other place as shall please your Highnes to appoint shalbe allowed to the said Collector uppon his account for
the same at every of the aforesaid severall tymes of payment for the charges of the said Colleccion Portage safe
conveying and paying of the said five Subsidies.</para>
		<para id="p18">
			<emph type="i">Incumbent monished to pay and making default ; Proceedings.; Such Default certified into Exchequer. ; Penalty.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p19">And moreover, that it may be enacted likewise, That after any payment of the said five Subsidies shalbe once due
by vertue of this Graunt, if any Incumbent of any Benefice or Promocion Spirituall charged to the payment of any
of the said five Subsidies or any part thereof being at any tyme after that the same payment shalbe due lawfully
monished either &bhopubr;sonallie or at his Dignitie Stall Church or Mansion house by the Archbishopp or Bishopp of the
Dioces or his Undercollector or Undercollectors Deputie or Deputies or by the Deane and Chapter (the See being
void) or by any of their Undercollector or Undercollectors Deputie or Deputies authorized in that behalfe to appeare
by himselfe or his Deputie at a certaine day and place of convenient distance to the said Incumbent then to be
signified and &bhopcrl;fixed and then and there to pay such part of the said five Subsidies for his Benefice or Promocion
Spirituall or the whole, as then by vertue of this Graunt shalbe due, doe not either at the same day and place so to
him signified and &bhopcrl;fixed trulie content and pay or cause to be contented and paid such payments of the said five
Subsidies as then by him shalbe due to be paid unto the same Archbishopp or Bishopp or to his Undercollector or
Undercollectors Deputie or Deputies or to the Deane and Chapter of any See being void or to their Undercollector
or Undercollectors Deputie or Deputies or to one of them shewing sufficient deputacion from the said Archbishopp
Bishopp or Deane and Chapter under his or their Seale in that behalfe being readie at the said day and place so
signified and &bhopcrl;fixed to receive any payment of the said five Subsidies then due and openlie demaunding the same or
els pay every of the payments of the said five Subsidies given by this Graunte within fiftie daies next after anie such
&bhopcrl;fixed daies of warning at the furthest, soe that open demaund be made of every of the said payments of the said
five Subsidies in and at the said place and day before &bhopcrl;fixed, That then every Incumbent so making default of any
of the payments aforesaid w<emph type="p">ch</emph> shalbe due from [him<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] for anie of the parts of the said five Subsidies aforesaid after such
default thereof certified into your Majesties Exchequer in writing under the Seale and hand writing of any Archbishopp
or Bishopp or the c&bhooov;mon Seale of the Deane and Chapter (the See being void) charged with the Colleccion of the
said five Subsidies or any part of them, so that the said Certificate shalbe made according to the forme hereafter
expressed and exhibited into your Majesties said Court of Exchequer videl[ia]t For every of the aforesaid payments of
the said five Subsidies which shalbe due the first day of December in any of the aforesaid yeares at or before the
last day of Februarie next following every of the aforesaid daies when every of the said payments shalbe due And for every of the aforesaid payments which shalbe due [upon<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] the first day of June in any of the aforesaid yeares at or,
before the last day of August next following every of the aforesaid daies when every of the aforesaid payments shalbe
due as aforesaid shall forfeit and lose to your Majestie your Heires and Successors all the proffitts which of that onelie
Dignitie Benefice or Promocion for the which he maketh such default of payment and whereof such Certificate shalbe
made shall come grow and arise unto him (over and above the charges of serving the Cure and the a&bhonov;uall Tenth
due to be paid out of the said Living) in one whole yeare next after such Certificate made and delivered unto
your Highnes Court of Exchequer and there admitted in case the said Incumbent shall so long live: And that
every such Certificate of any [such<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] default of payment shalbe made according to the tenor and effect ensuing
(mutatis mutandis)</para>
		<para id="p20">
			<emph type="i">Form of Certificate of Default</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p21">Honorabilib[us] &amp; egregijs viris D&ntilde;o Thesaurario &amp; Baronib, de Sc<emph type="p">a</emph>c<emph type="p">a</emph>io Illustrissimi D&ntilde;i nri D&ntilde;i Caroli Dei gra Angl[ia]
Scocie Francie&amp; Hib[er]&ntilde; Regis fidei Defensoris &amp;c.</para>
		<para id="p22">Vester humilis J. &bhopubr;missione Divina L. Ep[iscop]us authoritate &amp; vigore cujusdam Actus Parliamenti Anno Regni dci Dni
Regis quarto edit &amp; &bhopubrc;vis ad colligendum &amp; levandum quinq[ue] Subsidia eidem D[omi]no Regi in eodem Parliamento &bhopubr; Prelatos
&amp; Clerum Cantuar Provincie concess videl[ice]t &bhopubr; prima solu&bhocotil;ne primi Subsidij solvend primo die Decembris ultimo &bhopubr;&bhotcrl;it
infra Dioces n[ost]ram L. deputat &amp; authorizat &bhooov;nimodam reverenciam tantis viris debitam cum honore. Vris reverencijs
ha[rum] serie a[n]nuncio &amp; &bhoccrl;tifico me &bhopubr;fatum Ep[iscopu]m modo quo &bhopubr;fert<emph type="p">r</emph> deputatum &amp; authorizatum sufficien&bhotcrl; &amp; cum &bhooov;ni diligencia
requisivisse &bhopubr; N.O. Subcollectorem seu deputatum meum in hac parte de quovis beneficio &amp; &bhopubrc;mo&bhocotil;e eccl[es]iastica in
quadam Schedula &bhopcrl;sentib[us] annex sp[ec]ificat s&bhouov;mas solu&bhocotil;is dci primi Subsidij &bhopubr; dcis beneficijs &amp; &bhopubr;mo&bhocotil;ib[us] debitas &amp;
solvendas dco primo dic Decembris ulti&bhomtild;m &bhopcrl;&bhotcrl;it, &bhopubrc;ut in eadem Scedula &bhopcrl;sentib[us] annex plenius liquet &amp; apparet. Sed dcas
s&bhouov;mas ex causis in eadem Scedula allegatis reci&bhopubr;e non potui In cujus rei testimoni&bhouov; Sigillum meum &bhopcrl;sentib[us] apposui.
Dat[um] die mensis Anno D&ntilde;ni.</para>
		<para id="p23">
			<emph type="i">Form of Schedule referred to in Certificate</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p24">The forme of which Schedule above mencioned ensueth.</para>
		<para id="p25">Civitas L. vel Decanatus de H.A.B. Rector vel Vicarius ibidem monitus fuit apud &bhopcrl;dict
die ulti&bhomtild;m &bhopcrl;&bhotcrl;it &bhopubr; N.O. Subcollectorem seu deputat meum ad solvend apud Eccl[es]iam de L. in Com.
R. die &bhopubrc; p[ro]x sequen solu&bhocotil;em sive illam partem dci primi Subsidij &bhopubr; ipsm debitam primo die
Decembris ultim &bhopcrl;&bhotcrl;it &bhopubr; &bhopubr;mo&bhocotil;e sua &bhopubr;dca: Sed &bhopubr;dcus A. B. nec apud Eccl[es]iam de L. &bhopubr;dict eodem
die nec alibi &bhopubr; quinquaginta dies postea su&bhomov;am &bhopubr; ipsm debitam ut &bhopubr;fert<emph type="p">r</emph> solvit vel satisfecit neq dcam su&bhomov;am
de &bhopubrc;ficuis dce &bhopubrc;mo&bhocotil;is nec de bonis &amp; catallis dci A. B. aliquo modo levare sive recipe potui.</para>
		<para id="p26">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for Tender of Payment by Incumbent, &amp;c. before Certificate exhibited into the Exchequer; Trial of Tender.; If Issue found for Incumbent he shall enjoy his Promotion</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p27">Provided allwaies that if any Person or Incumbent chargeable by this Act or Graunt to any payment of the said
five Subsidies or any part thereof shall proffer or tender payment of any s&bhouov;me due to the Archbishopp or Bishopp
or to the Deane and Chapter where the See is void or to any Undercollector or Undercollectors Deputie or Deputies
of any Archbishopp Bishopp or Deane and Chapter aforesaid at anie tyme before the Certificate, exhibited into the
Exchequer as is aforesaid, that then notwithstanding the Certificate made as is aforesaid against any such &bhopubr;son against
whome the said Certificate was so made shall and may averr the offer or tender of his payment as is aforesaid and of
the same shalbe tried either by sufficient witnesses before the Lord Tresurer and Barons of the Exchequer or by the
triall of twelve men uppon any issue thereuppon to be joyned betwixt the said Incumbent and any other &bhopubr;son or
&bhopubr;sons that he or any, of them did offer or tender payment of the s&bhouov;me due as aforesaid, which being found for the
Incumbent then every such Incumbent shall have and enjoy his promocion or Promocions still without forfeiture
or losing to your Majestie your Heires or Successors any the proffitts thereof, and as though no Certificate or
default of any such payment had been made or exhibited, any thing in this &bhopcrl;sent Graunt or Acte to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		<para id="p28">
			<emph type="i">Quietus est to Archbishop, &amp;c. being Collectors. ; Fees for Quietusest.; Refusing Quietus est, or taking a larger Fee.; Penalty, &pound;10.; Particular Acquittance by Collector to Incumbent, &amp;c. a full Discharge in Law.; Acquittances before Certificate not good.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p29">And further that it may be enacted likewise that every Archbishopp and Bishopp and Deane and Chapter of
every See vacant and other &bhopubr;sons chargeable to and with the Colleccion of the said five Subsidies within the said
Province of Canterbury shall and may have uppon every payment of the said five Subsidies made to the Lord high
Tresurer or Undertresurer of England for the tyme being or to such other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons in place and places to
whome and where it shall please your Highnes or your Court of Exchequer to appoint for the receipt thereof at every
of the aforesaid tymes of payment, a sufficient Acquittance Discharge or Quietus est in writing of the aforesaid Lord
high Tresurer or Undertresurer or of such other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons as either your Highnes or your said Court of
Exchequer shall assigne for the receipt thereof or as heretofore in the like case it hath bene accustomed, the same
acquittance discharge or Quietus est witnessing the receipt of so much of the same s&bhooov;me of the said five Subsidies
as shalbe soe received and every such acquittance discharge or Quietus est in writing subscribed with the name or
names of the Lord high Treasurer or Undertresurer for the tyme being or of such Auditor or other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons
as it shall please your Highnes or your said Court of Exchequer to appoint for the same receipt or of such
others as heretofore in like cases it hath byn used shall and may be good and effectuall in the Law and be also as
sufficient a discharge to all and every the said Collectors to all such intents constructions and purposes as if the
same were made by Act of Parliament And that every of the said Collectors shall pay but onelie three shillings
foure pence for every generall or finall acquittance discharge or Quietus est for every payment of the said five
Subsidies. And if any &bhopubr;son so assigned shall refuse or delay to make such a generall or finall acquittance discharge
or Quietus est for any payment of the said five Subsidies or shall take or require for the same any more then three
shillings foure pence Or if any other Officer of the Exchequer shall take or requier of any Collector or Collectors or
of his or their Undercollector or Undercollectors Deputie or Deputies in respect of the Colleccion payment or account
of the said five Subsidies or any part of them for expedition or for any other cause or &bhopcrl;tence whatsoever concerning
the same any Fees or s&bhooov;mes of mony other then are before in this &bhopcrl;sent Graunt expressly allowed unto them, shall forfeit the s&bhooov;me often Pounds of lawfull mony of England to be paid and recovered in like manner and to the same
uses as is before lymitted and expressed in this Graunt touching the like forfeiture of Receivors and Auditors. And also
that every particular Acquittance which uppon any payment of the said five Subsidies shalbe made by anie Collector
or Collectors of the said five Subsidies or any payment of them or by his or their Undercollector or Undercollectors
Deputie or Deputies in that behalfe to any Incumbent of any Benefice or Promocion Spirituall or to any &bhopubr;son or
&bhopubr;sons contributary and chargeable to and with the said five Subsidies or any part or payment of them shall be good and
effectuall in Law and a full and sufficient discharge to every such Incumbent and other &bhopubr;son and his Benefice and
&bhopubrc;mocion Spirituall of and for all such s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes of mony as by the same acquittance shalbe acknowledged to
be received in respect of the same Benefice or &bhopubrc;mocion Spirituall for any payment or any part of the said five Subsidies:
And that none acquittance of any other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons made before such Certificate, shall in any wise discharge any
&bhopubr;son or &bhopubrc;mocion for any [Part or<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] payment of the said five Subsidies nor of any paine. penaltie or forfeiture specified
in this Graunt.</para>
		<para id="p30">
			<emph type="i">Names of under Collectors certified by Archbishop, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p31">And to the intent it may be knowen to the Court of Exchequer who be the Undercollector or Undercollectors
Deputie or Deputies of every such Archbishopp Bishopp or Deane and Chapter authorized to receive the same and
to make acquittance thereof, every Archbishopp Bishopp and Deane and Chapter of any See being void shall yearelie
together with their Certificates aforemencioned certifie the names of every the Undercollectors or Deputies to be
appointed as is aforesaid.</para>
		<para id="p32">
			<emph type="i">Process not to issue within 20 Days after Day prefixed for Payment. ; 
			Fee to Collectors on Acquittance</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p33">Provided alwaies that no Collector of the said five Subsidies or of any part of them shall use anie Processe or
compulsorie meanes or exact any Fees or s&bhooov;mes of mony for the same or otherwise of anie &bhopubr;son for not paying the said
five Subsidies or any part of them at such certaine day and place as shalbe by the Collector or his Undercollector
or Deputie &bhopcrl;fixed in case the said &bhopubr;son shall tender the same unto the Collector or his Undercollector or Deputie
within twentie daies next after such &bhopcrl;fixed day, And that the said Collectors shall not by themselves or anie others
take of anie &bhopubr;son for the receipt of any severall payment of the said five Subsidies, and for his acquittance thereuppon
any more then foure pence by anie Colour or &bhopcrl;text whatsoever.</para>
		<para id="p34">
			<emph type="i">Spiritual Promotions, &amp;c. not chargeable to any other Subsidy</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p35">Provided allwaies, that no Spirituall promocions nor any lands possessions or revenues annexed to the same being
charged by this Graunte of the Province of Canterbury or any goods or chattells growing being or renewing
uppon the same or elsewhere appertayning to the owners of the said Spirituall promocions or to any of them shalbe
charged or made contributary to any Fifteene or Tenth or to any other Subsidies alreadie graunted to your Highnes
by the Laitie or hereafter to be graunted during the tyme appointed by this graunt for the payment of the said
five Subsidies.</para>
		<para id="p36">
			<emph type="i">Deans, Archdeacons, &amp;c. Prebendaries, &amp;c. of Cathedrals, Colleges, &amp;c. how chargeable. ; Archbishop, &amp;c. to certify Portions chargeable and not chargeable into Exchequer</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p37">Provided also that all Deanes Archdeacons Dignities Masters Wardens and Prebendaries of all Cathedrall and
Collegiate Churches or any of them within the said Province shalbe charged with theise five Subsidies for those
possessions revenues and &bhopubrc;mocions onelie which to their severall &bhopubrc;mocions dignities and roumes are clearelie and
distinctlie lymytted, and to their onelie use severed thereof to pay (the tenth part being deducted) for every and
each of the said five Subsidies foure shillings of every full pound in manner and forme as is above rehearsed, And
that all those rents possessions proffitts porcions hereditaments and Spirituall &bhopubr;mocions and every of them heretofore
by your Highnes or any of the Kings or Queenes of this Realme or any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons whatsoever given graunted
bequeathed devised or impropriated unto the said Cathedrall or Collegiate Churches or Colledges or to anie of them,
which any waies be assigned imployed or used either for or towards the yearelie maynten<emph type="p">a</emph>nce of Readers of Divinitie
Poore men Schoolemaisters Ushers Grammarians Petie Canons Conducts Vicars chorall Singingmen Choristers Virgers
Sextons or of other necessarie or dailie Officers or Ministers in such Cathedrall or Collegiate Churches or Colledges
or any of them or for or towards the reedifying or repayring of any of the same Cathedrall or Collegiate Churches or
Colledges shall not be charged with any part of these five Subsidies the certentie of which porcions as well chargeable
[to theise five Subsidies as not chargeable<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] in this behalfe the Archbishopp or Bishopp of the Dioces or (the See being
void) the Deane and Chapter or any other to whome the same shall or may appertaine uppon due search and examina&bhocotil;n
shall certifie under his or their Seale into your Highnes said Court of Exchequer at or before the severall daies
aforesaid appointed for the payment of the said five Subsidies.</para>
		<para id="p38">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for Spiritual Persons paying Pensions</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p39">Provided alwayes that every Parson Vicar or other Spirituall &bhopubr;son, paying any Pension, whereof no allowance is,
made in the valuation of his Promocion or Benefice shall and may retayne to his owne use and releife so much, of
every pound of every such Pension for every payment of theise five Subsidies as he standeth charged by this Graunt
to pay for every part and payment of the said five Subsidies out of every pound for the whole valuacion of his
Spirituall Promocion, any Coven<emph type="p">n</emph>nt Graunte or Bond to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		<para id="p40">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for Lands, &amp;c. formerly granted for Obits, &amp;c. and come into the Hands of King E. VI. &amp;c. and in Act 1 E. VI. c. 14</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p41">Provided also, and your said Prelates and Clergie doe most humblie beseech your Highnes that it may be enacted
by your Majesties authoritie and your High Court of Parliament, that where certaine Lands Tenements Rents
Sp[irit]uall Promocions Tithes Pencions Porcions Fruits and other Hereditaments latelie belonging to divers Cathedrall
Churches and to other places Eccliasticall within the said Province of Canterbury which were given and assigned to
be bestowed and spent in and on finding and maintayning of certaine Chauntries Anniversaries Obits Lights Lampes
and other like charges intents and purposes of late come into the hands and possession of the late King of famous
memory Edward the sixt by force of a Statute thereof made in the first yeare of his raigne as by the said Statute
more plainelie appeareth: that the Cathedrall Churches and the Bishopps Deanes or Presidents and Chapters and
Prebendaries of the same and all other places and &bhopubr;sons Eccl[ia]sticall and every of them to whome the said Lands
Rents and other the &bhopcrl;misses or anie of them did latelie appertaine shall not during the time appointed by this Graunt
for payment of the said five Subsidies be charged to and with any payment of Subsidie of and for that part and porcion
of Landes Tenements Rents Spirituall &bhopubr;mocions and other Hereditaments or any of them whereunto the said late
[King<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] by force of the said Statute was intituled or possessed of nor of any yearelie Rents or Payments going out of
the said Cathedrall Churches and other the places and &bhopubr;sons Eccl[ia]iasticall aforesaid: And that deduccion and allowance
thereof be made to them and every of them accordinglie in and uppon every payment of the said five Subsidies out
of the whole valuacion taxacion and estimacion made for the payment of the said &bhopubr;petuall Disme or Tenth remayning
of Record in your Highnes Court of Exchequer as aforesaid for the rate and porcion of Lands Tenements Rents
Spirituall &bhopubr;mocions and other Hereditaments and those yearelie payments whereunto the said late King was intituled
or possessed of or which since the making of the said Statute, by reason that they have byn found as Lands Tenements
Rents Tithes or other Hereditaments concealed from the said late King Edward the sixt the late King Henry the
eight the late Queene Mary the late Queene Elizabeth your late most Royall Father or any of them or from your
Majestie or otherwise are severed from the possessions of the said Cathedrall Churches, and other places and &bhopubr;sons
aforesaid or of any of them by force of the Statute &bhopcrl;mised or any otherwise.</para>
		<para id="p42">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for the Universities.; Colleges of Windsor, Westminster, Eaton, and Winchester; Hospitals, Free Schools, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p43">Provided also, that the said five Subsidies graunted by the Clergie or any part of them shall not be demaunded
or levyed out of any Benefice house of Students or Colledge scituate or set within either of the Univ[er]sities of Oxford
or Cambridge or any Benefice Lands or other Revenues unto the said Univ[er]sities or either of them or to any house
of Students or Colledge in anie of the said Univ[er]sities united appropriated or appertayning or out of any Benefice
Lands or Revenues of the Colledge of Windsor or of the Colledge of Westminster or of the Colledge of Eaton neere
Windsor or of the Colledge called S<emph type="p">t</emph> Maries Colledge by Winchester founded by William Wickham sometyme Bishopp
of Winchester or of anie Hospitalls Almes houses or Grammer Schooles or of any Church Benefice or other revenues
to the said Colledges Hospitalls Almes houses or Grammer Schooles or to any of them annexed appropriated. or
otherwise appertayning.</para>
		<para id="p44">
			<emph type="i">Proviso for Livings not above &pound;6. 13s. 4d. yearly</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p45">Provided allwaies that all Parsons Vicars and all other Eccl[ia]sticall &bhopubr;sons whose Benefices are not above six pounds
thirteene shillings and foure pence by the yeare after the taxacion aforesaid shall not be charged with the said five
Subsidies or any part of the same.</para>
		<para id="p46">
			<emph type="i">Livings of &pound;8. and not above &pound;10. yearely Value shall pay 6s. 8d. on each Subsidy; 
Vicarages under &pound;8. Incumbent not charged</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p47">Provided also that every Viccar whose Benefice is eight Pounds or above and not above ten pounds by the yeare
after the taxacion aforesaid shall pay unto your Highnes your Heires and Successors six shillings and eight pence at
every payment of the said five Subsidies at such tymes and to such &bhopubr;sons as is aforesaid for his part of the said
five Subsidies, And if any Viccaridge be under eight pounds by the taxacion aforesaid, the Incumbent shall not be
charged with any part or payment of the said five Subsidies, and for the sure and true payment of the said five
Subsidies graunted by your said Prelates and Clergie of the Province of Canterbury according to the tenour purport
effect and true meaning of this &bhopcrl;sent Graunt, your said Prelates and Clergie most humblie desire your Highnes, that
this their said Gift Graunt and five Subsidies and every matter s&bhooov;me of mony Peticion Clause Provisions Reservacions
and Sentences in this Instrument conteyned concerning the said five Subsidies may be ratified established and confirmed
by the authoritie of your Highnes Court of Parliament.</para>
		<para id="p48">In quo[rum] o[mn]i[u]m &amp; singulo[rum] &bhopcrl;misso[rum] fidem &amp; testimoni&umacr; Nos Georgius Archiep[iscop]us Cantuar antedcus has &bhopcrl;sentes lras
nras Testimoniales sive hoc &bhopcrl;sens publicum Instrumentum ad humilem rogatum Prelato[rum] &amp; Cleri &bhopcrl;dict Sigilli nri
appensione ac signo n[om]i[n]e &amp; subscrip&bhocotil;e Johis Drake Notarij publici deputati Nichi Weston Registrarij nri principalis
jussim &amp; fecim co&bhomov;uniri, Dat dco septimo die mensis Maij Anno D&ntilde;i mill[essi]mo sexcentesimo vicesimo octavo Regniq[ue]
vri felicissimi Angl[ia] Scocie Francie &amp; Hib[er]&ntilde; quarto &amp; nre t<emph type="p">a</emph>nsla&bhocotil;is [Anno<emph type="p">r</emph>] decimo octavo.</para>
		<para id="p49">
			<emph type="i">Grant ratified by Parliament</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p50">Wherefore for the true and sure payment of the said Subsidies graunted by the said Prelates and Clergie of the
said Province of Canterbury according to the tenor effect and true meaning of the said Instrument. Be it enacted
by the Kings most Excellent Majestie with the assent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the C&bhooov;mons in this
&bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled and by the authoritie of the same that the said Guift and Graunte and every matter
s&bhooov;me of mony peticion provision clause and sentence in the same Instrument contayned shall stand and be ratified
established and confirmed by the authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Power to Collectors to levy Subsidies by Censures of the Church, and by Sequestration, Distress, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p51">
				<emph type="i">Farmers, &amp;c. may retain Monies paid for their Lessors. ; Sale of Distress.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p52">And further be it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid that every &bhopubr;son that shalbe appointed to the collecting and
gathering of the said Subsidies shall have power and authoritie to levie take and &bhopubr;ceive the said Subsidies by the
Authoritie of the censures of the Church That is to saie by Suspension Exc&bhooov;municacion or Interdiccion and also by
Sequestracion of the fruits and proffitts of their Benefices and &bhopcrl;mocions Spirituall in whose hands soever they be
and to make sale of the same fruits without daunger of the Lawes of this Realme or by distresse upon the possessions
of the Farmors or occupiers of the Lands and Tenements chargeable by the said Instrument for or to the payment
of any s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of mony to be due by force thereof or otherwise by the discrecion of the Collector thereof, And
that no Replevie Prohibicion or Su&bhopubr;sedeas shalbe allowed or obeyed for any &bhopubr;sons making default of the payment of
the said Subsidies or any of them contrary to the tenor of the Graunt thereof untill such time as they have trulie
satisfied and contented all such part and porcions as to them in that behalfe appertayneth And that every such Farmor
and Farmors their Executors and Assignes that shall fortune hereafter to be charged to or with the payment of the
said Subsidies or any part thereof shall by the Authoritie aforesaid be allowed and retaine in his hands as much of
his yearelie Rent and Farme as the S&bhouov;me which he shall fortune to pay for his Lord or Leasour shall extend unto
(except that the said Farmor or Farmors their Executors or Assignes by the Lease and Graunt that they have of any
part of the Lands Tithes Proffitts or Tenements chargeable to the said Subsidies or by force of any Covenant or
Article therein contayned be bound and charged to pay the same, and thereof to discharge the Leasour and Landlord
during the terme mencioned in the said Lease.)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Subsidies may be levied by Distress on Farmers of Impropriations.</head>
			<para id="p53">And likewise be it enacted by the authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, That whereas divers Curates liable to the
Subsidies being oftentimes removeable doe serve aswell in divers Impropriacions belonging to the Kings Majestie as in
other Spirituall promocions belonging to other &bhopubr;sons that for the speedie recovery of the said Subsidies it may be
lawfull to the said Collector or Collectors of the said Subsidies their Deputie or Deputies to levie the said Subsidies
uppon the Farmor or Farmors or occupiers of all such Impropriacions or Spirituall promocions by all censures of
the Church aforesaid and every of them or by way of distresse of Tithes of the said Impropriacion or Impropria&bhocotil;ns
and Spirituall promocions or otherwise uppon the Goods and Chattells of the said Farmor or Farmors and Occupiers:
in which case no inhibicion prohibicion Replevie or other &bhopubrc;cesse awarded to the contrary shalbe obeyed Any Lawes
Statuts Priviledges or Customes to the contrary hereof heretofore made graunted or used or hereafter to be made
graunted or used to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding, And that it may be lawfull to the Collector or other
Officers and Ministers of such Archbishopp Bishopp Deane and Chapter for not payment of the said Subsidies after
the same shalbe due in or at any [of the said<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] tymes of payment to prise and value the said Distresse and Distresses by
two indifferent neighbours by him to be chosen and the Distresse and Distresses so prised to sell and thereof to
detaine so much mony as shall amount to the s&bhooov;me payable to the Kings most excellent Majestie with the reasonable
charges also of the said Collectors susteined in that behalfe, and the rest of the mony made of the said Distresse to be
delivered and paid to the Owner and Occupier thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. How Lay Impropriators shall be charged for their Spiritual and Temporal Possessions.</head>
			<para id="p54">Provided allwaies and be it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid that every Lay &bhopubr;son having Spirituall promocion
chargeable by this Acte and also having Temporall possessions Goods Chattells and Debts charged to the said
Subsidies graunted in this Parliament by the Temporaltie shalbe taxed charged and sett for his said Spirituall
promocions with the Clergie and his Temporall possessions and Chattells reall with the Temporaltie and not otherwise,
any thing before mencioned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. This Act extended to the Subsidy of the Province of York.</head>
			<para id="p55">And be it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid that all and every graunt and graunts of all and every s&bhooov;me
and s&bhooov;mes of mony graunted or which hereafter shalbe graunted to the Kings Majestie by the Clergie of the Province
of Yorke shalbe of the same strength force and effect in all things as the said graunt made by the said Province of
Canterbury and shalbe taxed certified collected levyed gathered and paid according to the tenor forme and effect
of this &bhopcrl;sent Act of Parliament to all intents construccions and purposes in such manner and forme as though it
were sp[ec]iallie plainelie and particularlie expressed and rehearsed in this &bhopcrl;sent Act by expresse words termes and
sentences in their severall natures and kindes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Provisions in the Grants of the Clergy declared valid.</head>
			<para id="p56">Provided allwaies and be it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid that all &bhopcrl;visions before rehearsed contayned or
to be contayned in the said Graunt of the Prelates and Clergie of the Province of Canterbury and the like of
the same Provisoes [contayned<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] in the said Graunt of the Prelats and Clergie of the Province of Yorke shalbe
good and effectuall and to be observed and kept in every point and article according to the purport and true
meaning of the same.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This Act is mentioned in the Calendar at the Parliament Office to be "in the great square Trunck," but cannot now be found.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


