<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47212" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the preventing of inconveniencies happening by the long intermission.of Parliaments.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">Whereas by the Lawes and Statutes of this Realme the Parliament ought to bee holden att least once every
yeare for the redresse of greivances but the appointment of the time and place for the holding thereof hath
alwaies belonged as it ought to his Majestie and his Royall Progenitors. And whereas it is by experience found that
the not holding of Parliaments accordingly hath produced sundry and great mischeifs and inconveniences to the
Kings Majestie the Church and Common Wealth For the &bhopcrl;vention of the like mischeifs and inconveniences in
time to Comme.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">If no Parliament summoned before the 16th Sept. in the 3d Year after the last Day of the last Sitting,; then the Parliament to assemble at Westminster in the Manner, and by the Means, and at the Time hereafter mentioned.; 
Lord Chancellor and Commissioners to take an Oath to issue Writs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie with the consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
the C&bhooov;mons in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled that the said Lawes and Statutes bee from henceforth duly kept
and observed and your Majesties loyall and obedient subje&bholigct;s in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament now assembled doe humbly
pray that it bee ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed accordingly by the authority of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament That in case there
be not a Parliament summoned by Writt under the Great Seale of England and assembled and held [<ref idref="n1">1</ref>before the tenth
day of September which shall bee in the third yeare next after the last day of the last meeting and sitting in this
&bhopcrl;sent Parliament the begining of the first yeare to be accompted from the said last day of the last meeting and
sitting in Parliament and soe from time to time and in all times hereafter if there shall not bee a Parliament assembled
and held before the tenth day of September which shall be in the third yeare next after the last day of the last
meeting and sitting in Parliament before that time assembled and held the begining of the first yca&racute;e to bee accounted
from the said last day of the last meeting and sitting in Parliament That then in every such case as aforesaid the
Parliament shall assemble and bee held in the usuall place att Westminster in such manner and. by such meanes
onely as is hereafter in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; declared and ena&bholigct;ed and not otherwise on the second monday which shall
bee in the moneth of November then next ensueing And in case this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament now assembled and held
or any other Parliament which shall att any time hereafter bee assembled and held by Writ under the Great Seale
of England or in case any Parliament shall bee assembled and held by authority of this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; and such Parliam<emph type="p">ts</emph>
or any of them shall be prorogued or adjourned or continued by prorogation or adjournment untill the tenth day of
September which shall be in the third yeare next after the last day of the last meeting and sitting in Parliament to bee
accommpted as aforesaid that then in every such case every such Parliament so prorogued or adjourned or soe continued
by prorogation or adjournment as aforesaid shall from the said tenth day of September be thenceforth cleerely and
absolutely dissolved and the Lord Chancellor of England the Lord Keeper of the Great Seale of England and every
Commmissioner and Commmissioners for the keeping of the Great Seale of England for the time being shall within
six dayes after the said tenth day of September in every such third yeare as aforesaid in due forme of Law and without
any further Warrant or direc&bhocotil;n from His Majestie his Heires or Successors Seale issue forth and send abroad severall
and respe&bholigct;ive Writs to the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Peeres of this Realme Commmanding every such Peer that hee
personally bee att the Parliament to be held att Westminster on the second monday which shall be in November next
following the said tenth day of September then and there to treate concerning the high and urgent Affairs concerning
his Majestie the state and defence of the Kingdome and church of England and shall alsoe seale issue forth and send
abroad severall and respe&bholigct;ive Writs to the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Sheriffs of the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Counties
Cities and Boroughs of England and Wales and to the Constable of the Castle of Dover Lord Warden of the Cinque
Ports or his Lieutennant for the time being and to the Maior and Bailiffs of Barwick upon Tweed and to all and every
other Officers and Persons to whom Writs have used to be dire&bholigct;ed for the ele&bholigct;ing of the Knights Citizens Barons
and Burgesses of and for the said Counties Cities Cinque Ports and Boroughs of England and Wales respe&bholigct;ively in
the accustomed forme to appeare and serve in Parliament to be held at Westminster on the said second Monday which
shall be in November aforesaid which said Peers after the said Writs received and which said Knights Citizens Barons
and Burgesses chosen by vertue of the said Writs shall then and there appeare and serve in Parliament accordingly
And the said Lord Chancellour Lord Keeper Commissioner and Commissioners aforesaid shall respe&bholigct;ively take a
solemn Oath upon the Holy Evangelist for the due issuing of Writs according to the tenour of this A&bholigct; viz. in hec verba.</para>
			<para id="p4">You shall sweare that you shall truly and faithfully issue forth and send abroad all Writs of Summons to Parliament
for both Houses att such time and in such manner as is expressed and enjoyned by an A&bholigct; of Parliament intituled An
A&bholigct; for the &bhopcrl;venting of Inconveniencies happening by the long intermission of Parliaments.</para>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Failing to issue Writs; Perjury and Disability of Office and other Punishments. If Writs not issued, and Parliament do not meet, Peers enabled to meet in the old Palace of Westminster; and by virtue of this A&bholigct; to issue Writs. Clerks of the Petty Bag,&amp;c. to prepare such Writs for Signature of the Lords.
Omitting so to do, Punishment. Messengers,&amp;c. to deliver Writs. Omitting so to do, Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">Which Oath is forthwith to be taken by the &bhopcrl;sent Lord Keeper and to be administred by the Clerke of the Crowne to
every Lord Chancellour Lord Keeper Commissioner and Commissioners aforesaid and that none of the said Officers
respe&bholigct;ively shall henceforth execute any the said Offices before they have taken the said Oath And if the said Lord
Chancellour Lord Keeper or any the said Commissioners shall fail or forbeare soe to issue out the said Writs according to
the true meaning of this A&bholigct; then he or they respe&bholigct;ively shall beside the incurring of the grievous Sin of perjury be
disabled and become by vertue of this A&bholigct; incapable ipso fa&bholigct;o to beare his and theire said Offices respe&bholigct;ively and bee
further lyable to such punishments as shall be infli&bholigct;ed on him or them by the next or any other ensuing Parliament And
in case the said Lord Chancellour Lord Keeper Commissioner or Commissioners aforesaid shall not issue forth the said
Writs as aforesaid or in case that the Parliament doe not assemble and bee held att the time and place before appointed
Then the Parliament shall assemble and bee held in the usuall place att Westminster in such manner and by such meanes
onely as is hereafter in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; declared and ena&bholigct;ed and not otherwise on the third monday which shall bee in
the moneth of January then next ensuing And the Peers of this Realm shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; bee enabled and are
enjoyned to meet in the Old Palace of Westminster in the usuall place there on the third monday in the said moneth
of November and they or any twelve or more of them then and there assembled shall on or before the last monday
of November next following the tenth day of September aforesaid by vertue of this A&bholigct; without other Warrant issue
out Writts in the usuall forme in the name of the Kings Majestie his Heires or Successors attested under the Hands
and Seales of twelve or more of the said Peers to the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Sheriffes of the severall and respe&bholigct;ive
Counties Cities and Boroughs of England and Wales and to the Constable of the Castle of Dover Lord Warden of
the Cinque Ports or his Lieutennant for the time being and to the Maior and Bayliffs of Berwicke upon Tweed and to
all and every other the said Officers and Persons to whom Writs have beene used to bee dire&bholigct;ed for the ele&bholigct;ing of
the Knights Citizens Barons and Burgesses of and for the said Counties Cities Cinque Ports and Boroughs to bee and
appeare att the Parliament att Westminster aforesaid to be held on the third monday in January then next following
All and every which Writts the Clerks of the Pettibag and other Clerks to whom the writing of the Writs for
Summons to the Parliament doth and shall belong or whom the said Lords or twelve or more of them shall appoint
shall att the command of the said Lords soe assembled or of any twelve or more of them make and prepare ready
for the signature of the said Lords or any twelve or more of them under paine of the losse of theire places and offices
and of such other punishment as in the next or any other ensuing Parliament shall be infli&bholigct;ed on him or them And
it is ena&bholigct;ed that the said Writs soe issued shall be of the same power and force to all intents and purposes as the
Writs or Summons to Parliament under the Great Seale of England have ever beene or ought to bee And all the
Messengers of the Chamber or others whoe shall be appointed by the said Lords or any twelve or more of them are
hereby required faithfully and speedyly to deliver the said Writs to every person and persons Sheriffe Officers and
others to whom the same shall be dire&bholigct;ed which if the said Messengers or any of them shall faile to performe they
shall forfeit theire respe&bholigct;ive places and incurre such other pains and punishments as by that or any other ensuing
Parliament shall be imposed on them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Peers to assemble the 3d Monday in January.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">And in case Parliament not assembled before 23d January, then to be assembled by such Means only as hereafter mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And it is alsoe further ena&bholigct;ed that all and every the Peers of this Realme shall make theire appearance and shall
assemble on the said third monday in January in such manner and to such effe&bholigct; and with such power as if they had
received every of them Writs of Summons to Parliament under the Great Seale of England in the usuall and
accustomed manner And in case the said Lords or twelve or more of them shall faile to issue forth such Writs
or that the said Writs doe not come to the said severall Counties Cities Cinque Ports and Boroughs soe that an
ele&bholigct;ion bee not thereupon made And in case there be not a Parliament assembled and held] before the three and
twentieth day of the said moneth of January and soe from time to time and in all times hereafter if there shall not
be a Parliament assembled and held before the said three and twentieth day of January then in every such case as
aforesaid the Parliament shall assemble and be held in the usuall Place att Westminster in such manner and by such
meanes onely as is hereafter in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; declared and ena&bholigct;ed and not otherwise on the second Tuesday which
shall bee in the moneth of March next after the said three and twentieth day of January Att which Parliament the
Peers of this Realme shall make theire appearance and shall assemble att the time and place aforesaid and shall each
of them be liable unto such paines and censures for his and theire not appearing and serving then and there in
Parliament as if hee or they had beene summoned by Writ under the Great Seale of England and had not appeared
and served and to such further paines and censures as by the rest of the Peers in Parliament assembled they shall be
adjudged unto.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Sheriffs and all other Officers to cause Knights, &amp;c. to be chosen as if Writs had issued;</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">and if Sheriffs, &amp;c. do not proceed; then the Freeholders, &amp;c. and others having Voice in Ele&bholigct;ion, to proceed to Ele&bholigct;ion without further Warrant</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And for the better assembling of the Knights Citizens Barons and Burges to the said Parliament as aforesaid It is further
ena&bholigct;ed that the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Sheriffs of theire severall and respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cities and Boroughs of England
and Wales and the Chancellor Masters and Schollers of both and every of the Universities and the Maior and Bailiffs of
the Borough of Barwick upon Tweed shall att the severall Courts and Places to be held and appointed for theire
respe&bholigct;ive Counties Universities Cities and Boroughs next after the said three and twentieth day of January cause such
Knight and Knights Citizen and Citizens Burgesse and Burgesses of theire said Counties Universities Cities and Buroughs
respe&bholigct;ively to be chosen by such persons and in such manner as if severall and respe&bholigct;ive Writs of Summons to
Parliament under the Great Seale of England had issued and been awarded And in case any of the severall Sheriffs
or the Chancellour Masters and Schollers of either of the Universities or the Maior and Bailiffs of Barwick respe&bholigct;ively
doe not before ten of the clocke in the forenoone of the same day wherein the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Courts and
Places shall bee held or appointed for theire severall and respe&bholigct;ive Counties Universities Cities and Boroughs as
aforesaid begin and proceed on according to the meaning of this Law in causing Ele&bholigct;ions to be made of such
Knight and Knights Citizen and Citizens Burgesse and Burgesses of theire said Counties Universities Cities and
Boroughs as aforesaid then the Free holders of each County and the Masters and Schollers of every of the Universities
and the Citizens and others having voices in such Ele&bholigct;ion respe&bholigct;ively in each University City and Borough that shall
be assembled att the said Courts or Places to be held or appointed as aforesaid shall forthwith without further Warrant
or dire&bholigct;ion proceed to the Ele&bholigct;ion of such Knight or Knights Citizen or Citizens Burgesse or Burgesses aforesaid
in such manner as is usuall in case of Writs of Summons issued and awarded.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Sheriffs, Constables of Dover Castle, and Lord Warden of Cinque Ports, to send forth Precepts for Ele&bholigct;ion</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">as if Writs had issued. If Default, then Ele&bholigct;ors to proceed. Knights, &amp;c. ele&bholigct;ed to appear and serve in Parliament. Sheriffs, &amp;c. to make Returns as if Writs had issued; and if Default, then Ele&bholigct;ors to make Returns, which shall be good. Persons advising any Proceedings contrary to this A&bholigct;. Premunire, and Disability to sue, &amp;c. Sheriff or other Officer not obeying this A&bholigct;, Penalties. How recovered; 
Procuring A&bholigct;ion or Execution under this A&bholigct; to be stayed, &amp;c. Premunire. Such A&bholigct;ion not to abate by Death of Plaintiff. Forfeitures how to go and be disposed of. Proviso as to Ele&bholigct;ions afterwards adjudged void</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed that the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Sheriffs of theire severall and respe&bholigct;ive Counties and the
Constables of the Castle of Dover and Lord Warden of the Cinque Ports or his Leiutenant for the time being
respe&bholigct;ively shall after the said three and twentieth day of January and before the eighth day of February then
immediately next ensuing award and send forth theire Precepts to the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Cities and Boroughs within
theire severall Counties and likewise unto the said Cinque Ports respe&bholigct;ively comanding them respe&bholigct;ively to make
choice of such Citizen and Citizens Barons [Burge<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and Burgesses to serve in the said Parliament att the time and place
aforesaid Which said Cities Cinque Ports and Boroughs respe&bholigct;ively shall before the last day of the said Moneth of
February make ele&bholigct;ion of such Citizen and Citizens Barons Burgesse and Burgesses as if Writs for summoning of
a Parliament under the Great Seale of England had issued and beene awarded And in case no such &bhopcrl;cept shall come
unto the said Cities Cinque Ports and Boroughs respe&bholigct;ively by the time herein limited or in case any precept shall
come and no ele&bholigct;ion be made thereupon before the said last day of February That then the severall Citizens Burgesses
and other Persons that ought to ele&bholigct; and send Citizens Barons and Burgesses to the Parliament shall on the first
Tuesday in March then next ensueing the said last day of February make choice of such Citizen and Citizens Barons
[Burge<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and Burgesses as if a Writ of Summons under the Great Seale of England had issued and beene awarded
and precepts thereupon issued to such Cities Cinque Ports and Boroughs which Knights Citizens Barons and Burgesses
so chosen shall appeare and serve in Parliament att the time and place aforesaid and shall each of them be liable unto
such paines and censures for his and theire not appearing and serving then and theire in Parliament as if hee or they
had beene ele&bholigct;ed and chosen by vertue of a Writ under the Great Seale of England and shall be likewise subje&bholigct;
unto such further paines and censures as by the rest of the Knights Citizens and Burgesses assembled in the Commons
House of Parliament hee or they shall be adjudged unto And the Sheriffs and other Officers and persons to whom
it appertaineth shall make returnes and accept and receive the returnes of such Ele&bholigct;ions in like manner as if Writs
of Summons had issued and beene executed as hath beene used and accustomed and in default of the Sheriffs and
other Officers respe&bholigct;ively in not accepting or makeing returne of such Ele&bholigct;ions it shall and may be lawfull to and
for the severall Freeholders and other persons that have ele&bholigct;ed to make returns of the Knights Citizens Barons and
Burgesses by them ele&bholigct;ed which shall bee as good and effe&bholigct;uall to all intents and Purposes as if the Sheriffe or
other Officers had received a Writ of Summons for a Parliament and had made such returnes And that such Ele&bholigct;ions
Precepts and returnes shall bee had and made att such times by such persons and in such manner as before in this
A&bholigct; is expressed and declared according to the true intent and meaning of this Law Any Writ Proclamation Edi&bholigct; A&bholigct;
Restraint Inhibition Order or Warrant to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding And in case any person or persons
shall be soe hardy to advise frame contrive serve or put in execution any such Writs Proclama&bhocotil;n Edi&bholigct; A&bholigct; Restraint
Inhibition Order or Warrant thereupon then hee or they soe offending shall incur and sustain the paines penalties and
forfeitures limited ordained and provided in and by the Statute of Provision and Premunire made in the sixteenth
yeare of King Richard the Second and shall from thenceforth bee disabled during his life to sue or implead any person
in any a&bholigct;ion reall or personall or to make any Gift Grant Conveyance or other disposition of any his Lands
Tenements Hereditaments Goods or Chattels which hee hath to his owne use either by A&bholigct; executed in his life time
or by his last Will or otherwise or to take any Gift Conveyance or Legacie to his owne use or to take any benefit
of any Gift Conveyance or Legacie to his owne use And if any Sheriffe Constable of the Castle of Dover or Lord
Warden of the Cinque Ports shall not performe his duty enjoyned by this A&bholigct; then hee shall lose and forfeit the
sum of one thousand pounds and every County City Cinque Port and Borough that shall not make Ele&bholigct;ion of theire
Knights Citizens Barons and Burgesses respe&bholigct;ively shall incur the Penalties following (that is to say) every County the
s&bhouov;me of one thousand Pounds and every City which is noe County twoe hundred pounds and every Cinque Port and
Borough the s&bhouov;m of one hundred pounds All and every of which severall forfeitures and all other forfeitures in this
A&bholigct; mentioned shall and may bee recovered in any of the Kings Courts of Record att Westminster by and in the name
of the Lord Maior of the City of London for the time being without nameing the christian name or sirname of the
said Lord Maior for the time being by a&bholigct;ion of debt bill plaint or information wherein no essoin prote&bholigct;ion wager of
Law aid prayer priviledge injun&bholigct;ion or order of restraint shall bee in any wise prayed granted or allowed nor any
more then one imparlance And if any person after notice given that the A&bholigct;ion depending is grounded or prosecuted
upon or by vertue of this Statute shall cause or procure any such A&bholigct;ion to bee stayed or delayed before Judgement
by colour or meanes of any Order Warrant Power or Authority save onely of the Court wherein such A&bholigct;ion as
aforesaid shall be brought or depending or after Judgment had upon such A&bholigct;ion shall cause or procure the execution of
or upon any such Judgment to bee stayed or delayed by colour or meanes of any order warrant power or authority
save onely by Writ of Errour or Attaint that then the said persons soe offending shall incurre and sustain all and
every the paines penalties and forfeitures limited ordained and provided in and by the said Statute of Provision and
Premunire made in the sixteenth yeare of King Richard the Second And if any Lord Maior of London shall att any
time hereafter commence or preferre any such Suite A&bholigct;ion or Information and shall happen to die or be removed out
of his office before recovery and execution had that yet no such A&bholigct;ion Suit or Information sued commenced or
preferred shall by such displacing or death be abated discontinued or ended but that it shall and may be lawfull to
and for the Lord Maior of the City of London next succeeding in that office and place to prosecute pursue and follow
all and every such A&bholigct;ion Bill Plaint or Information for the causes aforesaid soe hanging and depending in such
manner and forme and to all intents and purposes as that Lord Maior might have done which first commenced or
preferred the same the fifth part of all and every the forfeitures in this A&bholigct; mentioned shall goe and be to and for
the use and behoofe of the City of London and the other four parts and residue to be employed and disposed to
and for such onely uses intents and purposes as by the Knights Citizens and Burgesses in Parliament assembled shall
be declared dire&bholigct;ed and appointed Provided that in case the Freeholders of any County and Inhabitants or other persons
having or claiming power to make ele&bholigct;ion of any Knights Citizens Barons or Burgesses shall proceed to making of
ele&bholigct;ion of theire Knights Citizens Barons and Burgesses which election shall afterwards fall out to bee afterwards
adjudged or declared void in Law by the House of Commons by reason of equality of voices or misdemeanour of any
person whatsoever then the said County City Cinque Port or Borough shall not incurre the penalties in this Law soe as
an ele&bholigct;ion de fa&bholigct;o be made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. As to the time of dissolving or proroguing Parliament after its First Meeting.</head>
			<para id="p13">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed that noe Parliament henceforth to bee assembled shall be dissolved or prorogued within
fiftie dayes att the least after the time appointed for the meeting thereof unlesse it be by assent of his Majesty his
heires or successours and of both Houses in Parliament assembled And that neither the House of Peers nor the House
of Commons shall be adjourned within fifty dayes att least after the meeting thereof unlesse it bee by the free consent
of every the said houses respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Peers and Commons to be assembled by virtue of this A&bholigct; may respectively choose their Speaker.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Such Speakers to enjoy all the accustomed Powers and Privileges</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by authority of this present Parliament that the Peers to be assembled att
any Parliament by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall and may from time to time att any time during such theire assembly in
Parliament choose and declare such person to bee Speaker for the said Peers as they shall thinke fitt And likewise
that the said Knights Citizens and Burgesses to bee assembled att any Parliament by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall and
may from time to time at any time during such theire assembly in Parliament choose and declare one of themselves
to bee Speaker for the said Knights Citizens and Burgesses of the House of C&bhooov;mons assembled in the said Parliament
as they shall thinke fitt which said Speakers and every of them aswell for the said Peers as for the said House of
Commons respe&bholigct;ively shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; be perfe&bholigct; and compleat Speakers for the said Houses respe&bholigct;ively
and shall have as full and large power jurisdi&bholigct;ion and priviledges to all intents and purposes as any Speaker or
Speakers of either of the said houses respe&bholigct;ively [herefore<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] have had or enjoyed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Parliaments assembled by Authority of this A&bholigct; to enjoy all the accustomed Privileges of Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p16">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that all Parliament hereafter to bee assembled by authority of this A&bholigct; and
every member thereof shall have and enjoy all rights priviledges jurisdi&bholigct;ions and immunities as any Parliament
summoned by Writ under the Great Seale of England or any member thereof might or ought to have and all and
every the Members that shall be ele&bholigct;ed and chosen to serve in any Parliament hereafter to be assembled by authority
of this A&bholigct; as aforesaid shall assemble and meet in the C&bhooov;mons House of Parliament and shall enter into the same
and have voices in such Parliament before and without the takeing the severall Oathes of Supremacy and Allegiance
or either of them any Lawe or Statute to the contrary thereof in anywise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Member of any Parliament to be hereafter assembled by Authority of this A&bholigct; to take the Oath of Allegiance if required by the King, or excluded.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided alwaies that if the Kings Majesty his heires or successors shall att any time during any Parliament
hereafter to be assembled by authority of this A&bholigct; as aforesaid award or dire&bholigct; any C&bhooov;mission or C&bhooov;missions unto any
person or persons whatsoever thereby giving power and authority to him or them to take and receive the Oath of
Supremacy and Allegiance of all or any the Members of the C&bhooov;mons house of Parliament and any the Members of
that House being duly required thereunto shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to take and pronounce the same that from
thenceforth such person soe refuseing or neglecting shall bee deemed no member of that house nor shall have any
voice therein and shall suffer such paines and penalties as if he had presumed to sit in the same house without
ele&bholigct;ion return or authority.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. This A&bholigct; to be publicly read at Sessions of the Peace and Assises. Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p18">And it is likewise provided and ena&bholigct;ed that this Statute shall be publikely read yearely att every Generall
Sessions of the Peace to be held next after the Epiphany and every Assizes then next ensuing by the Clerke of the
Peace and Clerke of the Assises for the time being respe&bholigct;ively and if they or either of them shall negle&bholigct; or fail
to doe the same accordingly then such party soe negle&bholigct;ing or failing shall forfeit the sum of One hundred Pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. The Royal Assent to this A&bholigct; not to determine the Sessions. Continuance of A&bholigct;s.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Continuance of A&bholigct;s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">And it is lastly provided and ena&bholigct;ed that His Majesties Royall Assent to this Bill shall not thereby determine this
present Session of Parliament and that all Statutes and A&bholigct;s of Parliament which are to have continuance unto the end
of this present Session shall bee of full force after His Majesties Assent untill this &bhopcrl;sent Session be fully ended and
determined And if this present Session shall determine by dissolution of this present Parliament then all the A&bholigct;s and
Statutes aforesaid shall be continued untill the end of the first Session of the next Parliament.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1"> annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2"> Burges <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3"> heretofore <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

