<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47215" pubid="351" publish="true">
<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
<subtitle>Chapter IV. An Act for the further releife of His Majesties Army and the Northern Parts of the Kingdome.[Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 1. nu. 4].</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head/>
<para id="p1">
<emph type="i">Distresses of the Army and People in the Northern Parts recited.; Grant of Four Subsidies by cap. 2. ante, recited.; Grant of Two entire Subsidies on personal Estate (after Payment of Debts, &amp;c.) 2s. 8d. in the Pound.; Aliens and Popish Recusants Convi&bholigct; 5s. 4d. in the Pound.; Poll Tax on Aliens and Popish Recusants Convict, not contributory as above, 8d.; Master, &amp;c. of such Alien, &amp;c. answerable</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">Most gracious Sovereign your Majesties most humble and loyall Subje&bholigct;s the Commons in your High Court of Parliament now assembled haveing duely considered the great wants and distresses that your Army and people in the Northern Parts of this your Kingdome do sustain and the eminent danger that your Kingdome is in Albeit Subsidies or the Supply or support of publike Affaires (by what name or names soever the same be called) are not used to be granted att the begining of Parliaments but after such time as the Grievances of the People have beene heard and redressed which cann never soe cleerely appeare to Soveraigne Majestie as in Parliaments where People have theire immediate accesse unto theire Soveraigne And albeit that in this present Parliament it is formerly ena&bholigct;ed that four entire Subsidies should be rated taxed levied and paid for such purposes and att and in such manner as in the said A&bholigct; intituled An A&bholigct; for the releife of His Majesties Army and the Northerne Parts of the Kingdome is expressed yet for the avoiding the eminent danger that your Kingdome is in for the present releife of your Army and of those distressed Countreys the safety of your Majesty and Children (soe that it be not drawn into President for future times) they humbly beseech your Majestie that it may be ena&bholigct;ed and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by authoritie of the same that twoe entire Subsidies shall be rated taxed leavied and paid at one entire payment at the time hereafter in this A&bholigct; expressed of every Person Spirituall and Temporall of what estate or degree he or they be of according to the tenor of England Wales or other the Kings [Dominions <ref idref="n1">1</ref>] as all and every Fraternity Guild Corporation Mysterie Brotherhood
and Communalty Corporate and not Corporate within the Realme of England Wales and other the Kings
Dominions being worth three pounds as well in Coine and the value of every pound that every such Person Fraternity Guild Corporation Mysterie Brotherhood &amp; Communalty Corporate or not Corporate hath of his or theire owne or any other hath to his or theire use as alsoe in Plate Stock of Merchandize all manner of Corne and Graine Houshouldstuffe and of all other goods moveable as well within this Realme as without and of all such S&bhouov;ms of Money as to him or them is or shall be owing whereof he or they trust in his or theire conscience surely to be paid (except and out of the premisses dedu&bholigct;ed) such Sums of Money as he or they doe owe and in his or theire consciences intend truly to pay and except alsoe the Apparell of every such persons theire wives and children belonging to theire owne bodies (saving Jewels Gold Silver Stone and Pearle) shall pay to and for either of the said Subsidies two Shillings eight pence of every pound and alsoe every Alien and Stranger borne out of the Kings obeysance aswell Denizens as others inhabiting within this Realme and alsoe every Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) or which are or shall be indi&bholigct;ed for Popish Recusancy and theire Indictments either are or shall be removed by Certiorari or being not removed shall not by appearance and traverse legally be discharged before the said Assessment soe to be made or shall not have received the Holy Communion according to the Rites of the Church of England within one whole yeare next before the said Assessment shall be made of every pound that he or they or any other to his or theire use in trust or otherwise shall have in Coine and the value of every pound in Plate Corne Graine Merchandize Housholdstuffe or other Goods Jewels Chattels moveable and immoveable as is aforesaid as well within this Realme as without and of all Sums of Money to him or them owing whereof he or they trust in his or theire conscience to be paid (except and out of the premisses dedu&bholigct;ed every such S&bhouov;me and S&bhouov;ms of Money which he or they doe owe and in his or theire conscience or consciences intend truly to pay) shall pay to and for either of the said twoe Subsidies five Shillings and foure pence of every pound And alsoe that every Alien and Stranger borne out of the Kings Dominions being denizen or not denizen (not being contributary to the rates aforesaid) and being of the age of seaven Yeares or above and every Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; or which before the time of the Assesment of the said two Subsidies by this present A&bholigct; granted shall be a Popish Recusant convi&bholigct;being of the age of seaventeene Yeares or which being of the age of one and twenty yeares hath not received the Holy Communion within one yeare then last past as aforesaid shall pay to and for either of the said twoe Subsidies eight pence for every poll and the Master or he or shee with whom the said Alien or such Papist is or shall be abiding at the time of the taxation or taxations thereof to be charged with the same for lack of payment thereof.</para></section>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. Two Subsidies on Real and Copyhold Estates, 4s. in the Pound.</head>
<para id="p3">
<emph type="i">Aliens and Popish Recusants convi&bholigct; 8s. in the Pound.; All Sums to be presented to be truly rated.; Plate, &amp;c. held for Corporations to be rated.; Lands, Corrodies, Fees, &amp;c.; Proviso for Ornaments, &amp;c. of Churches and Chapels.; Subsidies to be rated in Shires, Towns, &amp;c. before 20th Oct. 1641.; Sums and Names of Persons liable certified to the Exchequer.; Subsidies paid into the Chamber of London;; and Acquittances given to the Colle&bholigct;ors under Hand and Seal.; Producing Acquittances, Warrant for Colle&bholigct;ors to pass Accounts.; Payments in Liberties, &amp; c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p4">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that every person born under the Kings obeysance and every Corporation Fraternity Guild Mystery Brotherhood and Communalty Corporate or not Corporate for every pound that every the same persons and every Corporation Fraternity Guild Mystery Brotherhood &amp; Communalty Corporate or not Corporate or any other to his or theire Use in trust or otherwise hath in Fee Simple Fee Taile for terme of Life terme of yeares by execution Wardship or by Copy of Court Roll of and in any Honours Castles Mannors Lands Tenements Rents Services Hereditaments Annuities Fees Corrodies or other yeerely Proffits of the yearely value of twenty Shillings as well within ancient demeasne and other places priviledged as elsewhere and so upwards shall pay to and for either the said twoe Subsidies four shillings of and for every pound And every Alien Denizen or not Denizen borne out of the Kings obeysance and every Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; of what Estate or degree soever they be of or which before the time of the Assesment of the said two Subsidies by this present A&bholigct; granted shall be a Popish Recusant convi&bholigct;or which shall be indi&bholigct;ed for Popish Recusancie and theire Indi&bholigct;ments are or shall be removed by Certiorari or being not removed shall not by appearance and traverse legally be discharged before the said Assessment soe to be made or being of the Age of twenty and one yeares shall not have received the Holy Communion according to the Rites of the Church of England within one whole yeare next before the [said<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Assessment shall be made in such case to pay to and for either of the said twoe Subsidies eight shillings for every pound. And that all Sums to be presented and chargeable by this A&bholigct; either for Goods and debts or either of them or for Lands Tenements and other the premisses as is in this A&bholigct; contained shall be att the said [payments<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] set and taxed after the rate and proportion according to the [true<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] meaning of this A&bholigct; Lands and Tenements chargeable to the dismes of the Clergy and yearely Wages due to Servants for theire yearely Service (other then the Kings Servants taking yearely Wages of five pounds or above onely excepted and foreprized) And that all Plate Coine Jewels Goods Debts and Chattels Personals and all Lands Tenements and other the &bhopcrl;misses as aforesaid being in the rule and custody of any person or persons to the use of any Corporation Fraternity Guild Mistery Brotherhood or any Communalty being Corporate or not Corporate be and shall be rated set and charged by reason of this A&bholigct; at the value certified by the presenters in theire Certificate for every pound in goods and debts as is aforesaid and for every pound in Lands Tenements Annuities Fees Corrodies and other yearely proffitts as is aforesaid and the S&bhouov;ms
that are above rehearsed set and taxed to be leavied and taken of them that shall have such Goods in custody or
otherwise charged for Lands as is before rehearsed and the same person &amp; persons and Bodies Corporate by authority of this A&bholigct; shall be discharged against him or them that shall or ought to have the same at the time of the payment or delivery thereof or att his (otherwise) departure from the custody or possession of the same (except and alwaies
foreprized from the charge and assessement of the said Subsidies all Goods Chattells and Ornaments of Churches &amp; Chappels which have beene ordained and used in Churches and Chappels for the honour and Service of Almighty God) And the said twoe Subsidies shall be [by<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] authority aforesaid taxed sessed and rated according to this A&bholigct; in every Shire Riding Lathe Wapentake Rape Citie Borough Towne and in every other place within this Realme of England and Dominion of Wales before the twentieth day of O&bholigct;ober which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord God 1641 and the particular Sums of every Shire Riding Borough towne and other place aforesaid with the particular names of such as are or shall be chargeable to and for the payment of the said two Subsidies to be taxed and set by the Commissioners for the same to be limited or twoe of them at the least with the names of the high Colle&bholigct;ors and in the same forme shall be certified into the Kings Court of Exchequer before the twentieth day of November in the yeare of our Lord God 1641 and the said Sums in form aforesaid to be taxed to and for the payment of the said two Subsidies shall be paid in one intire Sum unto Thomas Soame and Isaac Penington Aldermen of the City of London now Members of the House of Commons in this present Parliament assembled and unto the Chamberlain of the said City of London for the time being at or before the first day of December which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God 1641 and the said S&bhouov;ms in manner and forme aforesaid to be taxed for the payment of the said twoe Subsidies shall be paid att one intire Sum unto the said Thomas Soame Isaac Penington and the said Chamberlain for the time being at or before the first day of December in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred fourty one And that the said Treasurers or Receivers or any one or more of them upon the receipt of any money from the high Colle&bholigct;ors by this Statute to be authorized shall make unto every of the said Colle&bholigct;ors one or more Acquittances under the hands and Seales of the respe&bholigct;ive Treasurers or Receivers that shall receive the same
testifying the receipt of soe much money as he shall receive and that the producing of the said Acquittances soe made shall be as sufficient a Warrant for the said Colle&bholigct;ors to passe theire Account as any Tallie or Constat out of the Receipt and the S&bhouov;ms above said of and for the said two Subsidies shall be taxed set asked and demaunded taken gathered levied and paid to the persons and uses in this present A&bholigct; expressed as well within liberties franchises san&bholigct;uaries ancient demeasnes and other whatsoever places exempt or not exempt as without (except such Shires places and persons as shall be foreprized in and by this present A&bholigct;) any Grant Charter Prescription Use or Libertie by reason of any Letters Patents or other priviledge prescription allowance for the same or whatsoever other matter or discharge heretofore to the contrary made granted used or obtained notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. Absentees, whether Natives or Aliens, charged by Certificate of Inhabitants of Place where Lands, &amp;c. be.</head>
<para id="p5">
<emph type="i">Rule by which they are to be charged</emph>.</para>
<para id="p6">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by authoritie of this present Parliament that every such person aswell such as be borne under the Kings Obeysance as every other person stranger born denizen or not denizen inhabiting within this Realme or within Wales or other the Kings Dominions which at the time of the same assessings or taxations or any or every of them to be had or made shall be out of this Realme or out of Wales and have Goods Chattels Lands or other Tenements Fees or Annuities or other Profits within this Realme or in Wales shall be charged and chargeable for the same by the certificate of the Inhabitants of the place where such Goods Chattels Lands Tenements or other the Premisses then shall be or in such place where such person or persons or his or theire deputie fa&bholigct;or or atturney shall have his or theire most resort unto within this Realme or in Wales in like manner as if the person were or had beene att the time of the said assessing within this Realme and that every person abiding or dwelling within or without this Realme shall be charged and chargeable to the said two Subsidies granted by this A&bholigct; according and after the rate of such yearely substance or value of Lands or Tenements Goods Chattels and other the premisses as every person soe to be charged shall be sett att at the time of the said assessing or taxation upon him to be made
and no otherwise.</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>IV. Commissioners to be appointed by Lord Chancellor, Lord Treasurer, and other great Officers.</head>
<para id="p7">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that for the assessing and ordering of the said Subsidies to be duely had the Lord Chancellour of England or the Lord Keeper of the Great Seale the Lord Treasurer of England the Lord President of the Kings Councell the Lord Privie Seale the Lord Admirall of England the Lord Steward of the Kings Household and the Lord Chamberlaine of the Kings Most honourable Household for the time being or twoe of them at the least whereof the Lord Chancellour or Lord Keeper of the Great Seale or the Lord Treasurer for the time being to be one)<?bignore?> shall and may name and appoint such and soe many persons as they in theire discretion shall thinke fit to be Commissioners for the rating and taxing of the honourable Household of the Kings Majestie in what Shire or other Place the said Household shall happen then to be. And the said Chancellor of England or Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the time being or such Commissioners as shall have the custodie thereof shall make and dire&bholigct; out of the Court of Chancery under the Great Seale severall Commissions for the sessing and leavying of the said severall Subsidies according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; in manner and forme hereafter expressed (viz.)</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>Names of the Commissioners.</head>
<para id="p8">For His Majesties household Unto the Persons in manner aforesaid to be nominated.</para>
			
		<section id="s6">
			<head>And for the County of Bedford</head>
<para id="p9">Unto Sir Beecham S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Knight Sir Robert Napier Knight and Baronet Sir Oliver Luke Sir Richard Conquest Sir Peter Osborne Sir Lewes Dive Sir Samuel Luke Sir William Bryers Sir George Russell Sir William Palmer Knights Richard Taylor Serjeant at Law John Burgoyne William Dumcombe William Boteler Thomas Rolt Oliver Boteler Roger Burgoyne James Beverley John Wingate Edward Cater Henry Chester Humphrey Fish Walter Rolt John Vaux Samuel Browne and Thomas Sadler Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>For the Town of Bedford</head>
<para id="p10">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir Samuel Luke Knight Richard Taylor Serjeant at Law Francis Bannaster Do&bholigct;or of Phisick Thomas Paradine Robert Hawse Thomas Hawes Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>For the County of Buckingham</head>
<para id="p11">Unto Sir Edward Tirrell Knight and Baronet Sir Edmund Verney Knight and Baronet Sir John Lawrence Baronet Sir Thomas Littleton Sir Richard Ingoldsby Sir Robert Dormer Sir William Andrewes Sir Thomas Sanders Sir Henry Crooke Sir Arthur Manwaring Sir Edward Salter Sir John Parsons Sir Robert Lovet Sir Ralphe Verney Knights Peter Dorrell Thomas Risley Richard Greenvile John Dormer Richard Winwood John Tirringham Thomas Tirringham Thomas Egleston Rames Lowe Thomas Duncombe of Brickhill Thomas Tirrel Thomas Longvile Thomas Lea the elder Richard Sergeant William Hackvile Thomas Westall John Duncombe of East Claydon Henry Bulstrode William Wheeler Edmund Waller of Gregories Robert Busby Thomas Hampson Thomas Stafford Francis Cheyney the elder Edmund West William Bowyer Gabriel Hipslowe John Crooke Anthony Ratcliffe Esquires</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>The Bayliffes for the time being for the Towne of Buckingham</head>
<para id="p12">Unto Sir Alexander Denton Knight Robert Smith John Nicholas Arthur Claver Gentl</para>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>For the County of Berks</head>
<para id="p13">William Lenthall Esquire now Speaker of the Commons House of Parliament Sir George Stonehouse Baronet Sir John Backhouse Knight of the Bath Sir Francis Knolls senior Sir Francis Knolls junior Knights Sir Richard Hanson Knight John Fetiplace Edmund Dunche Henry Martin Thomas Manwaring John Harrison George Purefey Thomas Fetiplace Samuel Dunche Henry Pole Humphrey Doleman William Barker and Roger Knight of Gwinham Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s11">
<head>For the Borough of New Windsor</head>
<para id="p14">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir William Salter Knight Sir Robert Bennet Knight Edmund Eyre Gentleman William Tayler George Weldon Esquires Thomas Johnson Gent. John Spencer Do&bholigct;or in Phisick and John Hersy John Worship Gentlemen Thomas Waller Esquire Henry Henn Gent. and Mathew Day Alderman.</para>
</section>
<section id="s12">
<head>For the County of Cornwall</head>
<para id="p15">Unto Sir John Trelawney Knight &amp; Baronet Sir Richard Buller Sir Nicholas Slannying Sir Richard Vivian Sir Bevill Grenvill Knights John Arundell of Trerise Francis Godolphin of Godolphin Peirs Edgecombe Charles Trevanion Thomas Lower John Harris of Landrest Francis Buller of Shillingham Alexander Carew John Trefusis John S<emph type="p">t</emph> Aubin Francis Basset Jonathan Rashley Peter Courtney Thomas Herle Hugh Boscawen Richard Erisy John Moyle Paul Speccot Ambrose Mannaton Nicholas Trefusis George Heale Humphrey Nicholl Francis Godolphin of Treveneage Thomas Gewen Walter Langdon William Glyn John Carter Thomas Arundell Hender Mouldworth John Polewhele and Joseph Jane Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s13">
<head>For the County of Cumberland</head>
<para id="p16">Unto Sir Patricius Curwen Sir William Dalston Sir Henry Fletcher Baronets Sir George Dalston Sir William Musgrave and Sir Thomas Dacres Knights Richard Barret John Skelton Peter Senhouse Richard Tolson William Lawson Thomas Lamplue John Eglonbie and William Briscoe Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s14">
<head>For the County of Cambridge</head>
<para id="p17">Unto Sir John Cuts and Sir James Reynolds Knights Francis Russell John Cotton James Reynolds William Allington Robert Peyton Michael Dalton Thomas Wendy Thomas Willis Isaac Baron Thomas Tirrell William March Robert Lukin Everard Buckworth Besney Betts William Barnes Dudley Pope John Craine James Ayliffe Thomas Simonds William Fisher Robert Castle John Hubbard Thomas Ducket John [Wildbore<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] and John Whistler Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s15">
<head>For the Towne of Cambridge</head>
<para id="p18">Unto Sir John Cuts Knight the Maior for the time being John Lowrey Esquire Talbot Pepys Recorder Esquire Samuel Spaulding John Sherwood Robert Twells Aldermen Thomas French</para>
</section>
<section id="s16">
<head>For the County of Chester</head>
<para id="p19">Unto Sir George Booth Sir Richard Wilbraham Sir Thomas Delves Sir Richard Grosvenor Knights and Baronets Sir Edward Fitton Sir William Brereton [Baronets Sir Thomas Brereton Knight Richard Brereton<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Henry Leigh Thomas Stanley William Downes Peter Venables George Cotton Roger Wilbraham Hugh Wilbraham Peter Warburton of the Graunge Henry Bunbury William Whitmore Henry Burkenhead William Glegg John Crewe George Spurstowe Thomas [Crackstone<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] William Liversage Philip Manwaring William Marbury and Thomas Cholmeley &amp; Henry Manwaring Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s17">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Chester</head>
<para id="p20">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir Thomas Smith Knight Robert Brerewood Esquire Serjeant at Law Recorder Francis Gamul William Gamul Christopher Bleasse Charles Walley and Nicholas Ince Aldermen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s18">
<head>For the County of Derby</head>
<para id="p21">Unto Sir George Greasley Sir Thomas Burdet Baronets Sir Edward Vernon Sir John Fitzherbert Sir Edward Leech Knights Thomas Greasley Christopher Horton John Agard Samuel Sleigh John Bullocke Simon Every Esquires John Gell Esquire Henry Gilbert Gentleman the Maior of Chesterfeild for the time being Christopher Fulwood John Milward John Frecheville John Shawcroft Randall Ashenhurst Francis Rhodes Edward Revill and Francis Revill Esquires Henry Wigfall and Lionell Fanshawe Gentlemen.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>And for the Borough of Derby</head>
<para id="p22">Unto the Maior for the time being John Hope Henry Wandell Luke Whittington Aldermen John Bullock Esquire Roger Allestry and Robert Meller Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s20">
<head>For the County of Devon</head>
<para id="p23">Unto Sir Edward Seymour Knight and Baronet Sir George Chudleigh Sir Edmund Fowell Sir Lewis Pollard Sir John Poole Sir Peter Prideaux Baronets Sir John Speccot Sir Samuel Role Sir Shilston Calmady Sir Nicholas Martin Sir John Young Sir Richard Reynell Sir John Chichester Knights John Bampfeild Arthur Basset John Ackland Arthur Champernon John Harris Hugh Fortescue John Gifford Anthony Dennis Thomas Southcot Edmund Arscote Samson Hele John Berry William Tothill Robert Savory Henry Waldron John Davy Francis Bluet Richard Columbe Henry Worth Walter Hele John Northcott Walter Young John Upton John Bampfeild George Trobridge George Peare Roger Mathew Edmund Prideaux James Welsh Edward Yard Richard Cabell Richard Duke Alexander Maynard William Maurice Thomas Risden Robert Stafford Edmund Fowell William Fry Humphrey Prouz John Peter and John Yeo Henry Aishford Edmund Tremaine William Carey Arthur Aishford John Foynes John Were Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s21">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Exon</head>
<para id="p24">Unto the Maior for the time being John Lynn Nicholas Spicer John Hackewill Adam Bennet Roger Malacke Robert Walker Esquires Robert Vilvaine Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke</para>
</section>
<section id="s22">
<head>For the County of Dorsett</head>
<para id="p25">Unto Sir Thomas Trenchard Knight Sir John Miller Knight George Lord Digby Denzell Hollis Esquire Sir John Strangewayes Sir Walter Earle Knights Richard Rogers Giles Strangwaies Gerrard Napper Thomas Earle William Whitaker Richard King Richard Rose Giles Greene Dennis Bond John Browne Angell Gray Gregory Gibs Richard Broderip John Arnold James Frampton George Williams Richard Bingham Thomas Tregunnell William Savage Esquires John Dollinge Bampfeild Chafing Edmund Ogden John Hannam Esquires and Robert Toope Gentleman</para>
</section>
<section id="s23">
<head>For the Town and County of Pool</head>
<para id="p26">Unto the Maior for the time being George Scutt Alexander Wayte and John Harward Gentlemen and William Constantine Recorder</para>
</section>
<section id="s24">
<head>For the County of Yorke and for the Westriding of the County of Yorke</head>
<para id="p27">Unto Ferdinando Lord Fairefax Sir Francis Wortley Knight and Baronet Sir William Savile Sir Henry Slingsby Baronets Sir Henry Goodricke Sir William Lister Sir Arthur Ingram junior Sir Thomas Wentworth Sir John Ramsden Sir George Wentworth Sir Edward Rhodes Sir William Fairefax Sir Jerves Cutler Sir Richard Hutton Sir William Ingram Sir John Wolstenholme Knights William Ingleby Henry Arthington John Kay Robert Rockley Ingram Hopton William West Jervas Hamond Henry Cholmely Nicholas Yarborough John Farrer William White Thomas Parker William Wombwell William Mallory Thomas Mauleverer John Reversby Esquires George Marwood Thomas Lister Richard Tankard John Robinson Gregory Armitage Thomas Stockdale Esquires Benjamin Wade and Joseph Hillary Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s25">
<head>For the Northriding of the County of Yorke</head>
<para id="p28">Unto Henry Bellasis Esquire Sir Marmaduke Wyvell Sir Thomas Gore Knights and Baronets Sir Coniers Darcy Sir William Sheffeild Sir Hugh Cholmely Sir Henry Anderson Sir Thomas Ingram Sir Richard Darley Sir Thomas Layton Sir Thomas Gore Sir Hugh Bethell Sir Henry Franckland Knights Henry Fowls Mathew Hutton John Dalton Henry Anderson John Calverley John Wastall John Dodsworth junior Arthur Awdbrough Roger Wyvell William Caley John Cholmeley Christopher Perchehay Charles Tankard John Talbot George Metcalfe George Trotter James Pennyman Thomas Heblethwaite Richard Wynn Christopher Waters Stephen Jackson Francis Rookeby Robert Strickland Richard Auldbrough Mathew Smelt Thomas Francklin Esquires John Ledgard of Maulton Esquire Francis Lassels Esquire Robert Wilde John Robinson Stephen Jackson James Cholmeley George Conyers Francis Thompson William Ford Richard Thompson William Staveley James Moore Thomas Lassels William Pinckney John Dent Robert Colchester &amp; William Fish Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s26">
<head>For the Eastriding of the County of Yorke</head>
<para id="p29">Unto Sir John Hotham Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Griffith Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Metham Sir William Alford Sir Philip Mountain Sir Michael Wharton Sir John Vavasor Sir Philip Stapleton Sir William Stri&bholigct;land Sir Thomas Remington Sir Arthur Robinson Knights Thomas Anlaby John Legard Richard Remington John [Botham<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]Michael Wharton William Saint-Quintin Thomas Heblethwait Christopher Appleyard John Constable William Grimston Robert Crompton Francis Thorpe Christopher Ridley Gregory Crake John Anlaby Charles Bowes Stephen Tompson John Overton and Ralph Lutton Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s27">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Yorke</head>
<para id="p30">Unto Christopher Croft Lord Maior, Sir William Allanson and Sir Roger Jaques Knights and Aldermen Sir Thomas Widdrington Knight Recorder Sir Robert Belt Knight Alderman Leonard Betson Edmund Cooper Robert Hemsworth Thomas Hoyle James Hutchinson Thomas Hodgson Henry Tompson John Vaux and William Scott Aldermen</para>
</section>
<section id="s28">
<head>For the Towne and County of Hull</head>
<para id="p31">Unto the Maior for the time being Peregrine Pelham Esquire Nicholas Denman Lancelot Roper William Popple James Watkinson Henry Barnard Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s29">
<head>For the County of Essex</head>
<para id="p32">Sir Thomas Barrington Sir Harbottle Grimston Knights and Baronets Sir Thomas Bendish Sir Benjamin Ayloffe Sir William Hicks Sir William Masham Sir Richard Everard Sir William Luckin Sir William Wiseman Baronets Sir Martin Lomley Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Mildmay Knight Master of the Jewell House Sir Thomas Cheeke Sir Henry Mildmay of Moulsham Sir William Maxey Sir Henry Holcroft Sir Thomas Bowes Sir Francis Cooke Sir Henry Saint George Sir William Rowe Sir William Martin Sir Thomas Honywood Sir Humphrey Mildmay Sir John Barrington Sir Thomas Wiseman Sir Gamaliel Capel Sir John Tyrrell Sir Cranmore Harris Knights Harbottle Grimston Henry Nevil James Cambell John Harvey Esquires George Walton Robert Kempe John Argoll Edward Keightley John Wakering Edward Eltonhead Esquires William Gouldingham Euseby Wright James Hyron Esquires Edward Palmer William Coniers Thomas Fanshawe John Wright Thomas Ayloffe Serjeant at Lawe William Atwood George Walton James Altham Timothy Middleton Nathaniel Bacon Anthony Luther Thomas Smith John Meade John Brooke, Cary Harvey Mildmay, Deane Tindall Henry Wiseman Robert Mildmay de Tarling Edward Berket Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s30">
<head>For the Towne of Colchester</head>
<para id="p33">The Maior for the time being Harbotle Grimston Esquire Recorder Robert Buckston Esquire Henry Barrington Alderman John Langley Daniel Cole Gentlemen</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>And for the Towne of Maiden</head>
<para id="p34">Unto the two Bailiffs for the time being Jeremiah Browning and John Francis.</para>
</section>
<section id="s32">
<head>For the Towne of Harwich</head>
<para id="p35">Unto the Maior for the time being Harbottle Grymston Esquire Recorder Richard Hawkins Robert [Hawes<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Roger
Coleman.</para>
</section>
<section id="s33">
<head>For the County of Gloucester</head>
<para id="p36">Unto Sir Humphrey Tracy Sir Baynham Throgmorton Sir Richard Duce Baronets Sir John Tracy Sir William Masters Sir Ralph Dutton Sir John Seamor Sir Maurice Berkley Sir Robert Cooke Sir Robert Tracy Knights
Richard Berkley Henry Poole John Dutton Nathaniel Stephens John Prettyman John Stephens Thomas Escourt John
Fetyplace Esquires [William Try John How Esquires<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Stephen Fowler Gentleman Thomas Chester Edward Stephens John Cothrington Samuel Cothrington John Smith junior Anthony Kinscot Esquires Francis Finch John Berrow Thomas Morgan William Jones John Chamberlain Michael Rutler John Kite Esquires Anthony Hodges Gentleman William Stratford Esquire.</para>
</section>
<section id="s34">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Gloucester</head>
<para id="p37">Unto William Lenthall Esquire now Speaker of the C&bhooov;mons House of Parliament and Recorder of the said City and to the Maior for the time being Anthony Robinson Toby Bullocke [James<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Brewster John Webb James Powell William Singleton William Capell and Thomas Pury Aldermen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s35">
<head>For the County of Huntington</head>
<para id="p38">Unto Sir Sidney Mountague Knight Sir William Armyn Baronet Onslow Winche John Castle James Ravenscroft Valentine Walton Robert Page Wheathill Audley Toorell Josselin Thomas Cater Esquires</para>
<para id="p39">(<ref idref="n12">12</ref>)</para>
<para id="p40">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir Oliver Cromwell Knight of the Bath Robert Barnard Esquire Lyonell Walden Gervais Fulwood Thomas Philipps and John Peacocke Aldermen</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>And for the County of Hertford</head>
<para id="p41">Unto Charles Viscount Cranborne Sir John Boteler Knight of the Bath Sir John Jennings Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Fanshawe Knight of the Bath Sir Richard Lucy Sir Thomas Hide Baronets Sir Charles Cesar Sir William
Litton Knights Sir John Gerrard Barronet Sir Charles Harbourd Sir Thomas Fotherley Sir John Colte Sir Thomas
Dacres Sir Edward Bash Sir John Wats Sir John Cesar Sir Peter Salstenstall Sir John Gower Sir John Harrison Knights
William Preistley George Tooke Francis Taverner Granley Morton Edward Wingate Henry Anderson John Brocket
James Mayne Francis Combes Esquires Thomas Blunt John Heydon Robert Dewhurst Edward Atkins Serjeant at Law
Thomas Cooke Richard Hale Thomas Hewit Henry Gardner John Gulston Arthur Poulter Ralph Freeman William
Newce John Brograve Edward Chester Edward Cason Arthur Capell Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s37">
<head>For the Town and Borough of Saint Albans</head>
<para id="p42">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir John Jennings Knight of the Bath John Robotham Thomas Cooley Ralph Pemberton Gentlemen</para>
</section>
<section id="s38">
<head>For the County of Hereford</head>
<para id="p43">Unto Sir Robert Harleigh Knight of the Bath Fitzwilliam Connisby Esquire Sir John Kirle Baronet Sir Richard Hopton Sir Robert Whitney Sir Humphrey Baskervile Sir William [Crofts<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Knights Wallop Brabazon Esquire Henry Lingen Roger Vaughan John Scudamore of Kent Church John Vaughan Ambrose Elton James Kirle William Rudhall William Scudamore Walter Kirle William Smallman Thomas Price Harbert Westfaling John Cornwall Paul Abrahall Epiphan Howorth Thomas Tomkins Walter Vaughan John Coles John Patshall Richard Barrowe Arnold Burghill William Cartwright Edward Broughton Henry Jones the Bailiffe of the Borough of Leominster for the time being</para>
</section>
<section id="s39">
<head>For the City of Hereford</head>
<para id="p44">Unto the Maior of the said City for the time being James Rodes Anthony Pembridge Richard Weaver and Richard Seabourn Esquires James Lane Gentleman.</para>
</section>
<section id="s40">
<head>For the County of Kent</head>
<para id="p45">Unto Sir Edward Hales Sir Edward Deering Knights and Baronets Sir Thomas Peyton Sir John Baker Baronets Sir Roger Twisden Sir John [Widley<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Knights and Baronets Sir Thomas Palmer Sir John Rivers Baronets Sir Humphrey Stile Knight &amp; Baronet Sir Michael Levesey Baronet Sir Edward Scot Sir William Brooke Sir George Sondes Knights of the Bath Sir Perivall Hart Sir Francis Barnham Sir Humphrey Tufton Sir Edward Boys Sir Thomas Walsingham Sir James Oxenden Sir Anthony Welden Sir Peter Wroth Sir John Honywood Sir Edward
Gilborne Sir Henry Grimston Sir Robert Filmer Sir John Culpepper Sir Cheiney Culpepper Sir Edward Master
Sir William Brockman Knights Edward Monyns Richard Hardres Stephen Leonard Robert Barnham Henry Heyman
Robert Bargrave Thomas Digges Anthony Hamman Richard Master John Boys Reynold Edwards Samuel Short
John Henden William Boys Edward Dering Nicholas Toke George Chute Norton Knatchbull Richard Lee George
Strode Thomas Seliard William James Thomas Blunt Edward Partherich Henry Dixon Thomas Godfrey Peter Godfrey
Henry Gilborne Goldwell John Harvey Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s41">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Canterbury</head>
<para id="p46">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir Edward Masters Knight John Nutt Francis Lovelace William Man Esquires
Thomas Courthope Esquire Avery Savyn &amp; James Masters Aldermen</para>
</section>
<section id="s42">
<head>For the City of Rochester.</head>
<para id="p47">Unto the Maior for the time being Henry Clearke Esquire Serjeant att Law Recorder Richard Lea George
Newman Esquires and John Cobham Gentleman.</para>
</section>
<section id="s43">
<head>For the Parts of Lyndsey in the County of Lincolne</head>
<para id="p48">Unto Edmund Lord Sheffeild Sir John Wray Knight and Baronet Sir Philipp Tirwhit Sir John Bolles Baronets
Sir Edward Askew Sir William Pelham Sir Charles Bolles Sir Christopher Wray Sir John South Sir Henry Radley
Knights Nathaniel Fynes John Bellasis Thomas Grantham Samuel Oldfeild Anthony Meeres Thomas Sanderson Edmund
Anderson Stephen Anderson Willoughby Hickman Charles Pelham John Broxholm Vincent Sheffeild Marmaduke Darrell
Edward Rositer Richard Toothby Thomas Ayscough senior John Bradley William Godfrey Francis Wolbey Esquires
William Loddington Gentleman the Maior of Grimsby William Coney Esquire Rutland Snowden Esquire.</para>
</section>
<section id="s44">
<head>For the City of Lincolne</head>
<para id="p49">Unto the Maior of Lincolne for the time being Thomas Grantham Esquire John Broxholm Esquire Richard White
William Watson Stephen Dawson Aldermen and Richard Ward Citizen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s45">
<head>For the Borough of Boston</head>
<para id="p50">Unto Sir Anthony Irby Knight William Ellis Esquire William Jenkinson Richard Westland Charles Empson
Edward Tilson John Whiting Thomas Askham Thomas Welby Gentlemen and the Maior of Boston for the time being.</para>
</section>
<section id="s46">
<head>For the Parts of Holland in Com &bhopcrl;d.</head>
<para id="p51">Unto Sir Anthony Irby Knight Thomas Ogle William Lo&bholigct;on Thomas Reade Bevill Wimberley William Ellis Dymock Walpole Philip Welby Thomas Ogle Esquires John Hobson Francis Empson Gentlemen John Harrington Esquire Thomas Irby Esquire.</para>
</section>
<section id="s47">
<head>For the Parts of Kestaven in the County of Lincolne</head>
<para id="p52">Unto Sir Robert Carr Sir William Armyn Baronets Sir John Brooke Sir Hamond Whitchcot Sir Gervas Nevill Knights Charles Dymock Thomas Hatcher Edmund Hall Thomas Harrington Thomas Lister John Brownlowe
Edward King Henry Pelham Esquires Edward Skipwith Robert Treadway William Savile John Archer Esquires the
Alderman of Stamford and the Alderman of Grantham</para>
</section>
<section id="s48">
<head>For the County of Leicester</head>
<para id="p53">Unto Sir Edward Hartoppe Baronet Sir Woolston Dixie Sir Richard Roberts Knights George Ashby Nicholas Lister Thomas Babington Thomas Brewdnell Richard Bent Henry Fawnt Arthur Staveley William Roberts William Quarles William Jerves Peter Temple Thomas Beamont George Puchin Simon Ridgeley William Davers Roger Smith John Saint-John Thomas Merry William Halford Francis Hacker Sen. Esq[uire]s.</para>
</section>
<section id="s49">
<head>For the Borough of Leicester</head>
<para id="p54">Unto the Maior for the time being Gilbert Fawsett William Billers Thomas Blounts John Norris Thomas Ruddiard Aldermen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s50">
<head>For the County Palatine of Lancaster</head>
<para id="p55">Unto Sir Gilbert Houghton Knight &amp; Baronet Sir Ralph Ashton Sir Thomas Stanley Baronets Sir Thomas Barton Knight Ralph Ashton [Robert<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] Kirkby Richard Shuttleworth John More Thomas Standish Ralph Ashton Richard Holland Charles Garrard John Atherton Robert Holt Alexander Rigby of Burgh Hugh Rigby Alexander Rigby William Farrington Thomas Preston John Gerlington George Dodding Edmund Hopwood Nicholas Townly Henry Ashhurst John Bradshawe Edward Veale Esquires Henry Ogle Savile Ratcliffe John Starkey Edward Butterworth
William Ambrose Christopher Banister Esquires Thomas Whittingham John Bradell Edmund Ashton Ratcliffe Ashton
Esquires Richard Shuttleworth Gentleman.</para>
</section>
<section id="s51">
<head>For the County of Middlesex</head>
<para id="p56">Unto Sir Edward Spencer Knight Sir Thomas Fowler Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Barkham Knight and Baronet Sir William Balfour Knight Leiutenant of the Tower of London Sir Francis Darcey Sir John Davers Sir
Thomas Lake Sir Edward Wardour Sir William Roberts Sir Henry Roe Sir John Bennet Sir Thomas Allen Sir
Robert Wood Sir Nicholas Raynton Knights John Page Esquire one of the Masters of the Chancery Thomas Gardiner
Esquire Recorder of the City of London William Hill Justinian Povey William Cholmley Robert Fenn John
Hawtrey Francis Poulton John Herne John Huxley George Long Edward Roberts Richard Blower Anthony Crofts
Richard Sprygenell Esquires John Smith Thomas Marsh John Hooker Edward Noell Gideon Awnsham Thomas
Jennings Richard Page and Thomas Wilcox Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s52">
<head>For the City of Westminster</head>
<para id="p57">Unto Sir Edmund Verney Sir William Ashton [Sir<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Randall Crewe Sir Robert Pye Sir Arthur Ingram Sir Edward Wardour Knights Robert Dixon Michael Oldesworth Mathew Hale Arthur Squibb John Glynn Peter Hayward Henry Lyde William Wheeler Esquires Robert Dixon George Bleverhaset William Bell John Brigham Gentlemen John Chicheley John Trenchard Robert Scawen Esquires and Richard Gammon Gentleman.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s53">
			<head>And for the Dutchy of Lancaster</head>
<para id="p58">Edward Lord Newburgh Chancelor of the Dutchy Sir Thomas Bedingfeild Knight Attorney Sir Edward Harbert Knight Atturney Generall to the Kings Most Excellent Majestie &amp; Challenor Chute Esquire.</para>
</section>
<section id="s54">
<head>For the City of London</head>
<para id="p59">Unto the Lord Maior for the time being Sir James Cambell Sir George Whitmore Sir Nicholas Raynton Sir Christopher Cletherow Sir Maurice Abbot and Sir Henry Garway Knights and Aldermen Thomas Gardiner Esquire
Recorder Thomas Soame Isaac Pennington Aldermen Mathew Cradock and Samuel Vassall Citizens.</para>
</section>
<section id="s55">
<head>For the County of Monmouth</head>
<para id="p60">Unto Edward Lord Herbert Sir Edmund Morgan and Sir William Morgan Knights William Kemeys Esquire William Harbert Richard Herbert Thomas Morgan de Maughen Trevor Williams William Harbert of Colebrooke
Nicholas Kemeyes John Milbourn Henry Probert David Lewes William Baker Philip Jones William Jones de Uske
George Probert Thomas Morgan de Lansore William Morgan of Tredonock Gentleman and Thomas Williams
Gentleman.</para>
</section>
<section id="s56">
<head>For the County of Northampton</head>
<para id="p61">Unto William Lord Fitzwilliams of Milton Sir Rowland S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Knight of the Bath Sir Lewes Watson Sir John Isham Knights and Baronets Sir Christopher Yelverton Sir William Chancey Sir Richard Samuel Sir William Wilmore Sir Edward Watson Sir Humphrey Ormes Knights Richard Lane Esquire Attorney to the Prince his Highnesse Richard Knightley the elder Charles Edmonds Francis Nicholls Edward Hardy John Barnard Robert
Mildmay John Cartwright Philip Houleman John Creswell Richard Trist William Pargiter John Wirley James
Anyan Edward Farmer Richard Owsly Clifton Catesby Robert Britton George Clarke Lawrence Manley Thomas
Andrew Thomas Genison John Gages John Sawyer Thomas Pentlowe Thomas Dove Francis Quarles John Claypool
Edward Dudley Thomas Elmes John Norton Esquires Edward Hanbury Edward Shugborough John Norwich John
Syres Edward Palmer Robert Kirkham and Thomas Rud Esquires and William Hack Esquire.</para>
</section>
<section id="s57">
<head>For the Borough of Northampton</head>
<para id="p62">Unto the Maior for the time being Richard Lane Esquire Recorder Attorney Generall to the Princes HighnesseSir Richard Samuel Knight Francis Nicolls Esquire Thomas Martin Joseph Sergeant John Gifford John Herbert and John Brett Aldermen</para>
</section>
<section id="s58">
<head>For the County of Nottingham</head>
<para id="p63">Francis Peirepont Esquire Sir Gervas Clifton Knight and Baronet Sir Francis Molineaux Sir Hardolph Wastenesse Baronets Sir John Byron Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Hutchinson Knight Sir Francis Thornhagh Sir Roger Cooper Sir Mathew Palmer Sir Gervas Eyre Knights Robert Sutton Isham Parkins Anthony Eyre John Nevill Thomas
Williamson William Stanhope Richard Byron John Wood Senior Timothy Pusey Gilbert Millington John Digby
A&bholigct;on Burnell Jervas Piggot Gervas Lee John Odingsell Hugh Cartwright William Saunderson Richard Hacker John
Wood Junior Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s59">
<head>For the Towne and County of Nottingham</head>
<para id="p64">Unto the Maior for the time being William Fletcher Recorder Francis Peirpoint Esquire Sir Gervas Clifton Knightand Baronet Sir Thomas Hutchinson Knight William Nix Alderman Richard Hardmeat Alderman William Gregory John James Robert Burton and Francis Toplady Aldermen Robert Sutton William Stannopp and Gilbert Millington
Esquires Huntington Plumbtree Do&bholigct;or in Phisick and Robert Greeves and John Gregory Gent.</para>
</section>
<section id="s60">
<head>For the Towne of Newarke upon Trent in Comit. Not[ts.]</head>
<para id="p65">The Maior for the time being Sir Mathew Palmer Knight Robert Sutton Lancelot Thompson Thomas Atkinson Edward Standish John Johnson Christopher Wilson.</para>
</section>
<section id="s61">
<head>For the County of Norfolke</head>
<para id="p66">Unto Sir John Hobart Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Richardson Knight Sir Thomas Woodhouse Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Berney Sir John Holland Baronet Sir Miles Hobart Knight of the Bath Sir Hamond Le Strange Sir Thomas Deereham Sir Charles Le Grosse Sir Robert Kempe Sir Anthony Gawdy Sir Thomas Hoogan Sir Edmund Mundeford and Sir Thomas Gawdy Knights William Paston Thomas Knivett Framlingham Gawdy James Hobart
John Potts John Buxton Thomas Windeham William Heveningham Robert Bacon Richard Catlyn Thomas Guybon
Robert de Grey John Spelman of Norborough John Smith Gregory Gawsell Charles Suckling Jeffery Cobb Thomas Fincham John Palgrave Francis Jermy Edward Gurney William Doily William Buckworth Valentine Pell
Robert Woods Robert Wilton James Scamler John Spelman Martin Sidley Robert Thonge Robert Houghton
and Thomas Wright Adam Scambler James Scambler Robert Mapes Thomas Wright Thomas Finsham Martin Sidley
Edward Chamberlaine Henry Taylor Thomas Reeve and John Kendall Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s62">
<head>For the Towne of Thetford</head>
<para id="p67">The Maior for the time being Henry Depneyes Alderman Edward Moore John Chapman Henry Kettall Robert Snelling Thomas Snelling Giles Alden John Salman Edmund Mobbs Gentlemen and Henry Mendham Gentleman.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s63">
			<head>And for the City of Norwich</head>
<para id="p68">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir William Denny Knight Francis Bacon Sergeant at Law Richard Rose Thomas Shipdham Henry Lane Christopher Barret Robert Sumpter Thomas Baker John Tooley Richard Harman Esquires John Thacker William Goslyn Lynewell Sherwood Francis Norris Thomas Barret Gentleman.</para>
</section>
<section id="s64">
<head>For the Towne of Lyn Regis</head>
<para id="p69">The Maior for the time being Francis Parlett Recorder Roger Bungey Walter Kirby Robert Hawley James Astwood Gentlemen</para>
</section>
<section id="s65">
<head>For the Towne of Yarmouth</head>
<para id="p70">Thomas Green Robert Wakeman Henry Davis Thomas Johnson Aldermen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s66">
<head>For the County of Oxford</head>
<para id="p71">Unto William Lenthall Esquire now Speaker of the Commons House of Parliament Sir Thomas Pope Knight Sir Thomas Peniston Knight and Baronet Sir Peter Wentworth Knight of the Bath Sir John Curson Sir Robert Dormer Sir Robert Jenkinson Sir John Lacy Sir Francis Norris Sir William Cobb Knights Edward Wray John Doily Thomas
Chamberlaine William Walter Thomas Tipping Robert Scroope Edmund Symeon Unton Croke Humphrey Elmes
Richard Hampden John Taverner Edmund Gooddier William Tipping John Griffith Edmund Chamberlaine
Bartholomew Hone Rice Jones and Walter Dunch Edward Clarke Charnell Pettie &amp; Vincent Barrey and Richard
Powell Esquires.</para>
			</section>
		<section id="s67">
			<head>And for the City of Oxon</head>
<para id="p72">Unto the Maior of the said City for the time being John Whistler Esquire Recorder William Potter Henry Southam John Sayer Martin Wright John Nixon Aldermen Timothy Carter Town Clerk.</para>
</section>
<section id="s68">
<head>For the County of Rutland</head>
<para id="p73">To Sir Edward Harrington Knight and Baronet Sir Francis Bodenham and Sir Henry Mynn Knights Henry Noell Alexander Noell Bryan Palms Edward Heath Evers Armyn John Osborne Everard Falkener Edward Cheseldine and Andrew Burton Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s69">
<head>For the County of Surrey</head>
<para id="p74">Unto William Mounson Knight Lord Viscount Mounson of Castlemaine Sir Anthony Vincent Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Younge Sir Ambrose Browne Baronets Sir Nicholas Carewe Sir Richard Onslowe Sir Arthur
Manwaring Sir Thomas Grymes Sir Francis Howard Sir Charles Howard Sir Francis Stidolph Sir John Howland
Sir John Lenthall Sir John Jaques Sir John Lydcote Sir John Tunstall Sir John Gresham Sir Thomas Evelyn
Sir William Elliot Sir Thomas Bludder Sir Dudley Carleton Sir Robert Parkehurst Knights Nicholas Stoughton Henry
Hilliard George Evelyn Samuel Owfeild Arthur Squibb George Mynn George Duncombe Senior William Muschampe
Robert Hatton John Evelyn Robert Goodwyn Edmund Saunders John Turner Henry Weston Robert Holman
Edward Bish the Elder Edward Bish the younger Hayward Bickerstaffe Richard Hackett Woolley Lee John Denham
Robert Hamond Mathew Carleton John Goodwin Esquires and John Wayte Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s70">
<head>For the Borough of Southwarke</head>
<para id="p75">Sir John Lenthall Knight Samuel Warcopp Esquire Robert Haughton Cornelius Cocke</para>
</section>
<section id="s71">
<head>For the County of Stafford</head>
<para id="p76">Unto Sir William Brereton Sir Harvy Bagot Sir Edward Littleton Baronets Sir Richard Leveson Knight of the Bath Sir Charles Egerton Ralph Snede Walter Wrottesley George Digby Thomas Crumpton Humphrey Worley
Mathew Moreton John Scrimshire William Cotton John Fowke Esquires Edward Manwaring Walter Grosvenor
Richard Pyat Michael Biddulph John Wedgewood William Brookes [Esquire<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Richard Jeven Richard Hinton Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s72">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Litchfeild</head>
<para id="p77">Unto the Bayliffes of the City for the time being Sir Walter Devereaux Knight Michael Noble Esquire John
Barnes Humphrey Mathewe Randulph Terricke Richard Baxter and Richard Drafgate Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s73">
<head>For the County of Salop</head>
<para id="p78">Unto Sir Robert Howard Knight of the Bath William Peirpont Esquire Sir Richard Levison Knight of the Bath Sir Paul Harris Knight and Baronet Sir John Corbet Baronet Sir William Whitmore Sir Richard Newport Sir
William Owen Sir Robert Eyton Sir Edward Kynaston Sir Gilbert Cornwell Knights Henry Broomeley Harcourt Layton
Esquire John Weld Esquire Richard Moore Charles Baldwyn Francis Carleton Walter Berker Edward Jones Thomas
Eyton Peter Corbet Edward Cresset Thomas Corbet Adam Littleton Thomas Cettleby Francis Herbert William
Littleton Morton Briggs Thomas Woolrich Walter A&bholigct;on Humphrey Walcott Walter Piggott John Newton Thomas
Nicholls Arthur Sandford William Fowler Thomas Mitton Andrew Lloyd Richard Lloyd Francis Thornes Robert
Powell Thomas Screven William Blunden Richard Okeley Walter Waring Thomas Sotherne Roger Kineston Esquires
Rowland Hill Arthur Ward Thomas Lochard Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s74">
<head>For the Towne of Shrewsbury</head>
<para id="p79">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir Richard Prince Knight Timothy Turner Thomas Jones Senior Richard Gibbons Esquires Edward Jones Thomas Owen Humphrey Mackworth Esquires William Rowley Simon Weston Charles Benyon Robert Betton Thomas Winfeild John Studley Aldermen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s75">
<head>For the Towne of Ludlowe</head>
<para id="p80">Unto the Bayliffes for the time being Ralph Goodwin Charles Baldwin Esquires Edward Jones Adam A&bholigct;on and Ellis Beddow Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s76">
<head>For the County of Southampton</head>
<para id="p81">Unto William Ashburneham Esquire Sir John Milles Baronet Sir Richard Tichborne Sir Richard Norton Knights and Baronets Sir William Lewes Baronet Sir Henry Wallop Sir William Uvedall Sir Richard Gifford Sir Francis
Dowse Sir Thomas Bilson Sir Henry Mildmay Sir Thomas Jervoise Sir Henry Clarke Sir John Compton Knights
Robert Wallop Thomas Willis Richard Whitehead Henry Sanders John Doddington William Jepson William Kingsmill
Richard Jarvoise Richard Norton of Southwicke Thomas Neale John Lisle Edward Pitt Benjamin Tichburne Dowse
Fuller Edward Goddard Joseph Wale Thomas Edmonds Edward Hooper John Hooke John Buckley Thomas
Betsworth Arthur Bromfeild Henry Tulse William Withers Richard [Major<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] and Thomas Chandelor Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s77">
<head>For the Isle of Wight</head>
<para id="p82">Unto Sir Henry Worsley Baronet Sir Robert Dellington Baronet Sir John Oglaunder Sir William Lisle Sir Edward Dennis Sir John Leigh Knights Barnaby Leigh John Lisle John Mens John Richards William Boarman and John Worsley Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s78">
<head>For the City of Winchester</head>
<para id="p83">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir William Ogle Knight John Lisle Raphe Riggs Gentlemen Joseph Butler Thomas Godson Aldermen</para>
</section>
<section id="s79">
<head>For the Towne and County of Southampton</head>
<para id="p84">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir John Mill Baronet Henry Brasbridge Nicholas Peascodd Peter Seale Thomas Mason Peter Clungeon Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s80">
<head>For the County of Suffolke</head>
<para id="p85">Unto William Spring Esquire Sir Edmund Bacon Sir William Playters Sir Robert Crane Knights and Baronets Sir John Barker Baronet Sir Butts Bacon Baronet Sir Roger North Sir Nathaniel Barnardiston Sir Philip Parker Sir Simond Dewes Sir William Soames Sir Charles Crofts Sir Robert Brooke Sir John Wentworth Sir William Harvey Sir
John Rowse [Knights<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Sir Thomas [See<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Knight Thomas Jermyn William Heveningham John Wingfeild John Gurdaine Wiseman Bokenam Morrice Barrow William Ryvet of Bilson Isaac Apleton Henry North Thomas Cole Richard Pepys Edmund Harvey of Wickamsith Thomas Playters Francis Bruster John Scrivener Henry North the elder Arthur Jenney Nicholas Bacon of Dennington Nathaniel Bacon of Fristow Nicholas Rivet of Drinson Nicholas Ryvet of Branston John Laney Francis Bacon William Bloys of Grundisburghe and John Clench junior Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s81">
<head>For the Towne of Ipswich</head>
<para id="p86">Unto the Bayliffes of the said Towne of Ipswich John Laney Esquire Robert Sparrowe John Sicklemore Edmund
Keene Richard Puplet Gentlemen</para>
</section>
<section id="s82">
<head>For the Borough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Edmunds Bury</head>
<para id="p87">Unto William Grigg Alderman Thomas Fletcher Esquire Robert Browne Alderman Richard Gipps &amp; John Lelham.</para>
</section>
<section id="s83">
<head>For the Towne of Aldborough</head>
<para id="p88">Unto John Bence and Richard Browne Bayliffes &amp; unto John Wall and Thomas Johnson.</para>
</section>
<section id="s84">
<head>For the Towne of Orford</head>
<para id="p89">Unto the Maior of Orford for the time being and to Daniel Herbert and Francis Burwell</para>
</section>
<section id="s85">
<head>For the Towne of Hadleigh</head>
<para id="p90">Unto the Maior for the time being Francis Bacon John Gale Thomas Allablaster and Thomas Richardson</para>
</section>
<section id="s86">
<head>For the County of Somerset</head>
<para id="p91">Unto Sir John Horner Sir Charles Berkley Sir Edward Berkley Sir Francis Doddington Sir Henry Berkley Knights John Mallet John Harrington William Wallrond Thomas Mallet Serjeant at Law George Powlett Richard Cole
Anthony Stocker William Capell John Symms William Every William Bull Robert Harbyn Thomas Bridges Francis
Hawley Edward Orange Thomas Lutterell Samuel Gorges Robert Henley William Strode of Barrington Amias Bampfeild
John Saint Albone John Hunt Edward Dyer William Hill of Pounsford Edward Weekes William Barow Senior John
Baber &amp; John Merefeild Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s87">
<head>For the City of Bath</head>
<para id="p92">Unto the Maior for the time being William Chapman Richard Chapman Robert Fisher John Biggs Aldermen</para>
</section>
<section id="s88">
<head>For the County of Sussex</head>
<para id="p93">Unto Sir Thomas Pelham Sir Thomas Bowyer Baronets Sir John Chapman Sir William Morley Sir Henry Dawtrey Sir Thomas Parker Knights Henry Garton Anthony Stapley Edward Forde Thomas Grey John Alford Thomas Milles Nicholas Wolfe Raphe Cooper Henry Goring Edward Goring Thomas May Thomas Middleton Hall Ravenscroft
William Marlott Edward Apsley William Michelborne James Rivers Harbert Morley Anthony Fowle Henry Shelley
John Ashburnham William White Harbert Hay John Baker Laurence Ashburnham Herbert Bourd John Busbridge
William Cawley Peter Furveden and Thomas Eversfeild Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s89">
<head>For the City of Chichester</head>
<para id="p94">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir William Morley Knight Robert Anderson George Greene and Henry Bellingham Esquires William Margerom Merchant Henshaw Stephen Humphreys Gent.</para>
</section>
<section id="s90">
<head>For the County of Westmerland</head>
<para id="p95">Unto Sir Philip Musgrave Baronet Sir James Bellingham Sir Richard Sandford Knight Sir Henry Bellingham Knight and Baronet Sir John Lowther Baronet Christopher Phillipson Gawen Brathwaite Allen Bellingham George Gilpin Richard Crackenthorpe Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s91">
<head>For the County of Wiltes</head>
<para id="p96">Unto Edward Lord Gorges Sir John S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Knight and Baronet Sir William Button Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Hungerford Knight of the Bath Sir Edward Bainton Sir John Earneley Sir Nevill Poole Sir Theobald Gorges Sir Henry Ludlowe Sir Walter Smith Sir John Lambe Sir George Ayloffe Sir John Evelin Sir James Thynn Knights John Glanvile Robert Hide Serjeants at Lawe Edward Seymor George Vaughan John Glanvile and Robert Hide
Serjeants at Lawe Laurence Hide Richard Goddard John Bowles Edward Tucker Francis Swanton John Sadler
Robert Drewe Edward Earnely William Bower John Toppe Thomas Moore Robert Eyre William Wallis Robert
Jennor Walter Longe John Ducket Edmund Escourt Robert Nicholas Charles Gore Thomas Hungerford Thomas
Bennet Henry Bayly Walter Norborne Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s92">
<head>For the City of New Sarum</head>
<para id="p97">Unto the Maior for the Time being Robert Hide Serjeant at Law Recorder Richard Goddard Esquire Mathew Bee Thomas Hancocke senior John Ivie James Abbot John Dove Aldermen</para>
</section>
<section id="s93">
<head>For the County of Worcester</head>
<para id="p98">Unto Sir Walter Devereaux Knight &amp; Baronet Sir John Rowse Knight Edward Dingley Edward Pitt William Jefferies of Ham Castle Philip Bruce Henry Townsend Henry Ingram John Savage John Nanfar Edward Vernon Thomas Cooke Thomas Good William Child Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s94">
<head>For the City and County of the City of Worcester</head>
<para id="p99">Unto the Maior for the time being John Cowcher Daniel Tyas Roger Gough John Hastocke John Hanbury John Nash Richard Hemming George Streete Humphrey Vernon and Francis Streete Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s95">
<head>For the Borough of Evesham</head>
<para id="p100">[To<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] the Maior of the said Borough for the time being Sir John Rowse Knight Francis Hurwell William Martin Samuel Gardiner Thomas Cresheld Gentlemen</para>
</section>
<section id="s96">
<head>For the County of Warwick</head>
<para id="p101">Unto Sir Thomas Holt Knight and Baronet Sir Peter Wentworth Knight of the Bath Sir Simon Clarke Sir Robert Fisher Baronets Sir Grevill Verney Sir Edward Underhill Sir Hercules Underhill Sir Henry Gibbs Sir Thomas Leigh Sir Francis Willoughby Sir Simon Archer and Sir George Devoreux Knights William Boughton William Combe Robert
Lee William Browne Robert Arden Richard Chamberlaine Spencer Lucy Rowley Ward [Serjeant<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] at Law Walter Chetwyn Clement Throgmorton Richard Shugborough John Lisle William Purefey James Onyon John Temple
Thomas Boughton Anthony Stoughton Robert Skelton Thomas Combe and John Fetherston Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s97">
<head>For the City of Coventrey</head>
<para id="p102">Unto the Maior for the time being Henry Million John Clarke Thomas Ward William Jessen Simon Norton JohnBarker Aldermen John Hales and Richard Greene Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s98">
<head>For the County of Anglesey and the Towne of Bewmares</head>
<para id="p103">Unto Sir Arthur Terringham Sir Thomas Holland Knights Thomas Bulkeley John Bodvel Hugh Owen de Bodeon Owen Woods William Robinson Richard Owen Henry White William Bold Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s99">
<head>For the County of Brecknock</head>
<para id="p104">Unto Sir Henry Williams Thomas Gwyn John Williams Richard Games John Walbiefe Jeoffry Jeffryes Richard Rumsey Edward Williams Meredith Lewes Roger Vaughan William Herbert Bailiffe of Brecknock William Watkins Davies Winter Lewes Meredith Hugh Meredith John Herbert Morgan Aubrey Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s100">
<head>For the County of Cardigan</head>
<para id="p105">Unto Sir Marmaduke Lloyd Knight Sir John Lewes Knight Richard Price James Lewes Henry Vaughan Even Gwynn John Stedman Thomas Price John Pugh David Evans John Phillips John Vaughan Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s101">
<head>For the County of Carmarthen</head>
<para id="p106">Unto Sir Richard Vaughan Knight of the Bath and Earle of Carbery Sir Rees Rudd Baronet Sir William Vaughan Knight Henry Jones David Guyn Richard Vaughan Rowland Gwyn Richard Phillips John Harris Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s102">
<head>For the Borough and the County of the Borough of Carmarthen</head>
<para id="p107">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir Richard Vaughan Knight of the Bath and Earle of Carbery Griffith Lewes Martin Bynon Thomas Wood Lewes Jones Thomas Jones Rowland Phillips and John Bloome Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s103">
<head>For the County of Carnarvan</head>
<para id="p108">Unto Sir Richard Wynn Knight and Baronet Sir William Williams Baronet Thomas Glyn Griffith Jones John Griffith Owen Wynn William Thomas John Owen Griffith Thomas Humphrey Jones Thomas Glynn of Nanley
William Glynn John Bodurda John Robins Thomas Maddryn William Lloyd Arthur Williams William Hookes Hugh
Griffith and Hugh Wynn Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s104">
<head>For the County of Denbye</head>
<para id="p109">Unto Sir Thomas Salisbury Baronet Sir Thomas Middleton Sir Edward Broughton Knights William Wynn Robert
Wynn Roger Holland John Lloyd Simon Theloall [Gerrard Eyton Thomas Strafford Edward Theloall<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] John Rodden
Richard Lloyd and Edward Meredith Esquires</para>
</section>
<section id="s105">
<head>For the County of Flint</head>
<para id="p110">Unto Sir Thomas Hanmer Baronet Sir Roger Moystyn [Knight<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] Sir Thomas Bruerton Sir Thomas Mostyn Knights Richard Grovesnor Thomas Ravenscroft Humphrey Dymocke Robert Davies Thomas Mostyn John Pilson John Salisbury John Eaton Robert Morgan William; Mostyn Peter Griffith Peter Evans Richard Parry &amp; Evan Edwards
Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s106">
<head>For the County of Glamorgan</head>
<para id="p111">Unto Philip Lord Herbert of Cardiffe Sir William Lewes Sir Thomas Lewes Sir Anthony Mansell Knights Edward Stradling John [Carne<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] John Oberry Nicholas Kemes Thomas Mathewes Richard Basset William Herbert of Swansey Anthony Gwyn William Harbert of Cogan Edward Thomas Thomas Lewis Thomas Carne David Evans Marmaduke Mathewes Watkin Lougher Jenkin Morgan Walter Thomas Esquires and Richard Seys Gentleman</para>
</section>
<section id="s107">
<head>For the County of Merenoth</head>
<para id="p112">Unto Sir James Price Knight William Salisbury Edmond Merick Hugh Nanny William Lewes Lewes Anwell William Wynn John Lloyd John Morgan John Lewes Lewes Nanny Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s108">
<head>For the County of Pembrooke</head>
<para id="p113">Unto Sir Richard Phillips Sir John Stepney Baronets Hugh Owen John Lawharne Thomas ap Rice Hugh Bowen Griffith White Arthur Owen Lewes Barlowe Davy Parry George Bowen and John Phillips Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s109">
<head>For the Towne and County of Haverford West</head>
<para id="p114">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir John Stepney Baronet Morrice Cannon William Maylor John Davies Gentlemen Jenkyn Howell Richard Bivans Aldermen William Bowen and Thomas Barlowe Esquires.</para>
</section>
<section id="s110">
<head>For the County of Mountgomery</head>
<para id="p115">Unto Sir John Price Baronet Sir Edward Lloyd Knight Richard Herbert Arthur Price Rowland Pughe John Blainey Edward Corbett Lloyd Peers John Price Richard Pughe Evan Glynn Edward Lloyd Thomas Morrice Thomas Owens Esquires Charles Lloyd Edward Wynne and William Ruffine Gentlemen.</para>
</section>
<section id="s111">
<head>For the County of Radnor</head>
<para id="p116">Unto William Vaughan James Price Richard Jones John Powell Rodericke Gwyn Morgan Vaughan Nicholas Meredith Hugh Lloyd Harbert Weston and Robert Williams Esquires.</para>
<para id="p117">
<emph type="i">Commission to be delivered to Commissioners before 1st O&bholigct;ober 1641; and Ten Schedules filed, and Schedules, &amp;c. of Names of Popish Recusants.; Commissioners to execute Commission, and sever themselves</emph>.</para>
<para id="p118">Which Commissions for the Payment of the said twoe Subsidies shall bee severally and respe&bholigct;ively delivered to the said Commissioners or to one of them before the first day of O&bholigct;ober in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six hundred fourty one and to every of the said Commissions ten Schedules (containing in them the tenour of this A&bholigct;) shall be affiled And for the Commissioners better discovery of Popish Recusants severall Schedules shall be delivered unto them with theire severall Commissions out of the Exchequer and Certificates from the Clerkes of the Assizes and of the Peace and other like Officers and from the Ministers and Churchwardens of every Parish of the Names of such Popish Recusants as are to be charged by this A&bholigct; by the which Commission the Commissioners in every such Commission named according to this A&bholigct; and as many of them as shall be appointed by the said Commission shall have full power and authority to put the effe&bholigct; of the said Commission in execution and that by authority of this A&bholigct; after such Commission to them delivered they may by theire assents and agreements sever themselves for the execution of theire Commission in Hundreds Lathes Wards Rapes Wapentakes Townes Parishes and other Places within the limits of the said Commission in such forme as to them shall seeme expedient to be ordered and
betweene them to be c&bhooov;muned and agreed according to the tenour and effe&bholigct; of the Commission to them therein dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
</section></section>
<section id="s112">
<head>V. Commissioners to execute A&bholigct; according to the tenor thereof.</head>
<para id="p119">
<emph type="i">Commissioners to dire&bholigct; Precepts to certain Number of Inhabitants in Hundreds, &amp;c. to appear before the Commissioners.; Persons who receive Precepts are to shew such Precepts to the other Inhabitants named therein. Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
<para id="p120">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by authority of this present Parliament that the Commissioners and every of them which are named limited and appointed according to this A&bholigct; to be Commissioners in every such Shire Ryding Lathe Wapentake Rape City Towne Borough Isle and the said Household or any other Place and none other
shall truly effe&bholigct;ually and diligently for theire parts execute the effe&bholigct; of this present A&bholigct; according to the tenour thereof in every behalfe and no otherwise by any meanes without omission favour dread malice or any other thing to be attempted or done by them or any of them to the contrary thereof And the said Commissioners or as many of
them as shall be appointed by the said Commission and none other for the execution of the said Commission and
A&bholigct; shall for the taxation of the said two Subsidies before the tenth day of O&bholigct;ober by vertue of the Commission delivered to them in forme aforesaid dire&bholigct; theire severall or joynt Precept or Precepts unto eight seaven six five four three or twoe (as for the number of Inhabitants shall be requisite) of the most substantiall discreet and honest
persons and inhabitants to be named by the said Commissioners or by as many of them as shall be appointed by
the said Commission of and in Hundreds Lathes Rapes Wapentakes Wards Parishes Townes and other Places aswell
within Liberties Franchises ancient demesne Places exempted and San&bholigct;uaries as without within the limits of the Shires Rydings Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Cities Townes Boroughs and Isle aforesaid and other Places within the Limits of
theire Commission and to the Constables Subconstables Bailiffes and other like Officers and Ministers of every of the said Hundreds Townes Rapes Wapentakes Wards Parishes and other Places aforesaid as to the said Commissioners
and every number of them or to three or twoe of them by theire discretion in division shall seeme expedient and as
by the manner and use of those parts shall be requisite straitly by the said Precept charging and commanding the
said Inhabitants Constables and other Officers aforesaid to whom such Precept shall be soe dire&bholigct;ed to appear in theire proper persons before the said Commissioners or such number of them as they shall divide themselves according to
the tenour of the said Commission at certaine dayes and places by the said Commissioners or any such number of
them as is aforesaid within Cities Boroughs or Townes Corporate or without in any other place as is aforesaid by
theire discretion to be limited thereunto to doe and accomplish all that to them on the parte of the Kings Majestie
shall be enjoyned touching this A&bholigct; commaunding further by the said Precept that he to whose hands such precept
shall come shall shew and deliver the same to the other Inhabitants or Officers named in the said Precept and that
none of them faile to accomplish the same upon paine of forty shillings to be forfeited to the Kings Majestie</para>
</section>
<section id="s113">
<head>VI. Persons named in Precept to appear before Commissioners.</head>
<para id="p121">
<emph type="i">Such Persons making Default, or refusing to serve.; Penalty 40s.; Upon Appearance charged to make Enquiry into the Substance of Persons to be charged; but such Enquiry not to be taken on Oath, and to certify before Commissioners.; Penalty &pound;5.; Thereupon Commissioners to read the Rates openly.; Afterwards another Day appointed by Commissioners for such Persons to appear.; Not appearing.; Penalty 40s.; or refusing to make Certificate.; Penalty 40s.; Commissioners to examine Presenters of Certificate.; Further Proceedings on Assessments by Precepts to Constables, &amp;c. to warn Persons named therein to appear.; Oath not allowed on Inquiry into the Substance of Persons charged.; Persons named in the said Precept called upon not appearing,; Penalty, Double Rate.; On Inquiry into the Substance of Persons charged Commissioners may increase Taxation.; Spiritual Persons how rated for Temporal Possessions</emph>.</para>
<para id="p122">And it is further ordained by the authority of this present Parliament that att the said day and place prefixed and limited in the said Precept every of the said Commissioners then being in the Shire and not having sufficient excuse for his absence at the day and place prefixed for that part whereunto he was limited shall appeare in his owne proper
person and there the same Commissioners being present or as many of them as shall be appointed by the Kings
Majesties Commission shall call or cause be called before them the said Inhabitants and Officers to whom they have
dire&bholigct;ed theire said Precepts and which had in commaundment there to appeare by vertue of the said Precept and if
any person soe warned make default unlesse he then bee letted by sicknesse or lawfull excuse and that let be then
witnessed by the oathes of two credible persons or if any appearing refuse to serve in forme following then every such
person soe making default or refusing to serve shall forfeite [to<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] the Kings Majestie forty-shillings and upon the same appearance had they shall be charged before the Commissioners by all convenient wayes and meanes other then by corporall Oath to enquire of the value of the substance after the usuall manner of every person dwelling and
abiding within the limits of the places that they shall be charged with and of others which shall have his or theire
most resort unto any of the said places and chargeable with any Sum of Money by this A&bholigct; of the said Subsidies
and all other thinges requisite touching the said A&bholigct; &amp; according to the intent of the same and thereupon as neere as it may bee or shall come to theire knowledge without respe&bholigct; of any former taxation heretofore had truly to present and certifie before the said Commissioners the names and sirnames and the substance and value of every of them
after the usuall manner as aforesaid aswell of Lands Tenements and other Hereditaments Possessions and Proffits as
of Goods Chattels Debts and other things chargeable by the same A&bholigct; without any concealment love favour affe&bholigct;ion dread or malice upon paine of forfeiture of five pounds at the most to be taxed extra&bholigct;ed and leavied in forme as hereafter in this present A&bholigct; shall be limited or appointed And thereupon the said Commissioners shall openly there read or cause to be read unto them the said rates in this A&bholigct; mentioned and openly declare the effe&bholigct; of theire Charge unto them in what manner and form they ought and should make theire Certificates according to the rates and s&bhouov;ms thereof abovesaid and of all manner of persons aswell Aliens and Strangers Denizens or not Denizens inhabiting within this Realme as of such Popish Recusants and other persons as be borne under the Kings obeysance chargeable to this A&bholigct; and of the Possessions Goods and Chattels of Fraternities Guilds Corporations Brotherhoods Mysteries C&bhooov;munalties and other as is abovesaid and of persons being in the parts beyond the Seas having goods and chattels Lands or Tenements within this Realme as is aforesaid and of all goods being in the custody of any person or persons to the use of any other as is abovesaid by the which information and shewing the said persons may have
such plaine knowledge of the true intent of this present A&bholigct; and of the manner of theire Certificate that the same
persons shall have noe reasonable cause to excuse them by ignorance And after such charge and the Statute of the
said two Subsidies and the manner of the said Certificate to be made in writing conteyning the names &amp; surnames of
every person and whether he be borne without the Kings Dominions or within and the value of every person in every
degree aswell of the yearely value of Lands and Tenements and of such like possessions and profits as of the value
of Goods and Chattels Debts and every thing to theire Certificate requisite and necessary to them declared the said
Commissioners there being shall by theire discretions limit and appoint unto the said persons another day and place
to appeare before the said Commissioners and charging the said persons that they shall in the mean time make diligent
enquiry by all wayes and meanes of the premisses and then and there every of them upon paine of forfeiture of
fourty Shillings to the Kings Majestie to appeare att the [said<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] next &bhopcrl;fixed day and place there to certifie unto the said Commissioners in writing according to theire said Charge and according to the true intent of the said grant of Subsidies and as to them in manner aforesaid hath beene declared and shewed by the Commissioners. At which day and place soe to them prefixed if any of the said persons make default or appeare and refuse to make the said Certificate
then every of them soe offending to forfeite to the Kings Majestie fourty Shillings (except there be a reasonable
excuse of his default by reason of his sicknesse or otherwise by the oathes of twoe credible persons there witnessed)
and of such as appeare ready to make Certificate as is aforesaid the said Commissioners there being shall take and
receive the same Certificate and every parte thereof and the names values and substance of every person soe certified
And if the said Commissioners see cause reasonable they shall examine the said Presenters thereof and thereupon
the said Commissioners at the said dayes and places by theire Agreement amongst themselves shall from time' to
time there openly &bhopcrl;fix a day att a certaine place or places within the limits of theire C&bhooov;mission by theire discretion for theire further proceeding to the said assessing of the same Subsidies. And thereupon att the said day of the
said Certificate as is aforesaid taken the same Commissioners shall make theire precept or precepts to the Constables
Subconstables Bailiffes or other Officers of such Hundreds Wapentakes Townes or other places aforesaid as the
same Commissioners shall be of comprising and conteyning in the said Precepts the Names and Surnames of all
persons presented before them in the said Certificate of whom if the said Commissioners or any of them as shall be thereunto appointed by the Kings Commission shall then have vehement suspe&bholigct; to be of more greater value or Substance in Lands Goods Chattels or S&bhouov;ms of Money owing unto. them or other Substance aforesaid then is upon such person or persons soe certified and specified as aforesaid the same Commissioners shall make theire precept or precepts dire&bholigct;ed to the Constables Bailiffes or other Officers commanding them to whom such Precepts shall be dire&bholigct;ed to warn such persons whose names shall be comprised in the said Precepts at theire Mansions or to theire persons that the same persons named in such Precepts and every of them shall personally appeare before the said Commissioners att the said new &bhopcrl;fixed day and place there to be examined by all wayes and meanes (other then by Corporall Oath) by the said Commissioners of theire substance and value in manner as aforesaid and of all and
every S&bhouov;ms of Money owing to them and other whatsoever matter concerning the premisses or any of them acording
to this A&bholigct; att which day and place soe prefixed the said Commissioners then and there being or as many of them
as shall be thereunto appointed by the Kings Commission shall cause to be called the said persons whose names
shall be comprised in the said Precept as is aforesaid for theire examination And if any of those persons which shall
be warned as aforesaid to be examined which at any time after the warning and before the day &bhopcrl;fixed shall be
within such place as he may [have<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] knowledge of his said appearance to be made shall make default and appeare not unlesse a reasonable cause or excuse by the Oathes of twoe credible witnesses before the said Commissioners be truly alleadged for his discharge that then every of them soe making default to be taxed &amp; charged with and att the double Sum of the rate that he should or ought to. have beene sett att for and after the value aforesaid of his Lands or Substance upon him certified if he had appeared by the discretion of the Commissioners there being which
Commissioners shall travell with every of the other persons soe then and there appearing whose names shall be
expressed in the said Precept or Precepts and in whom any vehement suspition was or shall be had in forme aforesaid
by all wayes &amp; meanes they can (other then by corporall Oath) for theire better knowledge of theire value as
aforesaid either in Hereditaments or Possessions or else in Goods or Debts and thereupon shall have power and
authority by virtue of this A&bholigct; according to theire discretions to inlarge and increase the taxation of such persons
as they shall soe finde by due examination to be of greater value or substance in Lands or Goods then they were
presented att And that every Spirituall person at every of the said taxations of the said Subsidies shall be rated and
set according to the rate abovesaid of and for every pound that the same Spirituall person or any other to his
use hath by descent bargain or purchase in Feesimple or Feetail terme of life terme of yeares by execution
wardshipp or Copy of Court Roll in any Mannors Lands Tenements Rents Services Offices Fees Corrodies Annuities
and Hereditaments after the true just and yearely value thereof and according as other the Kings Majesties
Subje&bholigct;s borne within this Realme be charged in forme above remembred soe the same extend to the yearely value
of twenty Shillings or above.</para>
</section>
<section id="s114">
<head>VII. Assessors misbehaving,</head>
<para id="p123">
<emph type="i">Commissioners may set a Fine upon them.; Certified and levied as other Subsidies.; Remedy for Persons aggrieved by the Assessment.; Commissioners may abate-or increase Assessment.; False Oath of Value of Lands, &amp;c.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p124">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed that if the said Taxers or Assessors shall not duely behave themselves in the inquiry taxation assessement or Certificate but shall affe&bholigct;ionately corruptly or partially demeasne themselves in that behalfe in such wise that the Commissioners shall by theire Considerations deeme them Offenders worthy of punishment for not doeing theire duties therein that then foure or more of the Commissioners in that County for the said two Subsidies shall have power and authority in theire discretions either to charge the said Assessors upon theire Corporall Oathes for the better Service aforesaid in that behalfe or else by theire discretion to tax and set upon the said Assessors for
theire misdemeanors in that behalfe such a fine or pain as they shall thinke good soe that it exceed not the Sum of
Ten Pounds and the same Fine or Pain at theire discretions to certifie to the Persons nominated as aforesaid every
which fine soe taxed and set by foure of the said Commissioners or more and being certified with the Schedule and
Bookes of that limit shall be leavied and answeared in like manner and forme to all intents and purposes as any
other Sums that shall be taxed and become due by vertue of this Statute and A&bholigct; of Subsidie and not in any other
wise or manner And if any person certified or rated by vertue of this A&bholigct; whether hee bee a Commissioner or other
to any manner of value doth find himselfe greived with the same presentment sessing or rating and thereupon complain
to the Commissioners before whom he shall be called sessed or taxed or before twoe of them before the same taxation
be certified into the Court of Exchequer that then the said Commissioners or twoe of them shall by all wayes and
meanes examine particularly and distin&bholigct;ly the person soe complaining upon his Oath and other his Neighbours by
theire discretions of every his Lands and Tenements above specified and of every his Goods Chattels and Debts above
mentioned and after due examination and perfe&bholigct; knowledge thereof had and perceived by the said Commissioners
or twoe of them which shall have power by authority aforesaid the said Commissioners or any twoe of them to
whom any such complaint shall be made by theire discretions upon the oath of the said person soe complaining
may abate defaulk increase or inlarge the said Assessments according as it shall appeare unto them just upon the
same examination and the same S&bhouov;m soe abated defaulked increased or inlarged shall be by them certified in forme
as is hereafter specified and if it be proved by witnesses or by the parties owne confession or other lawfull wayes or
meanes within a Yeare after any such Oath made that the same person soe rated and sworne was of any better or
greater value in Lands Goods or other things above specified att the time of his said Oath [then the same person so
sworn did declare upon his said Oath<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] that then every such person soe offending shall loose and forfeit to the Kings Majestie soe much lawfull money of England as he the same person soe sworne was sett at or taxed to pay.</para>
</section>
<section id="s115">
<head>VIII. Commissioners to be rated at such Place where they shall be Commissioners; other Persons where they have resided for the most Part of the preceding Year.</head>
<para id="p125">
<emph type="i">Absentees assessed where last abiding.; Rate to be according to the Substance of Persons liable.; Remedy for Commissioners and other Persons taxed in any Place other than where they are Commissioners or were resiant for most Part of the preceding Year.; Fee for Allowance</emph>.</para>
<para id="p126">And alsoe it is ena&bholigct;ed by the same authority that every person to be rated and taxed as is aforesaid shall be rated and set and the S&bhouov;m on him set to be levied at such place where he and his family were resident for the most part of the Yeare next before the presentment and taxation made and noe where else and that noe Commissioner for his Subsidie shall be taxed or rated for his Goods or Lands but in the Shire or other place where he shall be
Commissioner and that if any person chargeable by this A&bholigct; att the time of the said assessings happen to be out of
this Realme and out of Wales or far from the place where he shall be knowne then he to be set where he was last abiding in this Realme or in Wales and after the substance value and other profits of every person to be knowne by examination certificate or other manner of way as is aforesaid and that every person taxed in any County or Place other then where he or his family were resiant for the most parte of the Yeare then next before or in any
County or Place other then where he is Commissioner for the Subsidies if he be a Commissioner upon Certificate
made to the said Court of Exchequer under the hands &amp; seales of twoe Commissioners for the same Subsidie in the
same County or place where such person and his family were resiant for the most part of the Yeare then next before
or where he is a Commissioner for the taxation &amp; payment of the same Subsidy testifying his most resiance having a
family or being a Commissioner shall be a sufficient discharge for the taxation of that person in any other places and
of and for all other S&bhouov;ms of Money upon such persons soe set and taxed save only the taxations made in that
County or place from which such Certificate shall be made as is aforesaid and for the Sums of Money upon such
person there assessed or taxed and that such Certificate without any Plea or other Circumstance shall be a sufficient
Warrant aswell to the Barons and Auditors of that said Court of Exchequer as to all and every other Officers to
whom the Allowance thereof shall appertaine paying for such discharge and allowance onely six pence and noe more.</para>
</section>
<section id="s116">
<head>IX. Double Charges not to be allowed.</head>
<para id="p127">
<emph type="i">Remedy in respe&bholigct; of Double Charges</emph>.</para>
<para id="p128">Provided alwaies that every such person that shall be rated or taxed according to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; for paying of and to the said twoe Subsidies for and after the yearely value of his Lands Tenements or other reall possessions or profits at any of the said taxations shall not after be set and rated for his goods and chattels or other moveable substance at the same taxation and that he that shall be set charged or taxed for the same Subsidy for his Goods Chattels and other moveables at any of the said taxations according to the true meaneing of this A&bholigct; shall not after be taxed charged or chargeable for his Lands or other reall possessions or proffits aforesaid nor that any person by any taxation be doubly charged for the said (<ref idref="n29">29</ref>) Subsidies nor set or rated at severall places by reason of this A&bholigct; any thing contained in this present A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s117">
<head>X. Proviso for Persons having two Mansions, or being Houshold Servants or Waiting Servants to the King or others.</head>
<para id="p129">
<emph type="i">Persons unduly escaping Taxation,; on Proof thereof before Commissioners or Barons of the Exchequer,; taxed at Treble Value</emph>.</para>
<para id="p130">And be it ordained and ena&bholigct;ed by the authority of this present parliament that no person having twoe Mansions or two places to resort unto or calling himselfe household Servant or waiting Servant to the Kings Majestie or other Lord or Lady Master or Mistres be excused upon his saying from the taxes of the said two Subsidies in neither of the places where he may be set or taxed unlesse he bring a Certificate in writing from the Commissioners where he is [to<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] set or taxed indeed at one place and if any person that ought to be set and taxed to these two present Subsidies by reason of his removeing or resorting to two places or by reason of his saying that he was else where taxed or by reason of any priviledge of his dwelling or abiding in any place not being foreprised in this A&bholigct; or otherwise by his covin or craft or by any words or sayings or otherwise or if any that is a Commissioner or Assessor of others
happen to escape from the said taxations for the payment of the said twoe Subsidies or either of them and be not
set and taxed according to the true intent of this A&bholigct; and that proved by presentment examination information or
otherwise before the said Commissioners or twoe of them or before the Barons of the Kings Majesties Exchequer or
two Justices of Peace of that County where such person dwelleth then every such person that by such meanes or
otherwayes willingly by covin or without just cause shall happen to escape from the said taxations or payments
aforesaid or any of them and shall [not<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] be rated taxed and set shall be charged upon the knowledge and proofe thereof with and att the triple value of soe much as he should might or ought to have beene sett or taxed at by vertue of this A&bholigct; and the same triple value to be leavyed gathered and paid of his Goods and Chattels Lands
and Tenements towards the said Subsidies.</para>
</section>
<section id="s118">
<head>XI. The Power of Commissioners to tax other Commissioners, and also Assessors.</head>
<para id="p131">
<emph type="i">Barons and Persons of higher Estate taxed by the Lord Privy Seal, the Earl Marshall, and others.; Rate estreated and certified</emph>.</para>
<para id="p132">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said Commissioners in every Commission which shall be or inhabite in any County or Place within the limits of theire Commission or the more parte of them shall have full power and authority by this A&bholigct; to set tax and [sesse<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] every other Commissioner joyned with them in every such Commission and the said Commissioners within theire division shall alsoe assesse every Assessor within theire division for his or theire Goods Lands and other the premisses as aforesaid by which said Commission the Commissioners to whom it shall appertain shall indifferently set taxe and assesse themselves and the said Assessors and that aswell the Sums upon every of the said Commissioners and Assessors soe assessed rated and taxed as the Sums made and presented by the presentors as abovesaid shall be written certified set and estreated and the Estreats thereof to be made with other the inhabitants of that part and within the limits of the same Commission and division soe to be gathered and leavied in like manner as it ought and should have beene if the said Commissioners had not beene in
the said Commission And that all persons of the Estate of a Baron or Baronesse and every Estate above shall be charged
with theire freehold and value as is aforesaid by Henry Earle of Manchester Lord Privie Seale Thomas Earle of
Arundell and Surrey Earle Marshall of England Philip Earle of Pembroke and Montgomery Lord Chamberlain of
His Majesties Household Henry Earle of Bathe Thomas Earle of Southampton Robert Earle of Essex Edward Earle
of Dorset William Earle of Salisbury Robert Earle of Warwick Oliver Earle of Bullingbrooke Thomas Earle of
Berks Henry Earle of Dover Henry Earle of Stamford William Lord Viscount Say and Seale Mountague Lord
Willoughby de Er. Francis Lord Dacres Ferdinando Lord Hastings Philip Lord Wharton Edward Lord Mountague
Charles Lord Howard de Char. William Lord Grey de Warke John Lord Roberts John Lord Pawlet &amp; George
Lord Goring or any eleaven of them or more for the payment of the said two Subsidies after the forme of the said
Grant according to the taxation aforesaid and the S&bhouov;ms of and upon them to be taxed and set with the names of
the Colle&bholigct;ors which Colle&bholigct;ors shall be appointed by the Lord Chancellour or Lord Keeper of the Great Seale
for the time being for gathering and paying of the same to be estreated delivered and certified at the dayes and
places above specified by the said Henry Earle of Manchester Lord Privie Seale Thomas Earle of Arundell and Surrey
Earle Marshall of England Philip Earle of Pembroke and Montgomery Lord Chamberlaine of His Majesties Household
Henry Earle of Bathe Thomas Earle of Southampton Robert Earle of Essex Edward Earle of Dorset William Earle
of Salisbury Robert Earle of Warwicke Oliver Earle of Bullingbrooke Thomas Earle of Berks Henry Earle of
Dover Henry Earle of Stamford William Lord Viscount Say and Seale Mountague Lord Willoughby de Er. Francis
Lord Dacres Ferdinando Lord Hastings Philip Lord Wharton Ed. Lord Mountague Charles Lord Howard de
Char. William Lord Grey de Warke John Lord Roberts John Lord Paulet and George Lord Goring or any eleaven
of them and more.</para>
</section>
<section id="s119">
<head>XII. Rates estreated under the Seal and Sign Manual of the Commissioners, and Estrent delivered to sufficient Inhabitants, &amp;c. of Hundreds, &amp;c.</head>
<para id="p133">
<emph type="i">By virtue of Estreat Officers, &amp;c. to levy Rate.; Distress.; If Rate not paid in Eight Days, then Distress appraised and sold for Payment of Rate, Overplus to the Owner.; Officers, &amp;c. to answer for the Portion limited to them, only</emph>.</para>
<para id="p134">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that after the taxes and assesses of the said Summes upon and by the said Assessing &amp; Certificate as is aforesaid made the said Commissioners or as many of them as shall be thereunto appointed and have authority by the Kings Majesties Commission shall with all speed and without delay by theire writing estreat the said taxes thereof under the Seales and Signes Manuall of the said Commissioners or as many of them as shall be appointed at the least and the same shall deliver into sufficient and substantiall Inhabitants
Constables Subconstables Bayliffes and other Officers jointly of Hundreds Townes Parishes and other places aforesaid within theire Limits and to other sufficient persons inhabitants of the same onely by the discretion of the said Commissioners with the Assent of the High Colle&bholigct;ors and as the place and parties shall require as well the particular names and sirnames as the remembrance of all Sums of Money taxed and set of and upon every person as well Man as Woman chargeable by this A&bholigct; Householders and all other Inhabitants and dwellers within the said Parishes
Townes and Places contributary to this A&bholigct; of Subsidies by authority of which writing and Estreat soe delivered the said Officers and other persons soe named and deputed severally shall have full power and authority by vertue of this A&bholigct; immediately after the delivery of the said Writing of Estreat to demaund levie and gather of every person therein specified the Summe and Summes in the same Writing or Estreat comprised and for non payment thereof to distreine the same person or persons soe being behinde by theire Goods and Chattels and the distresse soe taken to keepe by the space of eight dayes at the Costs and Charges of the owner thereof and if the said Owner doe
not pay such S&bhouov;me of money as shall be taxed upon him or her by authority of this A&bholigct; within the same eight dayes then the same distresse to be apprised by foure three or two of the Inhabitants where such distresse is taken and alsoe then to be sold by the Constable or other Colle&bholigct;or for the payment of the said Money and the overplus coming by the sale (if any be) over and above the charge of keeping the said distresse to bee immediately restored to the Owner thereof which said Officers and other persons soe deputed to aske take gather and levie the said S&bhouov;ms shall answeare and be charged for the portion onely to them assigned &amp; limited to be gathered levied and comprised in the said Writing or Estreat soe to them as aforesaid delivered to the persons and uses in this A&bholigct; expressed and the said Summe in that writing or estreat to be comprised to pay unto the high Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors
of that place in manner and forme underwritten thereunto to be named and deputed.</para>
</section>
<section id="s120">
<head>XIII. Commissioners to appoint Colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
<para id="p135">
<emph type="i"> Qualification,; to be High Colle&bholigct;ors.; Commissioners to deliver Estreats under their Seals and Sign Manual to Colle&bholigct;ors.; Colle&bholigct;ors to answer the Sums comprised in Estreat</emph>.</para>
<para id="p136">And further be it ena&bholigct;ed by the said authority that such of the said Commissioners or the more parte of them as shall take upon them the execution and busines of the said Commission shall for the payment of the said Subsidies
name such sufficient and able persons which then shall have and possesse Lands or other Hereditaments in theire owne right of the cleare yearely value of fourty pounds or goods to the value of foure hundred pounds at the least as he shall be taxed in the Subsidie Booke (if any such be in the said limits) and for want such soe assessed then those to be appointed Colle&bholigct;ors that then shall be sufficient and rated and taxed in the Subsidy bookes in Lands and Goods neerest to the Values aforesaid as by theire discretions shall be thought good in Shires Ridings Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Cities Townes Corporate and other whatsoever places as well within places priviledged as without (not being foreprised in this A&bholigct;) to be high Colle&bholigct;ors and to have the Colle&bholigct;ion and receipt of the said Sums set and leviable within the Precin&bholigct;s Limits and Bounds where they shall be soe limited and appointed to be high Colle&bholigct;ors and to every of the said Colle&bholigct;ors soe severally named the said Commissioners or twoe of them att the least with all speed and without delay after the said twoe Subsidies be set by all the limits of the same theire Commission or in such limits as the high Colle&bholigct;ors shall be soe severally assigned shall under theire Seales and Signes Manuall deliver one Estreat indented in parchment comprising in it the names of all such persons as were assigned to levy the said particular S&bhouov;ms of every Hundred and Wapentake Towne or other place aforesaid with the names and Sirnames of the persons soe chargeable according to the Estreat soe hereof first made and delivered as is aforesaid and the Colle&bholigct;ors to be assigned shall be charged to answeare the whole Sum comprised in the said Estreat limited to his Colle&bholigct;ion as is aforesaid.</para>
</section>
<section id="s121">
<head>XIV. Commissioners to take Recognizances of High Colle&bholigct;ors, without Fee.</head>
<para id="p137">
<emph type="i">Condition of Recognizance.; Commissioners to certify Recognizances, &amp;c. into the Exchequer.; Penalty &pound;10.; Colle&bholigct;or not making Recognizance; Penalty &pound;20.; Exchequer to cancel Recognizances on Payment of Colle&bholigct;ion into Exchequer without Fee.; Colle&bholigct;or may appoint Days and Places for Payment of Colle&bholigct;ion.; Assessors, &amp;c. not paying Colle&bholigct;ion to High Colle&bholigct;ors,; with Allowance of 1d. in the Pound of Colle&bholigct;ion.; Distress.; Proceeding thereon</emph>.</para>
<para id="p138">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said Commissioners haveing authority by this A&bholigct; to nominate the high Colle&bholigct;ors of the said two Subsidies shall immediately upon that nomination and ele&bholigct;ion take by authority of this present Parliament sufficient Recognizances or Obligations without any Fee or Reward to be paid therefore of every person soe by them to be named to be high Colle&bholigct;ors to be bound to the
Kings Majestie in the double Sum of the Sum of his Colle&bholigct;ion and to be indorsed and made upon such condi&bhocotil;n that is to say for the due colle&bholigct;ions and payment of the said twoe Subsidies that if the said Colle&bholigct;or his Heires or
Executors doe truly content and pay to the persons aforesaid at the place aforesaid at or before the last day of February which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God 1641 soe much of the said S&bhouov;me of money allotted and appointed to his Colle&bholigct;ion that he shall colle&bholigct; and gather and content and pay the residue of his Colle&bholigct;ion and charge within one Moneth next after such time as he hath colle&bholigct;ed and gathered the same residue that then the same Recognizance or Obligation to be void Which said Recognizances or Obliga&bhocotil;ns soe to be taken the said Commissioners shall severally certifie and deliver into His Majesties Court of Exchequer with the severall Certificates of the said taxations and rates of the payment of the said Subsidies at and by the time to them prescribed and appointed by this A&bholigct; for the certificate of the said taxations of the said Subsidies upon paine of forfeiture of Tenn pounds to the Kings Majestie for every Recognizance or Obliga&bhocotil;n not soe certified And that every such Colle&bholigct;or soe named and chosen upon request to him made shall acknowledge and make the said Recognizance or Obliga&bhocotil;n
upon paine of forfeiture of Twenty pounds to the Kings Majestie for the refusall thereof And that the Treasurer and Barons of the Exchequer for the time being upon payment of the said severall Colle&bholigct;ions of the said twoe Subsidies
att the day and time herein limited for the payment hereof shall cancell and deliver the Recognizances or Obliga&bhocotil;ns for the payment thereof to the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors without any other Warrant and without any Fee or Reward
to bee paid for the same to any person and every Colle&bholigct;or soe deputed having the said Estreat in parchment as is aforesaid shall have authority by this A&bholigct; to appoint dayes and places within the circuit of his Colle&bholigct;ion for the payment
of the said twoe Subsidies to him to be made and thereof to give warning by proclamation or otherwise to all the Constables or other persons or inhabitants having the charge of the particular Colle&bholigct;ion within the Hundreds Parishes Townes or other Places by him or them limited to make payment of the said particular Colle&bholigct;ion of every S&bhouov;me as to them shall appertaine and if att the same day and place soe limited and prefixed by the said high Colle&bholigct;or the said Constable Officers or other Persons or Inhabitants as is aforesaid for the said particular Colle&bholigct;ion assigned.
and appointed within such Hundred City Towne or other Place doe not pay unto the said high Colle&bholigct;or the S&bhouov;me within theire severall Hundreds Townes Parishes and other places due and comprised in the said Estreat thereof to them delivered by the said C&bhooov;mission[er]s or some of them as is aforesaid or soe much thereof as they have by any meanes received (one penny for every pound for the said particular colle&bholigct;ion as is aforesaid alwaies thereof to be allowed excepted and abated) that then it shall be lawfull for the said High Colle&bholigct;ors and every of them &amp; for
theire Assignes to distrain every of the said Constables Officers and other Inhabitants for theire said severall and particular colle&bholigct;ion of the said S&bhouov;ms comprised in the said Estreat and writing thereof to them and every of them as is before expressed delivered or for soe much of the same S&bhouov;me as shall then soe happen to be gathered and leavied and behinde and unpaid by the Goods and Chattels of every of them soe being behinde and the distresse soe taken to be kept and apprised and sold as is aforesaid and thereof to take and leavie the S&bhouov;ms soe then being.
behinde &amp; unpaid and the overplus comeing of the Sale of the said distresse (if any be) to be restored and delivered unto the Owner in form above remembred.</para>
</section>
<section id="s122">
<head>XV. Persons living in Cities, &amp;c. not to be appointed Colle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. out of them.</head>
<para id="p139">Provided alwaies that no person inhabiting in any City Borough or Towne Corporate shall be compelled to be any Assessor or Colle&bholigct;or of or for any part of the said Subsidies in any place or places out of the said City Borough
or Towne Corporate where he dwelleth.</para>
</section>
<section id="s123">
<head>XVI. Assessors, Attornies, Fa&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. after being charged with Receipt of Assessment dying or removing or concealing their Goods, or when Monies comprized in Estreat cannot be levied by Distress.</head>
<para id="p140">
<emph type="i">or where Distress cannot be sold,; Colle&bholigct;or, &amp;c. discharged, and Process out of the Exchequer, and the Commissioners may dire&bholigct; Precepts to Officer to levy such Money; Who may distrain.; Distress kept, or appraised and sold.; If Distress taken out of Limits assigned, Allowance.; Persons charged discharged by Distress.; Persons distrained having no Lands, &amp;c.; Proceedings.; Imprisonment until Sums due, and also Fee for Arrest, paid.; Officer not executing Process.; Penalty 20s.; Gaoler suffering Escape.; Penalty 40s.; and double Value of Rate and Fees.; Like Process for Subsidies due by any Persons charged for another unpaid.; In Default of Payment,; Imprisonment.; Certificate by Commissioners.; Colle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. disobeying Commissioners,; or Persons suspe&bholigct;ed to be not indifferently taxed, refusing to appear or be examined, or resisting, &amp;c.; Penalty 40s. or under, at Discretion of Commissioners.; Commissioners may punish by Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
<para id="p141">And it is alsoe by the said Authority ena&bholigct;ed that if any Inhabitants or Officers or whatsoever other person or persons charged to and for the Colle&bholigct;ion and receipt of any part or portion of the said two Subsidies by any manner of meanes according to this A&bholigct; or any person or persons for themselves or as Keeper Guardian Deputy Fa&bholigct;or or Atturney of or for any other person or persons for any Goods or Chattels of the Owner thereof att the time of the
said assessing to bee paid being out of this Realme or in any other parts not knowne or of or for the Goods and Chattels of any other person or persons of any Corporation Fraternity Mystery or other whatsoever Communalty being Corporate or not Corporate and all persons having in theire rule governance and custody any Goods or Chattels att the time of the said assessing to be made or which for any cause for or by colle&bholigct;ion or for himselfe or for any other or by reason hee hath any rule governance or custody of any Goods or Chattels of any other person or persons Corporation Communalty Fraternity Guild or Mystery or any such other like or as Fa&bholigct;or Deputy
or Atturney of or for any person shall be taxed valued rated and set to any S&bhouov;me or S&bhouov;mes by reason of this A&bholigct; and if after the taxation and assessing upon any such person or persons as shall be charged with the receipt of the same happen to dye or depart from the place where he was soe taxed and sett or his Goods or Chattels to be soe eloyned or in such privy or covert manner kept as the same person or persons charged with the same by Estreats or other Writings from the said Commissioners or as many of them as shall be thereunto appointed by the said Commission as is aforesaid can ne may leavy the same Sum and Sums comprised within the same Estreate by
distresse within the limits of theire Colle&bholigct;ion as is aforesaid or cannot sell such distresse or distresses as be taken for any of the said payments before the time limited to the high Colle&bholigct;or for his payment to be made as [is<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] aforesaid then upon rela&bhocotil;n thereof with due examina&bhocotil;n by the oath or examination of such person or persons as shall be charged with and for the receipt and colle&bholigct;ion of the same before the said Commissioners or as many of them as
by the same Commission shall be thereunto appointed where such person or persons or other as is aforesaid theire Goods and Chattels were set and taxed and upon plaine Certificate thereof made by the same Commissioners as well of the dwelling place names and S&bhouov;mes of the said persons of whom the said S&bhouov;mes cannot be leavied and had as is aforesaid then as well the Constable and other Inhabitants appointed for the same particular colle&bholigct;ion against the high Colle&bholigct;our as the high Colle&bholigct;or upon his account and oath in the said Exchequer to be discharged thereof and Processe to bee made in the Kings Majesties name out of the same Exchequer by the discretion of the Barons of the same Exchequer against such person his heires or executors soe being behinde with his payment And over that the same Commissioners to whom any such declaration of the premisses shall be made in form aforesaid from time to time shall have full power and authority to dire&bholigct; theire precept or precepts to the said person or persons charged with any Sum of for and upon any such person and persons or other as is aforesaid or to any Sheriffe Steward Bayliffe or other whatsoever Officer Minister Person or Persons of such Place or Places where any such
person or persons soe owing any such Sum or Sums shall have Lands or Tenements and other Hereditaments or reall Possessions Goods and Chattels whereby any such person or persons soe indebted his heires executors or assignes or other having the Custody Governance or disposition of any goods or Chattells Lands Tenements or other
Hereditaments which ought or may by this A&bholigct; be lawfully distreined or taken for the same hath and shall have Goods Chattels Lands Tenements or other Possessions whereof such Sum and Sums which by any such person or persons may or ought to be leavied be it within the limits of such Commission where such person or persons was or
were taxed or without in any place within this Realm of England Wales or other the Kings Majesties Dominions Marches or Territories by which Precept as well such person or persons shall be charged to leavy such Money as the Officer of the place or places where such [distresses<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] may be taken shall have full power and authority to distrein every such person indebted charged or chargeable by this A&bholigct; or his Executors or Administrators of his Goods
and Chattels his Guardians Fa&bholigct;ors Deputies Lessees Farmours and Assignes and all other persons by whose hands or out of whose Lands any such person should have fee rent annuity or other profit or which att the time of the said assessing shall have Goods or chattels or any other thinge moveable of any such person or persons being indebted or owing such S&bhouov;me and the distresses soe taken cause to be kept appraised and sold in like manner and forme as is aforesaid for the distresse to be taken upon such persons to be taxed to the said two Subsidies and being sufficient to distrein within the limits of the Colle&bholigct;ors (<ref idref="n35">35</ref>) Inhabitants or other Officers charged with or for the said S&bhouov;mes soe upon them to be taxed And if any such distresse for non payment happen to be taken out of the limit of the said persons charged and assigned to leavy the said persons soe charged for the leavying of any such
Summes by distresse shall perceive and take of the same distresse for the labour of every person goeing for the execution thereof for every mile that every person soe laboureth for the same twoe pence And every farmour guardian tenant fa&bholigct;or or other whatsoever person being distreined or other person charged for payment of any such Sum
or S&bhouov;ms or any other Summe by reason of this A&bholigct; shall be of such S&bhouov;m or S&bhouov;ms of him or them soe levied and
taken discharged and acquitted at [this<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] day of payment for the same or att the delivery of such Goods and Chattels
as he that is soe distreined had in his Custody or governance against him or them that shall be soe taxed and set (any Grant or Writing Obligatory or other whatsoever matter to the contrary made heretofore notwithstanding) and if any such person should be soe distreined have noe Lands or Tenements sufficient whereby he and his tenants and farmours may be distreined or have aliened eloyned or hath his goods and chattels whereby he should or might be distreined in such manner that such goods or chattels cannot be knowne or found soe that the s&bhouov;me of or by him to bee
paid in the said forme shall not neither can be conveniently levied then upon relation thereof to the Commissioners or to as many of them as by the said Commission shall be thereunto appointed where such person or persons was
taxed and set by the oathes of him or them that shall be charged with the leavying and payment of that S&bhouov;me or Summes the same C&bhooov;missioners shall make a precept in such manner as is aforesaid for to attach take and arrest the body of such person or persons that ought to pay the said S&bhouov;mes And by this A&bholigct; shall be charged with and for the said Sum and Sums and them soe taken safely to keepe in prison within the Shire or other place where any such person or persons shall be taken and attached there to remaine without baile or mainprise untill he have paid the said S&bhouov;m or Sums that such person for himselfe or for any other by this A&bholigct; shall bee chargeable or ought to be charged withall and alsoe for the fees of every such Arrest to him or them that shall execute such Precept twentie pence And that every Officer unto whom such precept shall be dire&bholigct;ed doe his true diligence and execute
the same upon every person soe being indebted upon pain to forfeit to the Kings Majestie for every default in that behalfe twentie shillings And that no keeper of any Gaole from his Gaole suffer any person to goe at large by letting to baile or otherwise to depart out of his prison before he hath paid the said debt and the said twentie pence for his arrest upon pain to forfeit to the Kings Majestie fourtie shillings And the said Gaoler to pay to the
Kings Majestie the double value aswell of the rate which the said person soe imprisoned was taxed at as of the said twentie pence for the fees And like Processe and remedy in like manner and forme shall be granted by the said Commissioners or as many of them as by the said Commission shall be thereunto appointed at like information of
every person or persons being charged with any Sum of Money for any other person or persons by reason of the said twoe Subsidies and not thereof paid but willfully withdrawne nor the same leviable within the limits where such persons were thereunto taxed And if the Sum or Sums being behind unpaid by any person or persons as is aforesaid
be leavied and gathered by force of the said Processe to be made by the said Commissioners or if in default or for lacke of payment thereof the person or persons soe owing the said Sum or Sums of Money by processe of the same
Commissioners to be made as is aforesaid be committed to prison in form abovesaid that then the said Commissioner which shall award such Processe shall make such Certificate of that shall be done in the premisses after such Sum or Sums of money soe being behinde shall be leavyed and gathered of such person or persons for non payment
of the same committed to prison And if it happen any of the said Colle&bholigct;ors [to<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] be assigned or any Maiors Sheriffes
Stewards Constables Headboroughs Bursholders Bailiffes or any other Officer or Minister or other whatsoever person or persons to disobey the said Commissioners or any of them in the reasonable request to them made by the said Commissioners for the execution of the said Commission or if any of the Officers or other Persons doe refuse that to them shall appertaine and belong to doe by reason of any Precept to him or them to be dire&bholigct;ed or any reasonable commandment instance or request touching the &bhopcrl;misses or other default in any appearance or colle&bholigct;ion to make
or if any person being suspe&bholigct;ed not to be indifferently taxed as is aforesaid doe refuse to be examined according to the tenour of this A&bholigct; before the said Commissioners or as many of them as shall be thereunto assigned as is aforesaid or will not appeare before the same Commissioners upon warning to him made or else make resistance or rescues upon any distresse upon him to be taken for any parcell of the said Subsidies or commit any misdemeanour in any manner or wise contrary to this A&bholigct; or commit any wilfull omission or other whatsoever wilfull doeing or misdoeing contrary to the tenour of this A&bholigct; or Grant the same Commissioners and every number of them
above remembred or twoe of them at the least upon certaine knowledge of any such misdemeanour had by information or examination shall and may set upon every such offendor for every such offence in the name of a Fine by the same offendour to be forfeited fourty shillings or under by discretion of the same C&bhooov;mission[er]s and
further the said Commissioners and every number of them or two of them at the least shall have authority by this present A&bholigct; to punish every such offendor by imprisonment there to remaine and to be delivered by theire discretions as shall seeme to them convenient the said Fines [if<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] any such be to be certified by the said Commissioners that soe assessed the same into the Kings Majesties Exchequer to be levied and payed by the Colle&bholigct;ors of that part for the said twoe Subsidies returned into the said Exchequer to be therewith charged with the payment of the same Subsidies in such manner as if the said Fines had beene set and taxed upon the said Offendors for the
said two Subsidies.</para>
</section>
<section id="s124">
<head>XVIII. Allowance to High Colle&bholigct;ors and their Accountants.</head>
<para id="p142">
<emph type="i">Allowance to be paid by Colle&bholigct;ors to Commissioners for Expences and Labour of their Clerks.; Remedy for the same for Commissioners against Colle&bholigct;ors.; Commissioners, &amp;c. not compellable to make Presentments other than to Exchequer.; Persons assigned to be Commissioners not to be named Head Colle&bholigct;ors.; Head Colle&bholigct;ors acquitted of Fees.; Taking Fees of Accountants.; Penalty.; Imprisonment.; Commissioners at Meetings to shew Certificates and Presentments to the other Commissioners.; Indenture of Colle&bholigct;ors Names, and of Sums written to Colle&bholigct;ors, Fines, &amp;c. to be certified by Commissioners into the Exchequer.; Colle&bholigct;ors answerable for their own Colle&bholigct;ion only.; Commissioners, if they cannot agree, &amp;c. may make several Indentures.; Colle&bholigct;ors answerable for their own Colle&bholigct;ion only; and upon Payment to be discharged in the Exchequer without Fee.; Penalty.; Commissioners or Colle&bholigct;ors or Persons taxed dying before discharged, Heirs and Executors chargeable as such Persons would have been if alive.; Commissioners not thinking fit to join in one Certificate,; Proceedings.; Commissioners making Default of Certificate, Process out of Exchequer against them</emph>.</para>
<para id="p143">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by the said authority of this present Parliament that every of the said high Colle&bholigct;ors which shall accompt for any part of the said two Subsidies upon theire severall Accompts to bee yeelded shall be
allowed upon payment of the money chargeable upon his Colle&bholigct;ion for every pound limitted to his Colle&bholigct;ion whereof any such Colle&bholigct;or shall be charged and yeeld Accompt three pence as parcell of theire Charge (that is to say)
of every pound thereof for such persons as then have had the particular colle&bholigct;ion of the Townes and other places (as is aforesaid) specified in his Colle&bholigct;ion one penny and one other penny of every pound thereof (every of the said cheife Colle&bholigct;ors or theire Accomptants to retaine to theire owne use for theire labour and charge in and about the premisses and one penny of every pound residue to be delivered allowed and paid by the said Colle&bholigct;or soe being thereof allowed to such of the Commissioners as shall take upon them the busines and labour for and about the
premisses) that is to say every Colle&bholigct;or to pay that Commissioner or Commissioners which had the ordering of the writing of and for the said twoe Subsidies where the said Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors had theire colle&bholigct;ion for the
expences for the said Commissioners soe taking upon them the said busines and labour of theire Clerks writing the said Precepts and Extra&bholigct;s of the said Colle&bholigct;ions the said last penny of every pound to be divided amongst the said Commissioners having regard to theire labour &amp; busines taken by them and theire said Clerks in and about
the premisses for which part soe to the said Commissioners appertaining the said Commissioners six five foure three or two or as many of them as shall be thereunto appointed by the Kings Majesties Commission and every of them joyntly and severally for his and theire said part may have his remedy against the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors which thereof be or might have beene allowed by A&bholigct;ion of Debt in which the defendant shall not wage his Law neither prote&bholigct;ion neither injun&bholigct;ion or essoine shall be allowed And that noe person now being a member of this present Parliament nor any Commissioner shall be named or assigned to bee any Colle&bholigct;or or Subcolle&bholigct;or or Presentor of the said Subsidies or any part thereof nor any Commissioner shall be compelled to make any presentment or
certificate other then into the Kings Majesties said Exchequer of for or concerning the said two Subsidies or any part or parcell thereof And likewise that noe other person that shall be named and assigned to be Commissioners in any place to and for the execution of this A&bholigct; of Subsidies be or shall be assigned or named head Colle&bholigct;or
of the said Subsidies neither of any part thereof. And that every such person and person which shall be nominated and appointed as is aforesaid to be head Colle&bholigct;ors of and for the payment of the said Subsidies or of any part thereof be and shall be acquitted and discharged of all manner of Fees and Rewards and of every other charge in
the Kings Majesties Exchequer or elsewhere of them or any of them by reason of that Colle&bholigct;ion Payment or Accompt or any thing concerning the same to be asked and that if any person receive or take any Fees Rewards or Pleasures of any such Accomptants or use any unnecessary delay in theire Account that then he shall forfeit to the Kings Majestie for every peny or value of every penny soe taken five shillings and five pounds to the party greived for every such delay and suffer imprisonment at the Kings Majesties pleasure and after every taxing and assessing of the said Subsidies (as is aforesaid) had or made and the said Extra&bholigct;s thereof in parchment unto the
Colle&bholigct;or in manner and forme before rehearsed delivered the said Commissioners which shall take upon them the execution of this A&bholigct; within the limits of theire said Commission by theire Agreements shall have meetings togeather at which meeting every of the said Commissioners which then shall have taken upon them the execution of any
part of the said Commission shall by himselfe or his sufficient deputy truly certifie and bring forth unto the said Commissioners named in the said Commission the Certificate and Presentment made before him and such other Commissioners as were limited with him in one limit (so as the same Certificate may be accompted and cast with the other Certificates of the other limits within the same Commission) and then the said Commissioners and every number of them unto two att the least as is aforesaid if any be in life or the Executors or Administrators of theire goods if they then be dead shall joyntly and severally as they were divided in theire limits under theire Seales by theire discretions make one or severall writings indented containing in it aswell the names of the said Colle&bholigct;ors by
the Commissioners for such Colle&bholigct;ions and Accompts in the Exchequer and payments assigned as the grosse and severall S&bhouov;ms written unto every such Colle&bholigct;ors to receive the said Subsidies and alsoe all Fines Amerciaments and
other forfeitures (if any such be) by reason of this A&bholigct; as shall happen to be within the limit and precin&bholigct; of theire Commission to be certified into the Kings Majesties said Exchequer by the said Commissioners in which Writing or Writings indented soe to be certified shall be plainly declared and expressed the whole and entire S&bhouov;me and S&bhouov;ms of the said Subsidies severally limited to the Colle&bholigct;ion of the said Colle&bholigct;ors severally deputed and assigned to the said S&bhouov;ms soe as none of the said Colle&bholigct;ors soe certified in the said Exchequer shall be compelled there to accompt or be charged but onely to and for the S&bhouov;ms limited to his Colle&bholigct;ion and not to or for any S&bhouov;m limited to the colle&bholigct;ion of his fellowes but every of them shall be severally charged for theire part limited to theire Colle&bholigct;ion And if the said Commissioners joyned in one Commission amongst themselves in that matter cannot agree or if any of them be not ready or refuse to make certificate with the other of the same Commissioners that then the said
Commissioners may make severall Indentures in forme aforesaid of theire severall limits or separations of Colle&bholigct;ors within the limits of theire Commission upon and in the Hundreds Wards Wapentakes Lathes Rapes or such other like divisions within the said severall limits of theire Commission as the places there shall require to be severed and divided and as to the same Commissioners shall seeme meet to make divisions or other limits or colle&bholigct;ions for the severall Charges of the same Colle&bholigct;ors soe that alway one Colle&bholigct;or shall be charged and accompt for his part to be limited onely by himselfe and not for any Sum limited to the part of any of his fellowes And the
charges of every of the Colle&bholigct;ors to be set and certified severally upon them and every such Colle&bholigct;or upon his Accompt and payment of the S&bhouov;m of Money limited within his colle&bholigct;ion to be severally by himselfe acquitted and discharged in the said Exchequer without paying any manner of fees or rewards to any person or persons for the same upon paine and penalty last above said and not to be charged for any portion of any other colle&bholigct;ors and if any Commissioner after he hath taken certificate of them that as is aforesaid shall be before any Commissioners examined and the Sums rated and set and the books and writings thereof being in his hands or if any Colle&bholigct;or or other person charged with any receipt of any part of the said Subsidies or any other person taxed or otherwise
by this A&bholigct; charged with or for any parcell of the said Subsidies or with any other Sum Fine Amerciament Penalty or other forfeiture happen to die before the Commissioners Colle&bholigct;ors or other whatsoever person or persons have executed accomplished satisfied or sufficiently discharged that which to every such person shall appertain or belong to do according to this A&bholigct; then the Executors and Heires of [every<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] such person and all other seised of any Lands and Tenements that any such person being charged by this A&bholigct; and deceasing before he bee discharged thereof or any other to his use onely had of an estate of inheritance at the time that any such person was named Commissioner Colle&bholigct;or or otherwise charged with or for any manner of thing to be done satisfied or paid by reason of this A&bholigct;
and all those that have in theire possession or hands any Goods Chattels Leases or other things that were to any such person or persons at the time of his death or any Lands or Tenements that were the same persons att the time that hee was as is aforesaid charged by this A&bholigct; shall be by the same compelled and charged to doe and accomplish
in every case as the same person soe being charged should have done or might have beene compelled to doe if he had beene in plene life after such rate of the Lands and Goods of the said Commissioner and Colle&bholigct;or as the party shall have in his hands And if the said Commissioners for causes reasonable them moving shall thinke it not fit to
joyne in one Certificate as is aforesaid then the said person or persons that shall first joyne togeather or he that shall first certifie the said Writing indented as is aforesaid shall certifie all the names of the Commissioners of that Commission whereupon such writing shall be there then to be certified with the division of the Hundreds Wapentakes
Wards Tithings and other places to and among other such Commissioners of the same Commission with the names of the said Commissioners where such [separara&bhocotil;ns<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] and divisions shall be with the grosse S&bhouov;ms of Money as well of and for the said Subsidies taxed or set of or within the said Hundreds Wards Wapentakes or other places to him or them divided or assigned that shall soe certifie the said first writing as of the Fines Amerciaments Penalties and other forfeitures if any happen to be within the same limits whereof the same writing shall be certified And
after such [Writing<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] indented which as is aforesaid shall be certified and not containe in it the whole and full Sums set and taxed within the limits of the same Commission the other Commissioners of the same before the day of payment of the said Subsidies shall certifie into the said Exchequer by theire Writing or Writings indented to be made as is aforesaid the grosse and severall Sums set and taxed within the places to them limited for the said Subsidies and other Fines Amerciaments Penalties and Forfeitures with the names of the Hundreds Wards Wapentakes and other places to them assigned or else by theire said Writings indented certifie att the same place before the
same day of payment such reasonable causes for theire excuses why they may not make such Certificate of and for the said Subsidies Fines Amerciaments and other forfeitures growing or set by reason of the causes of theire letts or of theire not certifying as is aforesaid or else in default thereof Processe to be made out of the Kings Majesties said Exchequer against the said Commissioners and every of them not makeing Certificate as is aforesaid by the discretion of the Treasurer and Barons of the said Exchequer.</para>
</section>
<section id="s125">
<head>XIX. Proviso for Stamford Baron.</head>
<para id="p144">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the Inhabitants of the Parish of Saint
Martin called Stamford Baron in the Suburbs of the Borough and Town of Stamford in the South part of the Waters there called Wellands which hereafter shall be contributary to the payment of the said Subsidies shall be assessed rated and taxed for the same by such Commissioners as shall be appointed as aforesaid for the taxing rating and assessing of the same Subsidies within the County of Lincolne and shall be for the same contributary and pay to the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors which shall be assigned and appointed for the levying and gathering of the same as aforesaid.</para>
</section>
<section id="s126">
<head>XX. Persons having Spiritual and Temporal Possessions, and also Personal Property, not to be doubly charged.</head>
<para id="p145">Provided alwaies and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the [the<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] authority aforesaid that all and every person and persons
having Mannors Lands Tenements and other Hereditaments chargeable to the payment of the said two Subsidies granted by this A&bholigct; and alsoe having Spirituall Possessions chargeable to His Majestie by any Grant made or to be made by the Clergie of this Realme in theire Convocation and over this having Substance in Goods and Chattels
chargeable by the said A&bholigct; that then if any of the said person or persons bee hereafter charged assessed and taxed for the said Mannors Lands and Tenements and Spirituall Possessions and alsoe charged assessed and taxed for his and theire Goods and Chattels that then he or they shall be onely charged by vertue of this A&bholigct; for his and theire said Mannors Lands Tenements and Hereditaments and Spirituall Possessions or onely for his said Goods and Chattels the best thereof to bee taken and not to be charged for both or doubly charged for any of them Any thing in
this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s127">
<head>XXI. Proviso for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey, and Guernsey.</head>
<para id="p146">Provided alwaies that this Grant of Subsidies or any thing therein contained in any wise extend not to charge the Inhabitants of Scotland Ireland Jersey and Garnsey or any of them of for or concerning any Mannors Lands
Tenements or other Possessions Goods Chattels or other moveable substance which the said Inhabitants or Dwellers or any others to theire use have within Scotland Ireland Jersey and Garnsey or in any of them or of for or concerning any Fees or Wages which any of the said Inhabitants or Dwellers have of the Kings Majestie for theire attendance and doing Service to our Soveraigne Lord the Kings Majestie in Scotland Ireland Jersey and Garnsey or any of them any thing in this present A&bholigct; to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s128">
<head>XXII. Proviso for Patents of Liberties, &amp;c. to Cities, &amp;c.</head>
<para id="p147">Provided alsoe that all Letters Patents granted by the Kings Majestie or any of his noble Progenitors to any Cities
Boroughs or Townes within this Realme of any manner of Liberties Priviledges or Exemptions from the burthen and
charge of any such Grants of Subsidies which be att this present time of force and availeable shall remaine good and
effe&bholigct;uall to the said Cities Boroughs and Townes hereafter according to the purports thereof although the Inhabitants
of the same and alsoe the said Corporations shall upon the great and weighty considerations of the Grant aforesaid
be for this Grant charged and contributary in like manner forme and sort as other Cities Boroughs and Townes
which bee not in any wise priviledged but by this A&bholigct; charged.</para>
</section>
<section id="s129">
<head>XXIII. Proviso for Orphans and Infants.</head>
<para id="p148">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that no Orphane or Infant within the age of one
and twenty yeares borne within any of the Kings Majesties Dominions shall be charged with the payment of the
said two Subsidies for his or theire Goods or Chattels to him or her left or bequeathed Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained
to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s130">
<head>XXIV. Proviso for Universities of Oxford and Cambridge, Winchester College, Eton College, and the Poor Knights of Windsor, and for Free Schools, and Readers, &amp;c. in the Universities of Oxford and Cambridge, and for Hospitals, &amp;c.</head>
<para id="p149">Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend to the Lands or Goods of any Colledge
Hall or Hostell within the Universities of Oxon and Cambridge or any of them or to the Goods and Lands of the
Colledge of Winton founded by Bishop Wickham or to the Goods or Lands of the Colledge of Eaton next Windsor
or to the Lands Tenements or Revenues onely assigned and appointed for the sustentation and living of the Poore
Knights founded in the Castle or Colledge of Windsor by our late Soveraigne Lord King Henry the Eight or to
any the Goods or Chattels of the same Knights or any of them or to the Goods or Lands of any Common
Free Grammar Schoole within the Realme of England or Wales or the Goods of any Reader Schoolmaster or
Scholer or any Graduate resiant or remaining for Study without fraud or covin within any the said Universities
and Colledges or Townes of Oxford and Cambridge or Suburbs of the same or to any of them or to any of
theire Servants attending dayly upon any of them nor to the Goods of any Officer Minister Almesmen or Servants
belonging to any of the said Universities Colledges Halls or Hostels and dwelling and resiant within the said Universities
or either of them or within either [of<ref idref="n43">43</ref>] the said Townes of Oxford and Cambridge and the Suburbs of the same
without fraud or covin or to the goods and Lands of any Hospitall Measondieu or Spittlehouse prepared and
used for the sustentation and relief of poore people Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s131">
<head>XXV. Inhabitants of Cinque Ports, for the most Part of the Year before the Grant, acquitted during Resiance only.</head>
<para id="p150">Provided alsoe and be it further ena&bholigct;ed that the said Grant of the said twoe Subsidies or any thing therein
contained do not in any wise extend [to<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] be prejudiciall or hurtfull to any the inhabitants or resiants haveing dwelt for
the most part of the yeare next before the taxing and assessing of the Subsidies aforesaid within the Five Ports
Corporate or to any theire members incorporated or united to the said Five Ports or to any of them but such the
Inhabitants or resiants as aforesaid in the said Five Ports Corporate and theire members be and shall be of and
from the same Grant and Payment of the said two Subsidies and every part thereof and onely during theire resiance
as aforesaid and no longer clearely acquitted and discharged any matter or whatsoever thing in this present A&bholigct; had
or made to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s132">
<head>XXVI. Like Proviso for English Inhabitants of Rumney Marsh.</head>
<para id="p151">Provided alsoe that the said Grant of the said two Subsidies doe not in any wise extend to be prejudiciall or
hurtfull to the English Inhabitants or resiants at this present time within the Liberties of Rumney Marsh of or for
any part of the said Sums granted in this present Parliament of the said English Inhabitants now there resiants
or any of them to be taxed set asked levied or paid but that the English Inhabitants and now resiants of Rumney
Marsh aforesaid and every of them be and shall be of and from the Grant and payment of the said two Subsidies
during theire resiance there and no longer acquitted and discharged Any matter and whatsoever thinge in this present
A&bholigct; made to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s133">
<head>XXVII. Alien or Denizen assigning his Lands, &amp;c. to his Child, with Intent to defraud the Subsidy, such Child chargeable as an Alien.</head>
<para id="p152">Provided neverthelesse and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that if any Alien or Stranger born
denizen or not denizen and dwelling and inhabiting within this Realme of England shall assigne and convey over unto
any his or theire [child or children borne within the said Realme of England his or theire<ref idref="n43">43</ref>] Lands or Tenements Goods
or Chattels to the intent thereby to defraud or safeguard themselves of and from the payment of the Subsidies
aforesaid or any part thereof that then all and every such child and children soe being seized of any such Lands
and Tenements or possessed of (<ref idref="n45">45</ref>) such goods or chattels shall be charged and chargeable to and with the payment
of double the said Subsidies for the Lands Tenements Goods and Chattels at the said rates and values as Aliens
&amp; Strangers denizens or not denizens are before limited &amp; appointed to pay.</para>
</section>
<section id="s134">
<head>XXVIII. Proviso for County of Northumberland, Newcastle-upon-Tyne, Berwick-upon-Tweed, Bishoprick, and County Palatine of Durham.</head>
<para id="p153">Provided alwaies that the said Grant of and for the two Subsidies aforesaid or any clause matter or thinge
whatsoever therein contained shall not in any wise extend or be construed to extend to charge the Shire or County
of Northumberland the Towne Borough or County of Newcastle upon Tyne the Towne or Borough of Barwick upon
Tweed or unto the Bishoprick of Duresme or County Palatine of Duresme or any parts or places within them or any
of them or any the resiants or inhabitants thereof but that the said Shire and County of Northumberland the Towne
Borough and County of Newcastle upon Tyne the said Towne or Borough of Barwick and the Bishoprick and County
Palatine of Duresme and alsoe all and every the resiants and inhabitants of and within them and every of them
respe&bholigct;ively be and shall be of and from the said Grant and Payment of the said two Subsidies and every part
thereof freely acquitted and discharged Any matter or whatsoever thing in this present A&bholigct; had or made to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s135">
<head>XXIX. Recital that certain Citizens of London had advanced the Sum of &pound;120,000 for the present Supply.</head>
<para id="p154">
<emph type="i">Thomas Soame, Isaac Penington, and the Chamberlain of London for the Time being, the Receivers of the Two Subsidies, may repay such Monies out of the Subsidies, with Interest at &pound;8. per Centum per Annum; and employ the Surplus for the Purposes of the A&bholigct; as herein mentioned.; The Warrant of the Commissioners a Discharge to the Treasurers herein named</emph>.</para>
<para id="p155">And whereas the Sum of one hundred and twenty thousand pounds hath beene laid out and advanced or is agreed
to be laid out and advanced before hand by certain particular Citizens of the City of London for the present Supply of
your Majesties Army and the releife of the Northerne Parts of this your Majesties Kingdome of England Be it ena&bholigct;ed
by the authority of this present Parliament That the said Thomas Soame Isaac Penington and the Chamberlaine for
the time being by this present A&bholigct; of Parliament constituted and ordained Receivers of the said two Subsidies shall
and may satisfie pay and deliver unto the said Citizens that have or shall advance any Moneyes as aforesaid out of
the said Subsidies and Moneys by this A&bholigct; appointed to bee received the said Sums of Money so by them laid out
and advanced together with such other and further Sum and Sums of Money as the damages of and for the said
Sums shall amount unto after the rate of eight pounds per centum for a yeere from the day and time that the
same was laid out and advanced as aforesaid untill they shall respe&bholigct;ively have received the said Sums so disbursed
and the surplusage of the said Sums soe to be received shall pay imploy and disburse for the releife of the Kings
Army and of the Northerne Counties and for the payment of such person or persons as shall lend or advance any
Sum or Sums of Money for the use and purposes last before men&bhocotil;ned with theire damages in such manner and
forme as Francis Earle of Bedford William Earle of Hertford Robert Earle of Essex William Earle of Salisbury Robert
Earle of Warwick Henry Earle of Holland Thomas Earle of Berkshire Henry Earle of Stamford Francis Lord Dacres
Philip Lord Wharton William Lord Paget Robert Lord Brooke Edward Mountague Lord [of<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] Kimbolton John Lord
Paulet Edward Howard Lord Howard of Esterick Francis Leigh Lord Dunsmore or any foure or more of them
Denzill Hollis Esquire John Pymm Esquire Sir Christopher Wray Knight Sir John Hotham Baronet Thomas Lord
Wenman Sir Christopher Yelverton Knight William Cage Esquire Henry Martin Esquire Sir Dudley North Knight
Sir Thomas Bowyer Baronet Sir Edward Aiscough Knight Sir John Culpeper Knight Sir Robert Crane Knight and
Baronet John Hampden Esquire Sir Edmund Mountford Sir Walter Earle Sir Arthur Ingram Knights Sir Gilbert
Gerard Baronet Sir Guy Palmes Knight Samuel Owfeild Esquire Sir Henry Vane junior Knight Sir Hugh Cholmeley
Knight Harbottell Grimston Esquire Sir Philip Stapleton Knight Sir Edward Hales Knight Sir Thomas Widdrington
Kn<emph type="p">t</emph> Thomas Lord Gray Norton Knatchbull Esquire Edmund Waller Esquire Henry Lord Gray of Ruthyn or any
eight or more of them and soe proportionably in such manner and quality by any one or more Writing or Writings
under theire hands during this fitting of Parliament shall limit appoint and declare And that the Warrant or Warrants
of the said Commissioners before named or of such number of them as before is expressed proportionably togeather
with the Acquittance and Acquittances from the person or persons which shall be appointed as aforesaid by the said
Commissioners or of such number of them [proportionably<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] as before is expressed for receipt of the said Sum or
Sums of Money to the uses and purposes in this present A&bholigct; expressed shall be a sufficient discharge to the Treasurers in
this A&bholigct; named for so much money as shall be comprehended in such Acquittance or Acquittances for the issuing
out and payment of the said Sum or Sums of Money respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
</section>
<section id="s136">
<head>XXX. Treasurer not to pay any Money upon any other Warrant.</head>
<para id="p156">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said treasurers shall not att all pay any Sum or
Sums of Money to be by them received upon any other dire&bholigct;ion Warrant or Command whatsoever.</para>
</section>
<section id="s137">
<head>XXXI. The passing of this A&bholigct;, or the Royal Assent thereto, not to determine the Session.</head>
<para id="p157">
<emph type="i">All A&bholigct;s continued by 3 Car. I. c. 4. of Force until some other A&bholigct; be made touching the Statutes so continued</emph>.</para>
<para id="p158">Lastly provided and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the passing of this present A&bholigct; or (<ref idref="n47">47</ref>) any other A&bholigct;
or A&bholigct;s or His Majesties Royall Assent to them or any of them in this present Session of Parliament shall not be
any determination of the said Session And that all Statutes and A&bholigct;s of Parliament which have theire continuance
or were by an A&bholigct; of Parliament made in the third yeere of the Reigne of His Majestie that now is intituled An A&bholigct;
for the continuance and repeal of diverse Statutes continued until the end of the first Session of the then next
Parliament shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; be adjudged ever since the Session of Parliament in the said third yeare to
have beene of such force and effe&bholigct; as the same were the last day of that Session and from thenceforth untill some
other A&bholigct; of Parliament be made touching the continuance or discontinuance of the said Statutes and A&bholigct;s in the
said A&bholigct; of third (<ref idref="n48">48</ref>) yeare of His Majesties Reigne continued as aforesaid.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">or w[hi]ch before the time of the Assessment of the said two Subsidies by this present A&bholigct; granted shalbe a Popish Recusant convi&bholigct;<emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">payment <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n5" number="5">Wilbore <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n7" number="7">Crockstone <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n8" number="8">Hotham <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n9" number="9">Hawkes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n11" number="11">John <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
<note id="n12" number="12">Villa Hunting <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
<note id="n13" number="13">Crofte <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n14" number="14">Sidley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n15" number="15">Roger <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n16" number="16">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n17" number="17">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n18" number="18">Mayo'</note>
<note id="n19" number="19">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n20" number="20">Gee <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n21" number="21">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n22" number="22">Srjeants <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n23" number="23">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n24" number="24">
<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
<note id="n25" number="25">Carnye <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n26" number="26">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n27" number="27">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n28" number="28">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n29" number="29">two <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n30" number="30">soe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n31" number="31">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n32" number="32">assesse <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n33" number="33">
<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
<note id="n34" number="34">distresse <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n35" number="35">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n36" number="36">his <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n37" number="37">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n38" number="38">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n39" number="39">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n40" number="40">separa&bhocotil;ns <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n41" number="41"> Writings <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n42" number="42">
<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
<note id="n43" number="43">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n44" number="44">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n45" number="45">any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n46" number="46">1 interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n47" number="47">2 of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n48" number="48">3 the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
</section>

</report>


