<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47217" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER VI. An Act concerning the Limitation and Abbreviation of Michaelmas Terme. [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Inconvenience of Michaelmas Term being so soon after the Feast of St. Michael.; In Michaelmas Terms shall be Six common Days of Return only.; The Days of Return specified.; The Return Days to be observed.; Certain Days of Return not to be called.; When Michaelmas Term to begin.; Full Term of St. Michael when to commence</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Terme of Saint Michael comonly called Michaelmas Terme doth begin soe soone after the
Feast of Saint Michael that it is generally found to be very inconvenient to his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s both Nobles
and others as well for the keeping of the Quarter Sessions next after the Feast of Saint Michael the Archangell and
the keeping of theire Leets Law dayes and Court Barons which they can by no meanes attend in regard of the necessity
of theire coming to the said Terme soe speedily after the feast of Saint Michael the Archangell to appeare upon
Juries and to follow theire Causes and Suites in the Law the same time being the cheife time of all the yeare for
the sowing of Land with Winter Corne and for the disposing and setting in order [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] all theire Winter Husbandry
and busines and for the receiving and paying of Rents and in many parts of this Kingdome Harvest is seldome or
never inned till three weekes after the said Feast Therefore the Kings most excellent Majestie out of the Princely
care that he hath of all his loving Subje&bholigct;s having a speciall care to the increase and continuance of theire wealth
and good estates by the assent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same Ordaineth Ena&bholigct;eth and Establisheth That in the said Michaelmas Terme
there shall be six common dayes of Returne only and not above that is to say The first day of Return thereof shall
be and be called A die San&bholigct;i Michaelis in tres Septimanas The second day of Return of the same Terme shall be
and be called A die San&bholigct;i Michaelis in un&bhouov; Mensem The third day of Return of the same Terme shall be and be
called In crastino animarum The fourth day of Return of the same Terme shall be and be called In crastino San&bholigct;i
Martini The fifth day of Return of the same Terme shall be and be called In O&bholigct;abis San&bholigct;i Martini And the sixth
day of Return of the said Terme shall be and be called A Die San&bholigct;i Martini in quindecim dies And that the
same dayes of Return shall be observed in all the high Courts of Record of our Soveraigne Lord the King his Heires
and Successors hereafter to be holden at Westminster or other place or places at the assignement or appointment
of our Soveraign Lord the King his Heires and Successors And that from and after the Feast of Saint Michael the
Archangell next coming there shall not be nor be called any dayes of Return in O&bholigct;abis san&bholigct;i Michaelis nor A die
san&bholigct;i Michaelis in quindecim dies nor either of them And that the said Terme of Saint Michael yearely for ever
from and after the said Feast of Saint Michael the Archangell next coming begin in and upon the said Tres septimanas
san&bholigct;i Michaelis whensoever it [shall<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] happen to fall (except it be on the Lords day commonly called Sonday and
then on the morrow next after) for the keeping of the Essoignes Proffers Returns and other Ceremonies heretofore
used and kept in like manner and forme as hath beene used to be done in the day of the Return commonly called
O&bholigct;abis [Sain&bholigct;i<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Michaelis and that the full terme of Saint Michael shall yearely for ever from and after the [said<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
Feast of Saint Michael next coming in all the aforesaid Courts of Record begin and take his commencement upon
the quarto die of the said tres septimanas S[an]cti Michaelis and not before as formerly it hath been used upon the
quarto die of O&bholigct;abis San&bholigct;i Michaelis (except it be on the Lords day commonly called Sunday and then on the
morrow next after.)</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. How Days shall be given in Writs in real A&bholigct;ions, other than Writs of Entry, of Right of Advowson, or of Dower.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that if after the Feast of Saint Michael the Archangel next
coming any Writ in any reall A&bholigct;ion other then Writs of Entry for common Recoveries and Writs of right of
Advouson and Writs of Dower Unde nihil habet hereafter mentioned come in and be returnable in his Majesties
Court of Common Pleas in the day of Return of Tres septimanas San&bholigct;i Michaelis then day shall be given In Crastino
purifica&bhocotil;nis beate Marie and if A die San&bholigct;i Michaelis in unum Mensem then In O&bholigct;abis purifica&bhocotil;nis beate Marie
if In Crastino animarum then In quindena pasche if In Crastino San&bholigct;i Martini then A die pasche in [tres septimanas if
In O&bholigct;abis S[an]cti Martini then A die pasche<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) unum mensem if In quindena San&bholigct;i Martini then In quin&bhoqesq; septimanas
pasche if In O&bholigct;abis San&bholigct;i Hilarii then In Crastino Ascen&bhocotil;nis Domini if In quindena San&bholigct;i Hilarii then in Crastino
San&bholigct;e Trinitatis if In Crastino purifica&bhocotil;nis beate Marie then [In O&bholigct;abis S[anct]e Trinitatis if In O&bholigct;abis purifica&bhocotil;nis
b[ea]te Marie then<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] In quindena san&bholigct;e Trinitatis if In quindena pasche then A die San&bholigct;e Trinitatis in tres septimanas if
A die pasche in tres septimanas then A die San&bholigct;i Michaelis in tres septimanas if A die pasche in unum mensem then
A die S[an]cti Michaelis in unum mensem if A die pasche in quinque septimanas then In Crastino animarum if In Crastino
ascen&bhocotil;nis Domini then In Crastino San&bholigct;i Martini if In Crastino san&bholigct;e Trinitatis then In O&bholigct;abis san&bholigct;i Martini if In
O&bholigct;abis san&bholigct;e Trinitatis then In quindena san&bholigct;i Martini if In quindena san&bholigct;e Trinitatis then In O&bholigct;abis san&bholigct;i Hilarii
if A die san&bholigct;e Trinitatis in tres septimanas then In quindena San&bholigct;i Hillarii.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. How Days shall be given in Writs of Entry, of Right of Advouwson, and of Dower.</head>
			<para id="p4">And for the more speedie proceeding in Writs of Dower and Writs of Entry for common. Recoveries to be sued
and prosecuted by Writs of Entry or Writs of Right of Advouson. Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid
That if after the said Feast of Saint Michael the Archangell next coming any Writ of Dower Unde nihil habet or
any Writ of Entry whereupon a common Recovery is to be sued or Writs of Right of Advouson be returnable
A die San&bholigct;i Michaelis in tres septimanas then a day shall be given In O&bholigct;abis San&bholigct;i Martini if A die San&bholigct;i Michaelis
in un&bhouov; mensem then In quindena San&bholigct;i Martini if In Crastino animarum then In O&bholigct;abis San&bholigct;i Hillarii if In Crastino
San&bholigct;i Martini then In quindena San&bholigct;i Hillarii if In O&bholigct;abis San&bholigct;i Martini then In Crastino purifica&bhocotil;nis beate Marie
[if In quindena S[an]cti Martini then In O&bholigct;abis purifica&bhocotil;nis b[ea]te Marie<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] if In O&bholigct;abis San&bholigct;i Hillarii then In quindena pasche
if In quindena San&bholigct;i Hillarii then A die pasche in tres septimanas if In Crastino purifica&bhocotil;nis beate Marie then A die
pasche in un&bhouov; mensem if In O&bholigct;abis purifica&bhocotil;nis beate Marie then A die pasche in quinque septimanis if In quindena
pasche then In Crastino ascen&bhocotil;nis Domini if A die pasche in tres septimanas then In Crastino San&bholigct;e Trinitatis if
In Mense pasche then In O&bholigct;abis San&bholigct;e Trinitatis if In quinque septimanas pasche then In quindena San&bholigct;e Trinitatis
if In Crastino ascen&bhocotil;nis Domini then A die San&bholigct;e Trinitatis in tres septimanas if In Crastino San&bholigct;e Trinitatis
then A die San&bholigct;i Michaelis in tres septimanas if In O&bholigct;abis San&bholigct;e Trinitatis then A die S[an]cti Michaelis in unum
mensem if In quindena San&bholigct;e Trinitatis then In Crastino Animarum if A die san&bholigct;e Trinitatis in tres septimanas then
In Crastino san&bholigct;i Martini.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. In Writs of Dower, after Issue joined, Fifteen Days between the Test and Return sufficient.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided neverthelesse and be it likewise ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that in all Writts of Dower Unde
nihil habet after issue joyned it shall not be needfull or requisite to have above fifteene dayes betwixt the Teste and
Return of the Venire Facias [or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] any other processe to be [sued out for the triall of the said<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Issue [but that the Writ
of Venire Facias &amp; other &bhopcrl;cesse after Issue<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] joyned untill Judgement be given having only fifteene dayes betweene
the Teste and Return thereof shall be good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law as is used in personall A&bholigct;ions Any Law Statute
or usage to the contrary heretofore notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Crastino Ascensionis Domini a good Return, although not Fifteen Days, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p6">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that from and after the feast of Saint Michael the Archangel
now next coming the said day of Return called Crastino Ascen&bhocotil;nis Domini shall be a good and perfe&bholigct; Return
to all intents and purposes as any other of the said dayes of Return before men&bhocotil;ned is or hath beene used
notwithstanding there be not fifteene dayes betweene the quarto die of the said Return of Crastino Ascen&bhocotil;nis
Domini and the Essoine day of the Return of Crastino San&bholigct;e Trinitatis.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Writs in personal A&bholigct;ions, having Day from Tres Michaelis till Crastino Animarum good though not Fifteen Days, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That all Writs and Processe in personall A&bholigct;ions hereafter to be made out of any
of his Majesties said Courts at Westminster and having day from Tres Michaelis untill Crastino Animarum shall
be good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law notwithstanding there be not fifteene dayes betwixt the quarto die of the said Tres
septimanas san&bholigct;i Michaelis and the dayes of Essoines of Crastino Animarum Any Law Statute or Usage to the
contrary heretofore notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Writs returnable after Easter 1641.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided alwaies and be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all Writs and Processes to be made from
and after the Feast of Easter in the yeare of our Lord God 1641. returnable in O&bholigct;abis or Quindena san&bholigct;i Michaelis
now next ensuing or having dayes betwext any of the said Returns shall by force of this A&bholigct; have day unto Tres
septimanas san&bholigct;i Michaelis next and the Parties to the said Writs and Processe shall then appeare and plead and
proceed thereupon to all intents and purposes as if the said Writs and Processe had been made returnable A die
san&bholigct;i Michaelis in tres septimanas.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Writs of Summons ad Warrantizandum, upon common Recoveries, and Writs of Right of Advowson abridged to Five Returns.</head>
			<para id="p9">And whereas before the making of this A&bholigct; all Writs of Summons ad Warrantizand against the Vouchees upon
Common Recoveries had in Writs of Entry and Writs of Right of Advouson were made for nine Returns inclusive
Now for the more speedy perfe&bholigct;ing of such Recoveries Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That from and
after the said Feast of Saint Michael the Archangel next all and every such Writs of 	Summons ad Warrantizand upon
the appearance of the Tenant to every such Writ&bholngs; of Entrie and Writ of Right of Advouson shall and may be made
and abridged to five Returns as Writs of Summons ad Warrantizand in Writs of Dower unde nihil habet heretofore
have beene used and accustomed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Common Writs and Process to keep the aforesaid Returns.</head>
			<para id="p10">And it is further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all common Writs and Processe as well personall as
mixt which shall fortune to be returnable in the said Michaelmas Terme shall have and keepe the said Returns of
A die san&bholigct;i Michaelis in tres septimanas A die san&bholigct;i Michaelis in unum mensem In Crastino anima[rum] In Crastino
san&bholigct;i Martini In O&bholigct;abis san&bholigct;i Martini and A die san&bholigct;i Martini in quindecem dies or any of them</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Special Days for returning Writs, &amp;c. may be appointed as have been used.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwaies And it is further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid that in such and like cases &amp; Processe
as speciall dayes have beene used to be appointed and assigned and given for the returning of Writs and Processe
It shall be lawfull to the Justices of every of the Kings said Courts of Record for the time being in all the Processe
by them awarded to assigne and appoint speciall dayes of Returns as by theire discretions shall be thought convenient</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Days in Assize of Darrein Presentment, and in Plea of Quare impedit, by Stat. Marl.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">and in Attaint by 5 E. III. c. 6. and 23 H. VIII. c. 3. not contrary hereto, shall be in force</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">Provided alsoe And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the days in Assize of Darrein
presentment and in Plea of Quare impedit limited and appointed by the Statute of Marlebridge and alsoe the dayes
to bee given in Attaint limited in the Statute made in the fifth yeare of the Reigne of the Noble King Edward the
third And alsoe in the Statute made in the three and twentieth yeare of the Reigne of the late King Henry the
eighth of worthy memory being not contrary to the Tenours of this A&bholigct; shall be holden firme and stable and
shall stand in their full force and effe&bholigct;.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">shalbe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">San&bholigct;i <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">in <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


