<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47219" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER VIII. A Subsidie granted to the King of Tunnage Poundage and other sums of money payable upon Merchandize exported and imported. [Rot. Parl. 16. Car. p. 2. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Ancient Right of the Subje&bholigct; not to be taxed without Consent in Parliament.; Grant of Tonnage, every Tun of Wine imported, 3s. ; Like Duty on Sweet Wine imported by Merchant Aliens. Every Awme of Rhenish Wine imported, 12d.; Grant of Poundage, every 20s. worth of Goods exported, 12d.; The like Duty on Tin and Pewter Vessels exported. Proviso for Woollen Cloth wrought within the Realm and exported by Merchant Denizens; and for Wools, Woolfels, Hides, and Backs of Leather exported; and for all Wines not before mentioned; and for Fresh Fish and Bestiall imported</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas upon examination in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament of diverse of the Farmours Customers and Colle&bholigct;ors
of the Customes upon Merchandize and likewise upon theire owne confession it appeared that they have
taken diverse great sums of money of his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s and likewise of [mechants<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Aliens for Goods imported and
exported by the names of a Subsidy of Tunnage and Poundage and by colour of divers other imposi&bhocotil;ns laid upon
Merchandize which have beene taken and received against the Lawes of the Realme in regard the said sums of money
and impositions were not granted by common consent in Parliament and for soe doing have deserved condigne
punishment Be it therefore declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie and the Lords and Commons
in this present Parliament assembled And it is hereby declared and ena&bholigct;ed That it is and hath beene the ancient
right of the Subje&bholigct;s of this Realme That no Subsidy Custome Impost or other charge whatsoever ought or may be
laid or imposed upon any Merchandize exported or imported by Subje&bholigct;s Denizens or Aliens without common consent
in Parliament Yet neverthelesse the Commons before whom those examina&bhocotil;ns were taken taking into theire
considera&bhocotil;n the great perill that might ensue to this Realme by the not guarding of the Seas and the other
inconveniencies which might follow in case the said sums of money should upon the sudden be forborn to be paid
by and with the advice and consent of the Lords in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the
same Doe give and grant to our Supream Liege Lord and Soveraign One Subsidie called Tunnage that is to say
Of every Tun of Wine that is or shall come into this Realme or any his Majesties Dominions by way of Merchandize
the sum of three shillings and so after that rate And of every tun of Sweet Wines as well Malmsey as other that
is or shall come into this Realme by any Merchant Alien three shillings and soe after the rate over and above the
three shillings above men&bhocotil;ned And of every awme of Renish Wine that is or shall so come in twelve pence
And alsoe one other Subsidie called Poundage that is to say of all manner of Goods and Merchandize of every
Merchant Denizen and Alien carried or to be carried out of this Realme or any his Majesties Dominions or to be
brought into the same by way of Merchandize of the value of every twenty shillings of the same Goods and
Merchandize twelve pence and soe after the rate And of every twenty shillings value of Tin and Pewter Vessell carried
out of this Realme by every or any Merchant Alien twelve pence over and above the twelve pence aforesaid Except
and foreprized out of this grant of Subsidie of Poundage all manner of Woollen Cloth made or wrought or which
shall be made or wrought within this Realme of England and by every or any Merchant Denizen and not born
Alien carried or to be carried out of this Realm And [all manner of Wools Woolfels Hides &amp; Backs of Leather that
is or shall be carried out of this Realme And <ref idref="n2">2</ref>] all Wines not before limited to pay Subsidy or Tunnage And all
manner of fresh Fish and Bestiall coming or that shall come into this Realme.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Merchant Denizen to pay, every Sack of Wool 33s. 4d. every 240 Woolfells 33s. 4d.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">every Last of Hides and Backs &pound; 3. 6s. 8d. and so in Proportion for every greater or less Quantity.; Merchant Strangers to pay, every Sack of Wool &pound; 3. 6s. 8d. every 240 Woolfells &pound;3. 6. 8d.; every Last of Hides and Backs &pound; 3. 13s. 4d. and also certain Duties by Letters Patent, or Great or Privy Seal, since 1st Jac. I</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And further the said Commons by the advice assent and authority aforesaid Doe give and grant unto our said
Leige Lord our Soveraigne for the causes aforesaid One other Subsidie that is to say Of every Merchant born Denizen
of and for every Sack of Wooll thirty three shillings four pence and of and for every two hundred and fourty
Woolfells thirty three shillings foure pence And of and for every last of Hides and Backs three pounds six
shillings eight pence and soe after the same rate for every lesse or greater quantity for any the same Merchandize
more or lesse and of every Merchant Stranger not born Denizen of and for every Sack of Wooll three pounds six
shillings eight pence And of and for every twoe hundred fourty Wolfells three pounds six shillings eight pence
And for every Last of Hides and Backs three pounds thirteen shillings four pence and soe of all the said Woolls
Woollfels Hides and Backs and of every of them after the rate and such other s&bhouov;ms of Money as have beene imposed
upon any Merchandize either outward or inward by pretext of any Letters Patents Commission under the Great
Seale of England or Privie Seale since the first yeare of the reigne of his late Majesty King James of Blessed Memory
and which were continued and paid at the begining of this present Parliament To have take enjoye and perceive
the Subsidies aforefaid and other the foremen&bhocotil;ned s&bhouov;ms and every of them and every part and parcell of them
to our said Leige Lord and Soveraigne from the five and twentieth of May One thousand six hundred fourty one
to the fifteenth of July next ensuing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The said Subsidy to be applied according to 1 Jac. I. c. 33.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the said Subsidy of Tunnage Poundage Woolls and
other s&bhouov;ms of money shall be taken and imployed during the time aforesaid to and for the intents and purposes
and upon and under such Provisions Clauses and Limitations as are contained in one A&bholigct; made in the Parliament
held in the first yeare of the reigne of his said late Majestie King James of Blessed Memory entituled And A&bholigct; for
the granting of a Subsidie to the King of Tunnage Poundage Woolls &amp;c.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The above Rates on Merchandize to be altered in this Parliament as shall be thought fit.</head>
			<para id="p6">And it is hereby declared that the s&bhouov;ms of money hereby granted upon Merchandize are not the rates intended to be
continued but the same to be hereafter in this present Parliament altered in such manner as shall be thought fit</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Penalty in this A&bholigct; or in 1 Jac. I. c. 33. to attach unless on Persons refusing to compound for Goods imported or exported.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided that no penalty or forfeiture contained in this present A&bholigct; or in the said A&bholigct; made in the first yeare
of King James doe or shall ensue to any person or persons unlesse they refuse to compound for any Merchandize
or Goods imported or exported after notice given of this A&bholigct; Penaltie and Forfeiture by Proclama&bhocotil;n where the
said Goods are or ought to be entred.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Officer after the Determination of this Grant receiving the Subsidy, Premunire and Disability to sue.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed That any Customer or Comptroller or any other Officer or person that after the determina&bhocotil;n
of this Grant shall take or receive or cause to be taken or received the said subsidie s&bhouov;ms of money or any other
imposition upon Merchandize whatsoever exported or imported (except the same by Grant in Parliament be due or by
such Grant shall become due or have beene continually paid from the end of the reign of the late King Edward
the Third untill the begining of the reign of the late Queen Mary) shall incur and sustain the pains penalties and
forfeitures ordained and provided by the Statute of Provision and Premunire made in the sixteenth yeare of King
Richard the Second and shall alsoe from thenceforth bee disabled during his life to sue or implead any person in
any a&bholigct;ion reall mixt or personall or in any Court whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Tobacco of English Plantations.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alwaies That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to any imposi&bhocotil;n or charge upon any sort of Tobacco of
English Plantations but that the said Tobaccoes shall be charged onely with the payment of two pence in the pound
and no more.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Merchants <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


