<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47211" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1627</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER VIII. An Acte for the Graunt of five entire Subsidies graunted by the Temporaltie. [Rot. Parl. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">Most gracious Soveraigne wee your Majesties most humble and loyall Subject&bholngs; the C&bhooov;mons in your High
Court of Parliament now assembled, having dulie considered the many and weightie occasions, which
at this tyme doe presse your Majestie and require a greater expence of Treasure then your owne ordinarie Revenew
can supply both for the defence of your kingdome at this tyme more then in our memory endaungered by forreine
Enemies, as also for the assistance of your Majesties freindes and Allies abroad especially of those who to our great
greife are much affli&bholigct;ed and distressed: And in most thankefull acknowledgment of your Majesties great goodnes
many waies expressed in your just and tender care of the welfare of your people doe humblie &bhopcrl;sent your Majestie
with a free and cheerefull Guift of five entire Subsidies to be paid within one yeare.</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Grant of Five entire Subsidies: viz. on Personal Estate (after Payment of Debts, &#x0026;c.) 2s. 8d. in the Pound</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">And therefore wee humblie beseech your Majestie, That it may be ena&bholigct;ed and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the King&bholngs; most
Excellent Majestie the Lord&bholngs; Spirituall and Temporall and C&bhooov;mons in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled and by
authoritie of the same, that our said Soveraigne Lord the King&bholngs; Majestie his Heires and Successors shall have
receive and enjoy five, entire Subsidies to be rated taxed levied and paid at fower severall payment&bholngs; of every &bhopubr;son
Spirituall and Temporall of what estate or degree he or they be of according to the tenor of this A&bholigct; in manner and
forme following That is to saie, That aswell every &bhopubr;son borne within this Realme of England Wales or other the
King&bholngs; Dominions as all and every Fraternitie Guild Corporacion Misterie Brotherhood and C&bhooov;monaltie Corporate
and not Corporate within this Realme of England Wales or other the King&bholngs; Dominions being worth three pound&bholngs;
aswell in coyne and the value of every pound that every such &bhopubr;son Fraternitie Guild Corporacion Misterie Brotherhood
and C&bhooov;monaltie corporate [and<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] not corporate hath of his or their owne, or any other hath to his or their use, As
also in Plate stocke of Merchandize all manner of corne and graine houshold stuffe and of all other Good&bholngs;
moveable aswell within this Realme as without and of all such s&bhooov;mes of mony as to him or them is or shalbe owing
whereof he or they trust in his or their conscience surely to be paid (except and out of the &bhopcrl;misses dedu&bholigct;ed such
s&bhooov;mes of money as he or they doe owe and in his or their consciences intend trulie to pay, and except also the
apparell of every such &bhopubr;sons their wives and children belonging to their owne bodies (saving jewell&bholngs; gold silver
stone and pearle) shall pay to and for every of the said Subsidies two shilling&bholngs; eight pence of every pound.</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Aliens, and Popish Recusants Convi&bholngs;5s. 4d. in the Pound; Poll Tax on Aliens and Popish Recusants Convict not contributing as above, 8d</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p5">And also every Alien, and Straunger borne out of the King&bholngs; obeysance as well Denizens as others inhabiting within
this Realme and also every Popish Recusant convict or which before the tyme of the Assessment of the severall
Subsidies by this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; graunted shalbe a Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; or which are or shalbe indi&bholigct;ed for Popish
Recusancie and their Indi&bholigct;ment&bholngs; either are or shalbe removed by Cerciorari or being not removed shall not by
apparance and traverse legallie discharge their said Indi&bholigct;ment;&bholngs; at the next Assizes or within two generall Sessions
of the Peace where the said &bhopubr;sons shalbe indi&bholigct;ed respe&bholigct;ivelie of every pound that he or they shall have in coyne
and the value of every pound in plate corne graine merchandize housholdstuffe or other goods jewell&bholngs; chattell&bholngs;
moveables and unmoveable as is aforesaid aswell within this Realme as without and of all s&bhooov;mes of mony to him or
them owing whereof he or they trust in his or their conscience to be paid (except and out of the &bhopcrl;misses dedu&bholigct;ed
every such s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes of mony which he or they doe owe and in his or their conscience or consciences intend
trulie to pay) shall pay to and for every of the said severall Subsidies five shilling&bholngs; and fower pence of every pound.
And also that every Alien and straunger borne, borne out of the King&bholngs; Dominions being denizen or not denizen
not being contributorie to any the Rates aforesaid and being of the age of seaven yeares or above And every Popish
Recusant convi&bholigct; or which before the tyme of the assessement of the severall Subsidies by this(<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) A&bholigct; graunted shalbe
a Popish Recusant convi&bholigct;, and being of the age of seaventeene yeares or which being of the age of one and twentie
yeares, hath not received the holy C&bhooov;munion within one yeare then last past shall pay to and for every of the said
severall Subsidies eight pence for every poll. And the master or he or she with whome the said Alien is or shalbe
abiding at the tyme of the taxacion or taxacions thereof to be charged with the same for lacke of payment
thereof.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Five Subsidies on Real Estates, 4s, in the Pound.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Aliens and Popish Recusants Convi&bholigct; 8s. in the Pound.; Plate, &#x0026;c. held for Corporations to be rated.; Lands, Corodies, Fees, &#x0026;c.; Proviso for Ornaments, &#x0026;c. of Churches and Chappels</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That every &bhopubr;son borne under the King&bholngs; obeysance, and every
Corporacion Fraternitie Guild Misterie Brotherhood &amp; C&bhooov;monaltie corporate or not corporate for every pound that
every of the same &bhopubr;sons and every Corporacion Fraternitie Guild Misterie Brotherhood and C&bhooov;monalty corporate or
not corporate, or any other to his or their use hath in Fee simple Fee taile for terme of life terme of yeares by
Execucion Wardshipp or by Copie of Court Roll of and in any Honors Castles Mannors Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; Rent&bholngs;
Services Hereditament&bholngs; A&bhonov;uities Fees Corrodies or (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) yearelie proffitt&bholngs; of the yearelie value of twentie shilling&bholngs; as well
within auncient demesne and other places priviledged as elswhere and so [upward<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] shall pay to and for every of the
said five Subsidies foure shilling&bholngs; of and for every pound And every Alien denizen or not denizen borne out of the
King&bholngs; obeysance and every Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; of what estate or degree soever they be of, or which before the
tyme of the assessement of the severall Subsidies by this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; graunted shalbe a Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; or
which shalbe indi&bholigct;ed for Popish Recusancie and their indictment&bholngs; are or shalbe removed by Cerciorari or being not
removed, shall not by apparance and traverse legallie discharge their said indictment&bholngs; at the next assizes or within
two generall Sessions of the peace where the said &bhopubr;sons shalbe indi&bholigct;ed respe&bholigct;ivelie in such case to pay to and for
every of the said five severall Subsidies eight shilling&bholngs; for every pound, And that all s&bhooov;mes to be &bhopcrl;sented and
chargeable by this A&bholigct; either for good&bholngs; and debt&bholngs; or either of them or for Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; and other the &bhopcrl;misses
as is in this A&bholigct; conteyned shalbe at every of the said Payments set and taxed after the rate and &bhopubrc;porcion according
to the true meaning of this A&bholigct;, Landes and Tenement&bholngs; chargeable to the dismes of the Clergie and yearelie wages
due to servants for their (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) service (other then the King&bholngs; servant&bholngs; taking yearelie wages of five pound&bholngs; or above) onelie
excepted and foreprised, And that all Plate Coyne Jewell&bholngs; Good&bholngs; Debt&bholngs; and Chattell&bholigct; &bhopubr;sonalls and all Land&bholngs;
Tenement&bholngs; and other the &bhopcrl;misses as aforesaid being in the rule and custodie of any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons to the use of anie
Corporacion Fra&bhotcrl;nitie Guild Misterie Brotherhood or anie C&bhooov;monaltie being corporate or not corporate be and shalbe
rated sett and charged by reason of this A&bholigct; at the value &bhoccrl;tified by the presenters in their Certificate for every pound
in good&bholngs; and debt&bholngs; as is aforesaid. And for every pound in Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; A&bhonov;uities Fees Corrodies and other
yearelie &bhopcrl;ffitt&bholngs; as is aforesaid, and the s&bhooov;mes that are above rehearsed sett and taxed to be levied and taken of them
that shall have such good&bholngs; in custodie or otherwise charged for Land&bholngs; as is before rehearsed, And the same &bhopubr;son and
&bhopubr;sons and bodies corporate by authoritie of this A&bholigct; shalbe discharged against him or them that shall or ought to have
the same at the tyme of the payment or deliverie thereof or at his otherwise departure from the custodie or possession
of the same. Except and alwaies foreprised from the charge and assessement of the said Subsidies all Goodes Chattell&bholngs;
Jewell&bholngs; and Ornament&bholngs; of Churches and Chapples, which have been ordained and used in Churches and Chappell&bholngs; for
the honor and service of Allmightie God.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Times of rating First and Second Subsidies.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Third Subsidy.; Fourth Subsidy.; Fifth Subsidy.; Sums of Money and the Names of Persons chargeable to the First Two Subsidies and of the Names of High Collectors certified to Exchequer before 9th July next; Subsidies paid into Exchequer in one intire Sum.; Payments in Liberties, &#x0026;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And the first two of the said five Subsidies shalbe by authoritie aforesaid taxed sessed and rated according to
this A&bholigct; in every Shire Riding Lath Wapentake Rape Citie Borough Towne and everie other place within this Realme
of England Wales and other the King&bholigct; Dominions before the last day of June now next c&bhooov;ming. And the third of
the said five Subsidies shall by the authoritie aforesaid be taxed sessed and rated before the twentith day of September
now next ensuing, And the fowerth of the said five Subsidies shall by the authoritie aforesaid be taxed sessed and
rated before the thirtith day of November next coming, And the fift and last of the said Subsidies shall by the
authoritie aforesaid be taxed sessed and rated before the tenth day of February now next ensuing. And the
particular s&bhooov;mes of every Shire Riding Borough Towne and other place aforesaid with the particular names of such
as are or shalbe chargeable to and for the payment of the said two first of the said five Subsidies to be taxed and
set by the C&bhooov;missioners for the same to be lymitted or two of them at the least with the names of the high
Colle&bholigct;ors and in the same forme shalbe &bhoccrl;tified into the King&bholngs; Exchequer before the nyneth day of July next c&bhooov;ming.
And the particular s&bhooov;mes of every Shire Riding Borough Towne and other places aforesaid with the particular names
of such as are chargeable for the third of the said five Subsidies to be taxed and set by the C&bhooov;missioners for the
same to be lymitted or two of them at the least with the names of the high Colle&bholigct;ors and in the same forme
shalbe certified into the King&bholngs;Exchequer before the tenth day of O&bholigct;ober next c&bhooov;ming, And the particular s&bhooov;mes of every Shire Riding Borough Towne and other Places aforesaid with the particular names of such as are chargeable
for the fowerth of the said five Subsidies to be taxed and set by the C&bhooov;missioners for the same to be lymitted or two
of them at the least with the names of the high Colle&bholigct;ors and in the same forme shalbe certified into the King&bholngs;
Exchequer before the tenth Day of December next c&bhooov;ming And the particular s&bhooov;mes of every Shire Riding Borough
Towne and other places aforesaid with the particular names of such as are chargeable for the fift and last of the said
Subsidies to be taxed and sett by the C&bhooov;missioners for the same to be lymitted or two of them at the least with the
names of the high Colle&bholigct;ors And in the same forme shalbe certified into the King&bholngs; Exchequer before the twentith
Day of Februarie next c&bhooov;ming, And the same s&bhooov;mes in forme aforesaid to be taxed to and for the payment of the
said two first of the said five subsidies shalbe paid in one entire s&bhooov;me into the King&bholngs; receipt of the Exchequer aforesaid
to the use of our said Soveraigne Lord at or before the tenth day of July now next c&bhooov;ming, And the said s&bhooov;mes in
manner and forme aforesaid to be taxed for the payment of the third of the said five subsidies shalbe paied in one
intire s&bhooov;me into the King&bholngs; receipt of the Exchequer aforesaid to the use of our said Soveraigne Lord at or before the
twentith day of O&bholngs;ober now next c&bhooov;ming, And the said s&bhooov;mes in manner and forme aforesaid to be taxed for the
payment of the fowerth of the said five Subsidies shalbe paid in one intire s&bhooov;me into the King&bholngs; receipt of the
Exchequer to the use of our said Soveraigne Lord at or before the twentith day of December now next [c&bhooov;ming,<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]
And the said s&bhooov;mes in manner and forme aforesaid to be taxed for the payment of the fift and last of the said five
Subsidies shalbe paid in one intire s&bhooov;me into the King&bholngs; receipt of the Exchequer to the use of our said Soveraigne
Lord at or before the first day of March now next c&bhooov;ming, And the s&bhooov;mes abovesaid of and for the said Subsidies
shalbe taxed set asked and demaunded taken gathered levied and paid to the use of our said Soveraigne Lord his
Heires and Successors in forme aforesaid aswell within Liberties Francheses Sanctuaries Auncient [demesnes<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] and other
whatsoever places exempt or not exempt as without (except such Shires places and &bhopubr;sons as shalbe foreprised in and
by this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;) any Graunt Charter Prescripcion Use or Libertie by reason of any l&bhoalias;res Patent&bholngs; or other Priviledge
Prescripcion Allowance for the same or whatsoever other matter or discharge heretofore to the contrary made graunted
used or obtayned notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>VI. Absentees whether Natives or Aliens charged by Certificate of Inhabitants of the Place.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Rule by which they are to be charged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, that every such &bhopubr;son aswell such as be borne
under the King&bholngs; obeysance as every other &bhopubr;son Stranger borne Denizen or not Denizen inhabiting within this Realme
or within Wales or other the King&bholngs; Dominions, which at the tyme of the same assessing&bholngs; or Taxacions or any or every
of them to be had or made shalbe out of this Realme or out of Wales and have good&bholngs; chattell&bholngs; lands or tenement&bholngs;
Fees or a&bhonov;uities or other &bhopubrc;ffitt&bholngs; within this Realme or in Wales shalbe charged and chargeable for the same by the
Certificate of the Inhabitant&bholngs; of the place where such Good&bholngs; chattell&bholngs; land&bholngs; tenement&bholngs; or other the &bhopcrl;misses then
shalbee or in such place where such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons or his or their Fa&bholigct;or Deputy or Attorny shall have his or their most
resort unto within this Realme or in Wales in like manner as if the said &bhopubr;son were or had byn at the tyme of the said
assessing within this Realme. [And that every &bhopubr;son abiding or dwelling within or without this Realme<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] shalbe charged
and chargeable to the said severall Subsidies graunted by this A&bholigct; according and after the rate of such yearelie substance
or value of lands or tenement&bholngs; goode&bholngs; chattell&bholngs; and other the &bhopcrl;misses, as every &bhopubr;son so to be charged shalbe set at,
at the tyme of the said assessing or taxacion uppon him to be made and no otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>VII. Commissioners to be appointed by Lord Chancellor and other great Officers.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners not to execute A&bholigct; out of their Limits;Certificate by Commissioners into the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid, that for the assessing and ordering of the said five severall Subsidies
to be duly had the Lord Chauncellor of England or the Lord Keeper of the great Seale, the Lord Tresurer of
England the Lord President of the King&bholngs; Councell the Lord Privie Seale the Lord Admirall of England the Lord
Steward of the King&bholngs; houshold and the Lord Chamberlayne of the Kings most honorable Houshold for the Tyme
being or two of them at the least (whereof the Lord Chauncellor or Lord Keeper of the great Seale for the tyme
being to be one) shall and may name and appoint of and for every Shire Riding and other Places aswell within this
Realme as within Wales and other the King&bholngs; Dominions, as also of and for every Citie and Towne being a Countie
of it selfe and of and for the Isle of Wight such certaine nomber of &bhopubr;sons of every of the same Shires Riding&bholngs;
Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Cities Towne and Isle of Wight and every other Place as they shall thinke convenient
to be C&bhooov;missioners of and within the same place whereof they bee inhabitant&bholngs;, and also of and for the honorable
houshold of the King&bholngs; Majestie, in what Shire or other place the said houshold shall happen then to be. And the
Lord Chauncellor or Lord Keeper of the great Seale for the tyme being and other with him before named or two
of them as is aforesaid in like manner may name and appoint of every other such Cittie Borough and Towne
corporate aswell in England as in Wales and other the King&bholngs; Dominions as they shall thinke fitt and requisite sixe
five fower three or two of the head Officers and other honest inhabitant&bholngs; in every of the said Citties Boroughes
and Townes corporate according to the nomber and multitude of the people being in the same, The which &bhopubr;sons
(if any such be) thereunto named of the said Inhabitant&bholngs; of the said Cities Boroughes Townes Corporate not being
Counties of themselves shalbe joyned and put in as C&bhooov;missioners with the &bhopubr;sons named for such Shires and Riding&bholngs;
as the said Cities Boroughes and Townes corporate not being Counties in themselves be set and have their being:
Which &bhopubr;sons soe named of and for the said Cities Boroughes and Townes corporate not being Counties by reason
of their dwelling in the same shall not take uppon them or any of them to put any part of their C&bhooov;mission in execucion
for the &bhopcrl;misses out of the said Cities Boroughes and Townes corporate wherein they be soe named nor to execute
the said C&bhooov;mission within the Citie Burrough or Towne corporate where they shalbe so dwelling, but at such daies
and tymes as the said other C&bhooov;missioners for the same Shire or Riding shall thereunto lymitt and appoint within
the said Citie Borough and Towne corporate not being a Countie whereof they be soe named and not out of the
said Citie Borough or Towne and in that manner to be ayding and assisting with the said other C&bhooov;missioners in and
for the good executing of the effe&bholigct; of the said C&bhooov;mission uppon paine of every of the said C&bhooov;missioners soe named
for every such Citie Borough and Towne corporate not being a Countie to make such Fine as the said other
C&bhooov;missioners in the C&bhooov;mission of and for the same Shire or Riding so named or three of them at the least shall by
their discrecions set and certifie into the King&bholngs; Exchequer there to be levied to the use of the King&bholngs; Majestie in
like manner as if such or like s&bhooov;mes had byn set and rated uppon every such &bhopubr;son for the said Subsidies.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VIII. Such Commissioners not to have Fees.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Several Commissions dire&bholigct;ed out of Chancery.; Schedules delivered to Commissioners.; Commissioners to divide themselves.; copellable to a&bholigct; out of their Shires</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">The which C&bhooov;missioners so named of and for the said Cities Boroughes and Townes not being Counties, and
onelie put into the said C&bhooov;missions by reason of their dwelling in the same, shall not have any part or porcion
of the Fees [or<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] reward&bholngs; of the C&bhooov;missioners and their Clerkes in this A&bholigct; [afterward&bholngs;<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] specified and allowed. And
the Lord Chauncellor of England or Keep of the great Seale of England for the tyme being shall make and
dire&bholigct; out of the Court of Chauncery under the great Seale severall C&bhooov;missions, That is to saie, for every Shire
Riding Lathe Wapentake Rape Citie Towne Borough Isle and the said houshold unto such &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons as
by his discrecion and such of the other with him before named and appointed as is before rehearsed shalbe
thought sufficient for the sessing and levying of the said five severall Subsidies in all Shires and Places according
to the true meaning of this A&bholigct;, which C&bhooov;missions for the payment of the said two first of the said Subsidies
shalbe dire&bholigct;ed and delivered to the said C&bhooov;missioners or to one of them before the twentith day of June now
next c&bhooov;ming, And the C&bhooov;mission for the payment of the third of the said five Subsidies shalbe dire&bholigct;ed and
delivered to the said C&bhooov;missioners or to one of them before the last day of the Moneth of August now next c&bhooov;ming.
And the C&bhooov;mission for the payment of the fourth of the said five Subsidies shalbe dire&bholigct;ed and delivered to the
said C&bhooov;missioners or to one (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) before the tenth day of November next comming, And the C&bhooov;mission for the payment
of the fifth and last of the said Subsidies shalbe dire&bholigct;ed and delivered to the said C&bhooov;missioners or to one of them
before the twentith day of Januarie now next ensuing. And to every of the said C&bhooov;missions tenne Schedules
conteyning in them the tenor of this A&bholigct; shalbe affiled. And for the C&bhooov;missioners better discovery of Popish
Recusant&bholngs; severall Schedules shalbe delivered unto them with their severall C&bhooov;missions out of the Exchequer and
Certificates from the Clerkes of the Assizes and of the Peace and other the like Officers and from the Ministers
and Churchwardens of every Parishe of the names of such Popish Recusant&bholigct;as are to be charged by this A&bholigct;,
By the which C&bhooov;mission the C&bhooov;missioners in every such C&bhooov;mission named according to this A&bholigct;e and as many of
them as shalbe appointed by the said C&bhooov;mission shall have full power and authoritie to put the effe&bholigct; of the said
C&bhooov;mission in Execucion And that by authoritie of this A&bholigct;e after such C&bhooov;mission to them delivered they may by their
assent&bholngs; and agreement&bholngs; sever themselves for the execucion of their C&bhooov;mission [by<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Hundreds Lathes Wardes Rapes
Wapentakes Townes Parishes and other Places within the lymitt&bholngs; of the said C&bhooov;mission in such forme as to them
shall seeme expedient to be ordered and betweene them to be c&bhooov;muned and agreed according to the tenor and effe&bholigct;
of the C&bhooov;mission to them therein directed, Uppon which severance every &bhopubr;son of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament that shalbe
C&bhooov;missioner shalbe assigned to the Hundred where he dwelleth. Provided alwaies that no &bhopubr;son be or shalbe
nominated or appointed to be any C&bhooov;missioner to or for the execucion of this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct;, but onelie in the Shire
where he hath a Mansion house wherein he or his familie have resided and inhabited by the greatest part of three
yeares last past, And that any &bhopubr;son assigned to the contrary thereof in any wife shall not be compelled to put in
execucion the effe&bholigct; of this A&bholigct; or anie part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>IX. Commissioner being a Popish Recusant, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">or not having a Mansion-house, &#x0026;c.; Acting, Penalty &pound;100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">Provided alwaies, and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that if any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons shalbe named a
C&bhooov;missioner or C&bhooov;missioners for the assessing or ordering of the said five Subsidies or anie part of them that either
shalbe a Popish Recusant that hath forborne [to repayre<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] to some Church Chappell or usuall publike place of C&bhooov;mon,
Prayer to heare divine Service by the space of six moneths next before the end of this Session of Parliament, Or
that hath not in his or their owne possession and occupacion a Mansion house wherein he or they or his or their
family or families, or part of them have resided for the most part of three yeares next before the end of this Session
of Parliament scituate and being within the Countie wherein he or they shalbe named a C&bhooov;missioner or C&bhooov;missioners
as aforesaid and shall by vertue or colour of such C&bhooov;mission take uppon him or them to assesse or order any of the
said five Subsidies or anie part of them shall forfeit for every time that he or they shall take uppon him or them to
assesse or order any of the said five Subsidies or any part of them the s&bhooov;me of one hundred pound&bholngs; of lawfull mony
of England, The one Moytie to be to the use of the poore within the Countie or within the Riding or Division
of the Countie wherein he or they shall offend contrary to this A&bholigct;, and the said Moitie shalbe disposed of by the
C&bhooov;missioners of the Peace within the said Countie Riding or Division or by the greater nomber of them at their
generall Sessions of the Peace to be holden within the said Countie Riding or Division where the offence shalbe
c&bhooov;mitted as aforesaid and the other moytie to such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons as shall sue for the same in any Court of
Record by Accion of Debt Bill Plaint or Informacion wherein no Essoyne Proteccion or Wager of Law shalbe
allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>X. Commissioners to execute A&bholigct; according to the Tenor thereof.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to direct Precepts to certain Number of Inhabitants of Hundreds, &#x0026;c. to appear before Commissioners.; Persons who receive Precepts are to show such Precepts to the other Inhabitants named therein.; Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by [the<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, that the C&bhooov;missioners and every of them
which shalbe named lymitted and appointed according to this A&bholigct; to be C&bhooov;missioners in every such Shire Riding
Lathe Wapentake Rape Citie Towne Borough Isle and the said houshold or any other place and none other shall
trulie effe&bholigct;uallie and diligentlie for their Part&bholngs; execute the effe&bholigct; of this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; according to the tenor thereof
in every behalfe and no otherwise by anie meanes without omission favour dread malice or anie other thing to be
attempted or done by them or anie of them to the contrary thereof, And the said C&bhooov;missioners or as many of them
as shalbe appointed by the said C&bhooov;mission and none other for the execution of the said C&bhooov;mission and A&bholigct; shall for
the taxacion of the said two first of the said five Subsidies before the five and twentith day of June next c&bhooov;ming
And for the taxacion of the third of the said five Subsidies shall before the tenth day of September next ensuing,
And for the taxacion of the fourth of the said five Subsidies shall before the twentith day of November next c&bhooov;ming
And for the taxacion of the fift and last of the said Subsidies shall before the one and thirtith day of January next 
ensuing by vertue of the C&bhooov;mission delivered unto them in forme aforesaid dire&bholigct; their severall or joynt Precept or
Precept&bholigct; unto eight seaven sixe five foure three or two (as for the nomber of Inhabitants shalbe requisite) of the
most substanciall discreet and honest psons inhabitant&bholngs; to be named by the said C&bhooov;missioners or by as many of
them as shalbe appointed by the said C&bhooov;mission of and in Hundred&bholigct; Lathes Rapes Wapentakes Ward&bholngs; Parishes
Townes and other Places aswell within Lib[er]ties Francheses Ancient demesnes places exempted and San&bholigct;uaries
as without within the lymitt&bholngs; of the Shires Ridings Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Cities Townes Boroughs and Isle
aforesaid and other places within the lymitts of their C&bhooov;mission and to the Constables Subconstables Bayliff&bholngs; and
other like Officers and Ministers of every the said Hundred&bholngs; Townes Wards Lathe&bholngs; Wapentakes Parishes and other
places aforesaid as to the said C&bhooov;missioners and every nomber of them or to three or two of them by their discrecion
in division shall seeme expedient and as by the manner and use of those part&bholngs; shalbe requisite, straightly by the said
Precept charging and c&bhooov;maunding the said Inhabitant&bholngs; Constables and other Officers aforesaid to whome such
Precept shalbe soe: dire&bholigct;ed to appeare in their &bhopubrc;per &bhopubr;sons before the said C&bhooov;missioners or such nomber of them as
they shall divide themselves according to the tenor of the said C&bhooov;mission at certaine dayes and Places by the said
C&bhooov;missioners or any such nomber of them as is aforesaid within Cities Boroughes [and<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Townes corporate or without
in any other places as is aforesaid by their discrecion to be lymitted thereunto to doe and accomplish all that to
them on the part of the King&bholngs; Majestie shalbe enjoyned touching this A&bholigct; C&bhooov;maunding further by the same Precept
that he to whose hand&bholngs; such Precept shall come, shall shew and deliver the same to the other Inhabitant&bholngs; or Officers
named in the same Precept, And that none of them faile to accomplish the same uppon paine of fortie shilling&bholngs; to
be forfeited to the King&bholngs; Majestie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>XI. Persons named in such Precepts to appear before the Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Such Persons making Default or refusing to serve.; Penalty 40s.; Oath not allowed on Inquiry into the Substance of Persons liable to be charged.; Penalty.; Commissioners to read Rates openly.; and after such Charge, ; Commissioners to limit another Day.; Persons not attending.; Penalty 40s.; Penalty 40s; Commissioners to examine Presenters.; Further Proceedings on Assessments.; Commissioners suspecting greater Substance or Value than specified, ; to order personal Appearances of Persons charged.; Such Persons not appearing, ; Penalty double Value of Rate.; Oath not allowed on Inquiry into Substance of Persons liable to be charged.; Spiritual Persons how rated for Temporal Possessions</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And it is further ordeyned by the Authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament that at the said day and place &bhopcrl;fixed and
lymited in the said Precept every of the said C&bhooov;missioners then being in the Shire and not having sufficient excuse
for his absence at the day and place &bhopcrl;fixed for that [place<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] whereunto he was lymitted shall appeare in his owne &bhopubrc;per
&bhopubr;son and there the same C&bhooov;missioners being &bhopcrl;sent or as many of them as shalbe appointed by the 
King&bholngs; Majesties
C&bhooov;mission shall call or cause to be called before them the said Inhabitant&bholngs; and officers to whome they have dire&bholigct;ed
their said Precept&bholngs; and which had in c&bhooov;maundement there to appeare by vertue of the said &bhopcrl;cept, And if any
&bhopubr;son so warned make default unles he then be letted by sicknesse or lawfull excuse and that let be then witnessed by
the oathes of two credible &bhopubr;sons, or if any appearing refuse to serve in forme following, Then every such &bhopubr;son so
making default or refusing to serve shall forfeit to the King&bholngs; Majestie fortie shilling&bholngs;, and soe at every tyme appointed
by the said C&bhooov;missioners for the said severall Taxacions untill such tyme the nomber of every such &bhopubr;sons have
appeared and certified in forme underwritten every of them soe making default or refusing to serve shall forfeit to
the King&bholngs; Majestie fortie shilling&bholngs;, and uppon the same appearance had they shalbe charged before the C&bhooov;missioners
by all convenient waies and meanes (other then by corporall oath) to enquire of the value of the substance after the
usuall manner of every &bhopubr;son dwelling and abiding within the lymitt&bholngs; of the places that they shalbe charged with,
and of other which shall have his or their most resort unto any of the said places and chargeable with any s&bhooov;me of
mony by this A&bholigct; of the said Subsidies and of all other things requisit touching the said A&bholigct;i and according to the
intent of the same, and thereuppon as neere as it may be or shall come to their knowledge without respe&bholigct;of any
former taxacion heretofore had trulie to &bhopcrl;sent and certifie before the said C&bhooov;missioners the names and surnames and
the substance and values of every of them after the usuall manner as aforesaid as well of Land&bholngs; Tenement&bholngs; and
other Hereditament&bholngs; possessions and proffitt&bholngs; [and<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] of good&bholngs; chattell&bholngs; debt&bholngs; and other thing&bholngs; chargeable by the same
A&bholigct;.e without any concealment love favour affeccion dread or malice upon paine of forfeiture of five pound&bholngs; or more
to be taxed extra&bholigct;ed and levied in forme as hereafter in this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; shalbe lymitted or appointed And thereuppon
the said C&bhooov;missioners shall openlie there reade or cause to be read unto them the said rates in this A&bholigct; men&bhocotil;ned
and openlie declare the effe&bholigct; of their charge unto them in what manner and forme they ought and should make
their Certificates according to the rates and s&bhooov;mes thereof abovesaid and of all manner of &bhopubr;sons as well Aliens and
Straungers Denizens or not Denizens inhabiting within this Realme as of such Popish Recusant&bholngs; and others &bhopubr;sons as
be borne under the King&bholngs;. obeysance chargeable to this A&bholigct; and of the possessions good&bholngs; and chattell&bholngs; of Fraternities
Guilds Corporacions Brotherhood&bholngs; Misteries C&bhooov;monalties and other as is abovesaid and of &bhopubr;sons being in the part&bholngs;
beyond the Seas having Goodes and Chattell&bholngs; Land&bholngs; or Tenement&bholngs; within this Realme as is aforesaid and of all
good&bholngs; being in the Custodie of any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;son to the use of any other as is abovesaid, by the which Informacion
and shewing the said &bhopubr;sons may have such plaine knowledge of the true intent of this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; and of the manner
of their Certificate, that the same &bhopubr;sons shall have no reasonable cause to excuse them by ignorance, And after
such charge and the Statute of the said Subsidies and the manner of the said Certificate to be made in writing
conteyning the names and surnames of every &bhopubr;son and whether he be borne without the King&bholngs; Dominions or within
and the value of every &bhopubr;son in every degree as well of the yearelie value of Land&bholngs; and Tenement&bholngs; and of such like
possessions and proffitt&bholngs; as of the value of good&bholngs; and chattells debt&bholngs; and every thing to their Certificate requisite
and necessarie to them declared the said C&bhooov;missioners there being shall by their discrecions lymitt and appoint unto
the said &bhopubr;sons another day and place to appeare before the said C&bhooov;missioners and charging the said &bhopubr;sons that they
shall in the meane tyme make diligent inquiry by all waies and meanes of the &bhopcrl;misses, and then and there every of
them uppon paine of forfeiture of fortie shilling&bholngs; to the King&bholngs; Majestie to appeare at the said next &bhopcrl;fixed day and
place there to certifie unto the said C&bhooov;missioners in writing according to their said charge and according to the true
intent of the said Graunt of Subsidie and as to them in manner aforesaid, hath byn declared and shewed by the
C&bhooov;missioners, At which day and place so to them &bhopcrl;fixed if any of the said &bhopubr;sons make default or appeare and refuse
to make the said Certificate then every of them so offending to forfeit to the King&bholngs; Majestie fortie shilling&bholngs; (except
there be a reasonable excuse of his default by reason of his sicknes or otherwise by the oathes of two credible &bhopubr;sons
there witnessed) and of such as appeare ready to make Certificate as is aforesaid the said C&bhooov;missioners there being
shall take and receive the same Certificate and every part thereof and the names values and substance of every &bhopubr;son so
certified, And if the said C&bhooov;missioners see cause reasonable they shall examine the said Presenters thereof, and
thereup[p]on the said C&bhooov;missioners at the said daies and place by their agreement amongest themselves shall from tyme
to tyme there openlie &bhopcrl;fixe a day at a certaine place or places within the lymitts of their C&bhooov;mission by their discrecion
for their further &bhopubrc;ceeding to the said assessing of the same Subsidies And thereuppon at the said day of the said
Certificate as is aforesaid taken the same C&bhooov;missioners shall make their Precept or Precepts to the Constables
Subconstables Bailiffes or other Officers of such Hundreds Wapentakes Townes or other places aforesaid as the same
C&bhooov;missioners shalbe of comprising and contayning in the said Precepts the names and surnames of all &bhopubr;sons &bhopcrl;sented
before them in the said Certificate of whome [if<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] the said C&bhooov;missioners or as many of them as shalbe thereunto
appointed by the Kings C&bhooov;mission shall (<ref idref="n18">18</ref>) have vehement suspect to be of more greater value or substance in Lands
Goods Chattells or s&bhooov;mes of mony owing unto them or other substance aforesaid then is uppon such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons
soe certified and specified as aforesaid the same C&bhooov;missioners shall make their Precept or Precepts directed to the
Constables Bailiffs or other Officers c&bhooov;maunding them to whome such &bhopcrl;cept shalbe directed to warne such &bhopubr;sons
whose names shalbe comprised in the said Precepts at their mansions or to their &bhopubr;sons that the same &bhopubr;sons named in
such Precepts and every of them shall &bhopubr;sonallie appeare before the said C&bhooov;missioners at the said new &bhopcrl;fixed day and
place there to be examined by all waies and meanes (other then by corporall oath) by the said C&bhooov;missioners of their
substance and value in manner as aforesaid and of all and every s&bhooov;mes of mony owing to them and other whatsoever
matter concerning the &bhopcrl;misses or any of them according to this Act. At which day and place so &bhopcrl;fixed the said
C&bhooov;missioners then and there being or as many of them as shall be thereunto appointed by the Kings C&bhooov;mission shall
cause to be called the said &bhopubr;sons whose names shalbe comprised in the said Precept as is aforesaid for their examinacion
And if any of those &bhopubr;sons which shalbe warned as aforesaid to be examined (which at any tyme after the warning and
before the day &bhopcrl;fixed shalbe within such place as he may have knowledge of his said appearance to be made) shall
make default and not appeare unlesse a reasonable cause or excuse by the oathes of two credible &bhopubr;sons before the said
C&bhooov;missioners be trulie alleaged for his discharge, that then every of them soe making default to be taxed and charged
to the Kings Majestie with and at the double s&bhooov;me of the rate that he should or ought to have byn sett at for and
after the value aforesaid of his lands or substance uppon him certified if he had appeared by the discrecion of the
C&bhooov;missioners there being, which C&bhooov;missioners shall travaile with every of the other &bhopubr;sons so then and there appearing
whose names shalbe expressed in the said &bhopcrl;cept or &bhopcrl;cepts and in whome any vehement suspect was or shalbe had
in forme aforesaid by all waies and meanes they can (other then by corporall oath) for the better knowledge of their
value as aforesaid either in Hereditaments or possessions or else in goods or debts, and thereuppon shall have power and
authoritie by vertue of this Act according to their discrecions to inlarge and increase the taxacion of such &bhopubr;sons as
they shall soe finde by due examinacion to be of greater value or substance in lands or goods then they were &bhopcrl;sented
at, And that every Spirituall &bhopubr;son at every of the said taxacions of the said Subsidies shalbe rated and sett according
to the rate abovesaid of and for every pound that the same spirituall &bhopubr;son or any other to his use hath by
discent bargaine or purchase in Fee simple or Fee taile terme of life terme of yeres by execucion wardshipp (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) coppie
of Court Roll in any Mannors landes tenements rents s[er]vices offices fees corrodies a&bhonov;uities and Hereditaments after
the true just and yearelie value thereof and according as other the Kings Majesties Subjects borne within this Realme
be charged in forme above remembred so that it extend to the yearelie value of twentie shillings or above.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>XII. Proviso as to Englishmen being Nobility of Scotland and Ireland only residing in England.</head>
			<para id="p22">And it is further enacted by the Authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament that every Englishman residing in England
being a Viscount of Scotland or Ireland and not a Peere of the Realme of England shall not be taxed or rated in
the Subsidie Booke under one hundred pounds in lands And that every Englishman residing in England being a Baron
of Scotland or Ireland and not a Peere of the Realme of England shall not be taxed or rated in the Subsidie Booke
under one hundred markes in land, And that every Englishman being a Baronett of Scotland or Ireland shall not be
taxed or rated in the Subsidie Booke under fortie pounds in land.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XIII. Assessors misbehaving.</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may set a Fine upon them.; Estreated into the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And it is further enacted that if the said Taxors or Assessors shall not dulie behave themselves in their inquirie
taxacion Assessement or Certificate but shall affeccionatelie corruptlie or partially demeasne themselves in that behalfe
in such wise that the C&bhooov;missioners shall by their consideracions deeme them offenders worthie of punishment for not
doing their duties therein, that then foure or more of the C&bhooov;missioners in that Countie for the said Subsidie shall have
power and authoritie by their discrecions either to charge the said Assessors uppon their corporall oathes for the better
service aforesaid in that behalfe or else by their discrecions to taxe and set uppon the said Assessors for their
misdemeanors in that behalfe such a fine or paine as they shall thinke good, so that it exceed not the s&bhooov;me of tenne
pounds and the same fine or paine at their discrecions to estreat into the Court of (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Exchequer, Every which Fine
so taxed and set by foure of the said C&bhooov;missioners or more and being estreated with the Scedule and Bookes of that
lymitt shalbe levied and aunswered to the Kings use in like manner and forme to all intents and purposes as any other
s&bhooov;mes that shalbe taxed and become due by vertue of this Statute and Acte of Subsidie and not in any other wise
or manner.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XIV. Remedy for Persons aggrieved by the Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p25">And if any &bhopubr;son certified or rated by vertue of this Acte whether he be a C&bhooov;missioner or other to any manner
of value doth finde himselfe greived with the same &bhopcrl;sentment sessing or rating and thereuppon complaine to the
C&bhooov;missioners before whome he shalbe called sessed or taxed or before two of them before the same taxacion be certified
in the Court of Exchequer, that then the said C&bhooov;missioners or two of them shall by all waies and meanes examine
particulerlie and distinctlie the &bhopubr;son so complayning uppon his oath and other his neighbors by their discrecions of
every his Lands and Tenements above specified and of every his goods chattells and debts above mencioned, And
after due examinacion and &bhopubr;fect knowledge thereof had and &bhopubr;ceived by the said C&bhooov;missioners or two of them
which shall have power by Authoritie aforesaid the said C&bhooov;missioners or two of them to whome any such complaint
shalbe made by their discrecions upon the oath of the said &bhopubr;son soe complayning may abate defaulk increase or
inlarge the said assessments according as it shall appeare unto them just uppon the same examinacion, and the same;
s&bhooov;me soe abated defalked increased or inlarged shall be by them estreated in forme as is hereafter specified, And
if it be proved by witnesses or by the parties owne confession or other lawfull waies or meanes within a yeare after
any such oath made that the same &bhopubr;son so rated and sworne was of any better or greater value in lands goods or
other things above specified at the tyme of his said oath then the same &bhopubr;son so sworne did declare upon his said
oath, that then every such &bhopubr;son so offending shall lose and forfeit to the Kings Majestie soe much lawfull mony
of England as he the same &bhopubr;son soe sworne was set at or taxed to pay.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XV. Commissioners to be rated at such Place where they shall be Commissioners;</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">other Persons where they have resided for the most Part of the Year.; Absentees assessed where last abiding.; Rate to be according to Substance of Persons liable</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">And also it is enacted by the same Authoritie that every &bhopubr;son to be rated and taxed as is aforesaid shalbe rated
and set and the s&bhooov;me on him set to be levied at such place where he and his family were resident for the most part
of the yere next before the same &bhopcrl;sentment and taxacion made and no where else And that no C&bhooov;missioner for his
Subsidie shalbe rated or taxed for his goods or lands but in the Shire or (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) place where he shalbe [a<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] C&bhooov;missioner
And that if any &bhopubr;son chargeable by this Act at the tyme of the said assessings happen to be out of this Realme and
out of Wales or farre from the place where he shalbe knowen then he to be set where hee was last abiding within
this Realme or in Wales and after the substance value and other proffitts of every &bhopubr;son to bee knowen by examinacion
Certificate or other manner of way as is aforesaid, And that the said C&bhooov;missioners or as many of them as shalbe
appointed by the Kings Majesties C&bhooov;mission or C&bhooov;missions shall after the rate and rates aforesaid cause every &bhopubr;son
so to be set rated and taxed according to the rate of the substance and value of his lands goods chattells and
other proffitts chargeable by this Act, whereby the greatest or best s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes according to his substance as
aforesaid by reason of this Act might or may be set or taxed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XVI. Remedy for Commissioners and other Persons taxed in any Place other than where they are Commissioners, or where resiant for most part of the preceding Year.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Fee for Allowance</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">And that every &bhopubr;son taxed in any Countie or place other then where he (<ref idref="n23">23</ref>) is a C&bhooov;missioner for the Subsidie if he
be a C&bhooov;missioner upon certificate made to the said Court of Exchequer under the hands and seales of two
C&bhooov;missioners for the same Subsidie in the same Countie or Place where such &bhopubr;son and his family were resiant for the
most part of the yeare then next before or where he is a C&bhooov;missioner for the taxacion and payment of the same
Subsidie testifying his most resiaunce, having a family or being a C&bhooov;missioner shalbe a sufficient discharge for the
taxacion of that &bhopubr;son in any other places and of and for all other s&bhooov;mes of mony uppon such &bhopubr;sons [to be<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] set
and taxed save onelie the taxacions made in that Countie [and<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] place, from which such certificate shalbe made as is
aforesaid, and for the s&bhouov;me of mony upon such &bhopubr;son there assessed or taxed, And that such certificate without
any Plea or other circumstance shalbe a sufficient warrant as well to the Barons and Auditor and Auditors of the
said Court of Exchequer as to all and every other Officers to whome the allowance thereof shall appertaine paying
for such discharge and allowance onelie sixe pence and no more.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XVII. Double Charge not to be allowed.</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Remedy in respect of Double Charges</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">Provided allwayes that every such &bhopubr;son that shalbe rated or taxed according to the true meaning of this Act
for paying of and to theise Subsidies for and after the yearelie value of his Landes Tenements or other reall
possessions or proffitts at any of the said taxacions shall not after be set and taxed for his goods and chattells or
other moveable substance at the same taxacion, and that he that shalbe set charged or taxed for the same Subsidie
for his goods chattells and other moveables at any of the said taxacions according to the true meaning of this Act
shall not after be taxed charged or chargeable for his lands or other reall possessions or proffitts aforesaid at the
same taxacions or any of them, nor that any &bhopubr;son by any taxacion be doubly charged for the said Subsidies nor set
or rated at severall places by reason of this Acte, But if any &bhopubr;son happen to be double set taxed or charged either
in one place or [in<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] severall places then he to be discharged of the one taxacion and charged with the other according
to the [true<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] meaning and intent of this Act, any thing contayned in this &bhopcrl;sent Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVIII. Proviso for Persons having two Mansions, or being Household Servants or Waiting Servants to the King or others.</head>
			<para id="p32">
				<emph type="i">Persons unduly escaping Taxation; ; on Proof thereof before Commissioners or Barons of Exchequer; ; Taxed at double Value</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p33">And be it ordayned and enacted by the authoritie of this present Parliament That no &bhopubr;son having two mansions
or two places to resort unto or calling himselfe Houshold servant or Waiting servant to the Kings Majestie or other
Lord or Lady master or mistresse be excused uppon his saying from the taxes of the said Subsidies in neither of
the places where he may be set or taxed unlesse he bring a Certificate in Writing from the C&bhooov;missioners where
he is so set or taxed indeed at one place And if any &bhopubr;son that ought to be set and taxed to these &bhopcrl;sent Subsidies by
reason of his removing or resorting to two places or by reason of his saying that he was elswhere taxed or by reason
of any Priviledge of his dwelling or abiding in any place not being foreprised in this Act or otherwise by his covine
or craft or by any words or sayings or otherwise, Or if any that is a C&bhooov;missioner or Assessor of others happen to
escape from the said [taxacion<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] from the payment of these Subsidies or any of them and be not set and taxed according
to the true intent of this Act and that proved by Presentment Examinacion Informacion or otherwise before the
said C&bhooov;missioners or two of them or before the Barons of the Kings Majesties Exchequer or two Justies of Peace
of that Countie where such &bhopubr;son dwelleth Then every such &bhopubr;son that by such meanes or otherwise willinglie by
covine or without just cause shall happen to escape from the said taxacions or payments aforesaid or any of them and
shall not be rated taxed and set shalbe charged upon the knowledge and proofe thereof with and at the double value
of so much as he should might or ought to have bene set or taxed at by vertue of this Act, And the same double
value to be levied gathered and paid of his goods and Chattells Lands and Tenements towards the said Subsidies,
and further to be punished according to the discrecions of the said Barons Justices or C&bhooov;missioners before whome he
shalbe convicted for his offence and deceit in that behalfe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XIX. The Power of Commissioners to tax other Commissioners, and also Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Barons and Persons of higher Estate taxed by the Lord Chancellor, Lord Treasurer, and other Persons named by the King.; Rate estreated and certified</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">And be it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the said C&bhooov;missioners in every C&bhooov;mission which shalbe
or inhabite in any countie or place within the lymitts of their C&bhooov;mission or the more part of them shall have full
power and authoritie by this Act to set taxe and sesse every other C&bhooov;missioner joyned with them in every such
C&bhooov;mission and the said C&bhooov;missioners within their Division shall (<ref idref="n29">29</ref>) assesse every Assessor within their Division for his
or their goods lands and other the &bhopcrl;misses as is [aforesaid;<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] By which said C&bhooov;mission the said C&bhooov;missioners to
whome it shall appertaine shall indifferentlie sett taxe and sesse them[selves<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] and the said Assessors, and that aswell
the s&bhooov;mes uppon every of the said C&bhooov;missioners and Assessors so assessed rated and taxed as the s&bhooov;mes made and
&bhopcrl;sented by the Presenters as is abovesaid shalbe written certified sett and estreated and the Estreats thereof to be
made with other the inhabitants of that part and within the lymitts of the same C&bhooov;mission and Division so to be
gathered and levied in like manner as it ought and should have byn if the said C&bhooov;missioners had not byn in the said
C&bhooov;mission And that all &bhopubr;sons of the estate of a Baron or Baronesse and every estate above shalbe charged with their
freehold and value as is aforesaid by the Chauncellor or the Lord Keeper of the great Seale of England and the
high Treasurer of England for the tyme being or the one of them together with other such &bhopubr;sons as by the Kings
Majesties authoritie or c&bhooov;maundement shalbe named and appointed and they to be charged for the said severall payments
of the said Subsidies after the forme of the said Graunt according to the taxacion aforesaid And the s&bhooov;mes of and
uppon them to be taxed and sett with the names of the Collectors appointed for gathering and paying of the same
to be estreated delivered and certified at the daies and places above specified by the Lord Chauncellor or Lord
Keeper of the great Seale and Lord Tresurer or one of them together with such other &bhopubr;sons as thereunto shalbe
named as is aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XX. Rates estreated under the Sign Manual and Seals of Commissioners; and Estreats delivered to Sufficient Inhabitants, &#x0026;c. of Hundreds, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">By virtue of Estreat Officers, &#x0026;c.; to levy Rate.; Distress.; If Rate not paid in Eight Days, then Distress appraised and sold.; Officers, &#x0026;c. to answer for the Portion limited to them only.; Allowance to Officers on Rate recovered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">And be it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid, That after the Taxes and assesses of the said s&bhooov;mes uppon
and by the said assessing and certificate as is aforesaid made, the said C&bhooov;missioners or as many of them as shalbe
thereunto appointed and have authoritie by the Kings Majesties C&bhooov;mission shall with all speed and without delay by
their writing estreate the said taxes thereof under the Seales and Signes Manual of the said C&bhooov;missioners or as many
of them as shalbe appointed at the least; And the same shall deliver unto sufficient and substanciall Inhabitants
Constables Subconstables Bayliffes and other Officers joyntlie of Hundreds Townes Parishes and other places aforesaid
within their lymitts and to other sufficient &bhopubr;sons Inhabitants of the same onely by the discrecion of the (<ref idref="n32">32</ref>)
C&bhooov;missioners with the assent of the high Collector and as the place and parties shall require aswell the particuler
names and surnames as the remembrance of all s&bhooov;mes of mony taxed and sett of and uppon every &bhopubr;son as well man
as woman chargeable by this Act Housholders and all other Inhabitants and dwellers within the said &bhopubr;ishes Townes
and places contributory to this Act of Subsidies: By authoritie of which writing and estreat soe delivered the said
Officers and other &bhopubr;sons soe named and deputed severally shall have full power and authoritie by vertue of this Act
ymediatelie after the delivery of the said writing or estreat to demaund levy and gather of every &bhopubr;son therein specified
the s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes in the same writing [or estreat<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] comprised and for non payment thereof to distreyne the same &bhopubr;son
or &bhopubr;sons soe being behind by their goods and chattells and the distresse soe taken to keepe by the space of eight
daies at the costs and chargs of the owner thereof And if the said owner doe not pay such s&bhooov;me of money as
shall be taxed uppon him or her by authoritie of this Acte within the same eight daies, then the same distresse to be
appraised by foure three or two of the inhabitants where such distresse is taken, and alsoe then to be sold by the
Constable or other Collector for the payment of the said mony and the overplus c&bhooov;ming by the sale (if any be)
over and besides the charge of keeping the said distresse to be imediatelie restored to the owner thereof, Which
said Officers and other &bhopubr;sons so deputed to aske take gather and levie the said s&bhooov;mes shall aunswere and be charged
for the porcion onelie to them assigned and lymitted to be gathered levied and comprised in the said writing
or estreat soe to them as aforesaid delivered to the use of our Soveraigne Lord the Kings Majestie and his Heires
and Successors, and the said s&bhooov;me in that writing or Estreat to be comprised to pay unto the high Collector or
Collectors of that place in manner and forme under written, thereunto to be named and deputed and the same
Inhabitants and Officers so gathering the same particular s&bhooov;mes for their colleccion thereof shall retaine for every
twentie shillings so by them received and paid two pence, And that to be allowed at the payment of their colleccion
by them to be made to the high Collector or Collectors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XXI. Commissioners may appoint Collectors.</head>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">Qualification, ; to be High Collectors.; Commissioners to deliver Estreats under their Seals and Sign Manual to Collectors.; Collector to answer the Sums comprized in Estreat</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">And further be it enacted by the said Authoritie that such of the said C&bhooov;missioners or the more part of them as
shall take uppon them the execucion and busines of the said C&bhooov;mission shall for every of the said payments of the
said Subsidies name such sufficient and able &bhopubr;sons which then shall have and possesse lands or other Hereditaments in
their owne right of the cleere yearelie value of fortie pounds or goodes to the value of foure hundred pounds at
the least as he shalbe taxed in the Subsidie Booke (if anie such be in the said lymitts) and for want of such so
assessed, then those to be appointed Collectors that then shalbe sufficient and rated and taxed in the Subsidie
Bookes in lands and goods neerest to the values aforesaid as by their discrecions shalbe thought good in Shires
Ridings Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Cities Townes corporate and other whatsoever places aswell within places
priviledged as without not being foreprised in this Acte to be high Collectors and to have the colleccion and receipt
of the said s&bhooov;mes set and leviable within the &bhopcrl;cincts lymitts and bounds, where they shalbe so lymitted and
appointed to be high Collectors And to every of the said Collectors soe severallie named the said C&bhooov;missioners
or two of them at the least with all speed and without delay after the said whole s&bhooov;me, of any payment of the
said Subsidies be set by all the lymitts of the same their C&bhooov;mission or in such lymitts as the high Collectors shalbe
soe severallie assigned shall under their Seales and Signes manuall deliver one estreate indented in Parchment
comprising in itt the names of all such &bhopubr;sons as were assigned to levie the said particular s&bhooov;mes and the s&bhooov;mes of
every Hundred Wapentake Towne or other place aforesaid with the names and surnames of the &bhopubr;sons soe
chargeable according to the Estreate so thereof first made and delivered as is aforesaid, And the Collectors
to be assigned shalbe charged to aunswere the whole s&bhooov;me comprised in the said Estreate lymitted to his colleccion
as is aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XXII. Commissioners to take Recognizances of Collectors.</head>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">Condition of Recognizance for first Two Subsidies; ; for Third Subsidy; ; for Fourth Subsidy.; for Fifth Subsidy; Commissioners to certify Recognizances into the Exchequer.; Penalty, &pound;10.; Collectors not making Recognizance, Penalty &pound;20.; Exchequer to cancel Recognizances on Payment of Collection into Exchequer without Fee.; Collectors may appoint Days and Places for Payment of Collection.; Assessor, &#x0026;c. not paying Collection to High Collector, abating the Allowance of 2d. in the Pound.; Distress.; Proceedings thereon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">Provided allwaies and be it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid that the said C&bhooov;missioners having authoritie by
this Acte to name and nominate the said high Collectors of every the said Subsidies shall ymediatelie uppon
their no[i]acion and eleccion take by authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament sufficient Recognizances or Obligacions
without any Fee or reward to be paid therefore of every &bhopubr;son so by them to be named to be high Collectors
to be bound to the Kings Majestie in the double s&bhooov;me of the s&bhooov;me of his colleccion and to be indorsed and made
uppon such condicion that is to saie for the colleccion of the payment of the said two first of the said five Subsidies:
That if the said Collector his Heires or Executors doe trulie content and pay to the use of the Kinges Majestie his
Heires or Successors in the receipt of the said Exchequer att or before the tenth day of July now next c&bhooov;ming soe
much of the said s&bhooov;me of mony allotted and appointed to his colleccion as he shall collect and gather and content
and pay the residue of his colleccion and charge within one moneth next after such tyme as he hath collected and
gathered the same residue, that (<ref idref="n33">33</ref>) the said Recognizance or Obligacion to be void or els to stand in full strength and
vertue And for the colleccion of the third of the said five Subsidies uppon condicion, That if the said Collector
his heires or executors doe trulie content and pay to the use of the Kings Majestie his Heires or Successors in his
receipt of Exchequer at or before the twentith day of October next ensuing soe much of the said s&bhooov;me of mony
allotted and appointed to his colleccion as he shall collecte and gather and content and pay the residue of his
colleccion and charge within one moneth next after such tyme as he hath collected and gathered the same residue:
That then the said Recognizances or Obligacions to be void or els to stand in full strength and vertue, And for the
colleccion of the said fourth Subsidie of the five Subsidies aforesaid, uppon condicion, That if the said Collector his
heires or executors doe trulie content and pay to the use of the Kings Majestie his Heires or Successors in his receipt of
Exchequer at or before the said twentith day of December now next ensuing soe much of the said s&bhooov;me of mony
allotted and appointed to his colleccion as he shall collect and gather and content and pay the residue of his colleccion
and charge within one moneth next after such tyme as he hath collected and gathered the same residue, That then
the [same<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] Recognizances and Obligacions to be void or els to stand in full strength and vertue And for the
colleccion of the said fift and last of the said Subsidies uppon condicion That if the said Collector his heires or
executors doe trulie content and pay to the use of the Kings Majestie his heires and Successors in his receipt of
Exchequer at or before the said first day of March now next ensuing so much of the said s&bhooov;me of mony allotted
and appointed to his colleccion as he shall collect and gather and content and pay the residue of his colleccion and
charge within one moneth next after such tyme as he hath collected the same residue, That then the said Recognizances
or Obligacions to be void or els to stand in full strength and vertue, Which said severall Recognizances or
Obligacions soe taken the said C&bhooov;missioners shall severally certifie and deliver into the Kings Majesties Exchequer
with the severall Certificates of the said Taxacions and Rates of the payments of the said Subsidies at and by the
tymes to them &bhopcrl;scribed and appointed by this Acte for the certificate of the said severall Taxacions of the said
Subsidies uppon paine of forfeiture of ten pounds to the Kinges Majestie for every Recognizance or Obligacion not
soe certified And that every such Collector soe elected named and chosen uppon request to him made shall knowledge
and make the said Recognizance or Obligacion uppon paine of forfeiture of twentie pounds to the Kings Majestie
for the refusall thereof, And that the Tresurer and Barons of the Exchequer for the tyme being uppon payment of
the said severall colleccions of the Subsidies at the dayes and tymes herein lymitted for the payment thereof (<ref idref="n35">35</ref>) to the
Collector or Collectors without any other warrant and without any fee or reward to be paid for the same to any &bhopubr;son,
And every Collector so deputed having the said Estreat in parchment as is aforesaid shall have authoritie by this Act to
appoint daies and places within the circuit of his colleccion for the payment of the said Subsidies to him to be made and
thereof to give warning by &bhopubrc;clamacion or otherwise to all the Constables or other &bhopubr;sons or inhabitants having the charge
of the particular colleccion within the Hundreds Parishes Townes or other places by him or them lymitted to make
payment of the said particuler colleccion of every s&bhooov;me as to them shall appertaine And if at the same day and place
so lymitted and &bhopcrl;fixed by the said high Collector the said Constable Officers or other &bhopubr;sons or inhabitants as is
aforesaid for the said particular colleccion assigned and appointed within such Hundred Cittie Towne or other place
doe not pay unto the said high Collector the some within their severall Hundreds Townes Parishes and other places
due and comprised in the said Estreat thereof to them delivered by the said C&bhooov;missioners or some of them as is
aforesaid or so much thereof as they have by anie meanes received (two pence for every pound for the said
particular colleccion as is aforesaid allwaies thereof to be allowed excepted and abated) that then it shalbe lawfull
to the said high Collectors and every of them and to their assignes to distraine every of the said Constables
Officers and other inhabitants for their said severall and particular colleccion of the said s&bhooov;mes comprised in the said
Estreat and writing thereof to them and every of them as is before expressed delivered or for so much of the same
s&bhooov;me as so then shall happen to be gathered and levied and behind and unpaid by the goods and chattells of
every of them so being behind and the distresse so taken to be kept and appraised and sold as is aforesaid and
thereof to take and levie the s&bhooov;mes soe then being behinde and unpaid and the overplus c&bhooov;ming of the sale of the said
distresse (if any be) to be restored and delivered unto the owner in forme above remembred.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXIII. Persons having been Collectors of former Subsidies not to be appointed Collectors of subsequent Subsidies unless they shew Quietus est.</head>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;100</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">Provided alwaies, and be it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid, That no &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons shalbe nominated or
appointed to be a high Collector or Collectors for the second or other Subsidie graunted by this Act which before
that tyme hath byn a Collector or Collectors for the first or for any former Subsidie unlesse such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons so to
be nominated or appointed high Collector or Collectors for the second or any [such<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] other former Subsidie doe first
shew forth before him or them by whome he shalbe nominated and appointed his Quietus est for his discharge of
his colleccion before appointed to his charge uppon paine of one hundred pounds to be paid and forfaited by him
or them that [shall so<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] nominate and appoint any such Collector contrary to this &bhopcrl;sent Act.</para>
			<para id="p44">
				<emph type="i">Persons living in Cities, &#x0026;c. not to be appointed Collectors or Assessors out of them.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p45">Provided alwaies, that no &bhopubr;son inhabiting in any Cittie Borough or Towne corporate shalbe compelled to be any
Assessor or Collector of or for anie part of the said Subsidies in any place or places out of the said Cittie Borough
or Towne corporate where he dwelleth.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXIV. Assessors, Attornies, Factors, &#x0026;c. after being charged with Receipt of Assessment, dying or removing or concealing their Goods, &#x0026;c. or when Monies comprized in Estreat cannot be levied by Distress, or where Distress cannot be sold;</head>
			<para id="p46">
				<emph type="i">Process out of the Exchequer, and the Commissioners may direct Precepts to Officer to levy such Money.; Who may distrain.; Distress appraised and sold.; If Distress taking out of Limit assigned, Allowance.; Persons charged discharged by Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p47">And it is also by the said authoritie enacted That if any Inhabitants or Officers or whatsoever &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons
charged to and for the colleccion and receipt of any part or porcion of the said Subsidies by any manner of meanes
according to this Act: or any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons for themselves or as Keeper Gardian Deputie Factor or Attorny,
of or for any other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons for any goods or chattells of the owner thereof at the tyme of the said assessing
to be paid being out of this Realme or in any other parts not knowen, or of and for the goods and chattells
of anie other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons of anie corporacion Fraternitie Misterie or other whatsoever Commonaltie being corporate
or not corporate and all &bhopubr;sons having in their rule governance and custodie any goods [and<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] Chattells at the tyme
of the said [assessings<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] or anie of them to be made or which for any cause for and by colleccion of for himselfe or
for any other or by reason that he hath the rule governance or custodie of anie goods or chattells of any other
&bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons Corporacion Commonaltie Fraternitie Guild or Mistery or any such other like or as Factor Deputie
or attorny of or for any &bhopubr;son shalbe taxed valued [rated<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] and sett to anie s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes by reason of this Act
and after the taxacion and assessing uppon any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons as shalbe charged with the receipt of the same
happen to die or depart from the place where he was so taxed [or<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] sett or his goods or chattells to be soe eloined or
in such privie or covert manner kept as the same &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons charged with the same by Estreats or other
[writings<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] from the said C&bhooov;missioners or as many of them as shalbe thereunto appointed by the said C&bhooov;mission as is
aforesaid can ne may levie the same s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes comprised within the same Estreats by distresse within the
Lymitts of their colleccion as is aforesaid or cannott sell such distresse or distresses as be taken for anie of the
said payments before the tyme lymitted to the high Collector for his payment to be made in the Kings Majesties
Receipt then uppon relacion thereof with due examinacion by the oath or examinacion of such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons as
shalbe charged with and for the receipt and colleccion of the same before the said C&bhooov;missioners or as many of
them as by the said C&bhooov;mission shalbe thereunto appointed where such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons or other (as is aforesaid) their
Goods and Chattells were set and taxed and uppon plaine Certificate thereof made into the Kings Majesties
Exchequer by the same C&bhooov;missioners as well of the dwelling place names and [surnames<ref idref="n43">43</ref>] of the said &bhopubr;sons of whome
the same s&bhooov;mes cannott be levied, and had as is aforesaid: Then aswell the Constable and other Inhabitants appointed
for the same particuler colleccion against the high Collector as the high Collector uppon his account and Oath in
the said Exchequer to be discharged thereof and &bhopubrc;cesse to be made for the Kings Majestie out of the same Exchequer
by the discrecion of the Barons of the same Exchequer against such &bhopubr;son his Heires or Executors so being behind with
his payment. And over that the same C&bhooov;missioners to whome any such declaracion of the &bhopcrl;misses shalbe made in
forme aforesaid from tyme to tyme shall have [full<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] power and authoritie to direct their precept or precepts to
the said &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons charged with anie s&bhooov;me of for and uppon any such &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons or other as is
aforesaid or to any Sheriffe Steward Bayliffe or other whatsoever Officer Minister &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons of such place
or places where any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons so owing any such s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes shall have Lands or Tenements and
other Hereditaments or reall possessions goodes and chattells whereby any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons so indebted his
Heires Executors or Assignes or other having the Custodie governance or disposicion of any goods or chattells
landes tenements or other Hereditaments which ought or may by this Act be lawfullie distreined or taken for the
same hath and shall have goodes chattells landes tenements or other possessions whereof such s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes which
by any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons may or ought to be levied be it within the lymitts of such C&bhooov;mission where such &bhopubr;son
or &bhopubr;sons was or were taxed or without in any place within this Realme of England Wales or other the Kings
Majesties Dominions Marches or Territories, by which &bhopcrl;cept as well such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons shalbe charged to levie such
monie as the Officer of the place or places where such distresse may be taken shall have full power and authoritie
to distreine every such &bhopubr;son indebted charged or chargeable by this Act or his Executors or Administrators of his
Goodes and Chattells his Gardians Factors Deputies [Leassees<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] Farmors and Assignes and all other &bhopubr;sons by
whose hands or out of whose lands any such &bhopubr;son shall have Fee Rent A&bhonov;uitie or other proffitt or which at
the tyme of the said assessing shall have goods or chattells or any other thing moveable of any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons
being indebted or owing such s&bhooov;me and the distresses so taken cause to be kept appraised and sold in like manner
and forme as is aforesaid for the distresse to be taken uppon such &bhopubr;sons to be taxed to the said Subsidies, and being
sufficient to distreine within the lymitts of the Collectors Inhabitants or other officers charged with or for the said
s&bhooov;mes so uppon them to be taxed And if any such distresse for non payment happen to be taken out of the lymitt
of the said &bhopubr;sons charged and assigned to levie the said &bhopubr;sons so charged for the levying of any such s&bhooov;mes by distresse
shall &bhopubr;ceive and take of the same distresse for the labour of every &bhopubr;son going for the execucion thereof for every
mile that every [&bhopubr;son<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] so laboureth for the same two pence. And every Farmor Gardian Tenant Factor or other
whatsoever &bhopubr;son being distreined or other &bhopubr;son charged for payment of any such s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes or any
other s&bhooov;me by reason of this Act shalbe of such s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of him or them soe levied and taken discharged
and acquitted at his next day of payment for the same or at the delivery of such Goods and Chattells as he
that is so distreyned had in his custodie or governance against him or them that shalbe soe taxed and sett
Any graunte or writing Obligatorie or other whatsoever matter to the contrary made heretofore notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXVI. Persons distrained having no Lands, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p48">
				<emph type="i">Proceedings.; Imprisonment until Sums due, and also Fee for Arrest paid.; Officer not excuting Process.; Penalty 20s.; Gaoler suffering Escape.; Penalty 40s. and double Value of Rate and Fees.; Like Process for Subsidies due by any persons charged for another unpaid.; Certificate of Default, ; Imprisonment, &#x0026;c. by Commissioners.; Collectors, &#x0026;c. disobeying Commissioners; ; or Persons suspected not to be indifferently taxed refusing to be examined, or resisting Distress, &#x0026;c.; Penalty 40s. or under, at discretion of Commissioners.; Commissioners may punish by Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p49">And if any such &bhopubr;son that should so be distreyned have no Lands or Tenements sufficient whereby he and his
Tenants and Farmors may be distreyned or have aliened eloyned or hid his Goods and Chattells whereby he should
or might be distreyned in such manner that such goods or chattells should not be knowen or found, so that the
s&bhooov;me of or by him to be paid in the [forme aforesaid<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] shall not ne can be convenientlie levied, then uppon relacion
thereof to the C&bhooov;missioners or to as many of them as by the said C&bhooov;mission shalbe thereunto appointed where
such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons was taxed and sett by the oathes of him or them that shalbe charged with the levying and
payment of that s&bhooov;me or somes the same C&bhooov;missioners shall make a precept in such manner as is aforesaid for to
attach take and arrest the body of such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons that ought to pay the said s&bhooov;mes, and by this [Act<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] shalbe
charged with and for the said s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes and them soe taken safelie to keepe in prison within the Shire or
other place where anie such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons shalbe taken and attached there to remaine without baile or Maineprise
untill he [have<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] paid the said s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes that such &bhopubr;son for himselfe or for any other by this Act shalbe chargeable
or ought to be charged withall, and alsoe for the Fees of every such Arrest to him or them that shall execute such
precept twentie pence And that every Officer unto whome such &bhopcrl;cept shalbe directed doe his true diligence and
execute the same uppon every &bhopubr;son so being indebted uppon paine to forfeit to the Kings Majestie for every default
in that behalfe twentie shillings And that no keeper of anie Gaole from his Gaole suffer any such &bhopubr;son to goe at
large by letting to Baile or otherwise to depart out of his prison before he have paid his said debt and the said
twentie pence for his Arrest uppon paine to forfait to the Kings Majestie fortie shillings: And the said Gaoler to
pay to the Kings Majestie the double value aswell of the rate, which the said &bhopubr;son soe imprisoned was taxed at as
of the said twentie pence for the fees, And like processe and remedie in like forme shalbe graunted by the said
C&bhooov;missioners or as many of them as by the said C&bhooov;mission shalbe thereunto appointed at like Informacion of every
&bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons being charged with any s&bhooov;me of mony for any other &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons by reason of the said Subsidies
and not thereof payed but wilfullie withdrawen nor the same leviable within the lymitts where such &bhopubr;sons were
thereunto taxed, And if the s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes being behind unpaid by any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons as is aforesaid be levied and
gathered by force of the said &bhopubrc;cesse to be made by the said C&bhooov;missioners, or if in default or for lacke of payment
thereof the &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons so owing the said s&bhooov;me and s&bhooov;mes of mony by processe of the same C&bhooov;missioners to be
made as is aforesaid be c&bhooov;mitted to prison in forme abovesaid, that then the said C&bhooov;missioners, which shall award
such &bhopubrc;cesse shall make Certificate thereof in the said Exchequer of that shalbe done in the &bhopcrl;misses in the Terme
next following after such s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of mony soe being behind shalbe levied and gathered or such &bhopubr;son or
&bhopubr;sons for non payment of the same c&bhooov;mitted to prison And if it happen any of the said Collectors to be assigned
or anie Maiors Sheriffs Stewards Constables the Headborough Bursholder Bayliffe or anie other Officer or
Minister or other whatsoever &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons to disobey the said C&bhooov;missioners or anie of them in the reasonable
request to them made by the said C&bhooov;missioners for the execucion of the said C&bhooov;mission, or if any of the Officers
or other &bhopubr;sons do refuse that to them shall appertaine and belong to doe, by reason of anie Precept to him or them
to be directed or any reasonable c&bhooov;maundement instance or request touching the &bhopcrl;misses or other default in any
appearance or colleccion to make, or if any &bhopubr;son being suspected not to be indifferentlie taxed as is aforesaid doe
refuse to be examined according to the tenor of this Acte before the said C&bhooov;missioners or as many of them as shalbe
thereunto assigned as is aforesaid or will not appeare before the same C&bhooov;missioners uppon warning to him made or
else make resistance or rescues uppon any distresse uppon him to be taken for any parcell of the said Subsidies or
c&bhooov;mitt any misbehaviour in any manner or wise contrary to this Act or c&bhooov;mitt any wilfull omission or other
whatsoever wilfull doing or misdoing contrary to the tenor of this Act or Graunt, The same C&bhooov;missioners and
every nomber of them above remembred or two of them at the least uppon certaine knowledge of any such
misdemeanors had by Informacion or Examinacion shall and may sett uppon (<ref idref="n47">47</ref>) every such offence in the name
of a Fine by the same offendor to be forfaited fortie shillings or under by discrecion of the same C&bhooov;missioners.
And further the said C&bhooov;missioners and every nomber of them or two of them at the least shall have authoritie
by this &bhopcrl;sent Act to punish every such offendor by imprisonment there to remaine and to be delivered by their
discrecion as shall seeme to them convenient the said Fines if any such be to be certified by the said
C&bhooov;missioners that so assessed the same into the Kings Majesties Exchequer there to be levied and paid by the
Collectors of that part for the said Subsidies retorned into the said Exchequer to be therewith charged with the
payment of the said Subsidies in such manner as if the said Fines had byn sett and taxed upon the said offendors
for the said Subsidies.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXVII. Allowance to High Collectors and their Accountants.</head>
			<para id="p50">
				<emph type="i">Allowance to be paid by Collectors to Commissioners for their Expences and the labour of their Clerks.; Remedy for the same for Commissioners against Collectors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p51">And be it also enacted by the said authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament, That every of the said high Collectors,
which shall account for anie part of the said Subsidies in the said Exchequer uppon their severall accounts to be
yeilded shalbe allowed at every of the said payments of the said Subsidies for every pound lymitted to his colleccion
whereof any such Collector shalbe charged and yeild account six pence as parcell of their charge (that is to saie)
of every pound thereof for such &bhopubr;sons as then have had the particuler colleccion of the Townes and other places
as is aforesaid specified in his colleccion two pence and other two pence of every pound thereof every of the said
cheife Collectors or their Accomptants to retaine to their owne use for their labour and charge in and about the
&bhopubrc;misses and two pence of every pound residue to be delivered allowed and paid by the said Collector so being
thereof allowed to such of the C&bhooov;missioners as shall take uppon them the business and labour for and about the
&bhopcrl;misses, that is to saie Every Collector to pay that C&bhooov;missioner or C&bhooov;missioners which had the ordering of the
writings of and for every of the said Subsidies where the said Collector or Collectors had their colleccion for the
expences for the said C&bhooov;missioners so taking, uppon them the said busines and labour of their Clerkes writing
the said Precepts and Extracts of the said Colleccions, the said last two pence of every pound to be devided amongest
the said C&bhooov;missioners having regard to their labour and busines taken by them and their said Clerkes in and about
the &bhopcrl;misses, for which part so to the said C&bhooov;missioners appertayning the said C&bhooov;missioners six five foure three
or two or as many of them as shalbe thereunto appointed by the Kings Majesties C&bhooov;mission and every of them
joyntlie and severallie for his and their said part may have his remedie against the Collector or Collectors which
thereof byn or might have byn allowed by accion of debt, in which the Defendants hall [not<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] wage his Lawe neither
&bhopubrc;teccion neither Injunccion or Essoine shalbe allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXVIII. Commissioners, &#x0026;c. not compellable to make Presentment other than to Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p52">And that no &bhopubr;son now being of the nomber of the Company of this &bhopcrl;sent perliament nor any C&bhooov;missioner shalbe
named or assigned to be any Collector or Subcollector or Presenter of the said Subsidies or any part thereof,
nor any C&bhooov;missioners shalbe compelled to make any &bhopcrl;sentment or Certificate other then into the Kings Majesties
said Exchequer of for or concerning the said Subsidies or any part or parcell thereof, And likewise that no other
&bhopubr;son that shalbe named and assigned to be C&bhooov;missioners in any place to and for the execucion of this Act of
Subsidies be or shalbe assigned or named head Collector of anie of the Payments of the said Subsidies neither of
anie part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXIX. Head Collector for First Subsidy not compellable to be Collector for the other Subsidies.</head>
			<para id="p53">
				<emph type="i">Taking Fees of Accountants.; Penalty.; Imprisonment.; Commissioners at Meetings to shew Certificates and Presentments to the other Commissioners.; Indenture of Collectors' Names, and of Sums written to Collectors, Fines, &#x0026;c. to be certified by Commissioners into the Exchequer.; Collectors answerable for their own Collection only.; Commissioners, if they cannot agree, may make several Indentures of their several Limits; &#x0026;c.; Collectors not chargeable for other Collectors.; Commissioners or Collectors or Persons taxed dying before discharged, Heirs and Executors chargeable as such Persons would have been if alive</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p54">And that every such &bhopubr;son and [&bhopubr;son<ref idref="n49">49</ref>] which shalbe named and appointed as is aforesaid to be head Collectors of
and for the payment of the said first Subsidie or of anie part thereof shall not be compelled to be Collector for the
payment of the said second or other Subsidie nor anie part thereof And the said Collectors W<emph type="p">ch</emph> shalbe assigned for
the colleccion of the said five Subsidies or of anie part thereof and every of them be and shalbe acquited and
discharged of all manner Fees and Rewards and of every other charge in the Kings Majesties Exchequer or elswhere
of them or any of them by reason of that colleccion payment or account or any thing concerning the same to
be asked, And that if any &bhopubr;son receive or take any Fees Rewards or pleasures of any such Accomptants or use
any unnecessary delay in their accompt that then he shall forfait to the Kings Majestie for every penny or value
of every pennyworth soe taken five shillings and five pounds to the partie greived for every such delay and suffer
imprisonment at the Kings Majesties pleasure And after every taxing and assessing of the said severall Subsidies
as is aforesaid had or made and the said extracts thereof in Parchment unto the Collector in manner and forme
before rehearsed delivered, The said C&bhooov;missioners which shall take uppon them the execucion of this Act within
the lymitts of their C&bhooov;mission by their agreements shall [have<ref idref="n50">50</ref>] meetings together, Att which meeting every of the
said C&bhooov;missioners which then shall have taken uppon them the execucion of any part of the said C&bhooov;mission shall
by himselfe or his sufficient Deputie trulie certifie and bring forth unto the said C&bhooov;missioners named in the said
C&bhooov;mission the Certificate and &bhopcrl;sentment made before him and such other C&bhooov;missioners as were lymitted with him
in one lymitt soe as the same certificate may be accounted and cast with the other certificats of the other lymitts
within the same C&bhooov;mission, and then the said Comissioners and every nomber of them unto two at the least as is
aforesaid if any bee in life or their Executors or Administrators of their goods (if they then be dead) shall joyntlie
and severallie as they were devided within their lymitts under their seales by their discrecions make one or severall
writings indented contayning in it aswell the names of the said Collectors by the C&bhooov;missioners for such colleccions
and accounts in the Exchequer and payments in the said receipt deputed and assigned as the grosse and severall
s&bhooov;mes written unto every such Collectors to receive the said Subsidies and also all Fines Amerciaments and other
Forfeitures if any such by reason of this Acte happen to be within the lymitt and &bhopcrl;cinct of their C&bhooov;mission to be
certified into the Kings Majesties said Exchequer by the said C&bhooov;missioners, In which writing or writings indented
so to be certified shalbe plainelie declared and expressed the whole and entire s&bhooov;me or s&bhooov;mes of the said Subsidies
severallie lymitted to the colleccion of the said Collectors severallie deputed and assigned to the said s&bhooov;mes; Soe as
none of the said Collectors soe certified in the said Exchequer shalbe compelled there to accompt or to bee charged
but onelie to and for the s&bhooov;mes lymitted to his colleccion and not to or for any s&bhooov;me lymitted to the colleccion of his
fellowes, But every of them shalbe severally charged for [their fellowes for<ref idref="n51">51</ref>] their part lymitted to their Colleccion And if
the said C&bhooov;missioners joyned in one C&bhooov;mission amongest themselves in that matter cannott agree or if any of them
be not readie or refuse to make certificate with the other of the same C&bhooov;missioners that then the said C&bhooov;missioners
may make severall Indentures in forme aforesaid of their severall lymitts or separacions of Collectors within
the lymitts of their C&bhooov;mission uppon and in the Hundreds Wards Wapentakes Lathes Rapes or such other like
divisions within the said severall lymitts of their C&bhooov;mission as the places there shall require to be severed and
divided and as to the same C&bhooov;missioners shall seeme good to make divisions or other lymitts or Colleccions for
the severall charges of the same Collectors soe that alway one Collector shalbe charged and account for his part to
him to be lymitted only by himselfe and not for any s&bhooov;me lymitted to the part of any of his fellowes And the
charges of every of the Collectors to be set and certified severallie uppon them, And every such Collector uppon
his account and payment of the s&bhooov;me of mony lymitted within his colleccion to be severallie by himselfe acquited
and discharged in the said Exchequer, without paying any manner Fees or Rewards to any &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons for the
same uppon paine and penaltie last abovesaid and not to be charged for any porcion of any other Collector And
if any C&bhooov;missioner after he hath taken certificate of them, that, as is aforesaid shalbe before any C&bhooov;missioners
examined and the somes rated and set and the bookes and writings thereof being in his handes or if any Collector
or other &bhopubr;son charged with any receipt of any part of the said Subsidies or any other &bhopubr;son taxed or otherwise
by this Act charged with or for any parcell of the said Subsidies or with any other s&bhooov;me Fine Amerciament Penaltie
or other Forfeiture happen to die before the C&bhooov;missioners Collectors or other whatsoever &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons have
executed accomplished satisfied or sufficientlie discharged that to which every such &bhopubr;son shall appertaine or belong
to doe according to this Acte, Then the Executors and Heires of every such &bhopubr;son and all other seised of any Lands
and Tenements that any such &bhopubr;son being charged by this Acte and deceaseing before he be discharged hereof or
any other to his use onelie had of an Estate of Inheritance at the tyme that any such &bhopubr;son was named C&bhooov;missioner
Collector or otherwise charged with or for any manner of thing to be done satisfied or paid by reason of this Acte:
And all those that have in their possession or hands any Goods Chattells Leases or other things that were to
any such &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons at the tyme of his death or any Lands or Tenements that were the same &bhopubr;sons at the tyme
that he was as is aforesaid charged by this Acte shalbe by the same compelled and charged to doe and accomplish
in every case as the same &bhopubr;son so being charged should have done or might have byn compelled to doe if he
had byn in plaine life after such rate of the Lands and Goods of the said C&bhooov;missioner and Collector as the partie
shall have in his Hands.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXX. Commissioners not thinking fit to join in one Certificate, Proceedings.</head>
			<para id="p55">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners making Default of Certificate, Process out of Exchequer against them</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p56">And if the said C&bhooov;missioners for causes reasonable them moving shall thinke it not fitt to joyne in one Certificate
as is aforesaid then the said &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons that shall first joyne together or hee that shall first certifie the said
writing indented as is aforesaid shall certifie all the names of the C&bhooov;missioners of that C&bhooov;mission whereuppon such
writing shalbe there then to be certified with division of the Hundreds Wapentakes Wards Tythings and other
places to and among such C&bhooov;missioners of the same C&bhooov;mission with the names of the said C&bhooov;missioners where such
Separacions and Divisions shalbe with the grosse s&bhooov;mes of mony aswell of and for the said Subsidies taxed or
sett of or within the said Hundreds Wards Wapentakes or other places to him or them divided or assigned that
shall soe certifie the (<ref idref="n52">52</ref>) first Writings as of the Fines Amerciaments Penalties and other Forfeitures if any happen
to be within the same Lymitts whereof the same writings shalbe certified And after such writings indented which
as is aforesaid shalbe certified and not containe in itt the whole and full s&bhooov;mes sett and taxed within the Lymitts
of the same C&bhooov;mission the other C&bhooov;missioners of the same before the day of payment of the said Subsidie shall
certifie into the said Exchequer by their writing or writings indented to be made as is aforesaid the grosse and
severall s&bhooov;mes sett and taxed within the places to them lymitted for every of the said Subsidies and other fines
amerciaments penalties and forfeiture with the names of the Hundred Wards Wapentakes and other Places
to them assigned or els by their said writings indented to certifie at the same place before the same day of
payment such reasonable causes for their excuses why they may not make such certificate of and for the said
Subsidies Fines Amerciaments and other forfeitures growing or sett by reason of the causes of their letts or of their
not certifying as is aforesaid, or else in default thereof &bhopubrc;cesse to be made out of the Kings Majesties said Exchequer
against the said C&bhooov;missioners and every of them not making certificate as is aforesaid by the discrecion of the
Treasurer and Barons of the said Exchequer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXXI. Proviso for Stamford Baron.</head>
			<para id="p57">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid That the inhabitants of the Parish of Saint
Martine called Stamford Baron in the Suburbes of the Borough and Towne of Stamford in the South part of the
waters there called Wellands which hereafter shalbe contributorie to the payment of theise &bhopcrl;sent Subsidies granted
to the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors shalbe assessed rated and taxed for the same by such C&bhooov;missioners
which shalbe appointed for the taxing rating and sessing of the same Subsidies within the Countie of Lincolne
and shalbe for the same contributory and pay the said Subsidies to the Collector or Collectors which shalbe
assigned and appointed for the levying and gathering of the same with the Aldermen and Burgesses of the same
Borough and Towne of Stamford.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXXII. Persons having Temporal and Spiritual Possessions, and also Personal Property, not to be doubly charged.</head>
			<para id="p58">Provided alwaies, and be it further enacted by the authoritie aforesaid, That all and every &bhopubr;son and &bhopubr;sons
having Mannors Lands Tenements and other Hereditaments chargeable to the payment of the said Subsidies
graunted to the Kings Majestie by this Act, and also having Spirituall possessions chargeable to his said Majestie
by any graunt made or to be made by the Clergie of this Realme in their Convocacion, and over this having substance
in goods and chattells chargeable by this said Act, that then if any of the said &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons be hereafter charged
assessed and taxed for the said Mannors Lands and Tenements and Spirituall possessions and also charged assessed
and taxed for his and their goods and chattells, that then he or they shalbe onelie charged by vertue of this Acte
for his and their said Mannors Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Spirituall possessions or onelie for his said
goodes and chattells, the best thereof to be taken for the Kings Majestie and not to be charged for both or double
charged for any of them, Any thing in this Act contayned to the contrary [in any wise<ref idref="n53">53</ref>] notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXXIII. Proviso for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey, and Guernsey.</head>
			<para id="p59">Provided allwaies that this graunt of Subsidies or any thing therein contayned in any wise extend not
to charge the Inhabitants of Scotland Ireland Jersey and Garnesey or any of them of for or concerning any
Mannors Lands Tenements or other possessions goods chattells or other moveable substance which the said
Inhabitants or dwellers or any [other<ref idref="n54">54</ref>] to their use have within Scotland Ireland Jersey and Garnesey or in any
of them or of for or concerning any Fees or Wages which any of the said Inhabitants or dwellers have of
the Kings Majestie for their attendance and doing service to our Soveraigne Lord the Kings Majestie in Scotland
Ireland Jersey and Garnesey or any of them Any thing in this &bhopcrl;sent Acte to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXIV. Proviso for Patents of Liberties.</head>
			<para id="p60">Provided also that all Letters Patents graunted by the Kings Majestie or any of his [most<ref idref="n55">55</ref>] noble Progenitors to
any Citties Boroughes or Townes within this Realme of any manner of Liberties Priviledges or exempcions from
the burthen and charge of any such graunts of Subsidies which bee at this &bhopcrl;sent tyme in force and availeable shall
remaine good and effectuall to the said Citties Boroughes and Townes hereafter according to the purports thereof
although the Inhabitants of the same and also the said Corporacions shall uppon the great and waightie
consideracions of the Graunt aforesaid be for this Graunt charged and contributarie in like manner forme and sort
as other Citties Boroughes and Townes which be not in any wise priviledged but by this Acte charged.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXV. Orphans and Infants not chargeable to Subsidies.</head>
			<para id="p61">Provided alwaies and be it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid, That no Orphan or Infant within the age of one
and twentie yeares borne within any of the Kings Majesties Dominions shalbe charged to any payment of theise
Subsidies for his or their Goods and chattells to him or her left or bequeathed, Any thing in this Act conteyned
to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXVI. Proviso for Universities of Oxford and Cambridge, Winchester College, Eaton College, Poor Knights of</head>
			<para id="p62">
				<emph type="i">Windsor, and Free Schools, and Readers, &#x0026;c. in the Universities, and for Hospitals, &#x0026;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p63">Provided also that this Acte nor any [thing<ref idref="n56">56</ref>] therein contayned shall extend to the lands or goods of any Colledge
Hall or Hostell within the Univ[er]sities of Oxford and Cambridge or any of them or to the Goods or Lands of
the Colledge of Winton founded by Bishopp Wickham or to the goods or lands of the Colledge of Eaton next
Windsor or to the Lands Tenenments or revenews onelie assigned and appointed for the sustentacion and living
of the poore Knights founded in the Castle or Colledge of Windsor by our late Soveraigne Lord King Henry the
eight or to any the Goods or Chattells of the same Knights or any of them or to the Goods or lands of any (<ref idref="n57">57</ref>)
free Grammer Schoole within the Realme of England or Wales or the goods of any Reader Schoolemaister
or Scholler or any Graduate or Resiant or remayning for studie without fraude or covine within any the said
Univ[er]sities and Colledges or townes of Oxford and Cambridge or Suburbes of the same or to any of them or to
any of their servants attending dailie uppon any of them nor to the goods of any Officer Minister Almes men or
servants belonging to any of the said Univ[er]sities Colledges Halls or Hostells and dwelling and resiant within
the said Univ[er]sities or either of them or within either of the said Townes of Oxford and Cambridge and the Suburbs
of the same without fraude or covin or to the goods and lands of any Hospitall Maisondieu or Spittlehouse
&bhopcrl;pared and used for the sustentacion and releife of poore people Any thing in this Act contayned to the contrary
in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXVII. Inhabitants of Cinque Ports for the most Part of the Year before the Grant not chargeable during Resiance only.</head>
			<para id="p64">Provided also and be it further enacted that the said Graunt of Subsidies or any thing therein contayned do
not in any wise extend or be &bhopcrl;judiciall or hurtfull to any of the inhabitants or resiants having dwelt for the
most part of the yeare next before the taxing and assessing of the Subsidies aforesaid within the five ports
corporate or to any their members incorporated or united to the said five Ports or to any of the said five Ports,
but that such the inhabitants or Resiants as aforesaid in the said five Ports corporate and their members be and
shalbe of and from the said Graunt and payment of every of the said Subsidies and every part thereof and onelie
during their resiance as aforesaid and no longer clerelie acquitted and discharged. Any matter or whatsoever thing
in this &bhopcrl;sent Act had or made to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXVIII. Like Proviso for Inhabitants of Rumney Marsh.</head>
			<para id="p65">Provided also that the said Grant of Subsidies do not in any wise extend to be &bhopcrl;judiciall or hurtfull to the
English Inhabitants or Resiants at this &bhopcrl;sent tyme within the Liberties of Rumney Marsh of or for any part of
the said s&bhooov;mes graunted in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament of the said English Inhabitants now there Resiants or any of
them to be taxed set asked levied or paid but that the English Inhabitants and now Resiants of Rumney Marshe
aforesaid and every of them be and shalbe of and from the graunt and payment of the said Subsidies during their
Resiance there and no longer acquited and discharged, Any matter and whatsoever thing in this &bhopcrl;sent Acte made to
the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXIX. Alien or Denizen assigning his Lands, &#x0026;c. to his Child with Intent to defraud the Subsidy, such Child chargeable as an Alien.</head>
			<para id="p66">Provided neverthelesse, and be it enacted by the authoritie aforesaid, That if any Alien or straunger borne
Denizen or not Denizen (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) and inhabiting within this Realme of England shall assigne and convey over unto any his
or their childe or children borne within the said Realme of England any his or their Lands Tenements Goods
or Chattells to the intent thereby to defraud the said Kings Majestie of the said Subsidies of or for the same,
that then all and every such childe and children so being seised of any such Lands and Tenements and possessed
of anie such goods or chattells shalbe charged and chargeable to and with the payment of double the said
Subsidies for the same Landes Tenements Goodes and Chattells at the said rates and values as Aliens and Straungers
Denizens or not Denizens are before limited and appointed to pay.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>ITEM quedam Peti&bhocotil;es privatas &bhopubr;sonas con&bhoccrl;nentes in se formam Actus continen exhibite fuerunt &bhopcrl;dco D[omi]no Regi in
Parliamento &bhopcrl;dco Quar[um] Tituli subscribunt<emph type="p">r</emph> videlt.</head>
			<para id="p67">1. An Acte for the establishing and confirming of the foundacion of the Hospitall of King James founded in
Charterhouse in the Countie of Midd at the humble Peticion and onelie Costs and Charges of Thomas Sutton Esquire
and of the Possessions thereof.</para>
			<para id="p68">2. An Acte for assurance of a Joynture to Dame Fraunces wife of Sir Thomas Nevill Knight sonne and Heire
apparant of Sir Henry Nevill Knight Lord Abergavenny and to enable the same Lord and Sir Thomas to sell certaine
lands for payment of their Debts and &bhopcrl;ferment of their younger children.</para>
			<para id="p69">3. An Acte concerning the Inheritance Freehold and possessions of William Earle of Devon.</para>
			<para id="p70">4. An Acte concerning the Title Name and Dignitie of Earle of Arundell and for the annexing of the Castle
Honor Mannor and Lordshipp of Arundell in the Countie of Sussex: with the Titles and Dignities of the Baronies
of Fitz Allen Clun and Oswaldstre and Matravers and with divers other lands tenements and hereditam[en]ts hereafter
in this Acte men&bhocotil;ned being now parcell of the possessions of Thomas Earle of Arundell and Surrey Earle Marshall
of England to the same Tytle Name and Dignitie of Earle of Arundell.</para>
			<para id="p71">5. An Acte for the enabling of the right honorable Dutton Lord Gerrard Baron of Gerards Bromley to make
a Joynture to any wife which he shall hereafter marry and to make provision for any his younger children. And
for the better securing of porcions and lymittacion of mainten<emph type="p">a</emph>nce for Alice Gerrard Fraunces Gerrard and Elizabeth
Gerrard sisters of the said Dutton Lord Gerrard and daughters of the late right honorable Gilbert Lord Gerrard
deceased.</para>
			<para id="p72">6. An Acte for the confirmacion of tres Patents made by our late Soveraigne Lord King James to John Earle
of Bristoll by the name of John Digby Knight.</para>
			<para id="p73">7. An Acte for reestating certaine Mannors Lands and Tenements in the Countie of Somersett late of William
Morgan of Penrose in the Countie of Monmoth Esquire &#x0026; discharging the trust concerning them.</para>
			<para id="p74">8. An Acte for the Naturalizing of Sir Robert Dyell Knight one of the Gentlemen of His Majesties Privie Chamber
and George Kerke Esquier one of the Groomes of His Majesties Bedchamber.</para>
			<para id="p75">9. An Act for the Naturalizing of Sir Daniell Deligne of Harlaxton in the Countie of Lincoln Knight.</para>
			<para id="p76">10. An Acte for the Naturalizing of Isaac Asteley Henry Asteley Thomas Asteley and Bernard Asteley children
and sonnes of Sir Jacob Asteley Knight one of the younger sonnes of Isaac Asteley late of Melton Constable in the
Countie of Norff Esquire deceased.</para>
			<para id="p77">11. An Acte for the Naturalizing of Sir Robert Ayton Knight.</para>
			<para id="p78">12. An Acte for the Naturalizing of Samuell Powell borne at Hanborough in the parts beyond the Seas of
English parents.</para>
			<para id="p79">13. An Act for the amendement of a word casuallie mistaken and miswritten in an Act of Parliament made in
the Session of Parliament holden at Westminster the nyneteenth day of Februarie in the one and twentith yeare
of the Raigne of our late Soveraigne Lord King James of England intituled An Acte to enable Vincent Lowe of Denbigh
in the Countie of Derbie Esquire to sell part of his Lands for payment of his Debts.</para>
			<para id="p80">14. An Act for the Naturalizing of Alexander Levingston Gent.</para>
			<para id="p81">15. An Act for the Naturalizing of James Freese borne in Russia.</para>
			<para id="p82">16. An Act for restitucion in blood of Carew Raleigh sonne of Sir Walter Raleigh late attainted of high Treason
and for confirmacion of certaine l[ia]res Patents made by our late Soveraigne Lord King James to John Earle of Bristoll
by the name of John Digby Knight.</para>
			<para id="p83">17. An Acte for the Naturalizing of John Aldersey Mary Aldersey now the wife of Robert Crane Ann Aldersey
Elizabeth Aldersey and Margarett Aldersey children of Samuell Aldersey of the Citie of London Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p84">18. An Acte for the &bhopubr;fect setling and confirmacion of the Estates and Customes of the Customary Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nts
of the Right honorable Henry now Lord Morley and Lord Mountegle Baron of Rye within the Mannor of Horneby
and elsewhere within the Towneshipps of Tatham Gressingham and Eskrigg in the Countie Palatine of Lancaster.</para>
			<para id="p85">19. An Acte for the Naturalizing of John Trumball and Anne Trumball children of William Trumball Esquire and
of William Bere Edward Bere and Sidney Bere sonnes of John Bere Esquire and of Samuell Wentworth sonne of
William Wentworth of Dover Marchant.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">present <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">upwards <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">yearly <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">ensuing <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">demesne <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">of them <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">in <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">&bhopubr;te <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">as <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">then <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">or his Family <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">soe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">at <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">taxa&bhocotil;ns <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">alsoe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">abovesaid <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">then <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">shall cancell and deliver the Recognizances or obliga&bhocotil;ns for the payment thereof <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">soe shall <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39">assessing <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n42" number="42">writing <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n43" number="43">s&bhooov;mes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n44" number="44">saide forme <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n45" number="45">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n46" number="46">hath <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n47" number="47">every such Offendor for <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n48" number="48">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n49" number="49">persons <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n50" number="50">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n51" number="51">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n52" number="52">1 said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n53" number="53">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n54" number="54">others <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n55" number="55">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n56" number="56">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n57" number="57">c&bhooov;mon <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n58" number="58">and dwelling <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


