<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47224" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER XIII. An Act for the securing of such moneys as are or shall be due to the Inhabitants of the Countie of Yorke and the other adjoyning Counties wherein his Majesties Army is or hath beene billetted for the billet of the Souldiers of the said Army as also to certein Officers of the said Army who do forbear part of theire pay according to an Order in that behalfe made in the Commons House of Parliament this present Session for such part of theire pay as they shall so forbeare. [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Recital that several Counties have been at great Charges by the billetting of Soldiers, and that the Inhabitants have agreed to for bear Payment till November;and that divers Officers of the Army have in like Manner agreed to forbear Payment of their Pay.; Such Monies and Pay to be paid out of Monies raised under c. 9. ante.; Mode of Payment, and Persons by whom made, for the several Counties and Places herein mentioned, viz. Chamber of the City of York;; West Riding of Yorkshire;; North Riding of Yorkshire, and Places in the County of Durham;; East Riding of Yorkshire;Kingston-upon-Hull;; City of York;; County of Lincoln.; County of Nottingham;; to be paid according to Certificates; Rate for Foot Soldiers, 3s. per Week.; Horsemen 7s. 6d. per Week, unless Agreement.; Officers of Horse and Foot, such Rates as shall be set by the Lord General of the Army and the Lord Lieutenant of the County of York</emph>;</para>
		<para id="p2">Forasmuch as diverse of the Inhabitants of the severall Counties of Yorke Lincolne Nottingham and other
adjoyning Counties in the severall places where his Majesties Armie is and hath beene quartered and billetted
for his Majesties service have at theire great charges and to their much impoverishment kept and mainteined the
said Army for certaine moneths by past without any payment or satisfa&bholigct;ion for the same And whereas they the
said Inhabitants of the said severall Counties have beene desired and are contented to forbeare the moneys due and
to be due to them respe&bholigct;ively for the said Billett untill the moneth of November next (if there be not meanes to
pay and discharge the same in the meane time) And Whereas diverse of the Officers of the said Armie are
likewise contented to forbeare some part of theire pay according to an order in that behalfe made in the Commons
House of Parliament this present Session untill the time aforesaid To the end therefore that both the said Inhabitants
and the said Officers may be secured for the true payment of the said moneys accordingly and to avoide or decide
all differences and controversies which might arise upon the severall accounts betweene the said Inhabitants and
the Souldiers for the certaintie of the said Billett money May it please your Most Excellent Majestie that it may
be ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed by your Most Excellent Majestie the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by authoritie of the same that all and every the s&bhouov;m or sums of money which now are or before the
time of payment of the said Billett money shall appeare to be due and owing either to the said Inhabitants or any of
them for the Billett of the said Armie or any part thereof or to any of the said Officers according to the said Order
shall upon the tenth day of November next coming or sooner if there be meanes to doe it be well and truely paid
and discharged to the severall persons to whom the same are or shall be due respe&bholigct;ively out of the moneys which
shall be raised by vertue of an A&bholigct; made in this present Session of Parliament intituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy
provision of money for the disbanding the Armies and setling the Peace of the two Kingdomes of England and
Scotland by the Treasurers or persons appointed by that A&bholigct; for the receipt of the moneys soe to be raised or by
such other wayes and meanes as the House of Commons shall thinke fit and appoint in manner and form following
that is to say that the persons appointed by the said A&bholigct; for the receipt of such part of the said Moneys as is by
vertue thereof payable at the Chamber in the Citie of Yorke shall out of the same at or in the said Chamber upon
the said tenth day of November or sooner if there be meanes to doe it)<?bignore?> well and truly pay unto the hands of Sir
William Lister Sir Gervase Cutler Sir Arthur Ingram the Younger and Sir John Ramsden Knights John Kay
and Peter Jennings Esquires or to any two or more of them all such moneys as are or shall be due as aforesaid to
the severall Inhabitants of the West Riding of the said County of Yorke respe&bholigct;ively for the said Billett money
To the hands of Sir Marmaduke Wyvell Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Darley Knight Bryan Stapleton John
Calverley Henry Anderson John Dodsworth the Younger James Pennyman William Calye and Francis Lassells
Esquires or to any two or more of them all such moneys as are or shall be due as aforesaid to the severall
Inhabitants of the North Riding of the said County of Yorke and of such places within the County of Durham
where any of his Majesties said Army is or hath been quartered or billetted respe&bholigct;ively for the Billet of the said
Souldiers To the hands of John Legard of Gaunton Richard Remington Christopher Appleyard Francis Munckton
and Edward Paler Esquires or to any two or more of them all such moneys as are or shall be due as aforesaid to
the severall Inhabitants of the East Riding of the said County of Yorke respe&bholigct;ively for the said Billett money
To the hands of Lancelot Roper James Watkinson and Nicholas Denman Gentlemen or to any two of them all such moneys as are or shall be due as aforesaid to the severall Inhabitants of the Towne and County of Kingston upon Hull
respe&bholigct;ively for the Billett of the said Souldiers To the hands of Sir William Fairfaxe and Sir Thomas Harrison
Knights John Geldart Merchant and Robert Knight Grocer or to any three of them all such moneys as are or shall
be due as aforesaid to the severall Inhabitants of the said City of Yorke and County of the same respe&bholigct;ively for
the said Billett money To the hands of Sir William Pelham Knight Willoughbie Hickman Charles Pelham and
Thomas Sanderson Esquires or any twoe or more of them all such moneys as are or shall be due as aforesaid to
the severall Inhabitants of the said County of Lincoln respe&bholigct;ively for the said Billett Money. And to the hands of
John Nevile Anthony Ayre William Moseley and William Sanderson Esquires or to any two or more of them all
such moneys as are or shall be due as aforesaid to the severall Inhabitants of the County of Nottingham respe&bholigct;ively
for the said Billett money And that the said moneys so to be paid and every part thereof shall be paid according
to the Certificates for soe much as is already certainly certified and for the residue after the rate of three shillings
by the weeke for every common foot Souldier as shall appeare due by a certificate to be taken upon the disbanding
unlesse where it shall appeare that there hath beene some expresse agreement for an other rate and for the Horsemen
after the rate of seaven shillings and six pence by the weeke for every Common Souldier and his horse unlesse where
it shall appeare that there hath beene expresse agreement for another rate And for the Officers both of Horse and
Foot such rates as shall be set downe by the Lord Generall of the Army and the Lord Leiutenant of the County
of Yorke.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Acquittances by the above Persons a Discharge to the Parties paying.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the Acquittances of so many and such of the said
persons above named for the receipt of the said Moneys due to the said severall Inhabitants of the severall Counties
and Places above mentioned as shall receive the same respe&bholigct;ively as aforesaid shall be sufficient discharges to and
for the said persons from whom they shall [soe<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] receive the same by vertue of this A&bholigct; for such severall sums of
money as they shall so receive respe&bholigct;ively</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Persons who shall receive the Monies to arise under c. 9. ante, payable in London, to pay thereout the Monies due to the Officers, to the Treasurer of the Army, whose; Acquittance to be a Discharge.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it likewise further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the persons who shall by vertue of the said
recited A&bholigct; receive such part of the said moneys as is thereby payable at or in the Chamberlaines Office in
Guildhall within the City of London shall out of the same at or in the said Chamberlaines Office upon the said tenth
day of November (or sooner if there be meanes to doe it) pay to the hands of Sir William Uvedall Knight Treasurer
of his Majesties said Army all such moneys as are or shall be due as aforesaid to the severall Officers of the said
Army who shall forbear the same according to the Order above mentioned And that the Acquittances of the said
Sir William Uvedall shall be a sufficient discharge for what he shall soe receive.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


