<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47228" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER XVII. An Act for the Pacification between England and Scotland. [Rot Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 13.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that a Treaty had been appointed by the King for removing of all Differences between the two Kingdoms; and a Commission issued under the Great Seal of England, with the Approbation of Parliament.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Words of the Commission.; Recital that a Commission had been granted by the Committees of the Parliament of Scotland.; The Words thereof</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by his Majesties Roiall Wisdome and princely care of the peace and happines of His Majesties
Dominions a treaty hath beene appointed for removing [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] all differences raised betwixt the two Kingdoms
and betwixt the King and his Subje&bholigct;s of Scotland and for setling &amp; assuring a firm and blessed Peace for all
time to come and a Commission hath been given under the Great Seal of England with approbation of both Houses
of Parliament bearing date the three and twentieth day of November in the sixteenth yeare of his Majesties reign
and in the words following CHARLES by the Grace of God King of England Scotland France &amp; Ireland Defender
of the Faith &amp;c. To our right trusty and right welbeloved Cousins Francis Earle of Bedford William Earle of
Hertford Robert Earle of Essex and to our right trustie and right welbeloved Cousin and Counsellour William
Earle of Salisburie and to our right trusty and right welbeloved Cousin Robert Earle of Warwick and to our right
trusty and right welbeloved Cousin John Earle of Bristoll and to our right trusty and right welbeloved Cousin
and Counsellour Henry Earle of Holland and to our right trusty and right welbeloved Cousin and Counsellour
Thomas Earle of Berks and to our right trusty and welbeloved Philip Lord Wharton William Lord Paget Edward
Lord Kimbolton Robert Lord Brook John Lord Powlet Edward Lord Howard of Escrick Thomas Lord Savile and
Francis Lord Dunsmore Greeting Whereas divers of our Subje&bholigct;s of Scotland have by theire severall Petitions
humbly besought us that we would be graciously pleased to grant unto them certain demands WE reposing speciall
trust and confidence in your wisdomes and fidelities Have named assigned and appointed you And by these
presents Doe name assigne and appoint you to be our Commissioners and Doe hereby give and grant unto you or
any ten or more of you full power and authority to treat with John Earle of Rothess Charles Earle of Dunfermeling
John Lord Lowden Sir Patrick Hepburne of Waughtone Sir William Douglas of Cavers William Drummond of Ricarton
John Smith Bailiffe of Edenborough Alexander Wedderburne Clerke of Dundy Hugh Kennedy Burgesse of Aire
Alexander Henderson and Archibald Johnston or any of them or any others deputed or to be deputed by our said
Subje&bholigct;s of Scotland or nominated or to be nominated on their behalfe and to take into your serious consideration
the said demands and compose conclude and end all differences arising thereupon or otherwise as you or any ten
or more of you in your wisdomes shall thinke fit and whatsoever you our said Commissioners or any ten or more
of you shall doe in the &bhopcrl;misses Wee Doe by these presents ratifie and confirme the same In Witnes whereof we
have caused these our Letters to be made Patents Witnes our selfe at Westminster the three and twentieth day
of November in the sixteenth yeare of our Reign &bhopubr; ipm Regem And in like manner a Commission hath been
granted by the Committees of the Parliament of Scotland bearing date the last of O&bholigct;ober and fourth dayes of
November 1640 yeares and in the words following. Wee the Commissioners of the Parliament of [Scotland<ref idref="n2">2</ref>.] being a
full number of both the Quorums thereof undersubscrivand Forsomikell as the Kings Majestie our dread Soveraigne
hes been graciously pleased upon our humble supplications to appoint ane Treatie and conference at Rippon betwixt
our Commissioners choisen and sent by us for that effe&bholigct; and ane number of the Peers of England who accordingly
met and have accorded upon certaine Articles as well anent the maintenance of our Armie as anent the cessation
of Armes during the Treatie And because the time for the ensuing Parliament of England could not permit the
Treatie to come to the wished conclusion there his Majestie was therefore likewise pleased to transferre the said
Treatie to London where the Parliament is to hold that there these intrusted by his Majestie and the Estates of
Parliament may have the better time and place to treat and conclude thereanent Therefore wee the said Commissioners
being a full number of both Quorums thereof under subscrivand be vertue and conforme to the Commission
granted to us by the Estates of Parliament do not onely approve the said Articles already agreed upon and subscribed
by our said Commissioners at Rippon but alsoe doe give by these presents full power and warrand and Commission
to John Earle of Rothess Lord Lesly Charles Earle of Dunfermeling Lord Urguhart and Fivie John Lord Lowdon Sir
Patrick Hepburn of Waughton Sir William Dowglas of Cavers William Drummond of Riccartone John Smith of
Edenburgh [Master<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Alexander Wedderburn of Dundy and Hugh Kennedy of Aire as Members of the Estates of
Parliament And because many things may occur concerning the Church and Assemblies thereof therefore besides
these of the Estates wee nominate and appoint [Master<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Alexander Henderson and [Master<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Archbald Johnston whom
wee adjoyn for that effe&bholigct; with full power to them or any sevin of them there being alwaies two of every Estate
to passe to the said City of London and there or at any other place convenient (mutually to be agreed upon) to
meete and convene with any who shall be appointed by His Majesty and Estates of Parliament of England for the
foresaid Treaty giveand grantand and committand like as we by these presents gives grants and commits to them in
manner aforesaid full power warrant and commission to treat consult advise determine and agree as well anent
the satisfying and granting of our demands as in obtaining and securing a setled peace for all time coming conform
to the instru&bholigct;ions given to them herewith or whilk shall be sent to them hereafter by us or any one of the said
Quorums at the Campe or Edenburg thereanent with power to them as said is to do every thing which may
conduce for the better and easier obtaining of our said demands and establishing a setled peace conform to
the said particular instru&bholigct;ions in such like manner as wee might doe if we were all personally present our selves in
full number promising to hold firm and stable all and every thing our said Commissioners in manner foresaid shall
doe in the &bhopcrl;misses conform to the said instru&bholigct;ions and in case it shall be found expedient or necessary to adde
any more Commissioners to the foresaid persons these who shall so be sent authorized under our hands or the full
number of any [of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the said Quorums shall have a like power and Commission be vertue of these presents with the
forenamed Commissioners in sike like manner as if theire names were particular expressed herein In Witnesse
whereof thir Presents are subscribed at Newcastle &amp; Edenburgh the last of O&bholigct;ober and fourth of November
1640 yeares. Rothes Montrose Cassellis Lothian Lindesay Balmerino Naper Burghly Es Couper Thomas Hop
W. Riccarton Home W. Caprinton J. Gartgirth Dundas Edward Edgar Richard Maxwell James Scott Porterfeild
W. Hamilton [Master<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] William Moir Ja. Sword Hew Kennedy Rutherford.</para>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Recital that, by virtue of such Commission, the Heads and Articles following had been treated and agreed upon</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">And forasmuch as by vertue of the said Commissions the Commissioners therein authorized have at length treated
and by the assistance and blessing of God have agreed upon the heads and Articles following.<br/>
Articles of the large Treaty concerning the establishing of the Peace betwixt the Kings Majesty and his
people of Scotland and betwixt the two Kingdomes agreed upon by the English and Scottish Commissioners
at the Citie of Westminster the seventh day of August 1641. the Scottish Commissioners having given in
the Declaration following, viz.</para>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">First Demand, as to Publication of A&bholigct;s of the late Parliament; Answer thereto</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">Wee Doe still in all Loyaltie as becometh humble and dutifull Subje&bholigct;s acknowledge our dependancie upon his
Majestie as our dread Soveraigne whether his Majestie live in Scotland or in England and shall alwaies and in all
things witnesse our high respe&bholigct;s and best affe&bholigct;ions to the Kingdome and Parliament of England according to the
strong [bonds<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] of nature and religion by which the two Kingdomes are joyned under one head and Monarch yet as
wee are fully assured that the Kingdome and Parliament of England is for the present far from any thought of
usurpation over the Kingdome &amp; Parliament of Scotland or theire Lawes and Liberties so for [the<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] preventing the
misunderstanding of the posterity and of strangers and for satisfying the scruples of others not acquainted with the
nature of this Treaty and the manner of our proceedings which may arise upon our coming into England and our
treating in time of Parliament We Doe by these declare and make knowne that neither by our treaty with the English
nor by seeking our peace to be established in Parliament nor any other a&bholigct;ion of ours do wee acknowledge any
dependancy upon them or make them Judges to us or our Lawes or any thing that may import the smallest
prejudice to our Liberties but that wee come in a free and brotherly way by our informations to remove all doubts
that may arise concerning the proceedings of our Parliament and to joyne our endeavors in what may conduce for
the peace and good of both Kingdomes no otherwise then if by the occasion of the King his residence in Scotland
Commissioners in the like exigence should be sent thither from England did demand that his Majesty would be
graciously pleased to command that the A&bholigct;s of the late Parliament may bee published in his Highnes name as our
Soveraigne Lord with consent of the Estates of Parliament convened by his Majesties authority. Whereunto it is
answered and agreed that forasmuch as the Kings Majestie at the humble desire of his Subje&bholigct;s did call and convene a
Parliament to be holden at Edenborough the second day of June 1640 wherein certaine A&bholigct;s were made and agreed
upon which A&bholigct;s his Majesty (for the peace and good of his Kingdome) is pleased to publish in his owne name
with the consent of the Estates And therefore C&bhooov;mands that the said A&bholigct;s bearing date the eleaventh day of June
1640 bee published with the A&bholigct;s to be made in the next Session of the same Parliament and that all the said A&bholigct;s
aswell of the precedent as of the next Session to be holden have in all time comeing the strength of Law and to
be universally received and obeyed by all the subje&bholigct;s of the Kingdome of Scotland. His Majestie doth in the word
of a King promise the publishing of the said A&bholigct;s in such sort as is above specified As for the manner of publishing
the said A&bholigct;s his Majesty approves that the declaration of the Estates in the begining of the A&bholigct;s and the conclusion
at the end may be passed in silence at the publishing of the A&bholigct;s and left out in the printed Copies and if any
thing shall further accurre concerning the manner of publishing the said A&bholigct;s his Majesties Commissioner may then
offer it to the Estates to be considered of his Majesty being most assured that the Estates of Parliament will have a great
care not to suffer his Majesties authority to be prejudiced in the managing of these great affaires. 3 December 1640.</para>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">Second Demand, and Answer thereto</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p8">The Second Demand That the Castle of Edenburgh and other strengths of the Kingdome should with the advice
of the Estates of Parliament according to theire foundation be furnished and used for defence and security of the
Kingdome. Is agreed unto.</para>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">Third Demand, as to Scotchmen in England subscribing the Covenant and being compelled to take Oaths, and Answer thereto</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p10">The third Demand. That Scottismen within his Majesties Dominions of England and Ireland may be freed from
censure for subscribing the Covenant and be no more pressed with Oathes and subscriptions unwarranted by theire
Lawes and contrary to theire Nationall Oath and Covenant approved by his Majesty. It is thereto answered and
agreed in his Majesties name upon December 8. 1640. That as his Majestie hath granted your first and second
demand so we do now in his Majestyes name answer to the third That all those who in his Dominions of England
or Ireland have beene imprisoned forfeited or censured any other way for subscribing of the Covenant or refusing
to take any other Oath contrary to the same shall be freed of those censures and shall be fully restored to theire
liberties estates and possessions and for the time coming that the Subje&bholigct;s of Scotland as Subje&bholigct;s of Scotland shall
not be constrained to any Oath contrary to the Lawes of that Kingdome and the religion there established. but such
of the Kingdome of Scotland as shall transport themselves into the Kingdomes of England or Ireland and there be
setled Inhabitants either by way of having Inheritance or Freehold or by way of setled Trades (by which the way
of trading of the Fa&bholigct;ors of Merchants nor of Merchants themselves is not to be understood) shall be subje&bholigct; to the
Lawes of England or Ireland and to the Oathes established by the Lawes and A&bholigct;s of Parliament in the said
Kingdomes respe&bholigct;ively wherein they live and have theire ordinary and constant residence and not otherwise and the
English and Irish shall have the like priviledge in Scotland. December 8. 1640.</para>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">Fourth Demand, as to Incendiaries being liable to the Sentence of the Two Parliaments, and Answer thereto</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p12">To the fourth Demand Craving that his Majesty may be graciously pleased to declare as an A&bholigct; of his Royall
Justice serving much to his own honour for the establishing of his Throne and for the good and peace of both
Kingdomes that whoesoever shall be found upon triall and examination by the Estates of either of the two Parliaments
(they judging against the persons subje&bholigct; to theire owne authority) to have been the authours and causers of the
late and present troubles and combustion whether by labouring to make and foment division betwixt the King and
his people or betwixt the two Nations or any other way shall be lyable to the censure and sentence of the said
Parliaments respe&bholigct;ively conform to the paper of December 9. 1640. It is answered upon the eleventh of December 1640.
That his Majestie beleeveth that he hath none such about him and therefore concerning that point he can make
no other declaration then that he is just and that all his Courts of Justice are free and open to all men his
Parliament in this Kingdome is now sitting and the current Parliament of Scotland neere approaching the time of
theire meeting to either of which he doth not prohibit any of his subje&bholigct;s to present theire just greivances or
complaints of whatsoever nature each medling and judging against the persons subje&bholigct; to theire owne authoritie 11
December 1640. It is further answered upon the said eleventh of December 1640/1641 to the fourth demand concerning
Incendiaries that his Majestie beleeveth he hath none such about him therefore concerning that point he can
make no other declaration then that he is just and that all his Courts of Justice are free and open to all men his
Parliament in this Kingdome is now sitting and the current Parliament in Scotland neere approaching the time of
their meeting in neither of which respe&bholigct;ive he doth not prohibit the Estates to proceed in trying and judgeing of
whatsoever of his Subje&bholigct;s And Whereas It was further demanded that as his Majestie would not hinder any of
his Subje&bholigct;s to be tryed and judged by the Parliament so that none after the sentence of the Parliament should
have accesse to his Majestie or be maintained or enjoy places or Offices and have credit or authoritie to inform and
advise his Majestie conform to the paper of December 23. 1640. It is declared in his Majesties name upon
December 30. 1640/1641beside his Majesties former answer his Majestie hath commanded us to declare in his name
that he will not imploy any person or persons in Office or place that shall be judged incapable by sentence of
Parliament nor will he make use of theire service without the consent of Parliament nor grant them accesse to
his person whereby they may interrupt or disturbe that firme peace which he now so much desireth he being confident
that they will proceed in a faire and just way and according to their severall professions with that respe&bholigct; to his
honour which in reason he may expe&bholigct; from good and dutifull subjects 30 December 1640.</para>
<para id="p13"><emph type="i">Fifth Demand, as to Restoration of Ships and Goods, and Answer thereto</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p14">The fifth demand. That theire Ships and Goods and all damage thereof may be restored. Is condescended unto
and to be reciprocall that all Ships and Goods taken at Sea or stayed in Ports with damage be restored on both
sides and that some summarie course be agreed upon for the performance thereof upon [the<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] demands of the particulars
on both sides conform to the paper of December 30. 1640. And further it was agreed upon the seventh of January 1640/1641
that all Ships taken and stayed should be reciprocally restored on both Sides and that the Scottish Commissioners
having informed that about fourscore ships of Scotland are yet stayed in the Ports and are like to suffer much
further losse and damage if they shall not be delivered into some hands who may have care of them It is agreed
for the more speedy expeding of the Scottish Shipps and that the owners thereof be not longer damnified by the
want of them that warrants shall be presently granted for delivery of all theire ships and that four thousand
pounds be presently advanced for Caulking Sail Cordage and other necessaries for helping the present setting forth
of the said Ships And for the rest of this Article when it shall come in the sixt demand it shall be agreed unto
septimo Januarij 1640/1641.</para>
<para id="p15"><emph type="i">Sixth Demand, as to the friendly Assistance and Relief to Scotland, and Answer thereto</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p16">To the sixt demand Concerning the losses which the Kingdome of Scotland hath sustained and the vast
charges they have beene put unto by the occasion of the late troubles and the reparations desired from the justice
and kindnes of the Kingdome of England toward releife thereof in manner and upon the Grounds expressed in
the paper of the seaventh of January 1640/1641. It is answered that this House thinks fit that a freindly assistance and
releife shall be given towards supply of the losses and necessities of the Scots and that in due time this House will
take into consideration the measure and manner of it conforme to the paper of the two and twentieth of January 1640/1641
And further the Parliament upon the third of February did declare that they did conceave that the sum of three
hundred thousand pounds is a fit proportion of that friendly assistance and releife formerly thought fit to be given
towards supply of the losses and necessities of theire brethren of Scotland and that the House would in due time
take into consideration the manner how and the time when the same shall be raised conforme to the paper of the
third of February 1640/1641 and given in to the Treaty upon the fifth thereof And Whereas it was desired by the
Scottish Commissioners that the English Commissioners would let them know from the Parliament the security
manner and termes of payment of the foresaid sum of three hundred thousand pounds and of the arreares due
for [the<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] releife of the Northerne Counties. It was agreed unto by Warrant and Order of the Parliament that they
should have fourscore thousand pounds as a part of the foresaid sum of three hundred thousand pounds with the
whole arreares due to the Army before the disbanding thereof conforme to the paper of the 26 of May 1641. and
given into the treaty the 27 of the said moneth. And concerning the security for payment of the remanent of the
said sum of three hundred thousand pounds which is arrear extending to two hundred &amp; twenty thousand pounds
It is resolved and agreed unto by both Houses of Parliament that an A&bholigct; of Parliament of publike faith shall
passe for security thereof And that one moyetie or equall halfe of the same extending to one hundred and ten
thousand pounds shall be paid at Midsomer in anno 1642. and the other moiety or equall halfe to (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) payed at
Midsomer in anno 1643 as the order of the House of Parliament of the 19 and 25 dayes of June 1641 do more
fully purport And in like manner Whereas it was desired by the Scottish Commissioners that they might know to
whom they should adresse themselves for payment of the s&bhouov;ms at the dayes appointed by the Parliament conforme
the Parliaments determination of the nineteenth of June Secondly at what place the payment should be made Thirdly
That a safe condu&bholigct; may be granted for the secure transporting of the moneys to Scotland at the termes of payment
agreed upon. It is answered and resolved by the Parliament That these Earles Lords and Commissioners following
shall be the persons to whom the Scots shall adresse themselves for the receiving of the s&bhouov;ms at the dayes
appointed by the Parliament Earle of Bedford Earle of Essex Earle of Warwick Earle of Holland Earle of Stanford
Lord Wharton Lord Mandevill Lord Brooke Mr Martin Sir Thomas Barrington Mr Capell Sir Arthur Ingram Sir
Gilbert Gerrard Sir Robert Pye Mr Henry Bellasis Sir Walter Erle Sir William Litton Sir Henry Mildmay Sir Thomas
Cheek Sir John Strangwaies Mr Arthur Goodwin Mr Hampden Alderman Soame Alderman Pennington. Resolved
upon the Question That the place of payment shall be the Chamber of London. Resolved upon the Question. That
a safe condu&bholigct; shall be granted for the secure transporting of the money to Scotland at the termes of Payment
agreed upon at the charge of the Scotts conforme to the paper of the 22. June 1641.</para>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">Seventh Demand, as to suppressing Writings, and Answerthereto</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p18">To the seventh Demand Desiring that as his Majesty hath approven the A&bholigct;s of the late Parliament wherein all
such declarations proclamations books libels and pamphlets as have beene made written or published against his
loyall and dutifull subje&bholigct;s of Scotland are recalled and ordained to be suppressed and destroyed so his Majesty may
be pleased to give order that the same may be recalled suppressed and forbidden in England and Ireland and that
the loyalty integrity and faithfulnesse of his Majesties subje&bholigct;s of Scotland towards his Majesties Roiall person and
Governement may at the closing of the Treaty of Peace and the time of publique thanksgiving for the same be made
known in all places and in all the parish Churches in his Majesties kingdomes. This was the more earnestly desired
and confidently expe&bholigct;ed from his Majesties Justice and goodnes because no calamity or distresse hath so sore vexed
or so deeply wounded the hearts of his Majesties subje&bholigct;s as that theire loyalty and love towards theire native King
should have been contraverted and by the malignancie of bad instruments brought into suspition and because they
unfainedly desire and pray for his Majesties happines and are resolved by all meanes and at all occasions to deny
themselves and what they have for his Majesties honour as is more fully contained in the paper of the 8 of
February 1640/1641 It is answered upon the tenth of February 1640/1641 Wee doe agree that Declarations Proclamations
A&bholigct;s Books Libels and [Phamplets<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] that have beene made and published against the loyalty and dutifulnes of his
Majesties Subje&bholigct;s of Scotland shall be recalled suppressed and forbidden in England and Ireland and that this be
reciprocall in Scotland if any such have beene made or published there in prejudice of his Majesties honour and
this upon diligent enquiry to be done by the Authority of the Parliament next sitting in Scotland of which the
Commissioners of Scotland doe promise to have an especiall care And we doe alsoe agree that when it shall please
Almighty God to grant a happy close of this Treaty of Peace the loyaltie of his Majesties said Subje&bholigct;s shall be
made knowne at the time of publique thanksgiving in all places and particularly in the parish Churches of his
Majesties Dominions unto which wee are the rather induced for that you expresse how deeply it hath wounded the
hearts of his Majesties said Subje&bholigct;s that theire loyaltie and love to his Majestie theire native King should be brought
in question and suspition whereas they unfainedly desire and pray for his Majesties happines and are resolved by
all meanes and at all occasions to deny themselves and what they have for his Majesties honour 10. February 1640/1641.</para>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">Eighth Demand, as to dismantling Berwick and Carlisle, and removing the Garrisons, and Answer thereto; As to Unity in Religion, and Uniformity of Church Government.; As to the King and Prince sometimes residing in Scotland.; As to choosing Officers of State, &amp;c. in Scotland.; As to placing some Scotchmen about the King and Queen and Prince.; As to none being about the King and Prince but those of the reformed Religion.; As to the Copper Coin</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p20">Concerning the eight Demand For an happy and durable peace which is the cheifest of all our desires and unto
which all our former seven Articles being now agreed upon are as many preparations we doe first of all desire
that all monuments tokens and shewes of hostility upon the borders of the two Kingdomes may be taken away and
that upon the reasons and considerations particularly expressed in the paper of the tenth of February 1640/ 1641 That
not only the Garrisons of Barwick and Carlile may be removed but that the workes may be sleighted and the
places dismantled. It is answered and agreed upon the fourteenth of June that his Majestie is desirous that all
things betwixt the Kingdomes of England and Scotland be reduced into the same state they were in before the
begining of the late troubles And therefore he doth give his assent to the advice of the two Houses of Parliament
that the Garrisons of Barwick and Carlile upon the disbanding of the Scotish Army now in England and of all such Forces as are gathered togeather in Scotland be likewise &bhopcrl;sently removed And that the Fortifications of Berwick and
Carlile be also reduced to the same condition they were before the late troubles so that all Fortifications in Scotland
be likewise put in the same condition they were before the said troubles and that the Workes be not repaired but
suffered to decay and that the Ordnance and Am[m]unition be removed and that it be without prejudice to his
Majesties former grant of the second demand concerning the keeping of the Castles of the Kingdome of Scotland
the fourteenth of June 1641. To theire desire concerning unity in religion and uniformity of Church Government
as a speciall meane for conserving of Peace betwixt the two kingdomes upon the grounds and reasons conteyned
in the paper of the tenth of March given in to the Treaty and Parliament of England. It is answered upon the
eleventh of June that his Majestie with advice of both Houses of Parliament doth approve of the affe&bholigct;ion of his
subje&bholigct;s of Scotland in theire desire of having a conformity of Church Government between the two Nations
And as the Parliament hath already taken into consideration the reformation of Church Government so they will
proceed therein in due time as shall best conduce to the glory of God and Peace of the Church and of both
Kingdomes undecimo Junij 1641. To theire desire of the Kings Majestie and the Prince their coming and residing
sometimes in Scotland upon the reasons given in February 16. 1640/1641. It is answered upon the ninth of June that
his Majesty doth take in good part the sense his subje&bholigct;s of Scotland have of his absence and the dutifull expression
they make of theire desire to have him and the Prince his sonne frequently amongst them and assuring himselfe
that they have no other intention in this demand but meerly to expresse their love to his person and the welfare
of his ancient Kingdome he declares unto them that as he shall finde the urgency of those affaires require his
presence and his other conveniencyes here permit he will repaire thither and the Prince his sonne so far as he may
know and be acquainted with the people there 9 Junij 1641. To the desire concerning the manner of choosing
and placing of the Officers of State Counsellers and Sessioners within the Kingdome of Scotland by advise of the
Parliament upon the grounds and reasons given in March 15. 1640/1641 It is answered the ninth of June in his Majesties
name We intend nothing more heartily and really then that our people should be governed by the Lawes of the
Kingdome and that all Judges in their severall Judicatories should judge accordingly therefore wee will never allow
nor permit that either Councellors Officers of State or Judges be exeamed from our and our Parliaments triall and
censure for the discharging of theire duties in theire severall Offices and Places likewise we conceive that nothing
will conduce more to the good of our service and the peaceable and happy Government of the Kingdom then
that Offices of State Places of Councell and Sessions and other Judicatories be provided with honest able and
qualified men for which end and because of our necessary absence from that kingdome which maketh the qualification
of persons fit for places lesse known unto us Wee shall so far give eare unto the Informations of our Parliament
and when our Parliament is not sitting of our Councell and Colledge of Justice as that we shall either make choice
of some one of such as they by common consent upon the vacancy of the place shall recommend unto us or if
wee shall conceive an other person to be fitter then any of those recommended we shall make the same knowne
to the Parliament or in the time betweene Parliaments to our Councell and Session that from them we may be
informed of the qualifications and abilities of the person named by us to the effe&bholigct; that if by theire information
it shall appeare to us that there is just exception against the life and qualification of the said partie we may timely
nominate some other against whom there shall be no just exception by which meanes we doubt not but that wee
shall from time to time chuse such honest men as for theire knowne integrities and abilities shall be fit to discharge theire
places of Offices with that duty and sufficiency which wee and our Subje&bholigct;s may justly expe&bholigct; which intention of ours
being now so fully and cleerly expressed we doubt not but will give good satisfa&bholigct;ion to our ensuing Parliament
And as we never intended to remove just and able men from theire places in the Colledge of Justice so we do now
declare for our peoples full satisfa&bholigct;ion that theire places shall be provided unto them Quam diu se bene gesserint
And if this our answer cannot content the Scottish Commissioners we doe then remit the whole answer to be considered
by us or our Commissioners and the Parliament at the next sitting thereof 9. June 1641. To theire desire of placing
some Scottishmen [men<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] of respe&bholigct; about the King and Queenes Majesties and the Prince his highnes upon the
grounds and reasons given in the 9 of Aprill 1641. It is answered His Majesties Goodnes and grace towards his
Subje&bholigct;s of Scotland in placing them about his owne person in places of greatest neernesse and trust hathe beene
such as ought to give them full satisfa&bholigct;ion of his Royall affe&bholigct;ion towards his subje&bholigct;s of his native Kingdome
therefore for this point his Majestie needeth only to assure them that he shall continue the same care which
hitherto he hath done for theire satisfa&bholigct;ion in this particular and not onely so but shall recommend the same to the
Prince his sonne that successively the kingdome of Scotland shall so taste of the care of their Soveraigns that by
the grace of God they shall never want a sufficient number of honest and sufficient persons of that Nation about
the Kings person and Prince against whom there shall be no just exception 9. June 1641. To theire desire that none
may have place about his Majestie and the Prince but such as are of the reformed religion in manner expressed
in the paper 1. of April 1641. It is answered That his Majestie doth conceive that his subje&bholigct;s of Scotland have no
intention by this proposition (especially by way of demand) to limit or prescribe unto him the choice of his servants
but rather to shew theire zeale to religion wherein his owne piety will make him doe therein that which may give
just satisfa&bholigct;ion to his people 9 June 1641. To theire desire given in the first of Aprill concerning Copper Coin.
It is answered Whereas the Scottish Commissioners have represented unto His Majestie the great prejudice sustained
by the Kingdome of Scotland through the coyning of Copper money which hath passed there this long time by
gone for seven times above as much as the true value and worth thereof contrary to the continuall custome of
that kingdome And therefore desiring that no Copper money be coyned hereafter without consent of the Estates
convened in Parliament who may remedy the present prejudices the Countrey sustaines thereby and who upon good
consideration of the necessity thereof in time to come may appoint such a competent proportion as is fit and as
[they<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] countrey shall require for the use of the poore and for change in buying and selling of Commodities and
that the same shall not passe but according to the intrinsick value thereof with the allowance of a tenth part or such
a proportion as the Parliament shall thinke fitt to allow for the impression and workmanship in coyning His Majesty
is gratiously pleased to recommend unto the ensuing Parliament of Scotland the whole matter of Copper Coyn and
remits to their consideration to take such order therein as they shall thinke fitting not onely concerning the Copper
Coin to be coined hereafter but also the Copper money already coined how the same shall take vent and passe in payment in time coming conform to the paper of the 9 of June.</para>
<section id="s2"><head>Concerning an A&bholigct; of Pacification and Oblivion.</head>
		<para id="p21"><emph type="i">As to an A&bholigct; of Pacification and Oblivion.; To what Persons the Benefit of such an A&bholigct; shall not extend.; Proviso for Recovery of Debts due by, and Arrears due to, the Scottish Army; and for the friendly Assistance and Relief.; As to Ships of the King or others stopping the Trade of the Kingdom.; As to persons levying Armies, &amp;c.; Proviso as to particular Quarrels upon the Borders.; Powers of the Commission restrained to the Articles of Peace in this Treaty.; As to the ensuing Parliament of Scotland having Power to ratify the Treaty.; As to the Powers of the King's Commissioners then sitting, &amp;c.; As to Offenders in one Kingdom removing into another.; As to extending this Provision to Debts as well as Crimes</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p22">It is agreed unto That in the approaching Parliament of Scotland there shall be an A&bholigct; of Pacification declaring
that the late Commotions and troubles arising from the innovation of Religion and Corruption of Church
Government by the mercy of God and the Kings Royall Wisdom and fatherly care are turned into a quiet
calm and comfortable peace lest either his Majesties love or the constant loyalty of his subje&bholigct;s in theire intentions
and proceedings be hereafter called in question and that such things as have fallen forth in these tumultuous
times while Lawes were silent whether prejudiciall to his Majesties honour and authority or to the lawes and
liberties of the Church and Kingdome or to the particular interest of the subje&bholigct; (which to examine and censure
in a stri&bholigct; course of Justice might prove an hinderance to a perfe&bholigct; peace) may be buried in perpetuall oblivion
So it is expedient for making the peace and unity of his Majesties Dominions the more firm and faithfull and
that his Majesties countenance against all fears may shine upon them all the more comfortably that an A&bholigct; of
Pacification and Oblivion be made in the Parliaments of all the three Kingdomes for burying in forgetfulnes all A&bholigct;s
of Hostility whether betwixt the King and his subje&bholigct;s or betweene subje&bholigct; and subje&bholigct; or which may be conceived
to arise upon the coming of any English Army against Scotland or the coming of the Scotish Army into England
or upon any A&bholigct;ion Attempt Assistance counsell or [device<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] having relation thereunto and falling out by the occasion
of the late troubles preceding the conclusion of the treaty and the return of the Scotish Army into Scotland that
the same and whatsoever hath ensued thereupon whether trenching upon the lawes and liberties of the Church and
Kingdome or upon his Majesties honour and authority in no time hereafter may be called in question or resented
as a wrong nationall or personall whatsoever be the quality of the person or persons or of whatsoever kind or
degree civill or criminall the injury be supposed to be and that no mention be made thereof in time coming
neither in judgement nor out of judgement but that it shall be held and reputed as though never any such thing had
beene thought nor wrought And this to be extended not onely to all his Majesties subje&bholigct;s now living but to theire
heires executors successors and all others whom it may concerne in any time to come And for that end that by
the tenour of this Statute all Judges Officers and Magistrates whatsoever be prohibited and discharged of dire&bholigct;ing
of Warrants for Citation processing or executing any sentence or judgement upon record or any way molesting any
of his Majesties lieges concerning the premisses in all time coming like as that his majesty for himselfe and his
successours promise in verbo Principis never to come in the contrary of this Statute or San&bholigct;ion nor any thing
therein contained but to hold the same in all points firm and stable and shall cause it to be truly observed by all
his Majesties lieges according to the tenour and intent thereof for now and ever And that in all time coming these
presents shall have the full force and strength of a true and perfe&bholigct; security as if they were extended in most
ample and legall forme Providing that the benefit of the said Statute shall no wayes be extended to any of the
Scottish Prelates or to John Earle of Traquaire Sir Robert Spotswood Sir John Hay and [Master<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Walter Belcanquall
cited and pursued as incendiaries betwixt the Kingdomes and betwixt the King and his people and for bribery
corruption and many other grosse crimes contained in theire charges generall &amp; speciall nor to any other person
who are cited and shall be found by the Parliament of Scotland in his Majesties or his Commissioners theire owne
hearing to be so extraordinary guilty of these and the like crimes as they cannot in Justice and with the honour of
the King and Countrey passe from them Provided further that the benefit of this A&bholigct; shall not be understood to
extend to the favour of theeves robbers murtherers broaken men [horners<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] outlawers nor theire receptors with
reservation also of the legall pursuites and processes of the Scots in Ireland for the reparation of theire losses
according to justice against such who have illegally wronged and persecuted them since by one of the Articles of
the Treaty they are appointed to be restored to their meanes and estates. It is also to be understood that nothing
is meaned hereby to be done in &bhopcrl;judice either of the payment of the debts oughten upon promisses or security
by the Scottish Army to any of the Counties or to any person there (the same being instru&bholigct;ed before the removall
of the Scottish Army) or of the arreares due to the Scottish Army or to that brotherly assistance granted them by
the Parliament of England. That the great blessing of a constant and freindly conjunction of the two Kingdomes
now united by allegeance and loyall subje&bholigct;ion to one Soveraigne and Head may be firmly observed and continued
to all posteritie It is agreed that an A&bholigct; be past in the Parliament of England that the Kingdome of England or
Ireland shall not denounce nor make war against the Kingdome of Scotland without consent of the Parliament
of England as on the other part it shall be ena&bholigct;ed there that the Kingdome of Scotland shall denounce nor
make wars against the Kingdom of England or Ireland without the consent of the Parliament of Scotland.
No Ships either of the Kings or Freebooters or others shall stop the trade of the Kingdome or hinder or harme
theire neighbour kingdome without consent of Parliament declaring a breach of Peace And if any Armies shall
be levied or trade stopped and neighbors harmed or wronged the estates of the Countrie by which it is done to
be obliged to pursue take and punish the Offendors with all rigour And if any of the Kingdoms assist receave or
harbour them they ought to be punished as breakers of the peace and if after complaint and remonstrance to the
Commissioners after mentioned and to the Parliament redresse and reparation be not made then in that case the
same (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) be counted a breach of the peace by the whole kingdome And in case any of the Subje&bholigct;s of any of the
Kingdomes shall rise in Armes or make war against any other of the kingdoms and subje&bholigct;s thereof without consent
of the Parliament of that kingdome whereof they are subje&bholigct;s or upon which they doe depend that they shall be
held reputed and demained as traitours to the Estates whereof they are subje&bholigct;s and that both the Kingdoms in
that case be bound to concur in the repressing of those that shall happen to arise in Armes or make war without
consent of their own Parliament and that the way of convening forces for suppressing such as levy war be as in
case of invasion Provided that this be not extended to any particular quarrels upon the Borders And that it be
ena&bholigct;ed that in such case it shall be lawfull for any of the subje&bholigct;s to convene to suppresse such evill affe&bholigct;ed
persons and that each kingdome shall be bound by publique faith pun&bholigct;ually to performe this Article And if either
Parliament shall denounce war they shall give three monthes warning that the peace to be now established [may<ref idref="n16">16</ref>]
be inviolably observed in all time to come It is agreed that some shall be appointed by his Majestie and the
Parliaments of both Kingdoms who in the interim betwixt the sitting of the Parliaments may be carefull that the
peace now happily concluded may be continued and who shall endeavour by all meanes to prevent all troubles and
divisions And if any debate or difference shall happen to arise to the disturbance of the Common Peace they
shall labour to remove or compose them [according<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] to theire power It being supposed that for all theire proceedings
of this kinde they shall be answerable to the Kings Majestie &amp; the Parliaments and if any thing shall fall forth
which is above theire power and cannot be remedied by them they shall informe themselves in the particulars and
represent the same to the Kings Majestie and the ensuing Parliament that by their wisdoms and authoritie all occasion
and causes of troubles [being<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] removed the peace of the Kingdome may be perpetuall to all posteritie And it is
declared that the power of the Commission shall be restrained to the Articles of Peace in this Treatie. Where it is
desired that an A&bholigct; may be made in the Parliament of England for ratifying of the Treaty and all the Articles
thereof which is likewise to be ratified in the Parliament of Ireland (which in all the Articles is comprehended
under the name of England) And after the treatie is confirmed in the said English Parliament and all other
necessary conditions performed the Armies on both sides shall att a certaine day to be appointed for that effe&bholigct;
remove and disband so that when the Scottish Army shall remove from Newcastle the English Army shall likewise
be disbanded and repaire home to theire severall Countreys and Places of theire residence and the Irish Army to be
disbanded before that time that hereafter a quiet and durable peace may be kept according to the Articles And that
this treaty and whole proceedings thereof may be likewise ratified in the Parliament of Scotland and a firme peace
established It is desired that his Majestie may be gratiously pleased now to declare that the ensuing Parliament of
Scotland shall have full and free power as the nature of a free Parliament of that kingdome doth of it selfe import
to ratifie and confirme the treatie and whole Articles thereof and to receive account of all Commissions granted by
them examine theire proceedings and grant exonerations thereupon and to treate deliberate conclude and ena&bholigct;
whatsoever shall be found conducible to the setling of the good and peace of that Kingdome And that his Majesties
C&bhooov;missioners shall be authorized with full power to approve whatsoever A&bholigct;s &amp; Statutes which upon mature
deliberation shall happen to be accorded unto by the Estates in that behalfe and shall sit and continue without
interruption or prorogation while all things necessary for that effe&bholigct; be determined ina&bholigct;ed and brought to a finall
conclusion unlesse for the better convenience of affairs his Majesties Commissioner with the speciall advice and assent
of the Estates shall thinke fit to adjourne the same to any other time which shall no wayes derogate from the full
and perfe&bholigct; concluding of the whole premisses before the said Parliament be dissolved. This whole Article is assented
unto in so far as concerns the dayes and circumstances of disbanding to be agreed unto. Forasmuch as the severall
jurisdi&bholigct;ions and administrations of Justice in either Realm may be deluded and frustrated by delinquents for theire
owne impunity if they shall commit any offence in the one Realm and thereafter remove theire persons and make
theire abode in the other Therefore that no person sentenced by the Parliament of either Nation as Incendiaries
betwixt the nations or betwixt the King and his people shall enjoy any benefit civill or ecclesiasticall or have any
shelter or prote&bholigct;ion in any other of his Majesties Dominions like as where malefa&bholigct;ors and Criminals guilty of the
crimes mentioned in the A&bholigct; of Parliament 1612. Cap. 2. and others of that nature and committed by Scottishmen
within the Kingdomes of England or Ireland or any part thereof are taken and apprehended in England or Ireland
that it shall be lawfull to the Justices of England or Ireland to remaund them to Sea or Land as the A&bholigct;s beares And
further if any Malefa&bholigct;ors committing crimes in Scotland England or Ireland being duely processed in the Kingdoms
where the crimes are committed and being fugitives or remaining in any other of the Kingdomes foresaids that the
Judges of either Kingdome shall be houlden at the instance and suite of the partie offended to take and remaund
the criminals and Malefa&bholigct;ors to the Kingdomes where the crimes were committed and the like to be made in
Scotland And this would be extended aswell to debts as crimes and what further is requisite concerning this and
other particulars for setling of peace in the middle Shires and accelerating Justice upon the Delinquents both in
civill and criminall causes is to be considered by the Committee appointed for that effe&bholigct;. It is answered that
such persons as shall be Natives in either Kingdome and shall commit any offence in the Realme whereof they
shalbe Natives and shall afterwards remove their persons into the other and such persons as shall be Inhabitants
in either Kingdome and shall commit any Offence in the Realm where they shall be Inhabitants during the time
of their habitation there and shall afterwards remove theire persons into the other and shall be for the same censured
by the Parliament of that Nation where the offence was committed as Incendiaries betwixt the nations or betwixt the
King and his people shall not enjoy any benefit civill or ecclesiasticall or have any shelter or prote&bholigct;ion in any other
of his Majesties Dominions And that such Scottish Natives incensing the King of England against the Kingdome of
Scotland shall be remaunded at the desire of the Scottish Parliament into Scotland to abide theire tryall and censure
there so that the same be reciprocall to both Nations but other criminals and debts to be referred to the Lawes.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3"><head>The Propositions and Articles given in by the Scottish Commissioners after the Lord Lowdons return from
the Parliament of Scotland.</head>
<para id="p23"><emph type="i">Propositions by the Scottish Commissioners after Lord Lowdon's Return from the Parliament of Scotland</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p24">That the Treatie of Peace may be brought to a speedie and happie close Wee doe offer to your Lordshipps
consideration the particulars following.</para>
<para id="p25"><emph type="i">First.; Second.; Third.; Fourth.; Fifth.; Sixth.; Seventh.; Eighth.; Ninth.; Tenth.; Eleventh.; Twelfth</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p26">1. That so soone as the Scottish Army shall remove out of England to Scotland the English Garrisons of Barwick
and Carlile may remove simul et semel.</para>
		<para id="p27">2. Lest Malefa&bholigct;ors who have committed theft murder and the like crimes crave the benefit of the A&bholigct; of
Pacification and Oblivion for whom it is no wayes intended there would be an exception from the said A&bholigct;s of all
legall persuits intended or to be intended within the space of an yeare after the date of the treaty against theeves
sorners Outlawers fugitives murderers broken men or their receptaries for whatsoever thefts rifes hareships oppressions
depredations or murthers done or committed by them and all lawfull decreits given or to be given by the Parliament
or any Commissioners to be appointed by them for that effe&bholigct; who shall have power to dignosce and take cognition
whether the same falls within the said A&bholigct; of Pacification or Oblivion or not.</para>
		<para id="p28">3. It is desired that the demaund concerning the not making or denouncing war with forraigners without consent
of both Parliaments may be condescended unto by the King and Parliament of England which is ordinary and
universally observed in all mutuall leagues which are both offensive and defensive and because the wars denounced
by one of the Kingdomes with forreigners although made without consent of the other Kingdome will engage them
by necessary consequence or if the consideration of this proposition shall require longer time then the present
condition of the important affairs of the Parliament may permitt and least the speedy close of the treaty be thereby
impeded it is desired that this demand with the other two Articles of the same nature the one concerning leagues
and confederations and the other concerning mutuall supply in case of forraign invasion may all three be remitted
to Commissioners to be chosen by both Parliaments who shall have power to advise and treat thereupon for the
good of both Kingdoms and report to the Parliaments respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		<para id="p29">4. It is desired that the Articles concerning trade and commerce naturalization mutuall priviledge and capacity
and others of that nature already demanded may be condescended unto by the King and Parliament of England
and namely that demand anent the pressing of men and ships by sea or land or if shortnes of time and exigence of
affaires may not permit the present determination of these demands it is desired that the same (except so many of
them as are already agreed unto by the Commissioners for trade) may be remitted to the Commissioners to be
chosen by both Parliaments who shall have power to treat and advise thereof for the good of both Kingdomes and
to make report to the Parliaments respe&bholigct;ively and that the Charters or Warrants of the Scotch nation for freedom
of Shipping in England or Ireland from all customs imposts duties and fees more then are paid by the Natives of
England or Ireland granted by King James under the broad Seal of England upon the eleventh day of Aprill in the
thirteenth yeare of his reign and confirmed by King Charles upon the nineteenth of Aprill in the eight yeere of his
reign may be ena&bholigct;ed and ratified in this Parliament.</para>
		<para id="p30">5. That the extra&bholigct;s of Bonds and decreits put upon record and register in Scotland may have the like faith
and execution as the French Tabellions have in England and Ireland seeing they are of a like nature and deserves
more credit and if this cannot be done at this time that it be remitted to the former Commission from both
Parliaments.</para>
		<para id="p31">6. The manner of safe condu&bholigct; for transporting the moneys from England to Scotland by Sea or Land would be
condescended upon in such way as the charges be not exorbitant and may be presently knowne.</para>
		<para id="p32">7. The tenour of the Commission for conserving of Peace would be condescended unto togeather with the times
and places of meeting and whole frame thereof the draught whereof when it is drawn up in England is to be
represented to the Parliament of Scotland that they may make the like Commission and name their C&bhooov;missioners
for that effe&bholigct;.</para>
		<para id="p33">8. The Parliament of Scotland doe joyne theire earnest and hearty desires and craves the Parliaments of Englands
concurse that none be placed about the Princes Hignesse but such as are of the reformed religion.</para>
		<para id="p34">9. That an A&bholigct; of Parliament of publique faith for payment of the 220000 pound which is arreare of the
brotherly assistance may be presently framed and exped according to the termes agreed upon.</para>
		<para id="p35">10. It is desired that the Quorum to whom the Scots should addresse themselves for payment of the two hundreth
and twenty thousand pounds be condescended upon.</para>
		<para id="p36">11. That the Order for recalling all Proclamations &amp;c. made against his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s of Scotland be drawn
up and intimate in due forme and time with the publique thanksgiving at all the parish churches of his Majesties
Dominions.</para>
		<para id="p37">12. It is desired that the Articles concerning the Castle of Edenburgh and other strengths of that Kingdome may
be understood to be that the samen shall be disposed of for the weale of the Kingdome as the King and Parliament
shall thinke it expedient.</para>
</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>The English Lords Commissioners answer.</head>
			<para id="p38"><emph type="i">The English Lords Commissioners Answer to the First Proposition.; to the Second.; to the Third.; to the Fourth, Fifth, and Sixth.; to the Seventh.; to the Eighth.; to the Ninth.; to the Tenth.; to the Eleventh.; to the Twelfth.; The said Treaty ratified; and to be observed for ever</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">That upon the disbanding of the Scottish Armie the Garrisons of Barwick and Carlile shall be removed according
to the Article of the treatie in that behalfe.</para>
			<para id="p40">The second Article is condescended unto according to the Provision added to the A&bholigct; of Pacification.</para>
			<para id="p41">The third demand concerning making of War with forraigners with the other twoe Articles concerning leagues
and Confederations and concerning mutuall supply and assistance against foraign Invasion is agreed to be referred to
Commissioners to be chosen by his Majestie and the Parliaments.</para>
			<para id="p42">As likewise the fourth fift and sixt Articles concerning Trades Commerce Naturalization mutuall priviledges and
capacity and other of that nature and the demands concerning the extra&bholigct; of Bonds and decreits and the manner of
safe condu&bholigct; for transporting the moneyes from England to Scotland are all referred to be taken in consideration by
the Commissioners to be appointed by both Parliaments who shall have power to advise and treat thereupon and
report to the Parliament respe&bholigct;ive.</para>
			<para id="p43">It is just that the tenor of the Commission for conserving of Peace should be agreed on by mutuall consent but
the closing of the treaty not to stay hereupon but to be left to the Commissioners to be named.</para>
			<para id="p44">To that desire concerning such as should be placed about the Prince the King hath already given a clear and
satisfa&bholigct;ory answer.</para>
			<para id="p45">That there be an A&bholigct; of Parliament of publique faith for securing the payment of 220000 pounds which is arrere
of the brotherly assistance is just and order is given for it accordingly and it shall be communicated with the Scottish
Commissioners that it may be a perfe&bholigct; security.</para>
			<para id="p46">The tenth for appointing a Quorum for attending the payment of the money is already moved to the Parliament
and will be done as is desired.</para>
			<para id="p47">The eleventh Article is very just and Order shall be given accordingly for recalling all Proclamations and for
publique thanksgiving.</para>
			<para id="p48">This twelfth Article for the Castle of Edinburgh and other strengths of Scotland is to be setled betwixt his
Majestie and the Commissioners of Scotland or by his Majestie and Parliament of Scotland.</para>
			<para id="p49">All which Articles are assented unto and approved by his Majestie with the advice of the Parliament of England and
by the Committees of the Parliament of Scotland and are necessary for publique declaration of mutuall consent and
for firme observation to be confirmed and ratified in the Parliaments of both Kingdomes. Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by
his Majestie with the assent of the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled that the said Treaty
and the Articles thereof assented unto as aforesaid be and stand for ever ratified and established and have the force
vigour strength and authority of a Law Statute and A&bholigct; of Parliament.</para>
			<para id="p50">Like as this above written Treaty and whole Articles thereof are by his Majestie and the Estates of the Parliament
of Scotland to be ena&bholigct;ed and ordained to have in all time coming the full force and strength of a true and perfe&bholigct;
security and A&bholigct; of the said Parliament. And his Majesty for himselfe and his successours doth promise in verbo Principis
never to come in the contrary of this Statute and San&bholigct;ion nor any thing therein contained but to hold the same in all
points firme and stable and shall cause it to be truly observed by all his majesties lieges according to the tenour
and intent thereof for now and ever. Like as the Parliaments of both Kingdomes gives full assurance and do make
publique faith in name of both Kingdomes respe&bholigct;ively for the true and faithfull observance of this treatie and whole
Articles thereof inviolably hinc inde in all times to come.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2"> Scotland <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3"> M[er] <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5"> bands <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9"> be <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10"> Pamphletts <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12"> the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13"> advice <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14"> Mr <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15"> Sorners <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16"> to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


