<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47220" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER IX. An Act for the speedie provision of money for disbanding the Armies and setling the peace of the two Kingdomes of England and Scotland, [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. n. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Sums payable by Persons of the several Ranks hereafter mentioned.A Duke &pound;100.; A Marquis &pound; 80.; An Earl &pound;60. ; A Viscount &pound; 50.; A Baron &pound; 40.; Eldest Son of Earl &pound;40.; Eldest Son of Viscount &pound; 35.; Eldest Son of Baron &pound;30. ; A Baronet &pound;30.; A Knight of the Bath &pound;30.; Knight Batchelor &pound;20.; King's Serjeant &pound;25.; Serjeant &pound;20.; King's Counsel &pound;20.; Esquire &pound; 10.; Widow rated at One-third according to the Rank of her Husband.; All other Persons &pound;100. per Anu. &pound;5</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the present raising of great s&bhouov;ms of money for the speedy disbanding of both Armies is a
matter of so vast consequence and urgent necessity that not onely the firme and happy peace between the
two Kingdomes of England and Scotland but alsoe the well being and prosperity of this kingdome depends upon it
which said s&bhouov;ms of money cannot be soe suddenly raised as the pressing occasion doth require without some
extraordinary meanes used to the which all well affe&bholigct;ed persons in this soe visible exigent of the Common Wealth
will cheerefully submit. May it therefore please your Most Excellent Majestic That it may be ena&bholigct;ed And be
it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings Most Excellent Majestie the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled
and by the authority of the same That all and every person and persons of the severall rankes and degrees hereafter
men&bhocotil;ned shall to the purpose aforesaid contribute and pay the severall sums of money hereafter in this A&bholigct; set
downe and appointed that is to say Every person of the degree of a Duke of England Scotland or Ireland inhabiting
or residing within this Kingdome shall pay the s&bhouov;m of One hundred pounds Every person of the degree of a Marquesse
of either of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome the sum of fowerscore pounds
Every person of the degree of an Earle of either of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting and residing within
this Kingdome the sum of threescore pound Every person of the degree of a Viscount of either of the said three
Kingdomes and inhabiting and residing within this Kingdome the sum of fiftie pounds Every person of the degree
of a Baron of either of the three Kingdomes and inhabiting and residing within this Kingdome the sum of fourty
pounds The eldest Sonne of every Earle of either of the said three Kingdomes and residing within this Realme
being of the age of one and twenty yeares fourty pound The eldest Son of every Viscount of either of the said
three Kingdomes residing within this Realme being of the age of one and twenty yeares thirty five pounds the
eldest son of every Baron of either of the said three Kingdomes and residing within this Realme beinge of the age
of one and twenty yeares thirty pound Every person of the degree of Baronets of either of the three Kingdomes
or of Nova Scotia and inhabiting and residing within this Kingdome the sum of thirty pound Every person who is
a Knight of the Order of the Bath inhabiting and residing within this Kingdome the sum of thirty pound Every
person whoe is a Knight Batchelour inhabiting and residing within this Kingdome the sum of twenty pound Every
person whoe is the Kings Serjeant at Law the sum of twenty five pounds Every other Serjeant at Law the sum
of twenty pound Every person who is of the Learned Councell to the Kings Majestie the Queene or Prince and by
vertue thereof or by any Privie Seale pra&bholigct;ises within the Barrs at Westminster the sum of twenty pound Every
person of the degree of an Esquire or soe reputed inhabiting and residing within this Kingdome and above the age
of one and twenty yeares the sum of ten pounds Every Widdow respe&bholigct;ively according to her husbands degree
shall pay the third part rated by this Bill upon that degree of which the husband of such Widdow was in his life
time Every person of what degree or quality soever below the degrees above mentioned inhabiting and residing
within this Kingdome and whoe can dispend One hundred pounds per annum of his or her own either in Lands
Leases Money Stock or otherwise the sum of five pound</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Persons of the several Ranks hereaftermentioned.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Bishop &pound;60.; Dean &pound;40.; Canon &pound;20.; Prebend &pound;10.; Parson of &pound;100.; per Annum &pound;5. do&bholigct;or in Law, Advocate &pound;10.; Archdeacon &pound;15.; Chancellor to Bishop, &#x0026;c. &pound;15.; do&bholigct;or in Physick &pound;10.; Register to Bishop, &#x0026;c. &pound;10. &pound;5.; pro&bholigct;or &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that all and every person and persons of the severall ranks
and degrees hereafter mentioned shall to the purpose aforesaid contribute and pay the severall sums of money hereafter
in this A&bholigct; set downe and appointed that is to say Every Bishop of this Kingdome shall pay the sum of threescore
pounds Every Dean of any Cathedrall Church in England the sum of forty pounds Every Canon resident of any
Cathedrall Church within this Kingdome the sum of twenty pounds Every Prebend of any Cathedrall Church within
this Kingdome albeit he be not resident the sum of ten pound Every Parson or Vicar being Owner of a Parsonage
or Vicaridge or other Estate of the cleer yearely value of One hundred pounds the sum of five pound Every person
that is do&bholigct;or in the Civill or Cannon Lawes or Advocate the sum of ten pounds Every person who is an Arch
Deacon shall pay the sum of fifteen pound Every person who is Chancellour to any Bishop or Commissary or Officiall
to any Dean or Arch Deacon the sum of fifteene pounds Every do&bholigct;or in Phisick the sum of ten pounds Every
person who is Register to any Bishop ten pounds and to any Arch Deacon five pound Every pro&bholigct;or in any ecclesiasticall
Court five pound.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Lord Mayor of London &pound;40.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Sheriff or Alderman &pound;20.; Deputy Alderman &pound;15.; Masters of 12 first Companies &pound;10.; Wardens &pound;6. 13s 4d.; Common Council Man &pound;5.; Liverymen of the 12 first Companies. &pound;5.; Yeomen of such Companies &pound;3.; Masters of the Company of Dyers and other Companies &pound;6.; Wardens &pound;5.; Liverymen &pound;3.; Yeomen &pound;1.; Masters of the Company of Barber Surgeons and other Companies, &#x0026;c. &pound;3.; Wardens &pound;2.; Liverymen &pound;1.; Masters of the Founders and other Companies &pound;1.; Wardens 15s.; Liverymen 10s.; Liverymen of the Company of Bowyers and other Companies 5s.; Freeman of any Company IS.; Merchant Stranger being a Knight &pound;40.; Below that and trading to Sea &pound;10.; Merchant Stranger trading inland &pound;5.; English Merchants of London not free &pound;5.; English fa&bholigct;or of London 40s.; Handicraftsman 5s.; Alderman of any City under a Knight or Esquire &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that all and every person and persons of the severall degrees
and qualities hereafter men&bhocotil;ned shall to the purpose aforesaid contribute and pay the severall s&bhouov;ms of money
hereafter men&bhocotil;ned in this Bill and set downe that is to say the Lord Maior of London shall pay the sum of forty
pound Every such person who is either now Sheriffe or Alderman of the said City of London or hath fined for
Sheriffe or Alderman the Sum of twenty pounds Every person who hath beene or now is Deputy to any Alderman
within the said City the sum of fifteen pound Every person who hath beene or now is Master of either of the
twelve first Companies of the said City or hath fined for Master of either of the said twelve Companies the sum
of tenn pound Every person who hath beene or now is Warden of either of the twelve first Companies of the said
City or hath fined for Warden of either of the twelve first Companies six pound thirteene shilling four pence
Every person whoe is of the Common Councell of the said City the Sum of five pound Every person who is of the
Livery of either of the said twelve first Companies of the said City the sum of five pound Every person who is
of the Yeomanry of either of the twelve first Companies three pound Every person who is or hath been Master of
either of the Companyes of Dyers Brewers Leathersellers Girdlers Stationers Woodmongers [Upholsters<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Apothecaries
Pewterers Tallow [Chanlers<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Armorers or Sadlers the sum of six pound Every person who is or hath beene Warden
of either of the said Companies five pound Every person who is of the Livery of either of the said Companies three
pounds Every person who is of the Yeomanry of either of the said Companyes one pound Every person who hath
been or is Master of either of the Companies of Barber Chirurgions White Bakers Wax Chandlers Cutlers
Butchers Carpenters Cordwainers Painters Coopers Scriveners Brown-Bakers Turners or Inholders the sum of
three pound Every person who is or hath been Warden of either of the said Companies two pound Every person
who is of the Livery of either of the said Companies one pound Every person who is or hath been Master of either
of the Companies of Founders Curriers Masons Bricklayers Joyners Plasterers Weavers Fruiterers Marblers
Imbroderers Poulterers Cookes or Plumbers the sum of one pound Every person who is or hath beene Warden of
either of the said Companies fifteen shillings Every person who is of the Livery of either of the said Companies
ten shillings Every person whoe is or hath beene of the [Livory<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] of either of the Companies of Bowyers Fletchers
Blacksmiths Bottlemakers Wooll packers Farriers Pavyers Lorriners Glasiers Clarkes or Watermen five shillings
Every person who is a Freeman of any Company within the City of London the sum of one shilling, Every person
who is a Merchant Stranger if he be of the degree of a Knight the sum of forty pound if below that degree and
be a Merchant Stranger trading to Sea the sum of ten pound Every person who is a Merchant Stranger trading
within the Land the sum of five pound every person who is an English Merchant inhabiting and residing within
the said City of London and not free of the said City the sum of five pound Every English fa&bholigct;or residing in the said
City the sum of fourty shillings Every Handicrafts man or Artizan Stranger who is a Housekeeper (in any part
of this Kingdome) the sum of five shillings Every person who is [or<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] hath beene an Alderman of any City within
this Kingdome if he be below the degree of a Knight or Esquire the sum of five pound</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The several Offices hereafter mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Prothonotary K. B. &pound;40.; Clerk of the Crown K. B. &pound;20.; Custos Brevium K. B. &pound;40.; Master of the Rolls &pound;60.; Clerk of the Crown in Chancery &pound;20.; Clerk of the Chancery &pound; 30.; Usher of Chancery &pound;30.; Cursitor &pound;5.; Clerk of the Petty Bag &pound;10.; Examiner &pound;10.; Prothonotary of C. P. &pound;20.; Custos Brevium C. P. &pound; 60;Philazer of C. P. &pound;5.; Attorney of the Court of Exchequer &pound;10.; Auditor &pound;10.; Clerk of the Court of Wards and Liveries &pound;60.; Attorney of that Court &pound;5.; Auditor &pound;10.; Feodary &pound;10.; Escheator &pound;5.; Clerk of Duchy Court &pound;10.; Auditor &pound;10.; Clerk of the Privy Seal &pound;10.; Attorney of Court of Requests &pound;10.; Clerk of the Signet &pound;10.; Attorney at Law &pound;3.; Officer under the King, except Houshold, receiving &pound;10 per Ann. &pound;10.; Estate of &pound;50. per Ann. 40s. of &pound;20. per Ann. 5s.; of &pound;10. per Ann. 2s.; of &pound;5. per. Ann. 1s.; All other Persons above 16. and not receiving Alms, 6d</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every such person and persons who is possessed
of any of the severall Offices or Places hereafter men&bhocotil;ned in theire owne rights shall pay the severall sums hereafter
men&bhocotil;ned that is to say The Prothonotary of the Kings Bench the sum of fourty pound The Clarke of the Crowne
in the Kings Bench twenty pound The Custos Brevium of the Court of Kings Bench fourty pound The Master of
the Rolls threescore pound The Clarke of the Crowne in the High Court of Chancery twenty pound Every one of
the Six Clarks in the said Court of Chancery thirty pound The Usher of the Court of Chancery thirty pound
Every Cursitor of the said Court five pound Every Clarke of the Petty Bag ten pound Every Examiner of the said
Court tenn pound Every Prothonotor of the Court of Common Pleas twenty pound The Custos Brevium of the
Court of Common Pleas threescore pound Every Philizer of the said Court five pound Every Atturney of the Court
of Exchequer ten pound Every Auditor of the said Court ten pound The Clarke of the Court of Wards and
Liveries threescore pound Every Atturney of that Court five pound Every Auditor of that Court ten pound Every
Feodary ten pound Every Escheator five pound The Clarke of the Court of the Dutchy of Lancaster ten pound
Every Auditor of that Court ten pound Every Clarke of the Privie Seale ten pound Every Atturney of the Court of
Requests ten pound Every Clarke of the Signet ten pound Every Atturney at Law of any of the Courts at
Westminster the sum of three pound Every person in any Office or Place under his Majestie except his Majesties
Servants in ordinary of his Household who receiveth the yearely fee of ten pound the sum of ten pound Every
person that can dispend in Lands Leases Money Stocke or otherwise of his or her owne proper estate fifty pound
yearely the sum of fourty shillings Every person who can dispend of his or her owne proper estate twenty pound
yearely in Lands Leases Money Stock or otherwise the sum of five shillings Every person who can dispend of his
or her owne proper estate ten pound yearely in Lands Leases Money or Stock the sum of two shillings Every person
who can dispend of his or her owne proper Estate five pound yearely in Lands Leases Money or Stock the sum of
one shilling And every other person of what estate or degree soever he or shee be with in his Majesties Kingdome of
England and Dominion of Wales and not rated before in this present A&bholigct; nor receiving alms and above the age of
sixteen yeares shall pay six pence</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Popish Recusants convi&bholigct; of the aforesaid Degrees,</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Double Rate.; Times and Proportions of Rates to be paid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that every person who is a popish Recusant of any the
severall degrees rankes and qualities before in this Bill set forth and mentioned convi&bholigct; or which is or shall be
indi&bholigct;ed for Popish Recusancie and such Indi&bholigct;ments either are or shall be removed by Certiorari or being not
removed shall not by appearance and traverse legally be discharged before the said Assessment shall be due or shall
not have received the Holy Communion according to the rites of the Church of England within one whole yeare
next before the passing of this Bill every such person shall pay double the rate and proportion imposed on the said
degree ranke or quality of which he or shee the said Popish Recusant is or otherwise imposed on him or her by
vertue of this A&bholigct; And all the severall persons of the severall degrees ranks and qualities before set forth in this
Bill shall pay the severall propor&bhocotil;ns and rates appointed by this Bill in manner and forme to be disposed of as in
this present A&bholigct; hereafter is expressed that is to say Every person of the severall degrees ranks and qualities before
mentioned within the City of London and ten miles from the same shall within four dayes after Proclama&bhocotil;n made
of this A&bholigct; in the accustomed places within the said City and the severall Counties within the said distance respe&bholigct;ively
pay the severall rates appointed by this A&bholigct; to be paid by them and every person of what degree ranke or qualitie
soever thorowout the Kingdome of England &#x0026; Dominion of Wales within ten dayes after Proclamation made of
this A&bholigct; in the accustomed places of the severall Counties shall pay the severall rates appointed by this A&bholigct; to be
paid by them</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Commissions under the Great Seal for levying the Rate to the several Commissioners named in c. 4. ante.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners for Bristol.; The Cinque Ports.; Dover.; Folkstone.; Feversham.; Seaford.; Hastings.; New Romney.; Lidd.; Hithe.; Sandwich. Rye.; Winchelsea.; Ten Schedules affixed to Commissions containing the tenor of A&bholigct;.; Commissioners to divide themselves; and to execute A&bholigct; without Favour, &#x0026;c.; Commissioners to dire&bholigct; Precepts to certain Number of Inhabitants, &#x0026;c. in Hundreds, &#x0026;c. to appear before Commissioners; and on Appearance Commissioners to read the Rates, and instuct them how to make their Certificates, &#x0026;c. and after such Charge to prefix another Day for Appearance and bringing in Certificates, under a Penalty;and thereupon the Commissioners to make the Precepts to colle&bholigct;ors, &#x0026;c.; Commissioners suspe&bholigct;ing Estate &#x0026;c. to be of greater Value than specified may examine, but not on Oath, and set Rate.; Persons refusing to pay.; Distress.; If Rate not paid in four Days Distress appraised and sold.; Overplus to Owner.; Officers, &#x0026;c. to answer for the Portion limited to them only.; Money comprized in Estreat to be paid to the Sheriff of the County.; To whom Sheriffs of Counties, &#x0026;c. to pay Monies received by them.; Rate to be paid in current Money and none in Farthings</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p12">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that for the better sessing ordering and leavying of the said
sums soe limited and appointed by this A&bholigct; to be paid as aforesaid severall Commissions shall forthwith be made
and dire&bholigct;ed by the Lord Chancellour or Lord Keeper of the Great Seal of England for the time being out of the
Court of Chancery under the Great Seale unto the severall Commissioners named in one A&bholigct; lately made in this
present Parliament intituled An A&bholigct; for the further releife of his Majesties Armie and the Northern parts of the
Kingdome And alsoe one other Commission for the City of Bristoll to John Taylor Esquire now Maior of the said
City John Gomning John Tomlinson Andrew Charleton Richard Holworthy William Jones Ezekiell Wallis George
Knight and John Lock Esquires And other Commissioners to every of the Cinque Ports that is to say To the Maior
for the time being Stephen Munings Thomas Day John Brome William Richards Samuel Dell Robert Brome Jurats
for the towne and Port of Dover and theire eight members For the towne and port of Folston the Maior for the time
being Robert Culverdown Thomas Inneth For Fevesham to the Maior for the time being Reynold Edwards John
Castlock Boys Ower For Seaford to Walter Everenden Maior Sackvile Porter Thomas Elphick junior Jurats For
the Town and Port of Hastings to the Maior for the time being Master Boyse Master Barlowe Master Crompe For
the Towne and Port of New Romney to Robert Wyvell Maior Stephen Etherick John Wilcock William Lancaster
Gentlemen For the Towne of Lidd to Clement Tipp Bailiffe Thomas Struggle John Bate William Godfrey Gentlemen
For the Town and Port of Hieth and the Member of it to the Maior for the time being William Deed John
Downe John Hogben John Crumpe John Lambert For the Town and Port of Sandwich and the Members thereof to
Stephen Inkpett Maior William Wilson George Wood Mathew Peak Jurats For Rye with the Members thereof to
Robert Erwen Maior Richard Cockram Joseph Bembrick Allen Gribble Jurats The Members to Rye Tenderden
Robert Poope Maior Samuel Short Esquire John Austen Thomas Short Jurats For the Towne of Winchelsea to the
Maior for the time being and Daniel White a Jurat And to every of the said Commissioners ten Schedules containing
in them the tenor of this A&bholigct; shall be affixed by which Commission the Commissioners in every such Commission
named according to this A&bholigct; and as many of them as shall be appointed by the said Commission shall have full
power and authority to put the effe&bholigct; of this A&bholigct; in execution and after such Commissions to them delivered may
by theire consents and agreements sever themselves for the execu&bhocotil;n of the said Commissions in Hundreds Lathes
Wards Rapes Wapentakes Townes and Parishes and other places within the Limits of the said Commissions in such
manner and forme as by the said A&bholigct; is appointed and shall truly effe&bholigct;ually and diligently for their parts execute
the effe&bholigct; of this present A&bholigct; without omission favour dread malice or any other thing to be attempted or done by
them or any of them to the contrary and shall with in two dayes after the said Commission delivered to them
dire&bholigct; theire severall or joynt Precept or Precepts to such In habitants Constables Sub-Constables Bailiffes and other
like Officers and Ministers and such number of them and as in and by the said A&bholigct; is appointed and att such theire
appearances the said Commissioners or soe many as shall be thereunto appointed shall openly read or cause to be
read unto them the said Rates in this A&bholigct; men&bhocotil;ned and openly declare the effe&bholigct; of theire charge unto them
and how and in what manner they ought and should make theire Certificates according to the Rates and s&bhouov;ms
thereof abovesaid and of all manner of persons as well Aliens and Strangers Denizen or not Denizens inhabiting
within this Realme as of such Popish Recusants and other persons who be borne under the Kings Obeysance
chargeable by this A&bholigct; and after such charge given shall at the discretion of the said Commissioners or any two of
them prefix another day to the said persons to appeare before the said Commissioners and bring in theire Certificates
under such penaltie for every default as by the said A&bholigct; is appointed &#x0026; thereupon at the day of the said Certificate
the said Commissioners shall make theire Precept or Precepts to such Officers or colle&bholigct;ors being able and sufficient
in every Hundred Wapentake Town or other place aforesaid as they the said Commissioners or any two or more
of them shall thinke fit comprizing and containing in them the names and sirnames of all persons presented before
them in the said Certificate of whom or [of<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] any of them if the said Commissioners or any two of them in theire
severall Limits shall have certaine knowledge or vehement suspe&bholigct; that he or shee is of greater value then is upon
such person or persons soe certified or specified that then the said Commissioners shall upon examination thereof
by good and lawfull meanes without oath set such rate and rates upon every such person or persons as shall be
according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct; and if any person or persons shall refuse to pay the severall
sums and proportions appointed by this A&bholigct; for such person to pay upon demaund made by the Constable or
Officer of the said place according to the Estreats delivered to them by the said Commissioners it shall be lawfull
to and for such Constable or Officer for non payment thereof to distrain the person or persons so refusing by his
or theire Goods &#x0026; Chattels and the distresses so taken to keepe by the space of foure dayes at the costs and
charges of the Owner thereof And if the said Owner doe not pay the said sum of money due by this A&bholigct; within
the said foure dayes then the same distresse to be apprised by three or two of the Inhabitants where such distresse
is taken and then to be sold by the said Officer for the payment of the said money and the overplus coming
by the sale (if any be) over and above the charge of keeping the said distresse to be immediately restored to the
Owner thereof And the said Officers and other persons so deputed to aske take gather &#x0026; levie the said sums
shall answer and be charged for the portion only to them assigned and limited to be levied gathered and comprised
in the said writing and estreat soe to them as aforesaid delivered to the persons and uses in this A&bholigct; expressed and
the said s&bhouov;m in that writing or estreat to be comprized to pay unto the said Commissioners or any two of them with
all speed and without delay at such day and place as by them shall be appointed and the said Commissioners to whom
the said s&bhouov;ms or any of them shall be paid shall with all speed and without delay carry and pay the same unto
the Sheriff of the said County or Citie respe&bholigct;ively wherein the said s&bhouov;ms shall or ought to bee colle&bholigct;ed and paid
And every such Sheriffe shall with all speed and without delay pay or cause to be paid all and every the sums by
him received to the persons and uses in this A&bholigct; expressed that is to say the high Sheriffes of the severall Counties
of Yorkeshire Cumberland Westmerland Nottingham the Countie and Towne of Nottingham the County Palatine
of Chester the Countie of the Citie of Chester the County Palatine of Lancaster Lincolneshire the Countie and Citie
of Lincolne Derbyshire Staffordshire the Countie of the Citie of Litchfeild the Citie of Yorke and Countie of the
same the town and countie of Kingston upon Hull respe&bholigct;ively to the Lord Maior of the Citie of Yorke and to
Thomas Hodgson Henry Tompson and William Scot Aldermen of the said City at the Chamber in the said City
of Yorke and the high Sheriffs of every other County or City respe&bholigct;ively within this Kingdome of England or
Dominion of Wales to the Treasurers in this A&bholigct; named at or in the Chamberlaines Office in Guildhall within the
said City of London All &#x0026; every which said sum and sums soe to be paid by force and vertue of this A&bholigct; shall
be paid in currant money of England and none of it in farthings to the intent the same may be paid and received
with more expedition.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Persons neglecting to pay Rate within four Days,</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Double Rate to be levied by Distress.; Further Punishment.; Persons dissuading others from paying the Rate, or consenting that others shall be under-rated, proved on Oath of two Witnesses,; Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any person or persons shall neglect to pay such rate or proportion as is
appointed for him or her by and according to the tenor of this A&bholigct; or any part thereof within foure dayes next
after the time limited by this A&bholigct; for the payment thereof and demand to be made to such person or in his absence
at the house or other most usuall place of abode or resort then every such person so making default shall pay
double the sum so assessed upon him or her by vertue of this A&bholigct; the same to be leavied by distresse and sale of
his or her goods in such sort as is before limited for the said other s&bhouov;ms and shall be lyable to such further
punishment as by this Parliament shall be thought fit to be inflicted upon him or her And if any person or persons
shall disswade any other person from paying the rates or sums so to be rated and paid as aforesaid by force or
vertue or according to the tenor of this A&bholigct; or by corruption shall give consent that any person shall be rated
below or under the proportion which any such person ought to pay by the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct; and
the said Offences or any of them shall be proved by the Oath of two Witnesses before any two or more of the said
Commissioners who shall have power by this A&bholigct; to administer the said Oath shall by the said Commissioners or any
two or more of them be committed to the Common Goale of the same Countie there to remaine till he or she shall
be thenceforth delivered by the Justices of Assize or Justices of the Peace at the Generall Quarter Sessions to be
holden for the same County wherein any such Offence shall be committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Sums raised to be paid out by the Treasurers as House of Commons shall dire&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Officer making Default.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the sums soe to be colle&bholigct;ed and raised by and according to the
tenor of this A&bholigct; shall be paid and issued out by the Treasurers in this A&bholigct; named or any two or more of them
respe&bholigct;ively to such use and uses as by one or more Orders of the Commons House in this present Parliament
shall be appointed and not otherwise And that all and every the said person and persons whoe are to be charged
or chargeable with the Receipt of any the said sums in this A&bholigct; mentioned which shall wilfully neglect or make
default in the colle&bholigct;ing levying or paying of the severall sums by them or any of them respe&bholigct;ively to be
received or paid or in execution of theire severall duties according to the tenor and true meaning of this A&bholigct;
shall be accountable for the same to the Parliament and shall be lyable to such punishment as shall be thought fit
by the King and Parliament to be inflicted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Persons residing in London or within Fifteen Miles, paying as herein dire&bholigct;ed,</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Upon Certificate thereof discharged.; Persons residing in other Parts of the Kingdom, paying to certain Members of the House of Commons, on Certificate,; discharged.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p18">And It is further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid that if any person or persons of what degree
ranke or quality soever inhabiting and residieing within the Citie of London or within fifteen miles distant from
the said City shall before the time limited by this A&bholigct; pay unto Sir Edmund Wright Lord Maior of the Citie of
London Sir James Cambell Sir George Whitmore Sir Nicholas Rainton Sir Christopher Cletherowe Knights
Aldermen of the said City and Robert Bateman Esquire Chamberlain of the said City or any of them and to the
uses in this A&bholigct; men&bhocotil;ned such sum or sums of money as by this A&bholigct; he or shee is appointed to pay upon a
Certificate or Acquittance from the said Sir Edmund Wright Sir James Cambell Sir George Whitmore Sir Nicholas
Rainton Sir Christopher Cletherowe Robert Bateman or any of them acknowledging the Receipt of such sums the
said parties severally shall be thereby discharged of for or concerning the said sums and if any other person or
persons of what degree ranke or quality soever within the Kingdome of England or Dominion of Wales shall likewise
before the time limited by this A&bholigct; pay unto Sir Arthur Ingram Sir Robert Pye Knights William Wheeler and William
Bell Esquires Members of the House of Commons or any of them and to the uses in this A&bholigct; such sum or sums of
money as by this A&bholigct; he or shee is appointed to pay upon a Certificate or Acquittance from the said Sir Arthur Ingram
Sir Robert Pye William Wheeler and William Bell or any of them acknowledging the receipt of such sums the said
parties severally shall thereby be discharged of for or concerning the said sums and all such payments shall be taken
as an acceptable service to this Kingdome.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Persons lending &pound;100 on Credit of A&bholigct; before 20th July next,</head>
			<para id="p19">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid that if any person or persons shall lend the sum
of One hundred pound or any greater sum to or for the uses and purposes in this present A&bholigct; men&bhocotil;ned and
declared such person shall do very good and acceptable service to the Common Wealth.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Repayment secured, together with Interest at &pound;8 per Cent. per Annum.</head>
			<para id="p20">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That any person or persons which shall soe lend and advance such sum or sums of money
as aforesaid for this present occasion and shall before the twentieth day of July now next ensuing pay and deliver the
same to such person or persons as are authorised by this present A&bholigct; to receive the moneys charged hereby upon the
respe&bholigct;ive Inhabitants of the City of London shall be secured by this A&bholigct; for the repayment of the said moneys at
such time and place as by the Lenders of the said money shall be required and agree upon And alsoe of the interest
and damages sustained by the forbearance thereof after the rate of eight pound per centum for a yeare and untill such
time as they shall respe&bholigct;ively have received againe the said sums so lent and advanced.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. The said Receivers for London to repay such Loans, with Interest at the Rate aforesaid.</head>
			<para id="p21">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed that the said Sir Edmund Wright Sir James Cambell Sir George Whitmore Sir Nicholas
Rainton Sir Christopher Cletherow and Robert Bateman shall and may satisfie pay and deliver unto such person or
persons respe&bholigct;ively out of the said moneys soe be received such respe&bholigct;ive sum and sums of money as shall be soe
lent by him or them for the purposes aforesaid togeather with such other and further sum and sums of money as the
interest of and for the said s&bhouov;m and sums respe&bholigct;ively shall amount unto after the rate of eight pound per centum for
a yeare from the day and time that the same was soe advanced as aforesaid untill they shall respe&bholigct;ively have received the
said sum or sums so advanced.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. What Acquittances to Treasurers a good Discharge.</head>
			<para id="p22">And It is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed that the Acquittance or Acquittances from the persons before appointed for the
receipt of these moneys to the uses and purposes in this present A&bholigct; expressed or of any three of them shall be a
sufficient discharge to the Treasurers in this A&bholigct; named for soe much money togeather with interest for the same as
shall be comprehended in such Acquittance or Acquittances for the issuing out and payment of the said sum and sums
of money respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Persons rated in the last Book of Subsidies for the Four Subsidies lately granted, and rated by this A&bholigct; at a lesser Sum in respe&bholigct; of his Rank or Degree.</head>
			<para id="p23">Provided alsoe And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that if any person or persons whatsoever hath
or have beene rated taxed or assessed in the last Booke of Subsidies for the foure Subsidies lately granted in this
present Parliament at or above the rate of five pounds Lands or at or above the sum of seaven pound ten shillings in
goods and yet by this present A&bholigct; a lesser sum is laid set or charged upon him her or them for or in respe&bholigct; of his
her or theire Rank degree or quality that in every such case such person or persons as aforesaid shall pay the full and
intire sums hereafter men&bhocotil;ned that is to say he or shee that was rated at five pound Land shall pay five pounds he or
shee that was rated at ten pound Land shall pay ten pound hee or shee that was rated at twenty pound Land shall pay
twenty pound and so from five pound upwards proportionably and he or she that was rated at seaven pound ten
shillings in goods shall pay five pound he or shee that was rated at fifteen pound in Goods shall pay ten pounds and so
upwards from seaven pound ten shillings in Goods proportionably after the rate of two thirds of what he or she is set
in goods reference being had to the first rate that was made upon the said Bill of Subsidies and shall be acquitted and
discharged of and from the payment of every other sum and sums of money imposed upon him her or them for or in
respe&bholigct; of his her or theire respe&bholigct;ive rank degree or quality by this present A&bholigct; Any matter or whatsoever thing
herein made to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Proviso as to Archbishops, &#x0026;c. rated at a less Sum than shall amount to a double Tenth, as rated in the King's Books.</head>
			<para id="p24">Provided alwaies That if any Archbishop or Bishop be by this present A&bholigct; charged to pay a lesser sum then shall
amount to a double tenth as they respe&bholigct;ively stand rated in his Majesties Books of First Fruits and Tenths for theire
severall Archbishopricks and Bishopricks then every such Archbishop and Bishop shall pay by vertue of this A&bholigct; one
[full<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] double tenth as they stand rated as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Proviso for Northumberland, Newcastle-upon-Tyne, Berwick-upon-Tweed, and County Palatine of Durham.</head>
			<para id="p25">Provided alwaies That this present A&bholigct; or any clause matter or thing whatsoever therein contained shall not in any
wise extend or be construed to extend to charge the Resiants or Inhabitants of the Shire or County of Northumberland
of the Towne Borough or County of Newcastle upon Tyne of the Towne or Borough of Barwick upon Tweed or of
the County Palatine of Durham or of any parts or places within them or any of them to bee taxed set asked leavied or
paid but that all and every the Resiants and Inhabitants of and within them and every of them (saving such as are
hereafter particularly mentioned) respe&bholigct;ively be and shall be of and from the payments and taxes by this present A&bholigct;
imposed and of every part thereof cleerly acquitted and discharged Any matter or thing whatsoever in this present A&bholigct;
had or made to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Proviso as to Inhabitants of last-mentioned Counties, and Places having Lands, &#x0026;c. of &pound;20 yearly Value in other Counties or Places.</head>
			<para id="p26">Provided alwaies neverthelesse And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that all and every Resiant
and Inhabitant of and within the said respe&bholigct;ive Counties Townes and Boroughs and Places last before mentioned
which now hath any Mannors Lands Tenements or Hereditaments of the full and cleere yearely value of twenty
pounds and upwards within any the other County or Counties place or places within the Kingdome of England or
Dominion of Wales shall be rated and taxed according to his or theire respe&bholigct;ive rank degree and quality as if
he or shee were not Resiant or Inhabitant of or within the said respe&bholigct;ive Counties Boroughs or places hereby
formerly excepted Any thing herein to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Proviso for Inhabitants of County and City of York, Hull, and Carlisle, who have had Soldiers billetted on them.</head>
			<para id="p27">Provided likewise That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to charge any person or persons inhabiting in the County of Yorke
the City and County of the City of Yorke the Town of Hull and County of the same and the City of Carlisle upon
whom Souldiers are or have beene lately billetted and to whom money for the said Billet is still owing and who are not
by this A&bholigct; charged with the payment of above one shilling but that every such person shall be hereby quitted and
discharged from the said Payment</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Proviso against Double Charges.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Discharge by Certificate</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">Provided that no person of what degree rank or quality soever shall be doubly charged by this A&bholigct; (except Papists
Recusants who are to pay double as by this A&bholigct; is appointed) but that every such person shall pay the greatest proportion
he or shee is charged with by this A&bholigct; And every such person as by this A&bholigct; is appointed to pay any sum or sums of
money according to the rate and with reference to the said last Bill of four Subsidies shall pay the said sum or sums of
money according to the highest rate was set upon him or her by vertue of the said A&bholigct; in any one place and shall be
discharged from any other rates by such Certificate as by the said A&bholigct; is appointed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Rates on Peers to be paid to a colle&bholigct;or appointed by the Peers: his Duty.</head>
			<para id="p30">[Provided alwaies And be it hereby declared and ena&bholigct;ed That the severall sums rated and taxed upon the Lords
shall be received by a Collector to be nominated by the Peers which colle&bholigct;or so appointed by the Peeres shall dispose
of the said sums to such persons respe&bholigct;ively and such uses and purposes as by this A&bholigct; is appointed.<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1"> Upholsterers <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2"> Chaundelo's <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3"> Livery <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7"> annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a seperate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


