<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47229" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVIII. An Act for securing by publique faith the Remainder of the freindly assistance and releife promised to our brethren of Scotland.[Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 14.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that &pound;300,000. had been agreed to be given for Relief of our Brethren in Scotland, and that &pound;220,000.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">remained unpaid.; The said &pound;220,000. to be paid into the Chamber of London at the Days herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the sum of three hundred thousand pounds was in this present Session of Parliament agreed to
be given for a freindly assistance and releife towards the supply of the Losses and necessities of our brethren
of Scotland of which sum of three hundred thousand pounds there is already paid the full sum of eighty thousand
pounds and there remaines behinde and unpaid the sum of two hundred and twenty thousand pounds For securing
the payment whereof Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the King our Soveraign Lord and by the Lords and Commons in this
present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same that the said sum of two hundred and twenty
thousand pounds shall be paid into the Chamber of the Citie of London for the use of our said Brethren of Scotland
at the dayes hereafter in this A&bholigct; mentioned that is to say the sum of One hundred and ten thousand pounds
part thereof shall be paid into the said Chamber of London for the use aforesaid upon or before the foure and
twentieth day of June in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred fourty two and the sum of one
hundred and ten thousand pounds residue of the said sum of two hundred and twenty thousand pounds shall be
paid into the said Chamber of London for the use aforesaid upon or before the foure and twentieth day of June in
the yeere of our Lord God One thousand six hundred fourty three.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The Names of the Persons whom the said Brethren are to address for Relief out of the said Money.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">The said Persons to issue the said Money accordingly</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it alsoe declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that Robert Earle of Essex Lord Chamberlain
of his Majesties Houshold William Earle of Bedford Robert Earle of Warwick Henry Earle of Holland Henry
Earle of Stanford Philip Lord Wharton Edward Lord Mandevile and Robert Lord Brooke Peers of the House of
Lords and Henry Bellasis Esquire Sir Thomas Barrington Knight and Baronet Sir Gilbert Gerrard Baronet Sir Henry
Mildmay Knight Master of the Kings Jewell House Sir John Holland Baronet Sir Arthur Ingram Sir Robert Pye
Sir John Strangewayes Sir Walter Earle Sir William Litton Sir Thomas Cheek Knights Arthur Goodwin John Hampden
and Henry Martin Esquires Members of the House of Commons or any two of the said Peers togeather with any
four of the said Members of the House of Commons are and shall be the persons to whom our said Brethren of
Scotland shall and may from time to time addresse themselves for the receiving of the said Sum of two hundred
and twenty thousand pounds at the severall times and at the place herein before appointed And the [said<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Lords and
Commons herein before particularly named or any two of the said Lords togeather with any foure of the said Members
of the House of Commons are and shall be authorized and appointed by this A&bholigct; to cause the said sum of two
hundred and twenty thousand pounds to be issued out of the said Chamber of London and paid at the times and
place before in this A&bholigct; appointed unto such person or persons as by A&bholigct; of Parliament of the Kingdom of Scotland
shall be authorized to receive and to give acquittances and discharges for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Security by this A&bholigct; to Persons who may lend the said Money.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Two of the Lords, together with Four of the Commons, mayissue the Money.; The Persons receiving the Money giving Acquittances for the same under Hand and Seal.; Such Acquittances a Discharge</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that it shall and may be lawfull to and for such person
and persons as shall be authorized in that behalfe by A&bholigct; of Parliament of the said Kingdome of Scotland to give
security by this present A&bholigct; to any person or persons for the raising and taking up of any sum or sums of money
not exceeding the sum of two hundred and twenty thousand pounds and to be paid at the times and place
herein before mentioned and not otherwise for the supply of the occasions of our said Brethren of Scotland and for
that purpose to assigne over to any person or persons the said sum of two hundred and twenty thousand pounds or
any part thereof And the said person and persons to whom any such sum or sums as aforesaid shall be assigned
shall or may have and receive the same out of the said Chamber of London And the said Lords and Commons before
in this A&bholigct; particularly named or any two of the said Lords togeather with any four of the said Members of the
House of Commons are and shall be authorized and appointed by this A&bholigct; to cause such sum and sums of money
as shall be assigned according to this A&bholigct; to be issued out of the said Chamber of London and to be paid at the
times and place before in this A&bholigct; appointed unto such person or persons to whom any sum or sums shall be assigned
as aforesaid the said Assignees giving Acquittances under theire hands and seales respe&bholigct;ively for such sum and sums
of money as they or any of them shall receive as aforesaid respe&bholigct;ively And that such acquittances as shall be
given by any person or persons authorized by A&bholigct; of Parliament of the said Kingdome of Scotland for receiving
the said sum of two hundred and twenty thousand pounds or any part thereof as aforesaid or by any person or
persons to whom the said sum of two hundred and twenty thousand pounds or any part or parts thereof shall be
assigned as aforesaid shall be a sufficient discharge to and for the said Lords and Commons herein before particularly
named and to and for the Officers of the said Chamber of London And shall be likewise in full payment and
satisfa&bholigct;ion to our said Brethren of Scotland for so much money as shall be mentioned and contained in the said
Acquittances.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


