<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47223" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER XII. A Subsidy granted to the King of Tonnage and Poundage and other sums of money paiable uppon Merchandizes exported &amp; imported. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>)</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Grant of Tonnage, viz.;Wine imported, 3s. per Ton. Several Wines imported by Merchant Alien, 3s. per Ton, &amp;c. Rhenish. Wine imported, 12d. per Awme. Grant of Poundage, viz.; Merchandize of Merchant Denizens and Aliens exported and imported, 12d. for every 20s. worth. The like Duty on Tin and Pewter Vessels exported by Merchant. Aliens. Proviso for Woollen Cloths manufa&bholigct;ured here and exported by Denizens. Proviso for Wools and Leather exported, and for Wines not before mentioned, and for Fresh Fish and Bestial imported</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas uppon examina&bhocotil;n in this present Parliament of divers of the Farmoers Customers and Colle&bholigct;ors
of the Customes uppon Merchandize and likewise uppon theire owne confession it appeared that they have
taken divers great S&bhouov;ms of Monie of his Ma<emph type="p">t</emph>&bholngs; Subje&bholigct;s and likewise of Merchants aliens for Goods imported and
exported by the Names of A Subsidie of Tonnage and Poundage, and by colour of divers other Imposi&bhocotil;ns laide
uppon Merchandize w<emph type="p">ch</emph> have beene taken and received against the Lawes of the Realme in regard the said S&bhouov;ms
of Monie and imposi&bhocotil;ns were not granted by c&bhooov;mon consent in Parliament, and for soe doeing [have<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] deserved
condigne punishment: Bee it therefore declared &amp; ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent &bhomtie; and the Lord&bholngs; &amp;
C&bhooov;mons in this present Parliament assembled, And it is hereby declared and ena&bholigct;ed that it is and hath bin the
auncient right of the subje&bholigct;s of this Realme that noe Subsidie [Custome<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Impost or other charge whatsoever ought
or may bee laid or imposed uppon anie merchandize exported or imported by Subje&bholigct;&bholngs; Denizens or Aliens
w<emph type="p">th</emph>out c&bhooov;mon consent in Parliam&bhomsst; Yet nevertheles the C&bhooov;mons (before whome theis examina&bhocotil;ns were taken)
takeing into their considera&bhocotil;n the great perill that might ensue to this Realme by the not guarding of the Seas
and the other inconvenienc&bholngs; w<emph type="p">ch</emph> might follow in case the said s&bhouov;ms of monie should uppon the suddaine bee
forborne to bee paid, by and w<emph type="p">th</emph> the advise and consent of the Lords in this present Parliament assembled and by
the authority of the same Doe give and grant to our Supreame Leige Lord and Soveraigne One Subsidy called
Tonnage, (that is to say) Of everie Tonn of Wyne that is or shall come into this Realme or anie your Ma<emph type="p">t</emph>&bholngs; 
D&otilde;ions by way of Merchandize the s&bhouov;m of three shillings and soe after that rate And of every Tonn of Sweete
Wynes aswell Malmesey as other, that is or shall come into this Realme by anie Merchant Alien three shillings
and soe after the rate over and above the three shillings above men&bhocotil;ned And of everie awme of Rhenish Wyne
that is or shall soe come in twelve pence And alsoe one other subsidy called Poundage, (that is to say) Of all
manner of Good&bholngs; and Merchandize&bholngs; of everie Merchant Denizen and Alien carried or to be carryed out of this
Realme or any his Ma<emph type="p">t</emph>s D&otilde;ions or to be brought into the same by way of Merchandize of the value of
every twenty shillings of the same Goods and Merchandize twelve pence soe after the rate, and of every
twenty shillings value of tynn and Pewter Vessell carryed out of this Realme by every or anie Merchant Alien
twelve pence over and above the twelve pence aforesaid Except and foreprized out of this Grant of Subsidie of
Poundage all manner of Woollen Cloth made or wrought or w<emph type="p">ch</emph> shall be made or wrought w<emph type="p">ch</emph>in this Realme
of England, and by everie or any Merchant Denizen and not borne Alien carried or to be carried out of this Realme
And all maner of Wooll&bholngs; Woolfell&bholngs; Hides and Back&bholngs; of Leather, that is or shalbe carried out of this Realme and
all Wynes not before lymitted to pay Subsidy or Tonnage, And all maner of Fresh Fish or Bestiall c&bhooov;ming or that
shall come into this Realme.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. On Merchant Denizens, for Wool, 33s. 4d. per Sack, and for for every 240 Woolfells 33s. 4d. and for Hides and Backs &pound;3. 6s. 8d. per Last;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">On Merchant Aliens, for Wool, &pound;3. 6s. 8d. per Sack, and for every 240 Woolfells &pound;3. 6s. 8d. and for Hides and Backs &pound;3. 13s. 4d. per Last; and also all Duties on Merchandize exported or imported by virtue of Letters Patent since 1 Jac. I. and which were continued and paid at the Beginning of this Parliament</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And further the said Commons by the advise assent and authority aforesaid Do give and grant unto oer
said Leige Lord oer Soveraigne for the causes aforesaid, one other Subsidie that is to say Of every Merchant borne
Denizen of and for everie Sack of Wooll thirtie three shilling&bholngs; foure pence, and of and for everie two hundred
and fortie Woolfell&bholngs; thirtie three shilling&bholngs; and foure pence and of and for everie Last of Hides and Back&bholngs; three
pounds six shillings eight pence, and so after the same rate for everie lesse or greater quantitie for any the same
Merchandize more or lesse And of every Merchant stranger not borne denizen of and for everie sack of Wooll
Three Pound&bholngs; six Shilling&bholngs; and eight Pence And of and for everie two hundred and fortie Woolfell&bholngs; Three
Pound&bholngs; six [Shilling&bholngs;<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and eight Pence, and for everie Last of Hides and Back&bholngs; Three Pound&bholngs; thirteen Shilling&bholngs;
foure pence, and so of all the said Wooll&bholngs; Woolfell&bholngs; Hydes and Backs and of everie of them after the rate
And such other s&bhooov;mes of money as have been ymposed upon any Merchandize either outward or inward by &bhopcrl;text
of any tres Patent&bholngs; C&bhooov;mission under the Great Seale of England or Privie Seale since the first yeare of the raigne
of his late &bhomtie; King James of Blessed Memory and w<emph type="p">ch</emph> were continued and paid at the beginning of this &bhopcrl;sent
Parlia&bhomsst;. To have take enjoy and perceive the subsidies aforesaid and other the fore men&bhocotil;ned s&bhouov;ms and everie of
them and everie part and parcell of them to our said leige Lord and Soveraigne from the fifteenth of July One
thousand six hundred fourty one to the tenth [Day<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of August next ensueing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Subsidy and Monies granted by this A&bholigct; to be employed under the Provision of 1 Jac. I. c. 33.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said Subsidy of Tonnage and Poundage Woolls
and other s&bhouov;ms of money shall bee taken and imployed dureing the time aforesaid to and for the intent&bholngs; and
purposes and uppon and under such provisions clauses and limita&bhocotil;ns as are contained in one A&bholigct; made in the
Parliament held in the first yeare of the raigne of his said late &bhomtie; King James of Blessed Memorie intituled
An A&bholigct; for the granting of a Subsidy to the King of Tonnage Poundage Woolls &amp;c.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The above Rates to be altered as shall be thought fit.</head>
			<para id="p6">And It is hereby declared [that y<emph type="p">e</emph> s&bhouov;ms of money hereby granted<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] uppon Merchandize are not the rates intended
to bee continued but the same to be hereafter in this present Parlia&bhomsst; altered in such manner as shall bee
thought fitt:</para>
			<para id="p7">Provided that noe Penalty or Forfeiture contained in this present A&bholigct; or in the said A&bholigct; made in the first yeare
of King James doe or shall ensue to any person or persons unles they refuse to compound for anie Merchandize or
Good&bholngs; imported or exported after notice given of this A&bholigct; Penalties and Forfeiture by Proclama&bhocotil;n where the said
Goods are or ought to be entred.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Officer, &amp;c. after the Determination of this Grant unduly continuing to receive the Subsidy.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Premunire</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And It is further ena&bholigct;ed that any Customer or Comptroller or anie other Officer or person that after the
determina&bhocotil;n of this Grant shall take or receive or cause to be taken or received the said subsidy s&bhouov;ms of money
or any other imposi&bhocotil;n uppon Merchandize whatsoever exported or imported except the same by Grant in Parliament
bee due or by such Grant shall become due, or have bin continuallie paid from the end of the raigne of the late
King Edward the Third untill the begining of the raigne of the late Queene Mary shall incurr and sustaine the
paines penalties and forfeitures ordained and provided by the Statute of Provision and Premunire made in the sixteenth
yeare of King Richard the Second and shall alsoe from thencefourth bee disabled dureing his life to sue or impleade
anie person in anie Ac&bhocotil;n reall mixt or personall or [in<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] anie Court whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Proviso for Tobacco of English Plantations.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alwaies That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to anie Imposi&bhocotil;n or charge uppon anie sort of Tobacco of
English Planta&bhocotil;n but that the said Tobaccoes shall bee charged onely w<emph type="p">ch</emph> the payment of two pence in the
pound and noe more.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1"> From the Original in the Parliament Office. This A&bholigct; is not upon the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2"> interlined <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3"> interlined <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


