<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47234" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIII. An act for the better raising and levying of Mariners Saylers and others for the present guarding of the Seas and necessary defence of the Realme &amp; other his Majesties Dominions.[ Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 19.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>c.5. ante, recited.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reciting that a Fleet is preparing for the Defence of the Realm. ; Lord Admiral, &amp;c. empowered to impress Seamen.; Such impressed Men to have condu&bholigct; Money at the Rate of 1d. per Mile; and to have Wages and Entertainment at the like Rate as for the Three Years last past.; Seamen, &amp;c. refusing to be impressed, or hiding, &amp;c. themselves. Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas there was an a&bholigct; this present Parliament intituled An a&bholigct; for the better raising and levying of
Mariners Sailers and others for the present guarding of the Seas and necessary defence of the Realm which a&bholigct;
is now expired And Whereas alsoe a Fleet is now in preparing to be set forth with all expedition for the guarding
of the narrow Seas and necessary defence of this Realm and other his Majesties. Dominions in this time of imminent
danger which cannot accordingly be performed unlesse the same be furnished with fit and sufficient men for that
service. Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the authority of this present Parliament That the Lord Admirall that now is
shall and may at any time or times betweene the tenth day of December 1641. and the first of November next
coming by himselfe his Vice Admirall Commissioner or Commissioners or other Officer or Officers or any of them
togeather with one or more Justices of the Peace next the place where any presse shall be made shall raise levie and
impresse such and so many Mariners Sailers Watermen Chirurgions Gunners and Ship Carpenters as shall be
requisite and necessary for this present expedition or for any such further defence of the Realme or any other of
his Majesties Dominions which said Mariners Sailers and other such persons so to be levied and impressed as
aforesaid and every of them shall have paid and delivered unto him upon such his impressing by the person that
shall soe impresse him for condu&bholigct; money for every mile from the place where he shall be soe impressed to the
Ship or place to which hee shall be appointed to make his repaire the sum of one penny and the like sum of one
peny for every mile from the place of his discharge unto the place of his abode and shall be allowed for his
service the best wages and entertainment which have or hath beene allowed by his Majestie to any such person
or persons respe&bholigct;ively at any time within three yeares last past And if any Mariner Sailer Waterman Chirurgeon
Gunner or Ship Carpenter shall wilfully refuse to be impressed in or for the said Service or shall voluntarily hide
and absent himselfe at the time of such presse to avoid the said service that then every such person soe offending
shall suffer imprisonment by the space of three monthes without baile or mainprise</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Masters, Masters' Mates, &amp;c. that shall be in Employment, and for other Persons described.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwaies That this a&bholigct; shall not extend to the pressing of any master or masters mate gunner carpenter
or [Boatswain<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of any Ship or Vessell that is or shall be in imployment or of above one of ten Mariners of any Ships
that shall be inward or outward bound nor to any person that shall be under the age of eighteen or above the age
of fifty nor to any person that was rated in the last Subsidies or shall be rated in any Subsidies hereafter to be granted
before the time of his being impressed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. No Reward to be taken, or corrupt Practice used, in executing a&bholigct;; Penalty &pound;20.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwaies And be it ena&bholigct;ed that no money or other reward shall be taken or any corrupt pra&bholigct;ise used
by any the persons authorized by this a&bholigct; in or for the pressing changing sparing or discharging of any person or
persons to be impressed by force of this a&bholigct; under paine of forfeiture of twenty pounds by the person so offending
for every such offence the one halfe to his majesty his heires and successours the other halfe to him that will sue for
the same to be recovered by action of debt bill plaint or information in any of his Majesties Courts of Record or before
the Justices of Assisse Oyer and Terminer Goal Delivery or the Justices of the Peace of the County City or Towne
Corporate where such offence shall be committed at theire generall Quarter Sessions wherein no Wager of Law Essoign
prote&bholigct;ion or injun&bholigct;ion shall be admitted or allowed.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Boatson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
					</section>
	</section>
</report>


