<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47232" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXI. An act for the free bringing in of Gun-powder and Salt peter from Forraign parts and for the free making of Gunpowder in this Realme.[ Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 17.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Mischiefs by prohibiting Importation of Gunpowder, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Liberty to all to import Gunpowder, paying Duties</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Importation of Gunpowder from forreign parts hath of late times beene against Law prohibited
and the making thereof within this Realm ingrossed whereby the price of Gunpowder hath beene excessively
raised many powder workes decayed this Kingdome very much weakened and indangered the Merchants thereof much
damnified many Mariners and others taken Prisoners and brought into miserable Captivity and Slavery many Ships
taken by Turkish and other Pirates and many other inconveniences have from thence ensued and more are likely to
ensue if they be not timely prevented. Be it therefore Declared and Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie and
the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That it shall and may
be lawfull to and for all and singuler persons aswell Strangers as naturall born subje&bholngs; of this Realm to import
and bring into this Kingdome any quantities of Gunpowder whatsoever paying such Customes and Duties for the same
as by Authority of Parliament shall be limited and set downe.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. All subjects may make and sell Gunpowder, and import Saltpetre, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further Declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for all
and singuler His Majesties subje&bholngs; of this his Realm of England to make and sell any quantities of Gunpowder at his
and theire will and pleasure and alsoe to bring into this Kingdom any quantities of Salt peter Brimstone or any other
Materialls necessary or requisite for the making of Gun powder.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Putting in execution Letters Patents, Proclamations, &amp;c. against this Liberty.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Premunire</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And lastly be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority [aforesaid<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] That if any person or persons from and after the tenth day of
August which shall be in the Yeare of our Lord God one thousand six hundred fourty and one shall put in execution
any Letters Patents Proclamation Edict a&bholigct; Order Warrant Restraint or other Inhibition whatsoever whereby the
Importation of Gunpowder Salt peter Brimstone or other the materials aforementioned or any of them from Forraign parts
or the making of Gunpowder within this Realm shall be any way prohibited or restrained That then the said person and
persons so offending shall incurre and sustain the pains penalties and forfeitures contained and provided in the Statute of
provision and premunire made in the sixteenth yeare of the Reign of King Richard the Second.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


