<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47235" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIV. An Act for the releife of the Captives taken by Turkish Moorish and other Pirates and to prevent the taking of others in time to come.[ Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 20.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that many Subjects, expert Seamen, and others, were detained in Captivity, and forced to renounce the Christian Religion, &amp;c</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that Money had been since the King's Accession taken from the Subject without Consent of Parliament.; Reasons for passing this Act.; Additional Duty of Customs of One in the Hundred on all Duties to be laid on Goods exported and imported, as herein mentioned, for Three Years, to be received by the Lord Mayor and Chamberlain of London, to be laid out in maintaining a Fleet, under the Direction of a Committee of the Lords and Commons respectively; Lord Mayor, &amp;c. to be accountable to the said Committee</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas many thousands of your Majesties good and loving subje&bholigct;s with theire Ships and Goods have of
late time beene surprised and taken at Sea (as they were in theire lawfull trading) by Turkish Moorish and
other Pirats and some of them to free themselves of the cruell and barbarous usage of those Pirats have renounced the
Christian Religion and turned Turks and others yet kept in bondage are used with so extreame cruelty as they are in
great danger thereby to lose theire lives unlesse they shall alsoe forsake the Christian Religion And diverse of those
your subje&bholigct;s kept in bondage (being expert and skilfull Mariners) are usually imployed at Sea against others your
good subje&bholigct;s and prove [very<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] prejudiciall to them and hurtfull to the trade and merchandise of your Majesties Dominions
And whereas as well your Majesties subje&bholigct;s as Strangers exporting or importing theire goods and merchandize into this
Kingdome have ever sithence your Majesties accesse unto this Crowne beene charged with the payment of great sums of
money under the name of Custom and that without consent of Parliament which had they beene legally taken ought
to have been cheifly imployed to the safeguard of the Seas and preservation of your good subje&bholigct;s in theire trade of
merchandize from the spoile of Pirats and other Sea Robbers but have been exhausted by evil Ministers and not applied
to their proper uses so that your Highnes good subje&bholigct;s have beene exposed to the mercilesse cruelty of those Pirats and
barbarous infidels And the Commons taking into further consideration your Majesties pressing wants and great occasions
of moneys in these times of distemper aswell in the Kingdome of Ireland as other Kingdoms of forreign Princes so
that there will be required some further aid to inable your Highnes to effe&bholigct; so great a Worke besides the present
Tunnage and Poundage now granted to your Majestie have therefore for this present pressing occasion and for a time
hereafter limited taken into theire Resolutions a further way of raising a supply of moneys for the providing and
setting forth to the Seas a Navie aswell for the enlargement and deliverance of those poore Captives in Argier and
other places if Almightie God shall [so<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] please to give that blessing unto theire enterprises as alsoe for the preventing
of the like future dangers unto your good people theire persons ships and Merchandizes Do therefore pray your
Most Excellent Majestie that it may be ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed by authority of this present Parliament That
where any Subsidy Custome or other dutie after the nine and twentieth day of September in the yeare One thousand
six hundred fourty one and before the foure and twentieth day of June then next following shall be laid or imposed
by authority of Parliament upon any Goods Wares or other Merchandize of what nature kinde or qualitie soever to
be exported out of or imported into this your Majesties Realme of England or Dominion of Wales that one other
sum of One in the hundred according to the rates to be established by Parliament within the time aforesaid over
and above the said custome subsidie or dutie so to be laid or imposed shall be raised levied and paid from and after
the tenth day of December in the yeare One thousand six hundred fourty one aforesaid of and from all and every
such Goods Wares and other Merchandize to be imported into or exported out of this your Majesties said Realm of
England or Dominion of Wales the said summe of one in the hundred to be raised levied and paid for the space
of three yeares next after the said tenth day of December and no longer And received and taken by the Lord Maior
and Chamberlain of London for the Time being theire Deputies or Deputie and by them the said Lord Maior and
Chamberlain of London for the Time being to be layed out payed and imployed for providing and setting out to
sea and maintaining of one or more Fleet or Fleets of good and serviceable Ships and other necessaries to be used
and imployed for the purposes aforesaid in such sort as by order of a Committee of the House of Lords and a
Committee of the House of Commons in Parliament of this your Majesties Realme of England shall be dire&bholigct;ed
And such Lord Maior and Chamberlain of London who shall receive or disburse any the moneys aforesaid shall be
accountable and account for all and every theire receipts and disbursements afore mentioned to the said Committee
or to such person or persons as the said Committee shall order and appoint</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. If Goods attempted to be exported or imported, and the said Duty not paid,</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that if any Goods Wares or other Merchandize whereof the sum
of one in the hundred aforesaid is or shall be due and payable by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall att any time hereafter be
shipped or put into any Boat or other Vessell to the intent to be carried into the parts beyond the Seas or else be</para>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">the Goods to be forfeited</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">brought from the parts beyond the Seas into any part of this your Realm of England or Dominion of Wales by
way of Merchandize and unshipped to be laid on land the s&bhouov;me of one in the hundred as aforesaid due or to
be due for the same not payed or lawfully tendered and secured to be paid to the Maior and Chamberlain of
London for the time being or theire deputy or deputies for the uses aforesaid all the same goods wares and other
merchandize whatsoever shall be forfeited and lost the one moity of the rate or value thereof to be to him or
them that will seize or sue for the same and the other moytie to be imployed to and for the uses before
expressed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Captures from the Pirates how to be divided.</head>
			<para id="p6">And for the better incouragement of Mariners to undertake the said service and Owners of Ships to let out
theire Ships for the said imployment Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that if any Ships goods or
merchandize of the said Pirats or of the subje&bholigct;s of any that are or shall be in enmity with your Majestie your
heires or successors or the person of any such Pirates shall be taken by the Ships to be imployed in the service
before mentioned that one fourth part thereof shall be to the Mariners that shall take the same and one other
fourth part to the Owners of the said Ships over and above theire hire and wages and the other two fourth parts
to and for such uses as the said Committees shall order and appoint and the overplus of the money to be raised
by vertue of this A&bholigct; and not imployed to and for the service aforementioned (if any shall be) shall alsoe be
imployed according to the Order of the same Committees.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. This Act not to be drawn into Example.</head>
			<para id="p7">And be it further declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that this &bhopcrl;sent A&bholigct; for the raising of
moneys for the setting forth of Ships for the suppressing of Pirates and safety of Merchants shall not hereafter be
drawn into example but that your Majesty would in time to come be pleased to intrust such Ministers as may
faithfully imploy the moneys raised by Tonnage and Poundage unto the right and proper uses for the guarding of
the Seas and safety of Merchants which will advance the honour of your sacred Majestie abroad and procure the
safety peace and happines of your Highnes loyall and faithfull subje&bholigct;s at home.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


