<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47237" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXVI. An Act for the better raising and levying of Mariners Sailers and others for the present guarding of the Seas &amp; necessary defence of this Realme &amp; other his Ma[jes]ties Dominions.[Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 22.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>c. 23. ante, found ineffectual.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Lord Admiral empowered to impress Seamen.; Such impressed Men to have condu&bholigct; Money at the Rate of 1d. per Mile; and to have Wages and Entertainment at the like Rate as for Three Years last past.; Seamen, &amp;c. refusing to be impressed, or hiding themselves, &amp;c.; Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the late a&bholigct; intituled An a&bholigct; for the better raising and levying of Mariners Sailers and others
for the present guarding of the Seas and necessary defence of the Realme &amp; other his Majesties Dominions
is found by experience to be ineffe&bholigct;uall for the supply of the present expedition now intended for the defence of
all his Majesties Realmes and Dominions by reason of sundry restric&bhocotil;ns and doubtfull limita&bhocotil;ns in the said a&bholigct;
And forasmuch as it highly importeth the safety of all his Majesties said Dominions that severall Fleets of Ships be
with all possible speed set forth to the Seas and all manner of diligence be used therein for the raising of Mariners
Sailers and others to that purpose Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the authority of this present Parliament That the Lord
Admirall that now is shall and may at any time or times betweene the first day of February 1641. and the first of
November 1642 by himselfe his Vice Admirall Commissioner or C&bhooov;missioners or other Officer or Officers or any
of them levye and impresse such and soe many Mariners Sailers Watermen Chirurgions Gunners &amp; Ship Carpenters
as shall be requisite and necessary for this present expedition or for any such further defence of the Realm or any
other of his Majesties Dominions which said Mariners Sailers and other such persons so to be levied &amp; imprested as
aforesaid and every of them shall have paid &amp; delivered unto him upon such his impressing by the person that shall
so impresse him for condu&bholigct; money for every mile from the place where he shall be soe impressed to the Ship
or place to which he shall be appointed to make his repaire the s&bhouov;m of one peny and the like sum of one peny
for every mile from the place of his discharge unto the place of his abode and shall be allowed for his service the
best wages and entertainment which have or hath beene allowed by his Majestie to any such person or persons
respe&bholigct;ively at any time within three yeares last past And if any Mariner Sailer Watermen Chirurgion Gunner or
Ship Carpenter shall wilfully refuse to be impressed in or for the said service or shall voluntarily hide and absent
himselfe att the time of such presse to avoide the said service that then every such person so offending shall suffer
imprisonment by the space of three monthes without bail or mainprise.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Masters, Masters' Mates, &amp;c. in Employment.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwaies That this a&bholigct; shall not extend to the pressing of any Master of any Ship or Barque that hath
the charge of any Ship or Barque or unto any Masters Mate or Ship Carpenter of any Ship or Barque that is in
imployment at the time of the said presse.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. No Reward to be taken, or corrupt Practice used, in executing a&bholigct;; Penalty &pound;20.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwaies And be it ena&bholigct;ed that no money or other reward shall be taken or any corrupt pra&bholigct;ise used
by any the persons authorized by this a&bholigct; in or for the pressing changing sparing or discharging of any person or
persons to be impressed by force of this a&bholigct; under pain of forfeiture of twenty pounds by the person so offending
for every such offence the one halfe to his Majestie his heires and successours the other halfe to him that will sue
for the same to be recovered by a&bholigct;ion of debt bill plaint or information in any of his Majesties Courts of Records
or before the Justices of Assisse Oyer and Terminer Goal Delivery or the Justices of the Peace of the County City
or Town Corporate where such offence shall be committed at theire Generall Quarter Sessions wherein no wager
of Law Essoign Prote&bholigct;ion or Injun&bholigct;ion shall be admitted or allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. c. 23. ante, repealed.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwaies And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that one other a&bholigct; intituled An a&bholigct; for
the better raising and levying of Mariners Sailers and others for the present guarding of the Seas and necessary
defence of the Realme and other his Majesties Dominions made in this present Parliament and now in force and
every Article clause and provision therein contained be from the first day of February in the yeare of our Lord
God One thousand six hundred fourty one repealed and made utterly void and of none effect.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


