<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47230" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIX. An Act for the better ordering and regulating of the Office of Clarke of the Market allowed &amp; confirmed by this
Statute and [and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] for the reformation of false Weights and Measures. [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. n. 15.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Grievances by Clerks of the Market, and Inequality in Weights and Measures.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">There shall be but one Measure, one Weight, and one Yard.; Selling by or keeping any other Weight.; Penalty 5s.; How to be levied.; Default of Distress.; Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Forasmuch as the undue execution of the Office of Clerke of the Market hath beene very greivous unto
divers of his Majesties most loveing Subje&bholigct;s who have beene much troubled by unnecessary summons and
charged with exa&bholigct;ions of diverse sums of Money by colour of the said Office and in regard the said evills have
partly arisen by meanes of an inequality of Weights and Measures throughout this Kingdom and by granting and
letting to Farme the said Office of Clerke of the Market and the Execution thereof in and through all or the
most of the severall Counties of this Kingdome for great sums of Money which the said Farmours or Grantees by
theire unjust and undue proceedings in the said Office doe extort from his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s again to theire great
impoverishment and yet little or no redresse at all in theire said Weights or Measures or any benefit thereby
accruing to his Majestie For remedie whereof and for regulating [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] all Weights &#x0026; Measures according to the true
intent of this Statute and the other Statutes in that behalfe formerly made and provided and preventing the said
inconveniencies Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie the Lords and Commons of this present
Parliament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That from henceforth there shall be but one Weight one
Measure and one Yard according to the Standard of the Exchequer throughout all the Realme aswell in places
priviledged as without Any usage or custome to the contrary notwithstanding And that every Measure of Corne
shall be striked without heape And whosoever shall sell by or keepe any other Weight Measure or Yard then as
aforesaid whereby any corne graine or other thing is bought or sold after six monthes after the end of this present
Session of Parliament shall forfeite for every such offence five shillings being thereof lawfully convi&bholigct;ed by the Oath
of one sufficient Witnesse before any Justice of Peace Maior or other head Officer of the County City or Towne
Corporate respe&bholigct;ively where the said offence shall be committed Who by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall have power to
administer an Oath in that behalfe Which said sum or penalty of five shillings shall be levyed by the Church wardens and Overseers of the Poore of the Parish or some or one of them where such offence is or shall be committed to
the use of the Poore of the same Parish of the Goods and Chattels of such Offenders by way of Distresse and sale
of the Offenders goods rendering the Overplus to the partie so offending And in default of such distresse it shall
be lawfull for any Justices of Peace Maior or other Head officer of the Countie City or Towne corporate respe&bholigct;ively
to commit the said partie to the Prison or Goal there to remaine without Bail or Mainprise untill he shall pay such
s&bhouov;ms of Money forfeited as aforesaid.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Clerk of the Market of the King's House, his Limits.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Jurisdi&bholigct;ion of Mayors, Head Officers, and Lords of Liberties</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no Clarke of the Market of the Kings House which
now is or hereafter shall be or of the Prince his Highnes his Heires or Successours which is or shall be Duke
of Cornewall or his or theire Deputie or Deputies shall hereafter execute his or theire said Office or Offices
respe&bholigct;ively in any part of the Kingdom but onely within the Verge of the Kings Court where it shall then reside
for the time being And that it shall be alwaies hereafter lawfull for any Maior or other head Officer of any City
Burrough or Towne Corporate or for any Lord or Lords of Libertie Liberties or Franchises his or theire Deputie
or Deputies or Agents according to theire severall Liberties and Jurisdi&bholigct;ions to have full power to execute the said
Offices respe&bholigct;ively as they ought or might have done before the making of this A&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Clerks of the Market and other Officers sealing, &#x0026;c. other Weights, &#x0026;c. or refusing to seal, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">On Payment of proper Fee.; Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And for the more ease of his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s Be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That if any Clarke of the Market within
his aforesaid precin&bholigct;s and limits of the Verge of the Kings house onely or any Maior or other Officer whatsoever
who by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall have power to inquire of any abuses in Weights and Measures shall seale or
give allowance unto any other Weight or measure weights or measures other then according to the said Standard
of the Exchequer or shall upon reasonable request and warning refuse to seal or give allowance unto such weight
or measure weights or measures as are according to the said Standard of the Exchequer paying only such Fee or
fees for such allowance as by the Statute or statutes or by ancient custome are in that behalfe formerly provided
and allowed and no more That then the said Clarke of the Market Maior and other Officer or Officers of Citie
Burrough or Towne and the said Lord and Lords of Libertie or Liberties and his and theire Deputie and Deputies
and Agents respe&bholigct;ively shall forfeite for every such offence five pounds to be leavied as aforesaid to the use of the
poore of the parish where such offence is or shall be committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Clerk of the Market, &#x0026;c. taking unlawful Fines or Fees;</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">or imposing Fines, &#x0026;c. without legal Trial, &#x0026;c.; First Offence, Penalty &pound;5. Second Offence, &pound;10. Third and every other Offence, &pound;20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if the Clarke of the Market his Deputy or Deputies
or Agents within the Verge aforesaid or any Maior or any other Officer or Officers of any City or Town or any
Lord or Lords of Liberties his or their Deputy or Deputies Agents or Assignes respe&bholigct;ively shall take or receive
of any of his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s by colour of the said Office any common Fine or Fines or any Fees other then
are [former<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] allowed by the Statute or statutes or ancient custome in that behalfe made or used shall take any Fee
or Fees or other sum of money Reward or considera&bhocotil;n for the making signing or examination of any weights or
measures which have beene formerly marked or sealed or shall Impose or Assesse or cause to be Imposed or Assessed
any Fine or Amerciament Fines or Amerciaments without a due and legall triall of the offences for which the
said Fine or Fines Amerciament or Amerciaments are Imposed or Assessed or shall otherwise misdemean himselfe in
the execution of his said Office and be thereof lawfully convi&bholigct;ed He shall forfeit for the first Offence whereof he
shall be so lawfully convi&bholigct;ed five pounds And for the second offence ten pounds And for the third offence and
every other offence afterwards twenty pounds to be levied as aforesaid to the use of the poore of the parish where
such offence shall be committed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Not to be doubly fined.</head>
			<para id="p9">And be it ena&bholigct;ed That whosoever shall be fined or amerced by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall not be again fined or
amerced for the same offence by vertue of any former Law or Statute</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Proviso for Rents of Farms or Corn.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Water Measures to be continued</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwaies That this A&bholigct; or Statute shall not extend to the Rents of Farmes or Lands or any Corne or
Grain due or payable to any Lord or Lords or any Colledges Houses or other Societies by vertue of any Lease or
Leases or other Covenant or Agreement but [that<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the same during the continuation of such Lease Leases or other
Agreements shall be paid delivered and performed in such measure and forme as the same hath beene paid delivered
and performed before the making of this A&bholigct; And that such measure as is comonly called Water measure in any
Ports Maritine Townes or other places shall be still used and continued as formerly the same hath beene Any thing
in this Statute contained to the contrary hereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. General Issue may be pleaded in A&bholigct;ion for executing A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">Provided alsoe that no Justice or Justices of the Peace Maior Bailiffe or other head Officer Church wardens
Overseers or any other authorized by this Statute for the due execution thereof in any point shall be sued impleaded
or otherwise impeached for doing or executing theire said Offices respe&bholigct;ively And if any Suit or Suits hereafter
shall be commenced against them or any of them theire Agents or Assistants touching the premisses That then it
shall and may be lawfull for them and every of them so sued or troubled in any Court or Courts wheresoever
to plead the generall issue Not guilty and to give this Statute in Evidence or any other speciall matter in Evidence
And in case by or upon this Law they or any of them shall be found not guilty or the Plaintiffe be Non-suited
the Defendant or Defendants shall recover triple costs against the Plaintiffe for his unjust vexation.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">formerlie <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


