<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47233" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXII. A Subsidie granted to the King of Tonnage Poundage and other sums of money payable upon Merchandize exported &amp; imported.[ Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 2. nu. 18.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>c. 8. ante, recited.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for granting the Subsidy by the said a&bholigct;.; c. 12. ante, recited.; Reasons for present Grant.; Grant of Tonnage, every Tun of Wine imported, 3s.; Like Duty over and above on Sweet Wine imported by Merchant Aliens.; Every Awme of Rhenish Wine imported, 12d. Grant of Poundage, every 20s. worth of Goods exported, 12d.; The like Duty on Tin and Pewter Vessels exported. Proviso for Woollen Cloth wrought within the Realm and exported by Merchant Denizens; and for Wools, Woolfels, Hides, and Backs of Leather exported; and for all Wines not before mentioned; and for Fresh Fish and Bestiall imported</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an a&bholigct; was made this present Parliament intituled A Subsidie granted to the King of Tonnage
and Poundage and other sums of money payable upon merchandize exported and imported whereby it is
declared and ena&bholigct;ed that it is and hath beene the antient right of the subje&bholigct;s of this Realm that no subsidie
custome impost or other charges whatsoever ought or may be laid or imposed upon any merchandize exported or
imported by subje&bholigct;s Denizens or Aliens without c&bhooov;mon consent in Parliament And the said Commons then taking
into theire consideration the great perill that might have ensued by not guarding of the Seas and other inconveniencies
which might have followed in case the said Sums of money in the said a&bholigct; mentioned should not have beene
granted to your Majestie as in and by the said a&bholigct;, is expressed Did therefore by the advice of the Lords in this
present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same give and graunt unto your Majestie our leige Lord
and Soveraigne. One subsidie of Tonnage and one other Subsidie of Poundage in such manner and according to
such rates as in the said a&bholigct; is expressed To have take perceive and enjoy the subsidies and other sums so granted
by the said a&bholigct; and every of them and every part and parcell of them to your Highnes from the five and
twentieth day of May 1641. unto the fifteenth day of July then next ensuing And whereas the said a&bholigct; being
determined one other a&bholigct; of the same title was likewise made this present Parliament with like declaration of the
right of the subje&bholigct;s of this your Realm by which second a&bholigct; your said Commons did by the like advise of the
Lords in this present Parliament assembled and by the authoritie of the same give and grant to your Majestie one
Subsidie of Tonnage and one other Subsidie of Poundage in such manner and according to such rates as in the
said last recited a&bholigct; is specified and contained To have take perceive and enjoye the Subsidie and other s&bhouov;ms so
granted by the said last recited a&bholigct; and every of them and every part and parcell of them to your Highnes from
the said fifteenth day of July 1641 unto the tenth day of August then next ensuing The said Commons now
likewise again taking into theire considerations the great perill that might ensue to this Realm by the not guarding
of the Seas and the other inconveniencies which might follow in case the said Sums of money should upon the
suddain be forborne to be payed By and with the advice and consent of the Lords in this present Parliament
assembled and by the authoritie of the same Doe give and graunt to you our supreme leige Lord and Soveraigne
one Subsidie called Tunnage that is to say Of every tun of Wine that is or shall come into this Realme or any your
Majesties Dominions by way of merchandize the sum of three shillings and so after that rate and of every tunne of
Sweet wines aswell Malmesie as other that is or shall come into this Realme by any Merchant Alien three shillings
and soe after the rate over and above the three shillings above mentioned And of every awme of Renish Wine
that is or shall so come in twelve pence And alsoe one other subsidie called Poundage that is to say Of all manner
of Goods and Merchandize of every Merchant Denizen &amp; Alien carried or to be carried out of this Realm or
any your Majesties Dominions or to be brought into the same by way of Merchandize of the value of every
twenty shillings of the same Goods and Merchandize twelve pence and soe after the rate and of every twenty
shillings value of Tynne and Pewter Vessell carried out of this Realme by every or any Merchant Alien twelve pence
over and above the twelve pence aforesaid Except and foreprized out of this Grant of Subsidie of Poundage all
manner of Woollen Cloth made or wrought or which shall be made or wrought within this Realme of England and
by every or any Merchant Denizen and not born Alien carried or to be carried out of this Realme And all manner
of Woolls Woolfels Hides and Backs of Leather that is or shall be carried out of this Realme and all Wines not
before limited to pay Subsidie or Tonnage and all manner of fresh fish and bestiall coming or that shall come into
this Realme.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Merchant Denizen to pay, every Sack of Wool 33s. 4d. every 240 Woolfels 33s. 4d. every Last of Hides and Backs &pound;3. 6s. 8d. and so in Proportion for every greater or less Quantity.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Merchant Strangers to pay, every Sack of Wool &pound;3. 6. 8. every 240 Woolfels &pound;3. 6s. 8d. every Last of Hides and Backs &pound;3. 13s. 4d. and also certain Duties by Letters Patent, or Great or Privy Seal, since 1 Jac. I</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And further the said Commons by the advice assent and authoritie aforesaid Doe give and grant unto you our said
liege Lord our Soveraigne for the causes aforesaid One other subsidie that is to say Of every Merchant born Denizen
of and for every Sack of Wooll thirtie three shillings foure pence And of and for every two hundred and fourty
Woolfels thirtie three shillings four pence And of and for every last of Hides and Backs three pounds six
shillings eight pence and so after the same rate for every lesse or greater quantitie for any the same Merchandize
more or lesse And of every Merchant Stranger not born denizen of and for every Sack of Wooll three pounds six
shillings eight pence and of and for every two hundred fourtie Woolfels three pounds six shillings eight pence
And for every last of Hides and Backs three pounds thirteene shillings foure pence and so of all the said Wools
Woolfels Hides and Backs and of every of them after the rate And such other s&bhouov;ms of Money as have been imposed
upon any Merchandize either outward or inward by &bhopcrl;text of any Letters Patents Commission under the Great
Seale of England or Privie Seale since the first yeare of the Reigne of his late Majestie King James of Blessed memorie
And which were continued and paid at the begining of this present Parliament. To have take enjoy and perceive
the Subsidies aforesaid and other the aforementioned s&bhouov;ms and every of them and every part and parcell of them
to you our said leige Lord and Soveraigne from the ninth day of August 1641. to the first day of December next
ensuing</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The said Subsidy to be applied according to 1 Jac. I. c. 33.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said Subsidie of Tonnage Poundage Wooll and
other sums of money shall be taken and employed during the time aforesaid to and for the intents and purposes
and upon and under such Provisions clauses &amp; limitations as are contained in one a&bholigct; made in Parliament held
in the first yeare of the reign of his said late Majestie King James of Blessed memory intituled An a&bholigct; for the
granting, of a Subsidie to the King of Tonnage Poundage Woolls &amp;c</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The above Rates on Merchandize to be altered in this Parliament as shall be thought fit.</head>
			<para id="p6">And it is hereby declared That the sums of money hereby granted upon merchandize are not the rates intended
to be continued but the same to be hereafter in this present Parliament altered in such manner as shall be
thought fitt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Penalty in this a&bholigct; or in 1 Jac. I. c. 33. to attach, unless on Persons refusing to compound for Goods imported or exported.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided that no penaltie or forfeiture contained in this present a&bholigct; or in the said a&bholigct; made in the first yeare
of King James do or shall ensue to any person or persons unlesse they refuse to compound for any Merchandize
or Goods imported or exported after notice given of this a&bholigct; penaltie and Forfeiture by Proclamation where the
said Goods are or ought to be entred.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Officer, after the Determination of this Grant, receiving the Subsidy, &amp;c. Premunire, and Disability to sue. Exception.</head>
			<para id="p8">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed that any customer or comptroller or any other officer or person that after the determina&bhocotil;n
of this grant shall take or receive or cause to be taken or received the said Subsidy sums of money or any other
imposition upon merchandize whatsoever exported or imported except the same by Grant in Parliament be due or by
such Grant shall become due or have beene continually payed from the end of the reigne of the late King Edward
the Third untill the begining of the reigne of the late Queen Mary shall incur and sustain the pains penalties and
forfeitures ordained and provided by the Statute of Provision and premunire made in the sixteenth yeere of King
Richard the Second and shall alsoe from hence forth be disabled during his life to sue or implead any person in
any a&bholigct;ion reall mixt or personall or in any Court whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Tobacco of English Plantations.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alwaies That this a&bholigct; shall not extend to any imposition or charge upon any sort of Tobacco of
English Plantations but that the said Tobacco shall be charged onely with the payment of two pence in the pound
and no more</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Persons not to be charged by this a&bholigct; with pretermitted Customs.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alsoe And it is further ena&bholigct;ed that this a&bholigct; shall not extend or be construed to charge any person
or persons with an imposition or charge of late yeares imposed upon Woollen Cloth and Woollen Commodities known
by the name of the pretermitted Customs.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Grants of Subsidies by Letters Patent, &amp;c. void.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alsoe And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that all Grants and Letters Patents under
the Great Seale Privy Seale or otherwise containing the Grants of any Subsidies or imposts heretofore made or granted
unto any person or persons for or in respe&bholigct; of the transportation exportation or importation of any Goods or
merchandize pretended to be due or payable to your Majestie or by any such grants or Letters patents covenanted
to be enjoyed or had out of such Subsidies Imposts or Payments as hereafter should be setled by Parliament or
otherwise And all Letters Patents or other Grants of the colle&bholigct;ion of any Impositions heretofore set without consent
in Parliament made or granted to any person whatsoever And alsoe all pensions assigna&bhocotil;ns of moneys and all
other payments whatsoever charged or hereafter to be charged on this subsidy by this a&bholigct; other then for the uses
before in this a&bholigct; intended shall be from henceforth utterly void.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


