<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47243" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXII. An a&bholigct; for the raising and leavying of Moneys for the necessary defence and great affaires of the Kingdomes of England and Ireland and for the payment of debts undertaken by the Parliament. [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. p. 3. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for the present Grant.</head>
		<para id="p1">Most gracious Soveraigne Wee your Majesties most humble and loyall subje&bholigct;s the Commons in your High
Court of Parliament nowe assembled haveing duely considered the weightie occasions requiring an extraordinary
and certaine supply of moneys to be speedily raised for the necessary defence and great affaires of your Majesties
Realmes of England and Ireland and other your Majesties Dominions in these times of great and eminent danger
and for the better suppressing of that most wicked and execrable Rebellion in Ireland and for and towards the
payment of such debts and s&bhouov;ms of money for the which this Kingdome doth or shall stand ingaged by publique
faith. And finding that the urgent and pressing occasions aforesaid enforce a necessitie of raising the certain sum of
Four hundred thousand pounds at the least for the purposes aforesaid Do most humbly beseech your Majestie that
it may be ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings Most Excellent Majestie and by the Lords and Commons in this
present Parliament assembled and by authority of the same that the s&bhouov;m of Foure hundred thousand pounds and
such other sum and s&bhouov;ms as are appointed to be raised by this a&bholigct; for the intents and purposes aforesaid shall be
charged set assessed rated taxed leavied and paid at two severall taxations and payments by equall por&bhocotil;ns at the
times hereafter in this a&bholigct; expressed</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. &pound;400,000. to be raised by Two equal Payments on all Persons, Spiritual and Temporal;</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">charged on the Counties, Cities, and Places hereinafter named</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">And that every person and persons spirituall and temporall of what estate or degree soever he or they be of
(other then such persons as are hereby excepted) shall be liable thereunto and charged and chargeable with the
payment thereof according to the tenour of this a&bholigct; in manner and forme following that is to say For the more
equall and just raising thereof It is humbly desired that it may be ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie
aforesaid that the said s&bhouov;m of Four hundred thousand pounds and s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money aforesaid shall be charged
rated taxed and leavied upon all and every the severall Counties Cities Towns liberties places and persons hereafter
particularly men&bhocotil;ned and expressed according to the particular proportions rates and distributions thereof following
that is to say</para>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Bedford.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p5">Upon the County of Bedford Four thousand three hundred threescore twelve pounds and one shilling.</para>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Berks.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">The Countie (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Berks Five thousand six hundred twenty eight pounds fourteen shillings and two pence.</para>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Bucks.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">The County of Bucks Six thousand seaven hundred twelve pounds two shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Cambridge.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p11">The Countie of Cambridge Six thousand one hundred fourscore nineteen pounds eleven shillings and one penie.</para>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Isle of Ely.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p13">The Isle of Ely Two thousand two hundred fourscore seaventeene pounds.</para>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Cheshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p15">The Countie of Cest[e]r Two thousand eight hundred fourty and one pound eighteen shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Chester.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p17">The Citie and Countie of Cest[e]r Three hundred twenty six pounds and fifteen shillings.</para>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Cornwall.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p19">The Countie of Cornwall Ten thousand one hundred ten pounds fifteen shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Derbyshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p21">The Countie of Derby Two thousand eight hundred nineteene pounds one shilling seven pence halfepeny</para>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Devonshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p23">The Countie of Devon Twenty nine thousand thirty five pounds twelve shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">Exeter.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p25">The Citie and Countie of Exon One thousand fourty nine pounds four shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">Dorsetshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p27">The Countie of Dorset Seven thousand seven hundred one pound two shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Pool.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p29">The Town and County of Pool Fourscore pounds eighteen shillings six pence.</para>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Yorkshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p31">The Countie of Yorke Seventeen thousand three hundred fourscore pounds five shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p32">
				<emph type="i">York.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p33">The Citie and Countie of Yorke One thousand two hundred thirty one pounds four shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Kingston-upon Hull.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p35">The Town and County of Kingston upon Hull Four hundred nineteene pounds five shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">Essex.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p37">The County of Essex Eighteen thousand fourty eight pounds nine shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">Gloucestershire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p39">The County of Gloucester Nine thousand nine hundred threescore eighteen pounds five shillings and five pence.</para>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">Gloucester.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p41">The Citie and Countie of Gloucester One thousand one hundred eight pounds and fourteen shillings</para>
			<para id="p42">Herefordshire.</para>
			<para id="p43">The Countie of Hereffs Seven thousand one hundred fourty six pounds four shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p44">
				<emph type="i">Hertfordshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p45">The Countie of Hertford Seven thousand five hundred twentie five pounds and ten shillings.</para>
			<para id="p46">
				<emph type="i">Huntingdon.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p47">The Countie of Hunts Three thousand five hundred thirty three pounds eight shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p48">
				<emph type="i">Kent.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p49">The Countie of Kent Twenty thousand two hundred fourscore one pounds fiveteen shillings seven pence half peny.</para>
			<para id="p50">
				<emph type="i">Canterbury.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p51">City and County of Canterbury Eight hundred eighteen pounds fourteen shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p52">
				<emph type="i">Lancathire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p53">The Countie of Lancaster Four thousand three hundred fifty three pounds eleven shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p54">
				<emph type="i">Leicestershire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p55">The Countie of Leicester Three thousand eight hundred fourty eight pounds and five shillings.</para>
			<para id="p56">
				<emph type="i">Lincolnshire</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p57">The Countie of Lincoln Twelve thousand nine hundred fifty one pounds fifteen shillings ten pence halfe peny.</para>
			<para id="p58">
				<emph type="i">Lincoln.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p59">The City and County of Lincoln Five hundred thirty two pounds one shilling and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p60">
				<emph type="i">London.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p61">The City of London Fourty two thousand foure hundred threescore and sixteen pounds sixteen shillings and
three pence</para>
			<para id="p62">
				<emph type="i">Middlesex.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p63">The County of Middlesex Twelve thousand three hundred fifty four pounds twelve shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p64">
				<emph type="i">Monmouthshire</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p65">The County of Monmouth One thousand five hundred eightie eight pounds six shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p66">
				<emph type="i">Northamptonshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p67">The Countie of Northampton Four thousand eight hundred threescore nine pounds sixteene shillings and six pence</para>
			<para id="p68">
				<emph type="i">Nottinghamshire</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p69">The Countie of Nottingham Two thousand nine hundred and thirteen pounds fourteen shillings and three pence</para>
			<para id="p70">
				<emph type="i">Nottingham</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p71">The Town and County of Nottingham Fourscore sixteene pounds ten shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p72">
				<emph type="i">Norfolk.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p73">The Countie of Norffs Twenty one thousand nine hundred eight pounds six shillings one peny and half peny.</para>
			<para id="p74">
				<emph type="i">Norwich.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p75">City and County of Norwich Two thousand five hundred fourty four pounds four shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p76">
				<emph type="i">Oxfordshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p77">The County of Oxon Six thousand four hundred eighteen pounds four shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p78">
				<emph type="i">Rutland.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p79">The Countie of Rutland One thousand fiftie three pounds fourteen shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p80">
				<emph type="i">Shropshire</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p81">The County of Salop Four thousand five hundred threescore pounds five shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p82">
				<emph type="i">Staffordshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p83">The Countie of Stafford Three thousand seven hundred fourty three pounds ten shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p84">
				<emph type="i">Litchfield.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p85">City &amp; County of Litchfeild Fourscore eight pounds and seven shillings.</para>
			<para id="p86">
				<emph type="i">Somerset.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p87">The County of Somerset Sixteene thousand eight hundred threescore nineteene pounds and thirteene shillings.</para>
			<para id="p88">
				<emph type="i">Bristol.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p89">The City of Bristoll in the same Countie Nine hundred twenty seven pounds four shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p90">
				<emph type="i">Hampshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p91">The Countie of Southampton Twelve thousand foure hundred threescore foure pounds eleven shillings and nine
pence.</para>
			<para id="p92">
				<emph type="i">Southampton.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p93">The Town and County of Southampton Five hundred thirteen pounds eighteen shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p94">
				<emph type="i">Isle of Wight.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p95">The Isle of Wight One thousand seven hundred thirteene pounds foure shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p96">
				<emph type="i">Suffolk.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p97">The County of Suffolke Twenty thousand six hundred nine pounds and seaventeen shillings.</para>
			<para id="p98">
				<emph type="i">Surrey.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p99">The Countie of Surrey Ten thousand eight hundred eight pounds one shilling three pence.</para>
			<para id="p100">
				<emph type="i">Sussex.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p101">The County of Sussex Ten thousand nine hundred fourteen pounds fifteen shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p102">
				<emph type="i">Warwick.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p103">The Countie of Warwick Five thousand one hundred thirteene pounds six shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p104">
				<emph type="i">Coventry.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p105">The City and County of Coventry Six hundred fifty eight pounds two shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p106">
				<emph type="i">Worcestershire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p107">The Countie of Worcester Five thousand eight hundred two pounds ten shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p108">
				<emph type="i">Worcester.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p109">The City and County of Worcester Three hundred fifty six pounds four shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p110">
				<emph type="i">Wiltshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p111">The Countie of Wilts Eleven thousand seven hundred foure pounds and nineteene shillings.</para>
			<para id="p112">
				<emph type="i">Anglesey.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p113">The Countie of Anglesey Foure hundred eighteen pounds eighteen shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p114">
				<emph type="i">Brecknock.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p115">The Countie of Brecknock Eight hundred fifty pounds thirteen shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p116">
				<emph type="i">Cardiganshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p117">The County of Cardigan One thousand eight pounds six shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p118">
				<emph type="i">Carmarthenshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p119">The County of Carmarthen Eight hundred twenty nine pounds ten shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p120">
				<emph type="i">Carnarvonshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p121">The Countie of Carnarvon Three hundred fourty eight pounds eight shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p122">
				<emph type="i">Denbighshire</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p123">The County of Denbigh Four hundred forty seven pounds six shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p124">
				<emph type="i">Flintshire</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p125">The County of Flint Two hundred threescore and fourteen pounds five shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p126">
				<emph type="i">Glamorganshire</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p127">The Countie of Glamorgan One thousand fourscore four pounds seventeene shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p128">
				<emph type="i">Merionethshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p129">The County of Merioneth Two hundred fifty nine pounds eighteen shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p130">
				<emph type="i">Montgomeryshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p131">The County of Mountgomery One thousand thirteen pounds twelve shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p132">
				<emph type="i">Pembrokeshire.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p133">The County of Pembrooke Nine hundred fifty six pounds fifteen shillings and six pence.</para>
			<para id="p134">
				<emph type="i">Radnor.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p135">The Countie of Radnor Six hundred one pounds nineteene shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p136">
				<emph type="i">Haverfordwest.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p137">The Town and County of Haverford the West Fourscore three pounds seven shillings and three pence.</para>
			<para id="p138">
				<emph type="i">Cumberland.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p139">The Countie of Cumberland Six hundred thirty three pounds (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) eighteen shillings.</para>
			<para id="p140">
				<emph type="i">Durham.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p141">The Countie of Dursneham One thousand three hundred and nine pounds and thirteen shillings.</para>
			<para id="p142">
				<emph type="i">Wesmorland.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p143">The County of Westmerland Five hundred forty seaven pounds one shilling four pence half peny.</para>
			<para id="p144">
				<emph type="i">Newcastle, (County.)</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p145">The Countie of Newcastle Two hundred fourty five pounds and fourteen shillings.</para>
			<para id="p146">
				<emph type="i">Northumberland.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p147">The County of Northumb[er]l[an]d Eight hundred thirty pounds two shillings four pence half peny.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Persons of the Degree of a Baron or Baroness, and above, and all other Persons as well Ecclesiastical as Temporal, Fraternities, &amp;c. (after Payment of Debts) to pay towards the said &pound;400,000.</head>
			<para id="p148">
				<emph type="i">Aliens and Popish Recusants convi&bholigct; after Payment of Debts, to pay Double. ; One Moiety of the Money paid by Aliens or Recusants to be no Part of the said &pound;400,000, but Surplusage Money, and disposed of for Purposes of a&bholigct;.;
Poll Tax on Aliens and Popish Recusants convi&bholigct; not contributory as above, 2s. 8d. ; Master, &amp;c. of such Alien, &amp;c. answerable</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p149">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that as well every person of the estate of a Baron or [a<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
Baronesse and every estate above and all and every other person and persons born within this Realme of England Wales
or other the Kings Dominions as well ecclesiasticall as temporall as all and every fraternity guild corporation mystery
brotherhood and communalty corporate and not corporate as well ecclesiastical as temporall within the Realme of
England Wales or other the Kings Dominions being worth three pounds as well in Coyn and the value of every
pound that every such person fraternity guild corporation mysterie brotherhood and c&bhooov;munaltie corporate or not
corporate hath of his or theire owne or any other hath to his or theire use or uses as alsoe in plate stock of
merchandize all manner of Corne and Grain Householdstuffe and of all other Goods moveable as well within this
Realm as without and of all such s&bhouov;ms of money as to him or them is or shall be owing whereof he or they trust
in his or theire conscience surely to be paid (except and out of the &bhopcrl;misses dedu&bholigct;ed such summes of money
as he or they do owe and in his or theire conscience intend truely to pay) and except alsoe the apparell of every
such persons theire wives and children belonging to theire owne bodies saving jewels gold silver stone and pearle)<?bignore?>
shall pay towards the said Four hundred thousand pounds and other s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money aforesaid And alsoe
every Alien and Stranger born out of the Kings obeisance as well denizens as others inhabiting within this Realme
and alsoe every Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; or which before the time of the Assesment of the s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money
by this present a&bholigct; granted shall be a Popish Recusant convi&bholigct; or which are or shall be indi&bholigct;ed for popish recusancy
and theire indi&bholigct;ments either are or shall be removed by Certiorari or being not removed shall not by appearance
and traverse legally be discharged before the said Assesment so to be made or (being of the age of one and twenty
yeares) shall not have received the Holy Communion according to the rites of the Church of England within one
whole yeare next before the said Assessment shall be made Of every pound that he or they or any other to his or
theire use in trust or otherwise shall have in coyne and the value of every pound in plate corn grain merchandize
houshold stuffe or other goods jewells chattells moveables and immoveable as is aforesaid as well within this Realm
as without and of all s&bhouov;ms of money to him or them owing whereof he or they trust in his or theire conscience to
be paid (except and out of the &bhopcrl;misses dedu&bholigct;ed every such s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money which he or they do owe
and in his or theire conscience or consciences intend truly to pay) shall pay to and towards the said Foure hundred
thousand pounds and other s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money aforesaid a proportion double to those of the like estates being
no Recusants or aliens and the moiety or one halfe of the said Recusants part to be no part of the said Foure
hundred thousand pounds but surplusage money to be disposed for the uses aforesaid according to the true intent
and meaning of this a&bholigct;. And alsoe that every Alien and Stranger born out of the Kings Dominions being denizen
or not denizen not being contributary to any the rates aforesaid and being of the age of seven yeares or above and
every Popish Recusant convict or which before the time of the Assesment of the severall s&bhouov;ms of money by this
present a&bholigct; granted shall be a Popish Recusant convict being of the age of seaventeene yeares or which being
of the age of one and twenty yeares hath not received the Holy Communion within one yeare then last past and
being not contributary as aforesaid shall pay to and towards the said Four hundred thousand pounds and other
s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money aforesaid two shillings eight pence for every Poll and the Master or he or shee with
whom the said Alien or such Papist is or shall be abiding at the time of the taxation or taxations thereof to be
charged with the same for lack of payment thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Real and Copyhold Estates, Offices, and other Profits, to pay Proportion of Monies charged upon Counties according as the same shall be divided and set upon each Town, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p150">
				<emph type="i">Sums charged upon Offices taxed by Commissioners, to be Surplusage Money. ; Aliens and Popish Recusants Convict to pay Double.; The Moiety of such Payment to be Surplusage Money, and disposed of for the great Affairs of the Kingdom. ; Except Yearly Wages of Servants under &pound; 10. other than the King's Servants, taking &pound;5. ; Personal Estate held for Corporations to be rated;; and for every Pound in Land, Annuities, Corrodies, &amp;c. ; Proviso for Ornaments, &amp;c. of Churches and Chapels.; The first Moiety to be taxed before the 20th May 1642.; The other Moiety before the 20th Nov. 1642. ; Names of Persons charged and colle&bholigct;ors to be certified into the Exchequer. The First Moiety before the 20th June 1642.; and the other Moiety before the 20th December following.;
The First Moiety to be paid to the Lord Mayor, Aldermen, and Chamberlain of London, &amp;c.; 20 July 1642, at or in the Chambers of London and York respectively.; The other Moiety to the said Lord Mayor, &amp;c. of London on the 20th January 1642, ; in the said Chambers of London &amp; York respectively.; Acquittances to be given to the colle&bholigct;ors under Hands and Seals of Treasurers, &amp;c. ; Producing Acquittances, Warrant for colle&bholigct;ors to pass their Accounts. ; Payments within Liberties, &amp;c.</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p151">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that every person borne under the Kings obeysance as well
ecclesiasticall as temporall and every Corporation fraternitie guild mystery brotherhood and communalty corporate or
not corporate as well ecclesiasticall as temporall for every pound that every of the same persons and every Corporation
Fraternity Guild Mistery Brotherhood and Communaltie corporate or not corporate or any other to his or theire use
in trust or otherwise hath in fee simple fee tayle for terme of life terme of yeares by execution wardship or by Copy
of Court Roll of and in any Honours Castles Mannors Lands Tenements Rents Services Tithes Obla&bhocotil;ns Obven&bhocotil;ns
Annuities Offices of Proffit Fees Corodies or other yearely profits or hereditaments of the yearely value of twenty
shillings as well within ancient demeasne and other places priviledged as else where and so upwards shall pay to and
towards the said s&bhouov;m of Four hundred thousand pounds and other s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money aforesaid his and theire
proportionable part and portion of such s&bhouov; or s&bhouov;ms of money as are imposed charged and set upon each severall
Countie according as the same shall be divided distributed taxed or set upon each severall Town Hamlet Parish
or Place where such person or persons is or shall be chargeable by this a&bholigct; and the true intent &amp; meaning thereof
which said sum or s&bhouov;ms of money so to be charged upon or for Offices shall be taxed according to the discretion of
the Commissioners and to be surplusage money and no part of the Four hundred thousand pounds And every Alien
Denizen or not denizen borne out of the Kings obeysance and every Popish Recusant convict [of what estate or degree
soever they be or which before the time of y<emph type="p">e</emph> assessm&bhomsst; of the sd sum or s&bhouov;ms of money <ref idref="n4">4</ref>] by this present a&bholigct; graunted
shall be a Popish Recusant convict or [which shall be indicted for Popish Recusancy and <ref idref="n4">4</ref>] theire indi&bholigct;ments are or shall
be removed by Certiorari or being not removed shall not by appearance and traverse legally be discharged before the
said Assesment so to be made or being of the age of twenty and one yeares shall not have received the Holy
Communion according to the Rites of the Church of England within one whole yeare next before the said Assessment
shall be made in such case to pay to and towards the said s&bhouov;m of Four hundred thousand pounds and other s&bhouov;m and
s&bhouov;ms aforesaid a proportion double to those of the like estate being no Recusants or Aliens and the moyetie or one
halfe of the said Recusants part to be no part or parcell of the said Foure hundred thousand pounds but surplusage
money to be disposed for the great affaires of the kingdome according to the true intent and meaning of this a&bholigct;.
And that all s&bhouov;ms to be presented and chargeable by this a&bholigct; either for goods and debts or either of them or for Lands
tenements and other the premisses as is in this a&bholigct; conteyned shall be att the said payment sett and taxed after the
rate and proportion according to the true meaning of this a&bholigct; Yearely wages due to servant's for theire yearely service
under ten pounds by the yeare (other then the Kings Servants taking yearely wages of five pounds or above) onely
excepted and foreprized And that all plate Coyne Jewells Goods Debts and Chattels personall and all Lands
tenements and other the premisses as aforesaid being in the rule and custody of any person or persons to the use
of any Corporation Fraternity Guild Mystery Brotherhood or any Communalty being corporate or not corporate be
and shall be rated set and charged by reason of this a&bholigct; for and toward the payment of the said Four hundred
thousand pounds and other sum and s&bhouov;ms of money aforesaid in proportionable manner as aforesaid And for every
pound in Lands tenements annuities fees offices of profit corrodies and other yearely profits as is aforesaid And the
s&bhouov;ms that are above rehearsed set and taxed to be leavied &amp; taken of them that shall have such goods in custody
or otherwise charged for lands as is before rehearsed And the same person and persons and bodies corporate by
authority of this a&bholigct; shalbe discharged against him or them that shall or ought to have the same att the time of
the payment or delivery thereof or at his (otherwise departure from the custody or possession of the same Except
and alwaies foreprised from the charge and assesment of the said severall s&bhouov;ms of money all goods chattels and
Ornaments of Churches and Chappels which have beene ordained and used in Churches and Chappells for the honour
and service of Almighty God And the first [money<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] or one halfe of the said severall s&bhouov;ms so charged and set on the
said severall Counties Cities Towns liberties places and persons aforesaid shall be by the authority aforesaid taxed
sessed and rated according to this a&bholigct; in every Shire Riding Lathe Wapentake Rape City Borough Town and every
other place within this Realm of England and Dominion of Wales before the twentieth day of May in the yeare of our
Lord God One thousand six hundred forty two And the other moytie or one halfe thereof shall by the authority
aforesaid be taxed sessed and rated before the twentieth day of November 1642 And the particular s&bhouov;ms of every Shire
Riding Borough Town and other places aforesaid with the particular names of such as are or shall be chargeable to
and for the payment of the said severall s&bhouov;ms of money to be taxed and set by the Commissioners for the same to be
limited or two of them at the least with the names of the high Colle&bholigct;ors And in the same form shall be certified into
the Kings Court of Exchequer the first moytie or one halfe of the said severall s&bhouov;ms of money before the twentieth
day of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God (according to the computation of the Church of England)
One thousand six hundred fourtie two and the other moytie or one halfe of the same before the twentieth day of
December then next following and the said s&bhouov;ms in form aforesaid to be taxed to and for the payment of the aforesaid
first moytie or one halfe shall be paid in one entire s&bhouov;me unto Sir Richard Gurney Knight and Baronet Lord Maior
of the Citie of London Sir John Cordall Sir Thomas Soome Sir John Gayer Sir Jacob Garret Alderman Atkins
Alderman Pennington Sir John Wollestone Alderman Addams Alderman Warner Master Samuel Vassell Master John
Venn the Chamberlaine of the City of London for the time being and to such other person or persons as are appointed
by this a&bholigct; to receive the same to the uses in this a&bholigct; expressed at or before the twentieth day of July One thousand
six hundred fourtie two at or in the Chambers of the City of London and Yorke respe&bholigct;ively according to the intent
of this a&bholigct; And the said s&bhouov;ms in manner aforesaid to be taxed for the payment of the said other moytie or one halfe
shall be paid at one entire s&bhouov;me unto the said Sir Richard Gurney Knight and Baronet Lord Maior of the Citie of
London Sir John Cordall Sir Thomas Soome Sir John Gayer Sir Jacob Garrett Alderman Atkins Alderman Pennington
Sir John Wolleston Alderman Addams Alderman Warner Master Samuel Vassell Master John Venn the Chamberlaine
for the Citie of London for the time being and to such other person or persons as are appointed by this a&bholigct; to receive
the same to the uses in this a&bholigct; expressed at or before the twentieth day of January One thousand six hundred fourty
two at or in the said Chambers of the Cities of London and Yorke respe&bholigct;ively And that the said Treasurers or
Receivers or any one or more of them upon the receipt of any money from the High colle&bholigct;ors by this a&bholigct; to be
authorized shall make unto every of the said Colle&bholigct;ors one or more acquittance or acquittances under the hands
and scales of the respe&bholigct;ive Treasurers or Receivers that shall receive the same testifying the receipt of so much
money as he shall receive and that the producing of the said Acquittances so made shall be as sufficient a Warrant
for the said Colle&bholigct;ors to passe theire account as any tally or constat out of the receipt And the s&bhouov;ms aforesaid shall be
taxed set asked and demanded taken gathered leavied and paid to the &bhopubr;sons and uses in this present a&bholigct; expressed
as well within liberties franchises Sanctuaries ancient demeasne and other whatsoever places exempt or not exempt as
without (except such Shires places and persons as shall be foreprized in and by this &bhopcrl;sent a&bholigct;) Any Grant Charter
&bhopcrl;scription Use or Liberty by reason of any Letters Patents or other priviledge &bhopcrl;scription allowance for the same or
whatsoever other matter or discharge heretofore to the contrary made granted used or obtained notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Absentees, whether Natives or Aliens, charged by Certificate of Inhabitants of Place where Lands, &amp;c. lie.</head>
			<para id="p152">
				<emph type="i">Rate by which they are to be charged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p153">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by authority of this present Parliament that every such person as well such as be
born under the Kings obeysance as every other person stranger born denizen or not denizen inhabiting within this
Realme or within Wales or other the Kings Dominions which at the time of the same Assessings or taxations or
any or every of them to be had or made shall be out of this Realm or out of Wales and have goods Chattels
lands or other tenements fees or annuities or other profits within this Realme or in Wales shall be charged and
chargeable for the same by the certificate of the inhabitants of the place where such goods chatels lands tenements
or other the &bhopcrl;misses then shall be or in such place where such person or persons or his or theire factor deputy
or atturney shall have his or theire most resort unto within this Realme [or in Wales in like manner as if y<emph type="p">e</emph>
&bhopubr;son were or had beene at y<emph type="p">e</emph> time of the said assessing within this Realme<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] and that every person abiding or
dwelling within or without this Realm shall be charged and chargeable to the said sum and s&bhouov;ms of money
granted by this a&bholigct; according and after the rate of such yearely substance or value of Lands or Tenements
Goods Chattels and other the &bhopcrl;misses as every person so to be charged shall be sett at at the time of the said
assessing or taxation upon him to be made and no otherwise</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. The City of Bristol was casually omitted out of the a&bholigct; of the two last Subsidies; Provision for such Omission.</head>
			<para id="p154">And Whereas the City of Bristoll was casually omitted out of the a&bholigct; of the two last subsidies granted this
&bhopcrl;sent Parliament Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed that the said City of Bristoll shall pay over and above the summes of
money which they are to pay by force of this a&bholigct; as aforesaid two entire subsidies the same to be taxed rated
and assessed by the Commissioners in this a&bholigct; named in such manner and form as the said two subsidies lastly
granted were taxed and assessed in other places and to be taxed certified and paid within the times &bhopcrl;fixed by
this a&bholigct; for the said Four hundred thousand pounds to be colle&bholigct;ed and leavied by all such meanes as are appointed
for the said s&bhouov;m and to be paid to such persons and for such uses as in and by this a&bholigct; is appointed for the
said Four hundred thousand pounds And that the Commissioners in this a&bholigct; named for the said City of Bristoll
and the taxors assessors and Colle&bholigct;ors and other Officers and persons by this a&bholigct; authorized shall have the like
power and authority by this a&bholigct; for the leavying colle&bholigct;ing and receiving of the said two subsidies as for the said
s&bhouov;m of Four hundred thousand pounds is appointed by this a&bholigct; and the said subsidies to go in surplusage
over and above the said s&bhouov;m of Four hundred thousand pounds and other s&bhouov;ms by this a&bholigct; appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Lord Chancellor to issue Commissions for assessing and levying.</head>
			<para id="p155">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that for the assessing and ordering of the said sum and
s&bhouov;ms of money to be duly had taxed certified &amp; leavied to and according to this a&bholigct; the Lord Chancellour of
England or Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the time being or such Commissioners as shall have the
custody thereof for the time being shall make and dire&bholigct; out of the Court of Chancery under the Great Seal
severall Commissions for the sessing and leavying of the said sum and s&bhouov;ms of money according to the true
meaning of this a&bholigct; in manner and forme hereafter expressed. viz.</para>
			<para id="p156">
				<emph type="i">Names of Commissioners.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p157">For his Majesties Houshold Unto the persons by the said Lord Chancellour Lord Keeper or Commissioners for
the Great Seal Lord Privie Seale Lord Admirall and Lord Chamberlain of the Kings Houshold to be nominated.</para>
			<para id="p158">And for the County of Bedford.</para>
			<para id="p159">Unto Sir Beauchamp S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Knight Sir Robert Napier Knight and Baronet Sir Oliver Luke Sir Richard Conquest
Sir Peter Osborn Sir Samuel Luke Sir Thomas Alston Sir George Russell Sir William Palmer Sir William Boteleir
[Sir Roger Burgoine Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>&bholngs; William Duncombe Thomas Rolt Oliver Boteleir<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] James Beverley John Wingate Edward
Cater Henry Chester Humphrey Fish Walter Rolt John Vaux Samuel Browne and Thomas Sadler Esquires the
Maior of Bedford for the time being Francis Bannister Doctor of Phisick Thomas Paradine Robert Hawse and
Thomas Hawse Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p160">For the County of Buck</para>
			<para id="p161">To Sir Edward Terrell Sir Peter Temple Knights and Baronets Sir Edmund Verney Knight and Baronet Sir John
Lawrence Baronet Sir Thomas Littleton Baronet Sir Richard Ingoldsby Sir Alexander Denton Sir Robert Dormer
Sir William Andrewes Sir Thomas Sanders Sir Henry Crooke Sir Arthur Manwaring Sir Edward Salters Sir John
Persons Sir Robert Lovett Sir Ralphe Verney Sir Robert Bannister Knights John Hampden Arthur Goodwin Peter
Dorrell Thomas Risley Richard Greenvile John Dormer Richard Winwood John Tirringham Thomas Tirringham
Thomas Eglistone Raines Lowe Thomas Duncombe of Brickhill Thomas Tirrill Thomas Longvile Thomas Lea the
elder Richard Serjeant William Hackvile Thomas Westall John Duncombe of East Claydon Richard Winwood
Henry Bulstrode William Wheeler Edmund Waller of Gregories Robert Busby Thomas Hampson Thomas Stafford
Francis Cheyney the elder Edmund West William Bowyer Gabriell Hipsley John Crooke Anthony Ratcliffc Esquires
the Bailiffes for the time being of the Towne of Buckingham Robert Smith John Nicholas Arthur Claver
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p162">And for the County of Berks</para>
			<para id="p163">William Lenthall Esquire now Speaker of the Commons House of Parliament Sir George Stonehouse Baronet
Sir John Backhouse Knight of the Bath Sir Francis Knolls Senior Sir Francis Knolls junior Sir Robert Bennet
Sir Richard Harrison Knights John Fetiplace Edmund Dunch Henry Martyn Thomas Manwaring John Harrison
George [Purefey<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Thomas Fetiplace Samuel Dunch Henry Pole Humphrey Dolman William Barker and Roger Knight
of Gwynham Esquires to the Maior of the Borough of New Windsor for the time being Sir William Salter Knight
&amp; Thomas Waller Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p164">And for the County of Cambridge</para>
			<para id="p165">To Sir Dudley North Knight Sir John Cotton Baronet Sir Thomas Willis Baronet Sir John Cuts Knight Sir James
Reynolds Knight Thomas Chichley Francis Russell James Reynolds William Allington Robert Peyton Michael Dalton
Thomas Wendy Oliver Cromwell Isaac Barrow Thomas Terrell William March Walter Clopton Dudley Pope Bishy
Betts William Barnes Thomas Simonds Robert Castle John Crayne John Hubbard William Fisher James Ayloff Roger
Rant Thomas Ducket John Whistler John Wilbours Esquires Maior of Cambridge Talbot Peyps Esquire John Lowrey
Samuel Spalding Robert Robson Thomas French Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p166">For the County of Cornwall</para>
			<para id="p167">Unto Sir John Trelawney Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Carew Baronet Sir Richard Buller Sir Nicolas Slaning
Sir Richard Vivian Sir Bevill Greenvile Knights John Arundell of Trerise Francis Godolphin Peirs Edgcombe Charles
Trevanion Thomas Lower John Harris of Landrest Francis Buller of Shillingham Alexander Carew John Trefusis
John S<emph type="p">t</emph> Aubin Francis Basset Jonathan Rashley Peter Courtney Thomas Herle Richard Erisy John Moyle Paul
Speccot Ambrose Mannaton Nicholas Trefusis George Heale Humphrey Nicholls Francis Godolphin of Treveneage
Thomas Gewen Walter Langdon William Glynn John Carter Thomas Arundell Hender [Mouldworth<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] John
Polewhele Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p168">For the Countie of Cumberland</para>
			<para id="p169">Unto Sir Patricius Curwen Baronet Sir William Dalston Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Fletcher Baronet Sir George
Dalston Sir William Musgrave and Sir Thomas Dacres Knights Richard Barwise John Skelton Peter Senhouse Richard
Tolson William Lawson Thomas Lamplugh John Eglionbie and William Briscoe Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p170">For the Countie of Chester</para>
			<para id="p171">Unto Sir George Booth Sir Richard Wilbraham Sir Thomas Delves Sir Richard Grosvenor Knights and Baronets
Sir Edward Fitton Sir William Brereton Baronets Sir Thomas Brereton Knight Sir Thomas Smith Knight Richard
Brereton Henry Leigh Thomas Stanley William Downes Peter Venables George Cotton Roger Wilbraham [Hugh
Wilbraham<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Peter Warburton of the Graunge Henry Bunbury William Whitmore Henry Burkenhead William Glegg
John Crewe George Spurstowe Thomas Crackstone William Liversage Philip Manwaring William Marbury Thomas
Chomley and Henry Manwaring Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p172">For the City and County of the City of Chester</para>
			<para id="p173">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir Thomas Smith Knight Robert Brerewood Serjeant at lawe Recorder Francis
Gamul William Gamul Christopher Bleasse Charles Walley and Nicholas Ince Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p174">For the County of Derby</para>
			<para id="p175">Unto Sir George Greisley Sir Thomas Burdett Baronets Sir John Curson Knight &amp; Baronett Sir Edward Cooke
Baronet Sir Simon Everie Knight and Baronet Sir John Gell Baronett Sir Francis Rhodes Baronet Sir Edward Vernon
Knight Sir John Fitzherbert Knight of Norbery Sir John Fitzherbert of [Dissingston<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Knight Sir John Harpur Sir
Edward Leech Knights Sir John Coke junior Sir Samuel Sleigh Knight Thomas Greisley Jacinth Sacheverell Francis
Burdett Christopher Horton John Agard Richard Coke John Bullock Henry Gilbert Christopher Fulwood John Milward
John Shalcrosse Randall Ashenhurst John Thetchvile Edward Revill Francis Revill Esquires Thomas Saunders Henry
Wigfall Lionell Fanshawe Gent. the Maior of Chesterfield for the time being the Maior of Darby for the time being
William Allestre Esquire Nathaniell Hallowes and Edward Large Aldmen</para>
			<para id="p176">For the County of Devon</para>
			<para id="p177">Unto Sir Edward Seymour Knight and Baronet Sir Peter Prideaux Baronet Sir George Chudleigh Baronet Sir
Edmund Fowell Knight Sir John Poole Sir Thomas Heale Sir John Bampfeild Sir John Northcoot Baronets Sir
John Speccot Sir Samuel Roll Sir Shilston Calmady Sir Nicholas Martin Sir John Young Sir John Chichester
Knights John Bampfeild Arthur Basset John Ackland Arthur Champernon John Harris Hugh Fortescu Edmund
Fortescu John Gifford Anthony Dennis Edmond Arscott Sampson Hele John Berry William Tothill Robert
Savery Henry Waldron John Davy Baronet Francis Bluet Richard Callum Henry Worth Walter Hele Walter
Young Arthur Upton John Bamfeild George Trobridge George Peard Roger Mathewe Edmund Prideaux James
Welsh Edward Yard Richard Cabell Robert Duke junior Alexander Maynard William Maurice Peter Specott
Robert Stafford Edmund Fowell William Fry Humphrey Prouz John Peter John Yeo Henry Aishford Edmund
Treemaine William Carey Arthur Aishford John Foynes John Were Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p178">For the City and County of the City of Exon</para>
			<para id="p179">Unto the Maior for the time being John Lynne Nicolas Spicer John Hackwill Adam Bennet Roger Malack
Robert Walker Esquires Robert Vilvaine Doctor of Phisick Thomas Crossing</para>
			<para id="p180">For the County of Dorset</para>
			<para id="p181">Unto Sir Thomas Trenchard Knight [Dezill<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Hollis Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Strangwaies Sir Walter Earle Sir John Miller
[Knight<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Richard Rogers Giles Strangwaies Gerrard Naper Thomas Earle William Whittaker Richard King Richard
Rose Giles Greene Dennis Bond John Browne Angell Gray Gregory Gibbs Richard Broderipp John Arnold
James Frampton George Williams Richard Bingham Thomas Tregunnell William Savage John Trenchard John
Fitz James William Sidnam William Constantine John Dolling Bamfeild Chafing Edmund Ogden John Hannam
Esquires and Robert Troope.</para>
			<para id="p182">For the Town and County of Poole</para>
			<para id="p183">Unto the Maior for the time being William Constantine Esquire Recorder George Scutt Alexander Wayte and
John Harwood Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p184">For the County Palatine of Durham</para>
			<para id="p185">Unto Sir Richard Tempest Baronet Sir John Connyers Baronet Sir William [Kampton<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Sir Lionel Maddison Sir
Richard Bellasis Sir George Vane Sir William Darcy Knights Arthur Foulthorpe Thomas Davison Thomas Shadforth
Cuthbert Pepper Timothy Whittingham Thomas Swinburne Esquires Robert Hutton George Lilburne Gentlemen
the Maior of Durham for the time being Ralph Allenson.</para>
			<para id="p186">For the County of Yorke For the Westriding of the County of Yorke</para>
			<para id="p187">Unto Ferdinando Lord Fairfax Sir Francis [Vane<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Knight of the Bath Sir Francis Wortley Knight and Baronet Sir
William Savile Sir Edward Osborne Sir Henry Slingsby Sir Thomas Mauleverer Baronets Sir William Lister Sir Arthur
Ingram junior Sir Thomas Wentworth Sir John Ramsden Sir George Wentworth Sir Edward Rhodes Sir William
Fairfax Sir Jervis Cutler Sir Richard Hutton Sir Ralph Hansby Sir John Kaye Sir William Ingram Sir John
Woolstenholme Sir Henry Chomley Knights Sir John Goodricke Knight and Baronet Charles Fairfax Francis Nevile
William Mallory William Ingleby Henry Arthington John Key Robert Rockley Ingram Hopton William West
Jervice Hammond Nicholas Yarborough John Farrer William White Thomas Parker William Wombwell Thomas
Mauleverer John Rerersby Esquires George Marwood Thomas Lister Richard Tankard John Robinson Gregory
Armitage Thomas Stockdale Esquires Benjamin Wade and Joseph Hillary Gentlemen the Maior of Pomfrett for the
time being Thomas Austwick Gent..
			</para>
			<para id="p188">For the Northriding of the County of Yorke</para>
			<para id="p189">Unto Henry Bellasis &amp; Conniers Darcy Esquires Sir Marmaduke Wyvell Sir Thomas Gore Knights and Baronets Sir
William Sheffeild Sir Hugh Cholmeley Sir Henry Anderson Sir Thomas Ingram Sir Richard Darley Sir Thomas Laiton
Sir Thomas Gore Sir Hugh Bethell Sir Henry Franckland Henry Fowls Mathew Hutton Brian Stapleton John Dalton Henry
Anderson John Colverley John Wastall John Dodsworth junior Arthur Auldebrough Roger Wyvell William Caley
John Cholmeley Christopher Perchhay Charles Tankard John Talbots George Metcalf George Trotter James Penyman
Thomas Heblethwaite Richard Wynn Christopher Waters Stephen Jackson Francis Roodby Sir Robert Strickland
Richard Aldborough Mathew Smelt Thomas Francklin Esquires John Ledgard of Maulton Francis Lassels Toby Jenkins
Jefferie Gates Esquires John Robinson Stephen Jackson James Cholmeley George Conyers Francis Tomson William
Ford Richard Tompson William Staneley James More Thomas Lassell William Pinckney John Dent Robert Colchester
and William Fish Edmund Duncombe William Rosse Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p190">For the Eastriding of the County of Yorke</para>
			<para id="p191">Unto Sir John Hotham Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Griffith Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Metham Sir William
Alford Sir Philip Mountain Sir Michael Wharton Sir John Vavasor Sir Philip Stapleton Knights Sir William Strickland (<ref idref="n15">15</ref>)
Baronet Sir Thomas Remington Sir Arthur Robinson Knights Thomas Anlaby John Ledger Richard Remington John
Hotham Michael Wharton William Saint Quyntyn Thomas Heblethwaite Christopher Appleyard John Constable William
Grimston Robert Crompton Francis Thorpe Christopher Ridley Gregory Crake John Anlaby Charles Bowes
Henry Darly Richard Darly Francis Cob senior Francis Cob junior Stephen Thompson John Overton and Ralph
Sutton Esquires</para>
			<para id="p192">For the City and County of the City of Yorke</para>
			<para id="p193">Unto the Lord Maior for the time being Sir William Allanson Sir Roger Jaques and Sir Christopher Croft
Knights and Aldermen Sir Thomas Widdrington Knight Recorder Sir Robert Belt Knight Leonard Batson Edmund
Cooper Robert Hemsworth Thomas Hoyle James Hutchinson Thomas Hodgson Henry Tompson John Vaux and
William Scot Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p194">For the Towne and County of Hull</para>
			<para id="p195">To the Maior for the time being Peregrine Pelham Esquire Nicholas Denman Lancelot Roper William Popple
James Watkinson Henry Barnard Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p196">For the County of Essex</para>
			<para id="p197">Unto Sir Thomas Barrington Knight and Baronet Sir Harbotle Grimstone Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Bendish
Baronet Sir Benjamin Ayliffe Baronet Sir William Hicks Baronet Sir William Masham Baronet Sir Richard Everard
Baronet Sir William Luckin Baronet Sir William Wiseman Baronet Sir Martin Lumley Knight and Baronet Sir Henry
Mildmay Knight Master of the Jewell House Sir Thomas Cheeke Knight Sir Henry Mildmay of Moulsham Knight
Sir William Maxey Knight Sir Henry Holcroft Knight Sir Thomas Bowes Knight Sir Francis Coke Knight
Sir Henry Saint George Knight Sir William Rowe Knight Sir William Martin Knight Sir Thomas Honywood
Knight Sir Humphrey Mildmay Knight Sir Gamaliel Capell Knight Sir John Tyrrell Knight Sir John Barrington
Knight Sir Robert Kempe Knight Thomas Ayliffe one of the Kings Serjeants at Lawe Harbottle Grimstone
Esquire William Masham Esquire Henry Nevill Esquire James Cambell Esquire John Harvey Esquire James Altham
Esquire Timothy Middleton Esquire John Meade Esquire Dionisius Makering Esquire George Walton Esquire John
Argoll Esquire Edward Keightley Esquire William Gouldingham Esquire Euseby Wright Esquire William Atwood
Esquire Anthony Luther Esquire Sampson Sheffeild Esquire James Hyron Esquire Edward Palmer Esquire William
Coniers Esquire Thomas Fanshawe Esquire John Wright Esquire Nathaniel Bacon Esquire Thomas Smith Esquire
John Brooke Esquire Cary Harvey Mildmay Esquire Deane Tindall Esquire Henry Wiseman Esquire Robert Mildmay
Esquire of Tarling Edward Berkhead Esquire Serjeant at Armes George Thoroughgood Esquire the Maior of the Town
of Colchester for the time being Henry Barrington Alderman the Maior of Harwich for the time being the two
Bailiffs of Maulden for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p198">For the County of Gloucester</para>
			<para id="p199">Unto Sir Humphrey Tracy Knight Sir Baynam Throckmorton Sir Richard Ducey Baronets Sir John Tracey Sir
William Masters Sir Ralph Dutton Sir John Seymor Sir Maurice Berkley Sir Robert Coke Sir Robert Tracey Knights
Richard Berkley Henry Poole John Dutton Nathaniel Stephens George Bridgman John Pretyman John Stephens
Thomas Escourt John Fetyplace Walter Bourchier Esquires William Trye John Howe Esquires Stephen Fowler
Gentleman Thomas Chester Edward Stephens John Cottrington Samuel Cothrington John Smith junior Anthony
Kinscot William Stratford Edward Fust of Hull Esquires Francis Finch John Berrow Thomas Morgan William Jones
John Chamberlain Michael Butler John Kite Esquires Anthony Hodges Gentleman William Stafford Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p200">For the City and County of the City of Gloucester</para>
			<para id="p201">Unto William Lenthall Esquire now Speaker of the Commons House of Parliament and Recorder of the said City
and to the Maior for the time being John Brewster John Webb James Powell William Singleton William Capell and
Thomas Pury William Lugg Thomas Hill Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p202">For the City of Bristoll</para>
			<para id="p203">Unto the Maior for the time being Denzill Hollis Esquire John Taylor John Gomming John Tomlinson Andrew
Charleton Richard Holworthy William Jones Ezekiell Wallis George Knight John [Socke<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p204">And for the County of Hertford</para>
			<para id="p205">Unto Charles Viscount Cranborne Sir John Botler Sir John Jennings Sir Thomas Fanshawe Knights of the Bath
Sir Richard Lucy Sir John Gerrard and Sir Thomas Hide Baronets Sir Charles Cesar Sir William Litton Sir Thomas
Read Sir Charles Harbourd Sir Thomas Fotherley Sir John Colt Sir Thomas Dacres Sir Edward Bash Sir John Wats
Sir John Cesar Sir Peter Saltonstall Sir John Gower Sir Thomas Hewett Sir John Harrison Sir Simon Fanshawe
Knights Edward Atkins Sergeant at Lawe Rowland Litton William Lemman [John Brocket William Preistley George
Tuck William Lemman<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Francis Taverner Granley Morton Edward Wingate Henry Anderson James Mayne Thomas
Blount John Heydon Robert Dewhurst Thomas Tooke Richard Hale Henry Gardiner John Gulstone Arthur Poulter
Ralph Freeman William Newce John Brograve Edward Chester Edward Cason Esquires the Maior of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albanes
for the time being William New John Howland Esquire Recorder John Robotham Ralph Pemberton.</para>
			<para id="p206">For the County of Hereford</para>
			<para id="p207">Unto Sir Robert Harley Knight of the Bath Sir John Kirle Baronet Sir Richard Hopton Sir Robert Whitney Sir
Humphrey Baskervile Sir William Croft Knights Wallop Brabazon Fitzwilliam Conigsby Henry Lingen. Henry
Vaughan John Scudamore Walter Kirle William Smallman Thomas Price Herbert Westfaling John Cornwall Paul
Abrahall Exiphon Howorth Thomas Tomkins Walter Vaughan John Coles John Patshall Richard Barrowe Arnold
Burghill William Cartwright Edward Broughton Henry Jones Esquires the Bailiffe of the Borough Leominster for
the time being.</para>
			<para id="p208">Unto the Maior of the City of Hereford for the time being James Rodes Richard Weaver and Richard Seaborne
Esquires James Lane Philip Simonds Gent.</para>
			<para id="p209">For the County of Huntington</para>
			<para id="p210">Unto Sir Sidney Mountague Knight Sir William Armyn Baronet Sir Oliver Crumwell Knight of the Bath Henry.
Cromwell Valentine Walton Onslowe Winche Wheatehill Audley John Castle Torrell Josseline Esquires the Maior of
Huntington for the time being Thomas Templar John Peacock Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p211">For the County of Kent</para>
			<para id="p212">Unto Sir John Culpepper Knight Chancellor and Under Treasurer of his Majesties Exchequer Sir Thomas Peyton
Sir John Baker Baronets Sir Roger Tuesden Sir Edward Hales Knights and Baronets Sir Thomas Palmer Sir John Rivers
Baronets Sir John Sidley Sir Humphrey Stiles Knights and Baronets Sir Robert Honywood Knight Sir William Culpepper
Sir Michael Livesey Baronets Sir Norton Knatchball Sir Henry Hayman Sir Humphrey Tufton Knights and Baronets
Sir Edward Scot Sir William Brooke Sir George [Sands<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] Knights of the Bath Sir Percivall Hart Sir Francis Barnham
Sir Edward Boys Sir Thomas Wilsford Sir Thomas Walsingham Sir James Oxenden Sir Anthony Welden Sir Peter
Wrath Sir John Honywood Sir Edward Gilborne Sir Henry Grimston Sir Robert Filmer Sir Cheiney Culpepper Sir
Edward Master Sir William Brockman Sir Edward Parthrich Knights Sir Nicholas Miller Sir John Henden Sir Peter
Godfrey [Sir George Strode<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Sir William Man Knights Henry Clarke Serjeant at Law Edward Monyns Thomas Diggs
Robert Barnham Stephen Leonard John Boys of Elmington Richard Hardres Anthony Haymond Richard Masters
Robert Scot Richard Browne Thomas Scylieard Richard Lee Augustin Skynner Nicholas Toke George Newman
William James Reginald Edwards Samuel Shorte Richard Parker William Boys George Chute Thomas Blechinden
Marke Dixwell Henry Sandford Edward Deering Thomas Blunt George Rooke Henry Dixon Edward Boys Henry
James Henry Gilborne John Harvey John Goldwell of Beckesley.</para>
			<para id="p213">For the City and County of the City of Canterbury</para>
			<para id="p214">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir James Hales Sir Edward Master Sir William Man Knights Francis Lovelace
Recorder John Nutt Thomas Courthop Esquires. Avery Sabine James Master Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p215">For the Parts of Lyndsey in the Countic of Lincolne</para>
			<para id="p216">Unto Edmund Lord Sheffeild Sir John Wrey Knight and Baronet Sir Philip Terwhit Sir John Bolles [Baronets
Sir Edward Askew Sir William Pelham Sir Charles Bolles<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Sir Christopher Wrey Sir John South Sir Henry Radley
Sir Samuel Oldfeild Knights Nathaniel Fynes John Bellasis Thomas Grantham Anthony Meeres Thomas Sanderson
Edmund Anderson Stephen Anderson Willoughby Hickman Charles Pelham John Broxholm John Sheffeild Marmaduke
Darell Edward Rositer Richard Toothby Thomas Aishcough senior John Bradley William Godfrey Francis Woolbey
Esquires William Loddington Gentleman the Maior of Grimsby for the time being William Coney Rutland
Snowden Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p217">For the City and County of the City of Lincolne</para>
			<para id="p218">Unto the Maior of the said Citie of Lincolne for the time being Thomas Grantham John Broxholme Esquires Richard
White William Watson Stephen Dawson Aldermen and Richard Ward Citizen</para>
			<para id="p219">Unto the Maior of the Borough of Boston for the time being Sir Anthony Irby Knight Edward Tibson.</para>
			<para id="p220">For the Parts of Holland in the County aforesaid</para>
			<para id="p221">To Sir Anthony Irby Knight Thomas Ogle William Lo&bholigct;on Thomas Read William Ellis Dimock Walpole Philip Welby
John Harrington Thomas Irby Esquires John Harrington Samuel Cust Charles Empson John Hobson Francis Empson
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p222">For the Parts of Kestaven in the County of Lincolne</para>
			<para id="p223">Unto Sir Robert Carre Sir William Armin Sir William Brownelow Sir John Trollop Baronets Sir John Brooke
Sir Hamond Whitchcott Sir Gervas Nevill Knights Charles Dimock Thomas Hatcher Edmund Hall Thomas
Harrington Thomas Lister Edward King William Savile John Archer Esquires the Aldermen of Stamford and the
Aldermen of Grantham for the time being</para>
			<para id="p224">For the Countie of Leicester</para>
			<para id="p225">Unto Sir Edward Hartopp Baronet Sir Thomas Hartopp Sir Roger Smith Sir Woolston Dixie Sir Richard Roberts
Knights George Ashby Martin Lister William Herlford Thomas Brudnell Arthur Staveley William Roberts Peter
Temple George Ashby Thomas Babingston Simon Rugelie Henry Faunt William Jervise Richard Bent the Maior of
Leicester for the time being Thomas Rudier Gilbert Fawsett William Standly Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p226">For the County Palatine of Lancaster</para>
			<para id="p227">Unto Sir Gilbert Haughton Knight &amp; Baronet Sir Ralphe [Ashton<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Sir Thomas Stanley Baronets Sir Thomas Barton
Knight Ralph Ashton Roger Kirkby Richard Shuttleworth John More Thomas Standish Ralph Ashton Richard
Holland Charles Gerrard John Atherton Robert Holt Alexander Rigby of Burgh Hugh Rigby Alexander Rigby
William Farrington Thomas Preston John Garlington George Dodding Edmund Hopwood Nicholas Townly Henry
Ashhurst John Bradshawe Edward Veale Thomas Fell Henry Ogle Savile Ratcliffe John Starkey Edward Butterworth
William Ambrose Christopher Banister Thomas Whittingham John Bradell Edmund Ashton Ratcliffe Ashton Esquires
Richard Shutworth Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p228">For the County of Mi[ddlesex]</para>
			<para id="p229">Unto Sir Edward Spencer Knight Sir Thomas Fowler Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Barkham Knight and
Baronet Sir John Conniers Lieutennant of the Tower of London Sir John Davers Sir Gilbert Gerrard Baronet Sir
John Francklin Sir Thomas Lake Sir Edward Wardour Sir William Roberts Sir Henry Rowe Sir John Bennet
Sir Thomas Allen Sir Robert Wood Sir Nicholas Raynton Sir John Thoroughgood Knights John Page Esquire one
of the Masters of the Chancery Sir Thomas Gardiner Knight Recorder of the City of London William Hill Justinian
Povey William Cholmley Sir Robert Fenn John Hawtrey Francis Poulton John Herne John Huxley George Long
Edward Roberts Richard Blower Anthony Crofts Richard Sprygenell Esquires John Smith Thomas Marsh John
Hoker Edward Noell Thomas Jennings Richard Page Thomas Wilcock John Morris Richard Dunton Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p230">For the Citie of Westminster</para>
			<para id="p231">Unto Sir Edmund Verney Sir Randall Crewe Sir Robert Pye Sir Arthur Ingram Sir Edward Wardour Knights John
Glynne Esquire Recorder of the Citie of Westminster Robert Dixon Michael Oldesworth Mathew Hale Arthur
Squibb William Wheeler John Chichley John Trenchard Robert Scawen Esquires Robert Dixon George Bleverhaset
William Bell John Brigham and Richard Gammon Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p232">And for the Dutchy of Lancaster</para>
			<para id="p233">Unto Edward Lord Newburgh Chancellor of the Dutchy Sir Thomas Bedingfeild Knight Challenor Chute Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p234">For the Citie of London</para>
			<para id="p235">Unto the Lord Maior for the time being Sir George Whitmore Sir Nicholas Raynton Sir Maurice Abbot Sir
John Woolaston Sir Henry Garraway Knights and Aldermen Sir Thomas Gardiner Knight Recorder Thomas Soame
Isaac Pennington Aldermen John Venn Samuel Vassall Citizens.</para>
			<para id="p236">For the County of Monmouth</para>
			<para id="p237">Unto Philip Lord Harbert Sir Edmund Morgan and Sir William Morgan Knights William Kemys Esquire
William Harbert Richard Harbert Thomas Morgan of Mayhen Trevor Williams William Harbert of Colebrooke
Nicholas Kemys John Milbourne Henry Probert David Lewis William Baker Philip Jones William Jones of Usk
George Probert Thomas Morgan of Lanfore William Morgan of Tredonock Gentlemen and Thomas Williams
Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p238">For the County of Norfolke</para>
			<para id="p239">Unto Sir John Hubbart Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Richardson Knight Sir Thomas Woodhouse Knight and
Baronet Sir William Paston Baronet Sir John Pots Baronet Sir Richard Barney Sir John Holland Baronet Sir Miles
Hubbart Knight of the Bath Sir Hamond de Strange Sir Charles le Grose Sir Robert Kempe Sir Anthony Gawdie
Sir Thomas Hoogan Sir Edmund Mundford Sir Thomas Gawdie Sir Edward Kirkham Sir Robert le Grey Sir
Thomas Gibbons Knights Francis Bacon Serjeant at Lawe Thomas Knevitt Framlingham Gawdy James Hubbart
John Burton Thomas Wyndeham William Henningham Robert Bacon Richard Catlin Philip Calthropp Sir John
Spilman of Norbrough Knight John Smith Gregory Gawsell Charles Sucklin Jeffery Cobb Thomas Fisham John
Palgrave Francis Jermy Edward Garmy William Doyley William Buckworth Sir Valentine Pill Knight Robert
Wood Robert Wilton Adam Scambler James Scambler John Spelman Martin Sedley Robert Tong Robert Roughton
and Thomas Wright Adam [Scamley<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] James [Scamley<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] Robert Mapes Thomas Wright Thomas Fisham Martin
Sedley Edward Chamberlain Henry Taylor Thomas Reeve John Kendall John Houghton Esquires the Maior of
Thetford for the time being Thomas Lincoln</para>
			<para id="p240">For the City and County of the City of Norwich</para>
			<para id="p241">Unto the Maior for the time being Francis Bacon Serjeant at Law Thomas Shipdam Henry Lane Christopher
Barret Thomas Baker John Tooley Erasmus Earle Richard Catlyn Alexander Anguish Samuel Smith Richard Harman
Esquires John Thacker William Goslin Lynewell Sherwood Francis Norris Thomas Barret Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p242">To the Maior of Lyn Regis for the time being Francis Parlett Esquire Recorder William Doubty Joshua Green
Aldermen William Leake</para>
			<para id="p243">To the Bailiffe for the Town of Yarmouth for the time being Thomas Green Robert Wakeman Aldermen</para>
			<para id="p244">For the County of North[amp]ton</para>
			<para id="p245">Unto William Lord Fitzwilliams Sir Rowland S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Knight of the Bath Sir Christopher Yelverton Knight and
Baronet Sir John Norwich Baronet Zouch Tate Esquire Sir Francis Nicholas Baronet Sir William Chauncie Knight
Sir Christopher Hatton Knight of the Bath Sir Richard Samuel Knight John Blinchoe Esquire Sir Humfrey Orme
Knight Richard Knightly Senior Esquire Charles Edmonds Esquire Edward Harby Esquire John Bernard John
Cartwright Philip Holeman John Cresswell Richard Trist William Pargeter Richard Lane Esquire Attorney to the
Prince his Highnes James [Angou<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] Edward Farmer Clifton Catesby Lawrence Manley Thomas Genison Richard Owsley
John Sawyer Thomas Pentloe Thomas Dove Francis Quarles John Claypoole William Dudley Thomas Elme John
Norton Edward Duncumbes Edward Handbury Henry Freeman Esquires Edward Shugborough Esquire the Maior
of North[amp]ton for the time being Thomas Martin John Gifford Gentlemen</para>
			<para id="p246">For the County of Northumberland</para>
			<para id="p247">Unto Sir John Fenwicke and Sir William Widdrington Knights Sir John Delavale Knight Sir John Clevering
Knight Thomas Middleton Esquire Cuthbert Heron Esquire Sir Robert Collingwood Knight Gilbert Swinhoe
Esquire Sir Robert Jackson Knight William Shaftoe Esquire Henry Withrington Gentleman Sir Nicholas Temple
Knight Robert Midforth Gentleman Richard Heron Gentleman John Salkeld Gentleman Henry Ogle Gentleman
Ralph Carnaby Esquire Henry Whitehead Gentleman Richard Foster Gentleman Robert Clavering &amp; Martin
Fenwick Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p248">For the County and Town of Newcastle upon Tine</para>
			<para id="p249">The Maior for the Time being Sir Lionell Maddison Knight John Clavering Leonard Card Esquires Ralph Gray
Henry Lawson Henry Waxmouth Thomas Burler Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p250">For the County of Nottingham</para>
			<para id="p251">Unto Francis Perpoint Esquire Sir Jarvase Clifton Knight and Baronet Sir Francis Molineux Sir Hardoffe Wastenesse
Baronets Sir Thomas Hutchinson Sir Francis Thornhaighe Sir Roger Cooper Sir Mathew Palmer Sir Jervis Eyre
Knights Robert Sutton Isham Perkins Anthony Eyre John Nevile Thomas Williamson William Stanhope Richard
Byron John Wood Senior Timothy Pusy Gilbert Millington John Digby a&bholigct;on Burnell Jervis Piggott Jervis Lee
John Odingsell Hugh Cartwright William Saunderson Richard Hacker John Wood junior Esquires the Maior of
Newarke for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p252">For the Countie of the Town of Nottingham</para>
			<para id="p253">Unto the Maior for the time being John James Francis Peirpoynt Esquire Sir Jervis Clifton. Knight and Baronet
Sir Thomas [Hutchinson<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Knight William Nix Richard Hardmeate William Gregory Robert Burton Aldermen Robert
Sutton William Stanhope Gilbert Millington Esquires Huntington Plumbtree Do&bholigct;or of Phisick Robert Greves
John Gregorie senior.</para>
			<para id="p254">For the Countie of Oxford</para>
			<para id="p255">Unto William Lenthall Esquire now Speaker of the Commons House of Parliament Sir Thomas Pope Knight Sir
Thomas Penniston Knight and Baronet Sir Peter Wentworth Knight of the Bath Sir John Curson Sir Robert Dormer
Sir Robert Jenkinson Knight Sir John Lacy Sir Francis Norris Sir William Cobb Sir Thomas Cogghill Knights Edward
Wray John Doyley Thomas Chamberlaine Thomas Tipping Robert Scroope Edmund Simeon [Unto<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] Croke Humphrey
Elmes Richard Hampden John Taverner Edmund Goodier William Tipping John Griffith Edmund Chamberlaine
Bartholomew Hone Rice Jones Walter Dunch Edward Clarke Charnell Pettie Vincent Barrey and Richard Powell
Esquires Unto the Maior of the City of Oxon. for the time being John Whistler Esquire Recorder Henry Southam
John Smith John Nixon.</para>
			<para id="p256">For the County of Rutland</para>
			<para id="p257">Unto Sir Edward Harrington Knight and Baronet Sir Francis Bodenham Knight Richard Wynfeild Alexander Noell
Bryan Palmes Edward Heath Evers Armyn John Osborne Edward Faulconer Edward Chisledine and Andrew Burton
Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p258">For the County of Surrey</para>
			<para id="p259">Unto William Mounson Knight Lord Viscount Mounson of Castlemaine Sir Anthony Vincent Knight and Baronet
Sir Richard Young Sir Ambrose Browne Baronets Sir Nicholas Carew Sir Richard Onslow Sir Arthur
Manwaring Sir Thomas Grymes Sir Francis Howard Sir Charles Howard Sir Francis Stidolph Sir John Howland
Sir John Lenthall Knights Sir John Jaques Baronet Sir John Tonstall Sir John Gresham Sir Thomas Evelyn
Sir William Elliot Sir Thomas Bludder Sir Dudley Carleton Sir Robert Parkehurst Sir John Evelyn Sir Samuel Oldfeild
Knights Nicholas Stoughton Henry Hilliard George Evelyn Arthur Squibb George Mynn George Duncombe senior
William Mustchampe Robert Hatton Robert Goodwyn Edmund Saunders John Turnor Henry Weston Robert
Holman Edward Bish senior Edward Bish junior Heyward Bickerstaffe Richard Hacket Woolley Lea John Denham
John Hamond Mathew Carleton John Goodwyn Anthony Fane James Zouch Thomas Sands Cornelius Holland
Charles Hoskyns Esquires John Wayte Gentleman Samuel Warcupp Esquire Robert Haughton Cornelius Cooke.</para>
			<para id="p260">For the County of Stafford</para>
			<para id="p261">Unto Sir William Brereton Sir Harvy Baggot Sir Edward Littleton Baronets Sir Richard Leveson Knight of the
Bath Sir Charles Egerton Knight Ralph Snede Walter Wrotesley George Digby Thomas Crompton Humfrey
Worley Mathew Morton John Scrimshire John Fowke Esquires Edward Manwaring Arthur Grosvenor Richard
Pyat Michael Biddulph John Wedgwood junior William Brookes Esquires Richard Ever Richard Hinton Nicholas Hurt
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p262">For the City and County of the City of Litchfeild</para>
			<para id="p263">Unto the Bailiffs of the said City for the time being Michael Noble Esquire John Barnes Humfrey Mathew
Randall Terrick Richard Baxter Richard Drafgate Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p264">For the County of Salop</para>
			<para id="p265">Unto Sir Robert Howard Knight of the Bath William Peirpoynt Esquire Sir Richard Levison Knight of the Bath
Sir Paul Harris Knight and Baronet Sir John Corbet Sir Richard Lee Baronets Sir Thomas Woolrige Sir Moreton
Briggs Baronets Sir William Whitmore Sir Richard Newport Sir William Owen Sir Robert Eyton Knights Henry
Bromley Harcourt Layton Esquires John Wylde Esquire Richard More Charles Baldwyn Francis [Charleton<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] Walter
Barker Edward Jones Thomas Eyton Peter Corbet Edward Cresset Thomas Corbet Adam Littleton Thomas Kettleby
Francis Herbert William Littleton Francis Harbert Edward Acton Humfrey Walcott Walter Piggott John Newton
Thomas Nicholls Arthur Sandford William Fowler Thomas Mitton Andrew Lloyd Richard Lloyd Francis Thornes
Robert Powell Thomas Screven William Blundell Richard Oakely Walter Waring Thomas Southerne Roger Kinastone
Rowland Hill Robert Corbet of Stannadine Esquires Arthur Ward. Thomas Lockard Gentlemen the Maior of the
Towne of Shrewsbury for the time being Sir Richard Prince Knight Timothy Turner Thomas Jones senior Edward
Jones Thomas Owen Humfrey Mackworth Thomas Mitton Richard Gibbons Esquires William Rowley Simon Weston
Charles Benion Robert Betton Thomas Winfeild John Studley Aldermen of Shrewsbury the Bailiffs of the Town of
Ludlow for the time being Ralph Goodwyn Charles Baldwyn Esquires Edward Jones Adam Acton and Ellis Biddow
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p266">For the County of South[amp]ton</para>
			<para id="p267">Unto George Goring Esquire Sir John Mill Baronet Sir Richard Norton Baronet Sir William Lewes Baronet Sir
Henry Wellopp Knight Sir. Gabriell Dowse Knight Sir Francis Dowse Knight Sir Gerrard Fleetwood Knight Sir
William Uvedall Knight Sir Thomas Jarvis Knight Sir Thomas Bilson Knight Sir Henry Clarke Knight Sir John
Compton Knight Sir William Waller Knight Sir William Ogle Knight Robert Wallop Esquire Richard Whitehead
Esquire John Doddington Esquire Richard Norton of Southwicke Esquire Henry Sands Esquire Richard Jarvis Esquire
John [Lisle<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] Esquire Thomas Neale Esquire William Kingsmill Esquire Edward Pit Esquire Benjamin Tutchburne
Esquire Arthur Hide Esquire Dowse Fuller Esquire Thomas Wills Esquire John Button Esquire Francis Saintberb
Esquire John Hooke Esquire Edward Hooper Esquire Arthur Bromfeild Esquire John Kempe Esquire Henry Tulse
Esquire William Withers Esquire Thomas Brooke Esquire Richard Major Esquire Thomas Edmonds Esquire Francis
Tilney Esquire the Maior of Winton for the time being Thomas Chandler Thomas Betsworth Esquire Francis Rivet
Esquire Thomas Hussey [Esquire<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] Christopher Hussey Esquire Ralphe Rix the Maior of Portsmouth for the time being</para>
			<para id="p268">For the Town and County of the Town of South[amp]ton</para>
			<para id="p269">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir John Mill Baronet Nicholas Peascodd Alderman George Gollop Alderman
Peter Priaulx Alderman Edward Exton Alderman Thomas Mason Alderman Peter Clungion Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p270">For the Isle of Wight</para>
			<para id="p271">Unto Sir Henry [Worsley<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] Baronet Sir Robert Dillington Baronet Sir John Meux Baronet Sir William Lisle Sir
John Oglunder Sir John Leigh Knights Barnaby Leigh John Lisle Edward Dennis John Richards John Bulkley
William Bournam John [Worsley<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] Esquires Robert Urry Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p272">For the County of Suffolke</para>
			<para id="p273">Unto Sir Edmund Bacon Sir William Playteers Sir Robert Crane Knights and Baronets Sir John Barker Sir
Buttes Bacon Sir Simonds d' Ewes Knight and Baronet Sir William Spring Baronet Sir Roger North Sir Nathaniel
Barnardiston Sir Philip Parker Sir William Soame Sir John Rowse Sir Thomas Glemham Sir John Wentworth
Sir Charles Crofts Sir William Pooley Sir Robert Brooke Sir William Harvy Sir Thomas Gee Sir Edward Duke
Knights Henry Cooke Thomas Jermin William Heveningham Maurice Barrowe John Wingfeild John Gurdon
Wiseman [Bokenham<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] William Rivet of Bilson Henry North Isaac Appleton Thomas Plaiters Robert Raynalds John
Rowse Thomas Cole Richard Pepes Robert Brewster John Scrivener Henry North Senior Nicholas Bacon of
Dennington Thomas Blosse Arthur. Jenny Nathaniel Bacon of Friston John Lany Nicholas Rivet of Drinkston
Francis Bacon William Cage William Bloyse of Grandesbourgh John Clench junior Edmund Harvy of Wickhamskeythe
Esquires the Bailiffe of the Towne of Ipswich for the time being John [Sucklmor<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] Richard Puplet Gentlemen
Edmund Keyne John [Alde<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] Gentlemen the [Bailiffs<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] of Aldeburge for the time being Thomas Johnson Henry
Cleney Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p274">For the County of Somerset</para>
			<para id="p275">Unto Sir Thomas Mallet Knight one of his Majesties Justices of the Kings Bench Sir John Horner Sir Charles
Berkley (<ref idref="n33">33</ref>) Sir Francis Dodington Sir Thomas Wroth Sir Henry Berkley Knights Sir Thomas Bridges and Sir
Francis Hawle Knights John Mallet John Harrington William Walrond George Powlet Richard Cole Anthony
Stocker William Capell John Symmes William Every junior William Bull Robert Harbyn Thomas Lutterell
Samuel Gorges Robert Henley William Strode of Barrington Amias Bampfeild John S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albyne John Hunt
Edward Dyer William Hill of Pounsford Edward Wycks William Barrow senior John Baber John Merifeild
James Ash Henry Nevill Edward Baber Nathaniel Holbech Esquires unto the Maior of Bathe for the time being
Richard Chapman John Biggs Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p276">For the County of Sussex</para>
			<para id="p277">Unto Sir Thomas Pelham Sir Thomas Bowyer Baronets Sir John Chapman Sir William Morley Sir Henry
Dawtry Sir Thomas Parker Sir George Courtopp Sir Thomas Eversfeild of Denn Sir Thomas Eversfeild junior
Sir Thomas Henley Knights Philip Jarmin Serjeant at Lawe Anthony Stapley Edward Ford Thomas Grey John
Alford Thomas Mylles Nicholas Wolfe Ralph Cooper Henry Goring Thomas May Thomas Midleton Hall
Ravenscroft William Marlot Edward Apsley William Michillbourne Harbert Morley Anthony Fowle Henry Shelley
John Ashbournham William White Harbert Hay John Baker Laurence Ashbourneham Herbert Bourd John
Busbridge William Cawley Peter Farneden Thomas Whitfeild William Thomas John Downes Henry Peck Francis
Selwyn John Apsley Esquires Henry Bridgen Gentleman George Sampson &amp; William Bachelour of Winchelsey
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p278">For the County of Warwick</para>
			<para id="p279">Unto James Lord Compton Sir Thomas Leigh Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Holt Knight and Baronet Sir
Simon Clarke Baronet Sir Robert Fisher Knight and Baronet Sir Peter Wentworth Knight of the Bath Sir Grevill
Varney Knight Sir Hercules Underhill Knight Sir Henry Gibbs. Knight Sir Francis Willoughby Knight Sir Simon
Archer Knight Sir George Devereux Knight Rowley Ward Serjeant at Law Walter Chitwine Esquire Spencer Lucy
Robert Ardine George Browne Clement Throckmorton Robert Lee Richard Shugburgh William Combes John Lisley
William Purefey John Temple Thomas Boughton Anthony Stoughton James Onion Robert Shelton John Fetherston
Esquires Thomas Newsum Esquire Richard Bishopp Esquire Serjeant at Armes.</para>
			<para id="p280">For the City and County of the City of Coventry</para>
			<para id="p281">To the Maior for the time being Henry Million John Clarke Thomas Ward William Jessyn John Barker
Aldermen John Hales &amp; Richard Greene Esquires Thomas Basnett.</para>
			<para id="p282">For the County of Wilts</para>
			<para id="p283">Unto Edward Lord Gorges Sir John S<emph type="p">t</emph> Johns Knight and Baronet Sir William Button Knight and Baronet Sir
Edward Hungerford Knight of the Bath Sir John Glanvile Knight one of His Majesties Serjeants at Lawe Sir
John Davers Sir Edward Bainton Sir John Earnley Sir Nevill Poole Sir Theobald Gorges Sir Henry Ludlowe Sir
Walter Smith Sir John Lambe Sir George Ayloffe Sir John Evelyn Edward Seymer George Vaughan Lawrence
Hide Richard Goddard John Bowles Edward Tucker Francis Swanton John Saddler Robert Drewe Edward Earley
William Bowyer John Topp Thomas More Robert Eyre William Walleys Robert Genner Walter Longe John
Ducket Edmund Escourt Robert Nicholas Charles Gore Thomas Hungerford Thomas Bennet Henry Bayley John
Penruddock Richard Goddard Edward Goddard Walter Norburne George Lowe Henry Hawkins Philip Smith
Jasper More Thomas Grove John Francklyn Unto the Maior of New Sarum for the time being Richard Goddard
Esquire John Ivie John Dove</para>
			<para id="p284">For the County of Westmerland</para>
			<para id="p285">Unto Sir Philip Musgrave Baronet Sir James Bellingham Sir Richard Sandford Knights Sir Henry Bellingham
Knight and Baronet Christopher Phillipson Gawen Brathwaite Allen Bellingham George Gilpin Richard Crackenthorpe
Esquires John Dalston Esquire Christopher Dudley Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p286">For the County of Worcester</para>
			<para id="p287">Unto Sir Walter Devereux Sir Thomas Rous Baronets Sir John Rous Knight John Wilde Serjeant at Lawe Humfrey
Salwey Edward Pitt Edward Dingley William Jeffryes of Hamm Castle John Savage Henry Ingram Henry Townsend
John Nanfan Edward Vernon William Childe Thomas Good Robert Wilde of the Commanders John Winford Esquires
George Lench Philip Brace Roger Lowe John Colding Esquires Henry Dison Edward Barret &amp; Nicholas Gower of
Droytwich John Hailes &amp; Francis Gilding of Bewdley Daniel Dobbins Esquires the Bailiffe of Kidderminster for
the time being the Maior of Evesham for the time being Francis Harwell Thomas Chresheld Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p288">For the Citie and Countie of the Citie of Worcester</para>
			<para id="p289">Unto the Maior for the time being John Coucher Roger Gough John Hanbury John Nash William Norris
George Street Aldermen Francis Street Esquire Richard Heming Humphrey Vernon Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p290">For the County of Anglesey and Town of Beaumaris</para>
			<para id="p291">To Sir Arthur Terringham Sir Thomas Holland Knights Thomas Buckley Thomas Glyn Richard [Putherich<ref idref="n34">34</ref>]
John Bodevile Hugh Owen of Bodeon Owin Wood William Robinson Richard Owen Richard Merricke Henry
White William Bold Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p292">For the County of Brecon</para>
			<para id="p293">To Henry Williams Thomas Gwyn John Williams Richard Gaynes John Wabiefe Jeffery Jefferyes William
Morgan Richard Rumsey Edward Williams Meredith Lewis Roger Vaughan William Harbert Bailiffe of Brecknock
William Watkins Davies Winter Lewis Meredith Hugh Meredith John Herbert Morgan Aubrey Esquires</para>
			<para id="p294">For the County of Cardigan</para>
			<para id="p295">Unto Sir Marmaduke Lloyd Knight Sir John Lewis Knight Richard Price James Lewis Henry Vaughan junior
Evan Gwyn John Stedman Thomas Price John Pew David Evans John Phillipps John Vaughan Esq. Thomas
William Lloyd and Nicholas Williams Esquires</para>
			<para id="p296">For the County of Carmarthen</para>
			<para id="p297">Unto Sir Richard Vaughan Knight of the Bath and Earle of Carbury Sir Rees Rudd Baronet Henry Jones
David Guyn John Vaughan of Plose Richard Vaughan Rowland Gwyn Henry Vaughan junior Richard Phillips
John Harris Thomas Lloyd Nicholas Williams Esquires</para>
			<para id="p298">For the Borough and the Countie of the Borough of Carmarthen</para>
			<para id="p299">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir Richard Vaughan Knight of the Bath and Earle of Carbury in the
Kingdome of Ireland Griffith Lewis Martin Bynon Thomas Wood Lewis Jones Thomas Jones Rowland Phillips
David Bevan Owen Man and John Bloome Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p300">For the Countie of Carnarvan</para>
			<para id="p301">Unto Sir Richard Wynn Knight and Baronet Sir William Williams Baronet Thomas Glynn John Bodvell
Griffith Jones John Griffith John Owen Owen Wynn William Thomas Maurice Wynne Griffith Thomas Humfrey
Jones Thomas Glynn of Nanley William Glynn John Bodurda John Robins Thomas Maddryn William Lloyd
Arthur Williams William Hookes Hugh Griffith and Hugh Wynne Esquires and John Jones of Melnuen Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p302">For the Countie of Denbigh</para>
			<para id="p303">Unto Sir Thomas Salisbury Baronet Sir Thomas Middleton Sir Edward Broughton Knights William Salisbury
William Wynne Simon Thelwall Gerrard Eyton Edward Meredith Robert Wynn Richard Lloyd John Lloyd
Edward Thelwell Kenrick Eyton John Wynne Hugh Lloyd John Thelwall Richard Middleton John Roydon William
Parry Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p304">For the Countie of Flint</para>
			<para id="p305">Unto Sir Thomas Hanmer Baronet Sir Roger Mostyn Knight Sir Thomas Bruerton Knight Richard Grovesnor
Roger Mostyn William Conway Thomas Ravenscroft Humphrey Dymocke John Puleston Robert Davies Thomas
Mostyn John Salisbury John Eaton William Mostyn Peter Griffith Peter Evans Richard Parry Evan Edwards
and Ralph Hughes Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p306">For the County of Glamorgan</para>
			<para id="p307">Unto Philip Lord Harbert of Cardiffe Sir William Lewis Sir Thomas Lewis Sir Anthony Mansell Knights
Edward Stradling John Carne John Oberry Nicholas Kems Thomas Mathews Richard Basset William Harbert of
Swansey Anthony Gwyn William Harbert of Cogan Edward Thomas Thomas Lewis Thomas Carne David Evans
Marmaduke Mathews Watkin Lougher Jenkin Morgan Walter Thomas Esquires and Richard Seys Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p308">For the County of Mereonith</para>
			<para id="p309">Unto Sir James Price Knight William Salisbury Edmund Merick Hugh Nanny William Lewis Lewis Anwell
William Wynn John Lloyd John Morgan John Lewis Lewis Nanny Thomas Mytton Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p310">For the County of Pembrooke</para>
			<para id="p311">Unto Sir Richard Phillips Sir John Stepney Baronets Sir Hugh Owen Knight and Baronet John Lawharne
Hugh (<ref idref="n34">34</ref>) Bowen Esquires Thomas ap Rice Lewis Barber George Browne David Parry John Phillips John Gunter
Walter Cuny Thomas White the Maior of the Towne of Pembrooke and Timby for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p312">For the Town and County of Haverford West</para>
			<para id="p313">Unto the Maior for the time being Sir John Stepney Baronet Maurice Cannon William Maylor John Davies
Gentlemen Jenkyn Howell Richard Bivans Aldermen William Bowen &amp; Thomas Barlowe Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p314">For the County of Mountgomery</para>
			<para id="p315">Unto Sir John Price Baronet Sir Edward Lloyd Knight Richard Harbert Arthur Price Rowland Pugh John
Blaney Edward Corbet Lloyd Peirs John Price Richard Pugh Evan Glynn Edward Lloyd Thomas Maurice
Thomas Owens Esquires Charles Lloyd Edward Wynn William Ruffin Francis Harbert [Esquires<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] Randall Owen
Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p316">For the Countie of Radnor</para>
			<para id="p317">Unto Charles Price William Vaughan Richard Jones Robert Williams Senior Robert Williams junior Roderick
Gwyn Morgan Vaughan Nicholas Meredith Hugh Lloyd Harbert Weston Bryan Crowther Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p318">
				<emph type="i">Commissions to be delivered to the Commissioners before the 10th April 1642; and Ten Schedules of Tenor of a&bholigct; filed, and Schedules, &amp;c. of Names of Popish Recusants</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p319">Which Commissions for the payment of the said s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money shall be severally and respectively
delivered to the said Commissioners or to one of them before the tenth day of Aprill One thousand six hundred
fourty two and to every of the said [Commissioners<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] ten schedules (containing the tenour of this a&bholigct;) shall be filed.
And for the Commissioners better discovery of Popish Recusants severall schedules shall be delivered unto them
with theire severall Commissions out of the Exchequer and Certificates from the Clerkes of the Assizes and of
the Peace and other the like Officers and from the Ministers and Churchwardens of every Parish of the names
of such Popish Recusants as are to be charged by this a&bholigct; by [the<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] which Commission the Commissioners in every
such Commission named according to this a&bholigct; and as many of them as shall be appointed by the said Commission
shall have full power and authority to put the effect of the said Commission in execution.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Commissioners to meet together.</head>
			<para id="p320">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that after such Commission to them delivered the said
Commissioners for the better effe&bholigct;ing of the &bhopcrl;misses shall and may with all convenient speed assemble themselves
and meet together in every of the said Counties or Places respe&bholigct;ively (where they are Commissioners) in some
convenient place for the distribu&bhocotil;n of the said s&bhouov;m imposed upon each Countie to be divided into Hundreds
Lathes Wards Rapes Wapentakes Towns Parishes and other places according to the true meaning of this a&bholigct; and
that afterwards they may by theire assents and agreements sever themselves for the execution of theire Commission
into such Hundreds Lathes Wards Rapes Wapentakes Towns Parishes and other Places within the limits of the
said Commission in such forme as to them shall seeme expedient to be ordered and betweene them to be agreed
according to the tenour and effe&bholigct; of the Commission to them therein dire&bholigct;ed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Commissioners to execute a&bholigct; according to the tenor thereof.</head>
			<para id="p321">
				<emph type="i">For Payment of the Two Moieties of the said Money,; Commissioners to dire&bholigct; Precepts to a certain Number of Inhabitants in Hundreds, &amp;c. to appear before the the Commissioners.; Persons who receive Precepts are to shew such Precepts to the other Inhabitants named therein; Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p322">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by authoritie of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament That the Commissioners and every of them
which are named limited and appointed according to this a&bholigct; to be Commissioners in every such Shire Ryding Lathe
Wapentake Rape City Town Borough Isle or any other place and none other shall truely effe&bholigct;ually and diligently
for their parts execute the effe&bholigct; of this present a&bholigct; according to the tenour thereof in every behalfe and no otherwise
by any meanes without omission favour dread malice or any other thing to be attempted or done by them or any of
them to the contrary thereof And the said Commissioners or as many of them as shall be appointed by the said
Commission and none other for the execution of the said Commission and a&bholigct; shall for the taxation of the said first
payment being the moitie or one halfe of the said sume and s&bhouov;ms of money before the six and twentieth day of
Aprill in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred fourty two And for the taxation of the second payment
being the other moyety hereof before the first day of September One thousand six hundred fourty and two by vertue
of the Commission delivered to them in form aforesaid dire&bholigct;ts theire severall or joynt precept or precepts unto eight
seven six five four three or twoe (as for the number of the Inhabitants shall be requisite) of the most substantiall
discreet and honest persons Inhabitants to be named by the said Commissioners or by as many of them as shall bee
appointed by the said Commission of and in Hundreds Lathes Rapes Wapentakes Wards Parishes Towns and other
places aswell within Liberties Franchises ancient demeasne places exempted and Sanctuaries as without within the limits
of the Shires Ridings Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Cities Towns Boroughs and Isle aforesaid and other places within
the limits of theire Commission and to the Constables Subconstables Bailiffs and other like Officers and Ministers of
every of the said Hundreds Towns Rapes Wapentakes Wards Parishes and other places aforesaid as to the Commissioners
and every number of them or to four or three of them by theire discretion shall seem expedient and as by the manner
and use of those parts shall be requisite straitly by the said precept charging and commanding the said Inhabitants
Constables and other Officers aforesaid to whom such Precept shall be so directed to appeare in theire proper persons
before the said Commissioners or such number of them as(<ref idref="n38">38</ref>) shall divide themselves according to the tenour of the said
Commission at certaine dayes and places by the said Commissioners or any such number of them as is aforesaid
within Cities Boroughs or Towns corporate or without in any other place as is aforesaid by theire discretion to be
limited thereunto to do and accomplish all that to them on the part of the Kings Majestie shall be enjoyned touching
this a&bholigct; Commaunding further by the said precept that he to whose hands such precept shall come shall shew and
deliver the same to the other Inhabitants or Officers named in the same Precept and that none of them faile to
accomplish the same upon pain of five pounds to be forfeited to the Kings Majestie</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Commissioners to meet and call Persons named in Precept to appear before them.</head>
			<para id="p323">
				<emph type="i">Such Persons making Default, or refusing to serve; Penalty &pound;5.; Upon Appearance to be charged to make Inquiry into the Substance of Persons to be charged; but such Inquiry not to be taken on Oath; and to certify before Commissioners such Substance, and the Names of the Parties charged, &amp;c.; Penalty &pound;5.; Thereupon Commissioners to read the Rates openly, and instruct Officers how to make their Certificates, &amp;c.; Afterwards another Day to be appointed by Commissioners for such Persons to appear.; Such Persons not appearing, and refusing to make Certificate.; Penalty &pound;5.; Proviso for Sickness, &amp;c.; Commissioners to examine Presenters of Certificate.;
Further Proceedings on Assessments by Precepts to Constables, &amp;c. to warn Persons named therein to appear.; Oath not allowed on Inquiry into the Substance of Persons charged.; Persons named in the said Precept, called upon, not appearing.; Proviso for reasonable Excuse.; Panalty, Double Rate.; On Inquiry into the Substance of Persons charged, Commissioners may increase Taxation.; Spiritual Persons how rated for Temporal Possessions</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p324">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority of this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament That at the said day and place &bhopcrl;fixed and
limited in the said precept every of the said Commissioners then being in the Shire and not having sufficient excuse
for his absence at the day and place &bhopcrl;fixed for that part whereunto he was limited shall appeare in his owne proper
person and there the same Commissioners being &bhopcrl;sent or as many of them as shall be appointed by the Kings
Majesties Commission shall call or cause to be called before them the said Inhabitants and Officers to whom they have
directed theire said precepts and which had in commandment there to appeare by vertue of the said precept And
if any person so warned make default unlesse he then be letted by sicknes or lawfull excuse and that lett be then
witnessed by the Oathes of two credible persons which oath the said Commissioners or any two or more of them
shall have power by this a&bholigct; to administer or if any appearing refuse to serve in form following then every such
person so making default or refusing to serve shall forfeit to the Kings Majestie five pounds and so att every time
appointed by the said Commissioners for the said severall taxations untill such time as the number of every such
persons have appeared and certified in form underwritten every of them so making default or refusing to serve shall
forfeite to the Kings Majestie five pounds And upon the same appearance had they shall be charged before the
Commissioners by all convenient wayes and meanes other then by corporall oath to enquire of the value of the
substance after the usuall manner of every person dwelling and abiding within the limits of the places that they
shall be charged with and of other which shall have his or theire most resort unto any of the said places and
chargeable with any s&bhouov;m of money by this a&bholigct; and all other things requisite touching the said a&bholigct; and according
to the intent of the same and thereupon as neere as it may bee or shall come to theire knowledge without respe&bholigct; of
any former taxation heretofore had truly to present &amp; certifie before the said Commissioners the names and surnames
and the substance and values of every of them after the usuall manner as aforesaid as well of Lands Tenements Fees
Offices Tythes and other hereditaments possessions and proffits as well ecclesiasticall as temporall as of goods chattels
debts and other things chargeable by the same a&bholigct; without any concealment love favour affection dread or malice
upon paine of forfeiture of five pounds at the most to be taxed extra&bholigct;ed and levied in form as hereafter in this
&bhopcrl;sent a&bholigct;s shall be limited or appointed And thereupon the said Commissioners shall openly there read or cause to be
read unto them the said rates in this a&bholigct; mentioned and openly declare the effe&bholigct; of their charge unto them in what
manner and form they ought and should make theire certificates according to the rates and s&bhouov;ms thereof abovesaid
and of all manner of persons as well Aliens and Strangers Denizens or not Denizens inhabiting within this Realm as
of such Popish Recusants and other persons as be borne under the Kings obeysance chargeable to this a&bholigct; and of the
possessions Goods and Chattels of Fraternities Guilds Corporations Brotherhoods Mysteries Communalties and other
as is aforesaid and of persons being in the parts beyond the Seas having goods and chattells lands or tenements within
this Realm as is aforesaid and of all goods being in the custodie of any person or persons to the use of any other
as is aforesaid by the which information and shewing the said persons may have such plain knowledge of the true intent
of this &bhopcrl;sent a&bholigct; and of the manner of theire certificate that the same persons shall have no reasonable cause to excuse
them by ignorance And after such charge and the Statute concerning the said money to be raised and the manner of
the said Certificate to be made in writing containing the names and surnames of every person and whether he be born
without the Kings Dominions or within and the value of every person in every degree aswell of the yearely value of
Lands and Tenements and of such like possessions and proffits as of the value of Goods and Chattels Debts and every
thing to theire certificate requisite and necessary to them declared the said Commissioners there being shall by theire
discretions limit and appoint unto the said persons another day and place to appeare before the said Commissioners
and charging the said persons that they shall in the meane time make diligent enquiry by all wayes and meanes of the
&bhopcrl;misses and then and [theire<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] every of them upon pain of forfeiture of five pounds to the Kings Majestie to appeare
at the said next prefixed day and place there to certifie unto the said Commissioners in writing according to theire
said charge and according to the true intent of the said grant of the s&bhouov;ms of money aforesaid and to them
in manner aforesaid hath been declared and shewed by the Commissioners At which day and place so to them
&bhopcrl;fixed if any of the said persons make default or appear and refuse to make the said certificate then every of
them so offending to forfeit to the Kings Majestie five pounds (except there be a reasonable excuse of his
default by reason of his sicknes or otherwise by the Oathes of two credible persons there witnessed which Oathes
the said Commissioners or any two of them shall have power by this a&bholigct; to administer) And of such as
appeare ready to make certificate as is aforesaid the said Commissioners there being shall take and receive the
same certificate and every part thereof and the names values and substance of every person so certified And if
the said Commissioners see cause reasonable they shall examine the said Presenters thereof and thereupon the
said Commissioners at the said dayes and places by theire agreement amongst themselves shall from time to time
there openly &bhopcrl;fix a day att a certaine place or places within the limits of theire Commission by theire discretion
for theire further proceeding to the said assessing of the same s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money And thereupon at the
said day of the said Certificate as is aforesaid taken the same Commissioners shall make theire &bhopcrl;cept or &bhopcrl;cepts
to the Constables Subconstables Bailiffes or other Officers of such Hundreds Wapentakes Towns or: other places
aforesaid as the same Commissioners shall be of comprising and containing in the said precepts the names and
sirnames of all persons presented before them in the said Certificate of whom if the said Commissioners or as
many of them as shall be thereunto appointed by the Kings Commission shall then have vehement suspition to be
of greater value or substance in Lands Goods Chattels or s&bhouov;ms of money owing unto them or other substance
aforesaid then is upon such person or persons so certified and specified as aforesaid the same Commissioners
shall make theire precept or precepts directed to the Constables Bayliffes or other Officers commanding them to
whom such precepts shall be dire&bholigct;ed to warn such persons whose names shall be comprised in the said Precepts
at theire Mansions or to theire persons that the same persons named in such precepts and every of them shall
personally appeare before the said C&bhooov;mission[er]s at the said new &bhopcrl;fixed day and place there to be examined by
all wayes and meanes (other then by corporall oath) by the said Commissioners of theire substance and value
in manner as aforesaid and of all and every s&bhouov;ms of money owing to them and other whatsoever matter concerning
the &bhopcrl;misses or any of them according to this a&bholigct; At which day and place so &bhopcrl;fixed the said Commissioners
then and there being or as many of them as shall be thereunto appointed by the Kings Commission shall cause to
be called the said persons whose names shall be comprised in the said Precept [or<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] is aforesaid for theire examination
And if any of those persons which shall be warned as aforesaid to be examined which at any time after the
warning and before the day &bhopcrl;fixed shall be within such place as he may have knowledge of his said appearance
to be made shall make default and appeare not unlesse a reasonable cause or excuse by the Oathes of two
credible Witnesses before the said Commissioners which Oathes the said Commissioners or any two of them shall
have power by this a&bholigct; to administer be truly alledged for his discharge that then every of them so making
default to be taxed and charged with and at the double s&bhouov;m of the rate that he should or ought to have
beene set at for and after the value aforesaid of his lands or substance upon him certified if he had appeared
by the discretion of the Commissioners there being which Commissioners shall use theire best endeavors with
every of the other persons so then and [theire<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] appearing whose names shall be expressed in the said precept or
precepts and in whom any vehement suspicion was or shall be had in form aforesaid by all wayes and meanes
they can (other then by corporall Oath for theire better knowledge of theire value as aforesaid either in
hereditaments or possessions or else in goods or debts and thereupon shall have power and authority by vertue
of this a&bholigct; according to theire discretions to inlarge and increase the taxation of such persons as they shall [soe<ref idref="n42">42</ref>]
finde by due examination to be of greater value or substance in lands or goods then they were presented at
And that every spirituall person at every of the said taxations of the said s&bhouov;me or s&bhouov;ms of money shall be
rated and set according to the rate abovesaid of and for every pound that the same spirituall persons or any other
to his use hath in any Mannors Lands Tenements Rents Services Offices Fees Corodies Annuities Tithes and
Hereditaments ecclesiasticall or temporall as well in right of theire Churches as otherwise after the true just and
yearely value thereof and according as other the Kings Majesties subje&bholigct;s born within this Realm be charged
in form above remembred so the same extend to the yearely value of twenty shillings or above.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Assessors misbehaving;</head>
			<para id="p325">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may set a Fine upon them.; Such Fine to be certified and levied as other Sums under the a&bholigct;.; Remedy for Persons aggrieved by the Assessment.; Commissioners may abate or increase Assessment.; False Oath of Value of Lands, &amp;c.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p326">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed that if the said Taxers or Assessors shall not duly behave themselves in the inquiry
taxation assessment or certificate but shall affectionately corruptly or partially demeasne themselves in that behalfe
in such wise that the Commissioners shall by theire considerations deeme them offenders worthy of punishment
for not doeing theire duties therein that then four or more of the Commissioners in that County for the said s&bhouov;me
and s&bhouov;mes of money shall [have<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] power and authority by theire discretions either to charge the said Assessors upon
theire corporall Oathes for the better service aforesaid in that behalfe or else by theire discretion to tax and set
upon the said Assessors for theire misdemeanors in that behalfe such a fine or pain as they shall thinke good so
that it exceed not the s&bhouov;m of ten pounds and the same fine or pain at theire discretions to certifie to the persons
nominated as aforesaid Every which fine so taxed and set by four of the said Commissioners or more and being (<ref idref="n43">43</ref>)
with the Schedule and Book of that limit shall be leavyed and answered in like manner and form to all intents
and purposes as any other summs that shall be taxed and become due by vertue of this a&bholigct; and not in any otherwise
or manner And if any person certified or rated by vertue of this a&bholigct; whether he be a Commissioner or other to
any manner of value doth finde himselfe greived with the same presentment sessing or rating and thereupon
complain to the Commissioners before whom he shall be called sessed or taxed or before two of them before the
same taxation be certified in the Court of Exchequer that then the said Commissioners four or three of them shall
by all wayes and meanes examine particularly &amp; distinctly the person so complaining upon his Oath and other his
neighbors by theire discretions of every his Lands and Tenements above specified and of every his Goods Chattels
and debts above mentioned and after due examination and perfect knowledge thereof had and perceived by the said
Commissioners or three of them which shall have power by authority aforesaid the said Commissioners or any three
of them to whom any such complaint shall be made by theire discretions upon the Oath of the said persons so
complaining may abate defaulk increase or inlarge the said Assessments according as it shall appeare unto them just
upon the same examination and the same s&bhouov;m so abated defaulked increased or inlarged shall be by them certified in
form as is hereafter specified And if it be proved by witnesses or by the parties owne confession or other lawfull
wayes or meanes within a yeare after any such Oath made that the same person so rated and sworn was of any better
or greater value in lands goods or other things above specified at the time of his said Oath then the said person so
sworn did declare upon his [said<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] Oath that then every person so offending shall lose and forfeit to the Kings Majestie
so much lawfull money of England as he the same person so sworn was set at or taxed to pay.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Persons to be rated in the Counties, and in the several Places in Counties, where their Lands, &amp;c. lie.</head>
			<para id="p327">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by the same authority that every person to be rated and taxed as is aforesaid shall be
rated and set and the s&bhouov;m on him rated and set to be leavied in every county for the estate he hath either in Lands
tenements hereditaments rents annuities fees offices goods cattels or chattels [in that county only &amp; if he have an
estate either in Lands tenem[en]ts hereditam[en]ts rents a&bhonov;uities fees offices goods cattels or chattels<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] in severall places in one
county then to be rated in the said severall places in each severall County according to such his said estate in the
said severall places and the s&bhouov;m on him set to be there leavyed accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Lands let to Tenant for Life, Years, or at Will, for nearly the yearly Value; Person receiving the Rent to be charged; but, if let at under Value, the Charged to be apportioned between Landlord and Occupier, as the Taxers think meet.</head>
			<para id="p328">
				<emph type="i">Taxers doing wrong, Commissioners may rectify. ; Tenant unduly charged may retain out of his Rent,; or have his a&bholigct;ion of Debt.; Lands in several Counties, Hundreds, &amp;c. at one entire Rent, how charged. ; Debts owing within the Realm and beyond Sea to Persons within the Realm, to be charged at the Places of Abode at the Time of Taxation</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p329">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the Lands tenements [or<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] hereditaments of all and every
person or persons whatsoever of what degree or qualitie soever or in whose possession [soever<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] the same are shall be
rated charged and chargeable for and towards the raising and payment of the said Four hundred thousand pounds and
s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money aforesaid yet neverthelesse with this limitation and provision that if the land be set or let to
or neere the true yearely value thereof in the possession of any tenant for life lives yeares or at will such person or
persons to whom the rent thereof belongeth to be solely chargeable therewith but if the same be let at any easie or
small rent or under value then the sum taxed to be apportioned betweene the partie or parties to whom the rent
belongeth and the tenant or occupier of the Lands Tenements or hereditaments as the taxers shall thinke meet and
if they or any of them shall doe any injury the same to be rectified by the Commissioners according to theire
discretion And if any such tenant or occupier of Lands tenements or hereditaments shall or may be charged with
any s&bhouov;m of money contrary to the true intent and meaning of this a&bholigct; that it shall and may be lawfull to and for
such tenant or occupier to stop and detaine the same from and out of [this<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] rent due for the same Land or to take his
lawfull remedy against such person or persons to whom the said rent is or shall be due or belonging who ought by
the true meaning of this a&bholigct; to be charged therewith by action of Debt wherein no wager of law prote&bholigct;ion or
essoin shall be allowed And in case that any lands or hereditaments in severall Counties Hundreds Parishes or Places
shall be let or set for or charged with one entire rent or rents the owner of such rent or rents to be rated and charged
for the rent in each Countie Hundred parish or place proportionably and according to the value of the Lands or
hereditaments so let in every of the said Counties [Hundreds<ref idref="n47">47</ref>] Parishes and places and for all manner of debts whatsoever
or s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money due or owing to any person or persons by any person or persons within the Realm and
alsoe for any Debts goods or s&bhouov;ms of money remaining or being beyond the Seas out of his Majesties Dominions due
or belonging to any person or persons residing within England or Wales to be charged for the same in the place
of his residence or abode at the time of the taxation onely</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Proviso for Persons having two Mansions, or being Household Servants or Waiting Servants to the King or others.</head>
			<para id="p330">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners or Assessors unduly escaping Taxation,; charged at Treble Value</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p331">And be it ordained and ena&bholigct;ed by the authority of this present Parliament that no person having two Mansions
or two places to resort unto or calling himselfe houshold servant or waiting servant to the Kings Majestie or other
Lord or Lady Master or Mistresse be excused from the taxes of the said payments in any place or places where he may
be set or taxed And if any person that ought to [bet<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] set and taxed to the said payments by his coin craft
or by any words or sayings or otherwise or if any that is a Commissioner or Assessors of others happen to escape
from the said payments and be not set and taxed according to the true intent and meaning of this a&bholigct; and that proved
by presentment examination information or otherwise before the said Commissioners or two of them or before the
Barons of the Kings Majesties Exchequer or two Justices of the Peace of that County where such person dwelleth
then every such person that by such meanes or otherwayes willingly by covin or without just cause shall happen to
escape from the said taxations or payments aforesaid or any of them and shall not be rated taxed and set shall be charged
upon the knowledge and proofe thereof with and at the treble value of so much as he should might or ought to have
beene set or taxed at by vertue of this a&bholigct; and the same treble Value to be leavyed gathered and paid of his goods
and chattels lands and tenements towards the said payment</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Rates estreated under the Seal and Sign Manual of the Commissioners, and Estreat delivered to sufficient Inhabitants, &amp;c. of Hundreds, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p332">
				<emph type="i">By Authority of Estreat, Officers, &amp;c. to levy Rate.; Distress.; If Rate not paid in Eight Days, then Distress appraised and sold for Payment of Rate; Overplus to the Owner.;
Officers, &amp;c. to answer for the Portion limited to them only</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p333">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That after the taxes and assesses of the said sums upon
and by the said assessing and certificate as is aforesaid made the said Commissioners or as many of them as shall
be thereunto appointed and have authority by the Kings Majesties Commission shall with all speed and without
delay by their writing estreat the said taxes thereof under the Seales and Signes manuall of the said Commissioners
or as many of them as shall be appointed at the least And the same, shall deliver unto sufficient and substantiall
Inhabitants Constables Subconstables Bayliffes and other Officers joyntly of Hundreds Towns Parishes and other
places aforesaid within theire limits and to other sufficient persons inhabitants of the same onely by the discretion
of the said Commissioners with the assent of the High Colle&bholigct;ors and as the place and parties shall require as well
the particular names and sirnames as the remembrance of all s&bhouov;mes of money taxed and set of and upon
every person as well man as woman chargeable by this a&bholigct; housholders and all other Inhabitants and Dwellers
within the said Parishes Towns and places contributary to this a&bholigct; by authority of which writing and estreat so
delivered the said Officers and other persons so named and deputed severally shall have full power and authority
by vertue of this a&bholigct; immediately after the delivery of the said Writing or Estreat to demand leavie and gather
of every person therein specified the s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms in the same writing or estreat comprised and for [non<ref idref="n49">49</ref>] payment
thereof to distrain the same person or persons so being behind and the occupier or tenant of Lands tenements
or hereditaments chargeable by this a&bholigct; by his or theire goods and chattels and the distresse so taken to keepe
by the space of eight dayes at the costs and charges of the Owner thereof And if the said Owner do not pay
such s&bhouov;m of money as shall be taxed upon him or her by authority of this a&bholigct; within the same eight dayes
then the same distresse to be praised by four three or two of the Inhabitants where such distresse is taken and
also then to be sold by the Constable or other Colle&bholigct;or for the payment of the said money and the overplus
coming by the sale if any be over and besides the charge of keeping the said distresse to be upon demaund
restored to the Owner thereof which said Officers and other persons so deputed to aske take gather and leavie
the said s&bhouov;ms shall answer and be charged for the portion onely to them assigned and limited to be gathered
leavied and comprised in the said Writing or Estreat so to them as aforesaid delivered to the persons and uses
in the a&bholigct; expressed and the said s&bhouov;m in that writing or estreat to be comprised to pay [to<ref idref="n50">50</ref>] the High colle&bholigct;or
or Colle&bholigct;ors of that place in manner and form under written thereunto to be named and deputed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Commissioners to appoint colle&bholigct;ors;</head>
			<para id="p334">
				<emph type="i">to be High colle&bholigct;ors.; Commissioners to deliver Estreats indented under their Seals and Sign Manual to colle&bholigct;ors.; colle&bholigct;ors to answer the Sums comprized in Estreat</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p335">And further be it ena&bholigct;ed by the said Authority that such of the said Commissioners or the more part of them as
shall take upon them the execution and busines of the said Commission shall for the payment of the said moneys
name such sufficient and able persons in Shires Ridings Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Cities Towns corporate and other
whatsoever places as well within places priviledged as without not being foreprised in this a&bholigct; to be High colle&bholigct;ors
and to have the colle&bholigct;ion and receipt of the said s&bhouov;ms set and leviable within the &bhopcrl;cincts limits and bounds where
they shall be so limited and appointed to be High colle&bholigct;ors and to every of the said colle&bholigct;ors so severally
named the said Commissioners or two of them at the least with all speed and without delay after the said s&bhouov;ms
of money be set by all the limits of the same theire Commission or in such limits as the High colle&bholigct;ors shall
be so severally assigned shall under theire seales and signes manuall deliver one Estreat indented in parchment
comprising in it the names of all such persons as were assigned to leavy the said particular s&bhouov;ms of every Hundred
and Wapentake Town and other place aforesaid with the names and surnames of the persons so chargeable
according to the Estreat so hereof first made and delivered as is aforesaid And the colle&bholigct;ors to be assigned shall
be charged to answer the whole s&bhouov;m comprised in the said Estreat limited to his colle&bholigct;ion</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Commissioners to take Recognizances of High colle&bholigct;ors without Fee.</head>
			<para id="p336">
				<emph type="i">Condition of Recognizance.; Commissioners to certify.; Recognizances, &amp;c. into the Exchequer; Penalty &pound;10.; colle&bholigct;or not making Recognizance; Penalty &pound;20.; Exchequer to cancel Recognizances on Payment of colle&bholigct;ion into Exchequer without Fee.; colle&bholigct;or may appoint Days and Places for Payment of colle&bholigct;.; Assessors, &amp;c. not paying colle&bholigct; to High colle&bholigct;ors,; with Allowance of 1d. in the Pound of colle&bholigct;ion.; Distress.;
Proceedingsthereon</emph>.</para>
							<para id="p337">Provided alwaies And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said Commissioners having authority
by this a&bholigct; to nominate the High colle&bholigct;ors of the said moneys shall immediatly upon that nomination and
election take by authority of this present Parliament sufficient Recognizances or Obliga&bhocotil;ns without any fee or
reward to be paid therefore of every persons so by them to be named to be High colle&bholigct;ors to be bound to the
Kings Majestie in the double s&bhouov;m of the s&bhouov;m of his colle&bholigct;ion and to be endorsed and made upon such condi&bhocotil;n
that is to say for the due colle&bholigct;ion and payment of the moneys for and towards the first moyty of the said Foure
hundred thousand; pounds and s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms aforesaid that if the said colle&bholigct;or his heires or executors do truly
content and pay to the persons aforesaid at the [place<ref idref="n51">51</ref>] appointed by this a&bholigct; for payment thereof at or before the
twentieth day of July which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred fourty two so
much of the said s&bhouov;m of money allotted and appointed to his colle&bholigct; that he shall collect and gather and
content and pay the residue of his colle&bholigct;ion and charge within one moneth next after such time as he hath colle&bholigct;ed
and gathered the same residue that then the said recognizance or obliga&bhocotil;n to be void And for the colle&bholigct;ion of the
said latter payment for and towards the other moyetie or one halfe of the said Four hundred thousand pounds upon
condi&bhocotil;n that if the said Collectour his heires or executours doe truly content and pay to the persons aforesaid at
the places appointed by this a&bholigct; for payment thereof at or before the twentieth day of January which shall be in
the said yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred fourty two so much of the said s&bhouov;m of money allotted
and appointed to his colle&bholigct;ion as he shall colle&bholigct; and gather and content and pay the residue of his colle&bholigct;ion
and charge within one moneth next after such time as he hath collected and gathered the same residue that then
the said recognizance or Obliga&bhocotil;n to be void or else to stand in full force and vertue Which said severall and
respe&bholigct;ive recognizance or obliga&bhocotil;n soe taken the said Commissioners shall severally certifie and deliver into his
Majesties Court of Exchequer with the severall Certificates of the said taxations and rates of the said payments at
and by the times prescribed and appointed by this a&bholigct; for the certificate of the said taxations of the said payments
upon paine of forfeiture of ten pounds to the Kings Majestie for every recognizance or obliga&bhocotil;n not so certified
And that every such colle&bholigct;or so named and chosen upon request to him made shall acknowledge and make the
said recognizance or obliga&bhocotil;n upon pain of forfeiture of twenty pounds to the Kings Majestie for the refusall
thereof and that the Treasurer and Barons of the Exchequer for the time being upon payment of the said severall
colle&bholigct;ions of the said moneys at the dayes and times herein limited for the payment hereof shall cancell and deliver
the recognizances or obliga&bhocotil;ns for the payment thereof to the colle&bholigct;or or colle&bholigct;ors without any [other<ref idref="n52">52</ref>] Warrant
and without any fee or reward to be paid for the same to any person And every colle&bholigct;or soe deputed having the
said Estreat in parchment as is aforesaid shall have authoritie by this a&bholigct; to appoint dayes and places within the circuit
of his colle&bholigct;ion for the payment of the said moneys to him to be made and thereof to give warning by Proclamation
or otherwise to all the Constables or other persons or inhabitants having the charge of the particular colle&bholigct;ion within
the Hundreds Parishes Towns or other places by him or them limited to make payment of the said particular colle&bholigct;
of every s&bhouov;m as to them shall appertain And if at the same day and place so limited and &bhopcrl;fixed by the said High
colle&bholigct;or the said Constable Officers or other persons or inhabitants as is aforesaid for the said particular colle&bholigct;ion
assigned and appointed within such Hundred Citie Town or other place doe not pay unto the said High colle&bholigct;or the
s&bhouov;m within theire severall Hundreds Towns Parishes and other Places due &amp; comprised in the said Estreat thereof to
them delivered by the said Commissioners or some of them as is aforesaid or so much thereof as they have by any
meanes received (one peny for every pound for the said particular colle&bholigct;ion as is aforesaid alwaies thereof to be
allowed excepted and abated) that then it shall be lawfull for the said High colle&bholigct;ors and every of them and for
theire assignes to distreine every of the said Constables Officers and other Inhabitants for theire said severall and
particular colle&bholigct;ion of the said s&bhouov;ms comprised in the said Estreat and Writing thereof to them and every of them
as is before expressed delivered or for so much of the same s&bhouov;m as so then shall happen to be gathered and
leavied and behinde and unpaid by the goods and chattels of every of them so being behind and the distresse so
taken to be kept and appraised and sold as is aforesaid and thereof to take and leavy the s&bhouov;ms so then being
behinde and unpaid and the overplus coming of the sale of the said distresse (if any be) to be restored and
delivered unto the Owner in form above remembred.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Assessors, Attornies, Fa&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. after being charged with Receipt of Assessment, dying, or removing or concealing their Goods; or when Monies comprized in Estreat cannot be levied by Distress;</head>
			<para id="p338">
				<emph type="i">or where Distress cannot be sold; colle&bholigct;or, &amp;c. discharged, and Process out of the Exchequer, and the Commissioners may direct Precepts to Officer to levy such Money.; Who may distrain.; Distress kept, appraised and sold.; If Distress taken out of Limits assigned, Allowance.; Persons charged discharged by Distress.; Persons distrained having no Lands, &amp;c.;
Proceedings.; Imprisonment until Sums due, and also Fee for Arrest, paid.; Officer not executing Process,; Penalty 20s.; Gaoler suffering Escape,; Penalty 40s. and double Value of Rate and Fees.; Like Process for Subsidies due by any Persons charged for another unpaid.; In Default of Payment,; Imprisonment.; Certificate by Commissioners.; colle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. disobeying Commissioners,; and Persons suspected to be not indifferently taxed, refusing to appear or be examined, or resisting, &amp;c.; Penalty 40s. or under, at Discretion of Commissioners. ; Commissioners may punish by Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p339">And be it alsoe by the said authority ena&bholigct;ed that if any inhabitants or officers or whatsoever other person or
persons charged to and for the colle&bholigct;ion and Receipt of any part or portion of the said payments by any manner
of meanes according to this a&bholigct; or any person or persons for themselves or as Keeper Guardian Deputy Factor
or Attorney of or for any other person or persons for any goods or chattels of the Owner thereof at the time of
the said assessing to be paid being out of this Realme or in any other parts not knowne or of or for the goods
and chattels of any other person or persons of any corporation fraternity mystery or other whatsoever communalty
being corporate or not corporate and all persons having in theire rule governance and custody any goods or
chattels at the time of the said assessing to be made or which for any cause for or by colle&bholigct;ion or for himselfe
or for any other or by reason he hath any rule governance and custody of any goods or chattels of any other
person or persons corporation communalty fraternity guild or mystery or any such other like or as Factor Deputy
or Attorney of or for any person shall be taxed valued rated and set to any s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms by reason of this
a&bholigct; And if after the taxation and assessing upon any such person or persons as shall be charged with the Receipt
of the same happen to dye or depart from the place where he was so taxed and set or his goods or chattels to
be so eloyned or in such privy or covert manner kept as the same person or persons charged with the same by
Estreats or other Writings from the said Commissioners or as many of them as shall be thereunto appointed by
the said Commission as is aforesaid can ne may leavy the same s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms comprised within the same Estreats
by distresse within the limits of their colle&bholigct;ion as is aforesaid or cannot sell such distresse or distresses as be taken
for any the said payments before the time limited to the high colle&bholigct;or for his payment to be made as is afores[aid]
then upon rela&bhocotil;n thereof with due examination by the oath or examina&bhocotil;n of such person or persons as shall be
charged with or for the receipt and colle&bholigct;ion of the same before the said Commissioners or as many of them as
by the same Commission shall be thereunto appointed where such person or persons or other as is aforesaid theire
goods and chattels were set and taxed and upon plain certificate thereof made by the said Commissioners as well
of the dwelling place names and s&bhouov;ms of the said persons of whom the said s&bhouov;ms cannot be leavied and had as is
aforesaid then as well the Constables and other Inhabitants appointed for the same particular colle&bholigct;ion against the
High colle&bholigct;or as the high colle&bholigct;or upon his Accompt and Oath in the said Exchequer to be discharged thereof
and processe to be made in the Kings [Majestie<ref idref="n53">53</ref>] name out of the same Exchequer by the dire&bholigct;ion of the Barons
of the same Exchequer against such person his heires or executors so being behind with his payment And over
that the same Commissioners to whom any such declaration of the premisses shall be made in form aforesaid from
time to time shall have full power and authority to direct theire precept or precepts to the said person or persons
charged with any s&bhouov;m of for and upon any such person or persons or other as is aforesaid or to any Sheriffe
Steward Bailiffe or other whatsoever Officer Minister person or [persons<ref idref="n54">54</ref>] of such place or places where any such
person or persons so owing any such s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms shall have Lands and Tenements and other Hereditaments or
reall possessions goods and chattels whereby any such person or persons so indebted his heires executors or assignes
or other having the custody governance or disposition of any goods or chattels lands tenements or other
hereditaments which ought or may by this a&bholigct; be lawfully distreined or taken for the same hath and shall have Goods
Chattels Lands Tenements or other possessions whereof such sum and s&bhouov;ms which by any such person or persons
may or ought to be leavyed be it within the limits of such Commission where such person or persons was or
were taxed or without in any place within this realm of England Wales or other the Kings Majesties Dominions
Marches or Territories by which Precept as well such person or persons shall be charged to leavie such Money as
the Officer of the place or places where such distresse may be taken shall have full power and authority to distrein
every such person indebted charged or chargeable by this a&bholigct; or his executors or administrators of his goods
and chattels his guardians Factors deputies lessees farmours and assignes and all other persons by whose hands or out
of whose Lands any such [persons<ref idref="n55">55</ref>] should have fee rent annuity or other profit or which at the time of the said
assessing shall have goods or chattels or any other thing moveable of any such person or persons being indebted
or owing such s&bhouov;m and the distresses so taken cause to be kept appraised and sold in like manner and forme as
is aforesaid for the distresse to be taken upon such persons to be taxed to the said Payments and being sufficient
to distrein within the limits of the colle&bholigct;ors Inhabitants or other Officers charged with or for the said s&bhouov;ms so
upon them to be taxed And if any such distresse for non payment happen to be taken out of the limit of the
said persons charged and assigned to leavy the said sums as aforesaid the said persons so charged for the leavying
of any such s&bhouov;ms by distresse shall perceive and take of the same distresse for the labour of every person going
for the execu&bhocotil;n thereof for every mile that every person so laboureth for the same two pence And every farmour
Guardian Tenant factour or other whatsoever person being distreined or other person charged for payment of any
such s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms or any other s&bhouov;m by reason of this a&bholigct; shall be of such s&bhouov;ms of him or them so leavied and
taken discharged and acquitted at his next day of payment for the same or at the delivery of such goods and chattels
as he that is so distreined had in his custody or governance against him or them that shall be so taxed and set
([any<ref idref="n55">55</ref>] grant or writing obligatory or other whatsoever matter to the contrary made heretofore notwithstanding) And if
any such person that should be so distreined have no lands or tenements sufficient whereby he and his tenants and
farmours may be distreined or have aliened [or<ref idref="n56">56</ref>] eloyned his goods and chattels whereby he should or might be
distreined in such manner that such goods or chattels cannot be knowne or found so that the s&bhouov;m by him to be
paid in the said forme shall not neither can be conveniently leavied then upon rela&bhocotil;n thereof to the Commissioners
or to as many of them as by the said Commission shall be thereunto appointed where such person or persons was
taxed and set by the Oathes of him or them that shall be charged with the leavying and payment of that sum
or Sums the same Commissioners shall make a precept in such manner as is aforesaid for to attach take and arrest
the body of such person or persons that ought to pay the said s&bhouov;ms and by this a&bholigct; shall be charged with and
for the said s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms and them so taken safely to keepe in prison within the shire or other place where
any such person or persons shall be taken and attached there to remaine without bail or mainprise untill he have
paid the said s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms that such persons for himselfe or for any other by this a&bholigct; shall be chargeable or ought
to be charged withall and alsoe for the Fees of every such arrest to him or them that shall execute such precept
twentie pence And that every Officer unto whom such precept shall be directed do his true diligence and execute
the same upon every person so being indebted upon pain to forfeit to the Kings Majestie for every default in that
behalfe twenty shillings And that no Keeper of any Goal from his Goal suffer any person to go at large by
letting to bail or otherwise to depart out of his prison before he hath paid the said debt and the said twentie
pence for his arrest upon pain to forfeite to the Kings Majestie fourtie shillings And the said Gaoler to pay to the
Kings Majestie the double value aswell of the rate which the said person so imprisoned was taxed at as of the said
twenty pence for the fees and like Processe &amp; remedy in like manner and forme shall be granted by the said
Commissioners or as many of them as by the said Commission shall be thereunto appointed at like informa&bhocotil;n of
every person or persons being charged with any s&bhouov;m of money for any other person or persons by reason of the
said payments and not thereof paid but wilfully withdrawne nor the same [leavied<ref idref="n57">57</ref>] within the limits where such
persons were thereunto taxed And if the s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms being behind &amp; unpaid by any person or persons as is aforesaid
be leavied &amp; gathered by force of the said processe to be made by the said Commissioners or if in default or for
lack of payment thereof the person or persons so owing the said s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of Money by processe of the (<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) same
Commissioners to be made as is aforesaid be committed to prison in form abovesaid that then the said Commissioners
which shall award such processe shall make Certificate of that shall be done in the premisses after such sum
or sums of money so being behind shall be leavied and gathered of such person or persons for non payment
of the same committed to prison And if it happen any of the said colle&bholigct;ors to be assigned or any Maiors Sheriffs
Stewards Constables Headboroughs Bursholders Bailiffes or any other Officer or Minister or other whatsoever person
or persons to disobey the said C&bhooov;missioners or any of them in the reasonable request to them made by the said
Commissioners for the execution of the said Commission or if any of the Officers or other Persons doe refuse that
to them shall appertain and belong to do by reason of any Precept to him or them to be dire&bholigct;ted or any reasonable
commandment instance or request touching the premisses or other default in any appearance or colle&bholigct;ion to make
or if any person being suspe&bholigct;ed not to be indifferently taxed as is aforesaid do refuse to be examined according
to the tenour of this a&bholigct; before the said Commissioners or as many of them as shall be thereunto assigned as is
aforesaid or will not appeare before the same Commissioners upon warning to him made or else make resistance or
rescues upon any distresse upon him to be taken for any parcell of the said s&bhouov;ms or payments or commit any
misdemeanour in any manner of wise contrary to this a&bholigct; or commit any wilfull omission or other whatsoever wilfull
doeing or misdoing contrary to the tenour of this a&bholigct; or Grant the same Commissioners and every number of them
above remembred or three of them at the least upon certaine knowledge of any such misdemeanour had by information
or examination shall and may set upon every such offender for every such offence in the name of a fine by the
same offender to be forfeited fourtie shillings or under by discretion of the same Commissioners And further the
said Commissioners and every number of them or three of them at the least shall have authoritie by this present
a&bholigct; to punish every such offender by imprisonment there to remaine and to be delivered by theire discretions as
shall seeme to them convenient the said Fines (if any such bee) to be certified by the said Commissioners that so
assessed the same into the Kings Majesties Exchequer to be leavied and paid by the colle&bholigct;ors of that part for
the said payments returned into the said Exchequer to be therewith charged with the payment of the same in
such manner as if the said Fines had beene set and taxed upon the said Offenders for the said payments</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Allowance to High colle&bholigct;ors and their Accountants.</head>
			<para id="p340">
				<emph type="i">Allowance to be paid by colle&bholigct;ors to Commissioners for Expences and Labour of their Clerks.; Remedy for the same for Commissioners against colle&bholigct;ors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p341">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by the said authority of this present Parliament that every of the said high colle&bholigct;ors
which shall accompt for any part of the said payments upon their severall accompts to be yeelded shall be
allowed upon payment of the money chargeable upon his colle&bholigct;ion for every pound limited to his colle&bholigct;
whereof any such colle&bholigct;or shall be charged and yeeld accompt three pence [as<ref idref="n59">59</ref>] parcell of theire charge (that is to say)
of every pound thereof for such persons as then have had the particular colle&bholigct;ion of the towns and other places
(as is aforesaid) specified in his colle&bholigct;ion one peny and one other peny of every pound thereof (every of the said
cheife colle&bholigct;ors or theire accomptants to retaine to theire owne use for theire labour and charge in and about the
premisses and one peny of every pound residue to be delivered allowed and paid by the said colle&bholigct;or so being
thereof allowed to such of the Commissioners as shall take upon them the busines and labour for and about the
premisses) that is to say Every colle&bholigct;or to pay that Commissioner or Commissioners which had the ordering of the
writing of and for the said payments where the said colle&bholigct;or or colle&bholigct;ors had theire colle&bholigct;ion for the
expences for the said Commissioners so taking upon them the said busines and labour of theire Clerks writing,
the said precepts and extracts of the said colle&bholigct;ions the said last peny of every pound to be divided amongst
the said Commissioners having regard to theire labour and busines taken by them and theire said Clerks in and about
the premisses For which part so (<ref idref="n60">60</ref>) the said Commissioners appertaining the said Commissioners six five foure or three
or as many of them as shall be thereunto appointed by the Kings Majesties Commission and every of them
joyntly and severally for his and theire said part may have his remedie against the colle&bholigct;or or colle&bholigct;ors which
thereof beene or might have beene allowed by action of debt in which the defendant shall not wage his lawe neither
prote&bholigct;ion neither injun&bholigct;ion neither essoin shall be allowed And the said Treasurers and Receivers appointed by
this a&bholigct; for the said Four hundred thousand pounds and other s&bhouov;ms or as many of them as shall take upon them the
busines and labour in receiving and issuing out of the said moneys shall have one halfe peny in every pound so by
them received and issued out for theire paines in that behalfe the same to be dedu&bholigct;ed out of the [said<ref idref="n61">61</ref>] s&bhouov;ms so
by them to be received as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. No Member of Parliament or Commissioner to be named colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
			<para id="p342">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners not compellable to make Presentments other than to Exchequer.; Persons assigned to be Commissioners not to be named Head colle&bholigct;ors.; Head colle&bholigct;ors acquitted of Fees.; Taking Fees of Accountants; Penalty.; Imprisonment.; Commissioners at Meetings to shew Certificates and Presentments to the other Commissioners.; Indenture of colle&bholigct;ors Names, and of Sums written to colle&bholigct;ors, Fines, &amp;c. to be certified by Commissioners into the Exchequer.; colle&bholigct;ors answerable for their own colle&bholigct; only.; Commissioners, if they cannot agree, &amp;c. may make several Indentures.; colle&bholigct;ors answerable for their own colle&bholigct; only; and upon Payment to be discharged in the Exchequer without Fee Penalty.; Commissioners or colle&bholigct;ors or Persons taxed dying before discharged, Heirs and Executors chargeable as such Persons would have been if alive.;
And Persons having in their Custody Real or Personal Estates of Persons dead to answer as if such Persons were living.; Commissioners not thinking fit to join in one Certificate,; Proceedings.; Commissioners making Default of Certificate, Process out of Exchequer against them</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p343">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed that no person now being a member of this present Parliament nor any Commissioner
shall be named or assigned to be any colle&bholigct;or Subcolle&bholigct;or or Presenter of the said Payments or any part
thereof nor any Commissioner shall be compelled to make any presentment or certificate other then into the
Kings Majesties said Exchequer of for or concerning the said payments or any part or parcell thereof And likewise
that no other person that shall be named and assigned to be Commissioners in any place to and for the execution
of this a&bholigct; for the raising of money be or shall be assigned or named Head colle&bholigct;or of either of the said
payments neither of any part thereof And that every such person &amp; persons which shall be nominated and
appointed as is aforesaid to be Head colle&bholigct;ors of and for the payment of the said Four hundred thousand pounds
and s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money payable by vertue of this a&bholigct; or of any part thereof be and shall be acquitted and
discharged of all manner of fees and rewards and of every other charge in the Kings Majesties Exchequer or elsewhere
of them or any of them by reason of that colle&bholigct;ion payment or account or any thing concerning the same to be
asked And that if any person receive or take any fees rewards or pleasures of any such accomptants or use any
unnecessary delay in theire accompt that then he shall forfeite to the Kings Majesty for every peny or value of
every peny so taken five shillings and five pounds to the party greived for every such delay and suffer
imprisonment at the Kings Majesties pleasure And after every taxing and assessing of the [said<ref idref="n61">61</ref>] s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms
of money aforesaid had or made and the said extra&bholigct;s thereof in parchment unto the colle&bholigct;or in manner and
forme before rehearsed delivered the said Commissioners which shall take upon them the execution of this a&bholigct;
within the limits of theire said Commission by theire Agreements shall have meetings togeather At which meetings
every of the said Commissioners which then shall have taken upon them the execution of any part of the said
Commission shall by himselfe or his sufficient deputy truly certifie and bring forth unto the said Commissioners
named in the said Commission the certificate and presentment made before him and such other Commissioners
as were limited with him in one limit (so as the same certificate may be accompted &amp; cast with the other
certificates of the other limits within the same Commission) and then the said Commissioners and every number
of them unto three at the least as is aforesaid if any be in life or theire executors or administrators of theire
goods if they then be dead shall joyntly and severally as they were divided within their limits under their Seales by
theire discretions make one or severall writings indented containing in it aswell the names of the said colle&bholigct;ors by
the Commissioners for such colle&bholigct;ions and accompts in the Exchequer and payments assigned as the grosse and
severall s&bhouov;ms written unto every such colle&bholigct;ors to receive the said payments and also all fines amerciaments and
other forfeitures if any such be by reason of this a&bholigct; as shall happen [to be<ref idref="n62">62</ref>] within the limit and &bhopcrl;cinct of theire
Commission to be certified into the Kings Majesties Exchequer by the said Commissioners in which writing or
writings indented so to be certified shall be plainly declared and expressed the whole and entire sum and sums
of the said payments severally limited to the colle&bholigct;ion of the said colle&bholigct;ors severally deputed and assigned to the
said Sums so as none of the said colle&bholigct;ors so certified in the said Exchequer shall be compelled there to accompt
or be charged but only to and for the s&bhouov;ms limited to his colle&bholigct;ion and not to or for any sum limited to the
colle&bholigct;ion of his fellowes but every of them shall be severally charged for theire part limited to theire colle&bholigct;ion
And if the said Commissioners joyned in any one Commission amongst themselves in that matter cannot agree or if any
of them be not ready or refuse to make certificate with the other of the same Commissioners that then the said
Commissioners may make severall Indentures in form aforesaid of theire severall limits or separations of colle&bholigct;ors
within the limits of theire Commission upon and in the Hundreds Wards Wapentakes Lathes Rapes or other such
like divisions within the said severall limits of theire Commission as the places there shall require to be severed
and divided and as to the same Commissioners shall seeme good to make divisions or other limits or colle&bholigct;ions
for the severall charges of the same colle&bholigct;ors so that alway one colle&bholigct;or shall be charged and accompt for his
part to him to be limited onely by himselfe and not for any Sum limited to the part of any of his fellowes and the
charges of every of the colle&bholigct;ors to be set and certified severally upon them and every such colle&bholigct;or upon his
accompt and payment of the sum of Money limited within his colle&bholigct;ion to be severally by himselfe acquitted and
discharged in the said Exchequer without paying any manner of fees or rewards to any person or persons for the
same upon pain and penaltie last abovesaid and not to be charged with or for any portion of any other colle&bholigct;ors And
if any Commissioner after he hath taken certificate of them that as is aforesaid shall before any Commissioners
examined and the s&bhouov;ms rated and set and the bookes and writings thereof being in his hands or if any colle&bholigct;or or
other person charged with any receipt of any part of the said Four hundred thousand pounds or other s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms
of money payable by this a&bholigct; or any other person taxed or otherwise by this a&bholigct; charged with or for any parcell
of the said s&bhouov;m of Four hundred thousand pounds or other s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money payable by this a&bholigct; or with any
other s&bhouov;m fine amerciament penaltie or other forfeiture happen to die before the Commissioners colle&bholigct;ors or
other whatsoever person or persons have executed accomplished satisfied or sufficiently discharged that which to every
such person shall appertain or belong to do according to this a&bholigct; then the executors administrators and heires of
every such person and all other seised of any lands or tenements that any such person being charged by this a&bholigct; and
deceasing before he be discharged thereof or any other to his use onely had of an estate of inheritance at the time
that any such person was named Commissioner colle&bholigct;or or otherwise charged with or for any manner of thing to
be done satisfied or paid by reason of this a&bholigct; And all those that have in theire possession or hands any goods
chattels leases or other things that were to any such person or persons at the time of his death or any lands or
tenements that were the same persons at the time that he was as [is<ref idref="n63">63</ref>] aforesaid charged by this a&bholigct; shall be by the same
compelled and charged to do and accomplish in every case as the same person so being charged should have done or
ought have been compelled to do if he had beene in plene life after such rate of the Lands and Goods of the said
Commissioner and colle&bholigct;or as the partie shall have in his hands And if the said Commissioners for causes reasonable
then moving shall thinke it not fit to joyn in one certificate as is aforesaid then the said person or persons that
shall first joyne togeather or he that shall first certifie the said writing indented as is aforesaid shall certifie all
the names of the Commissioners of that Commission whereupon such writing shall be there then to be certified with
the divisions of the Hundreds Wapentakes Wards Tithings and other places to and [among<ref idref="n64">64</ref>] other such Commissioners
of the same Commission with the names of the said Commissioners where such eparations and divisions shall be
with the grosse s&bhouov;ms of money as well of and for the said s&bhouov;ms of money taxed or set of or within the said
Hundreds Wards Wapentakes or other places to him or them divided or assigned that shall so certifie the said first
writing as of the fines amerciaments penalties and other forfeitures if any happen to be within the same limits
whereof the same writing shall be certified And after such writings indented which as is aforesaid shall be certified
and not contain in it the whole s&bhouov;ms set and taxed within the limits of the same C&bhooov;mission the other Commissioners
of the same before the day of payment of the said s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money shall certifie into the said Exchequer
by their writing or writings indented to be made as is aforesaid the grosse and severall sums set and taxed within
the places to them limited for every of the said payments and other fines amerciaments penalties &amp; forfeitures
with the names of the Hundreds Wards Wapentakes and other places to them assigned or else by theire said
Writings indented to certifie at the same place before the same day of payment such reasonable causes for theire
excuses why they may not make such certificate of and for the said s&bhouov;ms of money fines amerciaments and other
forfeitures growing or set by reason of the causes of theire lets or of theire not certifying as is aforesaid or else
in default thereof processe to be made out of the Kings Majesties said Exchequer against the said Commissioners
and every of them not making Certificate as is aforesaid by the discretion of the Treasurer and Barons of the
said Exchequer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Proviso for Stamford Baron.</head>
			<para id="p344">Provided alwaies And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the Inhabitants of the parish of Saint
Martin called Stamford Baron in the suburbs of the Town and Borough of Stamford in the south part of the
Waters there called Wellands which hereafter shall be contributary towards the said payments shall be assessed
rated and taxed for the same by such commissioners which shall be appointed as aforesaid for the taxing rating and
assessing the same payments within the County of Lincoln and shall be for the same contributary and pay to the
colle&bholigct;or or colle&bholigct;ors which shall be assigned and appointed for the leavying and gathering of the same as
aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Proviso for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey, and Guernsey.</head>
			<para id="p345">Provided alwaies That this a&bholigct; or any thing therein contained in any wise extend not to charge the Inhabitants
of Scotland Ireland Jersey and Garnesey or any of them of for or concerning any Mannors Lands Tenements or
other possessions goods chattels or other moveable substance which the said Inhabitants or Dwellers or any others
to theire use have within Scotland Ireland Jersey and Garnesey or in any of them for or concerning any fees or wages
which any of the said inhabitants and dwellers have of the Kings Majestie for theire attendance and doing service to
our Soveraigne Lord the Kings Majestie in Scotland Ireland Jersey &amp; Garnesey or any of them Any thing in this
present a&bholigct; to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Patents of Liberties, &amp;c. to Cities, &amp;c. to be good, although charged by this a&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p346">Provided alsoe That all Letters Patents granted by the Kings Majestie or any of his noble Progenitors to any Cities
Boroughs or Towns within this Realm of any manner of Liberties Priviledges or Exemptions from the burthen and
charge of any a&bholigct; or grant of subsidies which be at this present time in force and available shall remaine good and
effectuall to the said Cities Boroughs &amp; Towns hereafter according to the purports thereof although the Inhabitants
of the same and alsoe the said Corporations shall upon the great and weighty considerations of the Grant aforesaid
be by this a&bholigct; charged and contributarie in like manner form and sort as other Cities Boroughs and Towns which
be not in any wise priviledged but by this a&bholigct; charged.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Proviso for Orphans and Infants.</head>
			<para id="p347">Provided alwaies And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that no [Orphane<ref idref="n65">65</ref>] or Infant within the age of one
and twenty yeares borne within any the Kings Majesties Dominions shall be charged to the payment of any moneys
by vertue of this a&bholigct; for his or theire goods or chattels to him or her left or bequeathed Any thing in this a&bholigct;
contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Alien or Denizen assigning his Lands, &amp;c. to his Child, with Intent to defraud the Subsidy, such Child chargeable as an Alien.</head>
			<para id="p348">Provided neverthelesse And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any Alien or Stranger born
Denizen or not Denizen and dwelling and inhabiting within this Realm of England shall assigne and convey over unto
any his or theire childe or children borne within the said Realm of England his or their Lands Tenements Goods or
Chattels to the intent thereby to defraud or safeguard themselves of or from the payment of the s&bhouov;ms of money
aforesaid or any part thereof that then all and every such childe or children soe being seized of any such lands
and tenements or possessed of any such goods or chattels shall be charged and chargeable to and with the payment of
double the said s&bhouov;ms of money for the lands tenements goods and chattels at the said rates and values as Aliens
and Strangers denizens or not denizens are before limited and appointed to pay</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Proviso for Berwick-upon-Tweed.</head>
			<para id="p349">Provided alwaies That the said Grant of and for the s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money aforesaid or any clause matter or
thing whatsoever herein contained shall not in any wise extend or be construed to extend to charge the Town or
Borough of Berwicke upon Tweed or any the Inhabitants or Resiants thereof with any the payments herein before
mentioned for any theire Lands Goods or Chattels within the said Town or Borough but that the said Town or
Borough of Barwick upon Tweed and alsoe all and every the Resiants and Inhabitants of and within the same
be and shall be of and from the said grant and payments and every part thereof cleerly acquitted and discharged
for any theire said Lands Goods and Chattels as aforesaid Any matter or thing whatsoever in this present a&bholigct; had
or made to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. The Lord Mayor, Aldermen, and Chamberlain of London to repay out of the said &pound;400,000. Monies lent or engaged to be paid by the Public Faith, with Interest at &pound;8. per Cent. per Ann. in such Manner as the Commissioners herein named shall, under theire Hands, appoint.</head>
			<para id="p350">
				<emph type="i">Warrant of the said Commissioners to be a Discharge to the Treasurers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p351">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority of this present Parliament That the said Sir Richard Gurney Knight
and Baronet Lord Maior of the Citie of London Sir John Cordall Sir Thomas Soame Sir John Gayer Sir Jacob
Garret Alderman Atkins Alderman Pennington Sir John Wollaston Alderman Adams Alderman Warner Master
Samuel Vassell Master John Venn the Chamberlain of the City of London for the time being and other persons by
this present a&bholigct; of Parliament constituted and ordained to be Treasurers and Receivers of the said Four hundred
thousand pounds and other s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money payable by this a&bholigct; the Survivors and survivor of them
respe&bholigct;ively shall and may satisfie pay and deliver out of the said Four hundred thousand pounds and other s&bhouov;m
and s&bhouov;ms aforesaid unto all and every County Place person or persons who have lent or advanced or to whom
any moneys are or shall be due arreare or owing and for the payment whereof both Houses of Parliament or the
House of Commons onely is are or shall be engaged by any a&bholigct; or Order of publique faith all and every such
s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money which shall be soe due arreare or unpaid so far as the said Four hundred thousand
pounds and other s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms granted by this a&bholigct; shall extend to together with such other and further s&bhouov;m
and s&bhouov;ms of money as the damages of and for the said s&bhouov;ms so lent or advanced due arreare or owing shall
amount unto after the rate of eight pounds per centum for a yeare from the day and time that the same was
laid out and advanced or did or shall become due and payable untill they shall respe&bholigct;ively have received the said
s&bhouov;ms so disbursed due or payable in such manner &amp; forme as William Earle of Bedford William Marquesse of
Hertford Robert Earle of Essex William Earle of Salisbury Robert Earle of Warwick Henry Earle of Holland Thomas
Earle of Berkshire Henry Earle of Stamford Francis Lord Dacres Philip Lord Wharton William Lord Pagett Robert
Lord Brooke Edward Mountague Lord of Kimbolton John Lord Pawlet Edward Lord Howard of Escrick Francis
Leigh Lord Dunsmore or any four or more of them Denzill Hollis Esquire John Pym Esquire Sir Christopher
Wray Knight Sir John Hotham Baronet Thomas Lord Wenman Sir Christopher Yelverton Knight William Cage
Esquire Henry Martin Esquire Sir Dudley North Knight Sir Thomas [Bower<ref idref="n66">66</ref>] Baronet Sir Edward Aiscough Knight
Sir John Culpeper Knight Chancellor of his Majesties Court of Exchequer Sir Robert Crane Knight and Baronet
John Hampden Esquire Sir Edmund Munford Sir Walter Earle Sir Arthur Ingram Knights Sir Gilbert Gerrard
Baronet Sir Guy Palmes Knight Sir Samuel Owfield Knight Sir Henry Vane junior Knight Sir Hugh Cholmeley
Knight Harbottell Grimston Esquire Sir Philip Stapleton Knight Sir Edward Hales Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas
Widdrington Knight Thomas Lord Gray Sir Norton Knatchbull Knight and Baronet Edmund Waller Esquire Henry
Lord Gray of Ruthyn or any eight or more of them and so proportionably in such manner and quality by any one
or more writing or writings under theire hands during this Parliament shall limit appoint and declare And that the
Warrant [and<ref idref="n67">67</ref>] Warrants of the said Commissioners before named for the issuing out of the said moneys or of such
number of them as before is expressed proportionably togeather with the Acquittance and Acquittances from the
person or persons which shall be appointed as aforesaid by the said Commissioners or of such number of them
proportionably as before is expressed for receipt of the said s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money according to this a&bholigct; shall
be a sufficient discharge to the Treasurers in this a&bholigct; named for so much money as shall be comprehended in
such acquittance or acquittances for the issuing out and payment of the said s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money respe&bholigct;ively</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Treasurers not to pay any Money upon any other Warrant.</head>
			<para id="p352">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said Treasurers shall not at all pay any s&bhouov;m or
s&bhouov;ms of money to be by them received upon any other dire&bholigct;ion warrant or command whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. The colle&bholigct;ors for Yorkshire and other Places herein named to pay their colle&bholigct;ions to the Lord Mayor and certain Aldermen of York at the Chamber of York, towards Payment of Billet Money due to the Inhabitants, and of Money due from Parliament to the Counties of Durham and Northumberland, City of Durham, and Newcastle-upon-Tyne.</head>
			<para id="p353">Provided alwaies And be it ena&bholigct;ed and declared that all and every colle&bholigct;or or colle&bholigct;ors of the severall
Counties of Yorke Cumberland Westmerland Northumberland the County Palatine of Durham the Town of
Newcastle upon Tyne the Citie of Durham Nottingham the County and Town of Nottingham the County Palatine
of Chester the County of the City of Chester the County Palatine of Lancaster Lincolneshire the County and City
of Lincolne Darbyshire Staffordshire the County of the City of Litchfeild the City of Yorke and County of the same
and the Town and County of Kingston upon Hull shall pay all and every the s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money by him
or them collected or received by vertue of this a&bholigct; to the Lord Maior of the City of Yorke for the time being
and to Thomas Hodshon Henry Tompson and William Scott Aldermen of the said Citie at the Chamber in the said
City of Yorke for and towards the payment of Billet money due and owing to the severall Inhabitants of
Yorkeshire and the Counties adjacent for the billetting of his Majesties late Army as also for and towards the payment
of such moneys as are due and owing by the Parliament to the Counties of Durham and Northumberland and
the City of Durham and Town of Newcastle upon Tyne Any thing in this &bhopcrl;sent a&bholigct; to the contrary in any
wise notwithstanding</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">&amp; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Moiety <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Purefry <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Moulworth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Dissington <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Dencell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">Knights <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">Lampton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Fane <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">K<emph type="p">t</emph> &amp; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">Locke <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">Sonds <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">Aston <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">Scamler <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">Anyou <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">Hutchison <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">Unton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">Chorleton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">Lisley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">Worstley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">Bockenham <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">Sucklemor <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">Aldes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">Bailiffe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">Sir Edward Berkley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">Pritherich <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">Hugh <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">Es&bhoqesq;</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">Comissions <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39">they <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">there <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41">as <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n42" number="42">there <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n43" number="43">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n44" number="44">certified <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n45" number="45">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n46" number="46">his <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n47" number="47">Hundred <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n48" number="48">be <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n49" number="49">not <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n50" number="50">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n51" number="51">places <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n52" number="52">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n53" number="53">Ma<emph type="p">t</emph>s <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n54" number="54">person <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n55" number="55">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n56" number="56">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n57" number="57">leviable <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n58" number="58">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n59" number="59">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n60" number="60">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n61" number="61">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n62" number="62">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n63" number="63">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n64" number="64">amongst <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n65" number="65">Orphant <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n66" number="66">Bowyer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n67" number="67">Or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


