<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47242" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>A Subsidy graunted to the King of Tonnage Poundage and other su[m]ms of money payable upon Merchandize exported &amp; imported.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>c. 8. ante, recited.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for granting the Subsidy by the said Act.; c. 12. ante, recited.; c. 22. ante, recited. ; c. 25. ante, recited.; c 29, ante, recited.; Reasons for the present Grant.; Grant of Tonnage, for every Ton of Wine imported, 3s.; The like Duty over and above on Sweet Wine imported by Merchant Aliens.; Every Awme of Rhenish Wine imported, 12d</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Grant of Poundage, every 20s. worth of Goods exported, 12d. ; The like Duty on Tin and Pewter Vessels exported.; Proviso for Woollen Cloth wrought within the Realm, and exported by Merchant Denizens; and for Wools, Woolfells, Hides and Backs of Leather exported, and for all Wines not before mentioned, and for Fresh Fish and Bestial imported</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p3">Whereas an a&bholigct; was made this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament entituled A Subsidy graunted to the King of Tonnage
and Poundage and other s&bhouov;ms of money payable upon Merchandize exported and imported whereby it is
declared and ena&bholigct;ed that it is and hath beene the ancient right of the subje&bholigct;s of this Realme that no subsidy
custome impost or other charges whatsoever ought or may be laid or imposed upon any merchandize exported
or imported by subje&bholigct;s Denizens or Aliens without c&bhooov;mon consent in Parliament And the said Commons then
taking into theire considera&bhocotil;ns the great perill that might have ensued by not guarding of the Seas and other
inconveniencies which might have followed in case the said s&bhouov;ms of money in the said a&bholigct; men&bhocotil;ned should not
have beene graunted to your Majestie as in and by the said a&bholigct; is expressed did therefore by the advice of the
Lords in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same give and graunt unto your Majestie
our leige Lord and Soveraigne One subsidy of Tonnage and One other subsidy of Poundage in such manner and
according to such rates as in the said a&bholigct; is ex&bhopcrl;ssed To have take perceive &amp; enjoye the subsidies and other
s&bhouov;ms so graunted by the said a&bholigct; and every of them and every part &amp; parcell of them to your Highnes from
the five and twentieth day of May One thousand six hundred forty and one unto the fifteenth day of July then
next coming And Whereas the said a&bholigct; being determined one other a&bholigct; of the same title was likewise made this
present Parliament with like declaration of the right of the subje&bholigct;s of this your Realme by which second a&bholigct; your
said C&bhooov;mons did by the like advice of the Lords in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled and by the authority of the
same give and graunt to your Majestie One Subsidy of Tonnage and one other subsidy of Poundage in such manner
and according to such rates as in the said last recited a&bholigct; is specified and conteyned To have take perceive and
enjoye the subsidies and other s&bhouov;ms so granted [by the said last recited a&bholigct;<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] and every of them and every part &amp;
parcell of them to your Highnes from the said fifteenth day of July One thousand six hundred forty and one unto
the tenth day of August then next ensuing And Whereas the said a&bholigct; being determined one other a&bholigct; of the same
title was likewise made this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament by which third a&bholigct; your said Commons did by the like advice of the
Lords in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same give and graunt to your Majestie One
subsidy of Tonnage and one other subsidy of Poundage in such manner and according to such rates as in the
said last recited a&bholigct; is specified &amp; conteyned To have take enjoye and perceive the said subsidies and other s&bhouov;ms
so granted by the said last recited a&bholigct; &amp; every of them &amp; every parte and parcell of them to your Highnes from
the ninth day of August One thousand six hundred forty and one to the first day of December then next ensuing
And Whereas the said a&bholigct; being determined one other a&bholigct; of the same title was likewise made this present
Parliament by which fourth a&bholigct; your said Commons did by the like advice of the Lords in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament
assembled and by the authority of the same give and graunt to your Majestie. One Subsidy of Tonnage and one
other subsidy of Poundage in such manner and according to such rates as in the said last recited a&bholigct; is specified
&amp; conteyned To have take enjoye &amp; perceive the said Subsidies &amp; other s&bhouov;ms soe granted by the said last recited
a&bholigct; &amp; every of them &amp; every part and parcell of them to your Highnes from the last day of November One
thousand six hundred fortie and one unto the first day of February then next ensuing And Whereas the said a&bholigct;
being determined one other a&bholigct; of the same title was likewise made this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament by which fifth a&bholigct; the
said Commons did by the like advice of the Lords in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled and by the authority of the
same give and grant to your Majestie One subsidy of Tunnage and one other subsidy of Poundage in such manner and
according to such rates as in the said last recited a&bholigct; is specified To have take enjoye &amp; perceive the said subsidies
&amp; other s&bhouov;mes soe granted by the said last recited a&bholigct; and every of them and every part and parcell of them to
your Highnes from the first day of February One thousand six hundred forty &amp; one unto the five and twentieth
day of March then next following The said Commons nowe likewise againe taking into theire consideration the
great. perill that might ensue to this Realme by the not guarding of the Seas and the other inconveniencies that
might follow in case the said s&bhouov;mes of money should upon the suddaine be forborne to be paid By and with the
advice and consent of the Lords in this present Parliament assembled &amp; by the authority of the same Doe give
and graunt to you our supreame Lord &amp; Soveraigne One subsidy called Tonnage that is to say Of every Tonne
of Wine that is or shall come into this Realme or any your Majesties Dominions by way of merchandize the
s&bhouov;me of three shillings and so after that rate And of every Tunne of Sweet Wines as well Malmsey as other that
is or shall come into this Realme by any Merchant Alien three shillings and soe after the rate over and above
the three shillings above men&bhocotil;ned And of every awme of Rhenish Wine that is or shall soe come in twelve
pence And alsoe one other Subsidy called Poundage that is to say Of all manner of goods &amp; merchandize of
every merchant denizen &amp; alien carried or to be carried out of this Realme or any your Majesties Dominions
or to be brought into the same by way of Merchandize of the value of every twenty shillings of the same
goods &amp; merchandize twelve pence and soe after the rate and of every twenty shillings value of Tynne and
Pewter Vessell carried out of this Realme by every or any Merchant Alien twelve pence over and above the
twelve pence aforesaid Except and foreprized out of this grant of Subsidy of Poundage all manner of Woolen
Cloath made or wrought or which shall be made or wrought within this Realme of England and by every or
any Merchant Denizen and not borne Alien carried or to be carried out of this Realme And all manner of Woolls
Woolfels Hides and Backs of Leather that is or shall be carried out of this Realme and all Wines not before
limited to pay subsidy or Tonnage And all manner of Fresh Fish &amp; bestiall coming or that shall come into this Realme.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Merchant Denizen to pay every Sack of Wool 33s. 4d.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">every 240 Woolfells 33s. 4d. ; every Last of Hides and Backs; &pound;3. 6s. 8d. and so in proportion for every greater or less Quantity.; Merchant Strangers to pay every Sack of Wool&pound;3. 6s. 8d.; every 240 Woolfells &pound;3. 6s. 8d.; every Last of Hides and Backs.; &pound;3. 13s. 4d; and also certain Duties by Letters Patent, or Great or Privy Seal, since 1 Jac. 1</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p5">And further the said Commons by the assent advice &amp; authority aforesaid Doe give and graunt unto you our
said leidge Lord our Soveraigne for the causes aforesaid One other Subsidy that is to say Of every Merchant
borne denizen of and for every sacke of Wooll thirty three shillings foure pence and of and for every twoe
hundred and forty woolfels thirty three shillings foure pence and of and for every Last of Hides &amp; Backs three
pounds six shillings &amp; eight pence and soe after the same rate for every lesse or greater quantity for any
the same merchandize more or lesse And of every Merchant Stranger not borne Denizen of and for every Sack
of Wool three Pounds (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) six shillings eight pence and of and for every two hundred forty Woolfels three
pounds six Shillings eight pence and for every Last of Hides and Backs three pounds thirteene shillings foure pence
and so of all the said Wools Woolfels Hides and Backs and every of them after the rate And such other s&bhouov;mes
of money as have beene imposed upon any merchandize either outward or inward by &bhopcrl;text of any Letters Patents
Commission under the Great Seale of England or Privy Seale since the first yeare of the reigne of his late Majestie
King James of Blessed Memory and which were continued and paid at the begining of this present Parliament
To have take enjoye and perceive the subsidies aforesaid &amp; other the aforementioned s&bhouov;mes and every of them and
every part and parcell of them to you our said leige [Lord<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] and Soveraigne from the foure and twentieth day
of March One thousand six hundred forty &amp; one to the third day of May next ensuing</para>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">&pound;3.; and also certain Duties by Letters Patent, or Great or Privy Seal, since 1 Jac 1</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the said subsidy of Tonnage Poundage Wooll and
other s&bhouov;mes of money shall be taken and employed during the time aforesaid to and for the intents and purposes
and upon and under such provisions clauses and limita&bhocotil;ns as are conteyned in one a&bholigct; made in Parliament held
in the first yeare of the reigne of his said late Majestie King James of Blessed Memory entituled An a&bholigct; for the
granting of a Subsidy to the King of Tonnage Poundage Wools &amp;c.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III The said Subsidy to be applied according to 1 Jac I c 33</head>
			<para id="p8">And it is hereby declared that the s&bhouov;mes of money hereby granted upon merchandize are not the rates intended
to be continued but the same to be hereafter in this present Parliament altered in such manner as shall be
thought fit</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The above Rates or Merchandize to be altered in this Parliament as shall be thought fit.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided that no penaltie or forfeiture conteyned in this present a&bholigct; or in the said a&bholigct; made in the first yeare
of King James doe or shall ensue to any person or persons unlesse they refuse to compound for any merchandize or
goods imported or exported after notice given of this a&bholigct; penalty and forfeiture by Proclamation where the said
goods are or ought to be entred</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Penalty in this a&bholigct; or in 1 Jac. I. c. 33. to attach unless on Persons refusing to compound for Goods imported or exported.</head>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Officer after the Determination of this Grant receiving Subsidy, Premunire and Disability to sue. Exception.</head>
			<para id="p10">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed that any Customer or Comptroller or any other Officer or person that after the
determina&bhocotil;n of this Grant shall take or receive or cause to be taken or received the said Subsidy s&bhouov;mes of money
or any imposition upon merchandize whatsoever exported or imported except the same by Grant in Parliament be due
or by such Grant shall become due or have beene continually paid from the end of the (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) late King Edward the
Third untill the begining of the reigne of the late Queene Mary shall incurr and sustaine the paines penalties
and forfeitures ordeined and provided by the Statute of Provision and Premunire made in the sixteenth yeare of King
Richard the Second and shall also from henceforth be disabled during his life to sue or implead any person in
any a&bholigct;ion reall mixt or personall or in any Court whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Tobacco of English Plantations.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwaies that this a&bholigct; shall not extend to any imposition or charge upon any sort of Tobacco of
English Planta&bhocotil;ns but that the said Tobacco shall be charged only with the payment of two pence in the
pound and no more.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Persons not to be charged by this a&bholigct; with pretermitted Customs.</head>
			<para id="p12">Provided alwaies And it is further ena&bholigct;ed that this a&bholigct; shall not extend or be construed to charge any person
or persons with an imposition or charge of late yeares imposed upon Woollen Cloath and Woolen c&bhooov;modities
knowne by the name of the &bhopcrl;termitted customes</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Grants of Subsidies by Letters Patent, &amp;c. void.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Allowance of Duties on imported Goods exported</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">Provided alsoe And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that all Grants and l[ia]res Patents under the
Great Seale Privy Seale or otherwise conteyning the Grants of any subsidies or imposts heretofore made or granted
to any person or persons for or in respe&bholigct; of the transporta&bhocotil;n exporta&bhocotil;n or importa&bhocotil;n of any goods or merchandize
pretended to be due or payable to your Majestie or by any such Grants or l[ia]res Patents covenanted to be enjoyed or
had out of such Subsidies Imposts or payments as hereafter should be setled by Parliament or otherwise And all
l[ia]res Patents or other Grants of the Colle&bholigct;ion of any impositions heretofore set without consent in Parliament made
or granted to any person whatsoever And alsoe all pen&bhocotil;ns assigna&bhocotil;ns of moneys and all other payments whatsoever
charged or hereafter to be charged on this subsidy by this a&bholigct; other then for the uses before in this a&bholigct; intended
shalbe from henceforth utterly voide Provided that if any Merchant shall exporte any Goods and merchandize which
have beene formerly imported &amp; the customes and other duties for the same truly paid that in such case the same
allowances shall be made to every such Merchant as have beene formerly by vertue of your Highnes Privy Seale.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">sixe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Raigne of the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

