<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47244" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the speedy and effectuall reducing of the Rebells in his Majesties Kingdome of Ireland to theire due obedience to his Majesty &amp; the Crowne of England</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Many Millions of Acres of Land of the Rebels to be confiscate</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Lords and Commons taking into theire serious consideration as well the necessity of a speedy
reducing of the Rebells of Ireland to theire due obedience as alsoe the great s&bhouov;ms of Money that the Commons
of this Realme have of late paid for the publique and necessary affaires of this Kingdome whereof the Lords and
Commons are very sensible and desirous to imbrace all good and honourable wayes tending to his Majesties greatnesse and profit the setling of that Realme and the ease of his Majesties Subje&bholigct;s of England And whereas diverse worthy and well affe&bholigct;ed persons perceiving that many millions of Acres of the Rebells Lands of that Kingdome which go under the name of profitable Lands will be confiscate and to be disposed of And that in case two millions and [an<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
halfe of those Acres to be equally taken out of the four Provinces of that Kingdome may be allotted for the satisfa&bholigct;ion
of such persons as shall disburse any s&bhouov;ms of money for the reducing of the Rebells there would effe&bholigct;ually accomplish
the same have made these Propositions ensuing (viz.)</para>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Two Millions and a Half of such Acres allotted to the Adventurers</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">1. That two millions and an halfe of those Acres may be assigned allotted and divided amongst them after this
proportion (viz) For each Adventure of two hundred pounds one thousand Acres in Ulster For three hundred
pounds one thousand Acres in Conaght. For foure hundred and fifty pounds one thousand Acres in Munster For
six hundred pounds one thousand Acres in Leinster All according to the English measure and consisting of Meadowe
Arable and profitable Pasture the Bogs Woods and barren Mountains being cast in over and above these two millions
and a halfe of Acres to be holden in free and common Soccage of the King as of his Castle of Dublin.</para>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">Rent reserved to the Crown</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">2. That out of these two millions and a halfe of Acres a constant yearely Rent shall be reserved to the Crowne
of England after this proportion (viz) out of each Acre thereof in Ulster one peny Out of each Acre in Conaght
three halfe pence Out of each Acre in Munster two pence farthing And out of each Acre in Leinster three pence
whereby His Majesties [Revenues<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] out of those Lands will be much improved besides the advantages that He will
have by the coming to His hands of all other the Lands of the Rebells and theire personall Estates without any
charge [unto<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] his Majestie.</para>
		<para id="p7">
			<emph type="i">Commissions for erecting of Manors, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p8">3. That for the ere&bholigct;ing of Mannors setling of Wasts and Commons maintaining of preaching Ministers creating of
Corporations and Regulating of the severall Plantations one or more Commissions be hereafter graunted by Authority
of Parliament.</para>
		<para id="p9">
			<emph type="i">Undertakers to subscribe within limited Times</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p10">4. That Moneys for this great occasion may bee the more speedily advanced All the Undertakers in the Citie of
London and within twentie miles distant thereof shall underwrite theire severall s&bhouov;ms before the twentieth day of
March one thousand six hundred fortie one and all within sixtie miles of London before the first day of Aprill one
thousand six hundred fourtie two and the rest of the Kingdome before the first day of May one thousand six hundred
fourtie two.</para>
		<para id="p11">
			<emph type="i">Sums underwritten to be paid in Four Payments.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p12">5. That the severall s&bhouov;ms to be underwritten shall be paid in at four payments (viz) One fourth part within ten
dayes after such underwriting and the other three parts at three Moneths (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) and three Monthes all to be paid into
the Chamber of London.</para>
		<para id="p13">
			<emph type="i">A Twentieth Part to be paid down</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p14">6. That for the better securing of the said severall s&bhouov;ms accordingly every one that doth soe underwrite shall at
the time of his Subscription pay down the twentieth part of the totall s&bhouov;m that shall be by him then underwritten And in
case that the residue of his first fourth part be not paid in to such person or persons as shall be appointed to receive
the same within the ten dayes before limited then such party shall not onely forfeit the twentieth part of the s&bhouov;m totall
formerly deposited but so much more of his first fourth payment to be added thereunto as shall make up the one
moyetie of the said first payment And if the same person shall faile [in<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] any other of the three payments he shall
[then<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] forfeit his entire first fourth part and all the benefit of his Subscription which forfeiture shall accrue to the
common benefit of the rest of the Underwriters.</para>
		<para id="p15">
			<emph type="i">Propositions ratified</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p16">And whereas aswell our Soveraigne Lord the King as the Lords and Commons have approved of the said Propositions
and assented that the said Proposi&bhocotil;ns and all other things necessarily conducing thereunto shall be ratified and
confirmed by Authoritie of Parliament. Be it therefore Ena&bholigct;ed by our Soveraigne Lord the King with the assent of
the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by Authoritie of the same That all and every of
the said Propositions and every clause therein contained are and shall be according to the tenour and purport
thereof hereby ratified established and confirmed with such explanations alterations and additions as in this A&bholigct;
are exprest.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Forfeitures of all Persons in Rebellion, after the 23d Oct. 1641.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">adjudged to be in the actual possession of the Crown</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every person and persons which upon the three and twentieth day of
O&bholigct;ober in the yeare One thousand six hundred fourtie one or at any time after shall be in Rebellion or levie
War against the Kings Majestie within his Realme of Ireland or shall willingly aid assist or countenance any person
or persons in Rebellion against the Kings Majestie shall lose and forfeit unto the Kings Majestie His Heires and
Successors all such right title interest use and possession which they [are<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] any of them or any other person or
persons in trust for them or any of them on the said three and twentieth day of O&bholigct;ober or at any time after
shall have of in or unto any Honours Castles Mannors Messuages Lands Tenements Rents Annuities Reversions
Remainders Uses Possessions Offices Rights Conditions or any other Hereditaments of what name nature or qualitie
soever they be and that all such right title interest use and possession which they or any of them or any other
person or persons in trust for them or any of them on the said three and twentieth day of O&bholigct;ober or at any
time after shall have or of right ought to have of in or to the same Honours Castles Mannors Messuages
Lands Tenements Rents Annuities Reversions Remainders Uses Possessions Offices Rights Conditions or any other
Hereditaments shall by the Authoritie aforesaid bee deemed vested adjudged and taken to be in the a&bholigct;uall and
reall possession of Our Soveraigne Lord the King His Heires and Successors without any Office or Inquisition
thereof hereafter to be found</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The said Two Millions and a Half of Acres of Land forfeited shall be allotted for Satisfaction of Money subscribed.</head>
			<para id="p19">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That two Millions and a halfe of Acres of Meadowe
Arable Land and profitable Pasture which are or shall be forfeited by the said Rebells or otherwise by vertue
of this A&bholigct; with Woods Boggs Loughs and barren Mountaines cast in over and above and with all the Buildings
&amp; Edifices thereupon are and shall be by vertue of this A&bholigct; for the satisfa&bholigct;ion of such person and persons as
shall underwrite any s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of Money and pay the same according to the true intent and meaning of
this present A&bholigct; the same to be allotted &amp; apportioned to each Underwriter according to the proportion of the
s&bhouov;ms to be underwritten and paid in and to be holden by such Rent and Tenure as in the said recited
Propositions are expressed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Persons nominated to receive Subscriptions in the Chamber of London.</head>
			<para id="p20">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That John Warner John Towse and Thomas Andrewes Aldermen and Lawrence
Halsted Esquire are and shalbe hereby appointed and authorised to give theire daily attendance at the said Chamber
of London to receive all such Subscriptions and s&bhouov;ms of Money and to give Receipts for the same under theire
hands as shall be there tendred and paid according to this A&bholigct; which said persons so appointed to receive the
said s&bhouov;ms of Money shall enter the names of the Underwriters togeather with the s&bhouov;m and time of Subscription
into one or more Bookes to be kept for that purpose and shall from time to time issue out the said s&bhouov;ms of
Money in such manner as both Houses of Parliament shall by Order direct.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Sheriffs to receive Subscriptions in their several Counties, and return the same with Names, &amp;c. to the Chamber of London.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Account thereof to Parliament</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Sheriffes of each Countie of England and Dominion of Wales shall receive
all such Subscriptions and s&bhouov;ms of Money as shall be by vertue of this A&bholigct; tendred to them in theire respective
Counties and shall appoint dayes and places for that Purpose and shall give Receipts for the s&bhouov;ms soe received
under theire hands and return the s&bhouov;ms subscribed and received togeather with the Names of the Underwriters
and the times of theire Subscriptions to the Chamber of London to the hands of the said John Warner John
Towse Thomas Andrewes and Lawrence Halsted or to any two of them with all convenient speed to be by them
entred into Bookes to [be<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] kept for that purpose And they the said John Warner John Towse Thomas Andrewes
and Lawrence Halsted or any two of them are hereby likewise authorized and required to give Acquittances or
Receipts for all s&bhouov;ms received of the said Sheriffs And that the said John Warner John Towse Thomas Andrewes
and Lawrence Halsted and the said Sheriffes theire Officers and Ministers theire Heires and Executors shall accompt
for all s&bhouov;ms of Money by them received according to this present A&bholigct; to such persons as both Houses of
Parliament shall direct</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Allowance to the Receivers.</head>
			<para id="p23">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said
John Warner John Towse Thomas Andrewes and Lawrence Halsted and the said Sheriffes respectively to deduct
and retain to theire owne use one peny out of every pound of all such s&bhouov;ms of money as they shall receive
according to this A&bholigct; towards theire charges and pains in attending and receiving the said Subscriptions and s&bhouov;ms
of money and in issuing out and returning up the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Upon Declaration by the Lords and Commons that the Rebels are subdued,</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">Commissions to issue for the surveying the Lands forfeited, and setting forth the same.; Division to be made by Order of the Lords and Commons, and to be done by Lot; Commissioners to return Allotments into Chancery</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That when the Lords and Commons of this Realme of England shall in Parliament
by Order declare that the said Rebells are subdued and that this present Rebellion in the said Kingdome of
Ireland is appeased and ended that forthwith after such Declaration made and sent to the Lord Chancellor or Lord
Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the time being the said Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper is hereby
authorised and required to issue forth Commissions into all the said four Provinces of that Kingdome of Ireland
for the surveying and setting forth of the said two Millions and halfe of Acres which Commission shall be to
such effect and directed to such persons as the said Lords and Commons in Parliament shall appoint Which said
Commissioners shall have power by this A&bholigct; to survey all the Lands of the said Rebells and all the Lands
forfeited by vertue of this A&bholigct; and to ascertain and measure forth of the same six hundred and five and twentie
thousand Acres in every of the said foure Provinces of Meadowe Arable and profitable Pasture with Woods Bogs
Loughes and barren Mountaines cast in over and above with the Houses and Edifices thereupon and after the same
measured and set forth shall indifferently divide the same by Lot among the severall Underwriters and among the
Heires of such Underwriters as shall die before the division and the assignee and assignees of such of the Underwriters as shall assigne theire shares or any part thereof before the said Division according to the proportions
mentioned in the said recited Propositions and according to the respective s&bhouov;ms paid in as aforesaid and according
to the purport of this present A&bholigct; which Division shall be made in such manner as the said Lords and Commons
in Parliament shall by Order direct in which Division no manner of favour or advantage shall be given or allowed
to any person whatsoever but all to be done and determined equally and by Lot and each Underwriters Land
to be laid togeather or so neere togeather as conveniently may be And in case six hundred twenty five thousand
Acres of the Rebells profitable Lands and of the profitable Lands forfeited by vertue of this Act shall not be
found in each province then so much of the said six hundred twentie five thousand Acres as shall be wanting
in any [one<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Province shall be made up in value out of the said Rebells Lands and for want thereof out of the profitable Lands forfeited by this A&bholigct; in the other Provinces at the discretion of the said Commissioners respe&bholigct;
being had to the value of the Lands in each Province according to the said Propositions which said Commissioners
shall returne the said allotments and all theire proceedings therein fairely ingrost in Parchment into his Majesties
Court of Chancery of this Kingdome there to remaine of Record and into his Majesties Court of Chancery of
the [said<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Kingdome of Ireland to remaine there likewise of Record</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. The Persons adjudged to be in Possession after their Lots drawn.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">Forfeiture of Lands and Goods</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed that immediately after every Underwriter Heire or Assignee of any Underwriter shall
have drawne his respective Lot containing the Meadow Arable and profitable Pasture with all the Woods Bogs
Loughs and barren Mountaines over and above togeather with the Houses and Edifices there upon which shall be
appointed for his share such Underwriter Heir and Assignee shall be and so shalbe adjudged to be by vertue of
this A&bholigct; in the a&bholigct;uall possession and seisin of all the said Lands with all things thereunto belonging mentioned
in his said Lot and that he shall and may forthwith after his Lot so drawn as aforesaid enter upon have and
enjoye to him and his heires all and singuler the Meadowe Arable profitable Pasture Woods Bogs Loughs Waters
Fishings and barren Mountaines togeather with the Houses and Edifices thereupon and in his said Lot contained
with all Easements and Comodities thereunto belonging.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Power after Allotment to create Manors, and hold Courts.</head>
			<para id="p28">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all and every person and persons which within three
monthes after the allotment so to be made as aforesaid shall have one thousand Acres or more of the said two
Millions &amp; halfe of Acres lying togeather in the Province of Leinster or two thousand Acres or more lying
togeather in the Province of Conaght or one thousand five hundred Acres or more lying togeather in the Province
of Munster or three thousand Acres or more lying togeather in the Province of Ulster shall have power by vertue
of this Act for every such thousand twoe thousand fifteene hundred and three thousand Acres to create a Mannor
within the limits of the said Lands respectively and to reserve tenures to hold of himselfe and his heires as of
his said Mannor or Mannors at his will and pleasure And that every such person shall have a Court Leet and
Court Baron and shall have full power to hold a Court Leete and Court Baron within the Precincts of every
such Mannor and to enjoye all such Royalties Franchises Fines and Amerciaments Suites Services and Immunities
as to view of Franke pledge or Court Baron is usuall &amp; belonging And alsoe within each respective Mannors to
have and enjoye as aforesaid all [Deodans<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Felons goods and goods of Felons of themselves togeather with all
Wayfes and Strayes</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. The Money paid to be employed for reducing the Rebels only.</head>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">Overplus how disposed of</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p30">And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That no part of the money which shall be paid in
according to this Act shall be imployed to any other purpose then the reducing of the said Rebels untill the
said Rebels shall be declared to be subdued by the said Lords and Commons as aforesaid And that the said
moneys shall be imployed for the speedie and effectuall subduing of the said Rebells by sending over into the
said Realm of Ireland and disposing there such Forces of Foot and Horse Monies Ammunition Victuall and all
other things necessary to a Warre in such manner as the said Lords and Commons in Parliament shall from
time to time direct and the overplus of the said money if any shall be to be disposed as the said Lords and
Commons shall likewise direct</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Plantations regulated, Churches, &amp;c. to be erected.</head>
			<para id="p31">And be it likewise Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That Plantations shall be regulated Corporations created
Churches erected and Preaching Ministers maintained within the Limits and p[re]cincts of the Lands so to be divided
in such manner as by Commissioners to be nominated and directed by the said Lords and Commons in Parliament
shall be ordered and provided</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Lord Chancellor to issue out Commissions.</head>
			<para id="p32">And it is further Enacted That the Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper of the great Seale of England for the time
being shall upon direction to him given by the said Lords and Commons in Parliament issue out one or more
Commissions for this purpose directed to such persons and in such manner as the said Lords and Commons in
Parliament shall order and appoint</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Patents granted of Rebels' Lands, &amp;c. without Consent of Lords and Commons, void, and all Pardons.</head>
			<para id="p33">And for the further encouraging and securing of all such persons as shall pay any su[m]m of money towards the
perfecting of this great Worke Be it likewise Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Patents which shall be granted
of any of the said Rebels Goods or Lands or of any Goods or Lands forfeited by vertue of this Act and all Pardons
which shall be granted to any of the said Rebells before attainder after the three and twentieth of October one
thousand six hundred fortie and one (without the assent of the said Lords and Commons in Parliament) shall be
adjudged void and of none effect</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Proclamations to be made concerning Claims.</head>
			<para id="p34">And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That the Commissioners authorised by this Act to set forth
the Underwriters Lands as aforesaid shall fourtie dayes before they set forth the same or any part thereof cause
Proclamations to be made by vertue of this Act in every Countie of the said Kingdome of Ireland to this effect (viz)
That every person which had any right title or interest the three and twentieth of October one thousand six hundred
fourtie one in or out of [any of<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] the said Rebels Lands or [the<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Lands forfeited by this Act lying within the Countie
where any such Proclamac[i]on shall be made shall enter his claim to the same upon record in His Majesties Court of
Chancery in the said Kingdome of Ireland within twenty dayes after the said Proclamation so made in the said County</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Endeavouring to introduce the Authority of the See of Rome into Ireland.</head>
			<para id="p35">And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every person which after the first day of March one
thousand six hundred and fourty shall make enter into or take any Compact Bond Covenant Oath Promise or
Agreement to introduce or bring into the said Realm of Ireland the authority of the Sea (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) Rome in any case whatsoever
or to maintain or defend the same shall by vertue of this Act forfeit to his Majestie his Heires and Successors all his
Lands Tenements &amp; Hereditaments entailed or not entailed Goods &amp; Chattels which he had or shall have in his owne
name or any other person or persons had or shall have in trust for him at the time of the making entring into or taking
any such Compact Bond Covenant Oath Promise or Agreement other then such Lands Tenements Hereditaments
Goods and Chattels as shall be bona fide and for valuable considera&bhocotil;ns sold before the said three and twentieth of
October one thousand six hundred fourtie one</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Such Rebels as be dead, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">Lands and Goods forfeited</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">And further be it Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any person since the three and twentieth day of
October One thousand six hundred fourty one be or hereafter shall be in Rebellion within the said Kingdome of Ireland
and be dead or shall die before attaindor or pardon for the same All the Lands Tenements and Hereditaments Estate
or Estates Goods or Chattels which such person had or shall have or any other person had or shall have in trust for or
to his use the said three and twentieth of October or at any time th ereafter shall be by vertue of this Act forfeited to
his Majestie His Heires and Successors and shall be adjudged to be in the actuall seisin and possession of the King His
Heires and Successors by vertue of this A&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. All Forfeitures from the 23d Oct. 1641 adjudged to be in the actual Seisin of the Crown.</head>
			<para id="p38">And further be it Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all Lands Tenements and Hereditaments whereof any
person in the said Kingdome of Ireland was seised the three and twentieth of October one thousand six hundred fourtie
one or att any time after shall be seised of any Estate tail or whereof any other person or persons shall be seised in
trust for him for any trust of inheritance who shall be attainted of High Treason in his life time or being in actuall
Rebellion shall die before he be attainted or pardoned for the same or who shall make enter into or take any such
Compact Bond Covenant Oath Promise or Agreement to such [person<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] as aforesaid shall by vertue of this Act be and
adjudged to be in the actuall seisin and possession of the King His Heires and Successors</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Certain Conveyances, &amp;c. made after 1st March 1640 by Rebels; the Uses, &amp;c. to be adjudged in the actual Possession of the Crown.</head>
			<para id="p39">And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That if any person or persons whatsoever that at any time
hereafter shall be attainted for Treason or shall die in actuall Rebellion before attaindor or pardon of the same or hath
or shall take enter into or make any such Compact Bond Covenant Oath Promise or Agreement as aforesaid shall
after the first day of March one thousand six hundred and fourtie make or hath made any Conveyance or Assurance
whatsoever of any Mannors Lands Tenements or Hereditaments in the Kingdome of Ireland unto or for his owne
use or unto or for the use of his wife or any of his children or in trust for himselfe his wife or any of his children
That then all the Uses Estates &amp; Trusts so limited other then such as are or shall bona fide be made before his her or
theire marriage or made in performance of any Convenant in writing made before marriage unto or for the use of
his wife or children shall be forfeited unto His Majestie His Heires and Successors and shall be adjudged to be by
vertue of this Act in the actuall possession of the King His Heires and Successors</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. The Time for Subscriptions; enlarged.</head>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">Subscriptions of &pound;10. and upwards.; Subscriptions of &pound;6. and upwards</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid in regard a great part of the time &bhopcrl;fixed in the said Propositions
for the Subscriptions of the said Underwriters is already elapsed that every one of the Kings Subjects of the Realms
of England Scotland or Ireland that shall underwrite within this Kingdome the s&bhouov;m of ten pounds or more for the
purpose aforesaid before the first day of May one thousand six hundred fourty two and before the said million of
money be underwritten and shall pay in one moiety thereof to the respective Receivers before nominated in this Act
at the time of such Subscription and shall pay in the other moiety residue thereof to the said Receivers within six
moneths after such Subscription and every one of the Kings Subjects of the Realmes of England Scotland and
Ireland that shall underwrite the s&bhouov;m of six pounds or more within the Realm of Ireland for the purpose aforesaid
(in one or more Books to be kept for that purpose by the Treasurer of the Army there for the time being) who is
authorized and required hereby to keepe such Booke or Books and to enter the names of such Underwriters and
the time of such Subscriptions togeather with the s&bhouov;ms subscribed before the first day of July one thousand six
hundred fourty two and before the said million of money shall be underwritten and shall at the time of such
Subscription pay one moietie of such sum so to be underwritten to the said Treasurer for the time being (who is
hereby likewise authorised to receive all such s&bhouov;ms of money and give Receipts for the same under his hand) and
shall pay to the said Treasurer the other moietic residue within six moneths after such Subscription every person so
underwriting in this Realme or in the Realm of Ireland as aforesaid shall have a proportionable share of the said
Rebels Lands and of other Lands to be forfeited by this Act according to the s&bhouov;m to be underwritten and paid
in as aforesaid and as if such person had underwritten within the times mentioned in the said Propositions and had
paid in his money accordingly</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Encouragement for a speedy Plantation.</head>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">Cattle may be exported for that Purpose for 2 Years Duty free.; General Saving</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">And for the better advancing of a speedie Plantation within that Kingdome which will soone redound to the great
increase of his Majesties Customes and Revenues there Be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That every
person which shall have any part of the said Lands so to be divided and allotted as aforesaid shall and may export
out of this Kingdome or Dominion of Wales any Horses Mares Cattell Sheep or other goods for the planting
improving and stocking of the said Lands or any part thereof at any time during the space of two yeares to
be accounted from such division and allotment to be made (as aforesaid) without paying any Custome Subsidy or
Impost for the same Neverthelesse upon sufficient securitie given to the Farmers or Collectors of His Majesties
Customes for the time being or to any one of them that the said Horses Mares Cattell Sheepe and goods so to
be exported shall be bona fide imployed for the planting improving and stocking of the said Lands or of some
part thereof and not to be imployed to any other purpose Saving to all and singular persons bodies Politique and
Corporate theire Heires and Successors and the Heires and Successors of every of them (other then the said Rebels
theire Aiders Abettors Comforters and Maintainers and other persons whose Lands are or shall be forfeited by this
Act and every of them theire and every of theire Heires and Assignes and all and every person or persons clayming
by from or under them or any of them or to theire or any of theire use or uses or in trust for them or any
of them since the said three and twentieth day of October) all such Right Title Interest Possession Reversion
Remainder Offices Annuities Rents and Commons which they or any of them had or ought to have had in to
or out of any the said Houses Mannors Castles Lands Tenements Hereditaments or Premisses forfeited by this Act
or any of them the three and twentieth day of October in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six hundred
fortie one so as every such person or persons bodies Politique or Corporate whose right or interest is saved by
this Act theire Heires or Successors doe make or enter or cause to be entred his or theire claim to any such
right title or interest in his Majesties Court of Chancerie in Ireland within twentie dayes after such Proclamation
made as aforesaid.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">a <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Revenue <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">three Monethes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Deodands <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">purpose <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

