<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47246" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles I, 1640</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXV. An Act to inable Corporations &amp; Bodies Politique to participate of the benefit of an Act lately passed entituled An Act for the speedie and effectuall reducing of the Rebells in his Majesties Kingdome of Ireland to theire due obedience to his Majestie and the Crowne of England. [Rot. Parl. 16 Car. þ. 3. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>c. 33. ante.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Corporations and Bodies Politic enabled to be Adventurers.; Times for Underwriting and Payment within 60 Miles from London.; Moneys to be paid to the Treasurers appointed by the said A&bholigct;.; Times for Underwriting and Payment by Corporations, &amp;c. being 60 Miles and more from London.; On Payment entitled to Allotments</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas diverse of his Majesties well affe&bholigct;ed Subject&bholngs; of this Kingdome have taken notice of the said A&bholigct;
and are willing to contribute to so good a Worke according to theire severall Estates and Abilities but every
Person in himselfe is not able to undertake any great s&bhouov;m of money yet many of them united and incorporated into
one Body Companie or Societie may by joyning togeather make up a considerable intire s&bhouov;m which may very much
advance so Honourable and Pious a Worke as the reducing of that Kingdome of Ireland And alsoe for the better
inabling of all Corporations and Bodies politique thorowout this Kingdome to be adventurers and undertakers in
the same Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the King our Soveraigne Lord and by the Lords and Commons in this Parliament assembled
and the Authoritie of the same That all and every Cities Boroughs and other Towns Corporate which have perpetuall
Communaltie and Succession being within sixtie miles of London And all and every Companies Guilds and Fraternities
of any Craft Mysterie or Trade united and incorporated within the said Citie of London or within any other Citie
within threescore miles distance thereof which at any time before the twentieth day of May in the yeare of our Lord
God one thousand six hundred fourty two by theire Citizens or Burgesses or by any one of them respe&bholigct;ively for
that place which he serveth in this present Parliament or by theire Maior Bailiffe Master Warden or other Head
Officer of any the said Cities Boroughs Towns Corporate Companies Guilds or Fraternities aforesaid shall underwrite
any such s&bhouov;m of money as in the said A&bholigct; is mentioned and pay the fourth part thereof on or before the said twentieth
day of May aforesaid and the other three parts of the s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms so to be subscribed within three moneths
three moneths and three monthes by equall por&bhocotil;ns accounting eight and twentie dayes to every moneth to be
accounted to begin from the said twentieth day of May aforesaid And all the said s&bhouov;ms to be paid at the Chamber
of the Citie of London to the four persons appointed to attend there by the said A&bholigct; or to any two of them Who
are hereby authorized and required to give Receipts for the same and to enter the said s&bhouov;m and the times of such
Subscription as aforesaid And all and every Cities Boroughs and other Towns corporate within the Kingdome of
England which have perpetuall Communalty and Succession being threescore miles or more from the said City of
London And all Companies Guildes and Fraternities of any Craft Mystery or Trade united &amp; incorporated within
any of the said Cities which at any time before the last day of May in the yeare of our Lord God one thousand six
hundred fourty two shall by theire Citizens or Burgesses or by any one of them respe&bholigct;ively for that place which he
serveth in this present Parliament or by theire Maior Bayliffe Master Warden or other Head Officer of any of the
said Cities Boroughs Towns Corporate Companies Guildes or Fraternities aforesaid underwrite any such sum of money
as in the said A&bholigct; is mentioned and pay the fourth part thereof on or before the said last day of May aforesaid
and the other three parts of the said s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms so to be subscribed within three monthes three monthes and three
monthes by equall por&bhocotil;ns accounting eight and twentie dayes to every moneth to be accounted to begin from the said
last day of May aforesaid and at such place and to such Persons as in and by the said A&bholigct; is appointed shall have a
<emph type="i">15 R. II. c. 5</emph>.
proportionable share of the said Rebels Lands and of other Lands forfeited and to be forfeited by the said A&bholigct;
according to the s&bhouov;ms to be by them underwritten and paid in as aforesaid under all other the Conditions and
Limitations in the said A&bholigct; or Propositions mentioned to all intents and purposes and in as large and beneficiall
manner as if such Underwriting had beene at the dayes in the said recited A&bholigct; or the Propositions therein expressed
Any thing therein contained or any thing in the Statute made the fifteenth yeare of King Richard the second entituled
Assurance of Lands to certaine Places Persons and Uses shall be adjudged Mortmain or any thing in any other
Statute of Mortmain whatsoever contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
</report>


