<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47251" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for the Continuance of Processe and Judiciall Proceedings. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p. 1. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Process, Writs, &amp;c. shall not be discontinued for not keeping or holding certain Days of Return</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the fower first Returns of Easter Terme in the yeare one thousand six hundred sixtie of late
called From Easter day in fifteene dayes, From Easter day in three weeks, From Easter day in one Moneth,
and From Easter day in five weeks, or any of them cannot be conveniently kept or holden: Now for avoiding
all manner of discontinuances whatsoever which by occasion therof should or might happen or be in any Matter
or Cause whatsoever in any the Courts at Westminster, Bee it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty and
the Lord&bholngs; and Commons assembled in Parliament That noe Pleas Writts Bills A&bholigct;ions Suites Plaints Processe
Precepts or other thing or things whatsoever pleaded returned or depending, or having day or dayes in any of
the said Courts in or at the said severall Returns or any of them, or at any other day or dayes certaine after
any of the said Returns shall be in any wise discontinued or putt without day for or by reason of the not
keeping or holding of the said Returns or dayes or any of them, but that all and singular the said Pleas Writts
Bills A&bholigct;ions Suites Plaints Processe Precepts and other the Premisses aforesaid shall stand continue and be good
and effe&bholigct;uall in Law to all Intents and Purposes as if the said Returns and dayes and every of them had beene
a&bholigct;ually kept and holden in all and every the said Courts, Any Law Statute Custome or Usage to the contrary
therof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Writs, Process, Pleas, &amp;c. returnable at a certain Day continued adjourned.; Parties in Pleas, &amp;c. having Day as herein mentioned, to have the Return.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Parties in Pleas, &amp;c. having Day as herein mentioned, to have the Return "In the Morrow of the Ascension, &amp;c." prefixed.; Sheriffs, &amp;c. to keep all Writs, &amp;c. until the Fifth Return</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all Pleas Writts Bills A&bholigct;ions Suites Plaints Processe
Precepts &amp; other thing or things whatsoever aforesaid pleadable or to be pleaded returnable or to be returned
or having day in any manner whatsoever at any of the said Returns, or any day or dayes certaine after any of
the said Returns Be and are hereby continued and adjourned unto (and shall and may be pleaded returned
heard and determined in the respe&bholigct;ive Courts aforesaid at or on the fifth Returne of the said Terme of late
called, In the morrow of the Assension of our Lord: And that all Parties in any Pleas Writts Bills A&bholigct;ions
Suites, Plaints Processe or other thing or things whatsoever haveing dayes given them at any of the said fower
first Returns, or at any other day or dayes certaine after any of the said Returns in the said Courts or any of
them by vertue of this present A&bholigct; have the said Returne of late called In the morrow of the Assension of our
Lord prefixed them therin And that all Sheriffes Officers, and other Ministers whatsoever and every of them
respe&bholigct;ively keepe in their han all Writts Bills Processe and Precepts and all other things whatsoever to them
dire&bholigct;ed respe&bholigct;ively returnable, or to be returned in the severall Courts aforesaid at the said fower first Returnes
or any of them in or at any day certaine as aforesaid untill the said fifth Returne of late called The morrow of the
Assension of our Lord, and then returne the same into the said severall Courts respe&bholigct;ively, That such proceedings
may be then had therupon as should have beene had in case the said fower first Returnes had beene kepte
and holden.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Process, Writs, Pleas, &amp;c. under certain Titles and Names, may be prosecuted and proceeded upon.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that noe Writts Processe Plaints Pleas Informations
Indi&bholigct;ments or Judiciall proceedings had commenced or prosecuted before the fifth day of May in the said yeare
of our Lord one thousand six hundred sixty in the Name Stile Title or [Test<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of Custodes Libertatis Anglie
Authoritate Parliamenti, or in the Name Stile Title or [Test<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of The Keepers of the Libertie of England by Authoritie
of Parliament, or in the Name Stile Title or [Test<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of Oliver Lord Prote&bholigct;or of the Commonwealth of England Scotland
and Ireland, and the Dominions thereto belonging, or in the Name Stile Title or [Test<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of Oliver Lord Prote&bholigct;or of
the Commonwealth of England Scotland and Ireland, and the Dominions and Territories thereunto belonging, or in
the Name Stile Title or [Test<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of Richard-Lord Protector of the Commonwealth of England Scotland and Ireland, and
the Dominions and Territories thereto belonging shall be putt without day abated quashed or discontinued by his
Majesties most just reassumption of the a&bholigct;uall Exercise of his Kingly Government in this Kingdome nor shall the same
bee cause of Error Abatement or Discontinuance, but that all such Writs Processe Plaints Pleas Informations
Indi&bholigct;ments and Judiciall proceedings and all Commissions for taking of Answers or Examination of Witnesses,
Commission for taking of Fines and Warrants of Attourney Guardians or Procheinamy shall stand and bee continued
and shall and may be proceeded upon prosecuted and returned notwithstanding the same were commenced or
prosecuted in English, and notwithstanding the present happy Change and Restitution of his Majesties Name and
Stile in Judiciall Proceedings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. A&bholigct; of 1650 continued till 1st August 1660.</head>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That one pretended A&bholigct; made in the yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred fifty entituled An A&bholigct; for turning the Bookes of the Law and all Processe and Proceedings
in Courts of Justice into English shall stand and be in force as if the same had beene a good and effe&bholigct;uall A&bholigct;
from the first Returne of Easter Terme in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred fifty one untill the first day of August [in the yeare of our Lord<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] one thousand six hundred sixtie and noe longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>IV. A&bholigct; of 1650 continued till 1st August 1660.</head>
			<para id="p7">And whereas by one other pretended A&bholigct; made in the said yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred fiftie
entituled An A&bholigct; touching Corne and Meale It was Ena&bholigct;ed or mentioned to be ena&bholigct;ed That from and after the
twentieth day of November One thousand six hundred fifty It should and might be lawfull to and for any person or
persons Defendant or Tennant for or by reason of any matter to be pleaded sett forth or alledged in Barr to any
A&bholigct;ion reall personall or mixt in any Court of Record to plead the Generall issue of Not Guilty, or the like
Generall Issue proper to the Nature of the A&bholigct;ion or Suite commenced, and for his or their Discharge or Acquitting
to give any such matter in evidence [to the Jury<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] that shall try the same, and that the said matter shall bee as 
				<emph type="i">and as to pleading the General Issue, continued till 1st August 1660</emph>.
			available to such person or persons Defendant or Tennant to all intents and purposes as if the said matter had beene
specially pleaded sett forth or alledged in Barr of such A&bholigct;ion; Bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed That the said pretended
A&bholigct; as touching the pleading of the Generall Issue shall by authoritie hereof stand and be in full force and effe&bholigct;
according to the Tenore therof untill the said first day of August as if the same had beene a good and effe&bholigct;uall
A&bholigct; of Parliament and noe longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Proviso as to former Pleas.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided allwayes That where the Generall Issue hath beene since the said twentieth day of November one
thousand six hundred fifty pleaded, or shall before the said first day of August in the said yeare of our Lord one
thousand six hundred sixtie be pleaded in any A&bholigct;ion That then upon the Triall of the said Cause such Evidence shall
and may be allowed as if the said pretended A&bholigct; touching the pleading of the Generall Issue had beene and continued
a good and effe&bholigct;uall A&bholigct; of Parliament not determined or discontinued.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. His Majesty's Assent to this Bill not to determine the Session.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alsoe That his Majesties Royall assent to the passing of this Bill shall not extend or be construed to
extend to the determining of the Session of this present Parliament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. All Writs, Patents, Commissions, &amp;c. to issue in the King's Name, as formerly.</head>
			<para id="p10">[Provided neverthelesse And be it Ena&bholigct;ed That all Writts Patents and C&bhooov;mmissions for constituting Justices of
either Bench, and Barons of the Exchequer Commissions of Oyer and Terminer and Goale Delivery [&amp; Precepts upon
C&bhooov;missions of Oyer &amp; Terminer &amp; Goale D&eacute;livery<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] and all other Commissions hereafter to be made by the Clerke of
the Crowne in the Chauncery Charters and Letters Patents under the Great Seale of Land&bholngs; Liberties Honours or Offices
doe or may issue in the Kings Majesties Name, in the same manner as was usuall before the making of the said
first recited pretended A&bholigct;. Any thing in this present A&bholigct; to the contrary therof before expressed in any wise
notwithstanding.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Teste <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


