<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47257" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IX. An Act for the speedy provision of money for disbanding and paying off the forces of this Kingdome both byLand and Sea. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p. 1. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>The Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Noblemen and their eldest Sons of the Age of 21.; A Baronet.; A Knight of the Bath.; Knight Batchelor.; King's Sergeant.; Esquires.; Widows rated at One-third according to Rank of Husbands.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the present raising of great s&bhouov;mes of money for the speedy disbanding of the forces both by Land
and Sea is a matter of vast consequence and urgent necessity soe that not onely the happines and peace of
his Majestyes Kingdomes, but alsoe the well being and prosperity of them depends upon it, which said summes of
money cannot be soe suddainely raised as the pressing occasions doe require without some extraordinary meanes used,
to the which all his Majestyes subje&bholigct;s in this visible exigence of the Kingdome will heartily and cheerfully submitt
seeing it is to free themselves from soe great a burthen and dayly increesing charge May it therefore please your
most Excellent Majesty that it may be ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings Most Excellent Majesty and by the
Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authority of the same that all and every person
and persons who at the time of the execution of this A&bholigct; shall be of the severall rankes and degrees hereafter
mentioned shall to the purpose afforesaid contribute and pay the severall summes of money hereafter in this A&bholigct; sett
downe and appointed that is to say Every person of the degree of a Duke of England Scotland or Ireland inhabiting
and residing within this Kingdome shall pay the summe of one hundred pound&bholngs;. Every person of the degree of a
Marquesse of any of the said Kingdomes inhabiting and residing within this Kingdome shall pay the summe of
fowerscore pound&bholngs;. Every person of the degree of an Earle of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting or
residing within this Kingdome the summe of threescore pound&bholngs;. Every person of the degree of a Viscount of any of
the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting and residing within this Kingdome the summe of fifty pound&bholngs;. Every person
of the degree of a Baron of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting or residing within this Kingdome the
summe of forty pound&bholngs;. Every eldest sonne of a Duke of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting or residing
within this Kingdome being of the age of one and twenty yeares the summe of threescore pound&bholngs;. Every eldest sonne
of a Marquesse of any of the said Kingdomes and inhabiting or residing within this Kingdome being of the age of
one and twenty yeares the summe of fifty pound&bholngs;. The eldest sonne of an Earle of any of the said three Kingdomes
and inhabiting or residing within this Kingdome being of the age of one and twenty yeares the summe of forty
pound&bholngs;. Every eldest sonne of a Viscount of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting or residing within
this Kingdome being of the age of one and twenty yeares the summe of thirty five pound&bholngs;. Every eldest sonne
of a Baron of any of the said three Kingdomes, and inhabiting or residing within this Kingdome being of the age
of one and twenty yeares thirty pound&bholngs;. Every person of the degree of a Baronet of any of the said three Kingdomes
or of Nova Scotia and inhabiting or residing within this Kingdome the summe of thirty pound&bholngs;. Every person that
is a Knight of the Order of the Bath inhabiting or residing within this Kingdome the summe of thirty pound&bholngs;.
Every person who is a Knight Batchelor inhabiting &amp; residing within this Kingdome the summe of twenty pound&bholngs;.
Every Sergeant at Law the summe of twenty pound&bholngs;. Every person of the degree of an Esquire, or soe reputed,
inhabiting and residing within this Kingdome and above the age of one and twenty yeares the summe of ten pound&bholngs;.
Every Widow respe&bholigct;ively according to her husbands degree, shall pay the third part [by this A&bholigct;<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] rated [by this A&bholigct;<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
upon that degree of which the husband of such Widdow was in his life time.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Parsons.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Do&bholigct;ors in Law. Advocates. Judges, &amp;c. in Courts of Admiralty, &amp;c. Do&bholigct;ors in Physic</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained that all and every person and persons of the severall rankes and degrees
hereafter in this A&bholigct; mentioned shall to the purpose aforesaid contribute and pay the severall summes of money
hereafter in this A&bholigct; sett downe and appointed, that is to say Every Parson or Vicar being possessed of a Parsonage
or Vicarage or other Estate of the cleare yearely value of one hundred pound&bholngs; the summe of forty shillings. Every
Do&bholigct;or in the civill, or canon Lawes and every Advocate the summe of five pound&bholngs;. Every person who is a Judge
or C&bhooov;missioner in the Courts of Admiralty or of the probate of Wills the summe of twenty pound&bholngs;. Every person
who hath pra&bholigct;ised as a Pro&bholigct;or in either of the Courts aforesaid the summe of five pound&bholngs;, Every Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke
the summe of ten pound&bholngs;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Lord Mayor Aldermen, &amp;c. of London.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Masters, Wardens, Livery Men, and Yeomen of Companies in London.; Hackney Coach Masters.; Merchant Strangers.; Alien Traders.; English Merchants and Fa&bholigct;ors of London.; Aldermen of any City.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the authority aforesaid that all and every person and persons of the
severall degrees and qualities hereafter mentioned shall to the purpose aforesaid contribute and pay the severall summes
of money hereafter mentioned and sett downe in this A&bholigct;, that is to say The Lord Maior of the Citty of London
shall pay the summe of forty pound&bholngs;. Every such person who [either <ref idref="n4">4</ref>] is now Sheriffe or Alderman of the said Citty
of London, or hath fined for Sheriffe or Alderman of London the summe of twenty pound&bholngs;. Every person who hath
beene or now is Deputy to any Alderman within the said Citty ten pound&bholngs;. The Towne Clarke [of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] London twenty
pound&bholngs;. Every person who is of the Common Councell of the said Citty the summe of five pound&bholngs;. Every person
who hath beene or now is Master of any of the twelve first companies of the said Citty, or hath fined for Master
of any of the said twelve companies the summe of ten pound&bholngs;. Every person who hath beene or now is Warden of
any of the said twelve first Companies of the said Citty, or hath fined for Warden of [any of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the said Companies
six pound&bholngs; thirteene shillings and fower pence, Every person who is of the Livery of any of the said twelve first
companies the summe of five pound&bholngs;. Every person who is of the Yeomanry of either of the said twelve first
companies three pound&bholngs;. Every person who is or hath beene Master of either of the companies of Diers Brewers
Leather Sellers Girdlers Stationers Woodmongers Upholsters Pothecaries Pewterers Tallow-Chandlers Armorers or
Sadlers the summe of six pound&bholngs;. Every person who hath beene Warden of either of the said Companies five
pound&bholngs;. Every person who is of the Livery of any of the said Companies three pound&bholngs;. Every person who is of
the Yeomanry of the said Companies one pound. Every person who hath beene or is Master of any of the companyes
of Barber Chirurgions White Bakers Wax Chandlers Cutlers Butchers Carpenters Painters Cordwayners Coopers
Scriveners Browne Bakers Turners or Inholders the summe of three pound&bholngs;. Every person who is or hath beene
Warden of any of the said Companies two pound&bholngs;. Every person who is of the Livery of any of the said Companyes
one pound. Every person who is or hath beene Master of either of the Companies of Founders Curryers Masons
Bricklayers Joyners Plaisterers Weavers Fruterers Marblers Imbroyderers Poulterers Cooks or Plumbers the summe of
one pound. Every person who is or hath beene Wardon of any of the said Companies fifteene shillings, Every
person that is of the Livery of the said Companies ten shillings. Every person who is or hath beene of the Livery of
either of the Companies of Bowyers Fletchers Blackesmithes Botlemakers Woolpackers Farriers Paviers Loriners
Glasiers Clerks or Watermen five shillings. Every person who is a Freeman of any Company within the Citty of
London the summe of one shilling. Every person that keepeth one or more Hackney Choaches shall pay for every
Hackney Choach and paire of Horses that he soe keepeth the summe of ten shillings. Every person who is a Merchant
Stranger if he be of the degree of a Knight the summe of forty pound&bholngs;, if below that degree and he be a Merchant
trading to Sea the summe of ten pound&bholngs;, if trading within the Land the s&bhouov;me of five pound&bholngs;. Every person being
an Alien borne and useing or exerciseing any trade, mistery, or manuall occupation within any of the Cittyes or
Corporations of this Kingdome being a Housekeeper the summe of ten shillings. Every person who is an English
merchant inhabiting and residing in or about the said Citty of London, and not free of the said Citty the summe
of ten pound&bholngs;. Every English Fa&bholigct;or residing within the said Citty the summe of forty shillings. Every person
who is or hath beene an Alderman in any City within this Kingdome if he be below the degree of a Knight or
Esquire the summe of five pound&bholngs;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Officers of the Courts of Chancery and King's Bench.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Warden of the Fleet.; Officers of the Courts of Chancery.; Officers of the Court of Common Pleas.; Officers of the Treasury, Exchequer, Duchy Court, &amp;c.; Attornies at Law.; Officers in His Majesty's Household.; Single Persons above 16.; All other Persons not before rated nor receiving Alms.; The said Rates to be paid in London, and within 10 miles, within Six Days after Proclamation of A&bholigct;. In all other Counties, &amp;c. within Twelve Days</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that all and every such person and persons who is possessed
of any of the severall Offices or Places hereafter mentioned in their owne rights shall pay the severall summes
hereafter sett downe that is to say The Prothonatary of the Court of Kings Bench the summe of One hundred
pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Crowne of the Court of Kings Bench aforesaid twenty pound&bholngs;. The Custos Brevium
of the said Court forty pound&bholngs;. The Marshall of the Kings Bench fifty pound&bholngs;. The Master of the Rolls threescore
pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Crowne in the Court of Chauncery forty pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Rules in the
Kings Bench ten pound&bholngs;. The Warden of the Fleet fifty pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Hannaper forty pound&bholngs;. The
Master of the Subpena Office forty pound&bholngs;. The Clerks of the Inrollment ten pound&bholngs; apeice. The Usher of
the Court of Chauncery thirty pound&bholngs;. Every one of the Six Clerks in the said Court of Chauncery forty pound&bholngs;.
Every Cursitor of the said Court ten pound&bholngs;. Every Clerke of the Petty Bag five pound&bholngs;. Every Examiner of
the said Court ten pound&bholngs;. The Cheife Register in the said Court of Chauncery twenty pound&bholngs;. Every Under
Register the summe of ten pound&bholngs;. Every person that is admited as an Underclerke in any of the Offices of the
Six Clerks in Chancery the summe of three pound&bholngs;. The Clerks of the Chappell of the Rolls three pound&bholngs;
apeice. Every Prothonotary of the Court of Common Pleas the summe of fifty pound&bholngs;. The Custos Brevium of the
said Court fowerscore pounds. Every Philezer of the said Court ten pound&bholngs;. The Master of the Fine Office thirty
pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Warrants ten pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Outlawryes twenty pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of
the Kings Silver Office twenty pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Statutes twenty pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Treasury ten
pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Habeas Corpora Office ten pound&bholngs;. The Exigenter of the Citty of London forty
pound&bholngs;. Every other Exigenter in the Common Pleas five pound&bholngs;. The Kings Remembrancer in the Court of
Exchequer the summe of forty pound&bholngs;. The Lord Treasurers Remembrancer in the said Court the s&bhouov;me of ten
pound&bholngs;. Every of the Tellers of the Court of Exchequer twenty pound&bholngs; apiece. Every Attourney of the Court
of Exchequer belonging to the Office of the Kings Remembrancer ten pound&bholngs;. Every Attourney of the Office of
Pleas in the Court of Exchequer ten pound&bholngs;. The Remembrancer of First Fruits and Tenthes in the said Court
the s&bhouov;me of twenty pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Pipe in the said Court the summe of forty pound&bholngs;. The Forraigne
Opposer in the said Court the summe of twenty pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Estreates in the said Court the
summe of twenty pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Pleas in the said Court the summe of thirty pound&bholngs;. The Auditor
of the Receipt of the Exchequer the summe of forty pound&bholngs;. The Clerke of the Pell in the receipt aforesaid
thirty pound&bholngs;. The Usher of the said Court of Exchequer the summe of twenty pound&bholngs;. Every Attourney in
the Office of Pleas in the said Court of Exchequer ten pound&bholngs;. Every Auditor in the said Court ten pound&bholngs;.
The Clerke of the Court of the Dutchy of Lancaster ten pound&bholngs;. Every Auditor of the said Court ten pound&bholngs;.
Every Clerke of the Privy Seale ten pound&bholngs;. Every Clerke of the Signet ten pound&bholngs;. Every Attourney at Law
of any of the Courts at Westminster or in the Courts of Law or Equity within any of the Countyes Palatine of
Chester Lancaster or Durham or Marches of Wales the summe of three pound&bholngs;. Every person in any Office or
place under his Majesty (except his Majestyes Household Servants in ordinary) who receiveth the yearely fee of
ten pound&bholngs; the summe of ten pound&bholngs;. The Leiutenant of the Tower of London fifty pound&bholngs;. Every person that
can dispend in Lands Leases Money Stocke or otherwise of his or her owne proper estate one hundred pound&bholngs;
per annum the summe of forty shillings and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser estate provided it extend
not to persons under five pound&bholngs; yearely. Every person being a single person and above the age of sixteene
yeares the summe of twelve pence. And every other person of what estate or degree soe-ever he or she be
within his Majestyes Kingdome of England and Dominion of Wales not rated before in this present A&bholigct;, nor
receiving Alms, and being above sixteene yeares of age shall pay six pence. And all the severall persons of the
severall degrees ranks and qualityes before sett forth in this Bill shall pay the severall proportions and rates
appointed by this Bill [in manner &amp; forme<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] to be disposed of as in this present A&bholigct; hereafter is expressed that is
to say Every person of the severall degrees ranks and qualityes before mentioned within the Citty of London and
ten miles from the same shall within six dayes after proclamation made of this A&bholigct; in the accustomed places
within the said Citty, and the severall Countyes within the said distance respe&bholigct;ively pay the severall rates appointed
by this A&bholigct; to be paid by them, and every person of what degree ranke or quality soe-ever throughout the Kingdome
of England and Dominion of Wales within twelve dayes after proclamation made of this A&bholigct; in the accustomed
places of the severall Countyes shall pay the severall rates appointed by this A&bholigct; to be paid by them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Commissioners named</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i"/>
			</para>
			<para id="p10">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the authority aforesaid that for the better assessing, ordering and
leavying of the said summes of money soe limitted and appointed by this A&bholigct; to be paid as aforesaid all and
every the persons hereafter named, shall be and are hereby appointed constituted and authorised to be Commissioners
for the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places within the Kingdome of England
Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweed hereafter mentioned.</para>
			<para id="p11">Bedford</para>
			<para id="p12">For the County of Bedford Lord Russell, Robert Lord Bruce Sir Roger Burgon Sir Thomas Alston Sir
Humphry Winch Sir Samuell Luke Knight Sir William Palmer (<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) Sir Beauchamp S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Knight, Samuell Browne
Sergeant at Law, Henry Chester Esquire William Becher Esquire Oliver Luke Esquire William Boteler Esquire
John Keeling Esquire John Vaux Esquire Thomas Snagg Esquire Humphrey Monoux Esquire Richard Tayler
Esquire George Bloundell Esquire Stephen Anderson Esquire Walter Rolt Esquire, S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Tompson Esquire S<emph type="p">t</emph> John
Charnock Esquire James Biverley Esquire John Harvey Esquire Sir Robert Nappier Sir John Duncombe John
Neale Esquire John Nappier Esquire Thomas Cobb Gent. Peter Mallory Gent.</para>
			<para id="p13">Berks</para>
			<para id="p14">For the County of Berks Sir Edmond Sawyer Sir Richard Braham Richard Aldworth William Barker William
Hide William Trumball John Whitfeild Anthony Barker Henry Hen William Backhouse The Maior of Windsor
for the time being Richard Palmer of Ockingham Sir Thomas Draper Knight and Baronet Christopher Monck
Thomas Garret Thomas Dolman John Elwes, The Maior of Reading for the time being Philip Weston John Davis
Roger Palmer Do&bholigct;or Hungerford of Reading John Harison of Beachill Alexander Baker Robert Mason Edward
Keat Paul Colton Sir George Stonehouse Sir Robert Pye Robert Packer M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Dunch George Purefoy
Senior John Southby George Purefoy junior Thomas Fettyplace junior Francis Peacock John Peacocke junior
Francis Pigot Thomas Holt James Heron Richard Broadrick Barth: Yeat George Hide Thomas Saunders Thomas
Rich John Blagrave The Maior of Abingdon for the time being, The Maior of Wallingford for the time being.
Richard Powle Henry Pro&bholigct;or William Tayler William Bowls Leonard Bennet.</para>
			<para id="p15">Bucks</para>
			<para id="p16">For the County of Bucks Sir Richard Temple Sir Anthony Chester Sir Toby Tirrell Sir John Burlace Sir
William Bowyer Baronets Sir Richard Pigot Sir Heneage Proby Sir Ralph Verney Thomas Tirrell Richard
Winwood Richard Hampden Tho: Lee Richard Ingolsby William Parsons Charles Cheney John Dormer William
Burlacy Edmund Petty Richard Greenvill William Terringham Francis Ingolsby Thomas Risley Edw: Greenvill
Henry Andrewes Tho: Duncombe of Broughton Bret Norton Thomas Farrer of Brafield William Salter Tho: Proby
Gab: Ipesly Edmund Waller of Gregories Tho: Stafford Francis Saunders Wil: Abraham Wil: Fleetwood
Wi: Penne Edw: Russell of Abbots Aston Edm: West Bernard Turney, The Bailiffe of Buckingham The Maior
of Wickham Robert Lovet, George Tashe Nich Grice.</para>
			<para id="p17">Cambridge</para>
			<para id="p18">For the County of Cambridge Sir Will: Compton K&ntilde;t Sir Dudley North K&ntilde;t of the Bath Sir Fran: Russell
Sir Tho: Hatton Sir John Cotton Sir Tho: Willis Sir John Cuts Baronets Tho: Chichley Sam Thor[n<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]ton Tho:
Wendy Isaac Thor[n<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]ton Esquires, Sir Will: Russell K&ntilde;t Wil: Russell Es&bhoqesq; Wil: Legat John Millecent Hum: Gardner
Sam: Fortry Wil: Willis Thomas Ducket junior Rob: Hamond Hen Pickering Tho Story Esquires John Nordon
Mr. Bing of Grancester Wil: Barns Mr John Pearson Mr Pigot of Abington Jeofrey Nightingal Es&bhoqesq; Dudley Pope.</para>
			<para id="p19">For the University and Towne of Cambridge.</para>
			<para id="p20">The Maior of Cambridge Roger Pepis Recorder John Jenkinson John Rant Esquires Christopher Rose Alder. Do&bholigct;or
Pepis Tho Crouch Esquire Do&bholigct;or Eade Do&bholigct;or Pormant, Tho: Tifford Ald Rowl: Simpson Tho French Alder:
[Richard Timms Alderman<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Mathew Barlow Do&bholigct;or of Phisick Thomas Gearing Mr Goslin Mr Sammes Mr Gore
Mr Smithes.</para>
			<para id="p21">For the Isle of Ely</para>
			<para id="p22">Anthony Hamond Wil: Colvil Wil Fisher Rob Balaam Anthony Fisher Tho March [Tho<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Towers Edw Partridge
Rob Twells George Clapthorne Rob Clapthorne Tho Stewart Esquires John Wilson Tho Pearson Nicholas
[Stanford<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Gent.</para>
			<para id="p23">Chester</para>
			<para id="p24">For the County of Chester Cha les Lord Viscount Kilmorey William Lord Brerton Sir George Booth Baronet Sir
Rich Grosvenor Baronet Sir Philip Egerton Knight Roger Grosvenor Esquire Peter Venables Esquire Rich: Legh Esquire
Thomas Legh Esquire<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]<?bignore?> Tho Marbury Esquire Tho Manwaring Esquire. John Ardern Esquire Tho: Cholmondeley
Esquire Henry Bunbury Esquire Peter Leicester Esquire Rog Wilbraham of Derford Esquire Jonathan Brewen Es&bhoqesq;
Henry Brooke Esquire Edward Hide Esquire Roger Wilbraham of Napwich Esquire [William Massey Es&bhoqesq;.<ref idref="n10">10</ref>]
Edward [Legg<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] of Gayton Esquire William Lawton Esquire,(<ref idref="n12">12</ref>)</para>
			<para id="p25">Citty of Chester</para>
			<para id="p26">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester John Johnson Maior John Racliffe Recorder Charles Walley
Wil: Edwards Tho Thrope Rob Harvey Tho Cooper Wil: Ince Edw. Bradshaw Rich: Bradshaw Wil: Crompton
Wil: Bennet Rich: Bird William Wright Peter Leigh Rich Minshal Gerard Jones Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p27">Cornwall</para>
			<para id="p28">For the County of Cornwall John Trelawney Knight and Barronet Pierce Edgecomb Esquire Wil Scawen Esquire,
George Keckwich Esquire Henry Spoore Esquire James Bond Esquire John Moil Esquire Tho Wills Esquire Edw
Elliot Esquire Tho : Blight Esquire John Lampen Es&bhoqesq; Edmond Fowel Es&bhoqesq; Sir Chichester Wrey Baronet John Arundel
of Dulo Es&bhoqesq; Charls Grills Esquire Rich Martin Es&bhoqesq; Walter Langden Es&bhoqesq; Nicholas Glin Esquire Tho: Waddon Es&bhoqesq;
Edm: Philips Esquire Henry Spoor junior Es&bhoqesq; George Hele Esq Fra Nichol: Es&bhoqesq; John Pierce Es&bhoqesq; Wil: Cotton
Es&bhoqesq; Cha Rostcarrock Es&bhoqesq; William Spry Es&bhoqesq; Tho Kestel Es&bhoqesq; Sir Wil: Godolphin Knight Sir James Smith Knight
Tho Treffrey Es&bhoqesq; John Nichol of Trewayne Es&bhoqesq; Sir Peter Courtney Knight Jonathan Rashley Es&bhoqesq; John Carew of
Penwarden Es&bhoqesq; Oliver [Scawle<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Es&bhoqesq; Walter Kendal of Pelin Esquire Charles Trevanion Es&bhoqesq; Charles Boscowen Esquire
John Polwheel Es&bhoqesq; Christopher Cooke Es&bhoqesq; Na: Mohun Es&bhoqesq; James [Pead<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Es&bhoqesq; Sir Peter Killigrew Knight John Gregor
Esq Rich Carter Es&bhoqesq; Edmond Prideaux Esquire Peter Jenkin Es&bhoqesq; John Vivian Es&bhoqesq; Tho Hoblin of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Ennodei Es&bhoqesq;
Sir John Arundel Knight Humphry Noy Es&bhoqesq; Rob: Hoblin Es&bhoqesq; Nich Arundell Es&bhoqesq; John Basset Es&bhoqesq; Wil: Godolphin
Es&bhoqesq; Francis Jones Es&bhoqesq; Ezckel Arundel Es&bhoqesq; Wil Harris Sir Rich: Vivian Kn<emph type="p">t</emph> Wil: Pendarves Es&bhoqesq; Rich
Erisey Chr Bellot Es&bhoqesq; Jo Thomas (<ref idref="n15">15</ref>) Anthony Chineweth (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Fra Godolphin [Esquires<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] John Arundel of Sythuy
Wil Painter (<ref idref="n18">18</ref>) John Benithon of Cartlew [Esquires<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] John Carnson Es&bhoqesq; John Pendarvis junior Esquire Wil: Trevissa
Es&bhoqesq; Tho Hoblin of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Stephens Hugh Trevanion of Gerans Es&bhoqesq; Nath Trevanion Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p29">Cumberland</para>
			<para id="p30">For the County of Cumberland Col Cha Howard Sir Philip Musgrave (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Sir Patr: Curwin (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Sir Edw.
Musgrave (<ref idref="n22">22</ref>) Sir John Lowther (<ref idref="n23">23</ref>) Sir Wil Dalston (<ref idref="n24">24</ref>) Sir George Fletcher [Baronets<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] Sir Tho Dacres (<ref idref="n26">26</ref>) Sir
Wilfrid Lawson (<ref idref="n27">27</ref>) Sir Wil: Carleton [Knights,<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] Wil: Brisco (<ref idref="n29">29</ref>) Rich Tolston (<ref idref="n30">30</ref>) Wilfr Lawson (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>) Wil: 
Pennington (<ref idref="n32">32</ref>) John Lamplugh (<ref idref="n33">33</ref>) Francis Salkeld (<ref idref="n34">34</ref>) Dan: Fliming (<ref idref="n35">35</ref>) Joseph Patrickson (<ref idref="n36">36</ref>) Tho Wibergh (<ref idref="n37">37</ref>)
Henry Tolson (<ref idref="n38">38</ref>) Lau Fletcher (<ref idref="n39">39</ref>) Leon Dikes (<ref idref="n40">40</ref>) Wil: Orfure (<ref idref="n41">41</ref>) Tho Lamplugh (<ref idref="n42">42</ref>) Chr Richmond (<ref idref="n43">43</ref>) John
[Seanhouse of Nether Hall (<ref idref="n44">44</ref>) John Hudson (<ref idref="n45">45</ref>) Robert Heymore (<ref idref="n46">46</ref>) John<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Barwis (<ref idref="n47">47</ref>) Rich: Lamplugh (<ref idref="n48">48</ref>)
Wil Mawson (<ref idref="n49">49</ref>) Wil: Laiton (<ref idref="n50">50</ref>) Anth. Latus (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) Ar: Skaiffe, (<ref idref="n52">52</ref>) Ar: Foster (<ref idref="n53">53</ref>) John Studart (<ref idref="n54">54</ref>) Peter Norman
[Esquiers,<ref idref="n55">55</ref>] The Maior of Carlisle for the time being, John Caplenby Anthony Bouch.</para>
			<para id="p31">Derby</para>
			<para id="p32">For the County of Derby Henry Viscount Mansfeild Anchetill Grey (<ref idref="n56">56</ref>) Geo Pierpoint [Esq[uires]<ref idref="n57">57</ref>] Sir Tho Greasley
Sir Francis Burdet Sir John Harper Sir John Curson Sir Edw Cooke Sir Hen Every Sir Wil Boothby Baronets Sir John
Harper Sir Sa: Sleigh Knights John Fretchvil German Pole John Ferrers John Gell John Stanhop John Munday Ri
Cooke John Milward Walter Horton Geo Vernon Cha Agard Henry Kendall Gilbert Thacker Wil: Fitz-herbert Cha
Cotton Henry Gilbert Ni Wilmot Robert Eyre Ja Abney Jeru Bennet Geo Sitwel Godfrey Clarke Edw Peg: sen
Roger Allestry John Dalton Wil Woolley Esquiers J Spateman Henry Buxton Gent., The Maior of Derby for the time
being Thomas Sleigh Wil Willot Tho Yowl Aldermen there, The Maior of Chesterfeild for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p33">Devon</para>
			<para id="p34">For the County of Devon Sir Wil Morris Knight Secretary of State Sir Edw Seymour Sir Peter Prideaux Sir
George Chudleigh Sir Courtney Poole Sir Tho: Heale Sir Hugh Pollard Sir Fra Drake Sir Coplestone Bampfeild Sir
John Northcoat Sir John Chichester Sir John Davy, Sir William Courtney Baronets, Sir Edmond Fowel Sir John
Young Sir John Chichester Sir Thomas Stukeley Sir John Drake Sir John Clobery Knights Arthur Northcot Arthur
Basset Peter Prideaux John Roll William Stroud John Fowel Walter Young Edward Wise Thomas Reynal Josias
Calmady William Martin William Morris Thomas Southcoat Robert Fortescue Francis Drew, Richard Duke Robert
Cary John Heale John Willoughby Mathew Heale John Gifford William Fry Arthur Upton Henry Norley Servington
Savory Henry Worth Richard Coffin Thomas Carew John Tuckefeild Edmond Parker John Bury John Arsecot Thomas
Drake Nicholas Ducke William Bastard John Wollacomb Henry Ford Henry Walter Thomas Bampfeild Thomas
Clifford John Quick John Champners John Davy of Canon Ting John Hale Christopher Clobery Robert Shapcot Samuel
Trelawney Richard Beavis Robert Savery Nicholas Dennis Arthur Fortescue Edmund Fowel Thomas Bear Jonathan
Sparke Esquiers, The Maior of Plimouth for the time being, The Maior of Dartmouth for the time being, The Maior
of Totnes for the time being, The Maior of Barnestable for the time being, The Maior of Tiverton for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p35">Exon</para>
			<para id="p36">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Exon The Maior for the time being, Sir Thomas Mallet Justice of the Kings
Bench Christopher Clarke Simon Snow Robert Walker James Marshal Nicholas Brooking, Ralph Herman Esquiers
Alderman Martin Alderman Crossing, Richard Evans, Henry Gaudy John Mane Thomas Westlacke John Aikland
Walter Holditch Edmond Star.</para>
			<para id="p37">Dorset</para>
			<para id="p38">For the County of Dorset Denzill Holles Esquires Sir Anthony Ashley Cooper Baronet Sir John Strangewayes
Knight Sir Gerrard Nappier(<ref idref="n58">58</ref>) Sir Hugh Windham [Baronets<ref idref="n59">59</ref>] Sir Walter Earle(<ref idref="n60">60</ref>) Sir Ralph Banks [Knights<ref idref="n61">61</ref>]
John Fitz-James Esquire Robert Coker (<ref idref="n62">62</ref>) John Stroud [Esquiers(<ref idref="n63">63</ref>)] Sir Francis Holles Knight John Trigonwel of
Milton(<ref idref="n64">64</ref>) John Trigonwel of Anderston,(<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Giles Strangewayes(<ref idref="n66">66</ref>) Edward Hooper (<ref idref="n67">67</ref>) Thomas Freke, (<ref idref="n68">68</ref>) Robert
Cullyford (<ref idref="n69">69</ref>) John [Hanman<ref idref="n70">70</ref>] John Whiteway(<ref idref="n71">71</ref>) Thomas [Bynard(<ref idref="n72">72</ref>)] William Thomas<ref idref="n73">73</ref> Bullen Reymes(<ref idref="n74">74</ref>)
Edmond Hull,(<ref idref="n75">75</ref>) George Fulford(<ref idref="n76">76</ref>) Maximilian Mohun(<ref idref="n77">77</ref>) James Gold(<ref idref="n78">78</ref>) William Constantine,(<ref idref="n79">79</ref>) Robert
Freke(<ref idref="n80">80</ref>) James Smith(<ref idref="n81">81</ref>) Winstine Churchill(<ref idref="n82">82</ref>) Peter Hoskins(<ref idref="n83">83</ref>) Michaell Harvey(<ref idref="n84">84</ref>) Thomas [Chafe<ref idref="n85">85</ref>] William
Fautleroy(<ref idref="n86">86</ref>) John Abington(<ref idref="n87">87</ref>) Thomas Freke of Hinton(<ref idref="n88">88</ref>) George Pitt [Esquiers(<ref idref="n89">89</ref>)] George Stile Gent. George
Hussey(<ref idref="n90">90</ref>) Wolley Miller(<ref idref="n91">91</ref>) Robert Lawrence,(<ref idref="n92">92</ref>) William Oakeden of Churchill(<ref idref="n93">93</ref>) Arthur Radford(<ref idref="n94">94</ref>) Henry
Butler(<ref idref="n95">95</ref>) John Dolling [Esquiers<ref idref="n96">96</ref>] Anthony [Estrick<ref idref="n97">97</ref>] Gent., John Rogers(<ref idref="n98">98</ref>) George Trenchard (<ref idref="n99">99</ref>) John
Troublefield(<ref idref="n100">100</ref>) John Jefferies(<ref idref="n101">101</ref>) Thomas Moore(<ref idref="n102">102</ref>) Henry Henley(<ref idref="n103">103</ref>) Edmond Holles(<ref idref="n104">104</ref>) Thomas Hussey of
Yenson(<ref idref="n105">105</ref>) Thomas [Fawnes(<ref idref="n106">106</ref>)] Henry Whitaker(<ref idref="n107">107</ref>) Robert Seymor(<ref idref="n108">108</ref>) Mathew Davis(<ref idref="n109">109</ref>) William Chaldecot(<ref idref="n110">110</ref>)
John Saint Low(<ref idref="n111">111</ref>) John Still (<ref idref="n112">112</ref>) Richard Swaine(<ref idref="n113">113</ref>) Robert Napier(<ref idref="n114">114</ref>) Humphrey Bishop (<ref idref="n115">115</ref>) John Browne(<ref idref="n113">113</ref>)
William Floyer(<ref idref="n117">117</ref>) Robert Tiderley(<ref idref="n118">118</ref>) John Ellesden(<ref idref="n119">119</ref>) John Mitchell [Esquiers<ref idref="n120">120</ref>] Arthur Hooks(<ref idref="n121">121</ref>) Henry
Harbin(<ref idref="n122">122</ref>) William Ellesdon [Gentlemen,<ref idref="n123">123</ref>] The Maior of Dorchester, The Maior of Weymouth Edmond Butler,
The Maior of Shaston, The Bailiffes of Bridport.</para>
			<para id="p39">Poole</para>
			<para id="p40">For the Towne and County of Pool Sir Anthony Ashley Cooper Sir Walter Earle William Constantine Esquire
Recorder Haveland Hely Collonell William Skut Maior, George Skut, Richard Dolbery Moses Dunnell, Lawrence
Giggar, The Maior for the time being, Aaron Durel Robert Cleeves.</para>
			<para id="p41">Durham</para>
			<para id="p42">For the County of Durham Collonel Charles Howard, Sir Thomas Widdrington Sir William Darsey Sir George
Vane Sir Nicholas Cole, Sir John Conyers Sir Ralph Delavall Sir Francis Anderson, Sir William Blackston of
Newton Knight, John Hilton of Hilton, Thomas Davison Thomas Dalavall Francis Wreen George Lilburne Thomas
Bowes of Streattam Henry Lampton of Lampton James Clavering Robert Elleson Nicholas Frevell Anthony Bierley.
Thomas Bonner Thomas Shadforth, William Strother of Grindonrig Ralph Davison Thomas Lilburne John Heath
John Tempest Thomas Lampton The Maior of Durham, The Maior of Berwicke William Blakiston of Pittington
Cuthbert Carr Thomas Fetherston Esquire, Clement Fulthorp Esquire, Richard Raw Cuthbert Pepper Henry Eden,
James Cole Gent. John Shaw Gent. Thomas Swinburne, Nicholas Chayter, Robert Shafto Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p43">Yorke</para>
			<para id="p44">For the West Riding in the County of Yorke Thomas Lord Fairfax Lord Castleton Sir Thomas Widdrington
Sir George Savill Sir John Dawney Sir Thomas Slingsby Sir George Wentworth of Wowley Sir John Kay Sir
John Goodrick Sir Thomas Osburne Sir Richard Tankard Sir William Inglesby Sir Richard Maliverer Sir Solomon
Swale Sir John Armitage Sir John Lewis Sir Henry Cholmeley Henry Arthington William Adams Francis Nevil
William Lowther William Stockdale Edmond Jenings John Stanhop Thomas Stringer Richard Hutton. Sir Thomas
Wentworth John Bright William Spencer Thomas Yarbrough of Campsall Sir Christopher Clapham Walter
Calverley Brian Cooke Henry Fairfax Sir Miles Stapleton William Fairfax Alexander Johnson John Ashton Sir
Ralph Knight John Otway Sir John Yorke John Vincent Godfrey Copley Henry Atkison Thomas Lister John
Bines Sir Francis Fane William Farrar Sir Thomas Beaumont Charles Tanckard of Whixley James Moyser George
Payler William Lister Francis Goodrick John Riccard Sheffeld Clapham, The Maior of Pontefra&bholigct; for the time being,
The Maior of Doncaster for the time being, The Maior of Rippon for the time being, The Alderman of Leeds
for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p45">Yorke North Riding.</para>
			<para id="p46">For the North Rideing in the County of Yorke Sir Francis Boynton Sir David Fowlis Sir Roger Langley Sir
William Cholmeley Sir William Strickland Sir Robert Strickland Sir Christopher Wivell James Darcy Conyers
Darcy Sir Henry Cholmeley John Dodsworth George Marwood William Thornton William Weddall John Hutton
Sir William Dalton James Medcalfe Leonard Westall John Gibson Robert Layton Sir Henry Franckland William
Wivel Thomas Lassels of Allerton Sir Henry Stapleton Barrington Bourcher Sir John Dawney Charles Tanckard
Henry Bethel James Moyser Sir John Yorke Metcalfe Robinson Sir Jordan Crosland M<emph type="p">r</emph> Danyel M<emph type="p">r</emph> Francis
Driffeild M<emph type="p">r</emph> Jackson of Cowling, The Alderman of Richmond for the time being, William Aiscough William
Thompson Nicholas Bethel, Charles Allison.</para>
			<para id="p47">Yorke East Riding</para>
			<para id="p48">For the East Riding in the County of Yorke Sir Francis Boynton Sir Watkinson Paylor Sir John Hotham Sir
William Strickland Sir Thomas Rudston Sir Mathew Apleyard Sir Robert Hilyard Sir Thomas Remington Sir
Thomas Norcliffe Sir Francis Cob Sir Hugh Bethel of Rise, Sir Philip Mounkton Sir Hugh Bethel of Ellerton
Sir Henry S<emph type="p">t</emph> Quinton, Sir Thomas Heblethwaite William Gee Durant Hotham John Anliby Sandford Nevil Richard
Robinson Richard Darley John Legard William Osbaldeston Michael Wharton John Ramsden Tobias Jenkins
Mathew Alered John Alured Edward Wingate Ralph Thorpe, John Vavasor William Hursler Hugh Lister William
Wise Edward Barnard William Grimston, Thomas Grantham John Pierson John Stapleton John Heame William
Lister Robert Orm Robert Southby Stephen Thompson Arthur Noel Thomas Swann Thomas Crompton Christopher
Legard Gregory Creyk.</para>
			<para id="p49">Beverley</para>
			<para id="p50">For the Towne of Beverley in the county of Yorke Edward Gray The Maior of Beverley William Wade William
Forge William Colson William Dunne John Standliffe Timothy Gray Robert Fotherby William Newcombe Josias
Acklam Edward Gray the elder John Tod William Nelson Edward Gray the younger William Garthwaite Abraham
Burnet Thomas Gossupe George Davis William Hunter Robert Richard&bholngs;on Thomas Bucke Jeremy Hudson
Thomas Johnson.</para>
			<para id="p51">Headon</para>
			<para id="p52">For the Towne of Headon in the County of Yorke Elizeus Boufrey Maior M<emph type="p">r</emph> Burstal M<emph type="p">r</emph> Nathaniel Norris
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Suthick M<emph type="p">r</emph> Banchard M<emph type="p">r</emph> Oumbler M<emph type="p">r</emph> Barn M<emph type="p">r</emph> Burton Aldermen Robert Burstal Mr. Davyson
Bayliffes</para>
			<para id="p53">Kingston upon Hull</para>
			<para id="p54">For the Towne and County of Kingston upon Hull M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Ramsden Maior William Lister Recorder Thomas
Raiks Henry Barnard Francis Dewick Richard Wood John Rogers William Dobson Leonard Barnard Robert Ripley
Robert Berier William Foxley William Maister Christopher Richardson Aldermen Hugh Lister Esquire Christopher
Legard(<ref idref="n124">124</ref>) Esquires M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edmond Popple M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Moore John Ramsden Andrew Marvel Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p55">Citty of Yorke</para>
			<para id="p56">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke Christopher Topham Lord Maior of Yorke Thomas Lord
Fairefax Sir Thomas Widdrington Sir Thomas Harison Metcalfe Robinson Esquire William White Esquire Henry
Thompson Robert Horner Brian Dawson William Tayler Leonard Thomson Richard Paget Ralph Chater George
Monklin Aldermen Sir Miles Stapleton Sir Thomas Slingsbey Thomas Hutton Nicholas Blackebeard Robert Scot Cressey
Burnet Henry Thomson junior, William Ramsden Edward Gale M<emph type="p">r</emph> Squire M<emph type="p">r</emph> Elcock M<emph type="p">r</emph> Loftus.</para>
			<para id="p57">Essex</para>
			<para id="p58">For the County of Essex Sir Harbotle Grimston Baronet Speaker of the House of Commons Edward Russel
Esquire Sir John Barrington Knight and Barronet Sir Henry Apleton Sir Benjamin Ayloff Sir William Hicks Sir
William Wiseman of Canfeild Sir Andrew Jennour Sir William Luckin Sir Richard Everard Sir Martin Lumley Sir
Thomas Abdy Sir Robert Abdy Sir Henry Wright Baronets, Sir William Wiseman Knight and Baronet Sir John
Terrell Sir Robert Kempe Sir Thomas Bowes Sir Capell Luckin Sir Richard Wiseman Sir Anthony Browne Knights
John Brampston Edward Turner James Altham Roger Palmer Thomas Smith Charles Fitch Gamaliel Capel William
Kempe Carew Harvey Mildmay Thomas Fanshaw Charles Maynard Thomas S<emph type="p">t</emph> George Anthony Luther Oliver
Reymond Moundeford Bramster one of the Maisters in Chancery John Atwood John Paschal Edward Harris of Much
Baddow Tristram Conyers, John Shaw Henry Wollaston Thomas Argall Peter Soame William Glascocke of Farneham
Henry Pert John Eldred senior George Walton John Godbolt Robert Josselyne Thomas Luther Thomas Midleton
Richard S&bhoaovm;mes John Josselyne Thomas [Gamball<ref idref="n125">125</ref>] Thomas Gardiner William Umfrevil James Silverlock Benjamin
Wright Thomas King Francis Finch Esquiers, The Maior of Colchester for the time being John Eldred junior
Thomas Talcot Esquire John Radhams Thomas Reynolds, The Bayliffes of Maulden for the time being John Stevens
Samuel Plume Ruben Robinson The Maior of Harwich John Hunter Richard Smart.</para>
			<para id="p59">Gloucester</para>
			<para id="p60">For the County of Gloucester Henry Lord Herbert Sir Henry Fredericke Thynne Knight Sir Edward Bathurst
Baronet Thomas Master Esquire Henry Powle Esquire Andrew Barker Esquire William Bourchier Esquire John How
Senior Esquire John How junior Esquire, Thomas Escourt Esquire John Stephens Esquire Stephen Fowler Esquire
Silvanus Wood Esquire Richard Atkins Esquire Sir Hugh Midleton Baronet, Sir Robert Poyntz Knight of the Bath
Sir William Ducy Baronet Sir Richard Ashfeild Baronet Sir John Seymour Knight Edward Stephens Esquire Thomas
Stephens Esquire John Fettiplace Esquire Richard Stephens Esquire John Codrington Esquire Samuel Codrington
Esquire John Smith Esquire Robert Pleydel Esquire William Dutton Esquire, Sir Thomas Overbury Knight William
Leigh Esquire Robert Atkins Esquire John Chamberlaine Esquire Gabriel Lowe Esquire Thomas Chester Esquire
Edward Rich Esquire Christopher Guise Esquire Sir Baynham Throckmorton Knight William Cooke Esquire Henry
Capel Esquire Richard Dowdeswel Esquire William Dowdeswell Esquire Evan Seyes Sergeant at Law Walter
Rawleigh Esquire John Barrow Esquire Thomas James Esquire Thomas Hodges Esquire Richard Cooks Esquire
Richard Baugh Esquire The Bailiffes of Tewksbury for the time being William Wilson Gent. David Williams Esquire
Edward Fust Esquire William Thorpe Esquire Jones Esquire Bernard Turn.</para>
			<para id="p61">Citty of Gloucester</para>
			<para id="p62">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester The Maior for the time being William Singleton William
Capel Luke Norse Dennis Wise Thomas Pury senior Lawrence Singleton James Stephens Robert Tenther Robert
Paine Aldermen William Cock, Silvanus Wood William Selwin John Robbins Christopher Giese Esquire Sir Edward
Massey Knight.</para>
			<para id="p63">Hereford</para>
			<para id="p64">For the County of Hereford Francis Pember Esquire High Sheriffe of the County Wallop Brabuzon Esquire Sir
John Kirle Baronet Sir John Scudamore Baronet, Sir Edward Hopton Knight Sir Henry Lingen Knight Collonel Edward
Harley Esquire William Hinson a[ia]s Powel Esquire Roger Bosworth Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke Herbert Westfailing Esquire
Robert Harley Esquire Job Charleton Esquire James Pitts Esquire, Collonel John Birch Esquire Herbert Awbrey Esquire
Thomas Thompkins Esquire Bennet Hoskins Esquire Richard Hopton John Barnaby Herbert Perrot John Price
Thomas Price Roger Vaughan Robert Kirle William Dawsey John Skipp Francis Uvet Humprey Cornwell<ref idref="n126">126</ref> John
Scudamore James Scudamore Thomas Cox Rudehall Guillym Humphrey Tayler Humphrey Haworth John Scudamore
junior Walter Pye Francis Uvet John Cholmeley John Vaughan Thomas Rodd Thomas Whitney Humphrey Baskervile
Thomas Geers Fulke Walwin John Hawford Thomas Baskervile Richard Wigmore Thomas Wigmore Richard Rodd
Thomas Harley William Gregory Richard Reed Thomas Carpender William Bridges John Nourse [Frances<ref idref="n127">127</ref>] Pember
Timothy Coles Robert Crofts Esquires Edward Mathews John Vaughon Thomas Delahay Robert Davis Gent. Priamus
Davis Thomas Blaney Henry Milburne Charles Milburne Robert Stratford Ambrose Elton Ralph Darnell Robert
Miners Esquiers Andrew Greeneley Arthur Cockram John Bridges Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p65">Citty of Hereford</para>
			<para id="p66">For the Citty of Hereford John Hill Maior Roger Bosworth Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Herbert Westfayling Esquire William
Gregory Esquire Thomas Alderne Do&bholigct;or in Lawes Nicholas Philpots David Bowen Thomas Paynard Jerom Addis
Humphrey Diggs Richard Lyde Robert Symonds Thomas Homes John Smith.</para>
			<para id="p67">Hertford</para>
			<para id="p68">For the County of Hertford Sir Harbotle Grimston Baronet Speaker of the House of Commons Hugh Lord
Coleraine William Cecill Esquire William Willoughby Esquire Sir Thomas Leventhorpe Sir Brocket Spencer Baronets
Sir Richard Adkins Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Franklin Baronet Sir Thomas Fanshaw Knight of the Bath Sir
Thomas Dacres Sir Thomas Hewit Sir John Gore Sir John Watts Sir Francis Boteler Sir Rowland Lytton Sir Henry
Cesar Sir John Hale Sir Henry Conesby Knights Philip Boteler Thomas Fanshaw Richard Jenings Thomas Dacres
John Cesar Humphrey Gore Ralph Freeman Thomas Dockwraw Robert Slingsbey Humphrey Shalcrosse Ralph
Baesh Thomas Conesby James Cooper Arthur Sparke William Priestley John Heyden Edward Gardiner Robert Hale
William Glascocke Esquiers Richard Goldston Edmond Smith Edward Wingate William Hale Graveley Norton
Erasmus Harby Robert Sadler Edmond Feild Edward Briscoe Thomas Coppyn, John Halsie, The Maior of Hertford
for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p69">S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albanes</para>
			<para id="p70">For the Borough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albanes Sir Harbotle Grimstone Baronet Speaker of the House of Commons The Maior
for the time being Richard Jenings Esquire Robert Robotham Esquire John Pemberton Robert Pemberton Thomas
Oxton Robert lvory John Gape Robert New Gent.</para>
			<para id="p71">Huntington</para>
			<para id="p72">For the County of Huntington Robert Viscount Mandeville Sir Edward Mountague Knight of the Garter Francis
Compton Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Cotton Baronet Sir Thomas Leventhorpe Baronet Sir Richard Stone Knight Sir Robert
Bernard Knight John Cotton Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Hewet Baronet Henry Cromwell Esquire John Bernard Es&bhoqesq; Nicholas
Pedley Esquire Robert Appreece Esquire John Heron Esquire Richard Draper Es&bhoqesq; Lawrence Torkington Es&bhoqesq; John
Simcots Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Lionel Walden Gent. Robert Vinter Gent.</para>
			<para id="p73">Towne of Huntington</para>
			<para id="p74">For the Towne of Huntington The Maior of the Towne for the time being Sir Robert Bernard Knight John Bernard
Esquire Nicholas Pedley Esquire Lawrence Torkenton Es&bhoqesq; Richard Weaver Gent. Gervasse Fulwood Gent. Thomas
Ashton Gent., and Lyonel Walden Gent.</para>
			<para id="p75">Kent</para>
			<para id="p76">For the County of Kent Philip Viscount Strangford Richard Spencer Esquire James Herbert Esquire Sir Thomas
Peyton Sir John Baker Sir Roger Twisden Sir Edward Hales Sir Edward Moneins Sir Henry Palmer Sir Francis
Vincent Sir Howland Roberts Sir Edward Deering Sir Thomas Stiles Sir Charles Sidley Sir Nortin Knatchbull
Sir John Tufton Sir John Sydley Sir Richard Hardresse Sir Stephen Leonard Sir Heneage Finch Sir Bazil
Dixwell Baronets Sir George Sonds Knight of the Bath Sir William Man Sir Robert Honywood Sir Anthony
Anchor Sir Thomas Culpeper Sir John Darel Sir William Wheeler Sir Edward Filmore Sir Christopher Harfleet
Sir Arnold Braines Sir Robert Moyle Sir Thomas Ingham Sir John Boys Sir Theophilus Bidolph Sir Francis
Clarke Sir John Marsham Sir Henry Oxenden Sir William Leech Sir Robert Austin Knights [John Knathbul<ref idref="n128">128</ref>] Robert
Barnham Richard Masters John Wroth John Boys of Fredvile Nicholas Toke Thomas Flud James Brockman
Humphrey Miller William Cage Thomas Lambert, Edward Honywood George Newman Maurice Diggs Edward
Hales Edward Finch Phineas Andrewes James Thurbarne Peter Pett Thomas Peake George Curteys Richard
Amherst William Boys Thomas Lake Thomas Henman Anthony Hamond Richard Wilkinson John Horsemanden
William [Heuson<ref idref="n129">129</ref>] Philip Packer George Polehill Henry Crispe John Roberts Norton Curteys Henry Paramore
Thomas Broadnix Henry Sanford John Smith James Newman Charles Toke Henry Honywood Laurence Rooke,
Charles Wheler Robert Luckenor Peter Heyman [Henry<ref idref="n130">130</ref>] Thornehill Henry Deering Cranmer Harris Thomas Bret
Esquires, Francis Barnham Alabaster Flud John Cage Francis Twisden William Buggins John Henden Robert
Watson Richard Marsh John Golder Walter Franklin John Alin Maximilion Dallison William Maddox John
Mun Zouch Brockman Esquiers Increased Collins Robert Oliver The Maior of Rochester,</para>
			<para id="p77">[And for the Cinque Ports their Members and the two auncient Townes (that is to say) For the Towne and Port of
Dover with the Members thereof The Maior for the time being Richard Jacob John Goulder John Loome Jurats James
Newman Henry Petit Gent., For the Port and Towne of Sandwich The Maior for the time being Tobias Clere Thomas
Browne Jurats James Thurbane Towne Clerke For the Port and Towne of New Romney Robert Wivel Maior Stephen
Bret Thomas Shalcroft Jeremiah Stanfort Jurats For the Port and Towne of Hithe John Finch Maior Elias Basset
James Pashley John Basset Jurats, For the Towne of Folkstone The Maior for the time being William Jenkins Jurat,
For the Towne of [Feathersham<ref idref="n131">131</ref>] The Maior for the time being John Trout, John Upton John Knoller Jurats For the
Towne of Lid The Bailiffe for the time being Peter Godfrey Gent. For the Towne of Tenderden The Maior for the
time being Edward Finch [Esquire<ref idref="n130">130</ref>] Peter Short William Stretton Jurats For the Towne and Port of Hastings The
Maior for the time being Denny Ashburnham Esquire William Lovel Herbert Lunsford Jurats For the Port and
Towne of Winchelsea The Maior for the time being Samuel Gott Esquire John Sampson George Sampson Gent. For
Rye with the Members there of The Maior for the time being William Hay Gent. Marke Thomas Gent. Thomas
Palmer Jurat, For the Towne of Pevensey The Bayliffe for the time being Edward Peake Thomas Andrews George
Eastman Jurats For the towne of Seaford The Bailiffe for the time being Thomas Beane Thomas Harison Peter
Guard Jurats<ref idref="n132">132</ref>.]</para>
			<para id="p78">Citty of Canterbury</para>
			<para id="p79">For the Citty of Canterbury and County of the said Citty M<emph type="p">r</emph> Squier Beverton the present Maior Francis Lovelace
Esquire Recorder Israel Jacob Sheriffe Sir Anthony Aucher Knight Sir William Man Knight John Boys Esquire
William Stanley John Leigh Henry Twyman Richard May William Turner Edward Andrewes Aldermen Thomas
Hardresse Thomas Peake John Best Paul Barret Anthony Aucher Paul Epps Leonard Spratling Esquiers George
Mills senior Gent. Thomas Courtop Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p80">Lancaster</para>
			<para id="p81">For the County of Lancaster William Stanley William Spencer Esquiers Sir Richard Houghton Sir Ralph Ashton
Sir Robert Bindlosse Baronets Sir Gilbert Ireland Sir Roger Bradshaigh Knights Richard Leigh Richard Shutleworth
Ralph Ashton Richard Holland Richard Standish Thomas Norris William Farrendon Richard Kirkby Robert Holt
Thomas Preston Thomas Greenalgh William Hulton Edward Fleetwood Roger Nowel Nicholas Towneley of Royle
Lawrence Rawsthorn Thomas Braddell Hugh Dickinson John Starky Edward Rigby Alexander Rigby of Preston
Robert Rawlinson John Lightbown Robert Booth Nicholas Moseley William Banks junior Pierce Leigh Thomas Ashton
James Duckenfeild Cuthbert Ogle John Entwisle Henry Porter William West Nathaniel West Thomas Whittingham
Alexander Rigby of Layton Richard Fleet wood of Rosse Hall Thomas Cole William Radley John Rishley Christopher
Parker John Case John Cunliffe Butler of Kirkland Esquires William Wall Gent., The Maior of Lancaster
for the time being, The Maior of Preston for the time being The Maior of Wiggan for the time being, The Maior of
Leverpoole for the time being, The Bayliffes of Cliderow for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p82">Leycester</para>
			<para id="p83">For the County and Burrough of Leicester Thomas Lord Beaumont Viscount Swords John Lord Roos Bennet Lord
Sherrard Anchetill Gray Esquire John Gray Esquire Sir George Villiers Baronet Sir Charls Sidley Baronet Sir Thomas
Cave Baronet Sir Wolston Dixy Baronet Sir John Hartop Baronet Sir Thomas Halford Baronet Sir Erasmus de la
Fountaine Knight Sir Thomas Hartop Knight Sir William Hartop Knight Sir John [Pettyman<ref idref="n133">133</ref>] Baronet Thomas Merrey
Mathew Babington George Faunt Richard Lister Beaumont Dixy Edward Smith William Quarles William Whaley
Varney Noell Casibilan Burton Theophilus Cave John Cave Henry Hudson William Boothby George Pochin William
Jervis William Wollaston John Stafford Richard Roberts Thomas Stanley Richard Brudinel John Barwel Thomas Bradgat
William Burrow James Winstanley Thomas Charnols Thomas Armston Thomas Hood John Needham Thomas Goddard
Richard Halford Walter Rudings John Chamberline John Danvers John Hacket Thomas Caldecot Thomas Allecock
John Turvil Richard Orton Ferdinando Sacheveril Esquiers John Cley Maior of Leicester William Ward Dannet
Abney Alexander Baker Daniel Deacon Thomas Henshaw Francis Noble Aldermen Francis Smaley Gent., John
Boardman Gent.</para>
			<para id="p84">Lincoln</para>
			<para id="p85">For the parts of Linsey in the County of Lincolne Gilbert Lord Haugton George Viscount Castleton William
Pierpoint Henry Howard [Esquire<ref idref="n134">134</ref>,] Sir John Munson Sir Phillip Terwhit Sir Robert Bollis Sir Thomas Williamson Sir
William Hickman Sir William Wray Sir Thomas Ellis Baronets Sir Charles Bolls Sir Markham Lister Sir Robert
Barkeham Sir Edward Rossiter Sir Edward Aiscough Sir Thomas Meeres Knights Stephen Anderson Philip Terwhit
John Munson William Oldfeild Edmund Anderson Charles Pelham senior Charles Pelham junior Charles Hall Cecil
Terwhit William Whichcot Edward Maddison Adrian Scroope Henry Massenbeard [Drayner Massingbeard<ref idref="n135">135</ref>] Edward
Nelthorp William Marwood William Wooley William Broxholme John [Nelthorp<ref idref="n136">136</ref>] Theophilus Hart Theophilus Harnesse
Marmaduke Dorrel senior Marmaduke Dorrel junior Francis Goodrick William Bard John Barnard William Anderson
Robert Christopher Richard [Nelthorpe<ref idref="n136">136</ref>] Esquiers George Hely Esquire The Maior of Grimsby for the time being
Thomas Newton Alderman William Beardshaw Alderman Francis Finch Esquire, For the parts of Kesteven in the
County of Lincolne John Lord Rosse Robert Lord Willoughby Sir Thomas Hussey Sir Michael Armin, Sir John
Brownlow Sir William Trollop Sir Richard Earle Sir William Thorold Sir Robert Markeham Sir William Brownelow,
Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath George Sherrard Richard [Browneley<ref idref="n137">137</ref>] Anthony Thorold Thomas Hatcher Charles
Hussey Robert Pierpoint Edward King Christopher Nevil Esquiers Sir Christopher Clapham Erasmus Deline John
Hatcher Thomas Hall John Newton Edward Skipwith Charles Dimock John Buck John White Mollinex Desney John
Teigh Francis Wingfeild Thomas Welby William Hide Charles Halford John Saunders William Dolman Francis Hatcher
William Sevil Thomas Rands Humphrey Walcot John Icy William Tompson Mathias Browne Esquiers Thomas Ellis
Esquire James Ashton Thomas Audley Adam Cleypoole Esquire Richard Coney Esquire William Blith Esquire Henry
Hall Esquire Redman Burrall Esquire Sir Christopher Clapham Knight John Mason Daniel Thoroughgood Gent., The
Alderman of Stamford Philip Eaton Esquire Francis Finch Esquire, For the parts of Hollond in the County of Lincolne
Sir Anthony Irby Knight Thomas Ogle Thomas Hall Anthony Oldfeild junior Henry Harne Mathew Woolmer Esquires
John Empson John Tilson John Atkin Walter Johnson Adlard Pury Gent. Joseph Moore Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Thomas
Welby Francis Finch Esquiers Anthony Oldfeild senior Gent. John Jay Esquire, The Maior of Boston for the time being,
The Alderman of Grantham.</para>
			<para id="p86">Citty of Lincolne</para>
			<para id="p87">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne The Maior for the time being Sir Thomas Meeres Knight John
Mounson Es&bhoqesq; Robert Marshall John Becke Thomas Dawson William Hall Stephen Fowler Aldermen Robert Marshel
the Younger Esquire William South Gent. William Bishop Gent. Richard Kyet Gent., M<emph type="p">r</emph> Miller M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robinson of
Branston M<emph type="p">r</emph> Lodinton Alderman Henry Morley Gent.</para>
			<para id="p88">London</para>
			<para id="p89">For the Citty of London Sir Thomas Alleyn Lord Maior, and the Sheriffes of the said Citty for the time being Sir
Thomas Adams Sir John Langham Sir James Bunch Sir Richard Browne Sir John Robinson Knights and Baronets,
Sir William Tomson Sir John Frederick Sir John Lawrence, Sir William Wale Sir Anthony Bateman Knights Tempest
Milner Richard King William Bolton Edward Backwell Aldermen Sir Theophilus Bydulph Sir William Vincent Sir
Richard Ford Sir Thomas Chamberlaine Sir Thomas Bloodworth Sir Lawrence Bromfeild Knights John Joyliffe
Maximilian Bard Thomas Gower Peter Midleton Henry Dunster Esquirs Leiutenant Collonell Thomas Cox Leiutenant
Collonell John Alsop Major Edward Storey Major William Har [d<ref idref="n140">140</ref>]ley Collonel Cleggat Collonell Allot Deputy Abraham
Johnson Deputy Thomas Min Deputy Robert Hanson Deputy Staine John Saunders George Smith Thomas
Pearle Nicholas Pening John Browne Peter Mills Lawrence Blomely James Noel Richard Cliff John Mascall Richard
Rives John Bathurst Henry Hamson Geoffrey Norley Thomas King James Aberthawitt Andrew Mildlenon.</para>
			<para id="p90">Midlesex</para>
			<para id="p91">For the County of Midlesex Sir Harbotle Grimston Baronet Speaker of the House of Commons, Sir Edward
Nicholas Principall Secretary of State Arthur Annesly Esquire one of his Majestyes Most Honourable Privy Councell,
Sir Anthony Ashley Cooper Baronet one of his Majestyes Most Honourable Pryvy Councell, Sir Gilbert Gerrard Baronet
Sir John Potts Baronet Edward Russell Esquire James Shefield Esquire Sir Jeromy Whitchcot Baronet Sir Solomon
Swale Baronet Sir William Waller Sir Thomas Ingram Sir Henry Row Sir Thomas Allen Sir Thomas Rowe Sir Henry
Wroth Sir Thomas Hewet Sir Thomas Reynall, Sir Robert Fen Sir Edward Walker Sir John Poole Sir William Wheler
Sir Francis Gerrard Sir Philip Warwick John Carey John Glyn Sergeant at Law John Maynard Sergeant at Law,
Gilbert Gerrard Thomas Allen Henry Mildmay George Pitt William Roberts Nicholas Ranton John Huxley Allen
Broderick John Mainard Ralph Hawtrey Challoner Chute Henry Murrey John Browne Richard Peacock William
Domvile Thomas Hinshaw Thomas Harrison James Hawley Henry Barker Richard Powel Edwin Rich Edward Rich
William Jessop Joseph Ash John Page Robert Page Do&bholigct;or Thomas Cox Daniell Pro&bholigct;or Christopher Eyres John
Robinson William Dier George Day John Lane John Hutchinson John Rives Robert Nelson Christopher Abdy William
Northey William Gouldsbury Edward Pecke Richard Sherwin Michael Holman John Millet John Hawtrey William
[Greenvil<ref idref="n138">138</ref>] John Bourchier John Norwood James Norffolke Edward Roberts Captaine Buckner of Isleworth Sir Lancelot
Lake Sir Richard Franckling John Bennet John Baldwin M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Glascocke.</para>
			<para id="p92">Westminster</para>
			<para id="p93">For the Citty of Westminster and Libertyes thereof Thomas Lord Fairefax Sir Edward Nicholas and Sir William
Morrice principall [Secretraries<ref idref="n139">139</ref>] of State John Lord Viscount Scudamore Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir William Waller Sir
Thomas Hewet Sir Anthony Irby Sir John Trever Sir Philip Howard Sir Thomas Clergis Sir Francis Gerrard Sir
William Poultney Sir William Plater Sir William Wheeler Alexander Popham Henry Slingsby James Palmer George
Mountague Gilbert Gerrard Richard Everard John Browne Richard Sherwin Esquires James Parcall Thomas Morris
William Oxton Henry Kem Emery Hill Edmond Waters Brian Barniby Robert Maure Gent. Henry Pecke John Pye
Esquire Francis Lucy Francis Bacon Ralph Hall Thomas Tayler Ambrose Scudamore John Throckmorton Edmond
Warcup Henry Murrey Esquires John Clendon John Breden William Baker John Tong Robert Brough Thomas
Darling George Greene Gent Richard Knightley [John Ansley<ref idref="n140">140</ref>] Esquiers D<emph type="p">r</emph> Baber John Chase Humphrey Grove
Samuel Smith John Browne Anthony Hall [Edmond Pattison<ref idref="n140">140</ref>] Laurence [Cuthesen<ref idref="n141">141</ref>] Simon Pardue Thomas Stephens of
Westminster Gent. Griffith Bodurda Esquire Kelway Guidert Henry Field, Thomas Brompstead Edward Bowers
William Habberfield Thomas Colchester Richard Downing Gent. John Hooker William Clerke Esquire George
Meryfield Thomas Halfepenny Mathew Cely Gent. Thomas Bayles Es&bhoqesq; Richard Everad Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p94">Monmouth</para>
			<para id="p95">For the County of Monmouth Henry Lord Herbert Sir Edward Morgan Baronet Sir Trever Williams Baronet, Sir
George Probert Knight Thomas Morgen of Maughen Esquire William Morgen of Maughen Esquire Charles Vaune
Es&bhoqesq; Walter Rumnsey senior Esquire Henry Probert Esquire John Milburne Esquire Edmond Morgan Esquire Thomas
Lewis Esquire William Morgan of Pencreig Thomas Hughs Esquires Edward Kemeis of Kemes Esquire George
Gwynn Esquire Thomas Morgan of Lanfore Esquire William Herbert Esquire William Milburne Esquire Roger
Williams Esquire Charles Hughes Esquire Henry Morgan Esquire William Jones Esquire Thomas Williams Es&bhoqesq; The
Maior of Monmouth for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p96">Northampton</para>
			<para id="p97">For the County of Northampton Charles Lord de la Spencer Sir William Farmer Sir Thomas Dacres Sir Thomas
Cave Sir Samuel Danvers Baronets Walter Kirkham John Lyn Thomas Dove Sir John Langham Francis Quarls Sir
James Langham Maurice Tresham Edward Palmer Oliver S<emph type="p">t</emph> John of Woodford Lewis Palmer William Tresham of
Newton Henry Robinson William Wilmer Thomas Roan Thomas Catesby Toby Chancy Henry Howard George
Tresham John Bernard John Sires John Cartwright Richard Samuell the younger Samuel Jonis William Nailer
Henry Edmund&bholngs; Esquiers Sir Henry Yelverton Baronet John Crew Thomas Crew Richard Knightly Richard Saltingston
Esquires Sir John Norwich Knight and Baronet William Ward William Langham George Clerke [Brian Janson
Robert Clerke<ref idref="n140">140</ref>] Edward Farmer [Brian Johnson Robert Clerke<ref idref="n142">142</ref>] Robert Pargiter Thomas Blincoe Christopher Thursby
Philip Holman Humphrey Orme William Lisle Richard Rainsford George Mountague John Delavale Esquiers The
Maiors of Northampton Brackley and Higham for the time being William Selby Joseph Sergeant John Gifford Thomas
Mainard and Edward Collis Aldermen of Northampton.</para>
			<para id="p98">Norfolke</para>
			<para id="p99">For the County of Norfolke Thomas Lord Richerdson Sir Edmond Bacon Sir John Hobert Sir Philip Woodhouse
Sir Charles Mordant Sir Horatio. Towneshend Sir Richard Barny Sir Edward Barkeham Sir Nicholas Lestrange Sir
John Holland Sir John Palgrave Sir William Paston Sir Ralph Hare Sir John Potts Sir Robert Kempe Baronets Sir
William Doyley Sir Thomas Guibon Sir Robert Paston Sir William Hovel Knights John Cooke John Potts James de Gray
John Knivet Buts Bacon Nicholas Stileman [William Hewet<ref idref="n143">143</ref>] John Windham Thomas Rant Jacob Preston, Humphrey
Rant Edward Denny Roger Spelman Edward Walpoole Edward Pepis The Maior of Lin for the time being Brig
Fountaine Oliver Neve Thomas Townsend Richard Catlin Francis Cory Lawrence Oxburge Robert Steward Thomas
Dearham John Spelman Luke Constable Clement Spelman Samuel Hasnet Robert Long John [Aguish<ref idref="n144">144</ref>] Robert Sucklin
Philipp Beddingfeild Peter Gleane Robert Keddington John Kendal Robert Buxton Robert Baldock George Towsend
William Rant Leonard Mapes Maurice Shelton John Lovel William Crane Henry Reps Thomas Meadowe Edward
Barber Thomas Drury Robert Gansall Thomas Johnson senior Thomas Gooth George Ingland Nicholas Cutting James
Simonds James Johnson.</para>
			<para id="p100">Norwich</para>
			<para id="p101">For the County and Citty of Norwich The Maior for the time being Adrian Parmenter Henry Watts John Rayly
Bernard Church William Barnham John Man Thomas Toft John Salter Samuel Puckle Christopher Jay Roger [Mingley<ref idref="n145">145</ref>]
William Davy Esquire Joseph Paine Thomas Rant John Hoberd Francis Bacon Thomas Bacon Francis Cory Thomas
Cory John Earle Edward Chamberlaine John Norris Esquiers Justinian Lewin Do&bholigct;or of the Law The Sheriffe for the
time being Richard Wenman Robert Allen John Andrewes Thomas Johnsons William Tooke Nicholas Poynter Robert
Holmes Aldermen Robert Gooch [Francis Norris Thomas Norris<ref idref="n146">146</ref>] William Trendle Robert Bendish Edmond Cock
Augustine Brigs.</para>
			<para id="p102">Northumberland</para>
			<para id="p103">For the County of Northumberland Lord Viscount Mansefeild Collonel Charles Howard Sir William Phenwicke
Baronet Sir Ralph Delavale Baronet Sir Thomas Widdrington Knight Sir Robert Collinwood Knight Sir George
Downing Knight Sir Ralph Knight Knight Thomas Grey of Chillingham Esquire Robert Delaval Esquire Daniell
Collingwood Esquire Edward Fenwicke Esquire Robert Mitford Esquire Thomas Foster of Etherston Esquire William
Forster of Balmeburgh Esquire William Shafto Esquire William Strother Esquire Richard Forster Esquire Thomas
Lorraine Esquire Cuthbert Heron Esquire [William Middleton Esquire James Ogle Es&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n143">143</ref>] Henry Widdrington of Blacke
Heddon Esquire Henry Oagle Esquire Thomas Card of Ford Es&bhoqesq; William Fenwicke of Bywel Esquire Gilbert
Swinnow Esquire Richard [Scoal<ref idref="n147">147</ref>] Esquire, The Bayliffes of Morpeth for the time being Ralph Grey Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p104">Newcastle upon Tine</para>
			<para id="p105">For the Towne and County of Newcastle upon Tine Thomas Bonner Esquire Maior Robert Shafto Recorder
Robert Shafto Alderman George Dalson Marke Milbanke Christopher Nicholson John Emerson Henry Rawlin
Aldermen James Brigs Sheriffe Robert Ellinson William Calverley Richard [Stot<ref idref="n148">148</ref>] Esquire John Cosins Ralph Grey
Henry Maddison Ralph Jennison John Butler Thomas Davison Thomas Errington William Blacket William Rutter
Robert Rodham Ralph Car William Huntly Miles Man Merchants Robert Car William Wallis Edward Middleton.</para>
			<para id="p106">Nottingham</para>
			<para id="p107">For the County of Nottingham Wentworth Earle of Kildare Gilbert Lord Haughton Anchetel Grey William
Pierpoint Arthur Stanhop Esquiers Sir William Hickman Baronet William Willoughby of Warsop Esquire Sir
Thomas Williamson Baronet Robert Pierpoint Esquire Sir Jervis Knifton Knight and Baronet, Sir George Savill
Baronet Sir Francis Mullineux Baronet Sir Ralph Knight William Stanhop [Esquire<ref idref="n143">143</ref>] Henry Sucheverell William
Willougby Jervas Pigot William Clarkeson William Cartwriht of Sutton [Esquire<ref idref="n149">149</ref>] Robert [Buller<ref idref="n150">150</ref>] Esquire
Thomas Charleton [Esquire<ref idref="n151">151</ref>] Anthony Air A&bholigct;on Burnel Francis Leake Francis Stringer William Childers Esquiers</para>
			<para id="p108">The Towne of Nottingham.</para>
			<para id="p109">For the Towne of Nottingham and County of the same Arthur Stanhop Robert Pierpoint Esquires The Maior for
the time being Charles Hutchinson Esquire William Skevington Esquire John Marton Samuel Sulley Gent. John
Parker Alderman The Maior of Newarke for the time being, The Bailiffes of Retford for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p110">Oxon</para>
			<para id="p111">For the County of Oxon Henry Lord Viscount Falkland Thomas Lord Viscount Wenman Sir Thomas Pope
Knight Sir Anthony Cope Sir Thomas Spencer Sir Thomas Penniston Sir Francis Henry Leigh Sir Thomas
Chamberlaine Sir William Walter Baronets Sir William Waller Sir William Fleetwood Sir William Morton
Knights Sir Timothy Tirrell Baronets Sir Thomas Hoard Sir Francis Norris Sir Henry Jones Sir Edmond Bray
Sir John Robinson [Knight<ref idref="n152">152</ref>] James Fiennes Edward Hungerford William Lewis John Clerke of Northweston John
Clerke of Aston John Doyley Edmund Lenthall Esquires Sir John Tiping Knight Francis Wenman Robert
Jenkinson Vincent Barry John Osbaldeston William Cope William Stonehouse Thomas Hoard John Fettiplace
Litleton Osbaldeston Row Lacy George Berry Compton Read Robert Dormer Charles Hallaway George Chamberlaine
Broome Whorwood William Dormer William Shepheard William Cartwright William Draper William Knolles
David Walter William Barber Edward Atkins Esquiers Thomas Clayton Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke James Huxley John
Clerke of Aston John Doyley Edmund Lenthall Esquires Sir John Tiping Knight Francis Wenman Robert
Jenkinson Vincent Barry John Osbaldeston William Cope William Stonehouse Thomas Hoard John Fettiplace
Litleton Osbaldeston Row Lacy George Berry Compton Read Robert Dormer Charles Hallaway George Chamberlaine
Broome Whorwood William Dormer William Shepheard William Cartwright William Draper William Knolles
David Walter William Barber Edward Atkins Esquiers Thomas Clayton Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke James Huxley John
Taverner Francis Martin George Crooke Thomas Cobb Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p112">The University of Oxon</para>
			<para id="p113">For the University of Oxford Do&bholigct;or Thomas Clayton Do&bholigct;or John Mills [D<emph type="p">r</emph> Elliot<ref idref="n153">153</ref>] Do&bholigct;or Timothy Baldwin
Do&bholigct;or Richard Lydall Master Charles Halloway M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Halloway M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Aslin M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Rowney
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Jackson M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Crosse M<emph type="p">r</emph> Francis Bowman M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Harlewood M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Robinson.</para>
			<para id="p114">The Citty of Oxford</para>
			<para id="p115">For the Citty of Oxford Henry Lord Viscount Faulkland The Maior for the time being James Huxley Esquire
John Nixon Humphrey Whistler Aldermen Richard Hallaway Esquire Sampson White John Souch John Harris
William Potter Francis Haward Thomas Tiping Roger Griffith Gent.:</para>
			<para id="p116">Rutland</para>
			<para id="p117">For the County of Rutland Bennet Lord Sherrard Philip Sherrard Samuel Browne Esquiers Sir Thomas Hartop
Sir Richard Wingfeild Sir Eusebeus Pelsant Alexander Noel Edward Heath Christopher Browne Richard Halford
Abel Barker Edward Falkoner Richard Fancourt Ezekiel Johnson Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p118">Salop</para>
			<para id="p119">For the County of Salop Charles Viscount Kilmurry William Pierpoint Esquire Sir Thomas Harris Baronet Sir
Henry Fredericke Thinne Baronet Sir William Whitmore Baronet Sir Thomas Wolrich Knight and Baronet Sir
Francis Lawley Sir Walter A&bholigct;on Baronets Sir Richard Leveson Knight of the Bath Sir William Owen Sir
Richard Prince Sir Richard Otley Knights Henry Vernon Esquire Francis Keniston Charles Manwering Richard
Scriven William Fowler Esqrs Timothy Litleton Sergeant at Law Robert Charleton Thomas Whitmore Job Charleton
John Walcot William Oakeley Thomas Ketleby Vincent Edwards Thomas Powis Thomas Crumpe Edmond Waring
of Owlebury John Newton Robert Leighton Richard Leister Esquiers Alexander Midleton Gent. Roger Keniston
Francis Thornes William Jones Edward Powel Edward Lloyd of Lanvarda Rees Tanat Robert Owen William
Owen of Porkington Esquiers, The Maior of Shrewsbury for the time being Timothy Turner Samuel Jones Thomas
Jones Roger Owen Philip Prince Thomas Hunt Esquiers Thomas Heyes Robert Forster Gent. Samuel Wingfeild
Adam Otley Esquirs Francis Smith Thomas Lockier Gent. Arthur Weaver Thomas Holland James Lacon Philip
Eyton Francis Charleton Esquiers Andrew Hill Gent. Thomas Piggot Robert Sandford Rowland Hill William
Cotton Esquiers Thomas Lockhard Gent. Edward Ketleby The Bayliffs of Ludlow and Bridgenorth Wenlocke and
Bishops Castle for the time being Do&bholigct;or William Child one of the Masters of the Chauncery, Edward Bawdewine
Esquire Ambrose Gataker Edward Pulley Gent.</para>
			<para id="p120">Stafford</para>
			<para id="p121">For the County of Stafford Sir Thomas Leigh Knight Sir Harvey Bagot Baronet Sir Richard Leveson Knight
of the Bath Sir Edward Litleton Baronet Sir Walter Wrotesley Baronet Sir Francis Lawley Baronet Sir John Worley
Sir John Bowyer Sir Brian Broughton Knights Edward Bagot William Sneyed Gualter Chetwin Henry Grey
Gerrard Scrimsher Michael Bydolph John Swinfen Samuel Terrick William Chetwin Rowland Cotten Jonathan
Cope Charles Cotten Rowland Oaker Thomas Kinnersley Thomas Whitgrave John Chetwood Edward Maniwering
John Withall George Parker John Lane Anthony Rudyard William Colclough Thomas Crumpton Henry Stone
Thomas Fox Richard Piet Esquiers Edward Kellet Gent.: Walter Grosvenor Es&bhoqesq; The Bailiffes of Tamworth.</para>
			<para id="p122">The Towne of Stafford</para>
			<para id="p123">For the Towne of Stafford the Maior for the Time being Robert Milward Esquire Edward Wilson Simon Fowler
Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p124">For the Towne of Newcastle</para>
			<para id="p125">The Maior for the time being Alderman Burslem Thomas Bagnal Thomas Wood Aldermen Samuel Terick
Gent.</para>
			<para id="p126">Litchfeild</para>
			<para id="p127">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Litchfeild The Bayliffes for the time being Anthony Dyott John Hill
Daniel Watson Michael Bidolph Esquiers Thomas Minors James Allen Gent. William Jessin John Perkins
Henry Mott.</para>
			<para id="p128">Somerset.</para>
			<para id="p129">For the County of Somerset Lord Hawley Francis Pawlet Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Stowel Sir Thomas Mallet Sir
Henry Berkley Sir Charles Berkley Sir Maurice Berkley Sir Thomas Bridges Sir William Windham Sir George
Norton Sir George Horner Sir John Warr Alexander Popham Edward Phelips Edward Hungerford Hugh Smith
Francis Roll John Harrington John Mallet. William Prin George Speake Francis Lutterel John Simes Henry Rogers
Samuel Georges Francis Windham William Bull Peregrine Palmer. Thomas Warr William Helliar of Cooker
Edward Court John Hyppesley Thomas Piggot John Buckland Peter Royner Thomas White John Churchill Henry
Bull George Trevillian Richard Jones William Waldrald John Tynte William Basset John Banfeild John Cary
George Sidenham Esquiers The Maior and eldest Aldermen of the Citty of Bath for the time being The Maior and
eldest Aldermen of the Citty of Wells for the time being, The Maior and eldest Aldermen of the respe&bholigct;ive Townes
of Bridgewater and Taunton for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p130">The Citty of Bristoll</para>
			<para id="p131">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Bristol John Locke Alexander James John Guning Richard Vickris
Miles Jackson Joseph Jackson Richard Balman Walter Sandy Arthur Farmer Henry Creswick Nathaniel Calo
Robert Aldworth Francis Gleed John Pope John Lawford Richard Grigson John Knight the Younger Robert Can
Robert Vickris.</para>
			<para id="p132">Southampton</para>
			<para id="p133">For the County of Southampton with the Towne and County Charles Lord S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Sir Robert Haward Knight
Sir Henry Worsley Sir William Lewis Sir John Norton Sir Robert Dillington Sir William Meux Baronet Sir John
Dingley. Sir John Leigh Sir Hugh Steukley Baronet Sir Richard Kingsmill Sir William Kingsmill Sir Thomas Badd
Knights Richard Whitehead Richard Norton John Button John Bulkley Thomas Knowles William Oglander
Robert Billington Thomas Jervice John Richard&bholngs; Henry Wallup Henry Whitehead Edward Trussell George Pitt
Esquiers Sir Nicholas Stewart Sir Andrew Henley Baronets Leonard Bilson Francis Roll John Hooke Thomas
Cole John Trot Lawrence Hyde Philip Leigh Edward Goddard Giles Hungerford Francis Rivet Roger Gallop
Francis Tilney John Lloyd Henry Bromfeild William Pitt Arthur Bold William Collins Edward Norton Richard
Goddard John Woulveridge Edward Exton William Wither Robert Richbell William Stanley Edward Worseley
Benjamin Ruddiard Edward Hooper Edward Fleming Edward Hooper of Peare Tree John Ford Francis Leigh
Henry Tulse Perkinson Odber Edward Hayes Thomas Edmond&bholngs; Robert Oxenbridge Robert Goffe Richard Love
William Knapton William Bishop, The Maior of Winton The Maior of Southampton The Maior of Portsmouth The
Maior of Newport M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Horn The Bailiffe of Andover.</para>
			<para id="p134">Isle of Wight</para>
			<para id="p135">For the Isle of Wight Sir Henry Worsley Sir Robert Dillington Sir William Meux Baronets Sir John Dingley
Sir John Leigh Knights Robert Dillington John Richard&bholngs; William Oglander William Bowreman Esquiers M<emph type="p">r</emph> Francis
Leigh M Edward Worseley M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Ringwood Maior of Newport.</para>
			<para id="p136">Suffolke</para>
			<para id="p137">For the County of Suffolke Sir Fredericke Cornewallis Treasurer of his Majestyes Household Sir Dudley North
Knight of the Bath Walter Devereux Esquire Sir Edmond Bacon Baronet Sir Lionel [Talmouth<ref idref="n154">154</ref>] Sir Henry Felton
Sir John Barker Sir Robert Kempe Sir Henry Wood Sir John Castleton Sir Henry North Sir Thomas Darcy Sir
Jervase Ellis Sir Robert Cordwell Baronets Sir Henry Crofts, Sir Philip Parker Sir Edmond Pooley Sir William
Pooley Sir Thomas Beddingfeild Sir Edward Duke Sir Sackevile Glemman Sir William Doyley Sir John Pettus
Sir George Reve Sir Robert Brooke Knights Charles Cornewallis John Rouse Robert Brooke Henry Parker Isaac
Appleton Thomas Walgrave Thomas Bacon Thomas Cullam Charles Gaudy William Bloys Senior John Knevet
Richard Cooke Joseph Brand John Harvey William Bloys junior Peregrine Doyley Esquire Sir Thomas Bernardiston
Robert Brumbrick John Beningfeild Edmond Ferneley William Gooding Francis Theobald Edward Man Benjamin
Culter Joseph Beomont Peter Alderman Nicholas Bacon of [Cussord<ref idref="n155">155</ref>] Nicholas Bacon of Shubland Henry Bacon
William Gooch John Garnish [Thomas Terrel Thomas Leman<ref idref="n156">156</ref>] Henry Warren [Henry North of Laxfield Philip
Parkor<ref idref="n157">157</ref>] John Warner John Hanmer Hamond Claxton Edmond Harvey Thomas Steward Thomas Veze John
Thurston Robert Gosnel Thomas Scrivener John Rivet Robert Stile Henry Yaksley senior Robert Mallet Thomas
Dade John Dauntry (<ref idref="n158">158</ref>) Robert King Jeffery Barwell (<ref idref="n159">159</ref>) John Sicklemore Francis (<ref idref="n160">160</ref>) Robert Penning Humphrey
Moseley Edmond Parker Gardenor Webb Isaac Mothum Thomas Read John Bence Thomas Butts Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p138">Ipsewich</para>
			<para id="p139">For the Town of Ipsewich The Baliffs for the time being Nathaniel Bacon Francis Bacon John Smithier Nicholas
Philips Robert Sparrow Henry Whiting.</para>
			<para id="p140">S<emph type="p">t</emph> Edmond&bholngs; Bury</para>
			<para id="p141">For S<emph type="p">t</emph> Edmond&bholngs; Bury The Alderman for the time being William Turner Francis Browne Nicholas Batteley John
Sotherby Recorder Stephen Cooke Francis Godfrey</para>
			<para id="p142">Sudbury</para>
			<para id="p143">For the Towne of Sudbury The Maior for the time being William Byat Joseph Man John Warner.</para>
			<para id="p144">Albrough</para>
			<para id="p145">For the Towne of Albrough The Bayliffe for the time being William Shipman Richard Browne John Burwood.</para>
			<para id="p146">Surrey</para>
			<para id="p147">For the County of Surrey Francis Lord Aungier Sir Francis Vincent Sir Richard Onslow Sir John Lenthal
Sir Edmond Bowyer Sir Charles Howard Sir John Evelyn Sir William Haward Sir Daniel Harvey Sir John
Maynard Sir Robert Parkehurst Sir Walter Raleigh Sir Thomas Bludworth Sir Richard Stidolph Adam Browne
Henry Hilyard Arthur Onslow Nicholas Carew George Chute John Scot John Heale Roger James William Elliot
Christopher Buckle George Evelin Marmaduke Gresham Henry Weston Edmond Hoskins John Goodwin Edward
Thurland William Hoskins William Wimonsould Richard Delves Edward Lenthrope George Smith Dixy Long
Robert Holman Edward Bish Thomas Turgesse George Browne John Floyd George Duncombe Roger Duncombe
Vincent Randall John Thynne Roger Heath George Vernon Francis Duncombe John Westbrooke Richard West
Do&bholigct;or Turner Richard Hatton Richard Evelyn Robert Wood John Bromfeild Peter Delanoy James Burton
George Moore Giles Walcop Hugh Currer John Nobbs William Austin Anthony Thomas.</para>
			<para id="p148">Sussex</para>
			<para id="p149">For the County of Sussex Sir John Pelham Sir Henry Goreing Sir Charles Shelley Baronets Sir Thomas Dyke
Sir Edward Ford Knights Henry Goreing Herbert Springet Herbert Morley John Stapeley Denny Ashburnham
George Courtop John Leuknor William Morley George Parker John Byne John Fagg Thomas Midleton Hall
Ravenscroft Henry Pecham [George Stewart<ref idref="n161">161</ref>] Edward Blaker Nisil Rivers Edward Eversfeild John Forrington William
Garaway Thomas Bettesworth Thomas Grey Thomas Palmer Allen Carr Esquiers Thomas Peckham Walter
Pauley Gent. Peter Bettesworth of Fitzales William Baldwin Gent. William Gratweek Hugh Petter John Paine
Esquiers Thomas Bernard Gent. Christopher Coles George Edmond&bholngs; Richard Mill Edward Cooke Henry Onslow
Edward Mitchel Esquiers Henry Chowne Bre Chowne John Bakshall William Strace John Gratweek of Eatons Edward
Paine William Dyke Esquire Francis Selwin Thomas Foster Esquiers John Fuller of Walden Sackvile Groves George
Nevil Esquire Walter Henley Anthony Shurley Esquiers Richard Bridger Ambrose Trayton Walter Burrel John
Oliver Anthony Stapeley Esquire Anthony Spriget Esquire Thomas Beard Roger Showeswell Esquire Edward
English Robert Fowler Edward May Esquire Edward [Petthill<ref idref="n162">162</ref>] John Dunk Thomas Sackvil John Dyne Walter
Everinden The Maior of Chichester for the time being Richard Shepherd Thomas Gratwicke of Morleyes Thomas
Bromfeild the elder William Gratweeke of Jervis Samuel Gott Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p150">Worcester</para>
			<para id="p151">For the County of Worcester George Coventree Esquire Sir William Russel Sir Henry Litleton Sir John
Packington Sir Thomas Rous Sir Gilbert Cornewall Baronets Sir Ralph Clare Knight of the Bath Sir Henry
Herbert [Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<ref idref="n163">163</ref>] Sir Rowland Berkley Sir John Windford Sir John Talbot Knights Edward Pits Samuel Sand&bholngs; William
Ligon John Egiock Henry Bromley of Holt Thomas Savage of Emley Sherrington Talbot Francis Finch Samuel
Sandis junior William Sheldon of Broadway Edward Rous Henry Bromley of Upton Edward Dingley Thomas
Foley Thomas Childe Henry Jefferies Richard Dowdeswell Philip Brace John Nanfan Philip Parsons William
Washburne George Symonds Richard Greves Edward Pennel Nicholas A&bholigct;on Edward Vernon John Bearcroft
Esquiers, The Maior of Evesham for the time being Theophilus Andrewes Esquire, The Bayliffes of Drotwich for
the time being John Allen of Drotwich Esquire Edward Wheeler Esquire The Bayliffe of Bewdley for the time
being Edward Carew Edward Bushel Thomas Watson Henry Towneshend Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p152">Worcester Citty</para>
			<para id="p153">For the Citty of Worcester Edward Ashby Maior John Nash Henry Ford Aldermen Edward Solley Richard
Carwardine Richard Henning Robert Sollers John Higgins William Smith John Bearcroft Thomas Piercey Thomas
Street [the<ref idref="n163">163</ref>] younger Humphrey Tyrer Gent. Thomas Hall Thomas Streete Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p154">Warwicke.</para>
			<para id="p155">For the County of Warwicke Kildare Lord Digby George Fane Esquire Charles Leigh Esquire Sir Robert Holt
Baronet Sir Richard Temple Sir Henry Puckering Sir Clement Fisher Sir Francis Lawley Sir Edward [Broughton<ref idref="n164">164</ref>] Sir
John Knightley Sir John Shugburch Baronets Sir Charles Adderley Knight Sir Francis Willoughby Sir Charles Lee
Sir William Underhil Sir George Browne Sir William Palmer Knights Richard Newdegate Sergeant at Law Richard
Lucy William Somervil Thomas Gibbs Clement Throckmorton Thomas Archer Francis Fisher John Lisle Clement
Throckmorton junior John Rous Thomas Marriot Thomas Temple William Dilke Charls Bentley John Fetherston
Thomas Flint William Booth Humphrey Jenings Thomas Fox Mathew Bridges Esquiers The Bayliffe of Tamworth for
the time being.</para>
			<para id="p156">Coventry</para>
			<para id="p157">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventy Richard Hopkins Esquire, Basil Feilding William Jesson Robert
Beake Maior Thomas Norton Esquires Mathew Smith Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p158">Warwicke</para>
			<para id="p159">For the Towne of Warwicke The Bayliffe for the time being Mathew Holbeck Es&bhoqesq; Roger Redes Gent.</para>
			<para id="p160">Wilts</para>
			<para id="p161">For the County of Wilts Denzell Holles one of his Majestyes honourable Privy Councell Sir Anthony Ashley Cooper
one of His Majestyes honourable Privy Councel Charles Seymoure Sir Robert Hyde Knight one of the Justices of
the Common Bench Sir Walter S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Sir Seymore Pile Sir George Grobhamhow Sir Hugh Speake Baronets Sir
James Thyn Sir Thomas Thin Sir John Granvil Sir John Evelin Sir Thomas Hall Sir Edward Poole Sir John Talbot
Knights Edward Tooker Richard Grobhamhow Walter Earneley Alexander Thistlewhait [senior<ref idref="n165">165</ref>] Giles Tooker Giles
Eyre [senior<ref idref="n165">165</ref>] John Bulkley Francis Swanton [Giley<ref idref="n166">166</ref>] Eyre [junior<ref idref="n167">167</ref>] Seymour Bowman Wadham Windham Edward
Manning John Mompesson Thomas Hawles Edward S<emph type="p">t</emph> Barbe William Swanton Joseph Stockman Edward Top John Low
Gilbert Raleigh Rowland Platt John Davenant Thomas Darell Henry Eyre Henry Clerke Alexander Popham Henry
Hyde John Earneley [junior<ref idref="n167">167</ref>] Ralph Frecke William [Hannell<ref idref="n168">168</ref>] John Playdell John Norden Jeffery Daniell John
Fitzherbert James Ash William Fisher William Sadler Nevill Maskline John Hawkins Robert Hippesley Edward
Carter Duke Stonehouse John Foyle John Collins William Thomas Thomas Gape Francis Wroughton William Yorke
Thomas Grub John Kent Robert Nicholas John Long Thomas Gore of Alberton Edward Not Edward Bainton
Edward Hungerford of Farley Castle Edward Hungerford of Caddenham Lawrence Washington George Ayloffe
Richard Southby Thomas Escourt George Ivy George Lowe Richard Escourt William Jordon John Eyre Anthony
Hungerford Richard Lewis William Brownker Henry Long Benjamin Gifford William Willoughby Thomas Mompesson
of Corton Thomas Grove Edward Yerbury William Eyre Thomas Bennet Edward Hyde Edward Medlecott John Eliot
William Ducket John Escourt James Mountegue John Danvers John Abury Walter Long Henry Hungerford Richard
Greene Thomas Bennet of Pithouse John Bennet.</para>
			<para id="p162">Sarum</para>
			<para id="p163">For the Citty of New Sarum The Maior for the time being Sir Robert Hyde Knight one of the Justices of the
Common Bench Edward Tooker Wadham Windham Francis Swanton John Holt Thomas Chafin Thomas Ovyat
Thomas Cutler Edward Edmund&bholngs; Thomas Ray [senior<ref idref="n165">165</ref>] Walter Earneley William Swanton Christopher Batt
Thomas Darrel,</para>
			<para id="p164">Westmerland</para>
			<para id="p165">For the County of Westmerland Sir Philip Musgrave Sir William Dalston Sir Richard Sandford [Sir John Lowther<ref idref="n169">169</ref>]
Sir John Lowther [junior<ref idref="n167">167</ref>] Baronets Sir Christopher Clapham Knight Richard Musgrave John Lowther John Dalston
Richard Braithwait [junior<ref idref="n167">167</ref>] Christopher Dudley Thomas Sandford Robert Hilton Lancelot Maitchell Edward Nevison
Allen Bellingham Richard Braithwaite Daniel Fleming James Ducket Thomas Braithwait Edward Wilson Henry Wilson
John Otway Esquiers, The Maior of Kendall for the time being Thomas Sand&bholngs; Gent.</para>
			<para id="p166">Anglesey</para>
			<para id="p167">For the Isle of Anglesey Robert Lord Viscount Bulkley Thomas Bulkley Esquire Sir Hugh Owen Sir John Carter
John Glynn Sergeant at Law Nicholas Bagnell Esquire John Bodnel Pierce Lloyd senior Pierce Lloyd junior Thomas
Wood Thomas Robinson William Bolda Richard Mairick Richard Owen Theodore Esquiers M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Win Bodywrid
Rowland Bulkley John Griffith Rowland White Griffith Bodurda Esquiers M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Owen Mathlie M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Lloyd
M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Owen Penrose M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Lewis Kemlin, The Maior of Beaumaris for the time being M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Jones
M<emph type="p">r</emph> David Lloyd</para>
			<para id="p168">Brecon</para>
			<para id="p169">For the County of Brecon Sir William Lewis Baronet Sir Henry Williams Baronet Herbert Price Thomas Lewis
Milburne Williams John Jefferies Henry Williams of Cabalva Esquiers Thomas Williams Recorder of Brecon Edward
Williams Walter Vaughan Esquiers William Thomas Bailiffe of Brecon Meridith Lewis James Watkins Hugh Powell
James Penry Thomas Bowen John Herbert George Gwin Rowland Lloid Thomas Williams John Stidman Morgan
Aubury Es&bhoqesq;s.</para>
			<para id="p170">Cardigan</para>
			<para id="p171">For the County of Cardigan Sir Richard Price Sir Walter Lloid Sir Francis Lloid James Lewis [senior<ref idref="n165">165</ref>] James Lewis
[junior<ref idref="n167">167</ref>] John Vaughan John Jones James Jones Roger Palmer Robert Birt Reignald Jenkins William Lloid Richard
Jones John Lloyd Thomas Powell Thomas Lewis John Lewis John Bowen.</para>
			<para id="p172">Carmarthen</para>
			<para id="p173">For the County of Carmarthen Arthur Annesley Esquire Francis Lord Vaughan Sir Erasmus Philips Sir Edward
Mansil Baronet Sir Sackvile Crow Knight Sir Francis Lloyd Roger Lort Howel Guin John Lloyd Nicholas Williams
Rowland Guin of Glanbraen George Jones Sir Edward Rice David Morgan Henry Mansel Thomas Lloyd of Duneralt
John Vaughan of Llanelly Thomas Lloyd of Lanlauddog Thomas Evans John Powell Charles Guin Thomas Williams
Richard Guin Owen Price John Evans John Philips Morgan Lloyd Thomas Guin Lewis Lloyd William Williams
Daniell Lloyd Esquires John Vaughen of Golden Grove John Vaughan of Court Francis Jones John Lewis John
Powell junior Anthony Mansell Philip Vaughan James Jones Thomas Morgan Humphrey Browne Henry Vaughan of
Derwide John Vaughan junior of Whitehouse Owen Brigstocke Esquire Evan Thomas of Langhorne Walter Vaughan
Gent., Walter Jones Esquire John Hughes Maior of Carmarthen Robert Birt William Slowman Griffith Bynon Daukins
Gough Anthony Jones Aldermen John Hughes senior Alderman Feines Walter Thomas Henry Midleton John Harris
William Guin.</para>
			<para id="p174">Carnarvan</para>
			<para id="p175">For the County of Carnarvan Robert Lord Viscount Bulkley Sir Owen Win Sir John Owen John Glin Sergeant
at Law Sir Richard Lloyd Sir Roger Mostin Sir John Carter Richard Wyn John Bodvel Griffith Jones Nicholas
Bagnall Sir Griffith Williams William Glyn William Griffith of Lyn William Vaughan Robert Win of Ystquckegid
Thomas Win William Hookes Hugh Wyn Robert Williams [John<ref idref="n170">170</ref>] Bodurda Edmund Glyn Thomas Vaughan Robert
Coitmore Owen Griffith Owen Wyn John Williams Esquiers M<emph type="p">r</emph> Hugh Bodurda Nicholas Baley Es&bhoqesq; M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Wyn
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Griffith M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Williams M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Lloyd of Nangwunable M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Spicer M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Arthur
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Evan Lloyd M<emph type="p">r</emph> Jeffery Williams.</para>
			<para id="p176">Denbigh</para>
			<para id="p177">For the County of Denbigh Sir John Salisbury Sir William Merideth Sir Thomas Powell Sir Evan Lloyd Sir
Edward Broughton Baronets Sir Thomas Midleton Sir Richard Lloyd Sir John Trevor Sir John Carter Sir Thomas
Trevor Sir Robert Hagborough Knights Thomas Midleton Simon Thelwel John Trevor John Robinson Bevis Lloyd
Richard Wynn Charles Salisbury Roger Grosvenor Thomas Terrel John Thelwell John Jefferies Eubal Thelwell
John Edisbury Hugh Wyn of Barthee Richard Midleton William Owen Charles Midleton John Wyn of Whatstey
Robert Wyn of Voylas Robert Price of Geeler Thomas Ravenscroft David Maurice of Penybont John Lloyd of
[Llanquys<ref idref="n171">171</ref>] Edward Maurice of Loran Kenrick Eaton Foulke Midleton Watkin Kiffin Samuell Jones William Price
John Wyn of Meley William Parry John Dolben Charles Goodman Thomas Holland Peter Foulks Edward Thelwell
of Lanbodar Thomas Price John Puleston Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p178">Flint</para>
			<para id="p179">For the County of Flint Sir Thomas Hanmer Baronet Sir Thomas Midleton Sir John Trevor Sir John Carter
John Glin Sergeant at Law Thomas Midleton Roger Mostin of Mostin John Trevor William Price Henry Conway
Mutton Davice Thomas Ravenscroft Roger Pulleston Baron Edwards Robert Davis Mutton Davis John Eaton John
Salisbury William Mostin Thomas Lloyd of Halton William Hanmer of Fenns Thomas Humphreys William Glyn
Robert Whitley Robert Mostin David Pennant Peter Griffith of Caerust Owen Barton Thomas [Cluchley<ref idref="n172">172</ref>] Hugh Pennant
Andrew Ellis Peter Foulks Luke Lloyd Thomas Dymocke Richard Young John Lloyd of Farm Esquiers Peter Foulks
of Maradocke William Griffith of Panty Loundis Samuell Mostin Eubal Hughes Roger Grosvener Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p180">Glamorgan</para>
			<para id="p181">For the County of Glamorgan Sir Edward Mansell Sir Edward Thomas Sir John Aubrey Baronets Sir Thomas
Lewis Sir Richard Basset Knights David Jenkins Robert Thomas William Lewis Edmond Thomas Miles Button William
Thomas William Herbert William Basset Esquiers Evan Seyes Sergeant at Law William Basset of Myskin the elder
Humphrey Windham Bussey Mansell Herbert Evens David Mathew Thomas Mathew Thomas Stradling senior Robbert
Button Gabriell Lewis Thomas Carne Thomas Thomas Richard Lougher John Avon Edmond Gammage John Windham
Lambrock Stradling Edward Mathew Walter Thomas Edward Turbervil John Carne Henry Basset John Price, Charles
Bowen Richard Davies Edward Mansell Henry Hill Richard Seys John Gibs.</para>
			<para id="p182">Merioneth</para>
			<para id="p183">For the County of Merioneth William Price William Vaughan William Salisbury Maurice Wyn of Crogan Howell
Vaughan of Glan Yllin John Lloyd of Maes Pandi William Vaughan of Caithley Lewis Lloyd Robert Wyn Edmond
Meyrick Lewis Owen Richard Anwell John Vaughon of Keren Bodge Humphrey Hughs Morrice Williams Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p184">Mountgomery</para>
			<para id="p185">For the County of Mountgomery Sir Mathew Price Baronet Sir Thomas Midleton Sir Edward Lloyd Knights Andrew
Newport Roger Palmer Thomas Midleton John Purcel John Blaney John Pugh Richard Herbert Richard Owen
Francis Buller John Price of Parke Mathew Morgans William Penrhin Roger Mostin John Blodwell Robert Lee
Thomas Wind Edward Evans John Newton William Oakeley Edmond Wareing John Mathewes Thomas Corbet
Thomas Morris Brockwell Griffiths Edward Lloyd of Maesmawer Francis Fitzherbert Thomas Jones Es&bhoqesq;s John
Wittingham David Powell Thomas Jukes Eubald Edwards Thomas Lloyd of Glenhaven John [Giffin<ref idref="n173">173</ref>] Arthur Weaver
John Oakley Samuel Biggs Edward Edwards Edmond Lloyd Gent.</para>
			<para id="p186">Pembrooke</para>
			<para id="p187">For the County of Pembrooke Sir Erasmus Phillips Sir John Stepney Baronets Sir Hugh Owen Knight and Baronet
George Haward Rowland Langhorne Essex Mericke Roger Lort Arthur Owen Henry White Lewis Barlow Hugh Bowen
Hugh Boteler William Philips Herbert Perrot William Scourfeild James Bowen Thomas Parrey John Lort James Lloid
Thomas Wogan of Lanstinan John Maltuas Thomas Cosens Isaac Lloid John Elliot the elder Isaac Loyd Esquiers The
Maior of Pembrooke for the time being Richard Browne Alderman, The Maior of Tenbigh for the time being, John
Proderough Alderman Collonell Edward Freeman.</para>
			<para id="p188">Haverford West</para>
			<para id="p189">For the Towne and County of Haverford West Henry Jones Maior Sir John Stepney Baronet Sir Hugh Owen Knight
and Baronet George Haward Esquire William Philips Arnold Thomas Isaac Lloyd Esquiers William Williams Henry
Bowen Thomas David&bholngs; Richard Bateman William Walter William Howell William David&bholngs; Alderman Mathew Prynn
John Williams.</para>
			<para id="p190">Radnor</para>
			<para id="p191">For the County of Radnor Arthur Annesley Esquier Edward Harley George Guin Robert Harley Richard Fowler
Henry Williams Thomas Lewis Esquiers James Price Nicholas Tayler Robert Martin Thomas Corbet Evan Davis
Samuell Powell Henry Probert Charles Lewis Griffith Jones Andrew [Phillyes<ref idref="n174">174</ref>] Herbert Weston Thomas Lewis junior
Hugh Lewis John Richard&bholngs; senior Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p192">Berwicke upon Tweed</para>
			<para id="p193">For the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede The Maior for the time being Sir Thomas Widdrington Knight Edward
Gray John Rushworth Esquiers John Sleigh Benjamin Clerke Andrewe Crispe Ralph Salkeild Thomas Watson Stephen
Jackson Alderman Roger Armorer Thomas Dickenson Marke Scot James Scot Edward Salkeild Elias Prat
Robert Turvon.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>V. Commissioners may execute A&bholigct; without further Commission.</head>
			<para id="p194">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may divide themselves; and dire&bholigct; Precepts to Inhabitants, &amp; c. to appear, and at such Appearance read the said Rates, and charge them how to make their Certificates, &amp;c.; and after such Charge prefix another Day and Place for Appearance &amp; bringing in Certificate Penalty 40s. ; Commissioners to make Precept to Colle&bholigct;ors containing Names of Persons Presented in Certificate.; Commissioners suspe&bholigct;ing Value of Estates; to set Rate Persons refusing to pay Rate; Officers may distrain.; If Rate not paid within Four Days, Distress appraised and sold for Payment of Rates, &amp;c. Overplus paid to Owner of Good&bholngs;. Officer charged only for his Portion; and to pay same to Commissioners; Commissioners to pay same to Sheriff; Sheriff to pay same to Treasurers.; Rates paid in current Money</emph>.
</para>
			<para id="p195">And Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained that the [severall<ref idref="n175">175</ref>] Commissioners aforesaid shall have full power and
authority by vertue of this A&bholigct; without any further Commission to putt the effe&bholigct; of this A&bholigct; in execution and in order
thereunto shall in their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places meete together at the most
usuall and common place of meeting within each of the said Countyes Cittyes Burroughs Townes and Places respe&bholigct;ively
within foure dayes after the proclayining of this A&bholigct;, and the said Commissioners or soe many of them as shall be
present at the said first generall meeting or the major part of them may by their consents and agreements sever themselves
for the execution of this A&bholigct; in Hundreds Rapes Wapentakes Wards Townes and other places within their limits [in such
manner &amp; forme<ref idref="n175">175</ref>] as to them shall seeme expedient and shall dire&bholigct; their severall or joynt precept or precepts to such
Inhabitants High Constables Petty Constables Bailiffes and other like Officers and Ministers and such number of them
and as in and by this A&bholigct; is appointed, and at such their appearances the said Commissioners or soe many of them as
shall be therunto appointed shall openly read or cause to be read unto them the said rates in this A&bholigct; mentioned, and
openly declare the effe&bholigct; of their charge unto them, and how and in what manner they ought and should make their
certificats according to the rates and summes therof abovesaid, and of all manner of persons as well Aliens and
Strangers Denizens or not Denizens inhabiting within this Realme as of such popish Recusants and other persons
who be borne under the Kings obeysance chargeable by this A&bholigct; and after such charge given shall at the discretion
of the [same<ref idref="n176">176</ref>] Commissioners or any three of them prefix another day and place to the said persons to appeare
before the said Commissioners and bring in their certificates under the penalty of forty shillings for every default, and
therupon at the said day and place prefixed and limited the said Commissioners shall make their precept or precepts
to such Officers or Colle&bholigct;ors being able and sufficient men in every Hundred Wapentake towne or [other<ref idref="n175">175</ref>] place
aforesaid as they the said Commissioners or any three or more of them shall thinke fitt, comprising and containing in
them the names and surnames of all persons presented before them in the said Certificates, of whom or of any of them
if the said Commissioners or any three of them in their severall limitts shall have certaine knowledge, or vehement
suspe&bholigct; that he or she is of greater value then is upon such person or persons soe certified or specified, that then the
said C&bhooov;missioners shall upon examination thereof by good and lawfull meanes without oath set such rate or rates upon
every such person or persons as shall be according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;, and if any
person or persons shall refuse to pay the severall summes and proportions appointed by this A&bholigct; for such person
to pay upon demand made by the Constable or Officer of the said place according to the Estreats delivered to
them by the said Commissioners, it shall be lawfull to and for such Constable or Officer for non payment thereof to
destraine the person or persons soe refuseing by his [and<ref idref="n177">177</ref>] their Good&bholngs; and chattels, and the distresse soe taken to keepe
by the space of fower dayes at the costs and charges of the owner thereof, And if the said Owner doe not pay the
said summe of money, due by this A&bholigct; within the said foure dayes, then the said distresse to be apprised by three
or two of the Inhabitants where such distresse is taken and then to be sould by the said Officer for the payment
of the said money, and the overplus comeing by the said Sale (if any be) over and above the charged of takeing and
keeping the said distresse to be immediately restored to the Owner their of, and the said Officers and other persons
soe deputed to aske take gather and leavy the said summes shall answere and be charged for the portion onely to
them assigned and limitted to be leavyed gathered and comprised in the said Writing and estreate soe to them as
aforesaid delivered to the persons and uses in this A&bholigct; expressed, and the said summe in that writing or estreat to be
comprized to pay unto the said Commissioners, or any three of them with all speede and without delay at such day
and place as by them shall be appointed, and the said Commissioners to whom the said summes or any of them shall
be paid shall with all speede and without delay carry and pay the same unto the Sheriffe or Sheriffes of the said
County or Citty respe&bholigct;ively wherin the said summes shall or ought to be colle&bholigct;ed and paid, and every such Sheriffe
respe&bholigct;ively within the Kingdome of England, and Dominion of Wales shall with all speede and without delay pay
or cause to be paid all and every the s&bhouov;mes by him or them received to the Treasurers in this A&bholigct; named, or any
three of them, all and every which said summe and summes of money soe to be paid by force and vertue of this
A&bholigct; shall bee paid in currant money of England,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VI. Persons dissuading others from paying Rate, or consenting that any other Person shall be under-rated.</head>
			<para id="p196">
				<emph type="i">Imprisonment.; Except Peers.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p197">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that if any person or persons shall disswade any other person from paying the rates
or summes soe to [to<ref idref="n178">178</ref>] bee rated as aforesaid by force or vertue or according to the tenor of this A&bholigct;, or by corruption
shall give consent that any person shall be rated below or under the proportion which any such person ought to
pay by the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;, and the said Offences or any of them shall be proved by oath of
two Wittnesses before any three or more of the said Commissioners who shall have power by this A&bholigct; to administer
the said Oath, shall by the said Commissioners or any three or more of them be committed to the common goale
of the same County (except they be Peeres of the Realme) there to remaine till he or she shall be thence delivered
by the Justices of Assize, or Justices of the Peace at the Generall Quarter Sessions to be holden for the same County
wherein any such offence shall be comitted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VII. Sums colle&bholigct;ed to be issued by Treasurers to the Uses in this A&bholigct; </head>
			<para id="p198">
				<emph type="i">mentioned. Officers making Default in colle&bholigct;ing, &amp;c.; accountable before Parliament</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p199">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed that all and every the summes to be colle&bholigct;ed and raised by and according to the
tenor of this A&bholigct; shall be paid and issued out by the [Treasurerers<ref idref="n179">179</ref>] in this A&bholigct; named or any two or more of them
respe&bholigct;ively to the use and uses in this present A&bholigct; mentioned and noe other, as by order of the Lords and Commons,
or of such persons as they shall authorize therunto shall be appointed and dire&bholigct;ed and not otherwise, and that all
and every the said person and persons who are to be charged or chargable with the receipt of any the said
summes in this A&bholigct; mentioned, which shall willfully [negclet,<ref idref="n180">180</ref>] or make default in the colle&bholigct;ing leavying or paying
of the severall summes by them or any of them respe&bholigct;ively to be received or paid, or in execution of their
severall dutyes [according to the tenor<ref idref="n181">181</ref>] and true meaning of this A&bholigct; shall be accomptable for the same to the
Parliament, and shall be lyable to such punishment as shall bee thought fitt by the Parliament to be infli&bholigct;ed,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>VIII. Persons residing in London or within 15 Miles paying before the time limited to the Persons herein named as Treasurers; </head>
			<para id="p200">
				<emph type="i">to receive an Acquittance, and taken to be an acceptable Service.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p201">And It is further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authoritie aforesaid that if any person or persons of what degree
ranke or quality soever inhabiting or residing within the Citty of London, or within fifteene Miles distant from the
said Citty shall before the time limitted by this A&bholigct; pay unto Sir Richard Browne Baronet, Sir John Langham
Baronet Sir William Wheeler Knight Sir William Vincent Knight Thomas Rich Esquire and the Chamberlaine of the
Citty of London for the time being, (who are hereby constituted and appointed Treasurers for the receiving and
issueing of all &amp; singuler the summes of money by this A&bholigct; intended to be raised) or unto any two of them, and
shall receive from the said Treasurers or any two of them a Certificate or acquittance acknowledging the receipt
of such summes, the said partyes severally shall thereby be discharged of for or concerning the said summes and
all such payments shall be taken as an acceptable service to his Majestye and the Kingdome</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>IX. Persons lending &pound;100. or upward&bholngs; declared a good Service.</head>
			<para id="p202">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authoritie aforesaid that if any person or persons shall lend the
summe of one hundred pound&bholngs; or any greater summe to and for the use and purposes in this present A&bholigct; mentioned
and declared such person shall doe very good and acceptable service to the Kingdome</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>X. Persons, &amp;c; lending before 1st Aug. 1660.,</head>
			<para id="p203">
				<emph type="i">Repayment secured with Interest at &pound;6. per Cent. per Annum.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p204">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that any person [or persons<ref idref="n181">181</ref>] that shall soe lend and advance such summe or summes
of money as aforesaid for this present occasion and shall before the first day of August one thousand six
hundred and sixty ensueing pay and deliver the same to such person or persons as are authorized by this present
A&bholigct; to receive the moneyes charged hereby upon the respe&bholigct;ive Inhabitants of the Citty of London shall be secured
by this A&bholigct; for the repayment of the said moneyes at such time and place as by the lenders of the said moneyes
shall be required and agreed upon, and alsoe of the interest and dammage sustained by the forbearance thereof after
the rate of six pound&bholngs; per cent. for a yeare and untill such time as they shall respe&bholigct;ively have received againe the
said summes soe lent and advanced,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XI. Treasurers to repay such Loans out of the Rates received by them, with Interest at &pound;6. per Cent. per Annum.</head>
			<para id="p205">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed that the said Sir Richard Browne Sir John Langham Sir William Wheeler Sir William
Vincent Thomas Rich and the Chamberlaine of London shall and may satisfie pay and deliver unto such person
or persons respe&bholigct;ively out of the said moneyes soe to be received by them such respe&bholigct;ive summe and summes of
money as shall be soe lent by him or them for the purposes aforesaid together with such other and further summe
and summes of money as the interest of, and for the said summe and summes of money respe&bholigct;ively shall amount
unto after the rate of six pound&bholngs; per cent. for a yeare from the day and time, that the same was advanced as
aforesaid, untill they shall respe&bholigct;ively have received the said summe or summes soe advanced,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XII. Acquittances from Persons appointed for Receipt of Rates a sufficient Discharge to Treasurers.</head>
			<para id="p206">And it is hereby [further<ref idref="n181">181</ref>] ena&bholigct;ed that the acquittance or acquittances from the persons before apointed for the
receipt of these moneyes to the uses and purposes in this present A&bholigct; expressed or of any three of them shall be
a sufficient discharge to the Treasurers in this A&bholigct; named for soe much money together with interest for the same
as shall be comprehended in such acquittance or acquittainces for the issueing out, and payment of the said summe
and summes of money respe&bholigct;ively,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIII. Allowance to Colle&bholigct;ors, Id. in the pound. Allowance to Commissioners' Clerks, Id. in the pound.</head>
			<para id="p207">And Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that there shall be allowed and paid by the C&bhooov;missioners aforesaid unto the respe&bholigct;ive
Colle&bholigct;ors of every parish the summe of one penny in the pound for all such summes of money as they shall colle&bholigct;
and pay in according to this A&bholigct;, and the said Commissioners shall likewise allow and pay out of the moneyes soe
colle&bholigct;ed and paid in one penny in the pound unto their Clerks and others imployed by them in this service.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XIV. Treasurers to pay to Sheriffs residing 50 Miles or upward&bholngs; from London 2d. in the Pound, and within that Distance 1d. Allowance to Treasurers of 1d. in the Pound.</head>
			<para id="p208">And Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that the severall Treasurers in this A&bholigct; named shall allow
and pay unto the respe&bholigct;ive Sheriffs of the severall Countyes residing fifty miles distant from the Citty of London or
upward&bholngs; two pence in the pound, and to such respe&bholigct;ive Sheriffes as shall reside within that distance from the said
Citty of London one penny in the pound for all such summes of money as the said Sheriffes shall pay in respe&bholigct;ively
unto the Treasurers in this A&bholigct; named, and the said Treasurers in this A&bholigct; named are hereby further authorized to
have and take unto themselves one penny in the pound out of the moneys soe paid in unto them by vertue of this
A&bholigct; to be distributed unto such person or persons as shall be imployed by them in receiving and issueing of the money
in and by this A&bholigct; granted in such manner and proportions as they shall thinke fitt.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XV. Rates upon Peers to be received by a Colle&bholigct;or nominated by them, who is to pay the same to the Treasurers.</head>
			<para id="p209">Provided alwayes And be it hereby declared and ena&bholigct;ed that the severall rates taxed upon the Lords shall be
received by a Colle&bholigct;or to be nominated by the Peers, which Colle&bholigct;or soe appointed by the Peeres shall pay over the
said summes to the Treasurers in this A&bholigct; named to be disposed of to such uses and purposes as by this A&bholigct; is
appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVI. No Double Charge allowed.</head>
			<para id="p210">Provided likewise that noe person or persons of what degree or quality soever shall be doubly charged by this
A&bholigct; but that every person shall pay the greatest proportion he or she is charged withall by this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVII. Rates received to be employed in paying Arrears, &amp;c. to the Army and Navy in Pay on the 10th June 1660. Account of Rates received to be given to Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p211">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritye aforesaid that all and every the summe and summes of money to be
leavyed and raised by vertue of this present A&bholigct; shall (by the Treasurers in and by this A&bholigct; appointed) be imployed
and disposed for and towards the paying of the arreares disbanding and discharging the respe&bholigct;ive forces of this
kingdome by Land and Sea who were in pay the tenth day of June One thousand six hundred and sixty, and to noe
other use or purpose whatsoever, and that an accompt of all the said moneyes shall be given by the said Treasurers to
this or the next or any other succeeding Parliament, or to such person or persons as shall by this or any other
succeeding parliament be thereunto appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XVIII. Persons assessed higher than their Rank to be assessed by Persons herein named.</head>
			<para id="p212">[Provided that if any of the Peeres be assessed higher then according to his or their ranke or degree perticularly
expressed in this A&bholigct;, they shall be assessed by George Duke of Albemarle John Marquesse of Winchester Henry
Marquesse of Dorchester Algernoone Earle of Northumberland William Lord Paget Philip Lord Wharton John Lord
Hunsden and Henry Lord Arundell or any five of them.<ref idref="n182">182</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Silkes Tapes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">John <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Sanford <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Glegg <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">William Massey Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">Sawle <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Prade <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Es&bhoqesq;, <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">Es&bhoqesq;, <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">Es&bhoqesq;<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">Barronett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">Barront <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">Barronet <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">Barronet <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">Barronet <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">Barr<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">Kn<emph type="p">t</emph>
				<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n42" number="42">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n43" number="43">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n44" number="44">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n45" number="45">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n46" number="46">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n47" number="47">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n48" number="48">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n49" number="49">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n50" number="50">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n51" number="51">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n52" number="52">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n53" number="53">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n54" number="54">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n55" number="55">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n56" number="56">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n57" number="57">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n58" number="58">Barronet <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n59" number="59">Barronett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n60" number="60">Knt <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n61" number="61">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n62" number="62">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n63" number="63">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n64" number="64">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n65" number="65">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n66" number="66">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n67" number="67">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n68" number="68">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n69" number="69">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n70" number="70">Hannam Esquier <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n71" number="71">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n72" number="72">Baynard Es&bhoqesq;, <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n73" number="73">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n74" number="74">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n75" number="75">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n76" number="76">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n77" number="77">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n78" number="78">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n79" number="79">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n80" number="80">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n81" number="81">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n82" number="82">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n83" number="83">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n84" number="84">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n85" number="85">Chaffe Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n86" number="86">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n87" number="87">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n88" number="88">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n89" number="89">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n90" number="90">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n91" number="91">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n92" number="92">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n93" number="93">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n94" number="94">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n95" number="95">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n96" number="96">Gentl[..]. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n97" number="97">Etericke <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n98" number="98">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n99" number="99">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n100" number="100">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n101" number="101">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n102" number="102">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n103" number="103">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n104" number="104">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n105" number="105">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n106" number="106">Fownes Esquier <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n107" number="107">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n108" number="108">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n109" number="109">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n110" number="110">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n111" number="111">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n112" number="112">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n113" number="113">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n114" number="114">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n115" number="115">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n116" number="116">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n117" number="117">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n118" number="118">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n119" number="119">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n120" number="120">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n121" number="121">Gent. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n122" number="122">Gent. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n123" number="123">Gent. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n124" number="124">Robert Legard <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n125" number="125">Cambell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n126" number="126">Thomas Cornewell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n127" number="127">Francis <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n128" number="128">Knatchbull <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n129" number="129">Hugheson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n130" number="130">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n131" number="131">Feversham <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n132" number="132">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n133" number="133">Pretiman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n134" number="134">Es&bhoqesq;s <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n135" number="135">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n136" number="136">Nelthrop <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n137" number="137">Brownlow <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n138" number="138">Greenhill <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n139" number="139">Secretaries <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n140" number="140">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n141" number="141">Cutbison.</note>
			<note id="n142" number="142">
				<emph type="i">O</emph> omits.</note>
			<note id="n143" number="143">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n144" number="144">Anguish <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n145" number="145">Mingay <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n146" number="146">Thomas Norris Francis Norris<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n147" number="147">Stole <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n148" number="148">Stott <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n149" number="149">Es&bhoqesq;s.</note>
			<note id="n150" number="150">Butler <emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n151" number="151">
				<emph type="i">0</emph> omits.</note>
			<note id="n152" number="152">Kn<emph type="p">ts</emph>
				<emph type="i">0</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n153" number="153">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n154" number="154">Tallmach <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n155" number="155">Culford <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n156" number="156">Thomas Leman Thomas Tirrell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n157" number="157">Phillip Parker Henry North of Laxfield <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n158" number="158">Robert Nanton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n159" number="159">John Laney <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n160" number="160">Blank in Original.</note>
			<note id="n161" number="161">John Steward <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n162" number="162">Polhill <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n163" number="163">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n164" number="164">Boughton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n165" number="165">the elder <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n166" number="166">Giles <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n167" number="167">the younger <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n168" number="168">Glanvill <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n169" number="169">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n170" number="170">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n171" number="171">Lanynys <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n172" number="172">Crutchley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n173" number="173">Kyffen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n174" number="174">Phillips O.</note>
			<note id="n175" number="175">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n176" number="176">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n177" number="177">or <emph type="i">O.</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n178" number="178">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits</note>
			<note id="n179" number="179">Treasurers <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n180" number="180">negle&bholigct; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n181" number="181">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n182" number="182">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


