<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47254" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act for the present Nominating of Commissioners of Sewers. [Rot. Parl 12 C. II. p. 1. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>23 H. VIII. c. 5. &sect; 1. recited</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners of Sewers to be made, by the Lord Chancellor, and others, before the 23d O&bholigct;ober next ensuing.; Their Power</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by a Statute made in the Three and twentyeth Yeare of the Raigne of King Henry the Eighth
It is ena&bholigct;ed That Commissions of Sewers shall be dire&bholigct;ed in manner as in the said A&bholigct;is expressed to
such persons as shall be named by the Lord Chauncellour and the Lord Treasurer of England, and the two Cheife
Justices for the time being or by three of them, wherof the Chauncellor to be one. And whereas our Soveraigne
Lord the King hath not as yet beene pleased to make or constitute any person to be Treasurer of England,
or Cheife Justice of either Bench. In default wherof noe Commissioners of Sewers can at this present time be
named according to the appointment of the said Statute. And now great Dam[m]ages haveing lately happened in
many parts of this Realme by Inundations of Waters which are likely to increase to the greater dammage of
the people unlesse speedy remedy be in this behalfe provided Bee it therefore Ena&bholigct;ed by this present Parliament
that C&bhooov;missions of Sewers shall and may at any time before the three and twentyeth day of O&bholigct;ober next ensueing
and not after be dire&bholigct;ed according to the manner and forme expressed in the said recited Statute, to such persons
as the Lord Chauncellor, the Lord&bholngs; C&bhooov;missioners of the Treasury, the Chauncellor of the Dutchy of Lancaster, the
Lord Cheife Barron of the Exchequer and the Justices of either Bench for the time being, or any three of them;
whereof the Lord Chauncellor to be one; shall nominate and appoint, Which said Commissioners which shall be
soe nominated shall have full power to doe and execute all matters and things as fully in all respe&bholigct;s as any
C&bhooov;missioners of Sewers at any time heretofore named by the Lord Chauncellor Lord Treasurer, the two Cheife
Justices or any three of them ever had, or might have by vertue of the said Statute, or any other Law now
in force, the said recited Statute or any other Law or Statute to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. 23 H. VIII. c. 5. not repealed</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes that this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained shall not extend to repeale or make void any
Clause, Article, Sentence or Power expressed or comprised in the said Statute made in the three and twentieth Yeare
of King Henry the Eighth touching Sewers from and after the three and twentyeth day of O&bholigct;ober next ensueing,
but that the same shall be of full power force and vertue as if this A&bholigct; had never beene made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The King's Assent not to determine this Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alsoe and it is declared that His Majesties Royall Assent to this A&bholigct; doth not, nor shall determine this
present Session of Parliament.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


