<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47263" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XV. An Act for the speedy disbanding of the Army and Garrisons of this Kingdome.[Rot. Parl. 12 C. II.p.2. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Army in England, Wales, and Berwick upon Tweed, and the English Forces in Scotland, disbanded. Exception</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS the people of this Kingdome lye under a great burthen and charge in the maintenance and
payment of the present Army. Now to the end the same may be disbanded and the Country eased and
the Officers and Souldiers who were in the Army [on<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the five and twentyeth day of April One thousand six hundred
sixty appearing by the Musters taken the seaventh of May following (being under God instrumentall in the just
and happy restitution of his Majestye to the exercise of his government and the people to their lawes and libertyes)
may be satisfied their just arreares Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings Most Excellent Majestye with the advice of the Lord&bholngs;
and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authoritie of the same that the said Army and all
the respe&bholigct;ive Regiments Troops and Companies Officers and Souldiers whether in field or garrison within this
kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede together with all the English
Forces now in Scotland except such as are in the following rules excepted be with all convenient speede disbanded
and discharged.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners named for the above Purpose.</head>
			<para id="p3">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed that his Royall Highnes the Duke of Yorke, The Duke of Albemarle The Lord Great
Chamberlaine The Lord Steward The Earle of Leicester and The Lord Roberts, Sir Richard Browne Sir William Doyley
John Birch William Prynne Edward King and Robert Scawen Esquiers or any three or more of them whereof one
of the Commissioners named by the House of Lord&bholngs; and one of the Commissioners named by the House of
Commons to be two shall be and are hereby constituted and appointed Commissioners for that purpose and shall
a&bholigct; therin according to the rules orders and instru&bholigct;ions hereafter exprest, or such other dire&bholigct;ions and rules as
shall hereafter be made on that behalfe by the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in Parliament assembled,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The present Treasurers at War, and the Treasurers under c. 9. ante, to issue Money for the above Purpose.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed that the present Treasurers at War, The Treasurers named in one A&bholigct; of this present
Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy provision of money for disbanding and paying off the forces of this
kingdome both by land and sea shall issue and pay such respe&bholigct;ive summe and summes of money as shall be
appointed and dire&bholigct;ed by the said Commissioners or any three or more of them as aforesaid, and all other persons
concerned in the rules and instru&bholigct;ions hereby given, are to give obedience accordingly.</para>
			<para id="p5">(<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Rules Orders and Instru&bholigct;ions for disbanding the Army.</para>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">As to the Manner of Commissioners proceeding</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">I. The Commissioners hereby appointed for disbanding the Army and respe&bholigct;ive forces shall proceed therein in
manner following (that is to say) the name of the Officer in cheife of each Regiment and Garrison within this
Kingdome (except such as are hereafter excepted) shall be written in a paper which paper shall be close rolled and
sealed up, and put into a glasse, and left with the Speaker of the House of Commons sitting the Parliament, or with
the Lord Chancellour in the intervall of Parliament, and when the aforesaid Commissioners shall be ready to disband
any the forces, they shall when the House of Commons is sitting, or in the intervall when his Majestyes Councell [is<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
sitting draw forth a certaine number of names not exceeding three and haveing there publiquely reade the names
proceed forthwith to disband them, and soe from time to time untill the whole be disbanded, yet soe as foure
Companyes in Hull, foure Companies in Berwicke and two Companyes in Carlisle of such as are now in the said
Garrisons respe&bholigct;ively, or such as shall be therunto appointed by the Kings Majestye be last disbanded.</para>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">As to Arrears of Pay</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">2. All generall Officers [of the Army<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] who were in service the five and twentyeth of April One thousand six
hundred(<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) sixty appearing by their Commissions, and all other Officers and Souldiers who were in service the five and
twentyeth of April One thousand six hundred and sixty and are found upon the Muster Rolls taken the seaventh
of May then next following and have not beene since discharged for refuseing to take the Oaths of alleigiance and
supremacy shall have and receive upon their disbanding their just arreares from the fourteenth of March One
thousand six hundred fifty eight defaulking for quarters by them oweing for such time for which arreares shall be
to them due and payable before the said five and twentyeth of April or since.</para>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">As to the disbanding the Duke of York's Regiment and others</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">3. That the Regiments of their Royall Highnesses the Dukes of Yorke and Gloucester and Lord Generalls
Regiments of Horse and Foote shall be last disbanded except the foure companyes in Hull, the foure companyes in
Berwicke and the two companyes in Carlisle aforesaid.</para>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">As to the disbanding Garrisons</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">4. That all Garrisons within this Kingdome or Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede and the
Island&bholngs; of Guernsey or Jersey shall be with all convenient speede in respe&bholigct; of their fortifications and walls and
numbers of men putt into the same condition they were in, in the yeare one thousand six hundred thirty seaven,
and the souldiers in them disbanded and discharged except such of them or any other as his Majestye shall thinke
fitt otherwise to dispose and provide for at his owne charge.</para>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">As to continuing Troops in Scotland</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">5. That if his Majestye shall thinke fitt to continue in Scotland three regiments of foote and one troope of horse
of the English forces now there they are not to be paid and maintained at the charge of this kingdome.</para>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to send to Treasurers named in c. 9. ante, to certify to them what Monies are in Hand</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">6. That the Commissioners by this A&bholigct; appointed doe send to the Treasurers named in one A&bholigct; of this present
Parliament entituled (An A&bholigct; for the speedy provision of money for disbanding and paying off the forces of this
kingdome both by land and sea) who are hereby required from time to time to certifie the aforesaid Commissioners
what moneyes remaines in their hand&bholngs;, or which they know to be in the hand&bholngs; of any Sheriffe or any Commissioners
of the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes when the Commissioners for the disbanding the Army shall have occasion for it, and
desire it.</para>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to dire&bholigct; Treasurers to grant Assignations for Monies on Sheriffs or Commissioners for raising Money by the aforesaid A&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">7. That the said Commissioners shall dire&bholigct; the said Treasurers from time to time to grant assignations (who are
hereby required to give obedience thereunto) for such and soe many summes of money on the respe&bholigct;ive Sheriffes
or Commissioners for raising money by the aforesaid A&bholigct; in the severall Countyes Cittyes or places where they
understand any of the said money lyes, [and<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] the Commissioners for disbanding the Army or any three or more of
them as aforesaid shall dire&bholigct; and appoint to such persons and in such manner as the said Commissioners or any
three or more of them as aforesaid shall dire&bholigct; and appoint.</para>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Auditors of Accounts of Officers and Soldiers appointed, to take an Oath before entering upon Duty.; Form.; Commissioners may administer Oath.; On Accounts certified, Commissioners to issue Warrants for Payment.; Discharge to Treasurers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">8. That for the better stating of the accompts of the Officers and Souldiers of the Armies and Garrisons within this
Kingdome of England and Dominion of Wales Arthur Sprey William Jessop Ralph Darnel Samuel Atkins Richard
Kingdon and Bartholimew Fillingham Esquiers shall be and are hereby appointed constituted and authorized to
audit and cast up the accompts of the aforesaid Armies and Garrisons and shall respe&bholigct;ively before they enter thereon
take an Oath in these word&bholngs; following (I doe sweare that to the best of my skill and judgement I shall examine
and truely state all such accompts as shall be committed to my care and trust by the Commissioners for disbanding
the Army or any three or more of them, and shall and will [make<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] to the best of my knowledge true certificates
of all such accompts to the said Commissioners or any three of them, Soe helpe me God, which said Oath the
Commissioners appointed for disbanding and pay of the Army or any three of them as aforesaid are hereby
authorized to administer accordingly, which accompts soe certified by the said Auditors or any three of them, the
said Commissioners or any three of them shall have power and authority, and are hereby authorized and impowered
to issue out Warrants from time to time to the respe&bholigct;ive Treasurers aforesaid for the payment of the severall
summes soe audited and due as aforesaid, which Warrants together with the acquittance or receipt of the persons
to whom the same is payable therupon shall be to the said Treasurers respe&bholigct;ively a sufficient warrant and discharge.</para>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Dire&bholigct;ions to Auditor when it appears that Monies have been paid and not applied to any Muster, or taken up without Warrant, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p23">9. If it shall appeare upon the examining and stating the arreares of any Regiment Troope Company or
Garrison that any moneyes have beene paid them by Warrant upon accompt, and not by such Warrant applyed
to any Muster or taken up without warrant of the Assesments or any other publique moneyes that then and in
all such cases the Auditors appointed by this A&bholigct; or any three of them shall be and are hereby authorized and
required to place such moneyes soe received (by warrant upon accompt or taken up without warrant) toward&bholngs;
pay of all the Officers and souldiers of such Regiment Troope Company or Garrison upon such Musters as in
course succeed the Musters upon which such Regiment Troope Company or Garrison was last paid and not
otherwise, and in all other cases concerning the Musters or receiving any money therupon or transposeing altering
modeling or reduceing of any Regiments Troops Companies or Souldiers, or where any doubt shall arise concerning
the just arreares due to any Officer or Souldier the said Auditours shall state and reporte the case to the
Commissioners for disbanding the Army, who, or any three or them as aforesaid are hereby authorized and
impowered to sett downe and give such orders rules and dire&bholigct;ions as they shall judge reasonable and meet
which orders rules and dire&bholigct;ions[the said Auditors<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] are hereby required and authorized to observe accordingly.</para>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">As to Auditors taking Security of Officers disbanded to pay Quarters owing.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p25">10. That forasmuch as severall forces have since the second of July One thousand six hundred fifty nine taken
free quarter in severall parts of this Kingdome and Dominion of Wales and severall Officers of the Army have
borrowed money of severall townes parishes and places and of private persons for discharge of such quarters since
that time which are yet unpaid, the Auditors aforesaid in that case shall receive the severall and respe&bholigct;ive
obligations of such Officers who are now to be disbanded under their hand&bholngs; and seales to satisfie and pay upon
demand the respe&bholigct;ive quarters or summes of money soe oweing, or such part as ought to be paid by any Officer
or Souldier of any Regiment Troope or Company to whom any arreares are now paid.</para>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">As to Troops, Horse and Foot, delivering up their Arms</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">11. That upon the disbanding of any part of the forces of this Kingdome, all foote Souldiers shall deliver up
all their Armes (except sword&bholngs;) and the Horse shall deliver up their defensive Armes for his Majestyes service
to such persons as shall be appointed by the Commissioners to receive the same who are hereby authorized and
impowered to give such orders and dire&bholigct;ions for the delivering receiving portage and secureing of them, and in
such manner as they shall thinke necessary, [and that noe private souldier (being disbanded) shall (after fourteene
dayes from the time of his disbanding) ride or travell with any fire armes upon paine of losing his said Armes
and of imprisonment dureing his Majestyes pleasure<ref idref="n8">8</ref>.]</para>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">As to Officers or Soldiers refusing to be disbanded; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">12. That if any Officer or Souldier hereby appointed to be disbanded shall refuse to give obedience therunto,
or diswade others from disbanding he or they shall be forthwith secured by the Lord Generall, and forfeit their
whole arreares and be proceeded against as Mutineers.</para>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Officers making false Muster; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">13. That in case upon the Muster, hereafter to be taken in order to the disbanding of the Army, any Officer
shall make any false Muster, or shall muster any souldier by a false name such Officer shall forfeit his or their</para>
			<para id="p32">
				<emph type="i">Officers making false Muster; Penalty.; As to Application of Monies issued</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p33">14. That all moneyes that shall be issued after foureteene dayes pay appointed for present supply of
the Army shall be onely for and toward&bholngs; the disbanding of the Army and other necessary charges therunto
belonging, [except onely a fourth part of the money to be raised by the Poll Bill which shall be imployed to the
paying off of the five and twenty Shipps come in from sea, and after for paying of such other shipps as the
summes will further extend unto.<ref idref="n8">8</ref>.]</para>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Present or late Commissary General of Musters to assist Auditors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">15. That the present or late Commissary Generall of Musters or their deputyes doe from time to time and as
often as the Commissioners for disbanding the Army shall require it assist and attend the Auditors appointed by this
A&bholigct; in order to the drawing up and perfe&bholigct;ing the accompts of arreares now to be stated, who are alsoe hereby
required to bring in all, or any the Muster Rolls of the Army as they shall bee thereunto ordered by the Commissioners
aforesaid.</para>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners for disbanding Army may issue their Warrant for pay of Salaries, &amp;c. to Auditors.; Discharge to Treasurers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">16. That the Commissioners for disbanding the Army or any three or more of them as aforesaid be and are
hereby authorized and impowered out of any moneyes within the receipt of the respe&bholigct;ive Treasurers aforesaid to
grant their Warrant or Warrants for pay of such salaries and Allowances to the aforesaid Auditors for their
encouragement paines and charge in the affaire by this A&bholigct; committed to their trust as shall by the said
Commissioners for the disbanding the Army or any three of them as aforesaid be agreed and thought fitt:
and the [Warrant<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] of the said Commissioners or any three of them as aforesaid for payment of the said
Auditors or pay of any other the salaries and contingent charges in this A&bholigct; mentioned together with the receipt
of the person to whom the same is payable shall be to the said Treasurers respe&bholigct;ively a sufficient Warrant and
discharge.</para>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners empowered to employ and pay Clerks, Accountants, &amp;c. and to defray contingent Charges</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p39">17. And the said Commissioners for the disbanding the Army or any three or more of them as aforesaid are
hereby authorized and impowered to nominate appoint and imploy such Accomptants Clerks Agents Messengers
and Servants and to make and [to<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] give unto them such Salaries Allowances and satisfa&bholigct;ions as they shall thinke
fitt, and to provide such Bookes Paper Inke Pens Wax Candles convenient houseroome and all other necessaries,
and to give their Warrants for payment of any summe or summes of money for the uses aforesaid as they shall
finde necessary, as alsoe for defraying of charges for portage of Arms and all other contingent charges relating
to this service.</para>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">and may give Dire&bholigct;ions to Sheriffs, &amp;c. to assist in disbanding the Army</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p41">18. That the Commissioners for disbanding the Army or any three of them as aforesaid shall and may give
dire&bholigct;ions from time to time that all Sheriffes and all other his Majestyes Officers in every County be ayding and
assisting to such person or persons as they shall imploy for disbanding of the Army and forces, and shall take
care to see them truely mustered and paid off on the place, and their quarters satisfied.</para>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Captains, &amp;c. who have served under General Monk, and have disbursed Money in Relief of Soldiers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">19. Provided alwayes that if any Captaine or other cheife Officer of any troope or company of the Army who
was in service under the command of Generall Monk on the seaventh day of May One thousand six hundred and
sixty and marched with him out of Scotland into England in January last shall by his Oath, which the said
Commissioners or any three [or more<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] of them as aforesaid are hereby impowered to administer and by his pay
booke make appeare that he hath disbursed any summe or summes of money for the releife of any souldier or
souldiers of his Troope or Company before the seaventh day of May aforesaid, which souldier or souldiers are not
capeable of receiving his or their arreares by the rules in this A&bholigct; mentioned, then and in such case the Commissioners
aforesaid for disbanding the Army or any three of them as aforesaid shall have full power, and are hereby required
to pay or cause to be paid unto the said Captaine or cheife Officer as aforesaid such summe or summes of money
soe by him disbursed as aforesaid, Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary notwithstanding, Provided that
the Commissioners aforesaid doe not allow in the whole for such disbursements above the summe of eight thousand
pound&bholngs;.</para>
			<para id="p44">
				<emph type="i">Chief Officer of the Navy to deliver to Commissioners a List of 25 Ships intended to be discharged, and the Names of the Officers and Men</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p45">[20. That the cheife Officer of His Majestyes Navy doe with all convenient speede deliver in unto the Commissioners
appointed for disbanding the Army a List of the names of the twenty five ships now in the River which are
intended to be discharged with a perticular accompt of the moneyes due to every ship, and the names of the Officers
and sea men to whom it is due, to the end that soe soone as any competent summe of money shall be received that
is hereby appointed for that service, the said ships may be paid off and discharged accordingly.</para>
			<para id="p46">
				<emph type="i">Dire&bholigct;ions to Commissioners as to paying off the said Ships</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p47">21. That the Commissioners for disbanding the Army or any three of them as aforesaid soe soone as they shall
finde soe much money to be in cash appointed for the Navy as will pay off and discharge one or more of the
aforesaid Ships, shall appoint a short day for that purpose and give notice thereof to the cheife Officers of his
Majestyes Navy who are to attend that service and pay off and discharge upon the place such ship or ships in the
presence and by the consent of any two or more of the Commissioners appointed for disbanding the Army who
are to take an accompt of the money soe issued, and all charges relating to that service and present the same fairely
written in a booke together with the accompt of moneyes paid for disbanding [of<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] the Army to this or the next
succeeding Parliament.</para>
			<para id="p48">
				<emph type="i">Treasurers under c. 9. ante, and c. 20. post, to issue Money for the Discharge of the said Ships.; Commissioners to issue Warrant for such Monies.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p49">22. That the Treasurers for the money ariseing by one A&bholigct; of Parliament (entituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy
provision of money for disbanding and paying off the forces of this Kingdome both by land and sea) and for the
money ariseing upon one other A&bholigct; for two moneths assesment, (intituled An A&bholigct; for raiseing seavenscore thousand
pound&bholngs; for the compleat disbanding of the whole Army and paying off some part of the Navy) are hereby
required to [issue &amp;<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] pay from time to time such summe and summes of money, and to such person or
persons for the discharge of the shipps aforesaid and such others as the money therunto appointed will extend
unto, as they shall by warrant under the hands of any three or more of the Commissioners as aforesaid for
disbanding the Army be appointed and dire&bholigct;ed, which Warrant or Warrants the said Commissioners for disbanding
the Army or any three of them as aforesaid are hereby authorized and impowered (as they shall see cause) to grant
accordingly.</para>
			<para id="p50">
				<emph type="i">Allowance to Commissioners of Id. in the Pound on Monies issued</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p51">23. That the Commissioners nominated by the House of Commons (that is to say) Sir William Doyly, Sir Richard
Browne, John Birch Edward King William Prynn and Robert Scawen Esquiers shall have and receive for their
charge in and about this service one penny in the pound and noe more out of all such moneyes as shall be issued
by vertue of this A&bholigct;, and for the uses therein exprest, which the Treasurers for the aforesaid moneyes are hereby
enabled and required to issue and pay accordingly.<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">are <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">as <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">annexed to the Original Rules in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Warrants <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">Annexed to the original Rules in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


