<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47260" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII. An Act for Confirmation of Judiciall Proceedings. [Rot. Parl. 12. C. II. p. 1. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Certain A&bholigct;s and Proceedings not to be avoided.</head>
		<para id="p1">BEE it Ena&bholigct;ed and it is Ena&bholigct;ed by His Majesty and the Lords and Commons in Parliament assembled and
by the Authoritie of the same That noe Fines nor finall Concord&bholngs; Chirographs nor Proclamations of Fines
nor any Recoveries Verdi&bholigct;s Judgements Statuts Recognizances nor Inrolments of any Deed&bholngs; or Wills or of any
such Fines Proclamations Recoveries Verdi&bholigct;s Judgments Statutes or Recognizances, nor any Exemplifications of them
nor any of them, nor any Inquisitions Indi&bholigct;ments Presentments Informations Decrees Sentences, Probats of Will,
nor Letters of Administration, nor any Writts nor A&bholigct;ings on, or Returns of Writts, Orders or other Proceedings
in Law or Equity had, made, given, taken or done or depending in the Courts of Chauncery, Kings Bench
Upper Bench Common Pleas and Court of Exchequer, and Courts of Exchequer Chamber or any of them sitting
at Westminster or in the Courts of the Great Sessions in Wales, the Courts of any Countyes Palatine or Dutchy
of Lancaster or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweed, or in any other inferiour Courts of Law or Equity, or by any
the Judges Clerks Officers Sheriffes Coroners or Ministers or others A&bholigct;ing in Obedience to them or any of them,
or by any the Courts of Admiralty Delegats Justices of Assize, Nisi Prius, Oyer and Terminer Goale Delivery
Justices of the Peace Commissioners of Sewers Banke-rupts or Charitable Uses, nor any A&bholigct;ings, Processe, Proceedings
nor Executions therupon had, made, given done or suffered in the Kingdome of England since the First of May
One thousand six hundred forty two shall be avoided for want or defe&bholigct; of any Legall Power in the said Courts
Judges Commissioners Justices or any of them, or for or by reason that the Premisses or any of them were
commenced, Prosecuted, had, made, held or used in the Name Stile or Title of the late King, or in the Name
Stile Title or Test of Custodes Libertatis Anglie Authoritate Parliament, Or in the Name Stile Title or Test
of the Keepers of the Liberty of England by Authority of Parliament, Or the Name Stile Title or Test of
Oliver Lord Prote&bholigct;or of the Commonwealth of England Scotland and Ireland and the Dominions therunto
belonging, Or of Oliver Lord Prote&bholigct;or of the Commonwealth of England Scotland and Ireland and the Dominions
and Territories therunto belonging, Or the Name Stile Title or Test of Richard Lord Prote&bholigct;or of the Commonwealth
of England Scotland and Ireland and the Dominions and Territories therunto belonging, or for or by reason of
any alteration of the said Names Stiles or Titles, Or for that the said Fines Recoveries Processe Pleadings Proceedings
and other things before mentioned, Or the Entry and inrolment of them, or any of them were in the Lattaine or
English tongue, But that all and every such Fines Recoveries and other things abovementioned and the A&bholigct;ings
Doeings and Proceedings therupon shall be of such and of noe other Force Effe&bholigct; and Vertue then as if such
Courts Judges Justices Commissioners Officers and Ministers had A&bholigct;ed by vertue of a True Just and Legall
Authority, and as if the same and the Entry and inrolment therof were in Latin, and as if the severall A&bholigct;s and
Ordinances or pretended A&bholigct;s or Ordinances made by both or either Houses of Parliamenr, or any Convention
assembled under the name of a Parliament, or by Oliver Cromwell late stiled Prote&bholigct;or of the Commonwealth of
England Scotland and Ireland and the Dominions therto belonging, and his Councell Warranting or Dire&bholigct;ing
such proceedings had beene Good True and Effe&bholigct;uall A&bholigct;s of Parliament.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Recital that since the Death of the late King Fines had been levied</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">without Entry, or Licentia concordandi.; Such Fines good</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p3">And whereas since the death of the late King severall Fines have beene Leavied without any Entry or due
Entring of any summe paid pro licentia concordandi commonly called the Kings Silver and without Entry, or due
Entry of any summe given to the party for the Concord. And alsoe whereas in the Terme of Saint Michael
last past severall Fines were Leavyed and Recorded in the Court of Common Pleas before one Judge onely of
the said Court, Bee it Ena&bholigct;ed That the said Fines and Proclamations therupon and every of them shall be
good and effe[&bholigct;]uall notwithstanding the defe&bholigct;s aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Fines and Recoveries of Lands in Durham.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it alsoe further Ena&bholigct;ed That all Fines Proclamations of Fines Recoveries and other Judiciall proceedings
in the Court of Common Pleas at Westminster since the death of His late Majesty King Charles the First had
Leavyed or Suffered of any Land&bholngs; lyeing in the County Palatine of Durham shall be good and effe[&bholigct;]uall notwithstanding
the said Land&bholngs; were lyeing in the said County Palatine.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The illegal Proceedings of the High Courts of Justice not allowed.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided That this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained shall not be Construed Deemed or Adjudged to make
good allow confirme or countenance any the Proceedings in the late Illegall and Unwarranted High Courts of
Justice or soe called or any of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V.Recital that Adherents of the Parliament and of the King had been indi&bholigct;ed:</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Such Indi&bholigct;ments, &amp;c. and all Grants thereupon, made void; and all Escheats, &amp;c. restored</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And whereas since the first day of May in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred forty one, and
before the five and twentyeth day of Aprill in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and sixty there
were diverse Persons that Adheered to both Houses of Parliament, who for or in respe&bholigct; of such their adherence
were Indi&bholigct;ed Charged or Impeached of Treason, And whereas since the said first day of May in the yeare
of our Lord One thousand six hundred forty one, and before the said five and twentyeth day of April in the
yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and sixty diverse persons who adhered to His Majestie or to the
late King were for such their adherence Charged Impeached or Indi&bholigct;ed of High Treason, Bee it further provided
and Ena&bholigct;ed That the said Charges Impeachments Indi&bholigct;ments and all Exigents Outlawries Convi&bholigct;ions and Attainders
therupon, and all Letters Patents and Grants therupon made of any Mannours Land&bholngs; Tenements or Hereditaments
Escheated or forfeited by reason of such Attainder, and all Title to any measne Profits by reason of such Convi&bholigct;ion
Outlawry Attainder or Grant be from henceforth repealed and discharged, And that all Escheats Forfeitures and
Confiscations by reason of such Outlawries Convi&bholigct;ion or Attainder Be and are hereby restored unto such Persons
soe Outlawed Convi&bholigct;ed or Attainted their Heires Executors and Administrators respe&bholigct;ively as if noe such Attainder
had beene.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Sales made by Ordinance of Parliament since 1st May 1642 not avoided or confirmed.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided Neverthelesse And be it Ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; or any thing herein contained shall not extend to
avoid or confirme any Sales or Estates made by vertue or pretence of any A&bholigct; Order or Ordinance or reputed
A&bholigct; Order or Ordinance of Parliament since the first day of May in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred forty two, nor any Confirmation therof made, or to be made therof in this present Parliament, but
that such Sales stand and be in the same plight and condition as they should or might have done if this A&bholigct; had
not been made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Recognizances, Obligations, &amp;c. to the late Prote&bholigct;ors.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Exception.; Judgments, &amp;c. for the said Prote&bholigct;ors may be prosecuted in the name and to the Use of the King.; Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all Recognizances Obligations or other Securities
made or given to the Keepers of the Libertie of England by Authoritie of Parliament, or to Oliver Lord Prote&bholigct;or
of the Commonwealth of England Scotland and Ireland and the Dominions therunto belonging, or to Oliver
Lord Prote&bholigct;or of the Commonwealth of England Scotland and Ireland and the Dominions and Territories therunto
belonging, or to Richard Lord Prote&bholigct;or of the Commonwealth of England Scotland and Ireland and the Dominions
and Territories therunto belonging, and not pardoned or discharged by any A&bholigct; passed or to be passed this present
Parliament or otherwise [other then such Recognizances Obligations and Securities as have beene made or given (to
any the pretended powers or persons aforesaid, or to any deriving or pretending to derive Authority from them)
by any person or persons for or by reason of their adherence to His Majesty or his said late Royall Father, or
relating to, or ariseing onely upon or in respe&bholigct; of the late Troubles, All which are hereby declared to be void
and to be delivered up to be Cancelled,<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] And all Judgements Extents Inquisitions Executions and Seizures had for
the said Keepers or Prote&bholigct;ors or any of them, and not likewise pardoned or discharged other then as aforesaid
shall and may be had and prosecuted in the name and to the use of His Majesty His Heires or Successors, [and
alsoe excepting all Obligations Bond&bholngs; or Recognizances entred into to the said Keepers or Prote&bholigct;ors or any of
them by any person or persons by Order or Dire&bholigct;ion of any Councell of State, Committee of Safety Major
Generalls Decimators or any Officer or other person under them, or any other Military power, all which Obligations
Bonds and Recognizances are hereby discharged and declared to be null and void to all intents and purposes.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>.]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Justices, Sergeants, Commissioners of Sewers, &amp;c. of the late Powers not continued.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alsoe and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; nor any thing therin contained shal not extend to continue
after the eighth day of May in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred and sixty any Justice or Justices
of one Bench or the other or Barons of the Exchequer Sergeants at Law Commissions of Sewers Commissions
of Bankerupts or of charitable uses made or constituted by or in the Name or Stile of any the late pretended
powers or authorities,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Writs of Error may be brought by Persons grieved by Judgments of the late Courts.</head>
			<para id="p12">Provided alwayes That it shall and may be lawfull to and for every person and persons who shall finde
themselves greived or damnified by any Judgement Fine Recovery Decree or Sentence given made leavied granted
or pronounced in any of the said Courts to proceed in due forme of Law either by Writt of Error, Bill of
Review Appeale or other lawfull remedy for the Reversing Annuling or Revoking of the same in such manner
as they might at any time heretofore have done if the said Courts had beene established by lawfull Authoritie
other then for those Errors and Defe&bholigct;s which are remedied or provided for by this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Non-claim upon Fines of Lands sold, &amp;c. by Ordinance of Parliament since the 1st May 1642, and before the 25th April 1660.</head>
			<para id="p13">Provided allwayes And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe Non-claim upon or after
any Fine or Fines hereby made good or confirmed shall extend or be construed to Bar or Prejudice any person
or persons their Heires or Successors or their Feoffees or Trustees (other then the partyes to the said Fines and
their Heires generall and speciall and his and their Trustees) as concerning such Right Claime and Interest as they
had in, or to any Land&bholngs; Tenements or other Hereditaments which by colour of any A&bholigct; Order or Ordinance of
both or either Houses of Parliament or any Convention sitting at Westminster under the Name or Stile or assuming
the Name or Stile of a Parliament since the first day of May, in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred forty and two, and before the five and twentyeth day of Aprill in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred and sixty were Sold Conveyed or Disposed as then or late the Land&bholngs; Tenements [and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Hereditaments of
the King Queene or Prince or of Archbishops Bishops Deanes, Deanes and Chapters or other Ecclesiasticall persons, or
as the Land&bholngs; Tenements [and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Hereditaments of any other persons for their Adherency to the late King or His Majesty
that now is, or for any their A&bholigct;ings relating to, or in respe&bholigct; of the late Troubles, soe alwayes that the said
[person or<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] persons aforesaid their Heires or Successors pursue their Title Claime or Interest by way of A&bholigct;ion or
lawfull Entry within five yeares next after the nine and twentyeth day of May in the yeare of our Lord one
thousand six hundred and sixty.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">The late Government declared to be usurped.; Recognition of His Majesty's just Title</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">And although in this Confirmation of Judiciall Proceedings it was necessary to mention Diverse pretensed A&bholigct;s
and Ordinances by the Names and Stiles which those Persons then Usurped who tooke upon them to passe the
same Namely some by the Stile and Name of the Keepers of the Liberty of England by authority of Parliament,
and others by the Name and Stile of Prote&bholigct;ors of the Commonwealth of England Scotland and Ireland and the
Dominions and Territoryes therunto belonging, Yet this present Parliament doth Declare, and it is Ena&bholigct;ed by
Authority of the same That the Names and Stiles aforesaid and every of them are most Rebellious, Wicked,
Trayterous and Abominable Usurpations Detested by this present Parliament as opposite in the Highest Degree to
His Sacred Majestyes most Just and undoubted Right to whom and to His Heires and Lawfull Successors the
Imperiall Crownes of the Realmes of England Scotland and Ireland with their and every of their Dominions and
Territoryes doe of Right appertaine and as violating and Infringing the just Rights and Priviledges of Parliament
and of both Houses therof now Assembled or that hereafter shall be called and assembled.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Indi&bholigct;ments of Persons for levying Wars against Oliver Cromwell, &amp;c. made void.</head>
			<para id="p16">Provided alwayes and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That all and every pretended Indi&bholigct;ment or Indi&bholigct;ments [Outlawes<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
Inquisitions and all Proceedings theron of High Treason against any Person or Persons whatsoever for Leavying
Warr against the late Tirant Oliver Cromwell, the pretended Keepers of the Liberty of England or any other
usurped Power shall be from henceforth void, and of none effe&bholigct; in Law. And that all Grants Conveyances Leases
Devices Assurances Statutes Recognizances and Judgements for Debt, D&bhoaovm;mages heretofore Had Made or Suffered
by any person or his Heires whose Convi&bholigct;ion, Utlagary or Attainder is by this A&bholigct; discharged or made void
shall be of the same force and effe&bholigct; as if noe such Convi&bholigct;ion Outlawry or Attainder had beene.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Outlawryes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


