<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47267" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIX. An Act to prevent Fraudes and Concealments of His Majestyes Customes and Subsidyes.[Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p. 2. nu.7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>c. 4.ante.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Persons conveying away Goods without Entry and Agreement for the Custom; Penalty.; Officer to break and enter Houses suspe&bholigct;ed.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">BEE it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the advice and consent of the Lord&bholngs; and
Commons in this present Parliament assembled That if any person or persons at any time after the first day
of September One thousand six hundred and sixty shall cause any Goods for which Custome Subsidy or other
dutyes are due or payable by vertue of the A&bholigct; passed this Parliament Entituled (A Subsidy granted to the King of
Tonnage and Poundage and other Summes of money payable upon Merchandize exported and imported) to be
landed or conveyed away without due entry therof first made, and the Customer or Colle&bholigct;or or his Deputy agreed
with, That then and in such case upon Oath thereof made before the Lord Treasurer or any of the Barons of the
Exchequer or cheife Magistrate of the Port or Place where the offence shall be committed, or the place next
adjoyning therunto, it shall be lawfull to and for the Lord Treasurer or any of the Barons aforesaid or cheife
Magistrate of the Port or Place where the offence shall be commited or the Place next adjoyning therunto to issue
out a Warrant to any person or person thereby enableing him or them with the assistance of a Sheriffe Justice of
Peace or Constable to enter into any House in the day time where such Good&bholngs; are suspe&bholigct;ed to be concealed, and
in case of resistance to breake open such Houses, and to seize and secure the same goods soe concealed, And
all Officers and Ministers of Justice are hereby required to be aiding and assisting therunto.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Limitation of Entry.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes That noe House shall be entred by vertue of this A&bholigct; unlesse it be within the space of one
moneth after the offence supposed to be commited.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; shall continue in Force[until<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the end of the first Session of the next Parliament
and noe longer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Damages and Costs against false Informers.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alsoe That if the Information wherupon any House shall come to be searched shall prove to be false,
that then and in such case the party injured shall recover his full damages and costs against the Informer by
A&bholigct;ion of Trespasse to bee therefore brought against such Informer.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


