<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47265" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVII. An Act for the Confirming and Restoreing of Ministers. [Rot.Parl.12 C.II.p.3.nu.2.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Certain ordained Ministers, having been in a&bholigct;ual Possession, restored.; The King bound.; The next Avoidance to be in the rightful Patrons.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p2">FORASMUCH as the confirming of some Ecclesiasticall persons and Ministers in possession and restoreing
of others who have beene sequestred or eje&bholigct;ed and are fitt to be restored in and to their severall
Ecclesiasticall Benefices Liveings and Promotions without force or suite of Law will much conduce to the peace
and welfaire of this Church and Kingdome. Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie with the advice
and consent of the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by authoritie of the same that
every Ecclesiasticall person or Minister being Ordained by any Ecclesiasticall persons before the five and twentyeth
day of December last past being of the age of fower and twenty yeares and haveing not renounced his Ordination,
who hath beene formerly since the first day of January in the years of our Lord One thousand six hundred forty
two presented, nominated to, or placed in, and in a&bholigct;uall possession, and takeing the profitts of any Ecclesiasticall
Benefice Re&bholigct;ory Parsonage Viccarage Church Chappell Cure or other Ecclesiasticall promotion with cure of Soules
within this Realme of England Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede which hath become void
either by death, voluntary resignation or surrender or other avoydance to the Patron, or any other person pretending
to have title to accepte of resignations since the said first day of January and before the said five and twentyeth
day of December last past, and was on the said five and twentyeth day of December in possession and received
the proffitts thereof being in the gifte donation, presentation collation or nomination of the Kings Majestie that now
is, or of his late Royall Father King Charles the first in right of the Crowne, or by reason of Wardship or any
other title, or of any Archbishop Bishop Deane, Deane and Chapter Prebend Archdeacon Body Pollitique or
Corporate or of any other person or persons whatsoever other then such as are hereby restored shall be and is
hereby declared adjudged and ena&bholigct;ed to have beene be and continue the reall and lawfull Incumbent Parson
Re&bholigct;or Viccar and possessor of the said Ecclesiasticall Benefices Liveings and Promotions respe&bholigct;ively to all Intents
and purposes whatsoever as if he or they had beene nominated presented collated admitted instituted and indu&bholigct;ed
thereunto or placed therein in due forme of Law and had read and subscribed the Articles according to the Statute
in that case made and provided, and notwithstanding any other matter or thing by him or them done or ommitted
to be done, And that as well against the Kings Majestie and against his Heires and Successors as against all and
every other person and persons Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate whatsoever and their respe&bholigct;ive Successors Heires
Executors Administrators and Assignes, Saveing to the Patrons and every of them their just right of patronage
donation presentation collation or nomination upon the next avoidance of every such Ecclesiasticall person Minister
or Incumbent hereby confirmed as is aforesaid in as full and ample manner as if this A&bholigct; had not beene made.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.Voluntary Resignations by Incumbent confirmed.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that every voluntary surrender or resignation made by any
Incumbent to the Patron of any Benefice, or to any late pretended powers since the said First day of January
of any Ecclesiasticall Benefice or Promotion shall be adjudged as an effe&bholigct;uall avoidance of such Benefice or
Promotion as if the same had beene made to the competent Ordinary and accepted by him.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The former Presentations, &amp;c. shall make no Usurpation.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed that noe presentation, collation, or disposition aforesaid, nor confirmation by this
A&bholigct; of any Person or Minister in or to any Ecclesiasticall Benefices Liveings or Promotions aforesaid shall be
construed or adjudged to amount to any usurpation in Law to the prejudice of any person or persons Bodyes
Pollitique or Corporate who have or shall have right to present therunto upon the said avoidance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. How the Persons to be restored are to be qualified.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">The Time until when the present Incumbent shall stay in; to give Bond on removal to pay moiety of Profits of Living to restored Minister.; Discharge to Minister removed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed that every Ecclesiasticall Person or Minister formerly sequestred or eje&bholigct;ed dispossest
and kepte out after lawfull presentation and perception of the proffits of any of the said Ecclesiasticall Benefices
Liveings or Promotions which hath not subscribed any Petition to bring the late King Charles of blessed memory
to tryall, or which hath not by writeing preaching printing or any other open A&bholigct; procured endeavoured, or
justified the murther of the said late King, or which hath not by preaching printing writeing or constant
refusall to Baptize declared his judgement to be against Infant baptisme shall be restored to the same and to
the possession thereof at or before the Five and twentyeth day of December next ensueing. And that every
Ecclesiasticall person aforesaid who shall be removed shall or may enjoy the Tythes Proffits Dutyes Gleebe and
Houses therunto belonging untill the said Five and twentyeth day of December next ensuesing, and shall then
upon such removall peaceably leave, or yeild up the possession thereof, and shall alsoe give his penall Bond to
the person or Minister soe to be restored to render to him his executors administrators and assignes the full
moyetie of the cleare proffitts and Tythes or the value thereof (to be ascertained by the Commissioners hereafter
appointed under their hand&bholngs;) from Michaelmas last past to Michaelmas next ensueing, (all Taxes and other
requisite charges and expences first dedu&bholigct;ed and allowed before the removall of the Good&bholngs; of the person or
Minister soe to be removed) or the Tythes or other proffitts from the same at or upon the said Five and twentyeth
day of December And the said person or Minister soe to be removed upon his quitting the possession at the time
aforesaid shall be and is hereby absolutely discharged and acquitted from all Tythes and proffits received, and all
and every arreares thereof, other then the moyetie of the proffitts and Tythes secured by Bond&bholngs; aforesaid before
and untill the said Feast of Saint Michaell next ensueing against the person or Minister soe restored his executors
administrators and assignes and against all other person or persons whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Minister to be restored to above one Benefice.; Exception.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">Provided alwayes that every minister not scandalous ignorant or insufficient as aforesaid being proved as
aforesaid heretofore sequestred or eje&bholigct;ed out of two or more Ecclesiasticall Benefices or Liveings with cure of
Soules shall be restored to one of them, and noe more at his Ele&bholigct;ion except where he hath formerly resigned
or surrendred any of the said Benefices or Liveings and therupon the right Patron or any other in his right hath
presented collated nominated placed or putt into the same any other Incumbent or Minister as aforesaid in which
case the said sequestred or eje&bholigct;ed Minister shall not be restored to such Benefice or Liveing soe resigned or
surrendred as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Further Provision on the above Head.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alsoe by the Authoritie aforesaid that every Minister who by vertue of this A&bholigct; is confirmed in
any Ecclesiasticall Benefice or Liveing with cure of Soules which shall have more then one Ecclesiasticall Benefice
or Liveing with cure of Soules shall hold and enjoy onely one of them and noe more at his Ele&bholigct;ion, except
where he hath formerly resigned or surrendred any of the said Benefices or Liveings and therupon the right
Patron or any other in his right hath presented collated nominated placed or putt into the same any other
Incumbent or Minister as aforesaid in which case the Minister soe to be confirmed shall and may retaine and
keepe the Benefice or Liveing which he hath not soe resigned or surrendred as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. The Party to be restored may confirm the present Possessor's Right.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Party removed to pay Tenths, and answer for Dilapidations; and pay Fifths, or money in lieu thereof.; Bond for the same, and on refusal, A&bholigct;ion for Minister retored</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And bee it likewise Ena&bholigct;ed that where the Person or Minister formerly sequestred or eje&bholigct;ed shall declare
his consent in writeing before the Commissioners appointed by this A&bholigct; that the present Possessor being not
scandalous ignorant or insufficient shall be and continue in such sequestred Benefice Liveing or Promotion that in
such case the present Possessor shall be hereby setled and confirmed therin as the sole and rightfull Incumbent
[and Possessor<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] therof to all intents and purposes Any former Statute or Law to the contrary notwithstanding And
that every Person or Minister who shall be removed by this A&bholigct; shall pay all Tenthes not pardoned, and repair
or make satisfa&bholigct;ion for all wilfull or negligent Diapidations made or suffered by him of, in or upon the premisses
or any of them since the twenty ninth of September last, And shall likewise pay or satisfie all Fifthes or any
other summe in lieu of Fifths which were in arreare or unpaid at the Feast of Saint Michaell the Archangell last
past due or payable by him, by any order or orders not reversed of any Committees or Commissioners formerly
appointed and authorized by any pretended authoritie or authorities whatsoever to grant and sett out the same,
or otherwise pay or satisfie all arreares then due of any summe or summes of money payable by agreement of
the partyes and not since quitted by like Agreement, the same to be ascertained by the said Commissioners,
For payment wherof the Minister soe to be removed before his removall shall alsoe give his penall Bond or
Bond&bholngs; unto the Minister to be restored to pay the same before the Five and twentyeth of December next,
And if he shall refuse to give such Bond or Bonds as aforesaid for the payment therof, that then the Minister
soe to be restored shall be and is hereby enabled to bring an A&bholigct;ion of Debt at the Common Law for the said
arreares, and shall recover over and above the said Debt the full value in Damages besides costs of Suite</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for Arrears of Fifths, or Money in lieu thereof.; Proviso as to Parson Honywood.</head>
			<para id="p12">And it is further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that every Ecclesiasticall Person or Minister now in
possession of any Ecclesiasticall Benefice Liveing or Promotion which shall continue and be setled therin by vertue
of this A&bholigct; shall pay all such arreares of Fifths or other summes of money in lieu therof due or payable by
him by any such order or orders or agreement as aforesaid, [Or to Master Honywood Parson of Kegworth in
Leicestershire who hath beene beyond Sea since the said First of January One thousand six hundred forty two
who hath therefore had noe order nor agreement for his Fifths<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] as have accrewed due or payable out of such
Ecclesiasticall Benefice Liveing or Promotion dureing such time as he hath beene possessed therof to such Person
or Minister as hath beene formerly eje&bholigct;ed or sequestred out of the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Persons to whom arrears of Fifths due, or their representatives, or Parson Honywood, enabled to recover the same by A&bholigct;ion of Debt.</head>
			<para id="p13">And whereas diverse Fifths or summes of money in lieu therof are in arreare and unpaid by such as have beene
formerly possessed of Sequestred Liveings It is further Ena&bholigct;ed by Authoritie aforesaid that every Ecclesiasticall
Person or Minister now liveing, or the Executors or Administrators of every Ecclesiasticall Person or Minister
deceased to whom any fifths or summes of money in lieu therof are or were due or payable by any such order
or agreement or to the said [Master<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Honywood as aforesaid and are yet in arreare shall have the said Fifths or
summes of money in arreare as aforesaid paid unto them respe&bholigct;ively, And they are hereby respe&bholigct;ively enabled
to recover the same by A&bholigct;ion of Debt at the Common Law to be brought against every such person or Minister
who ought to have paid the same by vertue of any such order or agreement or to the said [Master<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Honywood as
aforesaid dureing the respe&bholigct;ive possession of such Ecclesiasticall Benefice Liveing or Promotion of or for which the</para>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for former Payments</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">said Fifths or summes of money in lieu thereof were or ought to have beene or to be paid, in all which A&bholigct;ions
noe Essoygne Wager of Law or prote&bholigct;ion shall be allowed And that noe person to whom Fifths have beene
formerly paid shall be hereafter questioned for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Persons removed from Livings enabled to hold mesne Profits already received, and to recover Arrears.</head>
			<para id="p16">And be it alsoe Ena&bholigct;ed That every such Ecclesiasticall Person or Minister that is or shall be by vertue of this
A&bholigct; removed out of or confirmed in any such Benefice Liveing or Promotion which now is, or hath beene possessed
as aforesaid his or their Executors Administrators and Assignes shall be and is respe&bholigct;ively enabled to have hold
and enjoy all the meane proffitts already received and to receive recover colle&bholigct; or compound for, and enjoy
all and every the areares of Tythes proffits or dutyes thereunto belonging, or which shall belong therunto
incurred dureing such time as he was so possessor thereof, and before or untill the Feast of Saint Michaell the
Archangell now next ensueing, and to sue for the same in any Court of Common Law or Equity as if he or
they had beene and were the true and lawfull Incumbent or Possessor of such aforesaid Ecclesiasticall Benefice
Liveing or Promotion,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Persons having Benefice, &amp;c. who have petitioned to bring the late King to Trial, &amp;c. not to remain, and Patron may present.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided alsoe and be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any Minister or other such Ecclesiasticall
Person as aforesaid haveing any Ecclesiasticall Benefice or Liveing with Cure of Soules who is before in and by
this A&bholigct; declared adjudged and ena&bholigct;ed to continue the reall and lawfull Incumbent thereof which hath petitioned
to bring the late King Charles of blessed memory to Tryall, or which hath by writeing preaching printing or
any other open A&bholigct; procured endeavoured [or<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] justified the murder of the late King, or which hath by preaching
printing writeing or constant refusall to baptize declared his judgement to be against Infant baptisme, that then
such Minister or other Ecclesiasticall person shall not remaine continue and be or be taken to be the reall and
lawfull Incumbent of the Ecclesiasticall Benefice or Liveing, but the same shall become and is hereby declared to be
void to all intents and purposes as if the said Minister or other Ecclesiasticall Person were dead, and that the
Patron who hath the next and immediate right to present unto the same shall and may present unto the said
Ecclesiasticall Benefice or Liveing as in case of vacancy or avoidance by death of the Incumbent. Any thing in
this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary thereof notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Justices of Peace dwelling next to the Living, appointed Commissioners to execute this A&bholigct; without further Suit.; All former Suits made void.</head>
			<para id="p18">And it is further Ena&bholigct;ed That the persons in Commission of the Peace in the severall Countyes of this Realme
the Dominion of Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede on the first day of September One thousand six
hundred and sixtie within their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Limitts and Precin&bholigct;s or any Five or more of them liveing or
dwelling next to the Church or Liveing to which any [such<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Person or Minister is to be restored, or from which
any such Person or Minister is to be removed and who are noe wayes interested as partrons or partyes in the
Patronage, or Tithes of the said Church or Liveing or any part thereof shall be and are hereby constituted appointed
and authorized to be Commissioners to execute all and singular the Powers and Authorityes hereby granted within
their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes and Precin&bholigct;s for and concerning the removeing and restoreing of such Persons and
Ministers as aforesaid, and all other the premisses, And finally to determine all differences touching the same untill
the Five and twentyeth of December next, And that all Suites and A&bholigct;ions in Law or Equity, and all proceedings
and verdi&bholigct;s thereupon had or to be had for, touching or concerning the premisses or any of them shall be, and
are hereby stayed barred annulled and avoided.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Certain Leases made by former Ministers confirmed.; Exception.</head>
			<para id="p19">Provided alwayes and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That all Grants and Leases made for a valueable consideration paid or
given of any Copyhold or Freehold Land&bholngs; belonging to any Sequestred Liveing or Re&bholigct;ory (excepting the Glebe
and Tythes) for three Lives or Twenty one yeares according to former usage wherein the auntient Rent is reserved
made by any Minister or Ecclesiasticall person possessed of the said Re&bholigct;ory or Liveing by any reall or pretended
Authority before the five and twentyeth of December One thousand six hundred fifty nine shall continue as good
and effe&bholigct;uall in Law to all Intents against the Eje&bholigct;ed and Sequestred Incumbent to be restored and all others
as if they had beene made by the proper Incumbent.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Ministers refused to be approved by the pretended Approvers settled in their Churches.; Proviso.</head>
			<para id="p20">Provided alwayes and be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That if any rightfull Patron hath heretofore presented his Clerke to
any Benefice with Cure of Soules being then void unto those persons who were stiled Commissioners for approbation
of publique preachers sitting at Whitehall or the Committee for plundred Ministers who sate in the yeare One
thousand six hundred fifty and nine, and the same Clerke soe presented was refused to be admitted without any
lawfull cause That then such Clerke shall be taken and is hereby Ena&bholigct;ed to be [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] perfe&bholigct; Incumbent of such
Benefice to all intents and purposes Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding Unlesse such Patron have
since presented another Clerke to such Benefice who is now possessed thereof, or unlesse such Clerke soe presented
and refused as aforesaid be since presented to, and setled in some other Benefice.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. None to be restored which deserted their Livings.</head>
			<para id="p21">Provided that this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contayned shall not extend or be construed to confirme or
continue any person in any Benefice or Ecclesiasticall Liveing or Preferment which hath since the said Five and
twentyeth day of December last voluntarily yeilded up &amp; left the possession of the said Benefice or Ecclesiasticall
Liveing or Preferment and is still out of possession thereof, or which by any writeing executed under his Hand
and Seale hath agreed to yeild up and leave the possession thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Agreements made respe&bholigct;ing Fifths confirmed.</head>
			<para id="p22">Provided alsoe and it is hereby declared That where there hath beene any agreement betweene the persons
concerned in this A&bholigct; for the acquittall of the Minister who ought to have paid Fifths of and from the same or
any part thereof That in such case noe Fifths or satisfa&bholigct;ion for Fifths shall be claimed or paid contrary to the
said agreement.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Payments of Tithes, &amp;c. to the present Possessors a Discharge.</head>
			<para id="p23">Provided alwayes and bee it Ena&bholigct;ed That all and every person and persons who have paid or satisfied by
composition or otherwise any Tythes Pensions Oblations Obventions Rents or other Ecclesiasticall Dutyes belonging
to any Re&bholigct;ory Viccaridge or other Ecclesiasticall Benefice or Promotion to any person or persons being in
possession or receiving the proffitts thereof by colour or pretence of any Authoritie or to their Assignes or any
others, claiming from by or under them shall be and are hereby discharged of and from the same Tythes Pensions
Oblations Obventions Rents and other Ecclesiasticall Dutyes against all and every person and persons whatsoever,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Proviso as to Ewelme Re&bholigct;ory.</head>
			<para id="p24">Provided allwayes That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing herein contained shall extend to confirme or establish
the possession of the Re&bholigct;ory of Ewelme in the County of Oxon with Thomas Cole or any other person or persons,
who have lately by vertue of any pretended Title entered into the same, But that the said Re&bholigct;ory be restored to
Robert Saunderson Do&bholigct;or in Divinity and Regius Professor in the University of Oxon to be enjoyed by him and
his Successors according to a Grant made thereof by the late King James unto the Regius [Proversor<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] of Divinity
for the time being and his Successors for ever,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Proviso as to Somersham Re&bholigct;ory.</head>
			<para id="p25">Provided alsoe that noething herein contained shall confirme or establish the Possession of the Re&bholigct;ory of
Somersham in the County of Huntington with any person who hath by vertue of any pretended Title entered into
the same, But that the said Re&bholigct;ory be restored to Do&bholigct;or Anthony Tuckney the present Regius Professor of
Divinity in the University of Cambridge to be enjoyed by him and his Successors according to a former Grant
therof made unto the Regius Professor of Divinity for the time being and his Successors for ever, Any thing herein
contained to the contrary notwithstanding,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy to be taken by Persons restored.</head>
			<para id="p26">Provided [alwayes<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] that this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained shall not extend to confirme or restore any
Ecclesiasticall Person or Minister in or to any Benefice Liveing or Ecclesiasticall Promotion that shall refuse to take
the Oathes of Alleigiance &amp; Supremacy being tendered unto such Ecclesiasticall Person or Minister by the said
Commissioners or any three of them, which said Commissioners and every three of them are hereby enabled and
enjoyned to Administer the said Oathes accordingly</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Proviso for Presentations under the Great Seal.</head>
			<para id="p27">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed that this A&bholigct; or any thing herein contained shall not prejudice the Title
of any person or persons to any Ecclesiasticall Liveing Benefice or Promotion with cure of Soules in this A&bholigct;
mentioned who have beene and shall be presented to such Benefice or Promotion by his Majestye under the Great
Seale of England betweene the first day of May in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and sixty
and the Ninth of September in the same yeare, but that such Presentees soe presented by his Majesty as aforesaid
shall and may from and after the said Twenty ninth day of September enjoy the same Benefices and Promotions
respe&bholigct;ively as if this A&bholigct; had not beene made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Proviso for Possessors of Livings on 25th Dec. 1659 as to Charge for Profits received before 29th Sept. 1660.</head>
			<para id="p28">Neverthelesse it is Declared and Ena&bholigct;ed that such persons as up the Twenty fifth day of December One
thousand six hundred fifty nine were the possessors of such Benefices or Promotions shall not be charged by such
Presentees of his Majestie with or for any proffitts by them or any of them received before the [said<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] twenty nineth
day of September but shall hold and enjoy the proffitts of such Benefices and Promotions respe&bholigct;ively untill the said
twenty ninth day of September.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Proviso for Kidlington Vicarage.</head>
			<para id="p29">Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to confirme any person in the
Viccaridge of Kidlington in the County of Oxford But that the said Viccaridge shall remaine as formerly annexed
to the Re&bholigct;orship of Exeter Colledge in Oxford, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Garsington Re&bholigct;ory.</head>
			<para id="p30">Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to confirme any person in the
Re&bholigct;ory of Garsington in the County of Oxford but that the said Re&bholigct;ory shall remaine as formerly annexed to
the Presidentship of Trinity Colledge in Oxford, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Castor Re&bholigct;ory.</head>
			<para id="p31">Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contayned shall not extend to confirme any person in the
Re&bholigct;ory of Castor in the County of Northampton but that the said Re&bholigct;ory shall remaine as formerly annexed to
the Bishoprick of Peterborough Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Cudsden Vicarage.</head>
			<para id="p32">Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to confirme any person in the
Vicaridge of Cudsden in the County of Oxford but that the said Vicaridge shall remaine as formerly annexed to
the Bishopricke of Oxford, Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Persons having printed or preached against the King's Right to the Crown not to be restored.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided alwayes that this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend to the confirming or setleing any
person in a Liveing that hath malitiously printed any Treatise, or preached against his Majestye that now is, his
Right or Succession to the Crownes of these Realmes soe as the same be proved by the Oathes of two credible
Witnesses before the Commissioners appointed by this A&bholigct; (who have hereby power to administer the same) and
soe adjudged by the said Commissioners before the Five and twentyeth day of December One thousand six
hundred and sixtie,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Sheriff to give Possession to restored Ministers.</head>
			<para id="p34">Provided alsoe That if any Minister who shall by this A&bholigct; be adjudged to be removed shall not give up the
possession according to the Order of the said Commissioners then the said Commissioners or any Five of them shall
grant their Warrant to the Sheriffe of the County to put such person adjudged to be restored into possession
according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;, which said Sheriffe shall execute the same accordingly and
in default of such Warrant the Sheriffe of the County for the time being shall be, and is hereby enabled and
required to give possession accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXVIII. None to be restored who with Arms opposed the Restoration and a free Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p35">Provided That this A&bholigct; shall not extend or be construed to confirme any Ecclesiasticall person that did appeare
in Arms and march in a Troope in opposition to the intended restoring of his Majestie and a free Parliament since
the First day of August in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred fifty and nine soe as the same be
proved by the Oathes of two credible Witnesses before the Commissioners appointed by this A&bholigct; (who have hereby
power to administer the same) and soe adjudged by the said Commissioners before the Five and twentyeth day of
December One thousand six hundred and sixty.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXIX. Proviso for A&bholigct;on Re&bholigct;ory.</head>
			<para id="p36">[Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to confirme any person in the
Re&bholigct;ory of A&bholigct;on in the County of Midlesex, which Re&bholigct;ory his Majestie before the Six and twentyeth day of
August hath granted under his Signe Manuall to one of his Chaplins.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXX. Proviso for Peers presenting within Six Months from 1st Sept.1660.</head>
			<para id="p37">And lastly it is Declared and Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that all and every the Peeres of this Realme
according to their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Titles and Interests may at any time or times within the space of six
Kalender moneths from the First day of September in this present yeare One thousand six hundred and sixty
present and nominate their respe&bholigct;ive Clerke or Clerks unto any Ecclesiasticall Benefices Liveings or Promotions
of their respe&bholigct;ive Patronages, or whereunto they had right or title to present or nominate at any time since the
First of January One thousand six hundred forty two, And that the said Presentees shall be thereupon admitted
instituted and indu&bholigct;ed, and after have and enjoy and sue for and recover the possession, and from thenceforth
take the whole and entire proffits of the said Benefices Liveings and Promotions, and shall be accounted and shall
be full and perfe&bholigct; Incumbents of the same to all intents and purposes as fully and amply as if they had beene
presented and placed therein within six moneths next after the first Avoydances not with standing any Lapse or other
Title by reason of Lapse incurred or devolved to his late Majesty, or to the Kings Majesty that now is, or to any
other person or persons Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate, Any thing in this present A&bholigct; or otherwise to the contrary
hereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXI. Proviso for Presentees by the King before 9th Sept. 1660.</head>
			<para id="p38">Provided that such Presentees as have beene or shall be presented by his Majesty as aforesaid before the said
Nineth day of September in this present yeare One thousand six hundred and sixty by Title of Lapse or otherwise
as aforesaid shall [or<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] may enjoy the same Benefices and Promotions respe&bholigct;ively, the last mentioned Clause or
any other thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary notwithstanding.<ref idref="n9">9</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">M<emph type="p">r</emph><emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Professor <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">alsoe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


