<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47261" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An Act for restraining the takeing of Excessive Usury. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p. 2. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Abatement of Interest is advantageous to Trade.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.; None to take above Six Pounds for a Hundred Pounds.; All Securitites, on which higher Interest reserved, void.; Persons taking, &amp;c. by any Shift higher Interest; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">FOASMUCH as the Abatement of Interest from Ten in the Hundred in former times hath beene found by
notable experience beneficiall to the Advancement of Trade and Improvement of Lands by good Husbandry
with many other considerable advantages to this Nation, especially the reduceing of it to a nearer proportion
with Forraigne States with whom wee traffique, And wheras in fresh memory the like fall from Eight to Six in
the Hundred by a late constant pra&bholigct;ise hath found the like Successe to the generall contentment of this Nation
as is visible by severall Improvements. And whereas it is the endeavour of some at present to reduce it backe
againe in pra&bholigct;ice to the allowance of the Statute still in force to Eight in the Hundred to the great discouragement
of Ingenuity and industry in the Husbandry Trade and Commerce of this Nation. Bee it for the Reasons aforesaid
Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestye and the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in this present Parliament assembled
That noe person or persons whatsoever from and after the twenty ninth day of September in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred and sixty upon any Contra&bholigct; shall from and after the said twenty ninth (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) of
September take dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly for Loane of any [Money<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Wares Merchandice or other Commodityes whatsoever
above the value of Six Pound&bholngs; for the Forbearance of one Hundred Pound&bholngs; for a Yeare, and soe after that Rate
for a greater or lesser Summe or for a longer or shorter time, And that all Bond&bholngs; Contra&bholigct;s and Assurances
whatsoeyer made after the time aforesaid for payment of any principall or money to be lent or covenanted to be
performed upon or for any Usury, wherupon or whereby there shall be reserved or taken above the Rate of Six
pounds in the Hundred as aforesaid shall be utterly void, And that all and every person and persons whatsoever
which shall after the time aforesaid upon any Contra&bholigct; to be made after the said twenty ninth day of September
take accept and receive by way or meanes of any corrupt Bargaine Loane Exchange Cheivesaunce Shift or Interest
of any Wares Merchandise or other thing or things whatsoever, or by any deceitfull way or meanes or by
any covin, engine or deceitfull conveyance for the forbearing or giveing day of payment for one whole yeare of
and for their Money or other thing above the S&bhouov;me of Six pounds for the forbearing of One hundred pounds
for a yeare, and soe after that Rate for a greater or lesser Summe or for a longer or shorter Terme shall
forfeit and loose for every such offence the treble value of the Moneyes Wares Merchandize and other things soe
Lent Bargained Sold Exchanged or Shifted;</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Scriveners taking above 5s. for the Loan of &pound; 100 for a Year, or above 12d. for making, &amp;c. Bonds, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;20 and Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That all and every Scrivenor and Scrivenors Broker and
Brokers Sollicitor and Sollicitors Driver and Drivers of Bargaines for Contra&bholigct;s who shall after said twenty
nineth day of September take or receive dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly any Summe or Summes of Money or other reward
or thing for Brokage Solliciting Driving or Procureing the Loane or forbearing of any Summe or Summes of Money
over and above the Rate or Value of five shillings for the Loane, or forbearing of one hundred pound&bholngs; for a yeare
and soe rateably, or above twelve pence for [the<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] making or renewing of the Bond or Bill for the Loane, or for
forbearing thereof, or for any Counterbond or Bill concerning the same shall forfeite for every such Offence
twenty pound&bholngs; and have Imprisonment for halfe a yeare; The one moyety of all which forfeitures to be to the
King our Soveraigne Lord His Heires and Successors, And the other moyety to him or them that will sue for the
same in the same County where the severall Offences are committed and not elsewhere by a&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill
Plaint or Information, in which noe Essoigne Wager of Law, or prote&bholigct;ion to be allowed.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Day <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Moneyes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


