<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47268" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER XX. An Act for raising seavenscore thousand pound&bholngs; for the compleate disbanding of the whole Army and paying off
some part of the Navy. [Rot. Parl. 12 C.II. p. 2. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head></head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">&pound;70,000 per Month for Two Months assessed; under the same Commissioners (Exception) and;
by the same Rules, &amp;c. as by the Ordinance herein mentioned, and c.2. ante.;
The Commissioners to meet on 6th Nov. 1660, and execute the said Rules accordingly</emph>.
		</para>
		<para id="p2">The Commons assembled in Parliament doe give and grant unto your Most Excellent Majestye the summe
of seavenscore thousand pound&bholngs; to be raised and leavyed in manner following and for the uses and purposes
herein after declared, and Doe therefore humbly pray your Majesty that it may be ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed
by the Kings Most Excellent Majesty by and with the advice and consent of the Lord&bholngs; and Commons in this
present Parliament assembled that the summe of threescore and ten thousand pound&bholngs; by the moneth for two
[monenthes<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] begining from the first day of November One thousand six hundred and sixty shall be assessed taxed
colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid in the severall Countyes Cittyes Burroughs Townes and Places within England and
Wales and [the<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede according to such rates rules and proprotions and by the same
C&bhooov;missioners (excepting such as stand disabled by a certaine A&bholigct; passed this present Parliament intituled An A&bholigct;
of Indempnity free pardon and oblivion) and with like powers and authorityes as in and by a certain Ordinance
intituled An Ordinance of the Lord&bholngs; and Commons for an assesment of seaventy thousand pound&bholngs; by the moneth
upon England for three moneths for the supply of the present occasions of the Kings Majesty, and for and toward&bholngs;
the payment and satisfa&bholigct;ion of the Armies and Navies continued for the defence of this Kingdome, and for other
the necessary and urgent occasions thereof together with a certaine A&bholigct; passed this Parliament intituled An A&bholigct; for
putting in execution an Ordinance mentioned in the said A&bholigct;, are expressed declared and appointed, which said
Commissioners shall meete on or before the sixth day of November One thousand six hundred and sixty, and are
hereby enabled to use and execute all and every the like rates rules proportions powers and [ and<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] authoritiyes as in
and by the said Ordinance and A&bholigct; are mentioned and expressed as fully and amply as if the same had beene
perticularly inserted in this present A&bholigct;.</para>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">II. The Monies so colle&bholigct;ed to be paid at the Guildhall of London to Treasurers under c.9. ante; whose Acquitance to be a discharge.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p4">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that all and every the summes to be colle&bholigct;ed and raised
by vertue of this present A&bholigct; shall be paid at the Guildhall of the Citty of London unto Sir Richard Browne Sir
John Langham Sir William Wheeler Sir William Vincent Thomas Rich and the Chamberlain of the City of London
for the time being who are appointed Treasurers of the money to be raised by vertue of another A&bholigct; passed this
present Parliament intituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy provision of money for disbanding and paying off the forces
of this kingdome both by land and sea, and the acquaittance of them or any three of them shall be a sufficient
discharge for soe much money as shall be received by vertue of this A&bholigct; to any person or persons who shall
pay in the same.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>III. Allowance to Treasurers of id. per Pound.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed that the Treasurers by this A&bholigct; appointed shall receive for them and those to be
imployed under them in this service one penny in the pound in such manner as they ought to receive by the A&bholigct;
last before mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>IV. Treasurers to issue Monies received by them according to Warrants from the Commissioners under c. 15. ante, 
who are to take Care that the said Monies are employed first</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">in desbanding the Army,; and then in paying off a certain Part of the Navy</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed that all and every the summes of money which by vertue of this present A&bholigct; shall
be paid to, or received by the Treasurers aforesaid shall from time to time be issued out according to such Warrants
and Dire&bholigct;ions onely as they or any three of them shall receive from the Commissioners named in one A&bholigct; of
this present Parliament intituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy disbanding of the Army and Garrisons of this Kingdome
who are hereby required and enjoyed at their perrils to take care and provide that the moneyes soe as aforesaid
to be issued out be applyed onely to the uses intents and purposes hereafter following and to now other use intent
or purpose whatsoever that is to say principally and in the first place for and toward&bholngs; the totall disbanding of
the present. Army untill that worke be fully perfe&bholigct;ed and compleated according to such rules and instru&bholigct;ions as
touching the disbanding [of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the Army in the said A&bholigct; last mentioned are contained, and after the Army shall be wholly
disbanded, then the residue of the moneyes to be raised by vertue of this present A&bholigct; shall be imployed for and
toward&bholngs; the paying off such part of the Fleet and Navy that shall be returned into Harbor on or before the eighth
day of September One thousand six hundred and sixty according to such rules orders and instru&bholigct;ions as touching
the payment off of the Navy are in the said last mentioned A&bholigct; contained and not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>V. Account of Monies received to be given by Treasurers to Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p8">And Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that an accompt of all the moneyes by vertue of this A&bholigct; to be received shall be
given by the said Treasurers, to this or any other succeeding Parliament which shall require the same or to such
person or persons as by this or any other succeeding Parliament shall be therunto appointed;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>VI. Persons lending Money to Treasurers do a good Service to the King and Kingdom.;
Repayment secured with Interest at &pound;6 per Cent. Money to be employed to the Purposes aforesaid</head>
			<para id="p9">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that if any person or persons shall lend unto the Treasurers aforesaid any
summe or summes of money to and for the uses and purposes in this present A&bholigct; mentioned, such person shall doe
very good and acceptable service to the King and Kingdome and shall likewise be repaid the same with consideration
for the forbearance thereof after the rate of six pound&bholngs; per cen&tilde; out of the first moneyes which after such loane
shall come in upon this present A&bholigct;, and the said Treasurers or any three of them shall be and are hereby enabled
to repay the said moneyes accordingly to the party soe lending the same, whose acquittances shall be unto them a
sufficient discharge, and the money soe advanced by way of loane shall be imployed to the uses in this A&bholigct; mentioned
and not otherwise</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VII. The whole Money to be paid on 25th Dec. 1660.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to sign and seal Duplicate of Assessment,and 
certify to Treasurers with the Names of Receivers General.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p11">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed that this whole and intire summe of seavenscore thousand pound&bholngs; intended by this
A&bholigct; to be raised shall be fully paid in and compleated upon or before the twenty fifth day of December One
thousand six hundred and sixty. And that the Commissioners for the said monethly assessment or any two or more
of them in their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughs Townes and Places within England and Wales and the
towne of Berwicke upon Tweede shall signe and seale a duplicate of the said assessments and the same before the
said five and twentyeth day of December shall certifie into the Guildhall of the Citty of London unto the Treasurers
aforesaid together with the names of the respe&bholigct;iv Receivers Generall who shall be appointed to receive the same.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Monethes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


