<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47279" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXI. An Act for Confirmation of Leases and Grants from Colledges and Hospitalls. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p. 4. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that divers Members of the Universities, Cathedrals, Colleges of Eton, Winchester, &amp;c., had been amoved, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">and that afterwards other Persons had been ele&bholigct;ed and had exercised the same Places, and made Leases, Grants, &amp;c. upon which Questions might arise.; Ele&bholigct;ion of Officers of Colleges and Hospitals confirmed, and all Grants, &amp;c. by them; and all Leases by Masters, &amp;c. of Hospital of the Patronage of any Bishop, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">WHEREAS since the begining of the late Troubles diverse Masters Provosts Presidents Wardens Governours
Re&bholigct;ors Principalls and other Head&bholngs; Fellowes and Schollors of Colledges Halls or Houses of Learning in
either of the Universityes of Oxford and Cambridge and the Deane Cannons and Prebend&bholngs; of the Cathedrall or
Collegiat Church or Colledge of Christ Church in the University of Oxford and Provost Warden or other Head
Officer and Fellowes or Schollers of the Colledges of Eaton and Winchester and Masters and Governors Bretheren
Brothers and Sisters of diverse Hospitalls have beene amoved eje&bholigct;ed or sequestred by the Lord&bholngs; and Commons
assembled in Parliament, or by certaine Visitors by them appointed, or by some Conventions sitting at Westminster
under the name or stile of a Parliament or by some Authority or pretence of Authoritie derived from them or the
late pretended and usurped powers stiled Keepers of the Liberty of England by authority of Parliament, or Prote&bholigct;ors
of the Commonwealth of England Scotland and Ireland and the Dominions or Dominions and Territories thereunto
belonging. And whereas alsoe after these Amotions Eje&bholigct;ions or Sequestrations severall other persons have beene
either by ele&bholigct;ion of the said Colledges Halls Houses of Learning Church or Hospitalls or by some of the Powers
or pretended Powers above mentioned placed and substituted in these Mastershipps Headshipps Fellowshipps Deanarie
Canories Prebendaries Governorshipps and other Places aforesaid who have a&bholigct;ually exercised the same places and
beene de fa&bholigct;o Masters Provosts Presidents Wardens Governours Re&bholigct;ors Principalls and other Head&bholngs; Fellowes
Schollars Bretheren Brothers and Sisters Deane Canons or Prebend&bholngs; of such respe&bholigct;ive Colledges Halls Houses of
Learning Hospitalls Cathedrall Church or places, and have made diverse Grants by Copy of Court Roll, and Leases
and Licences to lett or assigne Grants and Presentations to and Ele&bholigct;ions of diverse persons, Re-entries for
non payment of Rent or breach of Conditions whereupon diverse Questions may in time to come arise. For
prevention whereof It is Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie with the Advice and assent of the Lord&bholngs;
and Commons in Parliament assembled and by Authority of the same That all Grants by Coppy of Court Roll
and Leases and Licences of setting and assigning Grants and Presentations And all Ele&bholigct;ions of Head&bholngs; Masters
Fellowes Schollers Students and Officers of the said Colledges Halls Church and Houses of Learning and Hospitalls
aforesaid into dead or other places then or since vacant Receipts &amp; Acquittances of Rents incurred Entryes for
forfeitures or Conditions broken had made or given since the five and twentyeth day of March in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred forty two, and before the five and twentyeth day of July in the yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred and sixty by any such Masters Provosts Presidents Wardens Governours Re&bholigct;ors Principalls
and other Head&bholngs; de fa&bholigct;o of the said Colledges Halls and Houses of Learning and Fellowes and Schollars de fa&bholigct;o
of the same respe&bholigct;ively in either of the said Universities, or Deane and Canons or Prebend&bholngs; de fa&bholigct;o of Christ
Church aforesaid, or Master Provost or Warden and Fellowes de fa&bholigct;o of the Colledges of Eaton or Winchester or
by such Master Warden or Governours de fa&bholigct;o, or Master Warden or Governours Bretheren Brothers or Sisters
de fa&bholigct;o of any Hospitall by whatsoever particular name or stile of Foundation the said Colledges Church Hospitalls
Masters Goverrnors Fellowes Deanes and Canons or Prebend&bholngs; are stiled founded knowne or incorporated and all
Leases granted by the Master Warden Bretheren Brothers or Sisters of any Hospitalls of the Patronage of any Bishop,
Deane, or Deane and Chapter and all surrenders to them made to inable such Leases Grants and Presentations shall
stand and be of the same and noe other force and effe&bholigct; as if the said Masters Provosts Presidents Wardens
Governours Re&bholigct;ors Principalls Head&bholngs; Fellowes Schollers Deane Canons Prebend&bholngs; Bretheren Brothers or Sisters had
beene such de jure and duely and de jure intituled [in and<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to the said Colledges Halls Houses of Learning Church Hospitall&bholngs; Offices or places respe&bholigct;ively, And as if such Leases granted by the Master and Bretheren of any Hospitall
of the patronage of any Bishop Deane or Chapter had beene confirmed by the said Bishop Deane or Chapter, And
that notwithstanding such defe&bholigct; in the said Lessors or Grantors, and notwithstanding the restitution of any [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the
persons soe eje&bholigct;ed, the Rents Covenants and Conditions contained in such Leases and Grants shall goe in succession
as if such Lessors or Grantors had beene de jure Masters Provosts Presidents Wardens Governors Re&bholigct;ors Principalls
Head&bholngs; Fellowes Schollers Deane Canons Prebend&bholngs; Bretheren Brothers and Sisters of such Colledges Halls Houses
of Learning Church Hospitalls and places respe&bholigct;ively Any former Law Custome or Statute to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Exception of Leases of Lands, &amp;c. of the Hospital of St. John Baptist in Northampton.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That noe thing in this A&bholigct; contained doe or shall extend to the confirming
or makeing good of any Lease or Leases of any parcell or parcells of Land&bholngs; Tenements Pastures Houses Orchards
Gardens or Barnes or any of the possessions of or belonging to the Hospitall of S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Baptist and the Evangelist in
the Towne of Northampton made betweene the first day of September in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred fifty and five and the five and twentyeth day of July in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
fifty and eight by the pretended Master George Goodman and his Co-bretheren of the aforesaid Hospitall by colour
of any pretended Grant or Patent whatsoever, or notwithstanding the Seale of the said Hospitall or Corporation
was to them or any of them set or affixed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Exception of Leases of Lands of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Oswald Hospital, in the County of Worcester.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided allwayes That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to make good in Law or
Equity any Lease or Leases made by Simon Moore Clerk late Master or pretended Master of the Hospitall of
S<emph type="p">t</emph> Oswald in the County of Worcester of any the Land&bholngs; Tenements and Hereditaments of or belonging to the said
Hospitall to Richard Moore sonne of the said Simon Moore or to any of the children or grandchildren of the
said Simon Moore or to any other person or persons in trust or for the use or uses of the said Simon Moore or
his Wife Children or Grandchildren or any or either of them</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Exception of Officers of Colleges not ordained where Ordination is requisite.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwayes that noe person or persons shall be confirmed in any Mastershipp Provostship Headshipp
Fellowship or Chaplains place in any Colledge or Hall in either of the Universities of Oxford or Cambridge or in
the Colledges of Eaton and Winchester that is not [an<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] ordained Minister by Bishops or Presbiters, (or being
ordained hath since renounced his Ordination) where by the locall Statutes of the said [respe&bholigct;ive<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Colledges or Halls
Ordination is required.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Exception of Leases of certain Re&bholigct;ories, &amp;c. in the Tenure of Lord Culpeper.; Proviso for Renewal by Lord Culpeper.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to confirme any Leases or Leases of the
Re&bholigct;ories and Parsonages of Randall and Litlecoates in the County of Lincolne which have long since beene in
the tenure or occupation of John Lord Culpeper as by severall Leases under the Seale of the Master and Fellowes
of the Colledge of the holy and undivided Trinity within the Towne and University of Cambridge of King Henry
the Eights Foundation may appeare and are now leased over the head of the said John Lord Culpeper the auntient
Tennant to one John West though according to usage he claimed to renew his Lease three yeares before the
expiration thereof at the usuall Fines or more, But that the said John Lord Culpeper his Executors or Administrators
reimbursing the said new Tennant or Lessee soe much money as hath beene really paid to the said Colledge for
the Fine for such Lease they shall be admitted to renew the said Lease for the said Fine.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Leases of Kirkham Re&bholigct;ory.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Thomas Clifton, Esquire</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">Provided alwayes That whereas Do&bholigct;or Owen late reputed Deane and the Chapter of the Cathedrall Church of
Christ in Oxon of the Foundation of King Henry the Eight by their Indenture dated the seaventh day of August
in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred fifty seaven did lease and demise unto John Arthur Clerke
Thomas Bromefield of London Es&bhoqesq; and Lawrence Marsh of Darking in the County of Surrey Es&bhoqesq; certaine Tythes
and Land&bholngs; parcell of the Mannour and Parsonage of Kirkham in the County of Lancaster and by severall other
Indentures did lease and demise unto severall other persons many other parts and portions of the [said<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Parsonage of
Kirkham (which had long beene in the tenure or occupation of Thomas Clifton Es&bhoqesq; and his Auncesters by severall
successive Leases under the Abbot and Covent of Vale Royall and the Colledge of Christ Church aforesaid
respe&bholigct;ively) for severall termes of yeares yet unexpired: Be it ena&bholigct;ed and ordained That Thomas Clifton now of
Litham in the County of Lancaster Esquire his Executors and Administrators (paying the severall and respe&bholigct;ive
Rents reserved unto the said Colledge, and secureing unto the said John Arthur [Thomas Bromefeild and Lawrence
Marsh or the Survivours or Survivour of them or the Executor or Executors of the Survivour of them for the
uses in the said Lease expressed and not otherwise<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] out of the Premisses the yearely summe of fower hundred pounds
to be paid halfe yearely by equall portions for the terme of eleaven yeares next ensueing, and reimbursing unto
the said severall other Lessees respe&bholigct;ively or their respe&bholigct;ive Assignes soe much money as was by them respe&bholigct;ively
and truely paid for their respe&bholigct;ive Fines) shall [and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] have and enjoy the said severall demised premisses for the
residue of the said severall termes of yeares yet to come as if the said severall Leases made unto them the said
John Arthur Thomas Bromfield and Lawrence Marsh, and unto the said severall other persons as aforesaid had beene
legally made unto the said Thomas Clifton by a lawfull Deane and Chapter This A&bholigct; or any other thing to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. College Officers relieved in nothing but in want of Ordination.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to confirme the Ele&bholigct;ion of
any Head Fellow [Scholler or<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Chaplaine of any Colledge or Hall in either of the Universities that upon any other
ground besides the want of Episcopall Ordination is or was not capable of being ele&bholigct;ed into such place or place
by the Statutes of the said Colledge or Hall into which he or they were chosen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for Presentees under Letters Patent.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to prejudice the Title of any person
or persons who by Letters Patents under the Great Seale since the first day of May and before the twenty sixth of
August One thousand six hundred and sixty have obtained from his Majestie any Grant of any Deanery Headship
of any House Re&bholigct;orship of any Colledge Canons place Prebendary Fellowship or Schollership within either of the
Universities or the Colledges of Eaton Westminster or Winchester but that all and every the said Grants and
Letters Patents shall be of such and noe other force and effe&bholigct; as the same should have beene if this A&bholigct; had not
beene made Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Exception of certain Leases of Lands, &amp;c. of Hospital of St. Katherine in Ledbury.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to confirme any Lease or Estate
made by John Tombes Clerke of any Land&bholngs; Tenements or Hereditaments belonging to the Hospitall of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Katherins
in Ledbury in the County of Hereford to any of the Children of him the said John Tombs or to any other person
or persons in Trust for him or them or any of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Exception of Leases of the Possessions of the Master of the Rolls.</head>
			<para id="p12">[Provided alwayes and be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein
contained shall in any wise extend to confirme or make good any Lease or Leases made by William Lenthall
pretended Warden of the House of Converts belonging to the Master of the Rolls since the thirtyeth day of January
One thousand six hundred forty and two of any Houses or Tenements thereto belonging to the prejudice of John
Lord Culpeper his Successors Lessees or Assignes the said Lord Culpeper paying or reimbursing unto the said Lessee
or Lessees of such Houses or Tenements such moneyes as they or any of them have paid with Interest for the same
he or they discounting for the meane proffits thereof<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Exception of Wm. Hooke as to the Mastership of the Savoy, and of Leases of the Lands, &amp;c. thereof.</head>
			<para id="p13">[Provided alwayes That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend to confirme William Hooke
in the Mastership of the Kings Majesties Hospitall of the Savoy nor to confirme or make good any Lease of any
Land&bholngs; or Tenements [belonging<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to the said Hospitall made betweene the thirtyeth day of January in the yeare of
our Lord One thousand six hundred forty eight and the first day of June One thousand six hundred and sixty
the Master of the said Hospitall for the time being allowing and reimbursing to all such Lessees all such summe
or summes of money as they or any of them paid to the then Master of the said Hospitall by way of Fine at
the time of such Lease makeing and Interest for the same, and the said Lessees and every of them discounting for
the meane proffitts of the same.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Exception of Leases, &amp;c. of certain Re&bholigct;ories, &amp;c. in the Possession of the late Marquis of Worcester, by the late Dean and Canons of Christ Church.</head>
			<para id="p14">[Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That this A&bholigct; or any thing therin contained shall
not extend to confirme or make good any Lease or Grant made or mentioned to be made to any person or persons
by John Owen late Deane and others Cannons or pretended Deane and Canons of the Colledge of Christ Church
in the University of Oxford or by any of them of any the Re&bholigct;ories Tythes or Gleabe Land&bholngs; of Hampton
Wickenford Badsey Aldington Uffenham South Litleton North Litleton and Midle Litleton in the County of
Worcester heretofore the possessions of Henry late Marquesse of Worcester and Dame Anne his Wife or either of
them, and wherof the said Henry was dispossest for his Alleigiance and Loyalty to his late Majestie of blessed
Memory, but that the Executor or Administrator of the said Henry shall and may be admitted to renew the Leases
of the said Tythes for such terme or termes as the said Deane and Chapter of Christ Church are by Law enabled
to grant the same, the said Executors or Administrators satisfieing and reimbursing to such person or persons all
such summe [or<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] summes of money as he or they have paid for the said Lease or Leases by way of Fine with
Interest for the same the said person or persons discounting to the said Executors or Administrators for the meane
Proffits received therupon<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Exception of Leases, if not good had they been made by lawful Lessors.</head>
			<para id="p15">[Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to confirme or make good any
Lease Leases or Estate made by any pretended Deane and Chapter Master or Head of any Colledge or Hall in
either of the Universities or of any pretended Master or Governours of any Hospitall which said Lease Leases or
Estate had not beene good or effe&bholigct;uall in Law had they beene made by a Lawfull Deane and Chapter Master Head
or Governour of any Colledge Hall or Hospitall aforesaid, This A&bholigct; or any thing herein contained to the contrary
notwithstanding.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Exception of Leases of the Re&bholigct;ories of Arrington and Soham, late of Thomas Chicheley.</head>
			<para id="p16">[Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; or any thing herein contained shall not extend to confirme or make good any
Lease or Leases of the Re&bholigct;ory or Parsonage of Arrington in the County of Cambridge which hath long beene in
the tenure and occupation of Thomas Chichley Es&bhoqesq; and his Auncestors by severall successive Leases from the Master
and Fellowes of Trinity Colledge in Cambridge, nor shall confirme or make good any Lease or Leases of the
Re&bholigct;ory or Parsonage of Soham in the said County of Cambridge which hath likewise beene and still is in the
occupation and possession of the said Thomas Chicheley by Lease from the Master and Fellowes of Pembrooke Hall
in Cambridge but that the said Thomas Chichley (paying and reimbursing the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Tennants or
Lessees the severall and respe&bholigct;ive summes of money by them severally and respe&bholigct;ively paid to the said Colledge
and Hall for or in the name of any Fine or Fines for the makeing or granting such new Lease or Leases with
Interest discounting such Rents [or<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Proffitts as by them respe&bholigct;ively have beene taken or received out of the Premisses)
shall be restored to his said auntient Possessions, and the said Colledge and Hall respe&bholigct;ively shall be enabled to
lease the said severall Re&bholigct;ories and Parsonages with their respe&bholigct;ive Appurtenances unto the said Thomas Chichley
This A&bholigct; or any thing herein contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Exception of Persons eje&bholigct;ed who were ele&bholigct;ed illegally.</head>
			<para id="p17">[Provided alwayes That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend to restore any person or
persons to any Headshipp Fellowship or Scholership of any Colledge or Hall or to any Chaplains or Clerks place
in any Colledge or Hall in either of the Universities or to any Le&bholigct;ure or Readers place that is or shall be before
the first day of January One thousand six hundred and sixty eje&bholigct;ed out of their respe&bholigct;ive Headship Fellowship
Schollership Chaplaine or Clerks place or out of any Le&bholigct;ure in the said Universityes by his Majestyes C&bhooov;missioners
under the Great Seale for not haveing beene legally and according to the severall Statutes of the said respe&bholigct;ive
severall places nominated ele&bholigct;ed or admitted in or to the same, Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary
notwithstanding.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3"> annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5"> annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6"> &amp; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


