<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47273" pubid="351" publish="true">
<title>Charles II, 16605</title>
<subtitle>Chapter XXV. An Act for the better Ordering the Selling of Wines by Retaile, and for preventing Abuses in the Mingling
Corrupting and Vitiating of Wines, and for Setting and Limitting the Prices of the same. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p 3. nu 5.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>Persons unauthorized uttering Wine by Retail.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">For the better Ordering of selling of Wines by retaile in Tavernes and other places (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>for preventing of Abuses
therein Be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the consent of the Lord&bholngs; and
Commons in Parliament assembled, and by the Authoritie of the same That noe person or persons whatsoever
from and after the five and twentyeth day of March one thousand six hundred sixty one unlesse he or they be
authorized and enabled in manner and forme as in this present A&bholigct; is prescribed and appointed shall sell or
utter by retaile that is by the Pint Quart Potle or Gallon, or by any other greater or lesser retaile measure any
kinde of wine or wines to be drunke or spent within his or their Mansion house or houses or other place in
his or their tenure or occupation, or without such Mansion house or houses or such other place in his or then
tenure or occupation by any colour craft or meane whatsoever upon paine to forfeit for every such offence the
summe of five pound&bholngs; the one moyety of every such penalty to be to our Soveraigne Lord the King, the other
moyety to him or them that will sue for the same by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of the
Kings Courts of Record in which A&bholigct;ion or Suite noe Essoigne wager of Law or Prote&bholigct;ion shall be allowed.</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. His Majesty may issue out Commissions under the Great Seal to license the uttering Wine by Retail.</head>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Persons appointed by such Commissions may contra&bholigct; for Licences</emph>.</para>
<para id="p4">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for his Majestie
his Heires and Successors from time to time to issue out under his or their Great Seale of England one or more
Commission or Commissions dire&bholigct;ed to two or more persons thereby authorizing them to license and give
authority to such person and persons as they shall thinke fitt to sell and utter by retaile all and every or any
kinde of wine or wines whatsoever to be drunke and spent as well within the house or houses or other place
in the tenure or occupation of the party soe Licensed as without in any Citty Towne or other place within the
Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne and Port of Berwicke upon Tweede, and such persons as
from time to time or at any time hereafter shall be by such Commission or Commissions as aforesaid in that
behalfe appointed shall have power and authority and hereby have power and authority to treat and contra&bholigct; for
Licence authority and dispensations to be given and granted to any person or persons for the selling and uttering
of Wines by retaile in any Citty Towne or other place as aforesaid according to the rules and dire&bholigct;ions of this
present A&bholigct;, and the true intent and meaning thereof, and not otherwise, Any Law Statute Usage or Custome to
the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. His Majesty's Agents for granting Wine Licences may grant Licences not exceeding 21 years, if the Person so long live.</head>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">Rent Half-yearly reserved, but no Fine to be taken</emph>.</para>
<para id="p6">And be it further, Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That such persons as shall be commissioned and appointed
by his Majestie his Heires or Successors [as aforesaid<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] shall be and be called his Majesties Agents for granting
Licenses for the selling and uttering of Wine by retaile, And his Majesties said Agents are hereby authorized
and enabled under their Seale of Office, the same to be appointed by his Majestie to grant License for the selling
and uttering of Wines by retaile to any person or persons and for any time or terme not exceeding one and
twenty yeares if such person or persons shall soe long live and for such yearely rent as they can or shall agree
and thinke fitt, soe as noe Fine be taken for the same But that the rent and summes of money agreed upon
and reserved be paid and answered halfe yearely by equall portions dureing the whole terme,</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>IV. Licences only to such as personally use the Trade.</head>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">Wine Licences not assignable</emph>.</para>
<para id="p8">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That such License shall not be given or granted but to
such who shall personally use the Trade of selling, or uttering Wines by retaile, or to the Landlord and owner
of the House where the person useing such Trade shall sell and utter Wine by retaile, nor shall the same be
assignable nor in any wise [beneficiall or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] extensive to indempnifie any person against the penaltyes of this present
A&bholigct; except the first taker.</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>V. The King may appoint Officers as he shall think fit.</head>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">Salaries not to exceed Sixpence in the Pound</emph>.</para>
<para id="p10">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for his Majestie
his Heires and Successors to constitute and appoint such and soe many [other<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Officers and Ministers as a Receiver
Register Clerke Comptroller Messenger or the like for the better carrying on of this service as he and they
shall thinke fitt, soe as the Salaries and Wages of all such Officers to be appointed together with the Salary or
Wages of his Majestyes said Agents doe not exceed six pence in the pound of the Revenue that shall hence arise.</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>VI. Revenue to be paid into Exchequer, and not to be charged with Gift or Pension.</head>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">Agents to return into Exchequer, in Michaelmas and Easter Terms, what Licences they have granted, and the Rents reserved</emph>.</para>
<para id="p12">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Rents Revenues and summes of money hence
ariseing, except what shall be allowed for the Wages and Sallaryes of such Officers and Ministers which is not to
exceed six pence out of every pound thereof shall be duely and constantly paid and answered into his Majestyes
Receipt of Exchequer and shall not be perticularly charged or chargable either before it be paid into the Exchequer
or after with any gift or penson, And his Majestyes said Agents are hereby enjoyned and required to returne into
the Court of Exchequer every Michaelmas and Easter Termes upon their Oathes (which Oathes the Barons of [the <ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
Exchequer or any one of them are hereby authorized to administer) a Booke fairely written containing a true and
full account of what Licences have beene granted the preceeding halfe yeare, and what rents and summes of [money <ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
are therupon reserved, and have beene paid, or are in arreare together with the securities of the persons soe in
arreare to the end due and speedy processe may be made out according to the course of the Exchequer for the
recovery of the same</para>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>VII. Proviso for the Privilege of the Two Universities.</head>
<para id="p13">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall not in any wise be prejudiciall to the
priviledge of the two Universityes of [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Land or either of them, nor to the Chauncellours or Schollers of the
same or their Successors but that they may use and enjoy such priviledges as heretofore they have lawfully used
and enjoyed, Any thing herein to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>VIII. Proviso for Society of Vintners of London.</head>
<para id="p14">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be prejudiciall to the Master
Wardens Freemen and Commonalty of the mistery of Vintners of the Citty of London or to any other Citty or
Towne Corporate but that they may use and enjoy such Liberties and Priviledges as heretofore they have lawfully
used and enjoyed, Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s9">
<head>IX. Proviso for the Borough of St. Albans.</head>
<para id="p15">Provided alsoe and be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained
shall not in any wise extend to debarr or hinder the Maior and Burgesses of the Burrough of Saint Albans in
the County of Hertford or their Successors from enjoying useing and exercising of all such Libertyes Powers and
Authorities to them heretofore granted by severall Letters Patents under the Great Seale of England by Queene
Elizabeth and King James of famous memoryes for the ere&bholigct;ing appointing and licensing of three severall Wine
Taverns within the Burrough aforesaid for and toward&bholngs; the maintenance of the Free schoole there, but that the
same Libertyes Powers and Authorities shall be and are hereby established and confirmed and shall remaine [&amp;
continue<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] in and to the said Maior and Burgesses and their Successors to and for the charitable use aforesaid, and
according to the tenor of the Letters Patents aforesaid as though this A&bholigct; had never beene made Any thing herein
contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>X. Fees of Officers for Licences, Acquittances, and Bonds, Penalty &pound;10.</head>
<para id="p16">Provided alsoe That it shall not nor may be lawfull to or for any Officer or Officers to be appointed by His
Majestie for the carrying on of this service to take demand or receive any Fees Reward&bholngs; or summes of money
whatsoever for or in respe&bholigct; of this Service other then Five shillings for a License Fower pence for an Acquittance
and Six pence for a Bond under the penalty of Ten pound&bholngs;, one moyety thereof to the Kings Majestie the other
moyety to the &bhopubr;son or &bhopubr;sons who shall sue for the same by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information wherein
noe wager of Law Essoigne or Prote&bholigct;ion shall be allowed, Any thing herein or any other matter or thing to
the contrary notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s11">
<head>XI. Mixing, &amp;c. Wines and other Things.</head>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">Persons selling Wines not to mingle the same.; Mingling or abusing Wines.; Penalty &pound;100.; Retailers offending, Penalty &pound;40</emph>.</para>
<para id="p18">And it is hereby further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Merchant Vintner Wine Cooper or other
persons selling or retailing any wine shall mingle or utter any Spanish wine mingled with any French wine or
Rinish wine Sider Perry Honey Sugar Sirops of Sugar Molasses or any other Sirops whatsoever, nor putt in any
Isinglasse Brimstone Lime Raisins Juce of Raisins Water nor any other Liquor [nor<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Ingredients, nor any Clary
or other Herbe nor any sort of Flesh whatsoever And that noe Merchant Vintner Wine Cooper or other person
selling or retailing any Wine shall mingle or utter any French wines mingled with any Rhinish wines or Spanish
wines Sider Perry Stummed wine Vitrioll Honey Sugar Sirop of Sugar Molasses or any (<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) Sirops whatsoever nor put in
any Isinglasse Brimstone Lime Raisons Juce of Raisons Water nor any other Liquor or Ingredients nor any Clary or
other Herbe nor any sort of Flesh whatsoever, And that noe Merchant Vintner Wine Cooper or other person
selling or retailing any Wine shall mingle or utter any Rhinish wine mingled with any French wines or Spanish
wines Sider Perry Stummed wine Vitrioll Honey Sugar Sirops of Sugar Molasses [nor<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] any other Sirops whatsoever,
nor put in any Isinglasse Brimstone Lime Raisons Juice of Raisons Water nor any other Liquor or Ingredients nor
any Clary or other Herbe, nor any sort of Flesh whatsoever, And that all and every person and persons committing
any of the offences aforesaid shall incurr the paines and penalties herein after mentioned That is to say Every
Merchant Wine-Cooper or other person selling any sort of Wines in grosse mingled or abused as aforesaid shall
forfeit and lose for every such offence One hundred pound&bholngs;, And that every Vintner or other person selling any
[sort<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] of Wine by retaile mingled or abused as aforesaid shall forfeite and lose [for every such offence<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] the summe of
Forty pound&bholngs;, of which forfeitures one moyety shall goe unto the Kings Majestie His Heires and Successors the
other moyety to the Informer to be recovered in any Court of Record by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or
Information wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or wager of Law shall be allowed.</para>
</section>
<section id="s12">
<head>XII. The Prices of Wine.</head>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p20">Provided alwayes and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That from and after the First day of September One thousand six hundred
sixtie and one noe Canary wines Muskadel or Alegant or other Spanish or sweet Wines shall be sold or uttered
by any person or persons within His Majestyes Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede by retaile for above Eighteene pence the Quart, And that noe Gascogne or French Wines whatsoever
shall be sold by retaile above eight pence the Quart, And that noe Rhenish wines whatsoever shall be sold by
retaile above Twelve pence the Quart (And according to these Rates for a greater and lesser quantity all and every
the said Wines shall and may be sold) upon paine and penalty that every [such<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] person and persons who shall utter
or sell any of the said Wines by retaile that is to say by the Pint Quart Potle, or Gallon or [by<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] any other greater or
lesser retaile measure at any rate exceeding the rates hereby limitted doe and shall forfeit for every such Pint Quart
Potle Gallon or other greater or lesser quantity soe sold by retaile the summe of Five pound&bholngs;, the one moyetie of
which forfeiture shall be to our Soveraigne Lord the King His Heires and Successors and the other moyety to him
or them that will sue for the same to be recovered in manner and forme aforesaid.</para>
</section>
<section id="s13">
<head>XIII. Lord Chancellor, &amp;c. may set the Prices of Wines yearly, or alter the same.</head>
<para id="p21"><emph type="i">Prices to be proclaimed.; Selling at greater Prices; Penalty.; Default of Lord Chancellor, &amp;c. setting Prices</emph>.</para>
<para id="p22">Provided neverthelesse That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Lord Chauncellour of England, Lord
Treasurer, Lord President of the Kings Councell Lord Privy Seale and the two Cheife Justices or Five Fower
or three of them, And they are hereby authorized yearely and every yeare betweene the twentyeth day of November
and the last day of December and noe other times to sett the Prises of all and every the said Wines to be sold by
retaile as aforesaid at higher or lower Rates then are herein contained, soe that they or any of them cause the
Prises by them sett to be written, and open Proclamation thereof to be made in the Kings Court of Chauncery
yearely in the Terme time, or else in the Citty Burrough or Towne Corporate where any such Wines shall be sold;
And that all and every the said Wines shall and may be sold by retaile at such Prises as by them or any Five, Fower
or Three of them shall be sett as aforesaid from time to time for the space of one whole yeare to commence from
the first day of February next after the setting thereof and noe longer, and noe greater Prises under the paines
and penaltyes aforesaid to be recovered as aforesaid, and afterward&bholngs;, and in default of such setting of Prises by
the said Lord Chauncellour of England Lord Treasurer Lord President of the Kings Councell Lord Privy Seale,
and the two Cheife Justices or Five Fower or Three or them as aforesaid at the respe&bholigct;ive Rates and Prises sett
by this A&bholigct;and under the penalties as aforesaid to be recovered as aforesaid.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n4" number="4">this <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n5" number="5">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n6" number="6">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n7" number="7">sorts <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


