<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47275" pubid="351" publish="true">
<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
<subtitle>Chapter XXVII. An Act for granting unto the Kings Majestic Fower hundred and twenty thousand pound&bholngs; by an Assessment of
three score and ten thousand pound&bholngs; by the moneth for six moneths for disbanding the remainder of the Army,
and paying off the Navy. [Rot. Parl. 12 C. II. p. 3. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
<section id="s1"><head>c. 9. ante.; c. 10.</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">ante.; c. 20.; ante.; Reasons for the present Grant.; Grant of &pound;420,000.; to be paid in Six Months at &pound;70,000 per Month.; By the Rules and Commissioners of c. 20.; ante.; Commissioners to meet 12th Jan. 1660, to execute A&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
<para id="p2">WHEREAS It was well hoped that the Moneyes ena&bholigct;ed to be raised by severall A&bholigct;s of this Parliament
that is to say one A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy provision of money for disbanding and paying off
the Forces of this Kingdome both by Land and sea, and one other A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for supplying and
explaining certaine defects in an A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy provision of money for the disbanding
and paying off the Forces of this Kingdome both by Land and Sea, and one other A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for
raising seavenscore thousand pound&bholngs; for the compleate disbanding of the whole Army and paying off some part
of the Navy would have effe&bholigct;ually sufficed to have compleately disbanded the Armies and paid off the Navy, but
by the slow comeing in of the same moneyes the growing charge being still kepte on the same cannot be effe&bholigct;ed
without further supply, and if [noe<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] further supply should be made the growing Charge would become insupportable,
The Commons assembled in Parliament doe therefore give and grant unto your most excellent Majestie for the
uses herein after expressed and noe other the summe of fower hundred and twenty thousand pound&bholngs; to be raised
and leavyed in manner following, and doe humbly pray your most Excellent Majestie that it may be ena&bholigct;ed, And
be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lord&bholngs; and Commons
in this present Parliament assembled that the summe of threescore and ten thousand pound&bholngs; by the moneth for six
moneths begining from the first day of January One thousand six hundred and sixty shall be assessed taxed
colle&bholigct;ed leayed and paid in the severall Countyes Cittyes and Burroughs Townes and Places within England and
Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede according to such rates rules and proportions and by the same
Commissioners as in and by a certaine A&bholigct; past this Parliament entituled A&bholigct; for raiseing of seavenscore thousand
pound&bholngs; for the compleate disbanding of the whole Army and paying off some part of the Navy, which said
Commissioners shall meete on or before the twelfth day of January One thousand six hundred and sixty, and are
hereby enabled to use and execute all and every the like rates rules proportions powers and authorities as in and
by the said A&bholigct; are mentioned and referred unto, or expressed as fully and amply as if the same had beene
perticularly inserted in this present A&bholigct;,</para>
<section id="s2">
<head>II. One Moiety of Assessment to be paid to Receiver General 1st February 1660.; The other Moiety 1st April 1661.</head>
<para id="p3">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed that the summe of Two hundred and tenn thousand pound&bholngs; being one Moyety of
the six moneths Assessment hereby imposed shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid into the Receiver or
Receivers Generall who shall be appointed by the said Commissioners upon or before the first day of February
One thousand six hundred and sixty, and the other Two hundred and ten thousand pound&bholngs; residue thereof upon
or before the first day of April One thousand six hundred sixty one,</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>III. Monies colle&bholigct;ed to be paid at the Guildhall of London to Treasurers hereby appointed.</head>
<para id="p4">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed that all and every the Summes to be colle&bholigct;ed and levyed by vertue of this present
A&bholigct; shall be paid at the Guild hall of the Citty of London unto Sir George Cartwright Sir Richard Browne Lord
Maior of the Citty of London Sir James Bunce Sir William Wheeler Sir William Vincent Thomas Rich Esquire and
the Chamberlaine of the Citty of London for the time being who are hereby appointed Treasurers for the Receipt
thereof, and the Acquittances of them or any three of them shall be a sufficient discharge for soe much as shall
be received by vertue of this A&bholigct; to any person or persons who shall pay in the same,</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>IV. Persons who have advanced Money on Credit of c. 20. ante, continuing the Loan and declaring the same under their Hand, and other Persons advancing Money;; to receive Payment out of the last &pound;110,000 of the said Assessment, with Interest at &pound;10 per Cent. per Ann </head>
<para id="p5">And whereas there is a present necessity of raising of eighty thousand pound&bholngs;, Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie
aforesaid that if any person or persons of the Citty of London or any other place who hath or have advanced
any moneyes upon the credit of an A&bholigct; of this Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; for raiseing seavenscore thousand pound&bholngs;
for the compleate disbanding of the whole Army and paying off some part of the Navy shall continue the Loane of
such Moneyes upon the Credit of this A&bholigct;, and declare the same under his or their hand&bholngs; unto the Treasurers by
this A&bholigct; appointed before the one and thirtyeth day of December one thousand six hundred and sixty, and if any
other person or persons shall advance One hundred pound&bholngs; or upward&bholngs; upon the credit of this A&bholigct; and before the
tenth day of January One thousand six hundred and sixty pay the same unto the said Treasurers then every such
person &amp; persons soe continuing or advancing as aforesaid shall not onely doe a very acceptable Service but shall
alsoe receive from the said Treasurers out of the last one hundred and ten thousand pound&bholngs; which shall be received
upon the second payment appointed by this A&bholigct; his and their principall money with interest at the rate of ten pound&bholngs;
per Cent. per Annum from the time of such declaration and advancement respe&bholigct;ively Any Law A&bholigct; or Statute to
the contrary notwithstanding, and the said Treasurers are hereby required to make payment accordingly, and not to
receive any more money to be advanced as aforesaid then what with the money soe to be continued will amount
to eighty thousand pound&bholngs;.</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>V. Allowance to Treasurers, &amp;c. 1d. in the Pound.</head>
<para id="p6">And Be it further Ena&bholigct;ed that the Treasurers by this A&bholigct; appointed shall receive for them and those to be
imployed under them in this Service one penny in the pound in such manner as they ought to receive by the
A&bholigct; last before mentioned,</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>VI. Monies to be issued by Treasurers according to</head>
<para id="p7">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed that all and every the Summes of money which by vertue of this present A&bholigct; shall
be paid to, or received by the Treasurers aforesaid shall from time to time be issued out according to such
Warrants and directions onely as they or any three of them shall receive from the Commissioners named in one</para>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>Warrant from Commissioners under c. 15. ante.; Monies issued to be employed, first, in disbanding the Army.; The Residue in paying off the Fleet and Navy by the Rules after mentioned</head><para id="p8">A&bholigct; of this present Parliament entituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy disbanding of the Army and garrisons of this
Kingdome, or three of them who are hereby required and enjoyned at their perrills to take care and provide that
the moneyes soe as aforesaid to be issued out be imployed onely to the uses intents and purposes hereafter
following and to noe other use intent or purpose whatsoever that is to say principally and in the first place for
and toward&bholngs; the totall disbanding of the present Army and Garrisons untill that worke be fully perfe&bholigct;ed and
compleated according to such rules and instru&bholigct;ions as touching the disbanding of the Army in the said A&bholigct; last
mentioned are contained. And after the Army shall be wholly disbanded, then the residue of the moneyes to be
raised by vertue of this present A&bholigct; or due or behind on any former A&bholigct; shall be employed for and toward&bholngs; the
paying off of the Fleet and Navy according to such rules orders and instru&bholigct;ions as touching the payment of the
Navy are herein after mentioned and not otherwise.</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>VII. Account of Money by Treasurers to Parliament.</head>
<para id="p9">And Be it further ena&bholigct;ed that an Accompt of all the moneyes by vertue of this A&bholigct; to be received shall be
given by the said Treasurers to this or any other succeeding Parliament which shall require the same, or to such
person or persons as by this or any other succeeding Parliament shall be thereunto appointed,</para>
</section>
<section id="s9">
<head>VIII. Manors, &amp;c. formerly assessed, and now in the Possession of the King and Queen, or of any Ecclesiastical Person, not exempt from Assessment.</head>
<para id="p10">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared that noe Mannors Land&bholngs; Tenements and Hereditaments which were
formerly assessed and taxed for and toward&bholngs; former Assessments and Land Taxes and are now in the possession
or holding of His Majestie or of the Queenes Highnesse, or of any Ecclesiasticall person or persons or his her
or their Farmers and Tennants shall be exempted from the payment of the severall summes of money in this
A&bholigct; comprised, but that the said Mannours Land&bholngs; Tenements and Hereditaments shall be rated assessed and taxed
for and toward&bholngs; the [said<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] severall Summes of money in this A&bholigct; comprised in such manner and forme as they
were of late rated taxed and assessed for and toward&bholngs; the said former Land Rates, Any Law Statute or Custome
to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>IX. Proviso for Peers.</head>
<para id="p11">[Provided alsoe that noe thing herein contained shall be drawne into example to the prejudice of the auntient
Rights belonging to the Peeres of this Realme<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]</para>
</section>
<section id="s11">
<head>X. Commissioners named.</head>
<para id="p12">And Be it declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid that these persons hereafter named shall be added
Commissioners for their severall Countyes Places and Precin&bholigct;s respe&bholigct;ively and shall exercise the same powers as
the other C&bhooov;missioners intended by this A&bholigct; are authorized and impowered to doe that is to say</para>
<para id="p13">Berks</para>
<para id="p14">For the County of Berks Peregrine Hobby Richard Harrison Esq<emph type="p">10</emph> John Fettyplace of Fernham Es&bhoqesq; Samuell
Woodcox.</para>
<para id="p15">Burrough of New Windsor</para>
<para id="p16">For the Burrough of New Windsor Andrew Plumpton Richard Fishborne Gent.</para>
<para id="p17">Bucks</para>
<para id="p18">For the County of Bucks William Tirringham Esquire, Sir Thomas Hampson Baronet, Sir Philip Palmer Baronet
Anthony Ratclisse Esquire.</para>
<para id="p19">Cambridge</para>
<para id="p20">For the County of Cambridge Sir Thomas Dayrell John Bennet Esquire Sir Anthony Cage Levinus Bennet.</para>
<para id="p21">Isle of Ely</para>
<para id="p22">For the Isle of Ely Roger Jennings Esquire.</para>
<para id="p23">Chester</para>
<para id="p24">For the County of Chester Sir George Warburton Baronet Edward Warren Esquire Jeffery Shakerley Esquire,
Henry Leigh Esquire.</para>
<para id="p25">Citty of Chester</para>
<para id="p26">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester, The Maior for the time being.</para>
<para id="p27">Cornwall</para>
<para id="p28">For the County of Cornewall Robert Roberts Esquire Sir William Tredingham Joseph Tredingham Thomas
Penhallow The Knights and Burgesses that serve for the said County, and James Eirsey Gent., The Maior of Lostwithell
for the time being John Mollesworth Esquire William Williams of Trevythen.</para>
<para id="p29">Cumberland</para>
<para id="p30">For the County of Cumberland M<emph type="p">r</emph> Anthony Bouch M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard Uriall M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Croswhat M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Webster.</para>
<para id="p31">Devon</para>
<para id="p32">For the County of Devon Nicholas Davyes Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke William Jennens Gent.>
Edmond Tremaine (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>)
William Putt (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) John Kellond (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) William Bogan (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) George Howard (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) John Kelley (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) James Rodd [Esquiers<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]
Walter Jago Francis Drew Esq<emph type="p">rs</emph> William Walrond Esquire John Blagdon Gent.> John Hamm Gent. Henry Newte.</para>
<para id="p33">Yorke</para>
<para id="p34">For the West riding in the County of Yorke Welbury Norton Esquire Robert Wivell Esquire Richard Roundhill
Gent. William Hamond Esquire Walter Hawkesworth Esquire Cuthbert Wade John Preston Gent. Arthur Ingram
Esquire Edward Atkinson William Witham Gent. Samuell Sunderland Esquire Thomas Ward Gent. Sir William
Ingram Knight Sir John Goodricke Baronet Sir Thomas Wentworth (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) Sir Edward Rodes [Knights<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Godfrey Copley
of Sprotsbrough John Clayton Josua Horton Thomas Stringer Esquiers, The Alderman of Leedes for the time being.</para>
<para id="p35">Yorke North-rideing</para>
<para id="p36">For the North-rideing in the County of Yorke Sir William Caley Arthur Caley Esquire William Wivell Esquire Sir
Thomas Gower Baronet Thomas Worseley (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) Charles Tankred [Esquiers<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Sir William Francklin Baronet, The Bailiffes
of Scarborough for the time being Tristram Fish Robert Belt (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) Thomas Robinson Thomas Scudamore Esquiers.</para>
<para id="p37">Yorke Citty</para>
<para id="p38">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke All the Aldermen of the Citty of Yorke.</para>
<para id="p39">Kingston upon Hull</para>
<para id="p40">For the Towne of Hull M<emph type="p">r</emph> George Crowle.</para>
<para id="p41">Essex</para>
<para id="p42">For the County of Essex M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Glascocke M<emph type="p">r</emph> Miles Hubbart M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Smart Captaine Hunter Dean Tindell
Esquire Isaac Wincoll Thomas [Clapton<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Thomas Peek, Peter Johnson Thomas Manby Esquiers</para>
<para id="p43">Gloucester</para>
<para id="p44">For the County of Gloucester Thomas Freame Thomas Floyd Samuell Shepard Phillip Shepard William Morgan
Richard Daston John Tooke Esquiers Robert Lord Tracy Thomas Morgan Esquire Sir Nicholas Throckemorton
Knight William Bromage Gent. William Winter of Dimmock Gent. Richard Matchen Gent., John Winnyatt Gent.
Thomas Aylway Gent..</para>
<para id="p45">Hereford</para>
<para id="p46">For the County of Hereford Sir Herbert Parret Knight, John Barnaby of Brookehampton Esq[uier] Thomas Baskerville
of Collington Gent. John Booth of Hereford Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
<para id="p47">Citty of Hereford</para>
<para id="p48">For the Citty of Hereford Thomas Davies Esquire Maior James Lawrence Gent. Thomas Clerke Gent..</para>
<para id="p49">Hertford</para>
<para id="p50">For the County of Hertford Marmaduke Rawden James Willimot junior Gent. Thomas Arras Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke
Richard Combes Es&bhoqesq; Sir Robert Joslin Knight Thomas Cappin Edward Briscoe John Halsey Es&bhoqesq; M<emph type="p">r</emph> Fetherstone
of Blackeswere Edward Brograve Ralph Gore Thomas Brograve Edward Cason Thomas Bonnest Henry Becher
Henry Chauncey George Bromley Alexander Meade John Crouch James Willimot junior George Poyner Gent.
John Jesson Es&bhoqesq;</para>
<para id="p51">S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albans</para>
<para id="p52">For the Burrough of Saint Albans William Foxwist Esquire Recorder M<emph type="p">r</emph> John New M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Eams M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas
[Cawley<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Senior M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Marston Sir Henry Conningsby Edmond Smith Alban Cox Richard Combes
Esquire Thomas Marston Gent..</para>
<para id="p53">Kent</para>
<para id="p54">For the County of Kent Sir William Mann Sir Edward Masters Thomas Peake Esquire, Sir Thomas Godfrey
The Maior of Maidston for the time being Sir William Merideth Baronet Sir Thomas Peirce Baronet M<emph type="p">r</emph> Richard
Manley M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Manley.</para>
<para id="p55">Sandwich</para>
<para id="p56">For the Towne of Sandwich John Verrier, Peter Peke Gent.</para>
<para id="p57">Lancaster</para>
<para id="p58">For the County of Lancaster Henry Bannester Esquire Jeffery Rushton Gent. Richard Fleetwood Gent. John
Mollineux Esquire William Fife Esquire Sir George Midleton Knight and Baronet Mathew Richardson Es&bhoqesq; Robert
Heywood Esquire Roger Stoughton of the Citty of London Thomas Butler Richard Farrington William Wall
William Turner Henry Brabin, William Hodgekenson Gent..</para>
<para id="p59">Lincolne</para>
<para id="p60">For the County of Lincolne and Citty and County of the same Edward Turney (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) William Lister [Esquiers<emph type="p">1</emph>] Sir
Robert Dallison Barronet Sir Charles Dallison Knight William Draper Samuell Pro&bholigct;or William Thompson Humphrey
Walcot Thomas Mills Maurice Dalton John Watson William Willoughby Henry Heron Marmaduke Darrell John
Ogle Anthony Treadway William Skipwith Thomas Browne of Eastkirby John Almore M<emph type="p">r</emph> Skinner of Thornton
Colledge Thomas Harrington William Whichcot Charles Pelham junior Roger Pelham M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Lockton M<emph type="p">r</emph> John
Hobson junior M<emph type="p">r</emph>Henry Hall M<emph type="p">r</emph> Charles Bawdes M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Colthurst M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Bishop and M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Blaw
Aldermen M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Perkins M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Mills M<emph type="p">r</emph> Peregrine Bucke M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Dowman M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Dickenson
M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Thornton and Richard Wetherell Aldermen.</para>
<para id="p61">London</para>
<para id="p62">For the Citty of London Nicholas Delves Es&bhoqesq; Benjamin Albin Richard Spencer.</para>
<para id="p63">Midlesex</para>
<para id="p64">For the County of Midlesex Sir John Robinson Barronet Leiutenant of the Tower Sir Richard Browne Thomas
[Bride<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Thomas Harrison of South Mimes Sir William Bateman Leiutenant Collonell Powell Charles Pitfeild Es&bhoqesq;
Robert Peyton John Jones John Limbrey Edward Chard Richard Shelton Es&bhoqesq; William Page Es&bhoqesq; Roger Jennings Es&bhoqesq;
Sir Heneage Finch [Baronet<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] His Majestyes Solliciter Generall Cheney of Hackney Es&bhoqesq; Leiutenant Collonell
Powell Charles Cheney of Chelsey Ch istopher Abdy Es&bhoqesq; Sir Allen Broadricke John Barton Esquire.</para>
<para id="p65">Westminster</para>
<para id="p66">For the Citty of Westminster and Liberties thereof Gabriall Becke Esquire M<emph type="p">r</emph> Graham, Peter Maplesden George
Plunknet Thomas Kirke William Greene George Farewell Ralph Darnell.</para>
<para id="p67">Monmouth</para>
<para id="p68">For the County of Monmouth William Jones of Frowen Esquire James Proger Charles Proger.</para>
<para id="p69">Northampton</para>
<para id="p70">For the County of Northampton Edward Onely (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) John Thornton (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) John Willoughby [Esquiers<emph type="p">1</emph>]</para>
<para id="p71">Norffolke</para>
<para id="p72">For the County of Norffolke George Windham Robert Doughty of Hanworth (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) Robert Legar [Esquiers<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]
Henry Scarborough Gent. M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Roops M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Talbot M<emph type="p">r</emph> Henry Blackborne Gent..</para>
<para id="p73">Burrough of Lyn Regis</para>
<para id="p74">For the Burrough of Lyn Regis John Basset Maior Robert Steward Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Thomas Greene William
Wharton Henry Bell Robert Thoroughgood Alderman Holley.</para>
<para id="p75">Great Yarmouth</para>
<para id="p76">For the Towne of Great Yarmouth Nicholas Cutting James Simond&bholngs; Bailiffes there Sir John Potts Knight and
Baronet Sir William Doyley Knight Sir Thomas Meadow Knight Thomas Gooch George England John Carter
Nathaniell Ashby Thomas Lucas John Woodroffe James Johnson Esquiers George Tilyard Gent..</para>
<para id="p77">Thetford</para>
<para id="p78">For the whole Burrough and Corporation of Thetford The Maior for the time being M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Kendall Gent.
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Bourage Martin Maurice Shelton [Esquiers<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Keddington Gent. M<emph type="p">r</emph> Nicholas Rookwood M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert
Wright of Kilveston.</para>
<para id="p79">Newcastle upon Tine</para>
<para id="p80">For the Towne and County of Newcastle upon Tine Sir Nicholas Cole Knight and Barronet Sir Francis Bows
Knight Sir Francis Anderson Knight Sir John Marley.</para>
<para id="p81">Nottingham</para>
<para id="p82">For the County of Nottingham Francis Sandis Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Bristow (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) William Newton [Gentlemen.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
<para id="p83">East Retford</para>
<para id="p84">For the Burrough of East Retford The Bayliffes for the time being.</para>
<para id="p85">Oxon</para>
<para id="p86">For the County of Oxon William Glyn (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) John West [Esquiers<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] John Coker Gent. James Herbert Es&bhoqesq; Sir
Thomas Tippin.</para>
<para id="p87">University of Oxford</para>
<para id="p88">M<emph type="p">r</emph> Robert Withers M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Master M<emph type="p">r</emph> David Thomas M<emph type="p">r</emph> Gregory Ballard M<emph type="p">r</emph> Timothy Horton.</para>
<para id="p89">The Citty of Oxford</para>
<para id="p90">For the Citty of Oxford Francis Holloway William Cornish.</para>
<para id="p91">Salop</para>
<para id="p92">For the County of Salop Charles Baldwin (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Samuel Baldwin [Esquiers<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> Moore of Midleton M<emph type="p">r</emph> [Bishop<ref idref="n13">13</ref>]
of the Moore Benjamin Buckley.</para>
<para id="p93">Stafford</para>
<para id="p94">For the County of Stafford Thomas Ruddiard Es&bhoqesq; John Colclough (<ref idref="n14">14</ref>) Timothy Edge [Gentlemen.<ref idref="n15">15</ref>]</para>
<para id="p95">Somerset</para>
<para id="p96">For the County of Somerset William Orange Es&bhoqesq; William Bacon Senior Gent. John Cridland Gent. Mawdley
Samborne (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) John Carew (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Roger Newborough (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) James Haise [Esq<emph type="p">rs</emph>.<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]</para>
<para id="p97">(<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) The Citty of Bristoll</para>
<para id="p98">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll The Maior and Sheriffes for the time being John Knight the
Elder William Coulston John Bradway William Coles.</para>
<para id="p99">(<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) The Citty of Bath</para>
<para id="p100">For the Citty of Bath John Vane John Masters Aldermen.</para>
<para id="p101">Southampton</para>
<para id="p102">For the County of Southampton with the Towne and County M<emph type="p">r</emph> Essex Powlet Richard Lucy, (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Gabriell Whistler
[Esquiers.<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]</para>
<para id="p103">Isle of Wight</para>
<para id="p104">For the Isle of Wight Thomas Bowreman Esquier John Oglander of Newport Gent..</para>
<para id="p105">Suffolke</para>
<para id="p106">For the County of Suffolke George Winiffe William Blumfield Es[q]s M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Brooke M<emph type="p">r</emph> Milton of Ipswich
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edmond Bedingfield M<emph type="p">r</emph> Francis Langley M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Read M<emph type="p">r</emph> Rabbit of Bramfield Isaac Matham Esquire
Gardiner Web Gent..</para>
<para id="p107">S<emph type="p">t</emph> Edmond&bholngs;s Bury</para>
<para id="p108">For S<emph type="p">t</emph> Edmonds Bury Francis Smith Robert Sharpe Samuell Hustler.</para>
<para id="p109">Surrey</para>
<para id="p110">For the County of Surrey Edward Evelin (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) John Yates (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Richard Knipe [Esquiers<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] M<emph type="p">r</emph> John Parker Sir Purbeck
Temple (<ref idref="n17">17</ref>) Sir Thomas Bludworth [Knights<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Thomas Rogers (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Charles Good Harmon Atwood Esquiers John
Parker of Rigate.</para>
<para id="p111">Rye in the County of Sussex</para>
<para id="p112">For the Towne of Rye Samuell Bembrig, James Welsh Thomas Ostmonton.</para>
<para id="p113">Worcester</para>
<para id="p114">For the [Towne<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] of Worcester Sir John Packington Baronet Sir Rowland Barkley Knight, Sir John Windford
Knight Samuell Sandis (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) Henry Townesend (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) John Bearcroft [Es[q]s,<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Sir Ralph Clare Knight of the Bath.</para>
<para id="p115">Worcester Citty</para>
<para id="p116">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester Edward Soley Alderman Samuell Smith (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) Thomas Twitty
[Gentlemen<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Henry Townsend Esquire Sir William Mooreton Knight Humphrey Tirer (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) Richard Heming (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) Stephen
Richardson [Gentleman<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Sir John Packington Sir Rowland Berkley Sir Ralph [Clare<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Sir John Wilford, Samuell
Sandis Esquire.</para>
<para id="p117">Warwicke</para>
<para id="p118">For the County of Warwicke Lister of Alveston Esquier Richard Bishop of Stratford Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
<para id="p119">Coventry</para>
<para id="p120">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry, Sir Arthur Caley Knight, The Maior of Coventry for the
time being Henry Smith Alderman Sir Richard Hoppkins Knight William Jesson (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Thomas Norton [Esquiers,<ref idref="n21">21</ref>]
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas Love (<ref idref="n22">22</ref>) Mathew Smith (<ref idref="n22">22</ref>) Samueli Snell (<ref idref="n22">22</ref>) William [Jellififfe<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] (<ref idref="n22">22</ref>) Robert Beake (<ref idref="n22">22</ref>) James Nailer
[Aldermen.<ref idref="n22">22</ref>]</para>
<para id="p121">Towne of Warwicke</para>
<para id="p122">For the Towne of Warwicke Sir Henry Puckerim Baronet Sir Clement Throckmorton Knight John Rouse (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Nathaniell
Stoughton, (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) John Stanton [Esquiers,<ref idref="n21">21</ref>]. Lister of Alveston Es&bhoqesq; Richard Bishop of Stratford.</para>
<para id="p123">Wilts</para>
<para id="p124">For the County of Wilts Walter Buckland (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Thomas Mompesson (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) William Caley [Esquiers<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] Mathew Rayman
Gent. Tho Hunt Gent. Robert Chandler Robert Nicholas of Alcainings William Broomewich Gent. Samuell Eyre
Gent. Simon Spatchurst Esquire Christopher Gardiner Gent. M<emph type="p">r</emph> Francis Parry.</para>
<para id="p125">Sarum</para>
<para id="p126">For the Citty of New Sarum Samuell Eyre Gent. Simon Spatchurst Es&bhoqesq; Christopher Gardiner Gent..</para>
<para id="p127">Anglesey</para>
<para id="p128">For the Isle of Anglesey Robert Lord Viscount Bulkley.</para>
<para id="p129">Brecon.</para>
<para id="p130">For the County of Brecon William Jones John Gwin Henry Stedman Edward Powell.</para>
<para id="p131">Cardigan</para>
<para id="p132">For the County of Cardigan James Phillips (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Morgan Herbert (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Thomas Jenkins (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Erasmus Lloyd (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Thomas
Evans (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Henry Vaughen (<ref idref="n21">21</ref>) Thomas Price the Elder [Esquiers<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] Thomas Lloyd of Yinshen (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) Morris Vaughan (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>)
John Price Gent. Thomas Parry Reighnold Jenkins John Bowen Thomas Lewis He&bholigct;or Phillips Nicholas Lewis William
Jones Abel Griffin Esquiers Wa&bholigct;kin Lloyde (<ref idref="n19">19</ref>) John Griffith of Noyadd [Gentlemen,<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] The Maior of Cardigan for
the time being Rees Gwin David Morgan Aldermen.</para>
<para id="p133">Carmarthen</para>
<para id="p134">For the County of Carmarthen Jonathan Lloyde Walter Lloyde Walter Mansell.</para>
<para id="p135">Carnarvon</para>
<para id="p136">For the County of Carnarvon Griffith Bodurda John Lloyde of Nangwanadale Robert Gwinn of Conway William
Winn of Pengwoone William Thomas of Carnarvon, Jonathan Lloyde Walter Lloyde Walter Mansell.</para>
<para id="p137">Denbigh</para>
<para id="p138">For the County of Denbigh Francis Manly Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
<para id="p139">Flint</para>
<para id="p140">For the County of Flint Kenrick Eaton Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
<para id="p141">Glamorgan</para>
<para id="p142">For the County of Glamorgan John Price of Courtcarne Morgan Morgan Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
<para id="p143">Mountgomery</para>
<para id="p144">For the County of Mountgomery William Oakly Edmond Wareing of Oldbury David Morris Es&bhoqesq;s John Mathews
Henry Pursell John Kiffin William Price of Llanligan John Loyde of Conway.</para>
<para id="p145">Haverford West</para>
<para id="p146">For the Towne and County of Haverford West Sir Herbert Perrot Knight William Browne Alderman.</para>
<para id="p147">Rules Orders and Instru&bholigct;ions for the discharging and paying off the Navy and other debts relating thereunto.</para>
<para id="p148"><emph type="i">Commissioners, after disbanding the remainder of the Army, to pay off 65 Ships</emph>.</para>
<para id="p149">i. The Commissioners hereby appointed for disbanding the Army and discharging the Navy shall proceede [therein<ref idref="n24">24</ref>]
in manner following viz First they are to disband the remaining part of the Army according to the former Rules in
that behalfe made, which done they are then first to discharge and pay off those sixty five Shipps which are now
out of imployment, and of them in the first place those whose Commanders Officers and Seamen have the least
pay due to them and after them [then<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] they are to pay off the Men aboard those thirty six ships now in His Majestyes
Service which entred on his pay the twenty fourth of June last</para>
<para id="p150"><emph type="i">Accounts of the said Ships to be stated, and to receive Arrears of Pay.; Commissioners, upon sight of Accounts stated, to cause Wages to be paid</emph>.</para>
<para id="p151">ij. That all the Commanders Officers and Marriners who served in person and were in Service upon any of the
sixty five of His Majestyes Ships on the twenty fifth of Aprill One thousand six hundred and sixty and have taken
the oathes of Alleigiance and Supremacie or shall take the same when they shall be therunto required and have
not since deserted the Service, nor beene discharged for misdemeanour shall with all convenient speede have their
Accompts stated (by the Auditors hereafter appointed) and therupon receive all their Arreares of their pay from the
fowerteenth of March One thousand six hundred fifty eight to the day of their discharge, And the C&bhooov;manders
Officers and Marriners of the aforesaid thirty six Ships which were in Service on the twenty fifth of Aprill One
thousand six hundred and sixty, and have taken the Oathes of Alleigiance and Supremacy or shall take the same
as aforesaid and have not deserted the Service shall have their Accompts stated as before, and receive their pay
from the said fowerteenth of March One thousand six hundred fifty eight untill the twenty fourth of June One
thousand six hundred and sixty next following, And the Commissioners appointed by this A&bholigct; shall upon sight of
the Accompts soe stated as before cause the said Captaines Officers and Marriners Wages successively to be paid
by the Treasurers appointed by this A&bholigct; out of the money which shall come in of the six monethes Assessment,
or any other money heretofore appointed for the paying or disbanding the Army, and discharging the Navy, [and if
any further Arreares shall be claimed and appeare to be due to any such Commanders Officers or Marriners in
Service as aforesaid for Service at Sea from or after the fowerteenth of March One thousand six hundred fifty
seaven, and to or before the fowerteenth of March one thousand six hundred fifty and eight, that in such case the
Auditors hereby appointed shall examine all such Arreares and draw up a state thereof to be presented to the next
Parliament in order to their satisfa&bholigct;ion.<ref idref="n25">25</ref>]</para>
<para id="p152"><emph type="i">As to short Allowance and Money, Clothes, &amp;c. paid or sold to Captains, &amp;c. of the said 65 Ships on account of their Pay</emph>.</para>
<para id="p153">iij. That noe Money be paid or allowed to any person before mentioned for any short allowance of Vi&bholigct;ualls
made or pretended to be made them either at Sea, or in harbour, and if it shall appeare that any money cloaths
good&bholngs; wares or merchandices have beene paid or sold by any publique Minister Officer or other person to any
Commander Officer or Seaman of the aforesaid Ships upon Accompt of their pay since the fowerteenth of March
one thousand six hundred fifty eight, in such case all the said Moneyes soe paid and the Value of the Cloathes
good&bholngs; wares and merchandices soe sold and delivered within the time of their said Service shall be defaulked
out of their pay aforesaid, and the Summes soe defaulked shall be paid by Warrants of the Commissioners charged
on the Treasurers unto such person &amp; persons to whom the same of right belongeth out of the money that shall
come in of the six moneths Assessment, or any other moneyes heretofore appointed for paying or disbanding of
the Army and Navy in course next after the Commanders Officers and Seamen are paid. </para>
<para id="p154"><emph type="i">As to Auditors stating the Accounts of Officers in the Yards, and Commissioners a&bholigct;ing thereon</emph>.</para>
<para id="p155">iv. That after the Accompts of the Commanders Officers and Seamen are stated then the Auditors shall state the
Accompt of the Ship-keepers, and of all Officers on Shore in the yard&bholngs; and Storehouses at Deptford Woolwich
Chatham Portsmouth Harwich and other places to be stated from the fowerteenth of March One thousand six
hundred fifty eight to the twenty fourth of June last past after the Rates accustomed to be paid by His Majestie and
according to their severall capacities at which time the said Commissioners are to give them Warrants charged upon
the Treasurers to pay them their severall Summes out of the moneye that shall come into their hand&bholngs; of the six
moneths Assessment or any other money heretofore appointed for paying or disbanding of the Army and Navy in
course next after the common Marriners Seamen Commanders Officers and their Servants are discharged and paid,
and the money from them defaulked as before fully satisfied.</para>
<para id="p156"><emph type="i">As to Auditors stating the Accounts of the Vi&bholigct;uallers, and assigning Payment on the Treasurers</emph>.</para>
<para id="p157">v. That the said Auditors shall state the Accompts of the Vi&bholigct;uallers from the said fowerteenth day of March
One thousand six hundred fifty eight to the day of the severall Ships discharge, for as many as are out of
employment as before, and to the twenty fourth day of June for the remaining part of the Navy now in His
Majestyes Service in the Winter guard and assigne them payment in course on the Treasurers before mentioned
to be paid out of the Money remaining in their hand&bholngs; out of the six moneths assessment or any other money
heretofore appointed for the paying or disbanding of the Army and Navy next after the S&bhouov;mes formerly ordered
are paid.</para>
<para id="p158"><emph type="i">As to Auditors stating the Accounts of Persons making Claims for Quarters and Cure of sick and wounded Seamen; and assigning Payment on Treasurers</emph>.</para>
<para id="p159">vj. That the Auditors shall from the said fowerteenth [day<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] of March One thousand six hundred fifty eight state
the Accompts of all Men that shall or may justly claime any Money for quarters and cures of the Sicke and wounded
Seamen sett ashore out of His Majestyes Ships in any Towne or Corporation in this Kingdome, and for the quarters
and Cures of the Sicke and wounded Soldiers sent over from Flaunders, which being soe stated the said Commissioners
shall assigne them their money by Warrant on the Treasurers to be paid in course next after the Commanders Officers
and Marriners aforesaid, and the Officers and Ship-keepers aforesaid are paid and satisfied.</para>
<para id="p160"><emph type="i">As to Auditors stating the Account of Arrears of Pay due to Captains, &amp;c. dead or discharged by Ticket, and Commissioners a&bholigct;ing thereon</emph>.</para>
<para id="p161">vij. That if in case any Commanders Officers or Marriners shall have dyed or beene discharged by ticket out of
any the said Ships and their arreares of pay not satisfied, in such case the Auditors shall state the Accompts of the
persons soe dead or discharged from the said fowerteenth day of March One thousand six hundred fifty eight to
the day of their death or discharge according to their severall capacities, and the Commissioners shall therupon
give Warrants upon the Treasurers by this A&bholigct; appointed for the payment of the S&bhouov;mes to them or their Assignes
in course when the Commanders and Officers of the severall Ships to which they did belong at the time of their
death or discharge, and the debts for cure of the sicke and wounded are satisfied.</para>
<para id="p162"><emph type="i">As to Auditors stating the Accounts of all other Persons making Claims for Maintenance of Prisoners, Stores, &amp;c. sold for the Use of the Navy, and assigning Payment on Treasurer</emph>.</para>
<para id="p163">viij. That the said Auditors shall alsoe state the severall Accompts of all other persons which can or may justly
claime any debt to be due unto him or them for any provision maintenance of prisoners good&bholngs; wares merchandices
stores ammunition and other necessaries sold and delivered to any publique Minister to and for the use of the
Navy aforesaid from the fowerteenth of March One thousand six hundred fifty eight to the twenty fourth of June
One thousand six hundred and sixty and order them payment in course after the before mentioned Summes are
paid by assignation on the Treasurers to be paid out of the money remaining in their hand&bholngs; out of the six
moneths Assessment or any other moneyes heretofore appointed for paying or disbanding of the Army and Navy.x</para>
<para id="p164"><emph type="i">As to the Appointment of Auditors.; Oath to be taken by Auditor before a&bholigct;ing.; Commissioners to administer Oath, and issue out Warrants for Payment of Accounts certified by Auditors</emph>.</para>
<para id="p165">ix. That for the better stating the Accompts of the Commanders Officers and Marriners of the said Navy and
the severall other Accompts before recited and hereafter mentioned Arthur Sprey William Jessop Ralph Darnall
Samuel Atkins Richard Kingdon and Bartholimew Fillingham Esquiers and John Walker Gentleman shall be and are
hereby appointed constituted and authorized to audite and cast up the Accompts of the aforesaid Commanders
Officers Marriners and all other Mens Accompts relateing to the debt of the said Navy as before, and shall
respectively before they enter theron, take an Oath in these word&bholngs; following. I doe sweare that to the best of my
skill and judgement I shall examine and truely state all such Accompts as shall be committed to my care and
trust by the Commissioners for disbanding the Army and discharging the Navy or any three or more of them, and
shall and will to the best of my knowledge make true Certificates of all such Accompts to the said Commissioners
or any three of them Soe helpe me God, Which said Oath the said Commissioners or any three of them as aforesaid
are hereby authorized to administer accordingly Which Accompts soe certified by the said Auditors or any two of
them, then the said Commissioners or any three of them shall have power and authoritie, and are hereby authorized
and impowered to issue out Warrants from time to time to the respe&bholigct;ive Treasurers aforesaid for the payment of
the severall Summes soe audited and due as aforesaid which Warrants together with the Acquittance of the
persons to whom the same is payable thereupon shall be to the said Treasurers respe&bholigct;ively a sufficient Warrant
and discharge.</para>
<para id="p166"><emph type="i">As to Chief Officers of the Navy delivering to Commissioners a List of the said Ships and their Officers and Crew, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p167">x. That the cheife Officers of His Majestyes Navy doe with all convenient speede deliver unto the Commissioners
appointed by this A&bholigct; a perfe&bholigct; List of the Names of all the aforesaid Ships that are to be discharged and the
places in which they lie, and the names and sirnames of the Commanders Officers Marriners and Common Seamen
to each Ship belonging and a perticular Accompt of the time that every person hath served, and what money or
goods every or any one of them hath received.</para>
<para id="p168"><emph type="i">As to Pursers, &amp;c. of the Navy attending and delivering Accounts, Books, &amp;c. to the Auditors</emph>.</para>
<para id="p169">xi. That the Pursers and Checks of the severall Ships of the Navy doe from time to time when they shall be
required thereunto attend the Auditors aforesaid, and deliver unto them a true and perfe&bholigct; Accompt of all the
Commanders Officers Marriners and Seamen belonging to the said Ships, and shall produce the originall Muster
booke and Pay bookes wherein the Names of the said Commanders Officers and Seamen were entered and give an
exa&bholigct; accompt of what arreares is due unto them, and how and in what manner the same becomes due, the which
bookes and Accompts shall by the said Pursers and Checks be delivered upon oath, which said Oath the
Commissioners aforesaid or any three of them are hereby ordered to administer accordingly.</para>
<para id="p170"><emph type="i">As to Pursers making false Musters, &amp;c. Penalty, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
<para id="p171">xij. That in case any Purser shall be found to make any false Muster, or shall muster any Captaine Officer or
Marriner by a false name or make any false ticket such Purser shall forfeit his or their respe&bholigct;ive wages, and be
imprisoned the space of six moneths, and in such case the Commissioners appointed by this A&bholigct; or any two of
them are hereby impowered to committ them to prison accordingly.</para>
<para id="p172"><emph type="i">As to Captains, &amp;c. upon their Discharge delivering up their respective Ships, &amp;c. to Persons appointed by the King or the Admiralty.; Captains, &amp;c. offending.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
<para id="p173">xiij. That upon discharge of any of the Commanders Officers and Marriners of the Navy aforesaid, all the said
Commanders Officers and Marriners shall deliver up all their respe&bholigct;ive Ships Guns Masts Sailes Yard&bholngs; Anchors
Cables Tackle Apparell Provisions Ammunition and Stores which are in their possessions for His Majesties use [<ref idref="n27">27</ref>]
such person or persons as His Majestie or the Lord High Admirall of England shall appoint to receive the same,
and if any Commanders Officers or Seamen shall refuse to be discharged, or to deliver up the Stores aforesaid,
or shall be found upon due proofe to have imbezelled any part thereof, or doe disswade others from being
discharged, he or they soe offending shall forfeite [all<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] his and their Arreares, and be further proceeded against
according to their demirrit.</para>
<para id="p174"><emph type="i">As to Commissioners appointing Clerks, &amp;c. and giving Salaries</emph>.</para>
<para id="p175">xiv. That the said Commissioners or any three of them as aforesaid shall have power to nominate appoint and
imploy such Clerks Agents Messengers and Servants as shall bee necessary for the said Worke, and to make and
give to them such reasonable Sallaries Allowances and Satisfa&bholigct;ions as they shall thinke fitt, and alsoe to provide
all other necessaries, and to defray all other charges relating to the same</para>
<para id="p176"><emph type="i">As to Allowance to Commissioners of 1d. in the Pound; and to Auditors of 20s. per Diem</emph>.</para>
<para id="p177">xv. That the Commissioners formerly nominated by the House of Commons and by this A&bholigct; continued and
appointed for this service shall have and receive for their Charge and paines in and about this Service one penny
in the pound and noe more out of all such moneyes as shall be issued by vertue of this A&bholigct;, and each of the
Auditors aforesaid shall receive for his paines and charges in and about this service the summe of twenty shillings
per diem dureing the continuance of this service, which the Treasurers of the aforesaid moneyes are hereby enabled
and required to issue and pay accordingly.</para>
<para id="p178"><emph type="i">Commissioners to direct Treasurers to grant Assignations of such Sums of Money, &amp;c. as Commissioners shall direct</emph>.</para>
<para id="p179">xvi. That the Commissioners shall dire&bholigct; the said Treasurers from time to time to grant assignations (who are
hereby required to observe the same) for such and soe many summes of money on the respe&bholigct;ive Receivers
or Treasurers for raiseing Money by the A&bholigct; aforesaid in the severall Countyes Cittyes or Places where they
understand any of the said money lyes, as the Commissioners for disbanding the Army and Navy, or any three
or more of them as aforesaid shall dire&bholigct; and appoint to such persons and in such manner as the said Commissioners
or any three or more of them as aforesaid shall direct and appoint.</para>
<para id="p180"><emph type="i">Commissioners to call the Treasurers to account, and certify Accounts into the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
<para id="p181">xvij. That the Commissioners herein named or any three of them shall and are hereby authorized to call to
accompt the present Treasurers in this A&bholigct; named, and James Nelthrope and John Lawson Esquiers late Treasurers
at Warrs or any other former Treasurers or Commissioners of the Army or Navy for all such summes of Money
as they or any of them stand accomptable for, and to certifie the same Accompts into his Majestyes Exchequer.</para>
<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
<note id="n4" number="4">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n5" number="5">Knight <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n6" number="6">Clopton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n7" number="7">Cowley <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n8" number="8">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n9" number="9">Bide <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n11" number="11">Gent. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n12" number="12">&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n13" number="13">Bushop <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n14" number="14">Gent.<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n15" number="15">Gent. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n16" number="16">For <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n17" number="17">Knight <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n18" number="18">County <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n19" number="19">Gent. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n20" number="20">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n21" number="21">Es&bhoqesq; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n22" number="22">Alderman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n23" number="23">Jelliffe <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
<note id="n24" number="24">interlined on the Roll.</note>
<note id="n25" number="25">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
<note id="n26" number="26"><emph type="i">O</emph>. omits</note>
<note id="n27" number="27">The Roll is illegible here, but the word "unto" is in the Original Act.</note>
<note id="n28" number="28">interlined on the Roll.</note>
</section>
</section>
</report>


