<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47283" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1660</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXV. An Act for Ere&bholigct;ing and Establishing a Post Office. [Rot. parl. 12 c. 11. p. 4 nu. 8. p. 4. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">A Letter Office ere&bholigct;ed in London.; A Master of the Office to be appointed by the King by the Name of Post Master General.; Power and Duty of Post Master General.; Exception as to Letters sent by Coaches, &amp;c.; by Ships,; by private ; Friends, and as to Messengers carrying Commissions, &amp;c.;</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS for the maintenance of mutuall Correspondencies and prevention of many Inconveniencies happening by
private Posts severall publique Post Offices have beene heretofore ere&bholigct;ed for carrying and recarrying of Letters
by Posts to and from all parts and places within England Scotland and Ireland and severall parts beyond the Seas
the well ordering whereof is a matter of generall concernment, and of great advantage as well for preservation of
Trade and Commerce as otherwise, To the end therefore that the same may be managed soe that speedy and safe
dispatches may be had which is most likely to be effe&bholigct;ed by ere&bholigct;ing one Generall Post Office for that purpose,
Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie &amp; the Lord&bholngs; and C&bhooov;mons in this present Parliament
assembled, and by the Authority of the same that there be from henceforth one Generall Letter Office ere&bholigct;ed and
established in some convenient place within the Citty of London from whence all Letters and Pacquets whatsoever
may be with speede and expedition sent unto any part of the Kingdomes of England Scotland and Ireland, or any
other of His Majestyes Dominions or unto any Kingdome or Country beyond the Seas, at which said Office all Returnes and Answers may be likewise received, and that one Master of the said Generall Letter Office shall be from
time to time appointed by the Kings Majestie His Heires and Successors to be made or constituted by Letters
Patents under the Great Seale of England by the name and Stile of His Majestyes Post Master Generall, which said
Master of the said Office and his Deputy and Deputyes by him thereunto sufficiently anthorized, and his and
their Servants and Agents, and noe other person or persons whatsoever shall from time to time have the receiving
takeing up ordering dispatching sending post or with speede and delivering of all Letters and Pacquets whatsoever
which shall from time to time be sent to and from all and every the parts and places of England Scotland and
Ireland and other his Majestyes Dominions, and to and from all and every the Kingdomes and Countryes beyond
the Seas, where he shall setle or cause to be setled Posts or runing Messengers for that purpose. Except such
Letters as shall be sent by Coaches common knowne Carriours of Good&bholngs; by Carts Waggons or Packehorses and
shall be carryed along with their Carts Waggons and Packehorses respe&bholigct;ively, and except Letters of Merchant&bholngs;
and Masters which shall be sent by any Masters of any Shipps Barques or other Vessell of merchandize or by any
other person imployed by them for the cariage of such Letters aforesaid according to the respe&bholigct;ive dire&bholigct;ions, and
alsoe except Letters to be sent by any private friend or friend&bholngs; in their wayes of journey or travill, or by any
messenger or messengers sent on purpose for or concerning the private affaires of any person or persons, and alsoe
except Messengers who carry and recarry Commissions or the Returne thereof Affidavits Writts Processe or
Proceedings or the Returnes thereof issueing out of any Court.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The Post Master General, and no other, to provide Horses for riding Post.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That such Post Master Generall for the time being as
shall from time to time be made and constituted by His Majesty His Heires and Successors and the respe&bholigct;ive
Deputyes or Substitutes of such Post Master Generall and noe other person or persons whatsoever shall prepare &amp;
provide Horses and Furniture to lett to Hire unto all Through posts and persons rideing in post by Commission or
without to and from all and every the [parts &amp;;<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] places of England Scotland and Ireland where any Post rodes are,
or shall be setled and established.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Rates for carrying Letters</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull to and for such Post Master
Generall to be constituted and appointed as aforesaid and his Deputy or Deputies by him thereunto sufficiently
authorized to demand have receive and take for the portage and conveyance of all such Letters which he shall soe
convey carry or send post as aforesaid, and for the providing and furnishing Horses for Through posts or persons
rideing in post as aforesaid according to the severall Rates and Summes of lawfull English money hereafter mentioned
and not to exceed the same (that is to say)</para>
			<para id="p6">For the port of every Letter not exceeding one sheate to or from any place not exceeding fowerscore English
miles distant from the place where such Letter shall be received Two pence,</para>
			<para id="p7">And for the like port of every Letter not exceeding two sheets Fower pence,</para>
			<para id="p8">And for the like port of every Pacquet of Letters proportionably unto the said Rates,</para>
			<para id="p9">And for the like port of every Packquet of Writts Deed&bholngs; and other things after the Rate of Eight pence for
every [one<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] ounce [weight<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p10">And for the port of every Letter not exceeding one sheete above the distance of fowerscore English miles from
the place where the same small be received Three pence,</para>
			<para id="p11">And for the like port of a Letter not exceeding two sheets Six pence, and proportionably to the same Rates
for the like port of all pacquets of Letters,</para>
			<para id="p12">And for the like port of every other pacquet of Writts Deed&bholngs; or other things after the rate of Twelve pence
of English money for every ounce weight,</para>
			<para id="p13">And for the port of every Letter not exceeding one sheete from London unto the Towne of Berwicke or from
thence to the Citty of London Three pence of English money,</para>
			<para id="p14">And for the like port of every Letter not exceeding two sheets Six pence and proportionably unto the same rates
for every pacquet of Letters</para>
			<para id="p15">And for every other other pacquet of greater Bulke One shilling and six pence for every Ounce weight,</para>
			<para id="p16">And for the port of such Letters &amp; Pacquets as shall be conveyed or carryed from the Towne of Berwicke
unto any place or places within forty English miles distance from Berwicke or any other place where such Letter
shall be received Two pence</para>
			<para id="p17">And for every Letter not exceeding two sheets fower pence and proportionably to the same rates for every pacquet
of Letters</para>
			<para id="p18">And for every other pacquet or parcell Eight pence for every Ounce weight,</para>
			<para id="p19">And for every Letter not exceeding One sheete to be conveyed or carryed a further distance then forty English
miles fower pence,</para>
			<para id="p20">And for the like port of every double Letter Eight pence, and proportionably unto the same Rates for the like
port of every pacquet of Letters</para>
			<para id="p21">And for the like port of every other pacquet One shilling for every Ounce weight,</para>
			<para id="p22">And for the port of every letter not exceeding one sheet from England unto the Citty of Dublin in Ireland, or
from the Citty of Dublin in Ireland unto England Six pence of English money,</para>
			<para id="p23">And for the like port of every letter not exceeding two sheets One shilling and proportionably to the same rates
for every pacquet of letters,</para>
			<para id="p24">And for the port of every other pacquet of any kinde of greater Bulke two shillings for every Ounce weight,</para>
			<para id="p25">And for the port of such letters or pacquets as shall be conveyed or carryed from the Citty of Dublin unto any
other place or places within the Kingdome of Ireland, or from any other place unto the said Citty, or to or from
any other place within the said Kingdome according to the rates and summes of English money hereafter following viz<emph type="p">t</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p26">For every letter not exceeding one sheete to or from any place within Forty English miles distance from Dublin
or any other place where such letter shall be received Two pence,</para>
			<para id="p27">And for every letter not exceeding two sheets Foure pence, and proportionably to the same rates for every
pacquet of letters,</para>
			<para id="p28">And for every other pacquet of greater bulke Eight pence for every Ounce weight,</para>
			<para id="p29">And for every letter not exceeding one sheete to be carryed or conveyed a further distance then forty English
miles Foure pence,</para>
			<para id="p30">And for the like port of every letter not exceeding two sheets Eight pence and proportionably unto the same
rates for the like port of every [pacquet<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] of Letters,</para>
			<para id="p31">And for the like port of every other packquets of greater bulke One shilling for every Ounce weight,</para>
			<para id="p32">And for all and every the letters pacquets and parcells of outward&bholngs; that shall be carried or conveyed to, or from
any of His Majestyes said Dominions to or from any other parts or places beyond the Seas according to the severall
and respe&bholigct;ive rates that now are and have beene taken for letters pacquets and parcells soe conveyed being rated
either by the Letter or by the Ounce weight That is to say</para>
			<table id="t1">
				<tr>
					<td cols="4"/>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">Morlaix Saint Maloes Caen Newhaven and places of like distance, portpaid to Roaen is for</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>o</td>
					<td>vj</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td cols="2">[j o<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Treble</td>
					<td cols="2">[j vj<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td cols="2">[j vj<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">Hamburgh Collen Frankfort port paid to Antwerp is</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>o</td>
					<td>viij</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td cols="2">[j iv<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Treble</td>
					<td cols="2">[ij o<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td cols="2">[ij o<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">Venice Geneva Legorne Rome Naples Messina and all other parts of Italy by way of Venice fran&bholigct; pro Mantua</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>o</td>
					<td>ix</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>vj</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Treble</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>iij</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>viij</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">Marcelia Smerna Constantinople Aleppo and all parts of Turky port paid to Marcelia</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>i</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Three quarters of an ounce</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>ix</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td>iij</td>
					<td>ix</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">Genova Legorne Rome and other parts of Italy by way of Lionsfran&bholigct; pro Lyons</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Three quar&bhotcrl;s of an ounce</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>ix</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td>iij</td>
					<td>ix</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td cols="4">And of Letters sent outward&bholngs;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">To Bourdeaux Rochel Nantz Orleans Byon Towers and places of like distance port paid to Paris</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>o</td>
					<td>ix</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>[iv<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Treble</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>iij</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">And for Letters brought from the same places into England</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>3 quarters of an ounce</td>
					<td>iij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td>iiij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td cols="4">Alsoe Letters sent outward&bholngs;</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">To Noremberg Bremen Dantzick Lubeck Lipswick and other place of like distance post paid to Hamburgh</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>3 quarters of an ounce</td>
					<td>iij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td>iv</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">And for Letters brough from the said places to England</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>o</td>
					<td>viij</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>iv</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Treble</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>ounce</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td cols="4">And for the Port Letters brought into England from</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">Calais Diep Bulloigne Abbeville Amiens Saint Omers Montrell</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>o</td>
					<td>iv</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>o</td>
					<td>viij</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Treble</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">Rouen</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>o</td>
					<td>vj</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Treble</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>vj</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>[iij <ref idref="n9">9</ref>]</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">Paris</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>o</td>
					<td>ix</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>vj</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Treble</td>
					<td>[j<ref idref="n10">10</ref>]</td>
					<td>iij</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">Dunkirke Ostend Lisle Ypre Courtrey Gaunt Bruxels Bridges Antwerpe and all other parts of Flaunders</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>o</td>
					<td>viij</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>iv</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Treble</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td/>
					<td/>
					<td>s.</td>
					<td>d.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td rows="4">Sluce Flushing Midleburgh Amsterdam Roterdam Delfe Hague and from all other parts of Holland and Zealand</td>
					<td>Single</td>
					<td>o</td>
					<td>viij</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Double</td>
					<td>j</td>
					<td>iv</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Treble</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ounce</td>
					<td>ij</td>
					<td>o</td>
				</tr>
				
			</table>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Merchants Accounts, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">and for Covers of Letters to Marseilles, &amp;c. to be sent to Turkey</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p34">Provided alwayes That all Merchants Accompts not exceeding one sheete of paper and all Bills of Exchange
Invoices and Bills of Ladeing are and shall hereby be understood to be allowed without Rate in the price of the
Letters, and likewise the Covers of Letters not exceeding one fourth part of a sheete of paper sent to Marseiles
Venice or Legorne to be sent forward to Turky shall be understood to be allowed to passe without rate or payment
for the same and according to the same rates and proportions for the port of Letters pacquets and parcells to or
from any of the parts or places beyond the Seas where Posts have not beene heretofore setled and may hereafter
be setled by the said Post Master Generall for the time being his Executors or Assignes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Rate of Hire for Post Horses.</head>
			<para id="p35">And it shall and may be lawfull to and for such Post Master Generall and his Deputy and Deputyes to aske
demand take and receive of every person that he or they shall furnish and provide with Horses Furniture and
Guide to ride post in any of the Post road&bholngs; as aforesaid Three pence of English money for each Horses hire or
postage for every English mile and Foure pence for the Guide for every Stage.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Recital that Ship Letters have been detained or delivered to improper Persons.</head>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">Ships Letters to be put into Post Office.; Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">And whereas upon the arrivall of Shipps from parts beyond the Seas into severall Ports within His Majesties
Dominions many Letters dire&bholigct;ed to severall Merchants and others have beene detained long to the great damage
of the Merchants in want of that speedy advice and intelligence which they might have had if the same had
beene forthwith dispatched by the setled Posts, and sometimes such Letters have beene delivered by the Masters
or Passengers of such Shipps to ignorant and loose hand&bholngs; that understand not the way and meanes of speedy
conveyance and delivery of Letters whereby great prejudice hath accrued to the affaires of Merchants and others
as well by the miscarriage of many Letters soe brought as oftentimes by the opening of the same to the discovery
of the Correspondencies and secrets of the Merchant. Be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all
Letters and Pacquets that by any Master of any Shipp or Vessell or any of his Company or any Passengers
therein shall or may be brought to any Port Towne within His Majestyes Dominions or any of the Members
thereof other then such Letters as are before excepted, &amp; may be sent by common knowne Carriours in manner
aforesaid or by a friend as aforesaid shall by such Master Passenger or other person bee forthwith delivered unto
the Deputy or Deputyes onely of the said Post Master Generall for the time being by him appointed for the said
Port towne and by him or them to be sent post unto the said Generall Post Office to be delivered according to
the severall and respe&bholigct;ive dire&bholigct;ions of the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Post Masters only to carry Letters.; Exception.; Carrying Letters, letting Post Horses, &amp;c. to hire contrary to this A&bholigct;, Penalty.; Penalties how divided.</head>
			<para id="p38">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the aforesaid Authoritie That noe person or persons whatsoever or Body Politique
or Corporate other then such Post Master Generall as shall from time to time be [nominated &amp;<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] appointed by His
Majestie his Heires or Successors and constituted by Letters. Patents under the Great Seale of England as aforesaid
and his Deputy and Deputyes or Assignes shall presume to carry recarry and deliver Letters for Hire other then
as before excepted or to sett up or imploy any Foote-post Horse-post Coach-post or Pacquet Boate whatsoever
for the conveying carrying and recarrying of any Letters or Pacquets by Sea or Land within His Majestyes
Dominions or shall provide and maintaine Horses and Furniture for the horsing of any Through posts or persons
rideing in post with a Guide and Horne as usuall for Hire upon paine of Forfeiting the summe of Five Pound&bholngs; of
English money for every severall offence against the Tenor of this present A&bholigct;, And alsoe of the forfeiture of the
summe of One hundred Pound&bholngs; of like English money for every weekes time that any Offender against this A&bholigct;
shall imploy maintaine and continue any such Foote post Horse post Coach post or Pacquet boate as aforesaid,
which said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Forfeitures shall and may be sued for and recovered by A&bholigct;ion or A&bholigct;ions of
Debt Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties Courts of Record wherein noe Essoigne priviledge prote&bholigct;ion
or wager of Law shall be admited, and the said severall and respe&bholigct;ive forfeitures that shall happen from time to
time to be recovered shall be and remaine the one moyety thereof to His Majesty and His Heires and Successors
and the other moyety thereof to such person or persons who shall or will informe against the Offender or Offenders
against this present A&bholigct;, and shall or will sue for the said forfeitures upon the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso where Post Master doth not provide Horses.</head>
			<para id="p39">Provided alwayes that if any Post Master of any respe&bholigct;ive place doth not or cannot furnish any person or
persons rideing in post with sufficient Horses within the space of one halfe houre after demand, that then such
person or persons are hereby understood to be left at liberty to provide themselves as conveniently they can,
And the persons who shall furnish such Horses shall not therefore be lyable to any penaltyes or forfeitures
contained in this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Post Master General not providing Horses, &amp;c. Penalty &pound;5.</head>
			<para id="p40">Provided alwayes That if through default or negcle&bholigct; of the Post Master Generall aforesaid any person or
persons rideing in post shall faile as aforesaid of being furnished with a sufficient Horse or Horses for his or their
use after demand as aforesaid That in every such case the said Post Master Generall shall forfeite the summe of
Five Pound&bholngs; sterling, the one moyety to His Majesty His Heires and Successors, and the other moyety to him or
them who shall sue for the same in any Court of Record to be recovered by Bill Plaint or other Information
wherein noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion or other wager in Law shall be admitted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Proviso for carrying Letters, &amp;c. to the next Post Stage.</head>
			<para id="p41">Provided alwayes and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That noe thing herein contained shall be understood to prohibite the
carrying or recarrying of any Letters or Pacquets to or from any Towne or Place to or from the next respe&bholigct;ive
Post road or Stage appointed for that purpose But that every person shall have free liberty to send and imploy
such persons as they shall thinke fitt for to carry the said Letters or Pacquets as aforesaid without any forfeiture
or penalty therefore Any thing contained in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Carrying Mail out of England in Foreign Vessels. Penalty &pound;100.</head>
			<para id="p42">Provided alwayes That if the Pacquet or Mail shall be carryed out of England into any part beyond the Seas
in any Ship or Vessell which is not of English built and navigated with English Seamen That in every such case
the said Post Master Generall shall forfeite the summe of One hundred Pound&bholngs; sterling, the one moyety to his
Majestie his Heires and Successors and the other moyety to him or them who shall sue for the same in any Court
of Record to be recovered by Bill Plaint or other Information wherein noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion or other wager in
Law shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Officers in the Post Office to take the Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy.</head>
			<para id="p43">Provided alsoe and be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that noe person or persons shall be capeable of
haveing useing or exercising the Office of Post Master Generall or any other imployment relating to the said Office
unlesse he or they shall first take the Oathes of Alleigiance and Supremacy before any two Justices of the Peace,
of the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes wherein such person or persons are or shall be resident, which said Justices are hereby
authorized to administer the said Oathes accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Proviso as to Marhasion, Kendall, Penrith, Lincoln, and Grimsby.</head>
			<para id="p44">Provided alsoe and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That a Letter or Pacquet post shall twice every
weeke come by the way of Trurow and Penrin to the Towne of Marketiew alias Marhasion in the County of
Cornwall and once a weeke to Kendall by the way of Lancaster and to the Towne of Penrith in Cumberland
by the way of Newcastle and Carlisle &amp; to the Citty of Lincolne and the Burrough of Grimsby in the County
of Lincolne Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Post Master to continue constant Posts.</head>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p46">Provided alsoe and be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That such Post Master Generall to be from time
to time appointed by His Majestie His Heires and Successors as aforesaid shall continue constant Posts for carriage
of Letters to all places though they lye out of the Post road&bholngs; as hath beene used for [the space of<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] three yeares
last past at the rates herein before mentioned under paine of forfeiture for every omission Five Pound&bholngs; to be
recovered by A&bholigct;ion Suite or Plaint in any His Majesties Courts of Record, the one moyety to the use of His
Majestie the other moyety to the use of the Informer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. The Post Master General, &amp;c. to observe such Orders as His Majesty shall make.</head>
			<para id="p47">
				<emph type="i">His Majesty may grant the said Office for Life or Years, not exceeding 21 Years</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p48">And for the better management of the said Post Office, and that the people of these Kingdomes may have
their intercourse of Commerce and Trade the better maintained and their Letters and Advices conveyed carryed
and recarryed with the greatest speede security and convenience that may be Be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That the said
Post Master Generall soe nominated appointed and constituted as aforesaid and his Deputyes shall from time to
time observe and follow such orders rules dire&bholigct;ions and instru&bholigct;ions for and concerning the setlement of convenient
Posts and Stages upon the severall road&bholngs; in England Scotland and Ireland and other His Majestyes Dominions,
and the providing and keepeing of a sufficient number of Horses at the said severall Stages as well for the carrying
and conveying of the said Letters and Pacquets as for the horsing of all thorow Posts and persons rideing in post
by warrant or otherwise as aforesaid as His Majestye His Heires and Successors shall from time to time in that
behalfe make and ordaine, And that His Majestie His Heires and Successors may grant the said Office of Post
Master Generall together with the powers and authorities thereunto belonging and the severall rates of portage above
mentioned and all proffits priviledges fees perquisites and emolluments thereunto belonging or to belong either for
life or terme of yeares not exceeding one and twenty yeares to such person or persons and under such Covenants
Conditions and yearely Rents to his said Majestie His Heires and Successors reserved as His said Majestie His Heires
and Successors shall from time to time thinke fitt for the best advantage and benefit of the Kingdome,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. No Horses to be taken without Consent of the Owners.</head>
			<para id="p49">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe person shall have power to take
use or seize any Horses for the service mentioned in this A&bholigct; without the consent of the owners thereof, Any
usage or pretence or any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Rates of Inland Letters to be paid where delivered. Exception.</head>
			<para id="p50">Provided alwayes and be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Inland Letters sent by any pacquet
Post established by this A&bholigct; as aforesaid doe and shall pay the rates and prices before mentioned at such Stage
where they are last delivered onely unlesse the party that delivers the Letters desireth to pay elsewhere, Any
thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Proviso for Letters sent to and from the Universities.</head>
			<para id="p51">Provided alwayes that all Letters and other things may be sent or conveyed to or from the two Universities
in manner as heretofore hath beene used Any thing herein to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3"> Pacquetts <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4"> xij<emph type="p">d</emph>. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5"> xviij<emph type="p">d</emph>. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6"> xvj<emph type="p">d</emph>. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7"> xxiiij<emph type="p">d</emph>. <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8"> vj <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9"> vj <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10"> ij <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12"> interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


