<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47289" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act against Tumults and Disorders upon &bhopcrl;tence of &bhopcrl;paring or &bhopcrl;senting publick Peti&bhocotil;ns or other Addresses
to His Majesty or the Parliament [Rot. Parl 13 C. II p. 1. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of tumultuous and disorderly preparing of Petitions.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">In what case only Persons may solicit or procure any Petition, &amp;c. for altering Matters established in Church or State.; Number of Persons who may assemble to present Petition to the King and Parliament.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas it hath beene found by sad experience that Tumultuous and other Disorderly solliciting and
procuring of Hands by private persons to Peti&bhocotil;ns Complaints Remonstrances &amp; Declarations and other
Addresses to the King or to both or either Houses of Parliament for altera&bhocotil;n of matters established by Law
redresse of &bhopcrl;tended greivances in Church or State or other publique Concernments have beene made use of to serve
the ends of Fa&bholigct;ious &amp; Seditious persons gotten into power to the violation of the publique Peace and have beene
a great meanes of the late unhappy Wars Confusions and Calamities in this Nation For &bhopcrl;venting the like mischeife
for the future Be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the consent of the Lords and
Commons assembled in Parliament and by the Authority of the same That no person or persons whatsoever
shall from and after the first of August One thousand six hundred sixty and one solicite labor or procure the
getting of Hands or other consent of any persons above the number of twenty or more to any Peti&bhocotil;n Complaint
Remonstrance Declara&bhocotil;n or other [Addresses<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to the King or both or either Houses of Parliament for altera&bhocotil;n of
matters established by Law in Church or State unlesse the matter thereof have beene first consented unto and
Ordered by three or more Justices [of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] that County or by the Major part of the Grand Jury of the County or
division of the County where the same matter shall arise at theire publique Assizes or Generall Quarter Sessions
or if arising in London by the Lord Maior Aldermen and Commons in Common Councell assembled And that no
person or persons whatsoever shall repaire to His Majesty or both or either of the Houses of Parliament upon
&bhopcrl;tence of presenting or delivering any Peti&bhocotil;n Complaint Remonstrance or Declara&bhocotil;n or other Addresses accompanied
with excessive number of people nor att any one time with above the number of ten persons upon pain of
incurring a penalty not exceeding the s&bhouov;m of One hundred pounds in money and three months Imprisonment
without Bail or Mainprize for every offence which offence to be prosecuted at the Court of Kings Bench or att
the Assizes or Generall Quarter Sessions within six moneths after the offence committed and proved by two or
more credible witnesses.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for presenting public or private Grievances; and for Addresses to the King by Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwaies That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not be construed to extend to debar or
hinder any person or persons not exceeding the number of Ten aforesaid to present any publique or private
Greivance or Complaint to any Member or Members of Parliament after his Ele&bholigct;ion and during the continuance
of the Parliament or to the Kings Majesty for any remedy to bee thereupon had nor to extend to any Address
whatsoever to His Majesty by all or any the Members of both or either Houses of Parliament during the sitting
of Parliament but that they may enjoye theire freedome of Accesse to His Majesty as heretofore hath beene used.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Addresse <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


