<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47296" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>CHAPTER XII. An Act for Explanation of a Clause contained in (<ref idref="n1">2</ref>) Act of Parliament made in the seventeenth yeare of the late
King Charles Entituled An Act for Repeal of a Branch of a Statute Primo Elizabethe concerning Commissioners
for Causes Ecclesiasticall. [Rot. Parl. 13 C. II. p. 1. nu. 12.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>17(16) C. I. c. II. recited, as repealing 1 Eliz. c. 1. &sect;18.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">The said Act not to take away ordinary Power from Archbishops, &amp;c. in Ecclesiastical Jurisdiction</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">WHEREAS in an A&bholigct; of Parliament made in the seaventeenth yeare of the late King Charles Entituled An
A&bholigct; for Repeal of a Branch of a Statute Primo Elizabethe concerning Commissioners for Causes Ecclesiasticall
it is amongst other things Ena&bholigct;ed That no Archbishop Bishop nor Vicar Generall nor any Chancellor nor Commissary
of any Archbishop Bishop or Vicar Generall nor any Ordinary whatsoever nor any other Spirituall or Ecclesiasticall
Judge Officer or Minister of Justice nor any other person or persons whatsoever exerciseing Spirituall or Ecclesiasticall
Power Authority or Jurisdi&bholigct;ion by any Grant Licence or Commission of the Kings Majestie His Heires or Successors
or by any Power or Authoritie derived from the King His Heires or Successors or otherwise (shall from and after
the first day of August which then should be in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred forty one)
award impose or infli&bholigct; any Pain Penalty Fine Amercement Imprisonment or other corporall punishment upon
any [of <ref idref="n2">1</ref>] the Kings Subje&bholigct;s for any contempt misdemeanor crime offence matter or thing whatsoever belonging to
Spirituall or Ecclesiasticall Cognizance or Jurisdi&bholigct;ion whereupon some doubt hath beene made that all ordinary
power of Coertion and Proceeding&bholngs; in Causes Ecclesiasticall were taken away whereby the ordinary course of
Justice in Causes Ecclesiasticall hath been obstru&bholigct;ed Be it therefore declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the Authority thereof That neither the said A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained doth or shall
take away any ordinary Power or Authority from any of the said Archbishops Bishops or any other person or persons
named as aforesaid but that they and every of them exercising Ecclesiasticall Jurisdi&bholigct;ion may proceed determine
sentence execute and exercise all manner of Ecclesiasticall Jurisdi&bholigct;ion and all Censures and Coertions apperteyning
and belonging to the same before the makeing of the A&bholigct; before recited in all causes and matters belonging to
Ecclesiasticall Jurisdi&bholigct;ion according to the Kings Majesties Ecclesiasticall Lawes used and pra&bholigct;ised in this Realme
in as ample manner and forme as they did and might lawfully have done before the makeing of the said A&bholigct;.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. 17(16) C. I. c. 11. repealed except as to High Commission Court.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the afore recited A&bholigct; of Decimo septimo Caroli and
all the matters and Clauses therein conteined (excepting what concernes the High Commission Court [or the new
ere&bholigct;ion of some such like Court by Commission<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]) shall be and is hereby repealed to all intents and purposes
whatsoever Any thing clause or sentence in the said Act contained to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. This Act not to give force to 1 Eliz. c. 1. &sect;18.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwaies and it is hereby Ena&bholigct;ed That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing herein contained shall extend
or be construed to revive or give force to the said Branch of the said Statute made in the said first yeare of the
Reigne of the said late Queen Elizabeth mentioned in the said A&bholigct; of Parliament made in the said seaventeenth
yeare of the Reigne of the said King Charles but that the said Branch of the said Statute made in the said first
yeare of the Reigne of the said Queene Elizabeth shall stand and be repealed in such sort as if this A&bholigct; had never
beene made</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso touching the Oath Ex Officio.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alsoe and it is hereby further Ena&bholigct;ed That it shall not be lawfull for any Archbishop Bishop Vicar
Generall Chancellor Commissary or any other Spirituall or Ecclesiasticall Judge Officer or Minister or any other
person having or exercising Spirituall or Ecclesiasticall Jurisdi&bholigct;ion to tender or administer unto any person whatsoever
the Oath usually called the Oath Ex Officio or any other Oath whereby such person to whom the same is tendred
or administred may be charged or compelled to confesse or accuse or to purge him or her selfe of any criminall
matter or thing whereby he or she may be lyable to any censure or punishment Any thing in this Statute or any
other Law Custome or Usage heretofore to the contrary hereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. This A&bholigct; not to give any other Jurisdi&bholigct;ion to Archbishops, &amp;c. than they had before 1639; nor to abridge the King's Supremacy; nor to confirm the Canons of 1640.</head>
			<para id="p6">[Provided alwaies that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be construed to extend, to
give unto any Archbishopp Bishop or any other Spirituall or Ecclesiasticall Judge Officer or other person or
persons aforesaid any power or authority to exercise execute infli&bholigct; or determine any Ecclesiasticall Jurisdi&bholigct;ion
Censure or Coertion which they might not by Lawe have done before the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred and thirty nine nor to abridge or diminish the Kings Majesties Supremacy in Ecclesiasticall matters and
affaires nor to confirm the Canons made in the yeare One thousand six hundred and forty nor any of them nor any
other Ecclesiasticall Lawes or Canons not formerly confirmed allowed or ena&bholigct;ed by Parliament or by the established
Lawes of the Land as they stood in the yeare of the Lord One thousand six hundred thirty and nine<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="2">an <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


