<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47299" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XV. An Act declaring the Paines Penalties and Forfeitures imposed upon the Estates and Persons of certaine notorious
Offenders excepted out of the Act of Free and Generall Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion. [Rot. Parl. 13C.II. p. I. nu. 15.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>12 C. II. c. 11. recited.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Recital that no Act has been passed infli&bholigct;ing Penalties on Lord Mounson and others.; The Manors, Lands, &amp;;c. of the said Lord Mounson and others,; of which they were seized the 20th March 1646, or since, forfeited and vested in His Majesty; and the personal Estate of which some of them were possessed at the time of their Death.; and of which others of them were possessed on 11th Feb. 1659; forfeited, and vested in His Majesty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">WHEREAS in a certaine A&bholigct; passed in the late Assembly held att Westminster in the twelfth yeare of His
Majesties Reigne and confirmed by the Authority of this present Parliament Entituled An A&bholigct; of Free
and Generall Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion (amongst other things) it is provided that nothing therein conteyned
should extend to discharge the Lands Tenements Goods Chattels Rights Trusts and other the Hereditaments late
of Isaac Ewre deceased Sir John Danvers deceased Sir Thomas Maleverer Baronett deceased William Purefey
deceased John Blakiston deceased Sir William Constable Baronett deceased Richard Deane deceased Francis Aleyn
deceased Peregrin Pelham deceased John Moore deceased John Aldred alias Alured deceased Humphrey Edwards
deceased Sir Gregory Norton Baronet deceased John Venn deceased Thomas Andrewes Alderman deceased Anthony
Stapley deceased Thomas Horton deceased John Fry deceased Thomas Hammond deceased and Sir John Bourchier
deceased of and from such paines penalties and forfeitures as by one other A&bholigct; of Parliament intended to bee
afterwards passed for that purpose should be expressed and declared All which persons before mentioned were
whilst they lived notoriously knowne to have beene wicked and a&bholigct;ive Instruments in the prosecution and compassing
of that horrid and Execrable Treason the Murder of our late Soveraigne Lord King Charles the first of ever
blessed memory And whereas William Lord Mounson James Challoner Sir Henry Mildmay Sir James Harrington
John Phelps and Robert Wallop who in the month of January One thousand six hundred forty and eight did
a&bholigct; and sit in that traiterous Assembly which proceeded against the Person and Life of our said late Soveraigne
(<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) King Charles the First and Sir Arthur Haslerig who in his life [time<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] did commit many horrid and traiterous
Crimes against the Person Crown and Dignity of his late Majestie of glorious memory and his Majesty that now
is are all of them excepted out of the said A&bholigct; and reserved to future Paines Penalties and Forfeitures not extending
to life since the passing of which A&bholigct; so as aforesaid confirmed Sir Arthur Haslerig and [James<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Challoner died and
no A&bholigct; hath yet passed for the infli&bholigct;ing of due Paines Penalties and Forfeitures upon the persons and Estates of
the Offenders aforesaid Wee therefore the Lords and Commons in Parliament assembled doe beseech your Majestie
that it may be Ena&bholigct;ed And be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and
consent of the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by authority of the same That all
and every the Mannors Messuages Lands Tenements Rents Reversions Remainders Possessions Rights Conditions
Interests Offices Fees Annuities and all other the Hereditaments Leases for yeares Chattels Reall and other things
of what nature soever they be of them the said Isaac Ewer Sir John Danvers Sir Thomas Maleverer William
Purefoy John Sir William Constable Richard Deane Francis Aleyn Peregrin Pelham John Moore John
Aldred alias Alured Humphrey Edwards Sir Gregory Norton John Venn Thomas Andrewes Anthony Stapley
Thomas Horton John Fry. Thomas Hammond Sir John Bourchier William Lord Mounson James Challoner Sir
Henry Mildmay Sir James Harrington John Phelps Robert Wallop and Sir Arthur Haslerig which they or any of
them or any other person or persons to theire or any of theire uses or in trust for them or any of them had
the five and twentieth day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred forty and six or att
any time since shall stand and be forfeited unto your Majesty your Heires and Successors and shall bee deemed
vested and adjudged to be in the a&bholigct;uall and reall possession of Your Majestie without any Office or Inquisicon
thereof hereafter to be taken or found And alsoe that all and every the Goods Debts and other the Chattels
personall whatsoever of them the said Isaac Ewer Sir John Danvers Sir Thomas Maleverer William Purefoy John Blakiston 
Sir William Constable Richard Deane Francis Aleyn Peregrin Pelham John Moore John Aldred alias
Alured Humphrey Edwards Sir Gregory Norton John Venn Thomas Andrewes Anthony Stapley Thomas Horton
John Fry Thomas Hammond Sir John Bourchier James Challoner and Sir Arthur Haslerigg whereof they or any
of them att the time of theire respe&bholigct;ive deaths or any other in Trust for them or any of them stood possessed
or interessed in Law or Equity and all the Goods Debts and other the Chattels personall whatsoever of them
the said William Lord Mounson Sir Henry Mildmay Sir James Harrington John Phelps Robert Wallop whereof
upon the eleventh day of February in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred fifty and nine they or
any of them on any other in trust for them or any of them stood possessed either in Law or Equitie shall bee
deemed and adjudged to be forfeited and are hereby vested and put into the a&bholigct;uall and reall possession of your
Majesty without any further Office or Inquisition thereof hereafter to be taken or found</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for Conveyances and Assurances, &amp;c. made bona fide since 1st Jan. 1641, and before 29th Sept. 1659;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and for Conveyances and Assurances made before 25th April 1660; so as they be enrolled in the Exchequer before 1st Jan. 1662</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwaies and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no Conveyance Assurance Grant Bargain
Sale Charge Lease Assignement of Lease Grants and Surrenders by Copy of Court Roll Estate Interest Trust or
Limitation of any use or uses of or out of any Mannors Lands Tenements or Hereditaments [not being the Lands
nor Hereditaments<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] of the late King Queene or Prince or of any Archbishops Bishops Deanes Deanes and Chapters
nor being Lands or Hereditaments sold or given for the delinquency or pretended delinquency of any person or
persons whatsoever by vertue or pretext of some A&bholigct; Order Ordinance or reputed A&bholigct; Order or Ordinance since
the first day of January One thousand six hundred forty and one not any Statute Judgement or Recognizance had
made acknowledged or suffered to any person or persons Bodies Politick or Corporate before the nine and twentieth
day of September One thousand six hundred fifty and nine by any of the Offenders before in this A&bholigct; mentioned
or theire Heires or by any other person or persons claiming by from or under them or any of them other then
[the<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Wife or Wives Child or Children Heire or Heires of such person or persons or any of them for money bona
fide to them or any of them paid or lent or other valuable considera&bhocotil;n nor any Conveyance Assurance Grant or
Estate made before the five and twentieth day of Aprill One thousand six hundred and sixty by any person or
persons to any of the Offenders aforesaid in trust and for the benefit of any other person or persons not being any
of the offenders aforesaid or in Trust for any Bodies Politique or Corporate shall be impeached defeated made voide
or frustrated hereby or by any of the Convi&bholigct;ions and Attainders aforesaid but that the same shall be held and
enjoyed by the Purchasers Grantees Leasees Assignes Cestuy que use Cestuy que trust and every of them theire
Heires Executors Administrators and Assignes respe&bholigct;ively as if this A&bholigct; had not beene made soe as the said
Conveyances and all and every the Grants and Assurances which by vertue of this A&bholigct; are and ought to be held
and enjoyed as aforesaid shall before the first day of January which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred sixty and two be entred and enrolled of Record in his Majesties Court of Exchequer and not
otherwise Any thing in this A&bholigct; herein before contained to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. William Lord Mounson, Sir Henry Mildmay, Sir James Harrington, Robert Wallop, and John Phelps, degraded.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That William Lord Mounson Sir Henry Mildmay Sir James
Harrington Robert Wallop Esquire and John Phelps and every of them shall be and are hereby degraded from and
made uncapable of all and every the Titles of Honour Dignities and Preheminencies which they or any of them
now have or which at any time hereafter may descend unto them And that neither they or any of them shall att
any time hereafter have beare or use the Name Stile Addition or Title of Lord Baronett Knight Esquire or
Gentleman or any of them nor shall use or have any Coates or Escutcheons of Armes whatsoever nor any other
legall Title or addition whatsoever but shall be for ever reputed and are hereby declared to bee Persons of Dishonour
and Infamy</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. William Mounson; Henry Mildmay, James Harrington, Robert Wallop, and John Phelps, to be drawn to Tyburn, as Persons executed for Treason, and back, and then imprisoned.</head>
			<para id="p6">And further that they the said William Mounson Henry Mildmay James Harrington Robert Wallop and John
Phelps and every of them shall upon the seaven and twentieth day of January which shall be in the yeare of
our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty one or so soon after as they shall be apprehended carried to the
Tower of London and from thence drawne upon Sledges with Ropes about theire necks and according to the
manner of persons executed for High Treason quite through the streets of London unto the Gallows att Tiburn
and from thence in like manner be brought back again to the Tower of London and [theire<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] or in such other
Prison as his Majesty shall thinke fitt continue Prisoners and suffer paines of Imprisonment for and during the
term of theire naturall lives</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Executors of the said Persons and Legacies.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwaies That no Executor or Administrator to any of the dead persons whose Estate is forfeited by
this A&bholigct; shall att any time hereafter be sued or molested for any Debt or Legacy by them paid as Executor or
Administrator to any person or persons to whom the same was due or bequeathed and was by the said Executor
or Administrator paid bona fide but the respe&bholigct;ive Legatees who have received any such Legacies from the said
Executors shall be accomptable to the Kings Majestie for all such Legacies as they have respe&bholigct;ively received and
shall pay the same to the Kings most Excellent Majesty</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Proviso for Sir William Lewis as to East Mean Park, &amp;c. in the County of Southampton.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">General Saving.; Proviso for Cuthbert Collingwood and George Collingwood in respe&bholigct; of the Manors of Barton, &amp;c. in the County of Northumberland.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">Provided alwaies That nothing in this A&bholigct; shall be construed to forfeit the Term Estate or Interest which
Sir William Lewes of Borden in the County of Southampton Baronett had or hath in the custody of the Parke
called East Mean Parke in the aforesaid County and in the game of Conies therein for the term of three yeares beene
to come from our Lady day last being the remaining yeares of a greater terme (he the said Sir William [having<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]
formerly possessed thereof) by an Assignement made by John Allen Executor of the said Francis Allen
the which said Parke and Premisses being part of the Possessions of the Bishop of Winchester the said Sir William
Lewes hath surrendred unto the said Bishop and hath now taken a new Lease thereof for three lives from the
Bishop of Winchester the which said Lease for three lives so made by the said Bishop unto the said Sir William
Lewes shall for and [and<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] notwithstanding this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained remain firm and good unto the
said Sir William Lewes according to the true meaning of [the<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] said Lease Saving alwaies to all and every person
and persons Bodies Politique and others theire respe&bholigct;ive Heires Successors Executors and Administrators all such
Estate Right and Title and Interest in Law and Equity which they or any of them have or ought to have of in
to or out of any of the Premisses not being in Trust for any the said Offenders nor derived by from or under
the said offenders since the five and twentieth day of March one thousand six hundred forty six Saving alwaies and
reserving to Cuthbert Collingwood Esquire and George Collingwood Gent. his Son theire and either of theire
Heires and Assignes and the Farmers and Tennants of the said Cuthbert and George Collingwood or either of
them and of theire Heires and Assignes all such Right Title of Entry and A&bholigct;ion Use Interest and Possession
which they or any of them or any in trust for them or any of them have or had or ought to have of in to or
out of the Manours Towneships Villages IIamblets and Precin&bholigct;s of Eslington Whittingham Barton Throunton
Fawden Keynton West Brunton East Brunton Dunnington Blakedon alias Blagdon and Wetslade or any of them
in the Countie of Northumberland and of in to or out of the Lands Tenements Hereditam Rights Members and
Appurtenances to them or any them belonging or appertaining as if this A&bholigct; had never beene made</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Rachael Powre as to a Copyhold in Chepmansford in the County of Southampton.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct; nor any thing herein contained shall extend to prejudice the Estate and Interest
in Law or Equity of Rachel Powre Widdow of in and to one Copyhold Messuage and Mill thereunto belonging with
theire Appurtenances scituate lying and being in Chepmansford in the County of Southampton being parcell of the
Mannour of Husband Priors which by Order and Decree of the High Court of Chancery of the one and twentieth
of June one thousand six hundred sixty one she is to be forthwith restored unto and put in to possession of
and to quietly hold and enjoye the same during her Widowhood with the meane proffits thereof taken by the said
Mr. Wallop But that it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Rachel Powre to hold and enjoye the same
according to the said Decree</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for Barrington Bourchier as, to Lands granted by Letters Patent 22d March, 13 Car. II.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwaies and it is hereby further Ena&bholigct;ed That it shall and may bee lawfull to and for Barrington
Bourchier Esquire Son and Heire of Sir John Bourchier herein before mentioned to hold and enjoye all and singuler
the Lands Tenements and Hereditaments to him lately granted and conveyed or men&bhocotil;ned to be granted and
conveyed in and by certaine Letters Patents under the Great Seale of England bearing date the two and twentieth
day of March in the thirteenth yeare of His Majesties Reigne against His Majesty His Heire and Successors for ever
according to the full intent and meaning of the said Letters Patents Any thing in this present A&bholigct; contained to
the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
			<para id="p12">ITEM quedam peti&bhocotil;nes privatas personas concernentes (in se formam a&bholigct;us continentes) exhibite fuerunt &bhopcrl;dicto Domino
Regi Parliamento predi&bholigct;o qua[rum] tituli subscribuntur</para>
			<para id="p13">1. An A&bholigct; for ascertaining and establishing the Fees of the Masters of the Chancery in ordinary.</para>
			<para id="p14">2. An A&bholigct; for confirming a sale made by Sir Thomas Prestwich and others of the Manour of Holm and certaine
Lands in the Parish of Manchester in the County of Lancaster unto Sir Edward Mosley Baronet.</para>
			<para id="p15">4. An A&bholigct; for restoring of Thomas Radcliffe Es&bhoqesq; to all his Lands and possessions in England and Ireland.</para>
			<para id="p16">5. An A&bholigct; enabling John Harbin Es&bhoqesq; to setle sell and dispose of severall Manours Messuages Lands Tenements
and Hereditaments with thappurtenances in the County of Somersett and Dorsett therein men&bhocotil;ned for payment of
his debts and to make provision for his younger children</para>
			<para id="p17">6. An A&bholigct; to enable the sale of some of the Lands of Thomas Hunt Es&bhoqesq; &amp; John Hunt Gent. for payment of
theire debts.</para>
			<para id="p18">7. An Act for setling the Manours of Knoll Seale and Kempsing in the County of Kent upon the Earle of Dorsett
and his heires &amp; charging the Manour of Bexhill and the Manour or Farm of Cowding and other Lands in the
County of Sussex with a rent charge of one hundred and thirty pounds per annu[m] in leiu thereof</para>
			<para id="p19">8. An A&bholigct; for confirma&bhocotil;n of the Charter &amp; priviledges of the Master Wardens &amp; Comonalty of Weavers
Fullers and Clothiers in the City of Worcester</para>
			<para id="p20">9. An A&bholigct; for setling severall Lands. late of Sir Edward Baesh Knight upon Sir Ralph Baesh Knight of the
Bath heir of the said Sir Edward and his heires</para>
			<para id="p21">10. An A&bholigct; for confirma&bhocotil;n &amp; explana&bhocotil;n of an A&bholigct; for the setling of some of the Manours &amp; Lands of the
Earle of Cleaveland in trustees to be sold for the satisfying of the debts of the said Earle and of Thomas Lord
Wentworth his sonne</para>
			<para id="p22">11. An A&bholigct; for the uniting the Parsonages of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Andrewes and S<emph type="p">t</emph> Mary Witton in Droitwich in the County of
Worcester.</para>
			<para id="p23">12. An A&bholigct; to enable John Lord Abergavenny son and heire of Henry late Lord Abergavenny to sell certaine
Lands for payment of his debts and preferment of his brother and sisters.</para>
			<para id="p24">13. An A&bholigct; for the naturalizing of Francis Brudenell Es&bhoqesq; son and heire apparent of the Right Honorable Robert
Lord Brudenell and of the Right Honourable Anna Maria Countesse of Shrewsbury daughter of the said Lord
Brudenell and now wife of the Right Honourable Francis Earle of Shrewsbury</para>
			<para id="p25">14. An A&bholigct; for the reviving a setlement of certaine lands on John Orlibeare for life the remainder to the sons
of the said John successively and the heires males of theire bodies &amp;c</para>
			<para id="p26">15. An A&bholigct; for confirming and continuing an A&bholigct; for necessary maintenance of the worke of drayning the Great
Levell of the Fenns.</para>
			<para id="p27">16. An A&bholigct; for confirming of an Inclosure of land formerly used for a C&bhooov;mon high way from Parsons Greene
to Southfeild in Fulham and the setling of other land for a c&bhooov;mon highway there in leiu thereof</para>
			<para id="p28">17. An A&bholigct; enabling trustees to sell certaine Lands &amp; Tenements in the Counties of Suffolk and Nortolke for
y<emph type="p">e</emph> payment of the debts of Richard Gipps Esquire and providing portions for his younger children.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Lord <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">there <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">his <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


