<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47291" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act for confirming Publique Acts. [Rot. Parl. 13 C. II. p. 1. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Lords and Commons assembled at Westminster 25th April 12 Car. IL and continued until 29th December following, and were then dissolved; and that during the said time divers Acts were passed; but that such Assembly is not to be drawn into Example.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">12 Car. II. c. 11.; c. 4.; c. 5.; c.8.; c. 9.; c.12.; c.15.; c.10.; c.19.; c.20.; c.23.; c. 24.; c.25.; c.26.; c. 27.; c. 28.; c. 29.; c. 30.; c.35.; c.2.; confirmed and declared to have the full force of Acts of Parliament</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas during the late Difficulties and Exigences of Affaires in the absence of His most Excellent
Majesty and in reference to his returne from beyond the Seas into these His Majesties Dominions The
Lords and Commons being assembled att Wesminster the five and twentieth day of Aprill in the Twelfth yeare of
His Majesties Reigne were from thence and after His Majesties returne continued untill the nine and twentieth day
of December then next following and now last past and then dissolved by His Majesty In which time severall A&bholigct;s
were passed by His Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the said Lords and Commons assembled as
aforesaid which being of necessary use are fitt to be continued &amp; confirmed although the manner of the said
assembling enforced by the difficulties and exigencies aforesaid which then lay upon the Nation is not to be
drawne into example Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and
Consent of the Lords and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same
That all &amp; singuler the A&bholigct;s made or men&bhocotil;ned to be made by His said Majesty by and with the advice or
Consent of the Lords and Commons upon or since the said five and twentieth day of Aprill herein after particularly
men&bhocotil;ned and expressed That is to say One A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; of Free and Generall Pardon Indempnity and
Oblivion One other A&bholigct; Entituled A Subsidy granted to the King of Tonnage and Poundage and other Summs of
Money payable upon Merchandize exported and imported One other A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for continuing the
Excize untill the twentieth of August One thousand six hundred and sixty One other A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for
continuing the Excise till the five and twentieth day of December One thousand six hundred and sixty One other
A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy Provision of Money for disbanding and paying off the Forces of this Kingdome
both by Land and Sea One other A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for Confirma&bhocotil;n of Judiciall Proceedings One other A&bholigct;
Entituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy disbanding of the Army and Garrisons of this Kingdome One other A&bholigct; Entituled
An A&bholigct; for supplying and explaining certaine Defe&bholigct;s in an A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy Provision of
Money for disbanding and paying off the Forces of this Kingdome both by Land and Sea One other A&bholigct; Entituled
An A&bholigct; to prevent Frauds and Concealments of His Majesties Customes and Subsidies One other A&bholigct; Entituled
An A&bholigct; for raising seavenscore thousand Pounds for the compleat disbanding of the whole Army and paying
off some parte of the Navy One other A&bholigct; Entituled A Grant of certaine Imposi&bhocotil;ns upon Beere Ale and other
Liquors for the increase of His Majesties Revenue during His Life One other A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for takeing
away the Court of Wards and Liveries and Tenures in Capite and by Knights Service and Purveyance and
for setling a Revenue upon his Majestie in leiu thereof One other A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for the better ordering
the selling of Wines by Retail and for preventing abuses in the mingling corrupting and vitiating of Wines and
for setting and limiting the prices of the same One other A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for the leavying of the arreares
of the Twelve Moneths Assessment comencing the Four and Twentieth of June One thousand six hundred fiftie
and nine and the Six Moneths Assessment comencing the Five and Twentieth of December One thousand six
hundred fiftie and nine One other A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for granting unto the Kings Majestie Four Hundred
and Twenty Thousand pounds by an Assessment of Threescore and ten thousand pounds by the Moneth for Six
Moneths for disbanding the Remainder of the Army and paying off the Navy One other A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct;
for further supplying and explaining certaine Defe&bholigct;s in an A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for the speedy provision of
Money for disbanding and paying off the Forces of this Kingdome both by Land and Sea One other A&bholigct; Entituled
An A&bholigct; for the raising of Seaventy Thousand pounds for the further Supply of His Majesty One other A&bholigct;
Entituled An A&bholigct; for the Attainder of severall Persons guilty of the horrid Murder of His late Sacred Majesty
King Charles the First One other A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for ere&bholigct;ing and establishing a Post Office One other
A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for putting in Execu&bhocotil;n an Ordinance men&bhocotil;ned in this A&bholigct; and all and every the Clauses
Sentences and Articles in them and every of them contained shall be and hereby are ratified and confirmed and
ena&bholigct;ed and declared to have the full Force and Strength of A&bholigct;s of Parliament according to the tenor and purport
thereof and soe shall be adjudged deemed and taken to all Intents &amp; Purposes whatsoever and as if the same
had beene made declared and ena&bholigct;ed by Authority of this present Parliament</para>
	</section>
</report>


