<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47295" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XI. An Act for Confirming of three Acts therein mentioned [Rot. Parl. 13 C. II. p. 1. nu. 11.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">12 Car. II. c. 29.; c. 33.; c.14.; confirmed and declared to have the full force of Acts of Parliament</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Bee it Enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords and
Comons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That the severall Acts herein
after mentioned made or mentioned to be made upon or since the (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) twenty fifth day of April in the Twelfth yeare
of His said Majesties Reigne by His said Majesty by and with the advice or consent of the Lords and Commons
assembled att Westminster upon the said twenty fifth of April and there continued untill the twenty ninth day of
December then next following and then dissolved Which said Acts are herein after particularly men&bhocotil;ned and expressed
by the severall and respective Titles following That is to say One Act Entituled An Act for the raising of Seaventy
thousand pounds for the further Supply of His Majesty And one other Act Entituled An Act for Confirmation of
Marriages. And one other Act Entituled An Act for a perpetuall Anniversary Thanksgiving on the twenty ninth
day of May and all and every the Clauses Sentences and Articles in them and every of them conteyned shall be
and hereby are ratified and confirmed and enacted and declared to have the full force and strength of Acts of
Parliament according to the tenor and purport thereof and soe shall be adjudged deemed and taken to all
intents and purposes whatsoever and as if the same had beene made declared and enacted by Authority of this
present Parliament.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


