<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47293" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IX. An Act for the Establishing Articles and Orders for the regulateing and better Government of His Majesties Navies
Ships of Warr &amp; Forces by Sea. [Rot. Parl. 13 C. II. p. 1. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Articles to be observed</head>
		
		<para id="p2">FOR the regulateing and better Government of his Majesties Navies Ships of War and Forces by Sea wherein
under the good Providence and prote&bholigct;ion of God the Wealth Safety and Strength of this Kingdome is soe
much concerned Bee it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty with the advice and consent of the Lords
and Commons in this present Parlia&bhomsst; assembled and by the Authority thereof That all and every the Articles and
Orders in this A&bholigct; men&bhocotil;ned shall be duely and respe&bholigct;ively put in Execution observed and obeyed in manner
hereafter men&bhocotil;ned.</para>
		<para id="p1000"><emph type="i">The public Worship of God.</emph></para>
			<para id="p3">1. That all C&bhooov;manders Captaines and other Officers att Sea shall cause the publique Worshipp of Almighty God
according to the Liturgy of the Church of England established by Law to be solemnly orderly and reverently
performed in theire respe&bholigct;ive Ships And that prayers and preachings by the respe&bholigct;ive Chaplaines in holy Orders
of the respe&bholigct;ive Ships be performed diligently and that the Lords Day be observed according to Law.</para>
		<para id="p1001"><emph type="i">Swearing, Drunkenness, &amp;c.</emph></para>
			<para id="p4">2. Every person and persons in his Majesties pay using unlawfull and rash Oathes Cursings Execrations Drunkennes
Uncleannes or other Scandalous A&bholigct;ions in derogation of Gods Honour and corruption of good manners shall be
punished by Fine Imprisonment or otherwise as the Court Martiall shall thinke fitt.</para>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Holding Intelligence with Foreign States, being Enemies, or with Rebels.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">3. If any Officer Mariner Souldier or other person in the Fleet shall give hold or entertaine Intelligence to or
with any King Prince or State being Enemy to or any persons in Rebellion against His Majesty His Heires and
Successors without dire&bholigct;ion or leave from the Kings Majesty the Lord High Admirall Vice Admirall or Commander
in Cheife of any Squadron every such person &amp; persons so offending shall be punished with death.</para>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Receiving Letters or Messages from any Foreign Prince, &amp;c. being an Enemy, and not revealing the same. Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">4. If any Letter or Message from any King Forreigne Prince State or Potentate being an Enemy to the Kings
Majesty His Heires and Successors or on theire behalfe be conveyed to any Inferior Officer Mariner or Souldier or
other in the Fleet and the said Officer Mariner Souldier or other as aforesaid doe not within twelve houres haveing
opportunity soe to do)<?bignore?> acquaint the Superior Commander with it or if a Superior Officer or Mariner being acquainted
therewith by an Inferior Officer Mariner or other or himselfe in his owne person receiving a Letter or Message
from any such Enemy or Rebell and shall not in convenient time reveale the same to the Admirall Vice Admirall
or the Commander of the Squadron every such person shall be punished with death or such other punishment as
the Court martiall shall thinke fitt.</para>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Relieving an Enemy or Rebel.; Punishment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p10">5. No person or persons of the Fleet shall releive an Enemy or Rebell in time of Warre with money vi&bholigct;uals
powder shott armes ammunition or any other supplies whatsoever dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly upon pain of death or such
other punishment as the Court martiall shall thinke fitt to impose.</para>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Papers, Charter-parties, &amp;c. taken in any Ship seized as Prize, to be preserved.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">6. All the Papers Charter Parties Bills of Lading Pasports and other Writings whatsoever that shall bee taken
seized or found aboard any Ship or Ships which shall bee surprised or seized as prize shall bee duely preserved
and not torne nor made away but the very Originals sent up intirely and without fraud to the Court of Admiralty
or such other Commissioners as shall be appointed for that purpose there to be veiwed made use of and proceeded
upon according to Law upon pain of losse of all the shares of the Takers and such further punishment to be infli&bholigct;ed
upon the Offenders therein as the quality of theire offence and misdemeanor shall be found to deserve and the
Court martiall shall impose.</para>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Taking out of Prize, or Ships or Goods seized for Prize, any Money, &amp;c. before Judgment had Punishment.; Proviso for Pillage.; Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">7. None in his Majesties pay shall take out of any Prize or Ship or Goods seized on for Prize any Money Plate
Goods Lading or Tackle before Judgement thereof first past in the Admiralty Court but the full and intire accompt
of the whole without imbezlement shall be brought in and Judgement past intirely upon the whole without fraud
upon pain of such punishment as shall be imposed by a Court martiall or the Court of Admiralty excepting That
it shall be lawfull for all Captaines Seamen Souldiers and others serving as aforesaid to take and to have to themselves
as Pillage without further or other account to be given for the same all such Goods and [Merchandize<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] (other then
Armes Ammunition Tackle Furniture or Stores of such Ship) as shall be found by them or any of them in any
Ship (they shall take in fight or prize) upon or above the Gundeck of the said Ship and not otherwise.</para>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Embezzling, &amp;c. Cables, Anchors, &amp;c.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">8. None shall imbezle steale or take away any Cables Anchors Sailes or any of the Ships Furniture or any of
the Powder or Armes or Ammunition of the Ship upon pain of death or other punishment as the quality of the
offence shall be found by a Court martiall to deserve.</para>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Pillaging, &amp;c. Captains, &amp;c. of Foreign Ships taken as Prize not making Resistance.; Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p18">9. If any foreign Ship or Vessell shall be taken as prize that shall not fight or make resistance that in that case
none of the Captaines Masters or Mariners being Foreigners shall be stripped of theire Clothes or in any sort
pillaged beaten or evill entreated upon pain That the person or persons soe offending shall forfeit double Damages
but the said Foreign Ships and all the Goods soe taken shall be preserved intire to receive Judgement in the
Admiralty Court according to Right and Justice.</para>
		<para id="p1002"><emph type="i">The Duty of Captains, &amp;c. upon Signal of Fight.</emph></para>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Punishment.; Yielding, &amp;c.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">10. Every Captain or Commander who upon signall or order of fight or view or sight of any Ships of the
Enemy Pirate or Rebell or likelihood of Engagement shall not put all things in his Ship in a fitt posture for fight
and shall not in his owne person and according to his place hearten and encourage the Inferior Officers and common
men to fight couragiously and not to behave themselves faintly shall bee [casheire<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] And if he or they shall yeild
to the Enemy Pirate or Rebells or cry for quarter he or they soe doeing shall suffer the paines of death or such
other punishment as the offence shall deserve.</para>
		<para id="p1005"><emph type="i">Inferior Officers not observing the Commands of their Superiors.</emph></para>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">11. Every Captaine Commander and other Officer Seaman or Souldier of any Shipp Frigott or Vessell of Warre
shall duly observe the Commands of the Admirall or other his Superior or Commander of any Squadron as well
for the assailing or setting upon any Fleete Squadron or Ships of the Enemy Pirate or Rebells or joyning Battel
with them or making defence against them as all other the Commands of the Admirall or other his Superior
Commander upon pain to suffer death or other punishment as the quality of his negle&bholigct; or offence shall deserve.</para>
		
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Officers in time of fight withdrawing or not fighting.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">12. Every Captaine and all other Officers Mariners and Souldiers of every Ship Frigott or Vessell of War that
shall in time of any fight or engagement withdraw or keepe backe or not come into the fight and engage and
do his utmost to take fire kill and endamage the Enemy Pirate or Rebells and assist and releive all and every
of His Majesties Ships shall for such offence of cowardice or disaffe&bholigct;ion be tried and suffer paines of death or
other punishment as the circumstances of the offence shall deserve and the Court martiall shall judge fitt.</para>
		
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Officers and Ships appointed for Convoy not fighting, or otherwise negle&bholigct;ing Duty.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">13. The Captaines Officers and Seamen of all Ships appointed for Convoy and Guard of Merchants Ships or
any other shall diligently attend upon that Charge without delay according to theire Instructions in that behalfe
and whosoever shall be faulty therein and shall not faithfully performe the same and defend the Ships and Goods
in theire Convey without either diverting to other parts or occasions or refusing or neglecting to fight in theire
defence if they be sett upon or assailed or running away cowardly and submitting those in theire Convoy to hazard
and perill or shall demand and exact any money or other reward from any Merchant or Master for conveying of
any such Ships or other Vessels belonging to His Majesties Subjects shall bee condemned to make reparation of
the damage to the Merchants Owners and others as the Court of Admiralty shall adjudge and alsoe be punished
criminally according to the quality of theire Offences be it by pains of death or other punishment according as
shall be judged fit by the Court martiall.</para>
		<para id="p1007"><emph type="i">Not chasing an Enemy, or not relieving a Friend. Punishment.</emph></para>
			<para id="p27">14. Whatsoever person or persons in or belonging to the Fleete either through cowardize negligence or disaffection
shall forbeare to pursue the chase of any Enimy or Pirate or Rebell beaten or flying or shall not releive or
assist a known freind in view to the utmost of his power shall be punished with death or otherwise as a Court
martiall shall find fitt.</para>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Discouraging the Service.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">15. When att any time service or a&bholigct;ion shall be commanded no man shall presume to stopp or put backward
or discourage the said service and a&bholigct;ion by pretence of Arreares of Wages or upon any pretence of Wages whatsoever
upon pain of death.</para>
		<para id="p1008"><emph type="i">Officers betraying their Trust, or yielding to the Enemy.</emph></para>
			<para id="p30">16. All Sea-Captaines Officers and Seamen that shall betray theire Trust or turne to the Enemy Pirate or Rebells
and either run away with theire Shipp or any Ordnance Ammunition or Provision to the weakning of the Service
or yeild the same up to the Enemy Pirate or Rebells shall be punished with death.</para>
		
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">Deserting.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p32">17. All Sea Captains Officers or Mariners that shall desert the Service or theire Imployment in the Ships or shall
run away or intice any others soe to doe shall be punished with death.</para>
		
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">Spies.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p34">18. All persons whatsoever that shall come or be found in the nature of Spies to bring any seducing Letters or
messages from any Enemy or Rebell or shall attempt or endeavor to corrupt any Captaine Officer Mariner or other
of the Navy or Fleete to betray his or theire Trust and yeild up any Shipp or Ammunition or turn to the Enemy
or Rebell shall be punished with death.</para>
		<para id="p1010"><emph type="i">Sedition, Mutiny, Punishment.</emph></para>
			<para id="p35">19. Noe Person in or belonging to the Fleete shall utter any words of Sedition or Mutiny nor make or endeavour
to make any mutinous Assemblies upon any pretence whatsoever upon pain of death.</para>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">Concealing traiterous or mutinous Pra&bholigct;ices or Words.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">20. Noe person in or belonging to the Fleet shall conceale any traiterous or mutinous pra&bholigct;ices designes or
[word<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] or any words spoken by any to the prejudice of His Majestie or Government or any words pra&bholigct;ices or designes
tending to the hindrance of the Service but shall forthwith reveale them to his Superior that a meet proceeding
may bee had thereupon upon pain of such punishment as a Court martiall shall finde to be just.</para>
	<para id="p1011"><emph type="i">Quarrelling with or striking a superior Officer.</emph></para>
			<para id="p38">21. None shall presume to quarrell with his Superior Officer upon pain of severe punishment nor to strike any
such upon pain of death or otherwise as a Court martiall shall finde the matter to deserve.</para>
		<para id="p1014"><emph type="i">Complaint of unwholesome Vi&bholigct;uals how to be made.; Exciting Disturbance thereon.; Punishment.;</emph></para>
			<para id="p39">22. If any of the Fleet finde cause of Complaint of the unwholesomnes of his Vi&bholigct;uals or upon other just ground
he shall quietly make the same knowne to his Superior or Captaine or Commander in Cheife as the occasion may
deserve that such present remedy may bee had as the matter may require and the said Superior or Commander is to
cause the same to be presently remedied accordingly but no person upon any such or other pretence shall
privately attempt to stirr up any disturbance upon pain of such severe punishment as a Court martiall shall finde
meete to infli&bholigct;.</para>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">Quarrelling, &amp;c.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">23. None shall quarrell or fight in the Ship nor use reproachfull or provokeing speeches tending to make any
quarrell or disturbance upon paine of Imprisonment and such other punishment as the Offence shall deserve and
the Court martiall shall impose.</para>
		<para id="p1015"><emph type="i">Wasteful Expence of Ammunition.; Punishment.</emph></para>
			<para id="p42">24. That there be [no<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] wastfull expence of any Powder Shott Ammunition or other [ores<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] in the Fleet nor any
imbezlement thereof but that the Stores and Provisions be carefully preserved upon such penalties by Fine Imprisonment
or otherwise upon the Offenders Abbetters Buyers and Receivers as shall bee by a Court martiall found just in
that behalfe.</para>
			<para id="p43">
				<emph type="i">Negle&bholigct; in condu&bholigct;ing and steering Ships.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p44">25. That care be taken in the condu&bholigct;ing and steering of the Ships that through wilfulnes negligence or other
defaults none of His Majesties Ships be stranded or run upon any Rocks or Sands or Split or hazarded upon pain
that such as shall be found guilty therein be punished by Fine imprisonment or otherwise as the Offence by a
Court martiall shall be adjudged to deserve.</para>
		<para id="p1030"><emph type="i">Burning Ship or Stores.; Punishment.</emph></para>
			<para id="p45">26. All persons that shall willingly burn or sett fire on any Shipp or Magazine or [sto<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of Powder or Shipp
Boat Ketch Hoy or Vessell or Tackle or Furniture thereto belonging not appertaining to an Enemy or Rebell shall
be punished with death.</para>
		<para id="p1031"><emph type="i">Sleeping upon Watch.; Punishment.</emph></para>
			<para id="p46">27. No man in or belonging to the Fleet shall sleep upon his Watch or negligently performe the Duty imposed
on hin or forsake his station upon pain of death or other punishment as the circumstances of the Case shall
require.</para>
		<para id="p1032"><emph type="i">Murders.</emph></para>
			<para id="p47">28. All Murders and wilfull killing of any persons in the ship shall be punished with death.</para>
		<para id="p1033"><emph type="i">Robbery and Theft.</emph></para>
			<para id="p48">29. All Robbery and Theft committed by any person in or belonging to the Fleet shall be punished with death
or otherwise as the Court martiall upon considera&bhocotil;n of circumstances shall finde meete.</para>
			<para id="p49">
				<emph type="i">Provost Marshall refusing to receive, &amp;c. Prisoners. Punishment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p50">30. No Provost marshall belonging to the Fleet shall refuse to receive or keepe any prisoner comitted to his
charge nor suffer him to escape being once [in<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] his custody nor dismisse him without order upon pain of being
lyable to the same punishment which should have beene infli&bholigct;ed upon the party dismissed or permitted to escape or
such other punishment as the Court marshall shall thinke fitt.</para>
		<para id="p1040"><emph type="i">Officers, &amp;c. not apprehending Offenders. Punishment.</emph></para>
			<para id="p51">31. All [Captaines<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Officers and Seamen shall doe theire endeavours to detect apprehend [and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] bring to
punishment all Offenders and shall assist the Officers appointed for that purpose therein upon paine to bee proceeded
against and punished by the Court martiall att discretion.</para>
			<para id="p52">
				<emph type="i">Sodomy</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p53">32. If any person [or<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] persons in or belonging to the Fleet shall commit the unnaturall and detestable sin
of Buggery or Sodomy with Man or (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) Beast he shall be punished with death without mercy.</para>
			<para id="p54">
				<emph type="i">Misdemeanors and Disorders at Sea</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p55">33. All other Faults Misdemeanors and Disorders committed att Sea not mentioned in this A&bholigct; shall be punished
according to the Lawes and Customes in such cases used att Sea.</para>
		<para id="p1045"><emph type="i">Lord High Admiral may grant Commissions to call Courts Martial.; Proceedings regulated.</emph></para>
			<para id="p56">
				<emph type="i">Sentence of Death, for Offences on Voyage, when executed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p57">34. And it is hereby further Ena&bholigct;ed That the Lord High Admirall for the time being shall by vertue of this
A&bholigct; have full power and authority to grant Commissions to Inferior Vice Admiralls or Commander in Cheife of any
Squadron of Ships to call and assemble [Court marshalls<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] consisting of Commanders and Captaines and no Court
martiall where the paines of death shall bee infli&bholigct;ed shall consist of lesse then Five Captaines at least the Admiralls
Lieutennant to be as to this purpose esteemed as a Captaine and in no case wherein sentence of death shall passe
by vertue of the Articles aforesaid or any of them (except in case of mutiny) there shall be execution of such
Sentence of Death without the leave of the Lord High Admirall if the offence be committed within the Narrow
Seas But in case any of the Offences aforesaid be committed in any Voyage beyond the Narrowe Seas whereupon
Sentence of Death shall be given in pursuance of the aforesaid Articles or of any of them then Execution shall not
be done but by Order of the Commander in Cheife of that Fleete or Squardron wherein Sentence of Death was
passed.</para>
			<para id="p58">
				<emph type="i">Judge Advocate to administer an Oath on Trial; or Court may appoint a Person to administer Oath</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p59">35. And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed and Declared That the Judge Advocate of any Fleete for the time being shall
have full power and authority to administer an Oath to any person or witnes in order to the Examina&bhocotil;n or Tryall
of any of the Offences aforesaid and in the absence of a Judge Advocate the Court marshall shall have full power
and authority to appoint any person to administer an Oath to the purpose aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>II. Proviso touching the Powers of the Lord Admiral.</head>
			<para id="p60">[Provided alsoe and bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That this A&bholigct; or any thing or things
therein conteyned shall not in any manner of wise extend to give unto the Lord Admirall of England for the time
being or to any his Vice Admiralls Judge or Judges of the Admiralty his or theire Deputy or Deputies or to any
other the Officers or Ministers of the Admiralty or to any others having or claiming any Admirall Power Jurisdi&bholigct;ion
or Authority within this Realme and Wales or any other the Kings Dominions any other Power Right Jurisdi&bholigct;ion
Preheminence or Authority then he or they or any of them lawfully have hath or had or ought to have and enjoye
before the making of this A&bholigct; other then for such of the Offences specified in the severall Articles conteyned in
this A&bholigct; as hereafter shall be done upon the main Sea or in Ships or Vessells being and hovering in the maine
Streame of great Rivers onely beneath the Bridges of the same Rivers nigh to the Sea within the Jurisdi&bholigct;ion of
the Admiralty and in none other places whatsoever and comitted only by such persons as shall be in a&bholigct;uall
Service and Pay in his Majesties Fleete or Ships of War.<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Merchandizes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">cashiered <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">words <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">the word is not clear on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">with <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Courts Martiall <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		
	</section>
</report>


