<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47308" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act for regulating the making of Stuffs in Norfolke and Norwich. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. I. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that divers Abuses have been used in making of Norwich Stuffs, &amp;c</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that the Power given by 7E. IV. c. 1. is not sufficient, &amp;c.; Regulations as to Choice of Wardens and Assistants.; Wardens to take an Oath.; What Persons may administer the same; Form.; Assistants to take the like Oath.; Wardens refusing to take the Oath, or dying before the End of the Year, Proceedings.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas divers abuses and deceipts have of late yeares beene had [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] used in the making of Worsteds and
other Stuffs comonly called Norwich Stuffs and in the reeling of Yarns whereof the said Stuffs are either
wholly or in parte made which tends to the debasing of the said Manufa&bholigct;ure unto the prejudice of the Publique
which said Trade of weaveing of Stuffs hath of late times beene very much encreased and great variety of new
sorts of Stuffs have beene invented so that the Power given by the Statute of the Seaventh of Edward the Fourth
Chapter the First is not sufficient for the regulateing of the same And that the number of the Wardens by the
same A&bholigct; appointed being but Eight are [to<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] few for the governeing and ordering the same Trade by which meanes
the same Manufa&bholigct;ure will soone be lost (if not prevented) and carried into forreigne Nations to the great [diminutions<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]
of his Majesties Customes and turning out of worke many thousands of poore people. For prevention of which
abuses deceipts and evils It is ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty with the advice and consent of the
Lords Spiritual and Temporall and Commons assembled in Parliament and by [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Authority of the same That there
shall be Twelve Wardens and thirty Assistants all which are to be Master Weavers within the County of the Citty
of Norwich and County of Norfolk six of which said Wardens and fifteen of the said Assistants shall be chosen
the first Monday after Pentecost in the Yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty and two and from
thence forth yearely and every yeare on the next Monday after Pentecost at some publique place by the Master
Weavers or the greater part of them present of the said City and County of Norwich and the other six Wardens
and fifteene Assistants shall be chosen upon the same day yearely within the City of Norwich or County of Norfolke
in some [publique<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] place by the Master Weavers or the greater part of them present of the County of Norfolke
And the said Wardens respe&bholigct;ively shall within fourteen Dayes after they shall be so chosen or ele&bholigct;ed and notice
thereof given take the Oath ensueing to bee administred by the Maior of the said City for the time being
or his Deputy and the Steward of the Dutchy of Lancaster within the said County for the time being if it shall
happen the said Steward shall be there present or else before the said Maior or his Deputy onely which Oath they
and every of them are hereby authorized and required from time to time to administer accordingly viz. I. A. B.
doe sweare that I will well faithfully and honestly performe and discharge the Office of a Warden of the said Trade
of Worsted Weavers according to the best of my skill power and knowledge. And that the said Assistants and
every of them within the time aforesaid shall take the like Oath before such person or persons before whom the
Wardens shall be sworne for the execution of that Office of an Assistant and that if it shall happen that any of
the said Wardens who shall be so chosen shall refuse to take the said Oath or after he be sworne shall dye before
the end of the yeare that then from time to time so often as need shall be it shall and may be lawfull to and for
the Master Weavers of the said City and County of the City of Norwich and County of Norfolke respe&bholigct;ively as
the cause shall require to chuse other Warden or Wardens in the place of him or them so dying or refusing who
shall be sworne in such manner as aforesaid</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Wardens and Assistants to meet at Weavers Hall in Norwich, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and may make Bye Laws, &amp;c. for the Regulation of the said Stuffs, and the Artificers of the same; and may make Seals for sealing the said Stuffs.; Regulations being ratified to be published</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the Regulation and good Government of the said Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ure the said Wardens and
Assistants or any thirteen of them whereof seaven to be Wardens shall and may from time to time meet and
consult togeather for the good and benefit of the said Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ure and for the due execution of the
Powers and Authorities given by this A&bholigct; so often as to them shall seeme expedient or when it shall be desired
by eight or more of the said Assistants att the place called Weavers Hall in the said City or att such other place
as they shall thinke fitt And that any thirteen or more of the said Wardens and Assistants whereof seaven att the
least to be Wardens shall have and hereby have Power and Authority from time to time so often as need shall
require to make and ordaine By-lawes Rules and Ordinances for and concerning the regulation of the said WorstedStuffs and other Stuffs nowe made and which hereafter shall be made within the said City and County of the City
of Norwich and County of Norfolk and in either of them both in length breadth and goodnesse and of such other
particulars as shall by the said Wardens and Assistants soe met or the greater number of them from time to time
be judged requisite for the better regulateing the said Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ure and the Artificers of the same in
the due execution of this A&bholigct; (and to make Seales from time to time for the sealing of the same Stuffs) which
By-Lawes Rules and Ordinances being ratified and confirmed by the Maior and two Justices of Peace of the said
City and County of Norwich for the time being and three other Justices of [the<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Peace of the said County of
Norfolke (whereof one to be of the Quo[rum]) shall be published foure times in the yeare at the least att foure
Publique Assemblies for the said Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ure and shall be obeyed and kept by the severall persons
within and under the said Regulation</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Wardens and Assistants may impose Fines.</head>
			<para id="p5">And the said Wardens and Assistants shall have and hereby have power to impose a Fine or Penalty upon any
person or persons under such Regulation as shall not conforme to such Rules Orders and Ordinances so made and
to be made and confirmed as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Not exceeding 10s.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided that the said Fine or Penalty upon any person for not conforming as aforesaid shall not exceed the
s&bhouov;m of Ten shillings for any one Offence</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Wardens and Assistants of the City to give Notice to Wardens of the County of making Bye Laws, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed That the Wardens and Assistants of the said City and County of the City of Norwich
shall from time to time give personall notice unto the Wardens of the said County of Norfolke or two of them
at the least of the time when they intend to consider of the making of By Lawes Rules and Ordinances as
aforesaid and shall sett it up in writing upon the Doore of theire Sealing Hall fourteen dayes att the least before
they shall proceed to the making the same to the end that such of the said Countrey Weavers as are therein
concerned may be there &bhopcrl;sent</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Yarns to be made without Fraud.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Regulations as to Reels.; Selling, &amp;c. Yarns unduly made, &amp;c.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And for the better Regulation and carrying on the worke aforesaid and for avoiding (<ref idref="n7">7</ref>) all Frauds and Deceipts
therein Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all Yarnes called Worsted Yarnes and such other
Yarns as are comonly used by the Worsted Weavers shall be made without Fraud and shall be reeled on a Reel
of a full Yard about and every Reel staff shall containe fourteen Leas and every Lea fourty threads twelve of
which Reel-staffs shall make a dozen and twelve of those dozens shall make a grosse And in case any Person
or Persons shall sell or expose to sale any of the said Yarns made and reeled in any other manner then as is
aforesaid that then every such Person or Persons shall forfeit the Moyety of the value of the said Yarns to the
use of the said Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ures after charges of Suit and of Prosecution first dedu&bholigct;ed out of the same
which forfeiture shall be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint Indi&bholigct;ment or Information in any of the Kings
Majesties Courts of Record wherein no wager of Law Essoyn or Prote&bholigct;ion shall be allowed for the Defendant</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Wardens and Assistants may search and view in Fairs and Markets, &amp;c.; and may seize Yarns unduly made, and try the same.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Power of Jury to fine</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And that it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Wardens and Assistants of the said Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ures
or any two of them from time to time to view and search in all Faires and Marketts and other publique places
of Sale of Yarnes within the said City of Norwich and County of the same and County of Norfolke and either
of them all Yarnes which shall be there exposed to sale and such of the said Yarns as they shall find defe&bholigct;ive contrary to the rules herein before sett that then it shall and may be lawfull to and for the same Wardens &amp;
Assistants or any two of them to seize the same Yarne and bring the same within twenty dayes next after the
Seisure thereof to Tryal by a Jury and to bee proceeded in and fined in such manner and form as in this present
A&bholigct; is limited and appointed for defe&bholigct;ive Stuffs which said Jury shall have and hereby have power to set such
Fine or Fines upon the said Yarnes as they shall in theire discretions see cause the same Fines not to exceed
the Moyety of the Yarn so found defe&bholigct;ive and the same Fines to goe to the Poore of the same Trade and
Manufa&bholigct;ure as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. No Double Punishment.</head>
			<para id="p12">Provided alwayes That no person or persons shall be doubly punished for any one Offence touching Yarnes
(that is to say) by this and the former clause in this A&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Stuffs and Makers of Stuffs to be under the Government of Wardens and Assistants.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Stuffs before offered for Sale to be brought to Weavers Hall; and if well made, to be sealed and allowed; if defe&bholigct;ive, seized and tried.; Regulations as to Jury, and impannelling.; Power of Jury to try the Stuffs and impose Fine.; Defe&bholigct;ive Stuffs to be detained until Fine paid; how to be disposed of if Fine not paid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That all sorts of Stuffs whether woven of Woollen only or of Wool and
other Materials within the City and County of Norwich and the County of Norfolke and the Makers and Weavers
of the same Stuffs shall be under the power goverment and regulation of the said Wardens &amp; Assistants in such
manner as by this and other A&bholigct;s of Parliament and the By Lawes made and to be made by vertue thereof
are or shall be established (except such Stuffs as are under the regulation of the Wardens and Fellowshipp of
the mystery of Russell Sattens, Sattens, Reverses and Fustians of Norwich making within the City of Norwich)
And that all Stuffs made or to be made under the Regulation aforesaid before the same shall be offered or put
to sale shall be brought to Weavers Hall for the time being within the County of the City of Norwich to be
veiwed and searched by the said Wardens or any two of them And if the same shall be found to be well and
sufficiently made and wrought according to the Rules and Ordinances of the said Trade then all such Stuffs shall
bee by the Wardens or any two of them sealed and allowed accordingly without any sum of money paid or to
be paid for the same And if upon search and veiw thereof any such Stuffs shall be found and appeare to be
defe&bholigct;ive contrary to the Rules and Ordinances of the said Wardens and Assistants then all such defe&bholigct;ive Stuffs
shall be seized by the said Wardens or any two of them and tried by a Jury of twelve Artificers of the said
Regulation of Worsted Weavers Six whereof to be of the City of Norwich and Six to be of the County of
Norfolke who shall be from time to time impannelled by a Precept under the Hand and Seale of the Maior of
the Citty of Norwich for the time being or his Deputie And if any who shall be so impannelled shall fail in
appearance the number to be made up either of the Master Weavers of the City of Norwich or of the County
of Norfolke by a Precept from the said Maior which Jury so impannelled or taken &amp; sworn before the Maior of
the said City for the time being shall try the said Stuffs and find whether they bee made according to this
A&bholigct; and the By Lawes and Ordinances made by vertue thereof or of any other A&bholigct; of Parliament and shall have
power to impose a moderate Fine according to the nature of the offence not exceeding the moyety of the value
of the defe&bholigct;ive Stuffs so seized and tried the same Fines to goe to the use of the Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ure And
those Stuffs which shall be found defe&bholigct;ive to bee detained untill the Fine or Fines set upon them by the Jury
be paid which if the Owner of the same Stuffs shall not pay to the said Wardens or some of them within
forty dayes after the Tryall then the same Stuffs to be sold by any two of the said Wardens and the overplus
of the moneyes thereof coming after the Fines dedu&bholigct;ed to be restored to the Owner upon demaund</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Wardens sealing Stuffs found defe&bholigct;ive by a Jury.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Penalty on Wardens to be imposed by Jury.; The same Jury may inquire into all other Frauds, &amp;c. of Wardens and Assistants; and may punish</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed That if any Warden or Wardens shall at any time seale or cause to be sealed any
Stuffs made under the said regulation which shall afterwards be discovered by any person to be defe&bholigct;ive contrary
to this present A&bholigct; and the By lawes Rules and Ordinances thereupon made or hereafter to bee made or any of
them and found soe to bee by a Jury of twelve Artificers of the said Trade from time to time to be impannelled
and sworn before the said Maior or his Deputie and the said Steward of the Dutchy of Lancaster for the time
being if he be there present And if the said Steward be absent then before the said Maior or his Deputy only
[of<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] which Jury six shall bee of the said City Weavers and the other Six of the said Countrey Weavers who shall
have and hereby have power to sett and impose a Fine upon the Warden or Wardens of the said Trade offending
for every peice of defe&bholigct;ive Stuff so sealed as the same Jury in theire discretion shall thinke fitt the same Fine
not exceeding the s&bhouov;m of fourty shillings which shall be to the use of the Kings Majestie And that the same
Jury or any other such like Jury from time to time to be impannelled by and sworn before the persons aforesaid
or any of them shall likewise enquire into all and every other the frauds abuses and Miscarriages of the Wardens
and Assistents and every of them in the Execution of theire Offices and corre&bholigct; and punish them and every of
them for theire severall offences in such manner as is herein before mentioned to bee done against any other
offenders who are under the said Regulation</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. If such Stuffs on Trial prove good, the Persons molesting Wardens to pay Double Damages.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided that if the said Wardens or any of them shall be unjustly molested and that if such Stuffs upon tryall
shall be found by the Jury to bee good and duly made or that they or the Assistents or any of them are not
guilty of any such frauds miscarriages or abuses as they are complained of for the person or persons so causelesly
molesting shall pay to the Wardens or Assistents or any of them so unjustly molested double the damages they
or any of them shall or may sustain by any such molestation</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Persons not to buy Stuffs unsealed.; Saving King's Right of Aulnage.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Stuffs unsealed found in Possession.; Exception.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That it shall not bee lawfull for any person or persons to
buy any peice or peices of Stuffs before the same be sealed by the Wardens of the said Trade saving to the Kings
Majesty his Heires and Successors all such right of Customes Subsidies and Aulnage of Norfolke and Norwich
Stuffs or Worsteds or any of them as he or they might lawfully have claimed before the making of this A&bholigct;. And
that if any peice or peices of Stuffs shall be found in the possession of any person or persons unsealed except in
the possession of the first Owner or Maker thereof the person or persons in whose custody the same shall be
found shall be adjudged guilty of deceit and shall forfeit for every such peice of Stuffe which be so found in his
or theire possession unsealed as aforesaid the s&bhouov;m of four shillings And the Maker and Seller of the same who
shall deliver the same out of his or theire possession before the same be sealed shall likewise forfeit for every
such peice other four shillings to the use of the poore of the said Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ure</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Counterfeiting Seal of Trade, or sealing with Counterfeit Seal, or removing Seal.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;20</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p21">And that if any person shall counterfeit any seale of the said Trade or shall seale any peice of Stuffe under the
Regulation with any counterfeit Seale or shall remove a Seale of one peice and sett it unto another peice which
hath not beene sealed by the Wardens every person so offending and being thereof convi&bholigct;ed by his owne
Confession or by the Oath of two or more Witnesses to be taken before the Maior of the said City or his
Deputy or any one Justice of Peace of the City of Norwich or County of Norfolke who respe&bholigct;ively have hereby
power to administer an Oath for that purpose shall forfeit for every such offence the sum of twenty pounds of
lawfull English money to the use of the Kings Majestie</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Unduly using Trade of a Weaver. Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p22">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no Person or Persons shall use or exercise the same
Trade as a Weaver unles he hath served to the same Trade as an Apprentice by the space of Seaven Yeares upon
pain of forfeiting Forty Shillings for every Moneth he shall use or exercise the same Trade not haveing served
thereunto as aforesaid the one halfe thereof to the Kings Majestie and the other halfe thereof to the Person or
Persons who will sue or prosecute for the same by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint Indi&bholigct;ment or Information in any of His
Majesties Courts of Record.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Mark of Weaver to be wove into Stuff. Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p23">And that every Person under the said Regulation shall weave his proper Stuff Mark into every peice of
Stuff which he shall weave or cause to bee woven at the head end of the same peice upon paine of forfeiting
three Shillings for every peice that shall be woven without such Marke to the use of the poore of the said Trade
and Manufa&bholigct;ure</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Powers to Wardens and Assistants to enter and search in Houses, &amp;c. of Artificers, Merchants, Dyers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">and to seize defe&bholigct;ive Stuffs there</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p25">And the said Wardens and Assistents or any two or more of them shall have and hereby have power to enter
into and search the Houses and Worke houses of any Artificers within the City of Norwich and County of
Norfolke under the Regulation of the said Wardens and Assistents and the Shops Houses and Ware houses of any
Merchant Common buyer Dealer in and Retayler of any the said Stuffs and into the House and Worke house of
any Dyer Sheerman Callender or other Workmans house and places of sale and dressing of the said Stuffs att all
times of the day and usual times of working and may there search and view the Stuffs there found whether they
be ordered and made according to this present. A&bholigct; and the Lawes Orders and Ordinances of the said Trade And
that if any such Stuff as aforesaid shall be found faultie or defe&bholigct;ive That then they or any two of them shall
seize take and carry away the same to be ordered and brought to Tryall and proceeded against in manner and
forme as is before in this present A&bholigct; men&bhocotil;ned and appointed for defe&bholigct;ive Stuffs</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Persons employing Two Apprentices to employ Two Journeymen.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">Employing more than Two; Apprentices or a Week Boy.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">And for the better providing that poor Journey men who have served in the said Trade and are not able
to set up for themselves may be imployed in worke It is hereby ena&bholigct;ed That whatsoever Person under the
Regulation of the said Trade who shall imploy two Apprentices in the said Trade shall likewise imploy and sett on
worke two Journey men in the said Trade during the time he imployes two Apprentices and that no Master Weaver
under the Regulation of the said Trade shall att any time have imploy or sett on worke above two Apprentices or
any weeke-Boy to weave in a Lombe in the said Trade in worsted weaving upon pain that every person shall forfeit
for every Moneth so offending as aforesaid the Sum of five pounds to the use of the Kings Majestie</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Persons concerned in this A&bholigct; to obey the same.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">Hindering Wardens, &amp;c. in executing their Office.; Penalty 40s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That all Persons who are or may be concerned in any thing contained in this present
A&bholigct; are hereby stri&bholigct;ly enjoyned and required to yeeld due Obedience thereunto according to the true intent and
meaning of this present A&bholigct;. And that if any Person or Persons shall refuse hinder or will not permit the said
Wardens or Assistants or any twoe or more of them to execute theire Office according to the tenour of this A&bholigct;
that then every person so offending being thereof convi&bholigct;ed by the Oath of one or more credible Wittnesses before
the Maior of the said City or his Deputy or any one Justice of Peace of the said City of Norwich or County of
Norfolke respe&bholigct;ively who are hereby authorized to administer such Oath shall forfeit the S&bhouov;m of Fourtie Shillings
to the use of the Kings Majestie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Refusing to appear on Jury or Trial.</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 5s.; Penalties to the ; Poor of the Trade.; Distress for Penalty where Recovery not otherwise provided for</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">And if any Person lawfully summoned to appeare upon any Jury or Tryall according to the tenor of this A&bholigct;
shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to appeare and proceed upon the same every person soe refusing or negle&bholigct;ing shall forfeit
for every such negle&bholigct; or refusall the s&bhouov;me of Five Shillings to the use of the poore of the said Trade and
Manufa&bholigct;ure which said penalties and forfeitures together with all other fines and penalties which are appointed to
goe to the poore of the Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ure or for the use thereof men&bhocotil;ned in this A&bholigct; the meanes of recoverie
of which is not alreadie otherwise herein provided and sett forth shall be levied by distresse and sale of the Offenders
goods and chattels by warrant to be granted by the said Maior or his Deputy for the time being or any one Justice
of Peace of the City of Norwich or County of Norfolke rendring the Overplus of such distresse to the Owner thereof
if any shall be and the same shall be by him demaunded or otherwise to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint
Indi&bholigct;ment or Information in any his Majesties Courts of Record wherein no wager of Law Essoyn or Prote&bholigct;ion shall
be allowed to the Defendant as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Recital of Custom that Weaving should cease during Harvest.</head>
			<para id="p32">
				<emph type="i">No Loom to be in Work from 15th August to 15th Sept. yearly.; Penalty</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p33">And whereas the Custome hath beene retained time out of mind and found expedient that there should be a
cessation of weaving every yeare in the time of Harvest in regard the Spinners of Yarn which the said Weavers doe
use are at that time cheifly imployed in Harvest worke Be it ena&bholigct;ed That no Weaver under the Regula&bhocotil;n of the said
Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ure shall sett any Loome on worke for the weaveing of any Stuffs under the said Regulation in
the time of Harvest yearely from the Fifteenth day of August in every Yeare untill the Fifteenth day of September
then next following upon pain of forfeiting to the Kings Majestie the Summe of Fortie shillings for every Loom
which shall be used in worke within the said time</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Account of Fines to be made at the Four Assemblies, and of necessary Charges touching the Manufa&bholigct;ure.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Overplus how to be disposed of</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That a true accompt shall be made at the foure Assemblies
(to be held quarterly as aforesaid) by the Wardens before the Maior of the City of Norwich for the time being and
one of the Justices of the Peace of the said City and County of Norwich and two Justices of the Peace of the County
of Norfolke of all such Fines and Forfeitures as shall be received and had belonging to the said Trade &amp; Manufa&bholigct;ure
and of the necessarie Charges and Disbursements touching the same Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ure and that the Overplus
which shall remaine after the said necessary Charges and Disbursements are dedu&bholigct;ed shall be devided into two
equall parts the one Moyetie thereof to be disposed (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) by the Wardens and Assistants of the said City of Norwich or
the greater parte of them and the other Moyety thereof by the Wardens and Assistants of the said County of Norfolke
or the greater parte of them for the use of the poore of the said Trade and Manufa&bholigct;ure in such manner as the
said Maior and Justices aforesaid respe&bholigct;ively shall order and dire&bholigct; and no other any thing in this A&bholigct; to the
contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Mayors, &amp;c. to be aiding Wardens and Assistants.</head>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">In A&bholigct;ions for executing A&bholigct;, General Issue. Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">And that all Mayors Justices Sheriffes Bayliffes Constables and all other Officers shall be aiding and assisting to
the said Wardens and Assistants or any of them as often as they shall be thereunto required and in all A&bholigct;ions and
Suits that shall be brought against any Person or Persons for a&bholigct;ing in any thing according to the true intent and
meaning of this A&bholigct; the Person or Persons soe sued or molested shall or may plead the generall Issue of not guilty
and give the speciall matter in evidence and shall recover double costs in every such case if the Verdi&bholigct; passe for such
Person or Persons or that the Plaintiffe or Plaintiffs be Non Suit therein</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Proviso for Yarmouth and Lynn as to bringing their Wares to Norwich to be sealed, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">14 (14 &amp; 15) H. VIII. c. 3</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">Provided alwaies That this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend to compell the Weavers of the Towns
of Great Yarmouth and Lyn in the said County of Norfolke to bring theire Wares to Norwich to bee sealed or be
prejudicial to the Weavers of the said towns or either of them to deprive them or either of them of such Liberties
or Priviledges as are granted unto them by an A&bholigct; of Parliament made in the Fourteenth Yeare of King Henry the
Eighth or by any other A&bholigct; of Parliament or Grant or Charter whatsoever This A&bholigct; to begin and take effe&bholigct; from
the Fifteenth Day of May One thousand six hundred sixty and two</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">too <emph type="i">O</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">diminution <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">of <emph type="i">O.</emph>
			</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


