<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47301" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act for prevention of Vexations and Oppressions by Arrests and of Delaies in Suits of Law.[Rot. Parl. 13 C. II. p. 2. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that by the Law of the Land, in case of Arrest, the Cause of A&bholigct;ion ought to be set forth in Process;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that of late divers, Arrests have been on general Writs of Trespass, &amp;c. in which no Cause of A&bholigct;ion expressed; and that such Arrests have been procured by malicious Persons, &amp;c.; No Person arrested compellable to give greater Bond of Appearance than &pound;40; The true Cause of A&bholigct;ion to be set forth in the Process.; 23 H.VI, c.9. &sect;3.; Sheriff enjoined to accept of such Bond.; 23 H. VI. c. 9. &sect; 3</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS by the Ancient and Fundamentall Lawes of this Realme in case where any person is sued
impleaded or arrested by any Writ Bill or Processe issuing out of [any of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] His Majesties Courts of Records
att Westminster in any Common Plea att the Suit of any common person the true cause of A&bholigct;ion ought to be
sett forth and particularly expressed in such Writ Bill or Process whereby the Defendant may have certaine
knowledge of the cause of the Suit and the Officer who shall execute such Writ Bill or Processe may know how
to take Security for the Apparance of the Defendant to the same and the Sureties for such Apparances may
rightly understand for what cause they become engaged And whereas there is a great complaint of the people
of this Realme that for diverse yeares now last past very many of His Majesties good Subje&bholigct;s have beene arrested
upon generall Writs of trespass quare claus&umacr; fregit Bills of Middlesex Latitat's and other like Writts issued out of
the Courts of King Bench and Common Pleas not expressing any particular or certain cause of A&bholigct;ion and thereupon
kept prisoners for a long time for want of Bayle Bonds with Sureties for Apparances having beene demaunded in
so great sums that few or none have dared to be Security for the Apparances of such persons soe arrested and
imprisoned although in truth there hath beene little or no cause of A&bholigct;ion and often times there are no such persons
who were named Plaintiffs but those Arrests have beene many times procured by malitious persons to vex and
oppress the Defendants or to force from them unreasonable and unjust compositions for obtaining theire Liberty
And by such evill pra&bholigct;ices many men have beene and are daily undone and destroyed in theire Estates without
possibility of having reparation the A&bholigct;ors imployed in such pra&bholigct;ises having beene for the most part poore and
lurking persons and theire a&bholigct;ings so secret that it hath beene found very difficult to make true discoveries or
proofe thereof For remedy and prevention of which so great growing evills and mischeifs and alsoe for discouraging
all frivolous and unjust Suits and causeless Arrests for the future Bee it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majesty by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present
Parliament assembled and by Authority of the same That from and after the Twelfth day of February in the
yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and one no person or persons who shall happen to be
arrested by any Sheriff Under-Sheriff Coroner Steward or Bailiff of any Franchise or Liberty or by any other
Officer Minister Under-bailiff or other person or persons whatsoever within this Realm having or pretending to
have Authority or Warrant in that behalfe by force or colour of any Writt Bill or Processe issuing or to be
issuing out of His Majesties said Courts of Kings Bench and Common Pleas or either of them in which said
Writt Bill or Processe the certainty and true cause of A&bholigct;ion is not expressed particularly and for which the
Defendant or Defendants in such Writt Bill or Process named is and are bailable by the Statute in that behalf
made in the Three and twentieth yeare of the Reigne of the late King Henry the Sixth shall be forced or
compelled to give Security or to enter into Bond with Sureties for the Apparances of such person or persons
soe arrested att the day and place in the said Writt Bill or Process specified or contained in any penalty or sum
or sums of money exceeding the sum of Forty pounds of lawfull money of England to be conditioned for such
Apparances And that all Sheriffs and other Officers and Ministers aforesaid shall lett to Bail and deliver out of
Prison and from theire and everie of theire Custodies respe&bholigct;ively all and every person and persons whatsoever by
them or any of them arrested upon any such Writ Bill or Processe wherein the certaintie and true cause of
A&bholigct;ion is not particularly expressed upon Security in the s&bhouov;m of Forty pounds and noe more given for Apparance
of such person or persons so arrested unto the said Sheriff or Officer aforesaid according to the said Statute in
the said three and twentieth yeare of the Reigne of the said late King Henry the Sixth in that behalfe made and
provided.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Upon Appearance in Court, such Bonds and all Amercements discharged.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Plaintiff not declaring.; Nonsuit and Costs.; 23 H. VIII. c. 15</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid that upon Apparance to be entred in the Terme
wherein such Writt Bill or Processe is retornable with the respe&bholigct;ive Officer in that behalfe for the said person
or persons by Attorney or Attorneys in the said respe&bholigct;ive Courts from whence the said Writ Bill or Processe
issued unto such Writ Bill or Processe the Bond or Bonds soe given for Apparance thereunto be and are hereby
satisfied and discharged And that after such Apparance so entred no Amerciaments be set or estreted upon or against
any Sheriff or other Officer aforesaid or any other person whatsoever concerning the want of such Apparance and
unlesse the Plaintiff or Plaintiffs in any such Writ Bill or Processe named shall put into the Court from whence
such Writ Bill or Process did issue his or theire Bill or Declara&bhocotil;n against the person or persons soe arrested in
some &bhopubr;sonall A&bholigct;ion or Eje&bholigct;ione firme of Lands or Tenements before the end of the Term next following after
Apparance that then a Non-suite for want of a Declara&bhocotil;n may be entred against the said Plaintiff or Plaintiffs
in the said Courts respe&bholigct;ively And that every Defendant in every such Writ Bill or Process named shall or may
have Judgement to recover Costs against every such Plaintiffe or Plaintiffs to bee assessed taxed and levied in
such manner and according as it is provided by the Statute for Costs made in the three and twentieth yeare of
the Reigne of the late King Henry the Eighth Any former or other A&bholigct; Statute Ordinance Law Custome Order
Course or Usage of either of the said Courts to the contrary thereof heretofore had made admitted or used in
any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for Capias utlagatum and other Process.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwaies that this A&bholigct; nor any Clause or thing herein before specified or conteined shall not extend
nor be construed or taken to extend unto any Arrests hereafter to be made upon or by vertue of any Writ of
Capias ut lagatum Attachment upon Rescous or Attachment upon any Contempt or of any Attachment of Priviledge
at the Suite of any priviledged person or of any other Attachment for contempt whatsoever issuing or to be
issuing out of either of the said Courts although there be no particular certainty of the cause of A&bholigct;ion expressed
or conteined in the said Writs But that neverthelesse no Sheriffe nor Under Sheriff nor any of the Officers or
Ministers aforesaid shall discharge any person or persons taken upon any Writ of Capias ut lagatum out of Custody
without a lawfull Supersedeas first had and received for the same and that upon the said Writs of Attachment such
lawfull course be taken for Security for Apparance therein as hath beene heretofore used Any thing herein before
expressed to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Recital that Prisoners in the Fleet continue there to delay their Creditors.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">How such Persons may be sued to Judgment in the Common Pleas.; Judgment by Nihil dicit.; Good cause of Detention to Warden.; Warden offending,; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And whereas many persons out of ill intent to delay theire Creditors from recovering theire just Debts continue
Prisoners in the Fleet whoe cannot bee proceeded against in such manner as they might bee if they were att large
Nowe for the better enabling all persons to recover theire just Debts and Demaunds against such Prisoners Be. it
further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every person or persons whatsoever who now hath or have or
which att any time hereafter shall have cause of any personall A&bholigct;ion against any person being a Prisoner in the
Prison of the Fleet may sue forth an Originall Writt upon his or theire cause of A&bholigct;ion And that a Writ of Habeas
Corpus bee granted to every such person or persons being Plaintiff or Plaintiffs desireing the same to be dire&bholigct;ed
to the Warden of the same Prison to have the Body of such Prisoner before the Justices of the Common Pleas att
some certaine day in any Term to answere the said Plaintiff or Plaintiffs upon his or theire said cause of A&bholigct;ion
And [that<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] if the said Plaintiff or Plaintiffs att the said day put into the said Court his or theire Declara&bhocotil;n according
to the said Originall Writt against the said Prisoner being present att the Barr the said Prisoner shall be bound to
appeare in person or to put in an Attorney to appeare for him in the said A&bholigct;ion And unlesse the said Defendant
plead upon a Rule given to be out at Eight dayes at the least after such Apparance Judgement by Nihil dicit may
be entred against such Defendant as appearing in Person which shall be good &amp; effe&bholigct;uall in Law And such
charge in Court by Declara&bhocotil;ns signified by Rule unto the said Warden shall be a good cause of detention of such
prisoner in his Custody from which he shall not be discharged without a lawfull Supersedeas or Rule of Court
And if the said Warden shall do otherwise he shall bee responsible to the Court and to the party greived for
Damages by A&bholigct;ion upon the Case to bee brought against him for discharging such prisoner.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Certain Judicial Writs good, though there be not Fifteen Days between the Test and Return.</head>
			<para id="p8">And whereas very many Suits commenced by Originall Writts have beene protra&bholigct;ed and long delayed from
Judgment and Execu&bhocotil;n by reason of the necessity of haveing Fifteene dayes att the least betweene the dayes of
the Teste and the dayes of Return of Writs now used in personall A&bholigct;ions and alsoe in A&bholigct;ions of Eje&bholigct;ione firme
for Lands and Tenements For remedy thereof and for the more easie expediteing Trialls and the better and more
speedie executeing of Judgements for the time to come Bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That
in all A&bholigct;ions of Debt and all other personall A&bholigct;ions whatsoever and alsoe in all A&bholigct;ions of Eje&bholigct;ione firme for
Lands or Tenements nowe depending or which att any time hereafter shall bee depending by Originall Writ in
either of his Majesties Courts aforesaid after any issue therein joyned to be tried by a Jury and alsoe after any
Judgement had or obtained or to be had or obtained in either of the Courts aforesaid in any such A&bholigct;ion as aforesaid.
there shall not need to bee fifteene dayes betweene the Teste day and day of Returne of any Writ or Writs
of Venire facias Habeas Corpora Jurato[rum] or Distringas Juratores Writs of Fieri facias or Writs of Capias ad
satisfaciendum And that the want of Fifteene dayes betweene the Teste day and the day of Retorn of any such
Writ shall not bee nor shall be assigned taken or adjudged to be any matter or cause of Error Any Law Custome
Statute Course or Usage to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Proviso for certain Process to Outlawry and against Bail.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided neverthelesse that this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein conteined shall not extend or be construed to
extend to any Writ of Capias ad satisfaciendum whereon a Writ of Exigent after Judgement is to be awarded
nor to Capias ad satisfaciendum against the Defendant in order to make any Baile liable But that the same continue
and be as if this A&bholigct; had never beene made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. 3. Jac. I. c.8. recited.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">In A&bholigct;ions of Debt for Tithes, Trover, Covenant, Detinue, and Trespass, no Execution staid by Writ of Error, unless Bail, &amp;c. 2 (2&amp;3) E.VI. c. 13</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">And whereas by an A&bholigct; of Parliament made in the third yeare of the Reigne of our late Soveraigne Lord
King James of blessed memory a very good Law was made for avoiding unnecessary delaies of Execution whereby
it is Ena&bholigct;ed That no Execution shall be stayed or delayed upon or by any Writ of Error or Supersedeas thereupon
to be sued for the reversing of any Judgement to be given in any A&bholigct;ion or Bill of Debt upon any single Bond
for Debt or upon any Obliga&bhocotil;n with Condi&bhocotil;n for payment of money onely or upon any A&bholigct;ion or Bill of Debt
for Rent or upon any Contra&bholigct; sued in any of His [Hignes<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Courts of [Records<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] att Westminster or in the Counties
Palatine of Chester Lancaster or Durham or in His Highnesse Courts of Great Sessions in any of the Twelve Shires
of Wales unless such person or persons in whose name or names such Writt of Error shall be brought with twoe
sufficient Sureties such as the Court wherein such Judgement is or shall be given shall allow of shall first before
such stay made or Supersedeas to be awarded be bound to the party for whom any such Judgement was or should
bee given by Recognizance to be acknowledged in the same Court in double the Sum adjudged to be recovered by
the said former Judgement to prosecute the said Writt of Error with effe&bholigct; and alsoe to satisfie and pay (if the said
Judgement shall be affirmed) all and singuler the Debts Damages and Costs adjudged or to be adjudged upon
the former Judgement And all Costs and Damages to be alsoe awarded for the same delaying of Execution
which Law hath beene found by experience to bee very good and beneficiall to the Commonwealth And forasmuch
as divers other Cases within the same mischeife by delayes and staying of Execu&bhocotil;n by Writs of Error and
Supersedeas thereupon are not provided for by the said Statute For further Remedy against delayes and staying
of Executions in the severall A&bholigct;ions hereafter specified. Be it further Ena&bholigct;ed and Ordeined by the Authority
aforesaid That from and after the twentieth day of January in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
sixty and one no Execution shall be stayed in any of the Courts aforesaid by any Writ or Writs of Error or
Supersedeas thereupon after any Verdi&bholigct; and Judgement thereupon obteined in any A&bholigct;ion of Debt grounded upon
the Statute made in the second yeare of the Reigne of the late King Edward the Sixth for not setting forth of
Tythes nor in any A&bholigct;ion upon the case upon any promise for payment of money A&bholigct;ions sur Trover A&bholigct;ions of
Covenant Detinue and Trespasse unlesse such Recognizance and in such manner as by the said recited former A&bholigct;
is directed shall be first acknowledged in the said Court where such Judgement is given.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. If Judgment affirmed on Writ of Error.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And be it alsoe Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any person or persons after the said day shall sue
or prosecute any Writ or Writs of Error for reversall of any Judgement whatsoever given after any Verdi&bholigct; in any
of the Courts aforesaid and the said Judgement shall afterwards be affirmed then every such person or persons
shall pay unto the Defendant or Defendants in the said Writ or Writs of Error his or theire double Costs to bee
assessed by the Court where such Writ of Error shall be depending for the delaying of Execution</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Proviso for A&bholigct;ion Popular, Indi&bholigct;ment, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided nevertheles That this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein conteyned shall not extend to any A&bholigct;ion Popular
nor unto any other A&bholigct;ion which is or hereafter shall bee brought upon any penall Law or Statute (except Debt
for not setting out Tythes as aforesaid) nor to any Indi&bholigct;ment Presentment Inquisi&bhocotil;n Informa&bhocotil;n or Appeal Any
thing herein before expressed to the contrary thereof notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Highnes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Record <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


