<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47306" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for ordering the Forces in the several Counties of this Kingdom. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II p. 1. nu. 3]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that the Government of the Militia, &amp;c. is in the King, and that Parliament cannot pretend of the same.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The King may issuse Commissions of Lieutenancy.; Power of Lieutenants to arm Troops; to appoint and give Commissions to Officers.; and to present Names of Deputy Lieutenants.; The King may displace such Officers.; Lieutenants and Deputy Lieutenants may train, &amp;c. Troops</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Forasmuch as within all His Majesties Realmes and Dominions the sole and supreame Power Government
Command and Disposition of the Militia and of all Forces by Sea and Land and of all Forts and places of
Strength is and by the Laws of England ever was the undoubted Right of His Majesty and His Royall Predecessors
Kings and Queenes of England and that both or either of the Houses of Parliament cannot nor ought to &bhopcrl;tend
to the same nor can nor lawfully may raise or levy any War offensive or defensive against His Majesty His
Heires or lawfull Successors and yet the contrary thereof hath of late yeares beene pra&bholigct;ised almost to the ruine
and destru&bholigct;ion of this Kingdome and during the late usurped Governments many evil and rebellious principles
have beene instilled into the minds of the people of this Kingdome which may breake forth unless prevented to
the disturbance of the peace and quiet thereof Bee it therefore declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons in Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same That the Kings most Excellent Majestie His Heires and Successors
shall and may from time to time as occasion shall require issue forth severall Commissions of Lieutenancy to
such persons as His Majesty His Heires and Successors shall thinke fit to be His Majesties Leiutenants for the
sevcrall &amp; respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cities and places of England &amp; Dominion of Wales and Town of Berwick upon
Tweed which Leiutenants shall have full power and authority to call togeather all such persons at such times
and to arm and array them in such manner as is hereafter experessed and declared and to form them into
Companies Troops and Regiments and in case of Insurre&bholigct;ion Rebellion or Invasion them to lead condu&bholigct; and
imploy or cause to be [lead<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] condu&bholigct;ed and imployed as well within the said severall Counties Cities and places
for which they shall be commissionated respe&bholigct;ively as alsoe into any other the Counties and places aforesaid for
suppressing of all such Insurre&bholigct;ions and Rebelions and repelling of Invasions as may happen to bee according
as they shall from time to time receive dire&bholigct;ions from His Majesty His Heires and Successors and that the said
respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants shall have full power and authority from time to time [to constitute appointe and give
Commissions to such persons as they shall thinke fitt to be Colonels Majors Captaines and other Commission
Officers of the said persons so to be armed arrayed and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] weaponed and to &bhopcrl;sent to His Majestie His Heires
and Successors the names of such person and persons as they shall thinke fitt to be Deputy Leiutenants and upon
His Majesties approba&bhocotil;n of them shall give them Deputa&bhocotil;ns accordingly Alwaies understood that His Majesty His
Heires and Successors have power and authority to dire&bholigct; and order otherwise and accordingly att His and theire
pleasure may appoint and commissionate or displace such Officers Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding
And that the said Leiutenants respe&bholigct;ively and in theire absence out of the Precin&bholigct;s and Limits of theire respe&bholigct;ive
Leiutenancies or otherwise by theire dire&bholigct;ions the said Deputy Leiutenant&bholngs; during theire said respe&bholigct;ive Depurations or
any two or more of them shall have power from time to time to train exercise and put in readines and alsoe to lead
and condu&bholigct; the persons so to be armed arrayed and weaponed by the dire&bholigct;ions and to the intents and purposes
as is hereafter expressed and declared</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Lieutenants. &amp;c. may charge Persons with Horsemen, Foot Soldiers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">What Estate shall render Persons liable to be charged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the providing Horse and Armes and Furniture thereunto belonging for the arming and weaponing the
persons aforesaid and alsoe for the defraying and paying the necessary charges thereunto belonging in manner as
hereafter followeth Be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That the said respective Leiutenants within the severall Counties Cities
and places, for which they are nominated respe&bholigct;ively and theire Deputies or the maior part of such Leiutenants
and Deputy Leiutenant&bholngs; then present or in the absence of the Leiutenant or Leiutenants the maior part of the
Deputy Leiutenants then &bhopcrl;sent which maior part shall bee three att the least have hereby full Power and Authority
to charge any person with Horse Horsman and Armes or with Foot Souldier and Armes in the same County
Shire City Burrough or Towne Corporate where his her or theire Estates lie having respe&bholigct; unto and not exceeding
the limitations and proportions hereafter mentioned (that is to say) No person shall be charged with finding a
Horse Horseman and Armes unless such person or persons have a Revenue of Five hundered pounds by the yeare
in possession or have an Estate of Six thousand pounds in goods or money besides the furniture of his or theire
houses and so proportionably for a greater Estate in lands in possession or goods as the respe&bholigct;ive Lieutenants and
theire Deputies as aforesaid in theire discretions shall see cause and thinke reasonable And they are not to charge any
person with finding a Foot Souldier and Armes that hath not a yearely Revenue of Fifty pounds in possession or a
personal Estate of Six hundred pounds in goods or moneys (other then the stocke upon the ground) and after the
aforesaid rate proportionably for a greater or lesser Revenue or Estate Nor shall they charge any person with the
finding both of Horse and Foot in the same County.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Persons chargeable to find a Horseman &amp;c. not chargeable for the same Estate for a Foot Soldier.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Lieutenants, &amp;c. may join Persons charegable</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">Provided That no person chargeable by this A&bholigct; to finds [a<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] House and Horseman with Armes or to be
contributory towards finding an Horse and Horseman with Armes shall for the same Estate be chargeable towards
finding a Foot Souldier with Armes or contributory thereunto And it shall be lawfull to and for the respe&bholigct;ive
Leiutenants and Deputies or any three or more of them as aforesaid to impose the finding and providing of Horse.
Horseman and Armes as aforesaid by joyning two or three or more persons togeather in the charge as to theire
judgement shall appeare most conducible to the service of this Kingdome</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Persons not having &pound;100 per Annum real, or &pound;1,200 of personal Estate, not liable to find Horsemen. Lieutenants, &amp;c. may hear Complaints.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided That no person that hath not One hundred pounds per annu[m] in possession in Lands Tenements or
Hereditaments Leasehold or Copihold or Twelve hundred pounds personal Estate shall be compellable to contribute in
finding any Horse and Horseman with Armes And the said respective Leiutenants and Deputies or any three
or more of them shall have power to heare Complaints and examine Witnesses upon Oath (which Oath they have
hereby power to administer) and [to<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] give redresse according to the merits of the cause in matters relating to the
execution of this A&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Lieutenants, &amp;c. may dire&bholigct; Persons charged to make Allowance to Troopers, &amp;c. on Exercise.</head>
			<para id="p8">Be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That the said Leiutenants and Deputies or any three or more of them in theire several
Counties and places respe&bholigct;ively shall require and dire&bholigct; all persons so charged as aforesaid with Horse Horsemen
and Armes to allow Two shillings by the day to the Troopers that serve with theire Horse and Armes for the
maintenance of the Man, and Horse and Twelve pence a day for the Foot Souldiers (if they serve not in theire
owne persons) for so many dayes as they shall be absent from theire Dwellings and Callings by occasion of Muster
or Exercise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Lieutenants may lay Rates for Ammunition.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">12 Car. II. c.29.; How and by whom such Monies assessed and paid.; In case of Invasion, such Persons to provide Soldiers with pay in hand; Provision for Repayment thereof, &amp;c.; Proviso where Month's Pay advanced</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And for furnishing Ammunition and other Necessaries the said respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants and Deputies or any three
or more of them shall have power to lay fitting Rates upon the respe&bholigct;ive Counties and Places not exceeding in
the whole in any one yeare the proportion of a fourth part of One Moneths Assessment in each County after the
Rate of Seaventy thousand pounds by the Moneth now or late charged by an A&bholigct; intituled An A&bholigct; for the raising
of Seventy thousand pounds for the further Supply of His Majesty which Moneys are to be assessed colle&bholigct;ed and
paid by such persons and, according to such Dire&bholigct;ions as shall be given from time to time by the said respe&bholigct;ive
Leiutenants &amp; Deputies or any three or more of them under the like penalties and by the like wayes &amp; meanes as
are prescribed in the said A&bholigct; for the Seventy thousand pounds by the Moneth And in case of Invasions Insurre&bholigct;ions
or Rebellions whereby occasion shall be to draw out such Souldiers into a&bholigct;uall Service the persons so charged as
aforesaid shall provide each theire Souldier respe&bholigct;ively with pay in hand not exceeding one moneths pay as shall be
in that behalfe dire&bholigct;ed by the said respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants and in theire absence as aforesaid or otherwise by theire
dire&bholigct;ions by theire Deputies or any two or more of them for repayment of which said Moneys and for satisfac&bhocotil;n of
the Officers for theire pay during such time not exceeding one moneth as aforesaid as they shall be with theire
Souldiers in such said a&bholigct;ual service It is hereby declared That provision shall be made for the same by His Majesty
His Heires and Successors out of His or Theire Publique Treasury or Revenue Nevertheles it is hereby further
Provided and Ena&bholigct;ed That in case a moneths pay shall be provided and advanced as aforesaid that no person who
shall have advanced his proportion thereof shall be charged with any other like moneths payment untill he or they
shall have beene reimbursed the said Moneths pay &amp; so from time to time the Moneths pay by him or them last
before provided and advanced as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Lieutenants may charge Carts, &amp;c. for Carriage of Powder, &amp;c. and make an Allowance;</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">may imprison Mutineers; and may fine or imprison Soldiers not doing their Duty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And be it Ena&bholigct;ed that the said Leiutenants and theire Deputies or the Cheife Officers upon the place in the
respe&bholigct;ive Counties and places as aforesaid may charge Carts Wagons Wayns and Horses for the carrying of
Powder Match Bullet and other Materials allowing six pence a Mile outward only to every such Cart Wagon
and Wayn with five Horses or six Oxen and so propor&bhocotil;nably And for every Horse imployed out of Wagon or
Cart for the uses aforesaid one penny so taken upon the Martching of any Regiment Company or Troope upon
occasion of Invasion Insurre&bholigct;ion or Rebellion And that the said Leiutenants or Deputies or the Cheife Officers
upon the place shall and may imprison Mutineers and such Souldiers as doe not theire Duties as Souldiers at
the day of theire Musters and Training and shall and may infli&bholigct; for punishment for every such Offence any
pecuniary Mul&bholigct; not exceeding five shillings or the penalty of Imprisonment without Bail or Mainprise not exceeding
twenty dayes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Persons charged by Lieutenants, refusing to provide Horsemen, &amp;c. or to pay, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Lieutenants may infli&bholigct; a Penalty, and levy such by Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed if any person or persons so to be assessed or charged by the said Leiutenants and
Deputies or any three or more of them respe&bholigct;ively shall refuse or negle&bholigct; by a reasonable time to be appointed to
provide and furnish such sufficient Horse and Horseman Horses and Horsemen Armes and other Furniture or to
pay such sum or sums of Money towards the providing and furnishing as aforesaid That then it shall and may be
lawfull to and for the respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants &amp; Deputies or any three or more of them for every such Offence from
time to time to infli&bholigct; a penalty upon such persons not exceeding twenty pounds And alsoe by Warrant under theire
or any three or more of theire hands and Seales to levy such s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money or the value of such Horse
or Horses Armes and Furniture and such penalty infli&bholigct;ed by Distresse and sale of the goods of the person or
persons so negle&bholigct;ing or refusing rendring the overplus to the party soe distrained all necessary charge in levying
thereof being first dedu&bholigct;ed And it is declared that the same be imployed to the same uses in default whereof the
same was imposed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Persons armed embezzling, &amp;c. Horse, Arms, &amp;c.; Lieutenants may imprison.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Persons not appearing to serve,; Lieutenants, &amp;c. may imprison, or infli&bholigct; a Penalty.; Persons assessed not delivering in Horse, &amp;c.; Lieutenant, &amp;c. may infli&bholigct; a Penalty, to be levied by Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That if any person or persons so to be armed arrayed and weaponed shall detaine or
imbezil his Horse Armes or Furniture wherewith he ought to serve or is intrusted that it shall and may be lawfull to
and for the said respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants and in theire absence as aforesaid or otherwise by theire dire&bholigct;ions to and for
theire Deputies or any two or more of them to imprison such person and persons till he or they have made satisfa&bholigct;ion
for the Horse Armes or other furniture so by him detained or imbezelled And alsoe that if any person so to be
armed horsed or weaponed as aforesaid shall not appeare and serve compleatly furnished with Horse and Armes and
other Furniture wherewith he is intrusted at the beat of Drum sound of Trumpet or other Summons that then and soe
often it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants and in theire absence as aforesaid or
otherwise by theire dire&bholigct;ions to and for theire Deputies or any two or more of them if the default be in the person or
persons so intrusted to imprison such person or persons for the space of five dayes without Baile or Mainprize or to
infli&bholigct; the penalty if a Horseman not exceeding twenty shillings and if a Foot man not exceeding ten shillings to be paid
downe without delay or forbearance And if any person or persons so assessed or charged as aforesaid shall refuse or
negle&bholigct; to send in or deliver his Horse Armes or other Furniture upon such summons or other notice as aforesaid
That then and so often it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants &amp; theire Deputies or any
three or more of them to infli&bholigct; a penalty not exceeding five pounds to be levied by Distresse and sale of the Goods
of such person or persons so refusing as aforesaid rendring the overplus to the party distrained necessary Charges for
levying being first dedu&bholigct;ed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Power to Lieutenants, &amp;c. to examine upon Oath.</head>
			<para id="p17">And for the better Discovery of the ability of the persons so to bee assessed and charged and (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) all Misdemeanors
tending to the hinderance of the service aforesaid the said respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants and theire Deputies or any three or
more of them are hereby enabled to examine upon Oath such person or persons as they shall judge necessary or
convenient or shall be produced by the party charged or accused other then the persons themselves [soe<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] to bee
assessed and accused</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Lieutenants to appoint Treasurers, Clerks, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">who are to account every Six Months.; Accounts to be Certified to the Privy Council.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p19">And for the better and more speedy execution of the &bhopcrl;misses bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the said respe&bholigct;ive
Leiutenants shall bee and are hereby required to appoint one or more Treasurer or Treasurers Clerke or Clerkes for
receiving &amp; paying such moneyes as shall be levied by vertue hereof of all which Receipts and Disbursements thereof
the said Treasurer Clerke and Clerkes are every six Monethes to give theire Accompts in writing and upon Oath
to the said Leiutenants and theire Deputies or any three or more of them which Oath they have hereby power to
administer And the said Accompt soe to be taken shall be forthwith certified to the Lords of His Majesties most
Honorable Privy Councell and a Duplicate thereof shall be certified to the Justices of [the<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Peace att the next
Generall Quarter Sessions</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII.; Deputy Lieutenants to obey Lieutenants.</head>
			<para id="p20">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Deputy Leiutenants shall observe and obey such Orders and Dire&bholigct;ions as
they shall from time to time receive from the respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants for the putting in execution the Powers given
by this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Lieutenants or Deputy Lieutenants may by Warrant employ Persons to search and seize Arms.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Hours at which Search may be made.; If Search resisted, Force may be used.; Proviso for Peers.; Arms seized may be restored.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p22">And for the better securing the Peace of the Kingdome be it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained and the respe&bholigct;ive
Leiutenants or any twoe or more of theire Deputies are hereby enabled &amp; authorized from time to time by Warrant
under theire Hands and Seales to employ such Person or Persons as they shall thinke fitt (of which a Commissioned
Officer and the Constable or his Deputy or the Tythingman or in the absence of the Constable and his Deputy and
Tythingman some other Person bearing Office within the Parish where the Search shall be shall be two) to search for
and seize all Armes in the custody or possession of any person or persons whom the said Leiutenants or any two or
more of theire Deputies shall judge dangerous to the Peace of the Kingdome and to secure such Armes for the
service aforesaid and thereof from time to time to give Accounts to the said respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants and in theire
absence as aforesaid or otherwise by theire dire&bholigct;ions to theire Deputies or any two or more of them. [Provided that
no such Search be made in any house or houses between Sun setting and Sun rising other then in Cities and theire
Suburbs and Townes Corporate Market Townes and houses within the bills of Mortality where it shall and may be
lawfull to search in the night time by Warrant as aforesaid if the Warrant shall so dire&bholigct; and in case of resistance to
enter by force And that no dwelling house of any Peere of this Realme be searched by vertue of this A&bholigct; but by
immediate Warrant from His Majesty under His Sign Manual or in the presence of the Leiutenant or one of the Deputy
Leiutenants of the same County or Riding And that in all places and houses whatsoever where search is to be made
as aforesaid it shall and may be lawfull in case of resistance to enter by force And that the Armes so seised may bee
restored to the Owners againe if the said Leiutenants or in theire absence as aforesaid theire Deputies or any two or
more of them shall so thinke fitt.<ref idref="n8">8</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Constables, &amp;c. to be aiding Lieutenants, &amp;c. in execution of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Persons who have executed Commissions of Lieutenancy indemnified</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And be it Ena&bholigct;ed that all high Constables petty Constables and other Officers and Ministers within the said
Counties Cities Parishes and places aforesaid be and are hereby required to be aiding and assisting to the said respe&bholigct;ive
Leiutenants and theire Deputies or any of them in execution of the premisses. And that all and every person and
Persons who shall a&bholigct; or do any thing in execution thereof shall be hereby saved harmeles and indemnified And alsoe
that all and every person and persons who have heretofore a&bholigct;ed or done any thing in execution of any Commission or
Commissions of Leiutenancy issued by the Kings Majesty that now is or by colour of them or any of them [or
touching, or concerning the same or any of them <ref idref="n6">6</ref>] or relating thereunto since the seaventh day of May One thousand
six hundred sixty and one until the twentieth day of May One thousand six hundred sixty and two shall be and are
hereby saved harmeles and indemnified in that behalfe</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Lieutenants to send. Notice of Charge to Persons charged in Counties, &amp;c. where they do not reside, or their Tenants, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Tenants or Servants receiving such Notice to convey the same to Landlord, &amp;c. and bring answer to Lieutenants; if Landlords negle&bholigct; to provide, Tenants to do so; if Tenants refuse, Lieutenants, &amp;c.; may levy Penalties.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p26">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained That where any person or persons shall be charged by vertue of
this A&bholigct; [to find<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] a Horse &amp; Horseman Horses and Horsemen and Armes or Foot Souldier and Armes in such
County City or place where he or they do not reside or inhabit That then and in such cases the respe&bholigct;ive
Leiutenants and Deputies or any three or more of them shall send Notice of every such charge if such person
have any land in his owne occupa&bhocotil;n to such person as he, doth imploy as his servant in managing the same
And in case all his Lands or other Estate be demised and to farme let then to one or two of the most sufficient
Tenant or Tenants who shall have the same in theire occupation who are hereby required forthwith with all

convenient speed to convey the same to theire Master or Landlord respe&bholigct;ively And within such time as shall bee
appointed in that behalfe bring an Accompt of theire Master or Landlords answer to the respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants
and Deputies or any three or more of them and upon negle&bholigct; or refusall of the Landlord to provide such Horse
and Horseman Horses &amp; Horsemen and Armes or Foot Souldier and Armes as is duly charged upon him [according
to the Rates mentioned in this A&bholigct; for the yearely Rent reserved upon every demise or other grant and not
otherwise<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] within the time limited for that purpose that then the said Tenant or Tenants shall provide and do as
the Landlord in that behalfe ought to have done And if the said Tenant or Tenants shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to
provide such Horse and Horseman Horses and Horsemen and Armes or Foot Souldier and Armes as are charged
upon his or theire Landlords within the time limitted that then and upon every such default it shall and may
be lawfull to and for the said respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants and in theire absence as aforesaid or otherwise by theire
dire&bholigct;ions to and for theire Deputies or any two or more of them by Warrant under theire hands and Seales
to levy all such penalties as are appointed by this A&bholigct; by distresse and sale of the offenders goods rendring the
overplus to the party distrained</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Tenants may dedu&bholigct; Rate paid by them and charged on Landlord out of Rent.</head>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">Tenants indemnified</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p28">And it is hereby ordained and ena&bholigct;ed that it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Tenant or Tenants
to defalke out of such Rent as shall be next due to his or theire Landlord all such Money as the said Tenant or
Tenants shall necessarily lay out or expend in providing such Horse and Horseman Horses and Horsemen and
Armes or Foot Souldier and Armes as are charged upon his or theire Landlord or shall pay or be leavyed upon
him or them by distresse for any default in manner as aforesaid Any condition reservation Covenant or Contra&bholigct; for
the payment of his or theire Rent to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding And for soe doeing the said Tenant
or Tenants shall be indempnified by Authority of this A&bholigct; unlesse the Landlord or Landlords shall make it appeare
within two Monethes after such levying such penalties before the respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants and in theire absence as
aforesaid or otherwise by theire dire&bholigct;ions before theire Deputies or any two or more of them that the default
and penalty was occasioned by the wilfull negle&bholigct; of the said Tenant or Tenants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Peers not to a&bholigct; as Lieutenants or Deputy Lieutenants without taking Oaths, &amp;c. which Six Lords of the Council may administer.</head>
			<para id="p29">Provided also that no person being a Peer of this Realme shall be capable of a&bholigct;ing or serving as Leiutenant
or Deputy Leiutenant by vertue of this A&bholigct; unless he or they shall first before six [of the <ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Lords of His Majesties
Privy Council for the time being or such other persons as shall be authorized by His Majesty to administer the
same take the Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy and alsoe this Oath following I. A. B. doc declare and beleive that
it is not lawfull upon any pretence whatsoever to take Armes against the King And that I doe abhor that
traiterous Position that Armes may be taken by His Authority against His Person or against those that are
Commissioned by Him in pursuance of such military Commissions So helpe me God Which Oathes they have
hereby power to administer</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. The like Provision as to Persons under Degree of a Peer.</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Justice of Peace may administer such Oaths; and Lieutenants, &amp;c. to Officers and Soldiers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p31">And that no person being under the degree of a Peer of this Realm shall be capable of a&bholigct;ing as
Leiutenant Deputy Leiutenant Officer or Souldier by vertue of this A&bholigct; unlesse he or they shall first take the
Oathes of Allegiance and Supremacy and this Oath following I. A. B. doe declare and beleive that it is not lawfull
upon any pretence whatsoever to take Armes against the King And that I doe abhor that traiterous Position that
Armes may be taken by His Authority against His Person or against those that are commissioned by Him in
pursuance of such military Commissions. So help me God. Which Oathes any one Justice of Peace of the
respe&bholigct;ive Counties and places aforesaid is enabled to administer to such respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenant as is not a Peer of
this Realm and the said Leiutenant or any one Justice of Peace of the respe&bholigct;ive Counties and places aforesaid is
enabled to administer to the respe&bholigct;ive Deputy Leiutenants not being Peers and the said respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants and
in theire absence as aforesaid or otherwise by theire dire&bholigct;ions when they are not absent theire Deputies or any two
of them shall and are hereby enabled to administer the said Oaths to the said Officers and Souldiers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Trained Bands, &amp;c. now raised to continue till 25th March 1663.</head>
			<para id="p32">And to the end there may be some convenient time to put in Execution the Powers of this A&bholigct; and preparing
an Establishment according to the same be it hereby ena&bholigct;ed That the Trained Bands and Forces now a&bholigct;ually
raised and in being shall so continue in each respe&bholigct;ive City and County of England and Wales untill the five
and twentieth [day<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] of March One thousand six hundred sixty and three and no longer unlesse an Establishment
according to this A&bholigct; be no sooner had Any thing in this present A&bholigct; to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Times for Training, Exercise, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">Single Companies how long to be continued in Exercise.; Ammunition to be brought to Muster.; Arms offensive and defensive described.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p34">And it is hereby declared and ena&bholigct;ed That the ordinary times for training exerciseing and mustering the Forces
to be raised by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be these following (that is to say) the General Muster and Exercise of
Regiments not above once a Yeare the training and exerciseing of single Companies not above foure times a Yeare
unlesse speciall Dire&bholigct;ions be given by His Majestie or His Privy Council And that such single Companies and
Troopes shall not att any one time be continued in Exercise above the space of two dayes And that att a Generall
Muster and Exercise of Regiments no Officer or Souldier shall be constrained to stay for above foure dayes
togeather from theire respe&bholigct;ive habita&bhocotil;ns And that att every such Muster and Exercise every Musqueteer shall
bring with him halfe a pound of Powder [at the charge of such person or persons as provide the said Foote
Souldier and Armes and every Horseman is to bring with him a quarter of a pound of Powder att the charge of
such person or persons as provide the said Horse Horseman and Armes <ref idref="n9">9</ref>] And the Armes offensive and defensive
with the Furniture for Horse are to be as followeth The defensive Arms a Back Breast and Pott and the Breast
and Pott to be Pistoll prooffe The offensive Armes a Sword and a Case of Pistolls the Barrells whereof are not
to be under fourteen Inches in length The furniture for the Horse to be a great Sadle or Padd with Burrs and
Strapps to affix the Houlsters unto a Bitt and Bridle with a Pe&bholigct;orell &amp; Crupper For the Foot a Musqueteer is to
have a Musquett the Barrell whereof is not to be under three Foot in length and the Gage of the Bore to be
for twelve Bulletts to the pound A Coller of Bandeleers with a Sword Provided that all Muster Masters shall
for the &bhopcrl;sent admitt and allow of any Musquetts already made which will beare a Bullett of fourteen to the
pound But no Musquetts which henceforth shall be made are to be allowed of but such as are of the gage for
twelve Bulletts to the pound A Pike man is to be armed with a Pike made of Ash not under sixteene foote in
length (the Head and Foote included) with a Back Breast Head peice and Sword Provided that all Muster Masters
shall for the present admitt and allow of any Pikes already made that are not under fifteen foot in length but
no Pikes which shall be hereafter made are to be allowed of that are under sixteene foot in length</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Militia of the Island of Purbeck.</head>
			<para id="p35">Provided also and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Militia of the Island of Purbeck shall
remaine separate from the County of Dorsett as heretofore hath beene used And that His Majesties Leiutenant of
the said Island and his Deputies or any three or more of them for the time being shall have power for the
levying arraying mustering and condu&bholigct;ing of such number of Foot for the defence of the said Island in such
manner and by such wayes and meanes as heretofore hath beene used And alsoe to use and execute within the
said Island all and every the Powers which by the true Intent of this A&bholigct; any of His Majesties Leiutenants or his
or theire Deputies or any of them might in any respe&bholigct;ive County use or execute</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. In case of apparent Danger, the King may raise the Sum of &pound;70,000 in one Year, and so for Three Years, to be levied by Lieutenants, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">13 Car. II. Stat. 2. c.3.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p37">Provided neverthelesse and be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That in case of apparent danger to the
present Government it shall land may be lawfull for His Majesty att any time or times that the same shall soe
happen during the space of three yeares from the five and twentieth day of June in the Yeare One thousand six
hundred sixty and twoe to raise such sum or sums of money for the defraying of the whole or such part of the
Militia aforesaid as His Majesty shall find himselfe obliged to imploy in order to the quiet and security of this
Nation the said s&bhouov;m not exceeding Seventy thousand pounds in one whole yeare And the same to be raised by
His Majesties Leiutenants or in theire absence as aforesaid by theire Deputies in theire respe&bholigct;ive Counties according
to the rules &amp; dire&bholigct;ions in an A&bholigct; in this Parliament for the raising of Eighteen moneths Assessment after the
rate of Seaventy thousand pounds per mensem as alsoe to continue the space of three yeares from the aforesaid
five and twentieth day of June and no longer Any thing in this A&bholigct; or any other to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Constables, &amp;c. to be reimbursed Monies paid by them for Arms, &amp;c. by Persons refusing to pay Rate.</head>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">Persons refusing to reimburse Constables, &amp;c. Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">Be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed That all Constables Tithingmen or other Officer or Officers who since the Foure and
twentieth of June One thousand six hundred and sixty have paid or disbursed or before the settlement of the
Militia to be established by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall pay or disburse any moneys for buying of Armes or defraying
of Charges of Souldiers sett or to be sett upon theire respe&bholigct;ive Parishes shall be reimbursed the same by those
who have refused to pay theire proportions thereof And in case hee or they shall refuse to pay the same then
to be levyed by distresse and sale of Goods rendring the Overplus to the Owner or Owners by Warrant under
the Hand and Seale of the Leiutenant or Leiutenants or in his or theire absence or otherwise by theire dire&bholigct;ion
when they are not absent of any two of theire Deputies dire&bholigct;ed to the respe&bholigct;ive Constables Tything men or other
Officer or Officers aforesaid of theire respe&bholigct;ive Parishes</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Persons charged not compellable to serve personally, but may find a Substitute.</head>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">Substitute required to serve.; Persons serving to give in at the next Muster their Names and Places of Abode.; Persons listed deserting; being exchanged; quitting Service without Leave.; Penalty &pound;20; Distress or Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">Provided alwaies and it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That no person charged with the finding of
Horse or Foote or with contributing thereunto as aforesaid shall be compellable to serve in his or their proper
person but may according to such proportion as they are or shall respe&bholigct;ively be charged by this A&bholigct; find one
or more fitt or sufficient man or men qualified according to this A&bholigct; to be approved by his or theire Captain
respe&bholigct;ively subje&bholigct; neverthelesse to be altered upon appeal to the Leiutenant or in his absence as aforesaid to his
Deputy Leiutenant&bholngs; or any two of them as there shall be cause And that every such person or persons so found
and provided shall and hereby are required to serve as Souldier and Souldiers in such manner and under such
penalties as are before appointed in this A&bholigct; And that every person or persons who shall serve in his or theire
owne persons who are alsoe to be approved of as aforesaid) or such person or persons as shall be accepted in
his or theire stead shall att the next Muster of such Troope or Company in which he or they are to serve give
in his or theire Christian and Sirnames and places of abode unto such person as the Leiutenant or in his absence
as aforesaid or by his dire&bholigct;ion when he is not absent any two Deputy Leiutenants shall appoint to the end
the same may be listed And that from thenceforth such person so listed shall not be exchanged or desert the
said service or be discharged thereof but by the leave and order of the Leiutenant or two Deputy Leiutenants
or his Captaine upon reasonable (cause subje&bholigct; neverthelesse upon appeale to be determined as aforesaid) first
obtained in writing under his or theire hands and seales under pain that such person departing from the said
service without leave as aforesaid shall forfeit the s&bhouov;m of Twenty pounds to be levyed upon his Goods and
Chattells in such manner as is by this A&bholigct; appointed for the levying of other penalties And for [non<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] payment
or want of distresse then every such person to be comitted to the C&bhooov;mon Goal of the County for any time not
exceeding three monthes without bail or mainprize Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Proviso for Tinners of Devon and Cornwall.</head>
			<para id="p42">Provided alwaies and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That nothing in this A&bholigct; contained shall extend to put any new charge
of Armes upon the Tinners in the Counties of Devon and Cornwall other then the Tax men&bhocotil;ned in the former
Proviso But that the Lord Warden of the Stanaries for the time being in pursuance of His Majesties Commission
in that behalfe and such as he shall commissionate and authorize under him according to the Rules and
Dire&bholigct;ions before men&bhocotil;ned in this A&bholigct; shall and may have and use [the like Powers and array assess arm muster
and exercise the said Tinners within the said Counties and either of them as hath been heretofore used and
according to the ancient Priviledges and Customes of the said Stanaries observing the Rules and Proportions
appointed by this A&bholigct;<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Power to Lieutenants to list and levy the Trained Bands for London;</head>
			<para id="p43">
				<emph type="i">and to impose Rate for Pay, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p44">Provided alwaies and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That His Majesties Leiutenants that are or shall
be commissionated for the Militia of the City of London may and shall continue to list and levy the Trained Bands
&amp; Auxiliaries of the said City as to number and quality of the persons in such manner as was used in forming
the &bhopcrl;sent Forces now raised by His Majesties Commission And in regard of the extraordinary duties which the
Forces of the said City that now are and formerly were raised in order to His Majesties happy Restauration
[haveing <ref idref="n15">15</ref>] of late and may againe be put to for the safety of His Majesties Person and for suppressing or preventing
of Insurre&bholigct;ions that it shall and may be lawfull for his Majesties Leiutenants of the said City by Warrant from
His Majestie to impose and levy yearely in the same so much money as they shall find needfull for defraying the
Arreares of those first raised for His Majesties happy Restauration and the Arreares and necessary charge of those
that now are and shall be raised with the Ammunition and other incident expences of theire Militia in such
manner as the &bhopcrl;sent Assessment is now levied and not exceeding in any one yeare the proportion of One moneths
Tax which the said City now payes towards the Tax of Seaventy thousand pounds by the Moneth and shall be
accomptable for the same as by this A&bholigct; is ordained Any'thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary of this Proviso in any
wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Officers or Soldiers of Trained Bands not compellable to appear at Muster, &amp;c. out of their City or Town.</head>
			<para id="p45">Provided alwaies That no Officer or Souldier of the Militia or Trained Bands belonging to any City Borough
or Towne Corporate being a County of it selfe or to any other Corporation or Port Town who have used and
accustomed to bee mustered only within theire owne &bhopcrl;cin&bholigct;&bholngs; shall be compellable to appeare [out<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] of the
Precin&bholigct;&bholngs; or Liberties of the same City Borough Towne Corporate or Port Towne att any Muster or Exercise
only and every of the said Cities Boroughs Towns Corporate and Port Towns are hereby chargeable to find theire
usuall number of Souldiers unlesse the respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants find cause to lessen the same Any thing in this
A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Proviso for Agreements between Landlords and Tenants concerning Rates, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p46">Provided That this A&bholigct; or any thinge herein contained shall not extend to avoid any Covenant or Agreement
which hath beene or shall be made between any Landlord and Tenant concerning the finding Horses or Armes
or the bearing or paying of any [Taxes Rates or other charges by any Tenant either by generall or speciall
Covenants but that the said Taxes Rates or other Charges shall be borne and paid by all respe&bholigct;ive Tenants
according to the said Covenant&bholngs; and Agreement&bholngs; Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof in any wise
notwithstanding<ref idref="n14">14</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Proviso for Militia of lsle of Wight.</head>
			<para id="p47">Provided That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend to make any alteration in the Isle of
Wight as to the Militia in that place either to raise Horse or Foote within the said Iseland in any other manner
then hath beene formerly and is now used &amp; pra&bholigct;ised there</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Proviso for Tower Hamlets.</head>
			<para id="p48">Provided alsoe and be it ena&bholigct;ed That whereas the Militia of the Tower Division in the County of Middlesex
comonly knowne by the name of the Tower Hamletts are and alwaies have beene under the c&bhooov;mand of His
Majesties Constable or Leiutenant of the Tower for the Service and Preservation of that His Royall Fort that it
shall and may be lawfull for His Majesties Constable or Leiutenant of the Tower for the time being to continue
to levy the Trained Bands of the said Division or Hamlets of the Tower in such manner and form as to the
number and quality of persons as was observed in forming the present Forces thereof Any thing in this A&bholigct; to
the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Proviso as to marching the Subje&bholigct; out of the Kingdom.</head>
			<para id="p49">Provided that neither this A&bholigct; nor any matter or thing therein contained shall be deemed construed or taken
to extend to the giveing or declareing of any power for the transporting of any the Subje&bholigct;s of this Realme or
any way compelling them to march out of this Kingdome otherwise then by the Lawes of England ought to
be done</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. In what manner Peers are to be charged.</head>
			<para id="p50">
				<emph type="i">Monthly Taxes excepted.; Imprisonment of Peers excepted.; Peers making Default; Distress and Proceeding thereon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p51">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no Peer of this Realme shall be charged
with Horse Horsemen and Armes or Foote Souldiers and Armes otherwise or in any other manner then is herein
after expressed (that is to say) that His Majestie His Heires and Successors shall and may from time to time
issue out Commissions under the Great Seale of England to so many Peeres (not fewer then twelve) as His Majestie
His Heires and Successors shall thinke fitt who or any five or more [of <ref idref="n14">14</ref>] them shall have power from time to
time to assess all and every or any the Peers of this Realme according to the limitations and proportions in this
A&bholigct; appointed for the finding of Horse Horsemen and Armes or Foot Souldiers and Armes and for other the
purposes in this A&bholigct; men&bhocotil;ned (except the Monthly Taxes which are to be leavied as is before &bhopcrl;scribed in this
A&bholigct;) and shall have power to put in execu&bhocotil;n all and every the Powers and Authorities of this A&bholigct; as well for
laying Assessments as imposing of Penalties (Imprisonment of the person of any Peere of this Realm only excepted)
which Assessment or Charge so made togeather with such penalties as shall be soe imposed (Imprisonment as
aforesaid only excepted) shall be from time to time respe&bholigct;ively certified to the respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants of each
County to the intent that the said Charge may be borne and the penalties (not before excepted) levied according
to the intent of this A&bholigct; And that in case there shall be any default in performance of any thing to be done or
paid by any Peer by vertue of this A&bholigct; that then it shall be lawfull for the respe&bholigct;ive Leiutenants &amp; Deputy Leiutenant&bholngs;
or any three of them to cause Distresses to be taken for the same in any of the lands of such Defaulter within
theire said Counties or Limit&bholngs; respe&bholigct;ively And in case satisfa&bholigct;ion shall not be given within the space of one
weeke after such Distresse taken then such Distresses to be sold for the performance of the said Service and the
charge incident thereunto and the Overplus (if any be) to be restored to the Owner And if a Tenant of any
Peere of this Realme shall be distrained for such default as aforesaid the Tenant soe distrained is hereby enabled
to dedu&bholigct; the s&bhouov;m levied out of his next Rent.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">ledd <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">an <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">none <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">in any wise <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">have <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


