<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47303" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IV. An Act to enable the Kings Majestie to make Leases Grants and Copies of Offices Lands Tenements and
Hereditament&bholngs; parcell of his Highnes Dutchy of Cornwall or annexed to the same and for Confirma&bhocotil;n of Leases
and Grants already made. [Rot. Parl. 13 C. 11. p. 2. nu. 4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that by means of Leases the Tenants of the Duchy have improved their Lands, but that of late no such Leases have been made.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Certain Leases made within Three Years by the King to be good</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas a great part of the Lands part of and annexed to the Dutchy of Cornwal have beene held by
sundry Leases thereof made for yeares and for one two and three Lives by meanes whereof the Tenants
having fixed Estates have beene encouraged to improve and manure the same and have improved the same and
therein laid out great s&bhouov;ms of money in building and otherwise to the great advantage of the Publique And whereas
for Twenty yeares and more now last past no such Leases have beene legally made so that it is probable most of
the Tenants Estates will be determined or neere determination are that there can be any Estates well and legally
renewed unlesse remedy therefore be provided by meanes whereof Waste Spoile and Dilapidation are likely to happen
the Lands worne out and decayed and great Disturbance and Impoverishment to the Tenants. And whereas on the
like considera&bhocotil;n King Charles the First was by special Law enabled to make such Leases Be it Ena&bholigct;ed by our
Soveraigne Lord the King by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Commons
in this present Parliament assembled and by Authoritie of the same That all Leases or Grants already made or hereafter
to be made within the space of Three yeares now next ensuing by our said Soveraigne Lord the King by Letters
Patents Indentures or other Writings under His Great Seale of England or Seale of the Court of Exchequer or by
Copy of Court Roll according to the Customes of the respe&bholigct;ive Mannors of any Offices Parks Lands Tenements
or Hereditaments (other then Honors Lordships or Mannors) parcell of the Possessions of the said Dutchy of
Cornwal or annexed to the same shall be good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law according to the purport and contents of the
said Leases Grants and Copies against our said Soveraigne Lord the Kings Majestie His Heires and Successors and
against all and every person or persons that shall hereafter have inherit or enjoy the said Dukedom of Cornwal
by force of any A&bholigct; of Parliament or other limita&bhocotil;n whatsoever.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. How Leases to be made, and what Rent reserved.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwaies that every such Lease so to bee made of any Park&bholngs; Lands Tenements or Hereditaments in
possession shall be made but for three lives or fewer or for One and thirty yeares or under or some other terme
of yeares determinable upon one two or three Lives and not above And if such Leases be made in Reversion that
then the same togeather with the Estates in possession do not exceed three Lives or [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] terme of One and thirty
yeares and not in any wise dispunishable of Waste and so [as<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] upon every such Lease shall be reserved the ancient or
most usual Rent or more or such Rent as hath beene yeilded or paid for the greater part of twenty yeares next
before the makeing of the said Leases and shall be reserved due and payable by or to him or her that shall have
the Inheritance or other Estate of the said Park&bholngs; Lands Tenements or Hereditaments and where no such Rent hath
beene reserved or payable that then upon every such Lease there shall be reserved a reasonable Rent not being under
the fourth part of the cleere yearely value of the Parks Lands Tenements or Hereditaments contained in such Lease.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. For and against whom Covenants, Conditions, &#x0026;c. in such Leases, &#x0026;c. to be good.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">General Saving</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ordained and enacted by Authority of this present Parliament that all Covenants Condi&bhocotil;ns
and Reserva&bhocotil;ns and other Agreements contained in every Lease Grant or Copy heretofore made or hereafter so
to bee made as aforesaid shall bee good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law according to the words and contents of the same
as well for and against them to whom the Reversion of the same Lands Tenements or Hereditaments shall come
as for and against them to whom the Interest of the said Leases Grants or Copies shall come respe&bholigct;ively as if
our Soveraigne Lord the Kings Majestie at the time of the making of such Covenant&bholngs; Condi&bhocotil;ns and Reserva&bhocotil;ns
and other Agreements were seized of an absolute indefeasable Estate in Fee simple in the same Lands Tenements
or Hereditaments Saving alwaies to all and every person&amp;Persons Bodies Politique and Corporate theire Heires
and Successors Executors Administrators and Assignes (other then our said Soveraigne Lord the Kings Majestie and
His Heires and all and every person and persons that shall hereafter have inherit or enjoye the said Dukedom
of Cornwal by force of any A&bholigct; of Parliament or other limita&bhocotil;n whatsoever) all such Rights Titles Estates
Customes Interest Termes Claimes and Demands whatsoever [of what kind nature or quality whatsoever<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of in to or
out of the said Offices Lands Tenements or Hereditaments or any of them as they or any of them had or ought
to have had before the making of this A&bholigct; to all intents and purposes and in as large and ample manner and form
as if this A&bholigct; had never beene had or made This A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<para id="p6">ITEM quedam Peti&bhocotil;es privatas Personas concernentes (in se formam A&bholigct;us continentes) exhibite fuerunt &bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o
Domino Regi [in<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Parliamento &bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o qua[rum] Tituli subscribuntur.</para>
			<para id="p7">1. An Act for confirming an A&bholigct; for restoring [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the Marquesse of Hertford in the Dukedome of Somersett.</para>
			<para id="p8">2. An Act for dividing Trinity Church in Kingston upon Hull from Hasle</para>
			<para id="p9">3. An Act to enable Algernon Peyton Do&bholigct;or of Divinity to make sale of parte of his Lands for payment of
Debts &amp;c.</para>
			<para id="p10">4. An Act for confirming an A&bholigct; for restitu&bhocotil;n of Thomas Earle of Arundell Surry and Norfolke to the Dignit<emph type="p">y</emph>
and Title of Duke of Norfolke.</para>
			<para id="p11">5. An Act for confirming of Private A&bholigct;s</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


