<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47307" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for the Uniformity of Publique Prayers and Administrac[i]on of Sacraments &amp; other Rites &amp; Ceremonies and for establishing the Form of making ordaining and consecrating Bishops Preists and Deacons in the Church of England.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that in the First Year of Queen Eliz. there was one uniform Order of Church Service compiled; and enjoined to be used by 1 Eliz. c. 2.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">that many Persons nevertheless refuse to come to their Parish Church; that by the Negle&bholigct; of Ministers many Persons have been led into Schism; that His Majesty, according to His Declaration of 25th O&bholigct;, 1660, had granted a Commission to review the Book of Common Prayer, and that the Convocations were assembled for that Purpose; that they had presented to His Majesty a Book of Common Prayer, which he had allowed and recommended to Parliament that the same should be used in all Churches, &amp;c.; that an universal Agreement in public Worship conduceth to settling the Peace of the Nation; Ministers in Churches, &amp;c. to use the said Book of Common Prayer;; and to read the Morning and Evening Prayers therein</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in the first yeare of the late Queene Elizabeth there was one uniforme Order of C&bhooov;mon Service
and Prayer and of the Administration of Sacraments Rites and Ceremonies in the Church of England
(agreeable to the Word of God and usage of the Primitive Church) compiled by the Reverend Bishopps and
Clergy set forth in one Booke entituled The Booke of C&bhooov;mmon Prayer and Admimistration of Sacraments and other
Rites and Ceremonies in the Church of England and enjoyned to be used by A&bholigct; of Parliament holden in the
said First yeare of the said late Queene entituled An A&bholigct; for the Uniformity of C&bhooov;mon Prayer and Service in the
Church and Administration of the Sacraments very comfortable to all good people desirous to live in Christian
conversation and most profitable to the Estate of this Realme upon the which the Mercy Favour and Blessing of
Almighty God is in no wise so readily and plentifully poured as by C&bhooov;mon Prayers due useing of the Sacraments
and often preaching of the Gospell with Devotion of the Hearers And yet this notwithstanding a great number
of people in divers parts of this Realm following theire owne sensualitie and liveing without knowledge and due
feare of God do willfully and schismatically abstaine and refuse to come to theire Parish Churches and other
Publique places where C&bhooov;mon Prayer Administra&bhocotil;n of the Sacraments and preaching of the Word of God is
used upon the Sundayes and other dayes ordained&amp;appointed to be kept and observed as Holy dayes And
whereas by the great and scandalous negle&bholigct; of Ministers in using the said Order or Liturgy so set forth and
enjoyned as aforesaid great mischeifs&amp;inconveniencies during the times of the late unhappy troubles have arisen
and grown and many people have beene led into Fa&bholigct;ions and Schismes to the great decay and scandall of the
Reformed Religion of the Church of England and to the hazard of many souls [For prevention whereof in time
to come for setling the Peace of the Church and for allaying the present distempers which the indisposi&bhocotil;n of
the time hath contra&bholigct;ed The Kings Majestie according to His Declaration of the Five and twentieth of O&bholigct;ober
One thousand six hundred and sixty granted His C&bhooov;mission under the great Seale of England to severall Bishops
and other Divines to [re<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] view the Booke of C&bhooov;mon Prayer and to prepare such Alterations and Additions as they
thought fitt to offer And afterwards the Convocations of both the Provinces of Canterbury and Yorke being by
His Majesty called and assembled and now sitting His Majestie hath beene pleased to authorize and require the
Presidents of the said Convocations and other the Bishopps and Clergy of the same to reveiw the said Booke of
C&bhooov;mon Prayer and the Booke of the Forme and manner of the making and consecrating of Bishops Preists and
Deac&bhooov;ns And that after mature considera&bhocotil;n they should make such Additions and Alterations in the said Bookes
respe&bholigct;ively as to them should seeme meet and convenient and should exhibit and present the same to His
Majesty in writing for his further allowance or confirmation since which time upon full and mature deliberation
they the said President&bholngs; Bishops and Clergy of both Provinces have accordingly reviewed the said Bookes and
have made some Alterations which they thinke fitt to be inserted to the same and some additionall Prayers to
the said Booke of C&bhooov;mon Prayer to be used upon proper and emergent occasions And have exhibited and
presented the same unto His Majestie in writing in one Booke entituled The Booke of C&bhooov;mon Prayer and
Administration of the Sacraments and other Rites and Ceremonies of the Church according to the use of the
Church of England togeather with the Psalter or Psalmes of David pointed as they are to be sung or said in
Churches and [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] forme and manner of making ordaining and consecrating of Bishopps Preists and Deacons All
which His Majesty haveing duly considered hath fully approved and allowed the same and rec&bhooov;mended to this
&bhopcrl;sent Parliament that the said Bookes of C&bhooov;mon Prayer and of the forme of Ordination and Consecration of
Bishops Preists and Deacons with the Alterations and Additions which have beene soe made and &bhopcrl;sented to his
Majesty by the said Convocations be the Booke which shall be appointed to be used by all that officiate in all
Cathedrall and Collegiate Churches and Chappells and in all Chappells of Colledges and Halls in both the Universities
and the Colledges of Eaton and Winchester and in all Parish Churches and Chappells within the Kingdome of
England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwick upon Tweed and by all that make or consecrate Bishops Preists
or Deacons in any of the said places under such San&bholigct;ions and Penalties as the Houses of Parliament shall thinke
fitt.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Now in regard that nothing conduceth more to the setling of the Peace of this Nation (which is desired
of all good men) nor to the honour of our Religion and the propagation thereof then an universall agreement
in the Publique Worshipp of Almighty God and to the intent that every person within this Realme may certainely
knowe the rule to which he is to conforme in Publique Worship and Administration of Sacraments and other
Rites and Ceremonies of the Church of England and the manner how and by whom Bishops Preists and Deacons
are and ought to be made ordained and consecrated Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by the
advice and with the consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the C&bhooov;mons in this present Parlaiment
assembled and by the Authority of the same That all and singuler Ministers in any Cathedrall Collegiate or
Parish Church or Chappell or other place of Publique Worship within this Realme of England Dominion of Wales
and Town of Berwick upon Tweed shall be bound to say and use the Morning Prayer Evening Prayer Celebra&bhocotil;n
and Administra&bhocotil;n of both the Sacraments and all other the Publique and C&bhooov;mon Prayer in such order and forme
as is men&bhocotil;ned in the said Booke annexed and joyned to this present A&bholigct; (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) and entituled The Booke of C&bhooov;mon
Prayer and Administration of the Sacraments and other Rites and Ceremonies of the Church according to the use
of the Church of England togeather with the Psalter or Psalmes of David pointed as they are to be sung or said
in Churches and [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] forme or manner of making ordaining and consecrating of Bishops Preists &amp; Deacons. And
that the Morning and Evening Prayers therein contained shall upon every Lords day and upon all other dayes and
occasions and att the times therein appointed be openly and solemnly read by all and every Minister or Curate in
every Church Chappell or other place of Publique Worshipp within this Realme of England and places aforesaid</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Parsons, Vicars, &amp;c. publicly to read and declare their Assent to the Use of the same.</head>
			<para id="p3">And to the end that Uniformity in the Publiq Worshipp of God (which is so much desired) may be speedily
effe&bholigct;ed bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every Parson Vicar or other Minister whatsoever
who now hath and enjoyeth any Ecclesiasticall Benefice or Promotion within this Realme of England or places
aforesaid shall in the Church Chappell or place of Publiq[ue] Worshipp belonging to his said Benefice or Promotion
upon some Lords day before the Feast of Saint Bartholomew which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God One
thousand six hundred sixty and two openly publiquely and solemnely read the Morneing and Evening Prayer
appointed to be read by and according to the said Booke of C&bhooov;mon Prayer att the times thereby appointed and
after such reading thereof shall openly and publiquely before the Congregation there assembled declare his
unfeigned assent &amp; consent to the use of all things in the said Booke contained and prescribed [in these words
and no other.</para>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Form of Assent</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">I. A. B. doe (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) declare my unfaigned assent and consent to all and every thing contained and prescribed in and by
the Booke intituled The Booke of C&bhooov;mon Prayer and Administration of the Sacraments and other Rites and
Ceremonies of the Church according to the use of the Church of England togeather with the Psalter or Psalmes
of, David pointed as they are to be sung or said in Churches and the form or manner of making ordaining and
consecrating of Bishops Preists and Deacons.<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Refusing so to do.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Deprivation.; Patrons may present</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And that all and every such person who shall (without some lawfull Impediment to be allowed and approved
of by the Ordinary of the place) negle&bholigct; or refuse to doe the same within the time aforesaid (or in case of such
Impediment) within one Moneth after such Impediment removed shall (ipso fa&bholigct;o) be deprived of all his Spirituall
Promotions And that from thence forth it shall be lawfull to and for all Patrons and Donors of all and singuler
the said Spirituall Promotions or of any of them according to theire respe&bholigct;ive Rights and Titles to present or
collate to the same as though the person or persons so offending or negle&bholigct;ing were dead.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Every Person presented, to read the Prayers according to the said Book, and declare his Assent thereto.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Refusing so to do.; Deprivation.; Patrons may present</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that every person whoe shall hereafter be presented or
collated or put into any Ecclesiasticall Benefice or Promotion within this Realme of England and places aforesaid
shall in the Church Chappell or place of publiq[ue] worshipp belonging to his said Benefice or Promotion within two
Monthes next after that he shall be in the a&bholigct;uall possession of the said Ecclesiasticall Benefice or Promotion
upon some Lords day openly publiquely and solemnly read the Morning and Evening Prayers appointed to be
read by and according to the said Booke of C&bhooov;mon Prayer att the times thereby appointed and after such reading
thereof shall openly and publiquely before the Congregation there assembled declare his unfeigned assent and
consent to the use of all things therein contained and prescribed according to the forme before appointed And
that all and every such person who shall (without some lawfull Impediment to be allowed and approved by the
Ordinary of the place) negle&bholigct; or refuse to doe the same within the time aforesaid (or in case of such Impediment
within one Moneth after such Impediment removed) shall (ipso fa&bholigct;o) be deprived of all his said Ecclesiasticall
Benefices and Promotions And that from thenceforth it shall and may be lawfull to and for all Patrons and
Donors of all and singuler the said Ecclesiasticall Benefices and Promotions or any of them (according to theire
respe&bholigct;ive Rights and Titles) to present or collate to the same as though the person or persons so offending or
negle&bholigct;ing were dead</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Incumbents of Livings residing and keeping Curates shall once in every Month read the Prayers, &amp;c. according to the said Book.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5.; Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p11">[And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That in all places where the proper Incumbent of any
Parsonage or Vicaridge or Benefice with Cure doth reside on his Living and keepe a Curate the Incumbent himselfe
in person (not haveing some lawfull Impediment to be allowed by the Ordinary of the place) shall once (at the
least) in every moneth openly and publiquely read the Comon prayers and Service in and by the said Booke
prescribed and (if there be occasion) administer each of the Sacraments and other Rites of the Church in the
Parish Church or Chappell of or belonging to the same Parsonage Vicarage or Benefice in such order manner
and forme as in and by the said. Booke is appointed upon pain to forfeit the s&bhouov;m of Five pounds to the use
of the poore of the Parish for every offence upon convi&bholigct;ion by confession or proofe of two credible Witnesses
upon Oath before two Justices of the Peace of the County City or Town Corporate where the offence shall be
comitted which Oath the said Justices are hereby impowered to administer) and in default of payment within
ten dayes to be levied by distresse and sale of the goods and Chattells of the Offender by the Warrant of the
said Justices by the Church wardens or Overseers of the Poore of the said Parish rendring the surplusage to
the party</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Deans, Readers in the Universities, Parsons, School masters, &amp;c. to subscribe the Declaration herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p12">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every Deane Canon and Prebendary of every
Cathedrall or Collegiate Church and all Masters and other Heads Fellowes Chaplaines and Tutors of or in any
Colledge Hall House of Learning or Hospitall and every Publique Professor and Reader in either of the Universities
and in every Colledge elsewhere and every Parson Viccar Curate Le&bholigct;urer and every other person in Holy Orders
and in every School master keeping any publique or private Schoole&amp;every person instru&bholigct;ing or teaching any Youth
in any House or private Family as a Tutor or School master who upon the First day of May which shall be in
the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty two or at any time thereafter shall be Incumbent or have
possession of any Deanry Canonry Prebend Mastershipp Headshipp Fellowshipp Professors place or Readers place
Parsonage Vicarage or any other Ecclesiasticall Dignity or Promotion or of any Curates place Le&bholigct;ure or School or
shall instru&bholigct; or teach any Youth as Tutor or Schoolmaster shall before the Feast day of S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Bartholomew which
shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty two or at or before his or theire respe&bholigct;ive
admission to be Incumbent or have possession aforesaid subscribe the Declaration or Acknowledgement following
scilicet.</para>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Form of the Declaration</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">I A. B do declare that it is not lawfull upon any &bhopcrl;tence whatsoever to take Armes against the King and that I
do abhorr that traiterous Position of taking Armes by His Authority against His Person or against those that are
commissionated by him And that I will conforme to the Liturgy of the Church of England as it is now by Law
established And I do declare that I do hold there lies no Obliga&bhocotil;n upon me or on any other person from the Oath
comonly called the Solemne League and Covenant to endeavour any change or alteration of Government either in
Church or State And that the same was in it selfe an unlawfull Oath and imposed upon the Subje&bholigct;s of this
Realme against the knowne Lawes and Liberties of this Kingdome.</para>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Before whom to be subscribed.; Deans,&amp;c. not subscribing the same; deprived.; Deanry,&amp;c. void.</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">Which said Declaration and Acknowledgment shall be subscribed by every of the said Masters and other Heads
Fellowes Chaplaines and Tutors of or in any Colledge Hall or House of Learning and by every publique Professor
and Reader in either of the Universities before the Vice Chancellor of the respe&bholigct;ive Universities for the time
being or his Deputy And the said Declaration or Acknowledgement shall be subscribed before the respe&bholigct;ive
Archbishopp Bishopp or Ordinary of the Diocesse by every other person hereby enjoyned to subscrible the same
upon pain that all and every of the persons aforesaid failing in such Subscription shall loose and forfeit such
respe&bholigct;ive Deanary Canonry Prebend Mastershipp Headship Fellowship Professors place Readers place Parsonage
Viccarage Ecclesiasticall Dignity or Promotion Curates place Le&bholigct;ure and School and shall be utterly disabled
and (ipso fa&bholigct;o) deprived of the same And that every such respe&bholigct;ive Deanry Canonry Prebend Mastership Headship
Fellowship Proffessors Place Readers Place Parsonage Viccarage Ecclesiasticall Dignity or Promotion Curates Place
Le&bholigct;ure and Schoole shall be void as if such person so failing were naturally dead</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Schoolmasters, &amp;c. instru&bholigct;ing in private Houses before License. (Fee for License.)</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">First Offence, Imprisonment; every other Offence, Imprisonment, and Fine of &pound;5.; Parsons, &amp;c. to procure Certificate of Subscription, and to read the same, with the Declaration, in Church, Penalty.; Parsonage, &amp;c. void.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p18">And if any Schoolmaster or other person instru&bholigct;ing or teaching Youth in any private House or Family as a
Tutor or School master [shall instru&bholigct; or teach any Youth as a Tutor or Schoolmaster<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] before Licence obtained from
his respe&bholigct;ive Archbishop Bishop or Ordinary of the Diocesse according to the Lawes and Statutes of this Realme
(for which he shall pay twelve pence onely) and before such subscription and acknowledgement made as aforesaid
then every such Schoolmaster and other instru&bholigct;ing and teaching as aforesaid shall for the first offence suffer three
monthes Imprisonment without bail or mainprize and for every second and other such offence shall suffer three moneths
Imprisonment without baile or mainprize and alsoe forfeit to his Majesty the s&bhouov;m of five pounds And after such
subscription made every such Parson Viccar Curate and Le&bholigct;urer shall procure a Certificate under the Hand and
Seale of the respe&bholigct;ive Archbishop Bishop or Ordinary of the Diocesse (whoe are hereby enjoyned and required upon
demaund to make and deliver the same) and shall publickly and openly read the same togeather with the Declaration
or Acknowledgement aforesaid upon some Lords day within three moneths then next following in his Parish Church
where he is to officiate in the presence of the Congregation there assembled in the time of Divine Service upon
pain that every person failing therein shall loose such Parsonage Vicarage or Benefice Curates place or Le&bholigct;urers
place respe&bholigct;ively and shall be utterly disabled and (ipso fa&bholigct;o) deprived of the same And that the said Parsonage
Viccarage or Benefice Curates place or Le&bholigct;urers place shall be void as if he was naturally dead</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. What Words to be omitted in the Declaration after March 25, 1682.</head>
			<para id="p19">Provided alwaies that from and after the Twenty fifth day of March which shall be in the yeare of our Lord
God One thousand six hundred eighty two there shall be omitted in the said Declaration or Acknowledg&bhomsst; so to
be subscribed and read these words following scilicet.</para>
			<para id="p20">And I do declare that I do hold there lies no Obliga&bhocotil;n on me or any other person from the Oath comonly
called the Solemne League and Covenant to endeavor any change or alteration of Government either in Church
or State and that the same was in it selfe an unlawfull Oath and imposed upon the Subje&bholigct;s of this Realme against
the knowne Lawes and Liberties of this Kingdome.</para>
			<para id="p21">So as none of the persons aforesaid shall from thence forth be at all obliged to subscribe or read that part of the
said Declaration or Acknowledgement.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. What Persons shall not hold Ecclesiastical Promotion.</head>
			<para id="p22">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed that from and after the Feast of S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Bartholomew which shall be in the
yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and two no person who now is Incumbent and in possession
of any Parsonage Vicarage or Benefice and who is not already in Holy Orders by Episcopall Ordination or shall
not before the said Feast day of S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Bartholomew be ordained Preist or Deacon according to the forme of Episcopall
Ordination shall have hold or enjoye the said Parsonage Vicaradge Benefice with Cure or other Ecclesiasticall
Promotion within this Kingdome of England or the Dominion of Wales or Town of Berwick upon Tweed but
shall be utterly disabled and (ipso fa&bholigct;o) deprived of the same And all his Ecclesiastical Promotions shall be void
as if he was naturally dead.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Persons administering the Sacrament before they are ordained Priests;</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;100; and Disability for One Year</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that no person whatsoever shall thenceforth be capable
to bee admitted to any Parsonage Vicarage Benefice or other Ecclesiastical Promotion or Dignity whatsoever nor
shall presume to consecrate&amp;administer the Holy Sacrament of the Lords Supper before such time as he shall
be ordained Preist according to the forme and manner in and by the said Booke prescribed unlesse he have
formerly beene made Preist by Episcopall Ordination upon pain to forfeit for every offence the s&bhouov;m of One
hundred pounds One moyety thereof to the Kings Majesty the other moyety thereof to be equally divided betweene
the Poore of the Parish where the offence shall be c&bhooov;mitted and such person or persons as shall sue for the same
by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majesties Courts of Record wherein no Essoine
Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed And to be disabled from taking or being admitted into the Order of
Preist by the space of one whole yeare then next following</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Proviso for Aliens of Foreign reformed Churches.</head>
			<para id="p25">Provided that the penaltics in this A&bholigct; shall not extend to the Forreiners or Aliens of the Forrein Reformed
Churches allowed or to be allowed by the Kings Majestie His Heires and Successors in England</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. No Title to present by Lapse under this A&bholigct;, but on Notice.</head>
			<para id="p26">Provided alwaies that no title to conferre or present by lapse shall accrewe by any avoydance or deprivation
(ipso fa&bholigct;o) by vertue of this Statute but after six moneths after notice of such voidance or deprivation given by
the Ordinary to the Patron or such sentence of deprivation openly and publiquely read in the Parish Church of
the Benefice Parsonage or Vicarage becomeing void or whereof the Incumbent shall be deprived by vertue
of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. No other Form of Prayer to be used but according to the said Book.</head>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">Heads of Colleges, &amp;c. within the time herein mentioned. to subscribe the 39 Articles mentioned. 13 Eliz. c. 12.; and declare their Assent thereunto,; and to the said Book; and once in every Quarter of the Year read the Prayers, &amp;c.; Suspension; and if Person so suspended do not within Six Months subscribe, then his Government, &amp;c. void.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p28">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that no Form or Order of C&bhooov;mon Prayers Administra&bhocotil;n
of Sacraments Rites or Ceremonies shall be openly used in any Church Chappell or other publique place of or
in any Colledge or Hall in either of the Universities the Colledges of Westminster Winchester or Eaton or any of
them. other then what is &bhopcrl;scribed and appointed to be used in and by the said Booke And that the present
Governour or Head of every Colledge and Hall in the [said<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Universities and of the said Colledges of Westminster
Winchester and Eaton within one moneth after the Feast of S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Bartholomew which shall be in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and two And every Governour or Head of any of the said Colledges or
Halls hereafter to be ele&bholigct;ed or appointed within one moneth next after his Ele&bholigct;ion or Collation and Admission
into the same Government or Headshipp shall openly and publiquely in the Church Chappell or other publique
place of the same Colledge or Hall and in the &bhopcrl;sence of the Fellowes and Scholars of the same or the greater
part of them then resident subscribe unto the Nine and thirty Articles of Religion mentioned in the Statute
made in the thirteenth yeare of the Reigne of the late Queene Elizabeth and unto the said Booke and declare his
unfeigned assent and consent unto and approbation of the said Articles and of the same Booke and to the use of
all the Prayers Rites and Ceremonies Formes and Orders in the said Booke prescribed and contained according to
the form aforesaid And that all such Governours or Heads of the said Colledges and Halls or any of them as
are or shall be in Holy Orders shall once (at least) in every quarter of the yeare (not having a lawfull Impediment)
openly and publiquely read the Morning Prayer and Service in and by the said Booke appointed to be read in the
Church Chappell or other publique place of the same Colledge or Hall upon pain to loose and be suspended of
and from all [the<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Benefitts and Profitts belonging to the same Government or Headshipp by the space of Six
moneths by the Visitor or Visitors of the same Colledge or Hall And if any Governour or Head of any Colledge
or Hall suspended for not subscribing unto the said Articles and Booke or for not reading of the Morning Prayer
and Service as aforesaid shall not att or before the end of Six monthes next after such suspension subscribe unto
the said Articles and Booke and declare his consent thereunto as aforesaid or read the Morning Prayer and Service
as aforesaid then such Government or Headshipp shall be (ipso fa&bholigct;o) void</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Proviso for reading the Prayers in Latin in Colleges, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">Provided alwaies that it shall and may be lawfull to use the Morning and Evening Prayer and all other Prayers
and Service prescribed in and by the said Booke in the Chappells or other publique places of the respe&bholigct;ive
Colledges and Halls in both the Universities in the Colledges of Westminster Winchester and Eaton and in the
Convocations of the Clergies of either Province in Latine Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary
notwithstanding<ref idref="n9">9</ref>]<?bignore?></emph>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Le&bholigct;urer to read the 39 Articles of 13 Eliz. c. 12. and declare his Assent thereto;</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">13 Eliz. c. 12.; and at the first time of Preaching to read the said Common Prayers, and declare his Assent thereto; also upon the first Le&bholigct;ure Day of every Month.; Refusing, &amp;c. so to do,; Disabled.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p31">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid [that no person shall be or be received as a Le&bholigct;urer or
permitted suffered or allowed to preach as a Le&bholigct;urer or to preach or read any Sermon or Le&bholigct;ure in any Church
Chappell or other place of Publique Worshipp within this Realme of England or the Dominion of Wales and Towne
of Berwick upon Tweed unlesse he be first approved and thereunto licensed by the Archbishopp of the Province
or Bishopp of the Diocesse or (in case the See be void) by the Guardian of the Spiritualties under his Seale and
shall in (<ref idref="n10">10</ref>) &bhopcrl;sence of the same Archbishop or Bishop or Guardian read the nine and thirty Articles of Religion
mentioned in the Statute of the Thirteenth yeare of the late Queene Elizabeth with declaration of his unfeigned
assent to the same And<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] that every person and persons whoe nowe is or hereafter shall bee licensed assigned [or<ref idref="n11">11</ref>&gt;]
appointed or received as a Le&bholigct;urer to preach upon any day of the weeke in any Church Chappell or place of
Publique Worship within this Realme of England or places aforesaid the first time he preacheth (before his Sermon)
shall openly publiquely and solemnly read the C&bhooov;mmon Prayers and Service in and by the said Booke appointed
to be read for that time of the day and then and there publiquely and openly declare his assent unto and
approbation of the said Booke and to the use of all the Prayers Rites and Ceremonies Formes and Orders therein
contained and prescribed according to the forme before appointed in this A&bholigct; And alsoe shall upon the first
Le&bholigct;ure day [of every moneth afterwards so long as he continues Le&bholigct;urer or Preacher there at the place appointed
for his said Le&bholigct;ure or Sermon before his said Le&bholigct;ure or Sermon openly publiquely and solemnly read the
Common Prayers and Service in and by the said Booke appointed to be read for that time of the day at which
the said Le&bholigct;ure or Sermon is to be preached and after such reading there of shall openly and publiquely before
the Congregation there assembled declare his unfeigned assent and consent unto and approbation of the said Booke
and to the use of all the Prayers Rites and Ceremonies Forms and Orders therein contained and prescribed
according to the forme aforesaid<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] And that all and every such person and persons who shall negle&bholigct; or refuse to
do the same shall from thenceforth be disabled to preach the said or any other Le&bholigct;ure or Sermon in the said
or any other Church Chappell or place of Publique Worship untill such time as he and they shall openly
publiquely and solemnly read the Common Prayers and Service appointed by the said Booke and conform in all
points to the things therein appointed and prescribed according to the purport true intent and meaning of
this A&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Proviso where Le&bholigct;ure preached in Cathedrals, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p32">[Provided alwaies That if the said Sermon or Le&bholigct;ure be to be preached or read in any Cathedrall or Collegiate
Church or Chappell it shall be sufficient for the said Le&bholigct;urer openly at the time aforesaid to declare his assent
and consent to all things contained in the said Booke according to the form aforesaid.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Persons so disabled preaching,; Imprisonment in Common Gaol.</head>
			<para id="p33">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any person who is by this A&bholigct; disabled to preach
any Le&bholigct;ure or Sermon shall during the time that he shall continue and remaine so disabled preach any Sermon
or Le&bholigct;ure that then for every such offence the person and persons so offending shall suffer Three Monthes
Imprisonment in the C&bhooov;mon Goal without baile or mainprize and that any two Justices of the Peace of any
County of this Kingdome and places aforesaid and the Maior or other Cheife Magistrate of any City or Town
Corporate within the same upon Certificate from the Ordinary of the place made to him or them of the offence
committed shall and are hereby required to committ the person or persons so offending to the Goal of the same
County City or Town Corporate accordingly</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. The said Common Prayers to be read whenever any Sermon or Le&bholigct;ure is preached.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Le&bholigct;urer to be present.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p35">[Provided alwaies and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That att all and every time and times
when any Sermon or Le&bholigct;ure is to be preached the Common Prayers and Service in and by the said Booke
appointed to be read for that time of the day shall be openly publiquely and solemnly read by some Preist or
Deacon in the Church Chappell or place of Publique Worshipp where the said Sermon or Le&bholigct;ure is to be
preached before such Sermon or Le&bholigct;ure be preached and that the Le&bholigct;urer then to preach shall be present att the
reading thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing University Sermons preached in the University Churches.</head>
			<para id="p36">Provided neverthelesse that this A&bholigct; shall not extend to the University Churches in the Universities of this
Realme or either of them when or att such times as any Sermon or Le&bholigct;ure is preached or read in the [said<ref idref="n13">13</ref>
Churches or any of them for or as the publick University Sermon or Le&bholigct;ure but that the same Sermons and
Le&bholigct;ures may be preached or read in such sort and manner as the same have been heretofore preached or read
This A&bholigct; or any thing herein contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.<ref idref="n11">11</ref>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Former Laws for the Uniformity of Prayers, &amp;c. confirmed.</head>
			<para id="p37">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that the severall. good Lawes and Statutes of this Realm
which have beene formerly made and are now in force for the Uniformity of Prayer and Administration of the
Sacraments within this Realme of England and places aforesaid shall stand in full force and strength to all intents
and purposes whatsoever for the establishing and confirming of the said Booke intituled The Booke of C&bhooov;mon
Prayer and Administration of the Sacraments and other Rites&amp;Ceremonies of the Church according to the use of
the Church of England togeather with the Psalter or Psalmes of David pointed as they are to be sung or said in
Churches and the forme or manner of making ordaining and consecrating of Bishopps Preists and Deacons herein
before mentioned to be joyned and annexed to this A&bholigct; and shall be applied pra&bholigct;ised and put in ure for the
punishing of all offences contrary to the said Lawes with relation to the Booke aforesaid and no other.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Prayers relating to the Royal Family to be altered as required.</head>
			<para id="p38">Provided alwaies and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That in all those Prayers Letanies and
Colle&bholigct;s which doe any way relate to the King Queene or Royall Progeny the Names be altered and changed from
time to time and fitted to the present occasion according to the dire&bholigct;ion of lawfull Authority.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. A true printed Copy of the said Book of Common Prayer to be</head>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">provided for Parish Churches, &amp;c. at the Costs of the Parishioners. Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p40">Provided alsoe and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid that a true printed Copy of the said Booke
entituled The Booke of C&bhooov;mon Prayer and Administration of the Sacraments and other Rites and Ceremonies of
the Church according to the use of the Church of England togeather with the Psalter or Psalmes of David pointed
as they are to be sung or said in Churches and the form and manner of making ordaining and consecrateing of
Bishops Preists and Deacons shall att the costs and charges of the parishoners of every Parish Church and
Chappelry Cathedrall Church Colledge and Hall be attained and gotten before the Feast day of St. Bartholomew
in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty and two upon pain of forfeiture of three pounds by
the moneth for so long time as they shall then after be unprovided thereof by every Parish or Chapelry Cathedrall
Church Colledge and Hall making default therein.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. The Bishops of Hereford, St. David, Asaph, and Bangor to take Order that the said Book shall be translated into Welch, and had in Churches, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p41">
				<emph type="i">and the Form of Prayer &amp;c. therein to be used.; The same to be paid for by the Churchwardens out of the Parish Money.; Bishops to set the Price.; And one other Book in the English Tongue to be also had.; Proviso for the Use of the former Forms until the said Book can be had.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p42">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Bishops of Hereford S<emph type="p">t</emph> Davies Asaph
Bangor and Landaff and their Successors shall take such order among themselves for the souls health of the
Flocks committed to theire Charge within Wales That the Booke hereunto annexed be truly and exa&bholigct;ly translated
into the British or Welsh Tongue and that the [same<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] soe translated and being by them or any three of them at the
least viewed perused and allowed be imprinted to such number at least so that one of the said Bookes so translated
and imprinted may be had for every Cathedrall Collegiate and Parish Church and Chapell of Ease in the said
respe&bholigct;ive Diocesses and places in Wales where the Welsh is c&bhooov;monly spoken or used before the First day of May
One thousand six hundred sixty five And that from and after the imprinting and publishing of the said Booke so
translated the whole Divine Service shall be used and said by the Ministers and Curates throughout all Wales
within the said Diocesses where the Welsh Tongue is c&bhooov;monly used in the British or Welsh Tongue in such
manner and forme as is prescribed according to the Booke hereunto annexed to be used in the English Tongue
differing nothing in any Order or Form the said English Booke for which Booke so translated and imprinted
the Church wardens of every the said Parishes shall pay out of the Parish [moneys<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] in theire hands for the use
of the respe&bholigct;ive Churches and be allowed the same on theire Accompt And that the said Bishops and theire
Successors or any three of them at the least shall sett and appoint the price for which the said Booke shall be
sold And one other Booke of Common Prayer in the English Tongue shall be bought and had in every Church
throughout Wales in which the Booke of C&bhooov;mon Prayer in Welsh is to be had by force of this A&bholigct; before the
First day of May One thousand six hundred sixty and foure and the same Booke to remaine in such convenient
places within the said Churches that such as understand them may resort at all convenient times to read and
peruse the same and alsoe such as do not understand the said Language may by conferring both Tongues
togeather the sooner attaine to the knowledge of the English Tongue Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary
notwithstanding and untill printed Copies of the said Booke so to be translated may be had and provided The
Form of C&bhooov;mon Prayer established by Parliament before the makeing of this A&bholigct; shall be used as formerly in
such parts of Wales where the English Tongue is not comonly understood</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Deans, &amp;c. to obtain Copies of this A&bholigct; and of the said Book;</head>
			<para id="p43">
				<emph type="i">to be kept by them and their Successors.; Copies of this A&bholigct; and of the said Book to be delivered to the Courts at Westminster and the Tower of London.; Such Copies to be examined with the Original and certified; and thereupon accounted good Records</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p44">And to the end that the true and perfe&bholigct; Copies of this A&bholigct; and the said Booke hereunto annexed may be
safely kept and perpetually preserved and for the avoiding of all disputes for the time to come Be it therefore
ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the respe&bholigct;ive Deanes and Chapters of every Cathedrall or Collegiate
Church within England and Wales shall at theire proper costs and charges before the Twenty fifth day of December
One thousand six hundred sixty&amp;two obtain under the Great Seale of England a true and perfe&bholigct; printed Copy
of this A&bholigct; and of the said Booke annexed hereunto to be by the said Deanes and Chapters and theire Successors
kept and preserved in safety for ever and to be alsoe produced and shewed forth in any Court of Record as
often as they shall be thereunto lawfully required And alsoe there shall be delivered true and perfe&bholigct; Copies of
this A&bholigct; and of the same Booke into the respe&bholigct;ive Courts at Westminster and into the Tower of London to be
kept and preserved for ever among the Records of the said Courts and the Records of the Tower to be alsoe
produced and shewed forth in any Court as need shall require which said Bookes soe to be exemplified under the
Great Seale of England [shall be examined by such persons as the Kings &bhomtie; shall appoint under the Great
Seale of England<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] for that purpose and shall be compared with the Originall Booke hereunto annexed and shall
have power to corre&bholigct; and amend in writing any Error committed by the Printer in the printing of the same
Booke or of any thing therein contained and shall certifie in writing under theire Hands and Seales or the
Hands and Seales of any three of them att the end of the same Booke that they have examined and compared
the same Booke and find it to be a true and perfe&bholigct; Coppy which said Bookes and every one of them so
exemplified under the Great Seale of England as aforesaid shall bee deemed taken adjudged and expounded to bee
good and available in the Law to all intents and purposes whatsoever and shall be accounted as good Records
as this Booke it selfe hereunto annexed Any Law or Custome to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Proviso for King's Professor of Law at Oxford for Prebend of Shipton.</head>
			<para id="p45">Provided alsoe that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not be p&bhopcrl;judiciall or hurtfull unto the Kings
Professor of the Law within the University of Oxford for or concerning the Prebend of Shipton within the
Cathedrall Church of Saru[m] united and annexed unto the place of the same Kings Professor for the time being by
the late King James of blessed memory</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Proviso in respe&bholigct; of the 36th Article, one of the said 39 Articles.</head>
			<para id="p46">Provided alwaies That whereas the Six and thirtieth Article of the Nine and thirtie Articles agreed upon by
the Archbishops and Bishops of both Provinces and the whole Clergy in the Convocation holden at London in
the yeare of our Lord One thousand five hundred sixty two for the avoiding of diversities of Opinions and for
establishing of consent touching true Religion is in these words following viz<emph type="p">t</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p47">That the Booke of Consecration of Archbishops and Bishops and Ordaining of Preists and Deacons lately set
forth in the time of King Edward the Sixth and confirmed at the same time by Authority of Parliament doth
contain all things necessary to such consecration and ordaining neither hath it any thing that of it selfe is
superstitious and ungodly And therefore whosoever are consecrated or ordered according to the Rites of that
Booke since the second yeare of the aforenamed King Edward unto this time or hereafter shall be consecrated
or ordered according to the same Rites We decree all such to bee rightly orderly and lawfully consecrated
and ordered.</para>
			<para id="p48">It be ena&bholigct;ed And be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all Subscriptions hereafter to be had or
made unto the said Articles by any Deacon Preist or Ecclesiasticall person or other person whatsoever who by
this A&bholigct; or any other Law now in force is required to subscribe unto the said Articles shall be construed and [be<ref idref="n17">17</ref>]
taken to extend and shall be applied (for and touching the said Six and thirtieth Article) unto the Booke containing
the forme and manner of making ordaining and consecrating of Bishops Preists and Deacons in this A&bholigct; mentioned
in such sort and manner as the same did heretofore extend unto the Booke sett forthe in the time of King
Edward the Sixth mentioned in the said Six and thirtieth Article Any thing in the said Article, or in any Statute
A&bholigct; or Canon heretofore had or made to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Proviso for the Use of Book of Common Prayer, &amp;c. as established by 1 Eliz. c. t. until the Feast of St. Bartholomew 1662.</head>
			<para id="p49">Provided alsoe That the Booke of C&bhooov;mon Prayer and Administration of the Sacraments and other Rites and
Ceremonies of this Church of England togeather with the form and manner of ordaining and consecrating Bishops
Preists and Deacons heretofore in use and respe&bholigct;ively established by A&bholigct; of Parliament in the First and Eighth
yeares of Queene Elizabeth shall be still used and observed in the Church of England untill the Feast of Saint
Bartholomew which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty and two.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">This Book is in Mauuscript and is in the Parliament Office, and in the same Press, but not in the same Division of that Press,
with the A&bholigct;s of this Year.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">here <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">same <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">some <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Money <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

