<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47304" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for preventing the Mischeifs and Dangers that may arise by certaine Persons called Quakers and others
refusing to take lawfull Oaths.[Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 1. nu. 1.</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Recital that Quakers have maintained that the taking an Oath is unlawful, and refused to take Oath; and that they met together to the endangering the public Peace.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Any Person maintaining such Doctrines, refusing to take lawful Oath; or by printing, &amp; maintaining such Doctrine; if such Persons depart from their Habitations, and assemble to the Number of Five, &#x0026;c; First Offence, Penalty.; Second Offence, Penalty.; Distress.; If no Distress, or Non-payment of Penalty.; Imprisonment for First Offence.; For Second Offence.; Penalties how employed.; Third Offence, Abjuration of the Realm, or Transportation</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Whereas of late times certaine persons under the names of Quakers and other names of Separation have
taken up and maintained sundry dangerous Opinions and Tenents and (amongst others) that the taking of
an Oath in any case whatsoever although before a lawfull Magistrate is altogeather unlawfull and contrary to the
word of God and the said persons do daily refuse to take an Oath though lawfully tendred whereby it often happens
that the truth is wholly suppressed and the Administration of Justice much obstru&bholigct;ed And whereas the said
Persons under a pretence of Religious Worship do often assemble themselves in great numbers in several parts of
this Realm to the great endangering of the Publick Peace and Safety and to the terror of the People by maintaining
a secret 'and' stri&bholigct; correspondence amongst themselves and in the meane time separating and dividing themselves from
the rest of his Majesties good and loyall Subje&bholigct;s and from the Pubilick Congregations and usual Places of Divine
Worshipp. For the redressing therefore and better preventing the many mischeifs and dangers that do and may
arise by such dangerous Tenents and such unlawful Assemblies Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty
by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and Comons assembled in Parliament and
by Authoritie of the same That if any person or persons who maintain that the taking of an Oath in any case
whatsoever (although before a lawfull Magistrate) is altogeather unlawfull and contrary to the word of God from
and after the Foure and twentieth day of March in this present yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty
and one shall wilfully and obstinately refuse to take an Oath where by the Laws of the Realm he or she is or
shal be bound to take the same being lawfully and duly tendred or shall endeavour to perswade any other person
to whom any such Oath shal in like manner be duly and lawfully tendred to refuse and forbeare the taking of
the same or shall by Printing Writing or otherwise go about to maintaine and defend that the taking of an Oath
in any case whatsoever is altogeather unlawful And if the said persons comonly called Quakers shall at any time
after the said foure and twentieth day of March depart from the places of theire severall habitations and assemble
themselves to the number of five or more of the age of sixteen yeares or upwards at any one time in any place
under pretence of joyning in a Religious Worship not authorized by the Lawes of this Realm that then in al and
every such cases the party so offending being thereof lawfully convi&bholigct; by verdi&bholigct; of twelve men or by his owne
confession. or by the notorious evidence of the fa&bholigct; shall loose and forfeit to the Kings Majesty His Heires and
Successors for the first offence such s&bhouov;m as shall be imposed upon him or her not exceeding five pounds And
if any person or persons being once convi&bholigct;ed of any such offence shall againe offend therein and shall inform
aforesaid be thereof lawfully convi&bholigct;ed shall for the second offence forfeit to the King our Soveraigne Lord His
Heires and Successors such s&bhouov;m as shall be imposed upon him or her not exceeding ten pounds The said
respective penalties to be levied by distresse and sale of the parties goods so convicted by warrant of the parties
before whom they shall be so convi&bholigct;ed rendring the overplus to the owners if any be and for want of such
distresse or non payment of the said penalty within one weeke after such conviction that then the said parties so
convi&bholigct;ed shall for the [first<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] offence be c&bhooov;mmitted to the C&bhooov;mon Goal or house of Corre&bholigct;ion for the space of
three monthes and for the second offence during six monthes without baile or Mainprise there to be kept at
hard labour which said moneys soe to be levied shall be paid to such person or persons as shall be appointed
by those before whom they shall be convi&bholigct;ed to be imployed for the increase of the stock of the house of
corre&bholigct;ion to which they shall be committed and providing materials to set them on worke And if any person
after he in form aforesaid hath been twice convi&bholigct; of any of the said offences shall offend the third time and
be thereof in form aforesaid lawfully convi&bholigct; that then every person so offending &#x0026; convi&bholigct; shall for his or her
third offence abjure the Realme or otherwise it shall and may bee lawfull to and for His Majestie His Heires and
Successors to give order and to cause him [her <ref idref="n1">1</ref>] or them to be transported in any Ship or Ships to any of His
Majesties Plantations beyond the Seas.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Justices of Oyer and Terminer, &amp; at General Scssions may determine Offences.</head>
			<para id="p3">And it is ordained and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every [Justice<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of Oyer and Terminer
Justices of Assize and Goal Delivery and the Justices of the Peace shall have full Power and Authority in every
of theire open and general Sessions to enquire heare and determine all and every the said Offences within the
limits of theire Commission to them dire&bholigct;ed and to make Processe for the execution of the same as they may
do against any person being indi&bholigct;ed before them of Trespas or lawfully convi&bholigct;ed thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Justices of Peace, Mayors, &amp; may commit or bind over.</head>
			<para id="p4">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Justice of Peace Maior or other
cheife Officer of any Corporation within theire several Jurisdi&bholigct;ions to commit to the C&bhooov;mmon Goal or bind over
with sufficient Sureties to the Quarter Sessions any person or persons offending in the Premisses in order to his
or theire conviction aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Persons convicted taking the Oaths and giving Security.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided alwaies and be it hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That if any of the said persons shall after such convi&bholigct;ion
as aforesaid take such Oath or Oathes for which hee or shee stands committed and alsoe give security that he
or she shall for the time to come forbear to meet in any such unlawfull Assembly as aforesaid that then and
from thence forth such person and persons shall be discharged from all the penalties aforesaid Any thing in this
A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Lords of Parliament tried by their Peers.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alwaies and be it ordained and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and singuler Lords of
the Parliament for every third offence committed against the tenor of this A&bholigct; shall be tried by theire Peers and
not otherwise.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Justices <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


