<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47305" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act for repairing the High wayes and Sewers and for paving and keeping clean of the Streets in and about the Cities of London &amp; Westminster and for reforming of Annoyances and Disorders in the Streets of and
places adjacent to the said Cities and for the Regulating and Licensing of [Hackey<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Coaches and for the enlarging of several strait &amp; inconvenient Streets and Passages. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 1. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of the bad State of the Common Highways leading to and from London and Westminster.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners to be nominated under the Great Scal; of whom Surveyor of His Majesty's Work's to be one.; Place of Meeting.; Power of Commissioners to make Vaults, Sewers, Drains, &amp;c.; and to remove Encroachments, &amp;c.; Proviso as to Encroachments that have continued above 30 Years.; Proceedings where; Owners of such Encroachments refuse Satisfa&bholigct;ion</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For as much as the Common High wayes leading unto and from the Cities of London and Westminster and
the Suburbs thereof and other places within the present Weekly Bills of Mortality by reason of the multitude
of Houses lately built and through the stopping and filling up the Ditches and Sewers and negle&bholigct; of timely
reparations are at present and for some yeares past have beene so miry and foul as is not only very noisom
dangerous and inconvenient to the inhabitants thereabouts but to all the Kings Leige people riding and travelling
to and from the said Cities May it therefore please your most Excellent Majestie [that it may be ena&bholigct;ed &amp; be it
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings-most Excellent Majestie<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporal and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same. That for the
surveying ordering and managing of the said High wayes Streets Allies and other passages within the said Cities
and places aforesaid and all things necessary for the repairing paving or keeping clean thereof there be from
hence forward Commissioners to be nominated by His Majesty under the Great Seale of England not exceeding
the number of One and Twenty besides such other Commissioners as are by this A&bholigct; nominated and appointed
(whereof the Surveyor of His Majesties [wo <ref idref="n3">3</ref>] for the time being to be alwaies one) that shall have theire place
of meeting att the Office of His Majesties workes in Scotland yard or at some one other place as they or the
greater number of them at any meeting shall dire&bholigct; from time to time as there shall be occasion which said
Commissioners or any five or more of them att theire meeting as aforesaid shall have full power and authority to
order and dire&bholigct; the making of any new Vaults or Sewers or to cut into any Dreine or Sewer already made or the altering enlarging amending cleansing or scowring of any old Vaults Sinks or Common Sewers or for the
making amending or altering of any new or old pavements or taking away [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] cross Gutters or Channells in
all or any of the streets and places aforesaid and for the removing of all kind of Nusances or any encroachment
by Sheds Stalls Bulks Stoops Posts or Wall beyond the old Foundations into the Streets in such places which
shall be adjudged inconvenient and to hinder the passage Provided that such encroachments as are aforementioned
which are Nusances that have continued above thirty yeares last past shall not be removed untill reasonable
satisfa&bholigct;ion shall be given by the said Commissioners to the party or parties that shall suffer thereby And if any
person or persons that owne the said encroachments or shall not accept of such reasonable satisfa&bholigct;ion as shall be
tendred or offered by the said Commissioners appointed for the Streets for the pulling downe or removing such
Nusances or encroachment&bholngs; as have beene continued before the time aforesaid That then and in such cases of
refusall the Barons of the Exchequer upon a Peti&bhocotil;n preferred to them by the party greived shall have power and
are required by this A&bholigct; to adjudge what satisfa&bholigct;ion shall be fit for the said person or persons to receive for
the removing or pulling downe any such Nusance or encroachment</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II.; Power to Commissioners to view Encroachments, &amp;c. Not removing, Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p3">And to prevent for the future all manner of Timber and other irregular Buildings the said Commissioners or
any five or more of them are hereby impowred to take a veiw of all such Nusances or encroachments and irregular
Buildings which said veiw shall be a good convi&bholigct;ion in Law and every person or persons having notice of the
said veiw or convi&bholigct;ion and shall not remove or take downe such Nusances or encroachments within one moneth
after notice shall forfeit Forty shillings for every moneth the said Nusances or encroachments shall afterwards
continue.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Recital that it is thought fit to repair certain Streets, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Inhabitants of such Streets and adjoining thereto to pay towards paving, &amp;c.; Rate</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And whereas the c&bhooov;mon High wayes and new built Streets hereafter mentioned are thought fitt immediately
to be repaired new paved or otherwise amended namely the street or way from the end of Petty France to
St James House and one other street from St. James House up to the High way and one other street in St. James
Feilds comonly called the Pall-mall and alsoe one other street begining from the Mews up to Pickadilly and
from thence towards the Stone bridge to the furthermost building neere the Bull art the corner of Air streete
be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed That all and every person and persons owners or inhabitants of all and every the Houses
built upon or adjoyning to the said wayes or streets so adjudged and thought fitt to bee paved and repaired shall
according to theire severall Interests and Estates and in such proportions as the said Commissioners or any five of
them shall thinke fit before the first day of May One thousand six hundred sixty two pay unto the said
Commissioners or any five or more of them so met as aforesaid which shall be nominated for the paving of the
said wayes or to such person or persons as they shall appoint such sum and s&bhouov;ms of money towards the paving of
the said streets or wayes and for the buying of new Stones and Gravell as shall amount to theire severall
proportions after the rate of sixteene pence for every square yard which the ground shall contain that lyes in
front before every dwelling House Yards or Gardens belonging to the said dwelling House and in the same breadth
extending to the midle of the High way or Street which lies before the said Houses Yards or Gardens belonging to
the said dwelling Houses respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV.; Driving and letting to Hire Hackney Coaches and Horses,; (Proviso for Stage Coaches);</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">without License from certain Commissioners.; Height of Horses used with such Coaches.; Number.; Mark on Coach.; Number of Coaches kept by one Person, &amp;c.; Penalty &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And for the better preserving of the said Streets and for defraying of the residue of the charge of the said
Pavements be it further ena&bholigct;ed That from and after the First day of May One thousand six hundred sixty and
two no person or persons shall presume to drive (excepting Stage Coaches) or let to hire by the houre or day or
otherwise any Hackney Coach or Coach Horses within the Cities of London and Westminster or Suburbs of the
same or within the Parishes comprised within the Bills of Mortality without an especiall leave or licence from such
Commissioners as His Majesty shall appoint under the Great Seale for the Licensing and Regulating of Hackney
Coaches according to the particular provisions and limitations of this Bill and that no Horse Gelding or Mare
to be used with such Coaches shall be under the sise of fourteen hands high according to the Standard and that
the number to be licensed shall not exceed Foure hundred And that every Coach so licensed shall have a marke of
distin&bholigct;ion by figure or otherwise as the Commissioners shall thinke fitt to the end they may be knowne if any
complaint shall be made of them And that no person shall be licensed to keepe more then two Coaches which
Coaches shall have every of them severall figures or markes of distin&bholigct;ion in the same manner as if belonging to
severall persons and that no person shall presume to put the same figure or marke of distin&bholigct;ion upon his Coach
that is appointed for any other Coach under the forfeiture of five pounds for every such offence one moyety
whereof shall be to the Informer and the other moyety to bee paid to the Commissioners that shall be appointed for
the paving and amending the streets.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. To what Persons Commissioners may grant Licenses.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Priority to ancient Coachmen and their Widows</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And the said Commissioners for the licensing and regulating of Coaches are to take especial care not to license
any person to drive or keepe any Hackney Coach or Coach Horses that useth any other trade or occupa&bhocotil;n and
in the first place to license all such persons as have beene ancient Coach men or such Coach men as have
suffered for theire service and affe&bholigct;ions to His late Majesty or His Majesty that nowe is or the widdow or widdowes
of any of them that have Coaches of theire owne</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI.; Commissioners licensing above the Number, Penalty &pound;100.</head>
			<para id="p10">And in case, the said Commissioners shall license more then the said number of four hundred Coaches every
of the said Commissioners soe licensing shall forfeit the sum of one hundred pounds for every such Coach so
licensed above the said number whereof twenty pounds to the Informer and the residue to be for the repairing
and paving the wayes and streets to be levied by distresse by warrant under the hands and Seales of five or more
of the other Commissioners that shall be appointed for the paving and mending of the streets and High Wayes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Rates of Hire.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Taking greater Rate; Penalty, 10s.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p12">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no Hackney Coachman so licensed shall presume to
take for his hire in or about the Cities of London and Westminster above the rate of ten shillings for a day
reckoning twelve houres to the day and by the houre not above eighteen pence for the first houre and twelve
pence for every houre after and that no Gentleman or other person shall pay from any of the Inns of Court or
thereabouts to any part of St. James or City of Westminster (except beyond Tuttle-street above twelve pence and
the same prices from the same places to the Inns of Court or places thereabouts and from any of the said Inns of
Court or thereabouts to the Royall Exchange twelve pence and if to the Tower of London or to Bishopsgate street
or Algate or thereabouts eight[een<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] pence and so from the same places to the said Inns of Court as aforesaid and
the like rates from and to any place at the like distance with the places before men&bhocotil;ned And if any Coachman
shall refuse to go at or [shall<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] exa&bholigct; more for his hire then the severall Rates hereby limited he shall for every
such offence forfeit the summ of ten shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII.; Rent to be paid by Coachmen.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Payable Quarterly.; To whom Rent to be paid.; Commissioners for Hackney Coaches to certify to Commissioners for Paving Names and Dwelling of licensed Coachmen, and Figures affixed to their Coaches.; Overplus of Paving Rates how employed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And be it further Enacted That every Coach so licensed as aforesaid shall pay to the C&bhooov;missioners that shall
be appointed for the regulating and licensing of Hackney Coaches the yearely Rent of five pounds and no more
whereof fifty shillings shall be paid at or before the twenty sixth day of May One thousand six hundred sixty and
two and the s&bhouov;m of five and twenty shillings att or upon the feast day of St. Michael the Archangell next coming
and Twenty five shillings att the Feast of the Nativitie of our Lord Christ and from thenceforward to bee paid
quarterly at the foure most usuall Feasts of the yeare by equall porc[i]ons (that is to say) at the Annunciac[i]on of the
Blessed Virgin, St. John the Baptist, St. Michael the Archangell and the Nativitie of our Lord Christ which said
S&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money the said Commissioners for the Hackney Coaches shall from time to time pay or cause
to be paid to the Commissioners appointed for the paving and amending of the Streets and High wayes within
[the<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Bill contained or to such Treasurer or Receiver as they shall appoint And the said Commissioners for
Hackney Coaches shall likewise from time to time certifie to the Commissioners appointed for the paving of the
Streets and High wayes the names and dwellings of all such persons as they shall license to drive or keepe Hackney
Coaches togeather with the severall figures or markes of distin&bholigct;ion which are appointed to belong and be affixed
to the severall Coaches to the intent that discovery may the better be made of any abuses that shall be committed
if any shall presume to affix 	the figure or marke of distin&bholigct;ion to any Coach which belong of right to another
and whereby the C&bhooov;missioners for the paving and amending the Streets and High wayes shall be enabled to call the
said Comissioners for the Hackney Coaches to a true and due accompt And in any case any overplus shall be of the
moneys appointed by this A&bholigct; to be raised for the paving and mending the Wayes and Streets as aforesaid then
such overplus shall be imployed towards the enlargment of such Streets or Places as are to be enlarged by vertue
of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Rates on Loads of Hay and Straw brought to be sold.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">To whom to be paid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And bee it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every load of Hay Which from the first day of May One
thousand six hundred sixty and two shall be brought and stand to be sold upon any the wayes hereby in this A&bholigct;
expressed and adjudged fitt to be new paved shall pay six pence for every load and likewise every Cart of Straw to be
sold in the said places shall after the said day pay two pence which said s&bhouov;ms shall be paid to the Commissioners
which shall be appointed for the paving and amending the High wayes and Streets or such as they shall appoint for
and towards the paving of the Streets and High wayes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X.; Penalties, &amp;c. to be levied by Distress.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">To be sold; Overplus returned to Owner.; If no Distress, &amp;c. Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all Fines Rents forfeitures and penalties as shall growe
due and payable to the said Commissioners by this A&bholigct; shall be levied by distresse upon the goods and Chattells of the
Offender or Offenders by warrant under the Hands and Seals of the Commissioners or any five or more of them which
shall be appointed by His Majesty which shall bee sold within Fourteen dayes and the overplus returned to the owner
and in default of distresse or [non<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] payment the person or persons so offending or negle&bholigct;ing to pay shall lie in
prison without Bail or Mainprize till he or they have paid such Rent Fine Forfeiture and Penalty as was due
from him or them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Commissioners for Paving may appoint Treasurer and other Officers;</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">and may contra&bholigct; for taking away Ashes, &amp;c.; and may call Scavengers to account; and may determine Disputes as to Paving, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">And the said Commissioners for the Streets and Wayes or any five or more of them so met as aforesaid are hereby
impowred to appoint a Treasurer or Collector and Clerke to attend them or such other Officer or Officers as they
shall find necessary for the carrying on of the said Service with such moderate allowances as shall be fitt And in case
any person shall propose to carry away the ashes dirt and other Filth for all or any the places aforesaid at lesse rates
then the yearely Raker or Undertaker can or will performe the same the said Commissioners shall have power and are
hereby authorized to contra&bholigct; with such person and for such term as they shall thinke fitt and they are alsoe
to require an accompt from time to time of all Scavingers within the said places and all other person [or<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] persons
that shall receive or disburse any moneys for the purposes in this Bill contained as often as they or any five or more of
them so met as aforesaid shall thinke fitting and necessary and shall heare and determine all Disputes and Differences
concerning the right and duty of paving and keeping clean any of the Streets Lanes or Allies or publique Yards
within the places aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Scavengers, &amp;c. lodging their Ashes, &amp;c. regulated by Commissioners;</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">and their passing through Places with their Carts; and giving Satisfaction to Owners.; Appeal from the Determination of Commissioners</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">Provided alwaies That the respective Scavingers Rakers or (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) Undertakers shall have liberty by the approba&bhocotil;n
of the said Comissioners or any five or more of them so met as aforesaid to lodge theire Ashes Dust Dirt or other Fifth
in such vacant publick places in or neere the Streets or High wayes as shall be thought convenient by the said
Commissioners for the accommodating of Countrey Carts returning empty And the said Scavengers Rakers or
other Undertakers shall have liberty to passe through such Wharffs Docks or Yards with theire Ashes Dust
Dirt &amp;c as shall be judged by the Commissioners to be most commodious for the carrying the same by water
they giving satisfa&bholigct;ion to the owners or occupiers of such wharffs or Yards and in case of unreasonable Demands
the said Commissioners shall heare moderate &amp; determine the same according to equity and good conscience and
in case any person or persons shall find him or themselves agreived or &bhopcrl;judiced by such determina&bhocotil;n of the said
Commissioners [or by any other the A&bholigct;s or Proceedings of the said Commissioners<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] wherein he or they shall conceive
themselves relievable in Justice or Equity the said party so aggreived shall and may have recourse in all cases to
the Lord Treasurer Chancellor of the Exchequer and Barons of the Court of Exchequer to set forth his or theire
case by Peti&bhocotil;n Bill or Plaint And the said Court is hereby impowred in such case of Appeale to heare and
determine all matters to them complained of concerning the same and thereupon to revoke make void alter or
confirm such A&bholigct;s or Proceedings of the said Commissioners as shall be agreeable to Equity and Justice</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Court of Exchequer may call Commissioners to account.</head>
			<para id="p23">And the said Court of Exchequer is hereby alsoe further impowred yearely to call the said Commissioners to an
account for all Rents Fines Penalties Contributions or any other s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money payable or that shall come to
theire or any of theire hands for any [of<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] the purposes in this Act intended</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Commissioners in Trinity Term to account to the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p24">And the said Commissioners are hereby required at or before [the end of<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] every Trinity Terme to deliverin a
true account before the Barons of the said Court of all theire Receipts and Disbursements for the yeare ended at Easter
then past and in default thereof Processe shall of Course be made forth against the said Commissioners by the Clarke
of the Extra&bholigct;s of the said Court at the Sealing day for the said Trinity Terme every yeare respe&bholigct;ively</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. A Decree made in a Session of Sewers at Westminster Hall, dated 8th August 1661, ratified;</head>
			<para id="p25">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Decree made at a Session of Sewers at Westminster
Hall within the City of Westminster and County of Middlesex the Eighth day of August One thousand six hundred
sixty and one holden before John Lord Roberts Lord Privy Seal James Duke of Ormond in the Kingdome of Ireland
Lord Steward of His Majesties Household and Earle of Brecknock Mountague Earle of Lindsey Edward Earle of
Manchester and others the Commissioners of Sewers then and [theire<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] assembled by Authority of His Majesties
Commission of Sewers to them and others dire&bholigct;ed for the making of two new Sewers and enlarging and amending the
old Sewers near Charing Crosse for conveying the water away from annoying His Majesties Pallace at Whitehall be and
is hereby ratified and confirmed and shall be put in execution according to the true intent and meaning thereof with
full power to levy all the Arreares as by a Commission of Sewers can or may be done And all and every person &amp;
persons imployed or that have a&bholigct;ed therein be and are hereby indemnified and saved harmless from all manner of
Suites and A&bholigct;ions that may or shall be brought against any of them for the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Recital that Sea Coal Ashes, &amp;c. are thrown into the Streets.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">Inhabitants to sweep the Streets before their respe&bholigct;ive Houses twice a Week; Penalty 3s. 4d.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p27">And whereas great quantities of Sea-coal-ashes dust dirt and other filth of late times have beene and daily are throwne
into the Streets Lanes and Allies of the Cities of London and Westminster and Borough of Southwark and other
parts adjacent to the great annoyance of Your Majesties good People Bee it therefore Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid
That all and every person and persons inhabiting within the said Cities of London and Westminster and the Suburbs
and Liberties thereof and the Borough of Southwarke or in any of the said new built Streets Lanes or Allies
shall from the first day of May One thousand six hundred sixty and two sweep and cleanse or cause to be swept &amp;
cleansed all the Streets Lanes Allyes and publick places before theire respe&bholigct;ive Houses Buildings and Walls twice
every weeke That is to say on every Wednesday and every Saturday in the Weeke and all the soyle dirt and other
fifth shall cause to be taken up into Baskets Tubs or other Vessells ready for the Raker Scavenger or other Officer
appointed for that purpose to carry away upon pain to forfeit Three shillings and foure pence for every offence or
negle&bholigct; respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Persons not to throw Ashes, &amp;c. before their Houses;; Penalty 58.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">nor before other Houses, or before Churches, &amp;c.; but to keep the same till the Scavengers come; Penalty 20s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p29">And that no person or persons whatsoever shall throw cast or lay or cause permit or suffer to be throwne cast or
laid any Sea-coal ashes dust dirt or other fifth or annoyance in any open Street Lane or Alley within the said Cities or
places aforesaid before or against his her or theire owne dwelling Houses Buildings or Walls on the penalty of Five
shillings and if before the Houses Buildings or Walls of any of theire Neighbors or other the Inhabitants of the cities or
places aforesaid or before or against any Church or Church yard or any of His Majesties Houses Buildings or Walls or
any other publick Houses Buildings or places whatsoever or shall cast lay or throwe or cause to be cast laid or throwne
into any common or publick sink vault watercourse common sewer or high way within the said Cities or places aforesaid
or any other private Vault or Sink of any of his Neighbors or other Inhabitants any Ashes Dust Filth Ordure or other
noisome thing whatsoever but shall keepe or cause the same to be kept in theire respe&bholigct;ive Houses Backsides or
Yards untill such time as the Raker Scavenger or other Officer thereto appointed of the Ward Parish Street or place
where they dwell do come by or neare theire houses or doores with his Cart Barrow or other thing or things used for
cleansing the streets and carrying away thereof and shall carry or cause to be carried the said Ashes Dust or other
Filth and Annoyance aforesaid forth of theire Houses and deliver it unto the said Raker Scavenger or Officer or
othe	rwise put the same in his Cart Barrow or other thing as aforesaid upon pain to forfeit the s&bhouov;m of Twenty
shillings for every such offence.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII.; Churchwardens and Officers of Palaces, &amp;c. liable to the like Penalties.</head>
			<para id="p30">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed That the respe&bholigct;ive Church-wardens the House keepers of Whitehall and other His
Majesties Houses House keepers or Porters of Noblemens Houses Ushers Porters or Keepers of Courts of Justice
and all other Publick Houses and Places respe&bholigct;ively shall be lyable to and shall suffer the like Penalties Forfeitures
and Punishments for every the before mentioned offences or negle&bholigct;s committed done or suffered to be done before
any Church or Church yard or before or any of His Majesties Houses Buildings or Walls or before any Noblemens
Houses Buildings or Walls or before any other Publick Houses Buildings or places whatsoever respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX.; Hooping Barrels, &amp;c. in the Streets;</head>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 20s.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p32">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the First day of May One thousand
six hundred sixty and twoe no person or persons shall hoope wash or cleanse any Pipes Barrells or other Caskes
or Vessells in any the Streets Lanes or open Passages aforesaid nor shall set out [any<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] empty Coaches to make or
mend or rough Timber or Stones to be sawen or wrought in the Streets on the penalty of Twenty shillings for
every offence</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX.; Scavengers, &amp;c. to bring Carts, &amp;c. and to give Notice thereof by a Bell, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">and to carry away Filth, &amp;c.; Penalty 40s.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p34">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Rakers Scavengers or other Officers thereunto
appointed every day in the weeke (except Sundayes and other Holydayes) shall bring or cause to be brought
Carts Dung pots or other fitting carriages into all streets and places within theire respe&bholigct;ive Wards Parishes
Charges and Divisions where such Carts or Carriages can pass and att or before theire approach by a Bell Horne
Clapper or otherwise shall make distin&bholigct; and loud noise and give notice to the Inhabitants of theire coming and
make the like noise and give the like notice in every Court Alley or place into which the said Carts cannot
passe and abide and stay there a convenient time in such sort that all persons concerned may bring forth theire
respe&bholigct;ive Ashes Dust Dirt Filth and Soil to the respe&bholigct;ive Carts or Carriages so staying as aforesaid all which the
said Rakers Scavingers or other Officers aforesaid shall dayly carry or cause to be carried away upon pain to
forfeit forty shillings for every offence or negle&bholigct; respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI.; All the Streets, &amp;c. (Exception) to be paved, &amp;c. at the Costs of the Householders.</head>
			<para id="p35">
				<emph type="i">How such Pavements to be done.; Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p36">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all the open Streets Lanes and Alleys within the
said Cities and Places aforesaid (excepting only the new Paving of such Streets and Places for which any of (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) the
Inhabitants have contributed and paid theire respe&bholigct;ive proportions to the Commission[er]s before named according to
the Rates aforesaid shall be forthwith sufficiently repaired or paved &amp; from time to time hereafter maintained
and kept sufficiently repaired or paved at the costs and charges of the Householders in the same Streets Lanes
and Alleys respe&bholigct;ively in manner following (that is to say) every of the said Householders to repaire and pave
and to keepe repaired and paved the Streets Lanes or Alleys before his House and so far as his Housing Walls or
Building extend unto the [Channell<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] or middle of the same Street Lane or Alley upon pain to forfeit Twenty
shillings for every Perch or Rod (and after that rate for a greater or lesser quantity) for every default and of
Twenty shillings a weeke for every weeke after untill the same shall be sufficiently paved and amended</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII.; Proviso for Custom of paving ancient Streets, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p38">Provided alwaies That such ancient Streets Lanes and Alleys within the said Cities or either of them the
Suburbs and Liberties thereof and Borough of Southwark as by custome and usage have beene repaired &amp; paved
in other manner shall be hereafter repaired paved and maintained in such sort and manner and by such person and
persons as have heretofore used to repaire pave and maintaine the same under the penalties aforesaid Any thing in
this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII.; Regulations for hanging Candles, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 1s</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p40">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every householder within the said Cities the
Suburbs and Liberties thereof and in all other the places aforesaid whose house adjoyns unto and is next the
Street from Michaelmas untill our Lady day yearely shall every hight set or hang out Candles or Lights in
Lanthornes or other wise in some part of his house next the street to enlighten the same for Passengers from such
time as it shall growe [darke<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] untill Nine of the clocke in the evening upon pain to forfeit the s&bhouov;m of One shilling
for every default.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Judges, Justices of Peace, &amp;c. upon View or Confession, or Proof by one Witness, may convi&bholigct; of any of the Offences aforesaid.</head>
			<para id="p41">
				<emph type="i">Penalties how to be disposed of.; Penalties to be levied by Distress; if no Distress or Non-payment of Penalty, (Exception of Peers) Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p42">And for the more speedy Reformation and punishment of all and [every<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] the offences aforesaid Bee it further
Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every one of His Majesties Justices of either Bench and Barons of his
Exchequer and every Justice of Peace of the said Cities of London and Westminster and places aforesaid (within
theire severall Limitts respe&bholigct;ively) shall have power and Authority upon his own knowledge or view confession
of the party or proof of one credible witnesse upon Oath before him (which Oath by vertue of this A&bholigct; such
Justice shall have power to administer) to convi&bholigct; any person or persons of any the Offences aforesaid whereby
such persons or persons so convi&bholigct; shall incur the penalties and forfeitures aforesaid one Moyety whereof shall be
disposed and imployed for and towards the reparation paving and cleansing of the Street or place where the offence
shall bee committed and as much or all of the other Moyety as the Justice shall thinke fitt for him or them that
shall discover and prosccute the same in case the said convi&bholigct;ion be by such discovery and prosecution and if
the convi&bholigct;ion be by the view or knowledge of such Justices then the said whole penalty to go and be imployed
for and towards the repairing paving and cleansing of the said streets or place and shall be leavyed by distresse
and sale of the Goods and Chattells of the Offender by warrant under the hand and seale of any such Justice
to be dire&bholigct;ed to the Constable or any other Officer of the same Parish rendring the surplusage to the party
and in default of distresse or non payment of the said penalties within six dayes after demand thereof or notice in
writing left att the House or dwelling place of the offender by the said Constable or any other Officer the said
Offender not being a Peer of this Realm shall bee committed to the Common Goal of the said County or City
respe&bholigct;ively by the warrant of any such Justice under his hand and seale there to remain without Bail or Mainprize
untill payment.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Scavengers to be ele&bholigct;ed, and Rates paid, according to ancient Custom.</head>
			<para id="p43">
				<emph type="i">Receivers accountable.; Officers how to be chosen in Westminster. Times of Ele&bholigct;ion in other Places.; Notice.; What Persons to be appointed.; To be confirmed by Justices.; and then to take Office upon them.; Proceedings in case of Refusal.; Penalty.; Penalties how to be employed; to be levied by Distress.; If no Distress, Improsonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p44">And for the better raising and leavying of moneys to defray the charges and pay the wages of the said
Scavengers Rakers or other Officers imployed in cleansing of the Streets Lanes Alleys and other places aforesaid
and carrying of the said ashes dirt filth and soyle. Be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid That within
the City of London and Liberties thereof the Scavengers Rakers and such like Officers shall be ele&bholigct;ed and the Rates Taxes and Assessments for Scavengers Rakers and such like Officers wages for cleansing the Streets shall be
rated taxed assessed raised and paid by the Parishoners and Inhabitants of every Parish and &bhopcrl;cin&bholigct; respe&bholigct;ively
within the said City and Liberties thereof according to the ancient custome and usage of the said City And the
Receivers of all such moneys shall be accomptable as formerly And all new Messuages Tenements and Houses
within the limits aforesaid shall be likewise rated taxed and assessed and shall pay proportionably with others.
And that within the City of Westminster the said Officers shall be chosen and the Rates made and paid according
to the ancient Custom of the said City And in all other the Parishes and places aforesaid upon every Tuesday
or Wednesday in Easter weeke the Constables Church wardens and Overseers for the poore and Surveyors of the
High wayes of every the said Parishes and places respe&bholigct;ively or the greater number of them giving notice unto
or calling togeather such other Inhabitants of theire respe&bholigct;ive Parishes as have formerly borne the like Offices
therein they or the greater number of them shall make choice of and shall nominate and appointe two or more
able persons that are Tradesmen of theire Parish to be Scavengers for the streets lanes and other open Passages
of each Ward and Division within the said Parish for the yeare then next following and untill others be chosen
and setled in theire places which persons soe chosen and being approved and confirmed under the hands of any
two Justices of Peace within theire respe&bholigct;ive Limits and Jurisdi&bholigct;ions shall within seaven dayes after theire
Ele&bholigct;ion and Confirmation and notice thereof take that Office and Duty upon them upon pain to forfeit Twenty
pounds by every refuser respe&bholigct;ively And in case of refusall by any person or persons so chosen and confirmed
then other able persons shall be chosen and confirmed in manner aforesaid within seaven dayes after such refusall
in the place of him or them which shall soe refuse and the person or persons so chosen and confirmed and having
notice thereof shall undergoe the like paine in case of refusall or not taking the said Office and Duty upon him or
them within seaven dayes after he or they shall be chosen and confirmed and have notice thereof as aforesaid the said
Penalties to be disposed and imployed for or towards the mending and repairing of the Streets and Wayes of the
same Parish Ward or Division and to be levied by Distresse and Sale of the Goods and Chattels of the Offender by
Warrant under the hand and seale of any Justice of the Peace of any of the places aforesaid to be dire&bholigct;ed to the
Constables or other Officers of the same Parish or any twoe or more of them (rendring the surplusage to the party)
and in default of distresse or [non<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] payment within six dayes after demaund thereof or notice left in writing att the
house or dwelling place of the offender by the said Constables or Officers the said offender to be committed to the
Goale of the said County or City respe&bholigct;ively by the warrant of any such Justice under his Hand and Seale there to
remaine without Baile or Mainprize until payment.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Within 20 Days after Ele&bholigct;ion of Scavengers. Inhabitants to meet on Summons of Churchwardens, &amp;c.and settle Rate</head>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">which being confirmed by Justices, to be paid Quarterly.; In case of Refusal, &amp;c. to pay, Distress or Imprisonment. Except Peers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p46">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That within Twenty dayes after the Ele&bholigct;ion and
Confirmation of the said Scavengers as aforesaid the Constables Church Wardens and Overseers for the Poore and
of the High wayes of the said Parishes and Places respe&bholigct;ively or the greater number of them giving notice unto
or calling togeather such Inhabitants of theire respe&bholigct;ive Parishes as have formerly borne the like office therein
They or the greater number of them then present shall make and setle a Tax Rate or Assessment according to
a Pound rate to be imposed or set upon the Inhabitants of the said Parish Ward or Division for the yeare following
for the purposes aforesaid which being allowed and confirmed by any two of the Justices of the Peace of the
places aforesaid respe&bholigct;ively shall be quarterly paid by every respe&bholigct;ive Inhabitant upon demaund made thereof by
the Beadle of the Parish or other Officer appointed to gather and colle&bholigct; the same And in case of refusall or
negle&bholigct; shall by warrant of any two such Justices of the Peace under theire Hands and Seales be levied by Distresse
and Sale of the Offenders Goods and for want of Distresse by Imprisonment of the Offender (he not being a Peere of
this Realme) untill payment as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. A&bholigct;ion brought against Persons executing A&bholigct; to be laid in the proper County.</head>
			<para id="p47">
				<emph type="i">General Issue.; Double Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p48">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion or Suit shall be brought
or prosecuted by any person or persons against any Judge Commissioner Justice of the Peace Constable or other
Officer or Minister aforesaid or against any person or persons imployed by them or any of them or authorized
by this A&bholigct; to do or perform as by this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed for any matter cause or thing by them or any of them
done committed or executed by vertue or reason of this A&bholigct; or any Clause or Article therein contained that then
in every such case the A&bholigct;ion shall be laid in the proper County where the fa&bholigct; was done and not else where
and the Defendant or Defendants may plead the General Issue and give the speciall Matter in Evidence att the
Tryall That the same was done in pursuance and by Authoritie of this A&bholigct; And if upon Examination it shall soe
appeare to be done the Jury shall find for the Defendant and in such [case<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] or if the Plaintiffe shall be Non suit or
discontinue his A&bholigct;ion after the Defendant hath appeared the Defendant shall have and recover his or theire double
costs which he or they shall sustaine or be put unto by reason of his or theire wrongfull vexation in defence of the
said A&bholigct;ion or Suit.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Recital that certain Streets, &amp;c. are too narrow to accommodate Coaches, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p49">
				<emph type="i">Lord Mayor, &amp;c. may receive Subscriptions for Enlargement thereof;; and may treat with Owners of Premises for pulling down, &amp;c.;Where Persons refuse or are unable to treat, Sheriff, &amp;c. may impannel a Jury.; Jury to assess Damage, &amp;c. on Oath.; Verdi&bholigct; of Jury and Judgments of Commissioners binding</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p50">And whereas the severall Streets and Passages hereafter mentioned (that is to say) The Street or Passage at or
neere the Stocks in London the Street and Passage from Fleet Conduit to S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Pauls Church in London the Passage
through the White Hart Inne from the Strand into Covent Garden The Street and Passage by and neare Exeter
house and the Savoy being obstru&bholigct;ed by a Rail and the unevennes of the ground thereabouts the Passage and
Street of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Martins lane out of the Strand the Passage or Street of Feild lane comonly called Jack an Apes lane
going betweene Chancery lane and Lincolns-Inn Feilds the Passage and Gatehouse of Cheape side into S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Pauls
Church yard the Passage against S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Dunstans Church in the West (being obstru&bholigct;ed by a Wall) the Street and
Passage by and neere the West end of the Poultrey in London and the Passage att Temple Barr are soe narrow that
they are incommodious to Coaches Carts and Passengers and prejudicial to Commerce and Tradeing Bee it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Lord Maior of the City of London the Recorder and Aldermen for the time
being togeather with such other Commissioners as His Majesty shall appoint under the Great Seale of England or
any five of them shall have full Power and Authority to receive all Subscriptions and Payments of voluntary
contributions of money or other endowments towards the Amendment and Enlargement of the Streets and places
before named or soe much of them or any of them as the said Commissioners or any five or more of them shall
judge fit a&bhonov;d necessary And are hereby further impowred to treat and agree with the Owners and Occupiers of
any such Houses as they shall judge fitt to be removed rebuilt or pulled downe or any part of them and upon
payment of such sum or sums of money soe agreed upon are hereby authorized to appoint workemen to pull the
said Houses downe or cause the said Owners or Occupiers to rebuild accordingly and this A&bholigct; shalbe sufficient to
indempnifie the said Commissioners and all persons authorized by them against the Heires Executors Administrators
or Assignes of any the said Owners or Occupiers as if the same had beene sold by Deed Feoffment bargain and
sale or other assurance in the Law and done by Fine and Recovery or any other way whatsoever And if there shall
be any persons Bodies Corporate or Collegiate that shall wilfully refuse to treat and agree as aforesaid or through
any disability by Non age Coverture or a speciall Entaile or other Impediment cannot That in such Cases the said
Commission[er]s are hereby authorized by vertue of this A&bholigct; to issue out Warrant or Warrant&bholngs; to the Sherrifs of
London whoe are hereby required accordingly to impannell and return a Jury before the said Commissioners
or any five of them which Jury upon theire Oathes to be administred by the said Commissioners are to enquire
and assesse such damage and recompence as they shall judge fit to be awarded to the Owners and Occupiers or
either of them of any such houses or any part thereof for theire respective Estates and Interest in the same as by
the said Commissioners shall be adjudged fitt to be pulled downe for the purposes aforesaid and such Verdi&bholigct; of
the Jury &amp; Judgement of the Commissioners thereupon and the legall payment or tender of the s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of
money so awarded and adjudged shall be binding to all intents and purposes against the said parties theire Heires
Executors Administrators and Assignes and others claiming any Title or Interest in the said Houses or in the
ground [whereupon<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] they stand or thereunto belonging and shall be a full Authority for the said Commissioners
or any five of them to cause the same to be executed and the said Houses accordingly to be removed and
pulled downe</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Houses on the other Side.</head>
			<para id="p51">
				<emph type="i">In case of Refusal or Incapacity of Owners to agree, Jury impannelled in the same manner.; Money or Rent assessed paid into the Chamber of London, and may be recovered at Law.; Monies so raised how employed.; Verdi&bholigct; of Jury and Judgment of Commissioners binding</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p52">And whereas the houses that shall remaine standing on the other side of the said Street or Streets or behind
the said Houses that shall be soe pulled downe as aforesaid will receive much advantage in the value of theire
Rents by the liberty of Air and free recourse for Trade and other conveniencies by such enlargment It is alsoe
ena&bholigct;ed by (<ref idref="n20">20</ref>) Authoritie aforesaid That in case of refusall or incapacity as aforesaid of the Owners or Occupiers of
the said Houses to agree and compound with the Commissioners for the same thereupon a Jury shall and may be
impannelled in manner and forme aforesaid to judge and assess upon the Owners and Occupiers of such Houses
such competent s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money or Annual Rent in considera&bhocotil;n of such improvement and melioration as
in reason and good conscience they shall judge and thinke fitt which said s&bhouov;m and s&bhouov;ms of money or Rent shall
be paid to the Chamberlaine of the City of London for the time being and such other Treasurer or Treasurers as
shall be appointed by the said Commissioners or any five or more of them who are hereby enabled from time
to time to receive and recover the same by A&bholigct;ion at Law and whose Receipt shall be a good Discharge to the
said Owners and Tenants and who are hereby appointed to receive and pay and be accomptable for the same
according to such dire&bholigct;ions as shall from time to time be given them by the said Commissioners and the Moneys
so raised or Rents so received shall be expended upon the Purchasing or Rebuilding Houses on the other side the
Street and upon paving and amending of the Wayes and Streets aforesaid according to the purport of this A&bholigct;
And the said Verdi&bholigct; of the Jury and Judgement of the Commissioners in the cases aforesaid shall be sufficient
and conclusive in Lawe to all intents &amp; purposes against the said Owners and Occupiers theire Heires Executors
Administrators and Assignes</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Commissioners to take an Oath.</head>
			<para id="p53">Provided alwaies and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no person shall be enabled to a&bholigct;
as a Commissioner to the intents and purposes aforesaid untill he shall first have taken his corporall Oath before
the Lord Chancellor or Lord High Treasurer of England for the time being for the due and impartial execution
of the Trusts by this A&bholigct; c&bhooov;mitted to him.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Lord Mayor, &amp;c. of London to be joint Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p54">
				<emph type="i">Dean of Westminster, &amp;c. to be joint Commissioners.; Continuance of A&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p55">Provided also That the Lord Maior Recorder &amp; Aldermen of the City of London for the time being shalbe
and are hereby authorized to be Joynt C&bhooov;mission[er]s &amp; to exercise all the Powers of this A&bholigct; to all the ends &amp;
purposes thereof which are to be ordered done or executed within the said City or the Liberties thereof And
likewise That the Deane of Westm[inster] the High Steward &amp; his Deputy Steward &amp; the two High Burgesses of the
said City of Westm[inster] for the time being shall be &amp; are hereby authorized to be Joynt C&bhooov;mission[er]s &amp; to exercise
all the Powers of this A&bholigct; to all the ends &amp; purposes thereof which are to be ordered done or executed within
the said City of Westm[inster] or the Liberties thereof Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding. This A&bholigct;
to continue &amp; be in force untill the end of the First Session of the next &bhopubr;liament</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Hackney <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">The Roll is illegible here, but it is "Workes" in the Original A&bholigct;.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">this <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">not <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">other <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">there <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Kennell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">drake <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">everyes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">not <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">whereon <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


