<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47300" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1661</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for the well Governing and Regulating of Corporations [Rot. Parl. 13 C. II. p. 2. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
		<section id="s1">
			<head>Recital that Questions are likely to arise concerning Ele&bholigct;ions in Corporations.; Commissions to issue for England, Wales, and Berwick.</head>
			<para id="p1">WHEREAS questions are likely to arise concerning the validity of Ele&bholigct;ions of Magistrates and other Officers
and Members in Corporations as well in respe&bholigct; of removing some as placing others during the late troubles
contrary to the true intent and meaning of theire Charters and Liberties And to the end that the succession in such
Corporations may be most probably perpetuated in the hands of persons well affe&bholigct;ed to His Majesty and the
established Government it being to well knowne that notwithstanding all His Majesties endeavors and unparaleld
Indulgence in pardoning all that is past neverthelesse many evill spirits are still working Wherefore for prevention
of the like mischeife for the time to come and for preservation of the Publique Peace both in Church and State
Bee it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons assembled in Parliament and by the Authoritie of the same That Commissions shall
before the twentieth day of February next be issued forth under the Great Seale of England unto such persons
as His Majestie shall appoint for the executing [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] the Powers and Authorities herein after expressed And that all
and every the persons to be named Commissioners in the said Commissions respe&bholigct;ively shall by vertue of this A&bholigct;
be Commissioners respe&bholigct;ively for and within the severall Cities Corporations and Burroughs and Cinque Ports and
theire Members and other Port Townes within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweed for which they shall be respe&bholigct;ively nominated and appointed</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II Proviso for Corporation Charters.</head>
			<para id="p2">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That no Charter of any Corporation Cities Townes
Burroughs Cinque Ports and theire Members and other Port Townes in England or Wales or Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweed shall at any time hereafter be avoided for or by reason of any a&bholigct; or thing done or omitted to be
done before the First day of this present Parliament</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Mayors, &amp;;c. before 25th March 1653.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">to take the Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy, and the Oath following</emph>;</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all persons who upon the Foure and twentieth day of
December One thousand six hundred sixty and one shall be Maiors Aldermen Recorders Bailiffes Towne-Clerks
Common Councel men and other persons then bearing any Office or Offices of Magistracy or Places or Trusts or
other Imployment relating to or concerning the Government of the said respe&bholigct;ive Cities Corporations and Burroughs
and Cinque Ports and theire Members and other Port Towns shall at any time before the Five and twentieth day
of March One thousand six hundred sixtie and three when they shall be thereunto required by the said respe&bholigct;ive
Commissioners or any three or more of them take the Oathes of Allegiance and Supremacy and this Oath
following.</para>
			<para id="p5">I. A. B. do declare and beleive That it is not lawfull upon any pretence whatsoever to take Arms against the
King and that I do abhor that Traiterous Position of taking Arms by His Authority against His Person or
against those that are c&bhooov;missioned by Him So helpe me God.</para>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">and subscribe the following Declaration</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And alsoe att the same time shall publiquely subscribe before the said Commissioners or any Three of them
this following Declaration.</para>
			<para id="p8">I. A. B. do declare That I hold that there lyes no Obligation upon me or any other person from the Oath commonly
called The Solemn League and Covenant and that the same was in it selfe an unlawfull Oath and imposed upon
the Subje&bholigct;s of this Realm against the knowne Laws and Liberties of the Kingdome.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Those who refuse to be removed,</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">and Offices void</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And that all such of the said Maiors and other the persons aforesaid by whom the said Oaths are to be taken
and Declaration subscribed as aforesaid who shall refuse to take and subscribe the same within the time and in
manner aforesaid shall from and imediately after such refusall be by Authority of this A&bholigct; (ipso fa&bholigct;o) removed and
displaced of and from the said Offices and Places [respe&bholigct;ively &amp;; the said Offices &amp;; Places<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] from and imediately
after such refusall shall be and are hereby declared and adjudged to be void to all intents and purposes as if the
said respe&bholigct;ive persons so refusing were naturally dead</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Commissioners may remove Persons, though they have taken the Oaths and subscribed the Declaration.</head>
			<para id="p11">And neverthelesse Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said Commissioners or any Five
or more of them shall have full power by vertue of this A&bholigct; by Order and Warrant under theire hands and seales
to displace or remove any of the persons aforesaid from the said respe&bholigct;ive Offices and Places or Trusts aforesaid
if the said Commissioners or the major part of them then present shall deem it expedient for the publique
safety although such persons shall have taken and subscribed or be willing to take and subscribe the said Oathes
&amp;; Declaration</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Commissioners may restore any Magistrate unduly removed.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Such Persons taking the Oaths and subscribing the Declaration</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And bee it alsoe Ena&bholigct;ed That the said respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any Five or more of them as aforesaid
shall have power to restore such person or persons as have beene illegally or unduely removed into the places
out of which he or they were removed and alsoe to put and place into the Offices and Places which by any of
the wayes aforesaid shall be void respe&bholigct;ively some other person or persons then being or which have beene
Members or Inhabitants of the said respe&bholigct;ive Cities Corporations and Burroughs and Cinque Ports and theire
Members and other Port Townes who shall before the said respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any three or more of
them take the said Oaths of Obedience and Supremacy and the said other Oath and subscribe the Declaration
herein before particularly mentioned and that the said persons from and after the taking of the said Oaths and
subscribing the said Declaration shall hold and enjoye and be vested in the said Places and Offices as if they had
beene duely ele&bholigct;ed and chosen according to the Charters and former usages of the said respe&bholigct;ive Cities Corporations
and Burroughs Cinque Ports and theire Members and other Port Townes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Commissioners empowered to give the Oaths, &amp;;c.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Who shall give the Oaths and Declaration after the Commissions are determined</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">And be it further Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any three or
more of them respe&bholigct;ively shall have power during the continuance of theire respe&bholigct;ive Commissions to administer
the Oathes aforesaid and tender the said Declaration to the said persons hereby required to take and subscribe the
same And from and after the expiration of the said respe&bholigct;ive Commissions the said three Oathes and Declaration
shall bee from time to time administred and tendred to such person and persons who by the true meaning of this
A&bholigct; or any Clause therein contained are to take the same by such person or persons respe&bholigct;ively who by the
Charters or Usages of the said respe&bholigct;ive Cities Corporations and Burroughs and Cinque Ports and theire Members
and other Port Townes ought to administer the Oath for due executing the said Places or Offices respe&bholigct;ively
and in default of such by two Justices of the Peace of the said Cities Corporations and Burroughs and Cinque
Ports and theire Members and other Port Townes for the time being if any such there be or otherwise by two
Justices of the Peace for the time being of the respe&bholigct;ive Counties where the said Cities Corporations or Burroughs
or Cinque Ports or theire Members or other Port Townes are.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. The Commissioners to cause Entries of Oaths taken;</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">and deliver them to the Town Clerks, &amp;;c. to be entered in Books</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And be it likewise Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said Commissioners Justices of the Peace and
other persons hereby authorized to administer the said Oaths and tender the said Declaration respe&bholigct;ively shall
cause Memorandums or Entries to be made of all Oathes taken before them and subscriptions made as aforesaid
and deliver the same once in a yeare to the respe&bholigct;ive Town Clerks or other Register or Clerke of the said
respe&bholigct;ive Cities Corporations and Burroughs and Cinque Ports and theire Members and other Port-towns who
shall cause the same to be fairely entred into the Books or Registers belonging to the said respe&bholigct;ive Cities
Corporations or Burroughs or Cinque Ports and theire Members or other Port-towns.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. None to be ele&bholigct;ed to the Offices aforesaid, unless he shall have received the Sacrament within a Year.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">and shall take the Oaths, and subscribe the Declaration</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">Provided alsoe and be it Ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the expiration of the said
Commissions no person or persons shall for ever hereafter be placed ele&bholigct;ed or chosen in or to any the Offices or
Places aforesaid that shall not [have<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] within one yeare next before such Ele&bholigct;ion or Choice taken the Sacrament
of the Lords Supper according to the Rites of the Church of England and that every such person and persons so
placed ele&bholigct;ed or chosen shall likewise take the aforesaid three Oathes and subscribe the said Declaration att the
same time when the Oath for the due execution of the said Places and Offices respe&bholigct;ively shall be administred
And in default hereof every such placing ele&bholigct;ion and choice is hereby Ena&bholigct;ed and Declared to bee void.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X.The usual Oath to be taken.</head>
			<para id="p20">Provided alwaies and be it Ena&bholigct;ed That every person who shall be placed in any Corporation by vertue of
this A&bholigct; shall upon his admission take the Oath or Oaths usually taken by the Members of such Corporation</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. How long Commissioners Power to continue.</head>
			<para id="p21">Provided alsoe and be it hereby Ena&bholigct;ed That the Powers granted to the Commissioners by vertue of this
A&bholigct; shall continue and be in force untill the Five and twentieth of March One thousand six hundred sixty three
and no longer</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Commissioners sued may plead the General Issue, and recover Treble Costs.</head>
			<para id="p22">Provided That if any A&bholigct;ion Bill Plaint or Suit shall att any time hereafter happen to be brought or commenced
against any person or persons nominated a Commissioner as aforesaid for any matter or thing by them or any of
them done by vertue or in pursuance of this A&bholigct; That then it shall be lawfull to and for every such person and
persons against whom such A&bholigct;ion Bill Plaint or Suit shall be brought or commenced to plead the Generall Issue
and to give this A&bholigct; or any other speciall matter in Evidence And if the Verdi&bholigct; shall passe with the Defendant
or Defendants in any such A&bholigct;ion or the Plaintiff or Plaintiffs become Non suite or suffer any discontinuance
thereof That in every such case the Judge or Judges before whom the said matter shall be tryed or be depending
shall by force and vertue of this A&bholigct; allow unto the Defendant or Defendants his or theire treble Costs which
he or they shall have sustained by reason of theire wrongfull vexation in defence of the said A&bholigct;ion or Suit for
which the said Defendant or Defendants shall have like remedy as in other cases where Costs by the Lawes of
this Realme are given to the Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for Reversions of Offices in London.</head>
			<para id="p23">Provided alwaies and it is hereby Declared That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend or
be to the prejudice of any person or persons whatsoever that hath any Reversion or Reversions of any [of<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] the
Offices or Places belonging to the City of London by force or vertue of any Order Grant Designation or Nomina&bhocotil;n
of the Lord Maior and Court of Aldermen of the said City heretofore respe&bholigct;ively made or granted to him or
them before the times of the late Wars for or in respe&bholigct; of such Grant Designation or Nominacon onely Any
thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">The whole of the Public A&bholigct;s of 13 Car. II. are contained in one Bundle at the Parliament Office, and are numbered in
succession; but in the " Long Calendar" at that Office those which here follow are distinguished as having been passed at the
"Second Meeting" in that Year, which, as appears by the Title of the Second Part of the Rolls containing the A&bholigct;s of such
Second Meeting, was from the 20th Day of November to the 20th Day of December next following after "Adjournment," and
not after "Prorogation", and they cannot therefore, corre&bholigct;ly, be stated as having passed in a Second Session; and the Public A&bholigct;s
of 13 Car. II. are intituled "Stat.1." "Stat. 2." to prevent confusion in reference from the private Editions, and in conformity
to the ancient method of making up the Statute Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


