<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47311" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for Distribution of Threescore thousand pounds amongst the truly Loyal &amp; Indigent Commission Officers
and for assessing of Offices and distributing [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Moneys thereby raised for theire further supply.[Rot. Parl. 14 C. II p. 2. nu. I.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that there was a loyal Party which bore Arms in defence of the late and present King;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that by means thereof the King had returned in Peace and Triumph.; Reasons for passing this Act.; &pound;60,000 to be distributed amongst the loyal and indigent Officers</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas there was a Loyall Party which through all hazards and extremities in the defence of the Kings
Person Crown and Dignity the Rights and Priviledges of Parliament the Religion Lawes and Honour of the
English Nation did beare Armes by the Command of His late Majestie of ever blessed Memory according to theire duty
and the known Lawes of this Land and did with an unwearied Courage Faith and Constancy with theire lives and
fortunes oppose that barbarous Rebellion raised against His most Excellent Majestie in the yeare One thousand six
hundred forty and twoe by some of the men then sitting at Westminster till by expresse Orders from His Sacred
Majesty in One thousand six hundred forty and six the said loyall and worthy persons were commanded to render and
disband which Orders being obeyed and a new discovery being made of further Treasons against the life of theire most
gracious Soveraign they entred into severall fresh attempts to save Him in which some fell a noble Sacrifice for theire
Countrey and the rest asserted with the same vigorous and a&bholigct;ive Loyalty after the horrid murder of that glorious Prince
the Rights and Interests of His Royall Successor and with the same restlesse zeale opposed all succeeding Usurpations
untill that Great Captaine-the Duke of Albermarle (a person for ever to be remembred by all English men with
Honour and Admiration) and other worthy persons did improve the long expe&bholigct;ed opportunity of theire Conjun&bholigct;ion
with the Loyall [Party<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of this Nation by meanes whereof His Sacred Majesty returned in Peace and Triumph and in
the safety and government of His gracious Majesty all the good people of England are restored to the well being of
the Publique and to all theire Lawes Liberties and Fortunes Wee therefore the Lords &amp; Commons for the perpetuall
memory of the eminent deservings of the said Loyall Party and the encouragement of Loyalty to future ages do
hereby declare and make manifest our high esteeme of theire great services and sufferings exceeding all possibility
of present compensa&bhocotil;n but that provision might be made for theire honourable Wants (so far as stands with a
Kingdome exhausted by the Rapine &amp; Oppression of a long Rebellion) wee have else where beseecht Your most
Excellent Majesty to ena&bholigct; a certaine annual Rate upon Parishes for the supply of all the Loyall and Suffering
Souldiers in generall And wee doe herein most humbly beseech Your Majesty That it may be ena&bholigct;ed and be it
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal
and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That the s&bhouov;m of Threescore
thousand [pounds<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] be with most convenient speed distributed amongst such truly Loyal and Indigent Officers who have
had real Command of Souldiers according to theire several Commissions and who have never deserted His Majestie
nor His blessed Fathers service during the late times of Rebellion and Usurpation and who have not a sufficient
livelihood of theire own nor have since His Majesties returne obtained any Reward Office or Imployment sufficient
for a livelyhood by such wayes meanes and proportions as shall be hereafter appointed</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. To be paid to a Treasurer chosen by Commissioners at the times and by the means herein mentioned</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">13 Car. II. Stat. 2. c. 3.; And upon Payment the Acquittance of such Treasurer to be a Discharge to Receiver General.; Receiver General not paying to Treasurer may be sued</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And to that purpose it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by His most Excellent Majesty (out of His special Grace and Favour
towards His faithfull Souldiers and Servants) that Threescore thousand pounds of good English money be paid
unto such person as shall be chosen Treasurer by the Commissioners according as is hereafter declared at such
time or times and by the wayes and meanes following (that is to say) That all the severall Moneys or Taxes
ariseing out of the Assessments of and from the Counties of Cornwal Rutland Monmouth Lancaster Westmerland
and Anglesey for all the Eighteen Monthes according to an Act entituled An a&bholigct; for granting unto the Kings
Majesty Twelve hundred and threescore thousand pounds to be assessed and levied by an Assessment of Threescore
and ten thousand pounds by the Moneth for Eighteen Moneths shall be duly paid unto such Treasurer as
aforesaid by the respe&bholigct;ive Receivers General or such other person or persons as are or shall be appointed by
His Majesty for the Receipt thereof in all or any the said Counties according to the several times and dayes of
Payment dire&bholigct;ed them in the said a&bholigct; [Any thing in the said a&bholigct;<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] contained to the contrary nowithstanding And
upon Payment of the said Moneys accordingly the Acquittance under the Hand and Seale of such Treasurer as
aforesaid shall be a sufficient discharge to any such Receiver General for such respe&bholigct;ive Payment against the
Kings Majesty and every other person or persons whatsoever and after such Payment made noe such Receiver
General shall undergoe any trouble or payment of Fees by reason of Processe from the Exchequer for the same
Moneys But if any such Receiver General or such other person or persons as are or shall be appointed by His
Majesty for the Receipt of such Assessments in the said several Counties shall refuse or faile to pay the same
respe&bholigct;ively unto such Treasurer as aforesaid according to the times and dayes of Payment aforesaid that then it
shall and may be lawfull for such Treasurer to sue for the same in any Court of Record at Westminster and to
recover the same with damages.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Commissioners named for granting Certificates to Officers.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it ena&bholigct;ed That for granting Certificates to such Officers as are before declared all and every the
persons hereafter named shall be Comissioners of and for the several and respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cities Burroughs
Townes and Places hereafter named that is to say.</para>
			<para id="p6">Bedford.</para>
			<para id="p7">For the County of Bedford Robert Lord Bruce eldest sonne of Thomas Lord Bruce of Wharleton in the
Kingdome of England and Earl of Elgin in the Kingdome of Scotland Sir Lewis Dives Sir Lodowick Dyar Sir
William Palmer of Hill Sir George Blundell Sir John Keeling Sir Humphrey Winch Francis Crawley Stephen
Anderson Richard Taylor Robert Audeley Richard Conquest Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p8">Berks.</para>
			<para id="p9">For the County of Berks George Fane John Lovelace Esquires Sir Richard Braham Knight and Baronett Richard
Nevil John Davis Richard Aldworth Humphry Hide Richard Harrison Esquires Sir Richard Powell Knight of the
Bath Sir Thomas Draper Baronet.</para>
			<para id="p10">Bucks.</para>
			<para id="p11">For the County of Bucks Sir John Burlace Sir Edmond Pye Sir William Bowyer Sir Philip Palmer Sir Robert
Croke Sir William Smith Sir William Tirringham William Burlace Henry Alnut Esquires Sir Toby Tirrell Baronet
Sir Ralph Verney Bret Norton [Es&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Robert Crooke Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p12">Cambridge.</para>
			<para id="p13">For the County of Cambridge The Lord Allington of Killard in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir William Compton
Sir Thomas Wendy Thomas Chicheley Esquire Thomas Crouch Esquire Sir John Cotton Sir Thomas Dayrel
Sir Isaac Thornton John Millicent Esquire and the Vice Chancellor of the University of Cambridge for the
time being.</para>
			<para id="p14">Chester.</para>
			<para id="p15">For the County of Chester and County of the City of Chester William Lord Brereton of Laghlin in the
Kingdome of Ireland Thomas Needham Esquire Sir Thomas Smith Sir George Warburton Baronets Sir Philip
Egerton Sir Jeffery Shackerly Sir Robert Cotton Knights Henry Leigh of Leigh Thomas Leigh of Adlington
Thomas Cholmondly Esquires Sir Richard Grosvenor Baronett.</para>
			<para id="p16">Cornwall.</para>
			<para id="p17">For the County of Cornwall Sir Chichester Wray Knight and Baronet Sir John Trelawney Knight and Baronet
Sir John Coryton Baronet Sir John Arundel Sir James Smith Bernard Greenvile Esquire Colonell Trelawney
Colonel Richard Arundell Colonel Edgcombe Colonel Trevanion Colonel Godolphin Colonel John Arundel John
Trelawney Esquire Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph>. Colonel Scawen Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph>. Colonel Robinson Major Degory Polewheele William Pendarvis
Charles Roscarrock Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p18">Cumberland.</para>
			<para id="p19">For the County of Cumberland Sir Philip Musgrave Sir Patricius Curwen Sir William Dalston Sir Edward
Musgrave Baronets Sir William Huddleston Sir Thomas Dacres Sir William Carleton Knights John Lamplew
William Musgrave George Denton John Lamplew Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p20">Derby.</para>
			<para id="p21">For the County of Derby The Lord Cavendish eldest Sonne of William Earle of Devonshire Anthil Grey
Esquire Sir John Harpur Knight John Frechvile John Milward Esquires Sir Henry Ivory Baronet George Vernon
of Sudbury William Fitzherbert of Tissington Edward Vernon John Low William Bullock Esquires Rowland
Eyre of Bradway Francis Barker Gentlemen Charles Cotton Henry Gilbert Richard Cooke Esquires Roger Allestry
Gen&bhocent; William Milward Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p22">Devon.</para>
			<para id="p23">For the County of Devon and City of Exon The Right Honourable Sir Hugh Pollard Comptroler of His
Majesties Household Sir Edward Seymour Sir Thomas Heal Sir Courtney Pool Baronets Sir James Smith Sir
Thomas Stuckley Sir Robert Cary Knights Arthur Basset John Giffard George Yeo Esquires Thomas Clifford John
Vowel Esquires Sir Coppleston Bampfeild Sir William Courtney Baronets</para>
			<para id="p24">Dorset.</para>
			<para id="p25">For the County of Dorset Colonel Strangewayes Colonel Lawrence Colonel Bishop Colonel Reymes Colonel
Radford Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph>. Colonel Uvedale Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph>. Colonel Butler Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph>. Colonel Philips Major Hastings Major Dolling Major
Hoskins Major Stiles Captaine Churchill Captaine Strangewayes Captaine Daubenay Captaine S<emph type="p">t</emph>. Loe Captaine
Miller Captain Freek Captaine William Ellisdon [Coronet<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Hussey.</para>
			<para id="p26">Durham.</para>
			<para id="p27">For the County of Durham Sir Nicholas Cole Sir Gilbert Gerrard Baronets Sir William Blakiston of Newton
Sir Francis Anderson Sir Joseph Cradock Doctor Thomas Burrell Colonel John Tempest Colonel Anthony Bierly
Cuthbert Car Esquire Colonel William Blakiston Colonel Forser.</para>
			<para id="p28">Newcastle upon Tyne.</para>
			<para id="p29">For the Town and County of Newcastle upon Tyne Sir John Marlay Maior Sir Nicholas Cole Knight and
Baronet Sir Thomas Davison Knight Henry Marlay Henry Brabant Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p30">Essex</para>
			<para id="p31">For the County of Essex Sir John Brampston Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Apleton Baronet Sir Edmond
Peirce Knight and Colonel Sir Henry Clerke Knight Sir William Ayloffe Baronet Colonel Gamaliel Caple Esquire
Captaine, William Bramston Captain, William Herris Captain John Turner Captain John Fanshaw Major John
Robinson Gen&bhocent;</para>
			<para id="p32">Gloucester</para>
			<para id="p33">For the County of Gloucester and the City and County of the City of Gloucester Henry Lord Herbert of
Ragland eldest Sonne of Edward Lord Marquesse of Worcester Robert Viscount Tracy of Ratchul in the Kingdome
of Ireland Sir Baynham Throckmorton Baronet Sir Nicholas Throckmorton Sir William Morton Knights Colonel
Richard Atkins Es&bhoqesq;uire Sir Henry Frederick Thyn Baronet Sir Robert Pointz Knight of the Bath John Grubham
How Thomas Chester Esquires Sir Gabriel Low Knight William Trye Richard Dowdswel Esquires Sir Richard
Ashfeild Sir Edward Bathurst Baronets Thomas Masters John Chamberlaine Esquires Sir Robert Atkins Knight
of the Bath Captaine Thomas Price Henry Powel Esquire (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) Earl of Newburgh in the Kingdome of Scotland
Sir Edward Massey.</para>
			<para id="p34">Hereford</para>
			<para id="p35">For the County of Hereford and City of the same Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland eldest Sonne of Edward
Lord Marquesse of Worcester John Viscount Scudamore of Sligoe in the Kingdome of Ireland James Scudamore
Esquire Sir Edward Hopton Sir Thomas Tomkins Fitzwilliam Conningsby Roger Vaughan Humphrey Cornwal Herbert
Westphaling Thomas Price Esquires Edward Aldern Do&bholigct;or of Law Herbert Awbrey John Skip Thomas Cocks
Esquires Sir John Kirle.</para>
			<para id="p36">Hertford.</para>
			<para id="p37">For the County of Hertford Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the Commons House of Parliament The
Lord Viscount Fanshawe of Donnamore in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Thomas Leventhorpe Baronet Sir Philip
Boteler Sir Ralph Bash Knights of the Bath Sir Francis Boteler Sir John Gore Sir John Wats Knights Sir Thomas
Fanshaw Knight of the Bath William Willoughby Arthur Sparks Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p38">Huntington.</para>
			<para id="p39">For the County of Huntington Colonel Henry Williams Sir John Hewet Baronet Lionell Walden John Heron
Robert Apreece Richard Nayler John Cotton Anthony South Esquires Sir Francis Compton.</para>
			<para id="p40">London and Westminster</para>
			<para id="p41">For the Cities of London and Westminster Sir Edward Turner Knight [Speakers<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] of the Commons House of
Parliament Sir Charles Berkley Knight Treasurer of His Majesties Household Sir William Compton Sir George
Carterett Sir John Denham Andrew Newport Es&bhoqesq; Sir Jeoffery Palmer Knight and Baronet His Majesties Attorney
General Sir Henage Finch Knight and Baronet His Majesties Sollicitor Generall Daniel Oneale Esquire William
Legg Esquire Sir Henry Bennett Sir Philip Warwicke Sir Allan Appsley Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir Nicholas Crisp
Major General Egerton Sir John Robinson Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph> of the Tower Colonel Robert Philips Renold Graham Esquire
Sir Herbert Price Baronet Sir Robert Haward John Ashburnham William Ashburnham Esquires Sir Richard Ford
John Birkenhead Doctor of Lawes Francis Finch Esquire Sir Thomas Smith Sir Robert Peake Sir Edmond Pearse
Knight William Garraway Esquire Sir John Harrison Sir John Jacob Sir John Wolstenholme Sir John Shawe
Sir Edmond Pye Sir Edward Ford Sir Richard Everard Sir Robert Bowles Sir Lancelot Lake Sir Thomas Allen
Sir George Benion Sir John Talbott John Russell Es&bhoqesq; Colonel Henry Washington Robert Lord Bruce eldest
Sonne of Thomas Lord Bruce of Wharlton in the Kingdome of England and Earl of Elgin in the Kingdome of
Scotland Edward Progers Esquire Sir Thomas Ingram Sir Robert Biron Sir Edward Broughton Thomas Morrice
Esquire Thomas Nevil Sir Richard Browne Sir Thomas Bludworth Sir Charles [Herbord<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Knight His Majesties
Surveyor General Colonel Richard Atkins John Porie Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p42">Kent.</para>
			<para id="p43">For the County of Kent and City of Canterbury Sir Thomas Payton Sir John Tufton Baronet Sir John Menns
Knight and Colonel Sir Francis Clarke Colonel Sir John Mayney Knight and Colonel Sir John Boys Knight and Colonel
Sir Edmond Peirse Knight and Colonel Colonel Thomas Colpeper Colonel Charles Finch Colonel Thomas Hestlackenden
Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph>. Colonel Henry Norwood Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph>. Colonel Richard Oxenden Major Manley Captain Richard Lee Captaine Pordage
Sir Anthony Aucher Knight John Heath Esquire Sir William Swan. Sir Francis Clerke Colonel.</para>
			<para id="p44">Lancaster.</para>
			<para id="p45">For the County of Lancaster The Honourable Edward Stanley Es&bhoqesq;uire William Stanley Es&bhoqesq; Sir George Middleton
Baronet Sir Henry Slaughter Sir Jeffery Shakerley Colonel Richard Kirkby Colonel Roger Noel Major William
Farrington Major Thomas Carus Captain Thomas Norris Robert Holt Es&bhoqesq; Sir Roger Bradshaigh Thomas Preston Hugh
Dickenson Esquires Major [Cothbert<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Ogle John Heath Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p46">Leicester</para>
			<para id="p47">For the County of Leicester Sir John Bale Sir [Wastan <ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Dixy Baronets Sir John Bale Knight Sir Eusaby Pelsant
Knight Edward Farnham of Quarnden Henry Turvill of Aston John Butler Esquires Robert Everard Gen&bhocent; Philip
Sherard Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p48">Lincoln.</para>
			<para id="p49">For the County of Lincoln the City and County of the same The Lord Viscount of Castleton in the Kingdome of
Ireland Sir Thomas Meres Sir Thomas Hussey Sir William Hickman Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath Sir Philip
Tirwhit Baronet Sir John Mounson Baronet &amp; Knight of the Bath Sir Robert Bolles Sir Robert Markham Sir William
Thorold Sir Robert Dallison Sir John Newton Sir Charles Hussey Baronetts Sir Adrian Scroope Knight of the Bath Sir
John Walpool Sir Charles Dallison Knights Charles Pelham Jarvis Hollis Erasmus Deligne Edward Tirwhit William
Whitchcoat Ralph Evers Redmain Burrell Henry Hall Edward Turney Thomas Thorie Charles Baodes Adam Claypool
John Lo&bholigct;on Thomas Booth Thomas Browne Esquires Mr. William Bishopp Edward Blow.</para>
			<para id="p50">Middlesex.</para>
			<para id="p51">For the County of Middlesex Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the House of Commons Sir Jeffrey Palmer
Knight and Baronet His Majesties Attorney General Sir Heneage Finch Knight and Baronet His Majesties Solicitor
General Sir John Bennet Knight of the Honourable Order of the Bath Sir Robert Howard Sir Thomas Ingram Sir
Thomas Allen Sir Henry Wroth Sir Francis Gerrard Sir Philip Warwick John Ashburnham Daniel Oneale Humphrey
Weld Esquires John Cary Esquire George Pitt Esquire Sir Lancelott Lake Knight Sir Henry Herbert Sir George Binion
Sir John Talbott John Russell Esquire Colonel Henry Washington Edmond Waller Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p52">Monmouth.</para>
			<para id="p53">For the County of Monmouth Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland eldest Sonn of Edward Lord Marquesse of Worcester
Sir Anthony Morgan Sir George Probert Knights William Jones of Lanarth Thomas Morgan of Lansoan Miles Morgan
William Morgan one of His Majesties Houshold Charles Hughes Roger Williams of Kentila Esquires James
Progers Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p54">Northampton</para>
			<para id="p55">For the County of Northampton Sir Jeffrey Palmer Knight and Baronet His Majesties Attorney General Sir Justinian
Isham Sir Thomas Cave Sir Samuel D'Anvers Baronet Samuel Clarke John Bagshaw Henry Edmonds John Willoughby
Richard Kingsman John Syers Lewis Palmer Humphrey Orme Christopher Thursby Walter Kirkham John Lynn
Christopher Pickering Goddard [Pemberton<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] William Stafford Esquires Colonel Henry Howard George Clarke
Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p56">Nottingham.</para>
			<para id="p57">For the County of Nottingham Sir Jervase Clifton Knight and Baronett Sir John Digby Francis Leeke Esquire
Colonel Isham Perkins Major General Anthony Eyre Cicil Cooper Es&bhoqesq; Colonel Anthony Gilby Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph>. Colonel Hugh
Carthwright Anthony Eyre Esquire Arthur Stanhop Henry Sacheveril Esquires.(<ref idref="n11">11</ref>)</para>
			<para id="p58">Norfolk.</para>
			<para id="p59">For the County of Norfolke and City of Norwich Lord Richardson of Cramond in the Kingdome of Scotland Sir
Ralph Hare Sir Allan Apsley Knight Roger L. Strange Edmond D'Grey Peter Glean Esquires John Anquish Thomas
Bozonn William Bladwel Robert London Gen&bhocent; Thomas Le Crosse Le Estrange Calthrope Esquires Sir Philip Woodhouse
Baronet John Cooke Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p60">Northumberland.</para>
			<para id="p61">For the County of Northumberland and Town of Berwick upon Tweed Henry Lord Viscount Mansfeild eldest
Sonne of William Lord Marquesse of Newcastle Colonel Edward Grey Sir Francis Liddell Sir Henry Widdrington
Colonel Thomas Fo[r<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]ster Colonel Ralph Hebburn Colonel James Ogle Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph>. Colonel John Rodliam Leiu<emph type="p">t</emph> Colonel John
Salkeild Daniel Collingwood.</para>
			<para id="p62">Oxon.</para>
			<para id="p63">For the County and City of Oxo&ntilde; The Lord Falkland in the Kingdome of Scotland Sir Henry Lea Sir Anthony Cope
Sir William Morton Sir Edmond Bray Colonel Sandys David Walter Es&bhoqesq; Major Healing Sir Thomas Penyston William
Knowles Esquire Sir John Clark Broom Whorwood Esquire Mr. Leonard Bowman now Maior of Oxford Colonel
Philip Wenman Sir Thomas Tipping George Chamberlain George Berrie of Culham Esquires Sir Timothy Tirrel Roger
Gregory Esquire Thomas Earl of Down in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir William Walter Sir William Fleetwood
Rowland Lacy Es&bhoqesq; William Shepard Captain Peter Langston Doctor Birkenhead John Wickham Gen&bhocent; James Herbert
Esquire and the Vice Chancelor of the University of Oxford for the time being John Stone Doctor Dalben Do&bholigct;or
Mewes Doctor Samuel Jackeson.</para>
			<para id="p64">Rutland.</para>
			<para id="p65">For the County of Rutland Philip Sherrard Sir Edward Heath Sir Richard Winckfeild Sir Edward Maria Winckfeild
Aelex Noel Esquire Abel Barker Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p66">Salop</para>
			<para id="p67">For the County of Salop Sir Francis Lawley Baronet Sir Thomas Woolrich Sir Walter a&bholigct;on Sir John Weld Sir
Richard Otley Andrew Newport Francis Thornes James Lacon Robert Sandford John Walcott Vincent Edwards Richard
Fowler Francis Walker Thomas Crumpe William Oakeley Esquire Edward Lloyd of Llanbardo.</para>
			<para id="p68">Stafford:</para>
			<para id="p69">For the County of Stafford and City and County of Litchfeild Walter Lord Aston in the Kingdome of Scotland
Sir Brian Broughton Knight and Baronet Randolph Egerton John Skrymsher the younger Esquire John Lane Edward
Vernon Anthony Dyott John Peirsehouse George Parker William Orme Esquires William Chetwynd Es&bhoqesq; Henry Gray
Es&bhoqesq; Sir Edward Bagott Baronett Robert Milward Es&bhoqesq; Sir Walter Wriothesly Baronet Colonel Harvey Bagott Richard
Snead Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p70">Somersett</para>
			<para id="p71">For the County of Somersett Francis Lord Hawley of Duncannon in the Kingdome of Ireland Amyas Pawlett
John Pawlett Esquires Sir Henry Berkley Sir Francis Dodington Sir Thomas Bridges Sir Hugh Windham Colonel
Edmond Windham Colonel Francis Windham Colonel George Stawell Colonel Robert Phillips Colonel Pigot Colonel
John Tint Colonel Helyer Edward Phillips Peregrine Palmer George Sydenham Robert Hawley Esquires John
Mallett Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p72">Bristol</para>
			<para id="p73">For the City and County of the City of Bristol Francis Lord Hawley of Duncannon in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir
Humphry Hooke Knight Nathaniel Cale Es&bhoqesq; William Colston Richard Gregson John Thrustone William Cole John
Knight the elder Henry Creswick John Lock Thomas Chester Sir Maurice Berkley John Knight the younger Sir Robert
Pointz Knight of the Bath.</para>
			<para id="p74">Southampton.</para>
			<para id="p75">For the County of Southampton and Towne and County of the same Charles Lord S<emph type="p">t</emph>. John of Basing eldest Sonne of
John Lord Marquesse of Winchester Sir John Mills Sir John Norton Baronets Sir Humphrey Bennett Knight Sir William
Courtney Knight and Baronett Richard Goddard Esquire Sir William Meux Colonel Walter Slingsby Edward Worsley
Esquire Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph>. Colonel Turney William Lisle [Es&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Sir Richard Ford Knight Laurence Hide Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p76">Suffolke.</para>
			<para id="p77">For the County of Suffolke Sir Henry Felton Sir Henry North Baronets Sir Edmond Pooley Sir George Reeve
Knights John Hervey Esquire Benjamin Cutler Fitz Nun Lambe Esquires Francis Cheney Gen&bhocent; Henry Jermin Esquire
Colonel Farr Deputy Governour of Languedforth Sir John Hanmer Sir Robert Brooke Baronet Sir John
Rouce Baronett Sir Robert Brooke Knight Sir Henry Crofts Christopher Milton Esquire Sir John Walkner.</para>
			<para id="p78">Surrey.</para>
			<para id="p79">For the County of Surrey Sir Adam Brown Sir Francis Vincent Baronets Sir Edmond Boyer Sir William Hayward
Knights Sir Charles Howard Charles Earle of Ancrame in the Kingdome of Scotland Edward Evelyn George Chute
Esquires Sir Ralph Freeman junior Knight Sir Henry Capell, Leivtennant Colonel Gardner George Moore Esquire
John Weston Esquire George Duke Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p80">Sussex.</para>
			<para id="p81">For the County of Sussex Sir John Covert Sir John Lewkner Sir Edward Ford Sir Thomas Woodcock Colonel Bishop
Colonel Sackvile Percy Goring William Garaway Ferdinando Marsham Esquires John Ashburnham Henry Goring
Esquires Sir George Courthop Sir John Pelham Baronet.</para>
			<para id="p82">Worcester.</para>
			<para id="p83">For the County of Worcester and City of Worcester Sir Henry Littleton Sir John Packington Sir William Russell
Baronets Thomas Savage of [Clinby<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Castle William Sandys Esquires Sir Rowland Berkley Sir John Winford Knights
Sherrington Talbott Philip Brace Thomas Wild Edmond Carew William Sheldon of Broadway Bridges Nasau Thomas
Street Esquires Captaine William Sheldon of Finstoll Edward Barret Gen&bhocent; Sir John Talbot Colonel Samuel Sandys
Captaine Thomas Wilde Henry Bromley Es&bhoqesq; Sir Henry Herbert Sir Ralph Clare Francis Finch Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p84">Warwick</para>
			<para id="p85">For the County of Warwick and City and County of Coventry Sir Robert Holt Sir Henry Puckering &bhoalias; Newton
Sir Clement Fisher Sir Herbert Prise Baronets Sir William Bromley Knight of the Bath Sir Charles Adderley Sir
John Repington Sir Charles Lee Sir Clement Throckmorton Sir Arthur Caley Knights Hervey Baggot Francis Fisher
Giles Palmer Thomas Corbin William Somerfeild Esquires Sir Edward Boughton Sir John Knightly Baronet John
Bridgman Esquire Sir Thomas North Sir Richard Hopkins.</para>
			<para id="p86">Wilts.</para>
			<para id="p87">For the County of Wilts and City of New Sarum and Close of the same Henry Lord Viscount Cornbury eldest
Son to Edward Earl of Clarendon Lord Chancellor of England Edward Howard Esquire Sir James Thynn Sir John
Hall Sir Henry Coker Sir Thomas Mompesson Knights Thomas Wancklyn Henry Clerke Henry Baynton Richard
Bowle William Kent Richard Davy Walter Bokeland Gilbert Rawleigh Edward Nott Robert Chaloner Thomas
Hunt John Dean John Yerbury William Duckett Edward Penruddock Esquires Edward Hide of Hatch Walter Sharpe
Esquires John Earnley Sir Edward Hungerford Knight of the Bath Anthony Hungerford Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p88">Westmerland</para>
			<para id="p89">For the County of Westmerland Sir Philip Musgrave Sir John Lowther of Lowther Baronets Sir Thomas Strickland
Knight John Lowther John Dalston James Ducket Walter Strickland Richard Braithwait of Burnside Esquires Robert
Hilton Thomas Sandford Esquire John Lowther Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p90">York</para>
			<para id="p91">For the County of Yorke and City of Yorke Robert Lord Bruce eldest Son of Thomas Lord Bruce of Wharleton
in the Kingdome of England and Earl of Elgin in the Kingdom of Scotland Colonel Conyers Darcy Sir Thomas
Gowre Sir Thomas Osborne Sir John Goodrick Sir Thomas Strickland Sir Thomas Slingsby Sir Mathew Appleyard
Sir Solomon Swale Sir Jordan Crosland Sir Richard Mauleverer Sir Thomas Ingram Sir William Lowther Richard
Hutton Esquire Colonel Gilby Colonel Warton Colonel Pudsey Colonel Scot Leiu<emph type="p">t</emph> Colonel Strickland Major Talbot
John Wandesford Sir Robert Strickland Sir Robert Hillyard Sir Philip Monckton Sir Francis Cobb Sir Richard Tankard
Sir Thomas Wentworth Sir James Penyman Colonel Jenkin Colonel Daniel Colonel Atkins Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph> Colonel Wickham
Sir John Key Sir Godfrey Copley Sir Francis Fane Colonel Henry Cheator George Mountague Esquire The Lord
Erwyn in the Kingdome of Scotland Sir Christopher Wyval James Darcy Esquire Sir Joseph Craddock Christopher
Wandesford Esquire Major Norton Es&bhoqesq; Major Thomas Norton.</para>
			<para id="p92">Anglesey.</para>
			<para id="p93">For the Isle of Anglesey Colonel John Bodvel Colonel John Robinson William Bold John Wyn Esquires Major
David Lloyd Captaine Henry Jones Captaine John Owens of Lanvaithley Nicholas Bagnold Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p94">Brecon.</para>
			<para id="p95">For the County of Brecon Sir Herbert Price Baronet Sir John Herbert Knight now Sheriffe Edward Progers Esquire
John Jeffreys Milborn Williams John Stedman Esquires Thomas Roberts Alderman Daniel Winter Gen&bhocent;.</para>
			<para id="p96">Cardigan.</para>
			<para id="p97">For the County of Cardigan Sir Richard Price Baronet Sir Francis Lloyd Knight James Lewes Esquire Henry Vaughan
Jonathan Lloyd Morgan Herbert Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p98">Carmarthen</para>
			<para id="p99">For the County of Carmarthen Sir Francis Lloyd Sir Henry Vaughan Knight William Gwinne of Talliaris John
Vaughan of Court Dertlis Walter Vaughan of Derwith Captaine Anthony Rise Walter Mansell Thomas Lloyd of
Danyraht Thomas Williams of Tally John Vaughan of Trescot Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p100">Carnarvan.</para>
			<para id="p101">For the County of Carnarvan Sir Richard Wynne Sir Griffith Williams Baronets Sir John Owen Sir Richard Lloyd
Knights John Bodvel William Griffith of Kynn Hugh Wynne Esquires M<emph type="p">r</emph>. Hugh Bodurda.</para>
			<para id="p102">Denbigh.</para>
			<para id="p103">For the County of Denbigh Sir Evan Lloyd Baronet Sir Richard Lloyd Sir Robert Townsend Knights Sir Edward
Broughton William Owen of Glanden Esquire Colonel Hugh Wynne Colonel John Robinson Colonel Robert
Broughton Bevis Lloyd Charles Salisbury Esquire John Lloyd of L'anvuis Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p104">Flint</para>
			<para id="p105">For the County of Flint Sir Thomas Hanmer Sir Henry Conway Sir Roger Mostyn Baronets Robert Davyes John
Mostyn Roger Whitley Esquires William Hanmer.</para>
			<para id="p106">Glamorgan.</para>
			<para id="p107">For the County of Glamorgan Sir Edward Thomas Baronet Sir John Awbrey Knight and Baronet Sir Richard
Basset Knight Robert Thomas David Mathewes David Jenkins William Thomas Sir Edward Mansell Baronet Miles
Mathewes Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p108">Merioneth.</para>
			<para id="p109">For the County of Merioneth Sir Richard Wyn Sir Thomas Midleton Baronets Sir John Owen Sir Richard Lloyd
Knights William Price Lewis Lloyd Rowland Vaughan Esquires Richard Jones Gent. William Vaughan William
Salisbury Howel Vaughan John Lloyd Roger Mostyn Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p110">Montgomery.</para>
			<para id="p111">For the County of Montgomery Sir Edward Lloyd Andrew Newport Esquire Richard Owen John Price John Blaney
Esquires Richard Herbert Esquire Charles Salisbury Esquire John Purcell Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p112">Pembroke.</para>
			<para id="p113">For the County of Pembroke and Town and County of Haverford West Sir John Stepne Baronet John Barloe
Rowland Langharn Esquires Colonel Miles Button Leiv<emph type="p">t</emph> Colonel George Owen Captain William Williams Arthur
Owen Esquire Geo: Barloe Es&bhoqesq;uire.</para>
			<para id="p114">Radnor.</para>
			<para id="p115">For the County of Radnor Sir Richard Lloyd Knight John Walcote Esquire High Sheriffe of the County of
Radnor John Vaughan Esquire Richard Fowler of Abby Comhir James Price of Pillith Samuel Powell of Stanedge
Marmaduke Lloyd Griffith Jones of Trewern Evan Davies Andrew Phillips Esquires.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Commissioners authorized to apportion the Monies raised under this a&bholigct; in the manner herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p116">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to nominate Treasurer, &amp;c. taking Security; and to allow Salaries, &amp;c.; Commissioners in the Counties to send Certificates concerning Officers to Commissioners at Westminster.; Breviates of such Certificates to be entered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p117">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That all the persons above named or any Nine or more of them shall be Commissioners
hereby authorized to apportion the moneys which shall be received or raised by vertue of this a&bholigct; and for
executing all the Powers and Clauses of this a&bholigct; in manner following that is to say They or any Nine or more
of them are hereby dire&bholigct;ed and appointed to meet First in the Star-Chamber near Westminster Hall on the first
day of June One thousand six hundred sixty and two in the Afternoon and from and after that time they are
to meet in the said place every Tuesday only in the Afternoon until the powers and duties dire&bholigct;ed in this a&bholigct;
be fully executed and finished And at their [said<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] first meeting they or the major part of them shall nominate a
Treasurer a Register and one or more Collector or Collectors taking good and sufficient Security severally of them
for discharge of their several Trusts to whom the said Commissioners may make such allowance upon the clearing
theire Accompts for necessary Expences and Salaries as they shall judge reasonable so as such Allowance and
Salaries togeather with all contingent expences whatsoever shall not exceed three pence in the pound out of what
shall be assessed and received by any person or persons by vertue of this a&bholigct; And to the end that the Commissioners
sitting att Westminster may knowe to whom and in what proportions the moneys to bee received and levied by
vertue of this a&bholigct; shall be apportioned and distributed the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners in the severall Counties are
hereby dire&bholigct;ed and appointed to send Certificates as is hereafter declared unto the Commissioners sitting att
Westminster concerning all such Officers as aforesaid in each respe&bholigct;ive County sometime before the Nine and
twentieth day of September One thousand six hundred sixty and two which said Certificates shall be signed and
sealed by the major part of the Commissioners which shall be present at such publique meetings and all such
Certificates shall be safely kept by the said Register and Breviates of every such Certificate shall be fairely entred
by him into a Booke in such method as the Commissioners shall direct and the said Register shall also from
out of the Journall of the Commissioners Orders and Proceedings transmit and enter against the Brcviate of each
Officers Certificate the S&bhouov;m of Money ordered to him by the Commissioners for his proportion according to the
distribution by vertue of this a&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Certificate after Sept. 29, 1662.</head>
			<para id="p118">And it is hereby declared That after the said nine and twentieth of September One thousand six hundred
sixty &amp; two no Certificate shall be admitted nor any distribution thereupon made</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. What such Certificates to contain;</head>
			<para id="p119">And to avoid mistakes it is further ena&bholigct;ed That every Certificate shall particularly describe the degree and
quality of the Officer therein certified and shall recite the qualifications according to this a&bholigct; of such as ought
to receive distribution in manner following To the Honourable the Commissioners for distributing the monies
given by a&bholigct; of Parliam[en]t amongst the truly loyal and indigent Officers These are to certifie That it doth appeare
unto us that A. B. of C was a Captaine &amp; (Et sic mutatis mutandis) and that he is truly loyal and indigent
and hath had a real command of Souldiers according to his C&bhooov;mission and hath never to the best of our knowledge
or information deserted His M&atilde;ties or his blessed Fathers service during the late times of Rebellion and Usurpation
and that he hath not a sufficient livelihood of his owne nor hath since His Majesties returne obtained any Reward
Office or Imployment sufficient for a livelihood Wherefore wee do hereby recommend him as a person fit to
receive a &bhopubrc;por&bhocotil;n of all such monies as are to be by you distributed according to a&bholigct; of Parliament And every</para>
			<para id="p120">
				<emph type="i">to be signed and sealed by certain of the Commissioners.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p121">such Certificate shall be signed and sealed by the major part or any five of the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners of any
County Cities or Places respe&bholigct;ively where the Officer so certified doth at present reside otherwise the Certificate
shall be invalid and not to be allowed by the Commissioners sitting att Westminster as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Commissioners meeting at Westminster, or a certain Number of them, to proportion Monies raised under this a&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p122">
				<emph type="i">Payments ordered, and other Proceedings thereon.; In what Case only Commissioners to issue Warrants for Payment.; Treasurer not to issue monies but on receipt of Warrants from Commissioners.; Treasurer accountable to His Majesty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p123">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the said Commissioners or any Nine or more [of<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] them meeting att Westminster
in manner as is before declared shall and may according to theire best discretions after the First Day of November
One thousand six hundred sixty and two proportion the monies to be received or levied by vertue of this a&bholigct;
amongst such Officers as aforesaid according to the number of such true Certificates then sent in and that they
afterwards proceed to vote and order payments to be made to every of such Officers or theire Assigns or to such
Person whom such Officers or any of them shall under Hand &amp; Seal before twoe sufficient witnesses depute to
receive the same respe&bholigct;ively And after such Vote and Order thereupon the said C&bhooov;missioners or any Seaven of
them present at the making such respe&bholigct;ive Order or Orders are hereby dire&bholigct;ed to issue forth severall Warrants
according to the several Orders for payment of the several proportions or distributions of the said moneyes to such
Officer or Officers as aforesaid or to his or theire Deputy or Assignee as aforesaid but the said C&bhooov;missioners shall
issue forth no Warrants for payment of any moneys unlesse such monies be first ordered to be accordingly paid
by the major part of the Commissioners mett according to the directions of this a&bholigct; And that the said Treasurer
shall issue no monies paid to him by vertue of this a&bholigct; unlesse upon receipt of Warrant under the Hands and
Seales of Seven or more of the Commissioners before named which Warrant shall be a full discharge to such
Treasurer upon cleering his Accompts who is hereby made accomptable to his Majesty or whom he shall depute as
alsoe to the Commissioners appointed by this a&bholigct; or any Nine or more of them for all monies by him received by
vertue of this a&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Distribution to be according to Proportion of Pay.</head>
			<para id="p124">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That the distribution of all monies (by vertue of this a&bholigct;) amongst the said
Officers shall be according to the proportion of theire different pay according to his Majesties present Establishment
amongst his Forces now in England so that a Colonel of Foot shall have soe much more then a Captaine of Foot
by how much such Colonels pay doth exceed such Captains pay and the like Rule and Proportion is to be observed
and kept by the said Commissioners for and betwixt all other Officers as aforesaid whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Recital that Offices have not been assessed.</head>
			<para id="p125">
				<emph type="i">Recital of 13 C. II. st. 2. c. 3.; Commissioners, or certain Number of them, authorized to assess Offices before 1st August 1662.; Duplicates to be kept, and Monies paid to Treasurer before 1st Nov. 1662.; Rates of Assessment on Office of &pound;100 per Annum, and of greater or less Value</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p126">And whereas the severall Offices within England and Wales and Town of Berwick upon Tweed doe yeild
annually to the Officers or Owners of them great s&bhouov;ms of money and profitt and have hitherto either not been
assessed at all or but easily assessed in proportion to Lands and Rents of the same yearely value in the same
places And whereas an a&bholigct; is past for granting to the Kings Majesty an Assessment of Threescore and ten
thousand pounds by the Moneth for eighteen Monthes commencing from the five &amp; twentieth day of December
One thousand six hundred sixty and one To the end therefore that all yearely incomes perquisites and profits
whatsoever may contribute equally towards the necessary charge of the Government of this Nation and be proportionably
and impartially assessed for the said eighteen moneths commencing the five and twentieth of December One thousand
six hundred sixtie and one Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Commissioners before named or any
Nine or more of them being mett att any time as aforesaid or the major part of them so mett are hereby
appointed and authorized to rate and assesse all and every Officer or Officers that holds any Place or Office
within this Realme or Town of Berwick upon Tweed of the yearely value of five pounds or more and they are
hereby impowred and dire&bholigct;ed by Oath other then of the Officer himselfe if they find cause and by all other
lawfull wayes to find out with convenient speed the full value of all Offices as aforesaid to the intent that all
the Offices and Officers may be assessed before the First of August One thousand six hundred sixty and two
whereof Duplicates are to be kept and all the moneys soe severally assessed are to be levied and paid to the said
Treasurer before the First of November One thousand six hundred sixty and two And the said Commissioners
are hereby authorized and dire&bholigct;ed to rate or assesse every Officer (the prequisites and profits of whose Office shall
be by them adjudged to be clearely worth One hundred pounds per Ann&bhouov;) to pay for all the said eighteen
moneths the full s&bhouov;me of twelve pounds and so propor&bhocotil;nably for any Office or Place of a greater or lesser value
so as such Office be not under the value of five [pounds<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] per Ann&bhouov; And the said Register is hereby to enter all
Rates or Assessments so made by the said Commissioners into a Booke and to deliver Duplicates of them signed
by the said Register unto the said Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors and they or any of them according to such Duplicates
are hereby impowred to demand and leavy respe&bholigct;ively the several s&bhouov;mes of money therein contained</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Officer not paying within 20 Days after Notice;</head>
			<para id="p127">
				<emph type="i">Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p128">And be it ena&bholigct;ed That if any such Officer shall not pay his Tax or Proportion so rated or assessed sometime
within twenty dayes next after notice left thereof in writing signed by the said Register at his Office or att the usual
place of his abode and after demand thereof made at such place by some Collector that then it shall and may be
lawfull for such Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors to distrain upon any [of<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] the goods and chattels of such Officer and
the same to sell and to restore the Overplus dedu&bholigct;ing his own reasonable Charges in taking the distresse</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Colle&bholigct;ors vested with Powers of 13 C. II. st. 2. c. 3.</head>
			<para id="p129">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Colle&bholigct;ors herein appointed for the better levying &amp; receiving the several Rates
and Taxes that are or shall be imposed according to this a&bholigct; are hereby impowered to make use of all such Powers
and Authorities as are given to any Collector or Sub Colle&bholigct;or by the late a&bholigct; intituled (An a&bholigct; for granting unto the
Kings Majestie Twelve hundred and threescore thousand pounds to bee assessed and leavied by an Assessment of
Threescore and ten thousand pounds by the moneth for eighteen monthes)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Such Assessments on Offices how to be distributed.</head>
			<para id="p130">And be it ena&bholigct;ed That all the moneys so to be-raised out of Offices or Officers shall be alsoe distributed by the
said Commissioners unto such truly loyal and indigent Officers as are before declared in such sort and by such
wayes and meanes as the said Threescore thousand pounds is before dire&bholigct;ed by this a&bholigct; to be distributed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Commissioners for Counties, &amp;c. to certify to Commissioners at Westminster Number of Offices, &amp;c. chargeable.</head>
			<para id="p131">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Commissioners for the several Counties Cities or Places or any three or more
of them do with convenient speed certifie under theire hands unto the Commissioners sitting att Wesminster the full
number of all the Offices and Officers in each respe&bholigct;ive County that are chargeable by this a&bholigct; as also theire
opinions of the yearely value of such Offices whereupon or upon other reasonable ground the Commissioners sitting
att Westminster as aforesaid may proceed to rate and assesse every or any such Officer and direct the levying of
the Assessment so set in forme aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Officers rated to monthly Assessments, and assessed by 13 C.II. st. 2. c. 3.</head>
			<para id="p132">
				<emph type="i">to have Abatement in respect of Payments under this a&bholigct;.; Certificate of former Charge</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p133">And to the intent that no Officer shall pay Assessments for the proffits of his Office above the rate of Eight
pounds per cent&bhocent; for one yeare It is hereby provided and declared That every Officer whose Office hath usually
beene rated in the monethly Assessments and whose Office is assessed by vertue of the said a&bholigct; intituled An a&bholigct;
for granting unto the Kings Majesty Twelve hundred and threescore thousand pounds to be assessed and levied by an
Assessment of Threescore and ten thousand pounds by the moneth for eighteen moneths)<?bignore?> shall for what he is really
charged with for and in respect of his Office only by vertue of the said [last<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] recited a&bholigct; be abated and discharged
out of such Tax as hee shall be assessed to pay by vertue of this present a&bholigct; so as he deliver a Certificate of such
former charge signed by some Commissioner and Colle&bholigct;or of such place respe&bholigct;ively unto the Colle&bholigct;or hereby
appointed to receive his Tax charged by vertue of this a&bholigct; such Certificate not being reasonably disallowed by the
said Commissioners herein appointed and he paying as aforesaid the residue of Tax due from him by vertue of this
present a&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Recital that there are many Hospitals and other Charities in London and other Places.</head>
			<para id="p134">
				<emph type="i">The aforesaid Loyal Persons and their Widows, &amp;c. to be admitted thereto in preference on Vacancy; so as such Persons be qualified for the same.; Proviso for the Kindred of Founders of such Hospitals, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p135">And whereas there are in and about the Cities of London and Westminster and in several other Cities
Burroughs Towns Corporate and other Parishes and Places in this Kingdome of England and Dominion of Wales
many Hospitals and other Houses and Places of receipt profit benefit and advantage for persons of several rankes
ages and qualities respe&bholigct;ively and some of them very indigent maimed and decayed persons as alsoe there now
are or hereafter may be several stipends pensions and charitable gifts and bequests given and disposed to such like
persons in general without any particular designation and appointment by pious and worthy Benefa&bholigct;ors Be it likewise
ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That att all time and times hereafter and upon all occasions where any vacant
place or places shall happen to be in such Hospitals or other Houses or Places aforesaid or where such stipends pensions
or other charitable bequests shall be given and disposed of as aforesaid all Masters Fellowes Guardians and Governours
of such Hospitals and Places aforesaid and all persons whatsoever who have the power and authority of admitting and
receiving into the said Hospitals and Places aforesaid or have or shall have in their hands the power and disposition
of any such stipends pensions gifts or other bequests as aforesaid shall by this present a&bholigct; be bound &amp; obliged and
are hereby required and appointed in the first place to admitt and receive into such Hospitals and Houses and Places
aforesaid &amp; to &bhopcrl;ferr before all others in such admissions all and every such Loyall person or persons desiring the
same as have served the late King and his present Majesty in theire Wars and have not any way deserted theire
loyaltie and duty and being conformable to the Doctrine and Discipline of the Church of England so as such Person
be duly qualified to hold such place and to such Persons in the first place and before all others to give bestow and
dispose of the said Stipends Pensions and other Charitable gifts and bequests aforesaid And [that<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] the Widowes and
Children of such Loyal Persons aforesaid be likewise preferred before all others except the Founders Kindred
where the Original Constitutions of the said Hospitals and places do necessarily require in the Admission into giving and
disposing of all such vacant places in Hospitals and other Houses aforesaid and in receiving of the Pensions Stipends
Benefits Gifts and Bequests aforementioned according to theire Conditions and Capacities</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Commissioners not entitled to the aforesaid Monies.</head>
			<para id="p136">Provided alwaies That nothing in this a&bholigct; shall extend to impower any Person or Persons to order distribute or
pay any of the aforesaid moneys unto any Person named a Commissioner in this a&bholigct;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Officers who are Members of the House of Peers to be assessed by Lord Chancellor, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p137">
				<emph type="i">The Number of such Commissioners Commission to be issued before June 24, 1662</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p138">Provided alwaies That all Officers whoe are Members of the House of Peers shall be assessed for theire respe&bholigct;ive
Offices by the Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper of the Great Seale of England The Lord High Treasurer of England
The Lord President of the Council The Lord Privy Seale for the time being or one of them and such other Persons
as shall be appointed by His Majesty under the Great Seale of England or any five of them Which C&bhooov;missioners are
not to be fewer than twelve And that the said C&bhooov;mission shall be issued before the Foure and twentieth day of
June One thousand six hundred sixty and two and that the said C&bhooov;missioners or any five or more of them shall put
in execution all the powers of this a&bholigct; as to assessing of Peers for theire Offices</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. How far this a&bholigct; not to be drawn into Precedent.</head>
			<para id="p139">Provided alsoe That nothing in this a&bholigct; contained shall be drawn into President as to the disposing of Moneys
formerly granted to the King or the taxing [of<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] any particular sort of men distinct from the body of the People.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Part <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Cornett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">ye <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Speaker <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Harbord <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Cuthbert <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Walston <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Pemmerton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Sr <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Elmby <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">Pound <emph type="i">O.</emph>
			</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


