<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47321" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVIII. An Act against exporting of Sheepe Wooll Woolfells Mortlings Shorlings Yarn made of Wool Woolflocks Fullers Earth Fulling Clay and Tobacco pipe Clay. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 3. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Sheep Wool, &amp;c. have been exported contrary to Law, and that great Mischief has arisen therefrom.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Exporting Sheep, Wool, Woolfells, &amp;c. Fullers Earth, &amp;c. or loading for Exportation.; Felony</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS against the Lawes of this Kingdome great number of Sheep and great quantities of Wooll Woolfels
Mortlings Shorlings Yarn made of Wool Woolflocks Fullers Earth or Fulling Clay are secretly exported
transported carried and conveyed out of the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales the Towne of Berwicke upon
Tweed and Kingdome of Ireland into the Kingdom of Scotland and into Forreigne parts to the great decay of the
Woollen Manufa&bholigct;ures the ruine of many Families and the destru&bholigct;ion of the Navigation and Commerce of the
Kingdoms Town and Dominion aforesaid which is like dayly to encrease if some further remedy be not provided and
further penalties imposed upon the Offenders therein. Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty
by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by the Authority of the same That if any person or persons shall from and after the First day of
August One thousand six hundred sixty and two dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly export transport carry or convey or shall
cause to be exported transported carried or conveyed out of or from the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales
or Town of Berwick upon Tweed or after the First day of January One thousand six hundred sixty and two out of
the Kingdome of Ireland into any parts or places out of the Kingdomes or Dominion aforesaid or into the Kingdome
of Scotland any Sheepe or Wool whatsoever of the breed or growth of the Kingdomes or Dominion aforesaid or
any Woolfells Mortlings Shorlings Yarn made of Wool Wool flocks or any Fullers Earth or Fulling Clay whatsoever
or shall dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly pack or load or cause to be packed or loaden upon any Horse Cart or other Carriage
or shall load or lay on board or cause to be loaden or laid on board in any Ship or other Vessel in any place
within the Kingdomes of England or Ireland Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwick upon Tweed aforesaid
any such Sheep Wooll Woolfels Mortlings Shorlings Yarn made of Wooll Woolflocks Fullers Earth or Fulling Clay
to the intent or purpose to export transport carry or convey the same or to cause the same to bee exported transported
carryed or conveyed out of the Kingdomes of England or Ireland the Dominion of Wales or Town of Berwicke
upon Tweed aforesaid into the Kingdome of Scotland or into any Forreign parts that then every such Offence shall
be adjudged Felony and the Offender or Offenders being duly convi&bholigct;ed shall suffer and forfeit as in case of Felony</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Owners and Masters, &amp;c. of Ships, Horses, &amp;c. employed in such Exportation, and knowing thereof, and assisting;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and all Fa&bholigct;ors, Servants, Custom house Officers, &amp;c. assisting; Felony</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every owner of any such Ship or other Vessell and
every owner of every Horse Cart or Carriage upon which any Sheepe Wool Woolfels Mortlings Shorlings Yarn
made of Wool Woolflocks Fullers Earth or Fulling Clay shall be so exported transported carryed or conveyed as
aforesaid or to any such intent or purpose as aforesaid knowing thereof and being wittingly and willingly ayding
assisting or consenting thereunto and alsoe every Master and Mariner of or in such Shipp or other Vessell wherein
any such Sheep Wool Woolfels Mortlings Shorlings Yarn made of Wool Woolflocks Fullers Earth or Fulling
Clay shall be so exported transported carryed or conveyed or loaden or laid on board as aforesaid to any such
intent or purpose as aforesaid knowing thereof and being wittingly and willingly aiding assisting or consenting
thereunto and alsoe every Fa&bholigct;or or Servant or other person whatsoever and every Customer Comptroller Waiter
Searcher Surveyor or other Officer or Person whatsoever knowing thereof and being wittingly or willingly aiding
assisting or consenting thereunto shall be and shall be adjudged and taken to be a Felon and every Offender or
Offenders therein being duly convi&bholigct;ed shall suffer and forfeit as in case of Felony</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Offences to be inquired of in the County where Sheep Wool, &amp;c. laden for Exportation, or where Offender shall be arrested.</head>
			<para id="p5">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every offence which shall be done or committed
contrary to this A&bholigct; shall and may be enquired of and heard examined tried and determined in the County where
such Sheepe Wooll Woolfels Mortlings Shorlings Yarn made of Wooll Woolflocks Fullers Earth or Fulling Clay
respe&bholigct;ively shall be so packed loaden or laid on board as aforesaid or else in the County where such Offender
shall happen to [be<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] apprehended or arrested for such offence in such manner and form and to such effe&bholigct; to
all intents and purposes as if the same offence had beene wholly done and committed in the same County</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Peers offending to be tried by their Peers.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alsoe that every Baron and other Peer of this Realm which shall be indi&bholigct;ed or accused as principall
or accessary in or to any offence made Felony by this A&bholigct; shall have his her or theire Tryal by his her or theire
Peeres as in cases of Felony att Common Law</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Limitation of Prosecution.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no person or persons whatsoever shall att
any time hereafter be impeached for any offence made Felony by this A&bholigct; unlesse such person or persons shall
be thereof indi&bholigct;ed within the space of one yeare next ensuing such offence committed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Recital that Wools, &amp;c. are packed with Screws and other unlawful Engines, and then laden on board Ship as other Goods;</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">and also laid at or near the Sea Coast, &amp;c. and laden by Night on foreign Ships Persons so packing Wool, &amp;c. or laying it near the Sea Coast, &amp;c. with intent to export; Wool, &amp;c. forfeited.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">And for as much as great quantities of Wooll Woollen Yarn and Woolflocks are close packed and pressed
togeather with Scrues and other unlawfull Engines into Butts Pipes Hogsheads Chests and other Cask and Vessells
and into Sacks Baggs and other Wrappers made of Wool or Linnen and under colour of Bales Sacks Baggs Packs
and Cask of other Goods and otherwise great quantities of the same are daily loaden on board of Ships or other
Vessels and soe are carryed conveyed exported and transported out of the Kingdomes Town of Berwick and
Dominion aforesaid and alsoe great quantities are daily carried and laid at or neere the Coasts of the Sea or some
navigable Rivers into Storehouses and Barnes and by night are laid on board of Shallops and other Vessells
belonging to Aliens and so carried and exported out of the Kingdomes Town of Berwick and Dominion aforesaid
Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the said First day of August no person or
persons shall presse together with any Scrues Presses or other Engines into any Sacke Pack Bagg or other Wrapper
or shall put presse pack or stean any Wooll whatsoever or any Yarn made of Wooll into any Butt Pipe Hogshead
Chest or any other Cask or Vessell upon any pretence whatsoever or shall carry or lay or cause to be carried
or laid at or neare the Shoar or Coasts of the Sea or of any navigable River or into any House or Place near
adjoyning thereunto any such Wooll Woolflocks or Yarn made of Wooll with intention to export transport carry
or convey the same out of the Kingdomes of England or Ireland Town of Berwick upon Twede or Dominion of
Wales into the Kingdom of Scotland or into any foreign parts under the penalty of the losse and forfeiture of
all such Wooll Woolflocks and Yarn made of Wooll as shall be so packed or pressed or put or laid into Cask
or carried or laid near to the Sea shoar or to any navigable River as aforesaid or the value thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Exporting Tobacco Pipe Clay;</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 3s. per Pound.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p11">And whereas great quantities of Fullers Earth or Fulling Clay is dayly carried and exported under the colour
of Tobacco pipe Clay Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no Tobacco pipe Clay shall from
and after the First day of August One thousand six hundred sixty and two be exported transported carried or
conveyed out of or from the Kingdome of England Town of Berwick upon Twede or [after the First day of
January One thousand six hundred sixty and two out of or from the Kingdome of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Ireland or the Dominion of
Wales into the Kingdome of Scotland or into any forreign parts or into any port or place out of the Kingdomes
or Dominion aforesaid under the penalty of three shillings for every pound of Tobacco pipe Clay which shall be
exported or transported contrary to this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Packs of Wool not to be put into Carts, &amp;c. or carried by Land, but in the Day-time,</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">at the Hours herein mentioned, on Forfeiture of the said Goods</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the First day of August One thousand
six hundred sixty and two no Packs Sacks Bags or Caske of any Wooll Woolfels Mortlings Shorlings Yarn made
of Wooll Woolflocks Fullers Earth Fulling Clay or Tobacco pipe Clay shall be laid or loaden on any Horse Cart
or other Carriage whatsoever or shall be carried or conveyed by land to or from any place or places within the
Kingdom of England Town of Berwick or Dominion aforesaid nor after the First day of January One thousand
six hundred sixty two in the Kingdome of Ireland but in the day time and att seasonable houres (that is to say)
from and after the First day of March to the Nine &amp; twentieth day of September yearely between the houres of
Foure of the Clock in the Morning and Eight of the Clock in the Evening and from the Nine and twentieth day
of September to the first day of March yearly between the houres of Seven of the Clocke in the Morning and
Five of the Clock in the Evening under the penalty of the losse and forfeiture of all such Goods or the value
thereof the one moiety of all which forfeitures mentioned in this A&bholigct; to be to the use of the King His Heires
and Successors and the other moyetie to him or them that will sue for the same by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint
or Information in any Court of Record in which no Essoign Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be admitted
or allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Proviso for the Penalties imposed, and also for the shipping Wether Sheep, &amp;c. under 12 Car. II. c. 32.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided neverthelesse That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not extend or be construed to extend
to repeal disanul and make void any the Penalties Clauses or Provisoes mentioned in one A&bholigct; of this present Session
of Parliament made against the Transportation of Wooll Woolfels Fullers Earth or any kind of Scouring Earth or
to the prohibiting of the loading on board of any Ship or Vessel of any Weather Sheep Wooll Woolflocks or other
Goods men&bhocotil;ned in this A&bholigct; that by the aforesaid A&bholigct; is permitted to be loaden on board of any Ship or Vessel
for the necessary use or provision of such Ship or Vessel as aforesaid Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the
contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Owners and Mariners of Ships exporting Wool, &amp;c. within Three Months after knowing thereof, giving Information to the Court of Exchequer,</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">on Oath of the Particulars of the said Goods; such Owners, &amp;c. not punishable for Felony, but remain subje&bholigct; to Penalties.; Exportation a common Nuisance</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">Provided alwaies That if any Owner of any Ship or Vessel or any Master or Mariner knowing of such
Transportation of such Sheep Wooll Woolfels Mortlings Shorlings Yarn made of Wooll Woolflocks Fullers Earth
Fulling Clay or Tobacco pipe Clay shall within three monthes next after the knowledge thereof or after his
returne into the Kingdom of England or Ireland or into the said Town of Berwick or Dominion of Wales aforesaid
give the first information bona fide before any of the Barons of either of the Courts of the Exchequer in England
or Ireland for the time being or before the Head Officer of any Port where he shall first arrive upon his or theire
Oath of the number and quantity of the Goods mentioned in this A&bholigct; so carried conveyed &amp; transported and
by whom where and in what Shipp or Vessell and afterwards shall be ready upon reasonable warning by Processe
to justifie and prove the same that then such Owner or Owners Master Mariner and Mariners shall not be punished
for Felony by vertue of this A&bholigct; but shall neverthelesse be subje&bholigct; to all other penalties and forfeitures in this or
any other A&bholigct; contained for the Offence aforesaid and all such Exportation Transportation carrying or conveying of
any the Goods Wares or Comodities in this A&bholigct; mentioned is hereby declared and adjudged to be a common and
publicke Nusance</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Justices of Assize, &amp;c. to inquire in Quarter Sessions as to all the Offences, and Mayors, &amp;c. as to those not made Felony.</head>
			<para id="p17">And for the better execution of this A&bholigct; be it further ena&bholigct;ed That all Justices of Assize Justices of Goal
Delivery and Justices of Peace shall enquire of all the premisses in theire General Quarter Sessions and heare and
determine the same and that all Maiors Bayliffs and other Head Officers of Cities Burroughs and Towns not having
Jurisdi&bholigct;ion to try Felony shall enquire of all and every Offence within this A&bholigct; not made Felony and heare and
determine the same.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


