<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47320" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVII. An Act for Releife of Colle&bholigct;ors of Publick Moneys and theire Assistants and Deputies. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 3. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Colle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. levying Monies under any A&bholigct; of Parliament, &amp;c. in A&bholigct;ion brought may plead the General Issue.</head>
		<para id="p1">BE it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual
and Temporal and the Commons in Parliament now assembled and by Authority of the same That all Colle&bholigct;ors
and other persons who have levied or colle&bholigct;ed or shall levy or colle&bholigct; any s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money or other a&bholigct;
done or shall doe in order to the same by vertue of any A&bholigct; of Parliament now in force or of any other A&bholigct; Order
or Ordinance allowed to be put in execution by any such A&bholigct; of Parliament as aforesaid and who is or shall be
sued for or concerning the same by any other then the Kings Majesty His Heires and Successors he and they may
plead the General Issue and thereon give the special matter in evidence for his excuse and justification And that all
and every person or persons already sued or impleaded for any the Causes aforesaid may notwithstanding any Plea
or Demurrer already made by any such Defendant have liberty to change such his Plea and to plead the General
Issue if he shall thinke fitt so to do</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. A&bholigct; not to authorize levying Monies pardoned by 12 Car. II. c. 11.</head>
			<para id="p2">Provided alwaies That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend or be construed to extend
to authorize the levying or colle&bholigct;ing of any s&bhouov;m or s&bhouov;ms of money which are pardoned by the late A&bholigct; entituled
An A&bholigct; of Free and General Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


