<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47323" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XX. An Act for providing Carriage by Land and by Water for the use of His Majesties Navy and Ordnance. Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 3. nu. 5.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 12 Car. II. c. 24. &sect; 12, 13.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Carriages, Horses, &amp;c. may be taken for the Service of the Navy or Ordnance; on Notice to Two or more neighbouring Justices; who shall issue Warrants to Places within Twelve Miles. Rate of Recompense</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS by an A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for taking away the Court of Wards and Liveries and Tenures in
Capite and by Knights Service and Purveyance and for setling a Revenue upon His Majestie in lieu thereof
it was amongst other things enacted for the reasons and recompence therein expressed That from thence forth no
Person or Persons by any Warrant C&bhooov;mission or Authority under the Great Seal or otherwise by colour of buying
or makeing provision or purveyance for His Majesty or any Queen of England for the time being or of any the
Children of any King or Queen of England that shall be or for his theire or any of theire Houshold shall take
any Cart Carriage or other thing whatsoever of any of the Subje&bholigct;s of His Majesty His Heires or Successors
without the free and full consent of the Owner or Owners thereof had and obteined without Menace or
Enforcement nor shall summon warn take use or require any of the said Subje&bholigct;s to furnish or find any Horses
Oxen or other Catle Carts Ploughs Wayns or other Carriages for the use of His Majesty His Heires or Successors
or of any Queen of England or of any Child or Children of any the Kings or Queenes of England for the time
being for the carrying the Goods of His Majesty His Heires or Succesors or the said Queenes or Children or any
of them without such full and free consent as aforesaid Any Law Statute Custome or Usage to the contrary
notwithstanding Be it notwithstanding ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the advice and
consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Commons in this &bhopcrl;sent Parliament assembled and by the
Authority of the same That from and after the Foure and twentieth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred sixty and two as often as the Service of His Majesties Navy or Ordnance shall require any
Carriages by Land within the Kingdome of England and Dominion of Wales and Town of Berwick upon Tweed
upon notice given in writing by Warrant under the Hand and Seal of the Lord High Admiral of England for the
time being or under the Hands &amp; Seals of twoe or more of the principal Officers or Commissioners of His Majesties
Navy or under the Hand and Seal of the Master of his Majesties Ordnance for the time being or under the Hand
and Seale of the Leiutenant of his Majesties Ordnance for the providing of Carriages for the respe&bholigct;ive Service of
the Navy or Ordnance unto two or more Justices of the Peace dwelling neere unto the place where the said Carriages
shall be required the said Justices of the Peace may and shall immediately issue forth theire warrants to such of the
adjacent Parishes Hundreds or Divisions as they shall judge fitt within theire respe&bholigct;ive Counties and Divisions
not being above Twelve miles distant from the place of lading for the sending to a certaine place and att certaine
times (to be specified and appointed in the said Warrants) such numbers of Carriages with Horses or Oxen sufficient
for the said Service as by the Lord High Admiral of England for the time being or by the Master or Leiutenant
of His Majesties Ordnance for the time being or by the principal Officers or Commissioners of His Majesties Navy
respectively as abovesaid shall be by writing under theire Hands and Seales required the Owners of which Carriages
or theire Servants shall receive for every Load of Timber per Mile one shilling for every reputed Mile which they
shall goe laden and for other Provisions the S&bhouov;me of eight pence per Mile for every Tunn they shall carry</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Admiralty, Commissioners of the Navy, Master and Lieutenant of the Ordnance, may impress Ships, Hoys, &amp;c. for the Service.</head>
		<para id="p3">
			<emph type="i">Rates of Hire.; If not agreed, to be settled by Trinity House</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p4">And be it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That it may and shall be lawfull for the Lord High
Admiral of England for the time being by Warrant under his Hand and Seale and alsoe for the principal Officers
and Commissioners of His Majesties Navy by Warrants under the Hands and Seales of any twoe or more of them
as alsoe for the Master of His Majesties Ordnance for the time being by Warrant under his Hand and Seale and
alsoe for the Leiutenant of his Majesties Ordnance by Warrants under the Hands and Seales of either of them as
often as the Service of His Majesties Navy or Ordnance respe&bholigct;ively shall require any Carriage by Water to appoint
such Person or Persons as they shall judge fitting to impresse and take up such Shipps Hoys Lighters Boats or
any other Vessel whatsoever as shall be necessary for the accommodation of His Majesties said Service the Owners
of which said Ships Hoys Lighters Boats or other Water Carriage aforesaid or such as they shall appoint shall
receive for the Hire of every such Shipp Hoy Lighter Boat or other Vessel per Tun according to the Rates usually
paid by Merchants from time to time And in case His Majesties Officers and the Owners of such Shipps Hoys
Lighters Boats or other Vessels shall not agree on the said rates then the rate to be setled by the Brotherhood of
Trinity house of Deptford Strand.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>III. Persons refusing to furnish Carriages, Ships, &amp;c. or after they have undertaken neglecting, &amp;c. the same;</head>
		<para id="p5">
			<emph type="i">on Conviction by Oath of Officer or two other Witnesses; Penalty; to be levied by Distress</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p6">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That in case any of His Majesties Subje&bholigct;s of this Realme
shall refuse or wilfully negle&bholigct; after reasonable notice to make theire appearance with such sufficient carriages by
Land or to fitt provide and furnish their Shipps Hoys Lighters Boates or other Vessells for the Service of his
Majesties Navy or Ordnance as is before expressed or shall after they shall have undertaken such Service negle&bholigct;
or delay the same that then upon due proofe and convi&bholigct;ion of such refusall or negle&bholigct;	 by the oath of the Constable
or other Officer or twoe other credible witnesses before the said Justices of Peace of the County or Maior or other
cheife Officer of the City or Corporation where hee or they inhabit (which Oath they shall have power to administer)
for the Land Carriages and for the Water Carriages by the Oath of such person as shall be appointed by the Lord
High Admiral the principal Officers or Commissioners of his Majesties Navy the Master of His Majesties Ordnance
or the Leiutenant of His Majesties Ordnance as aforesaid or other two credible witnesses before the principal Officers
or Commissioners of His Majesties Navy or Master or Leiutenant of His Majesties Ordnance respe&bholigct;ively (which Oath
they shall have likewise power to administer) the party soe refusing or negle&bholigct;ing shall for every such refusal or
negle&bholigct; forfeit the sum of Twenty shillings for the Land Carriage and for Carriage by Water treble the freight of
such Ship or Vessel not exceeding fifty pounds in the whole to the Kings Majestyes use to be forthwith levied in
default of payment upon demand by distresse and sale of his Goods and Chattels by Warrant from the said
Justices of the Peace Maior or other Cheife Officer or from the principal Officers or Commissioners of His Majesties
Navy or Master or Leiutenant of His Majesties Ordnance respe&bholigct;ively (rendring to the parties the Overplus upon
every such Sale if there shall be any) the charge of distraining being first dedu&bholigct;ed.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>IV. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Length of Journey and Continuance in Employment.</head>
		<para id="p7">Provided alwaies that no Horses Oxen Cart Wayn or other Land Carriage shall be enforced to travel more
dayes Journey from the place where they receive theire lading or be compelled to continue longer in the imployment
then shall be appointed by the Order of the said Justices of the Peace and that ready Payment shall bee made
xx	in hand for the said Carriages at the place of Lading without delay according to the aforesaid Rates.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>V. Justices or Persons appointed by Admiralty, &amp;c. taking Gift to spare any Person, or charging Persons not liable, or impressing more Carriages than necessary. Penalty &pound;10.</head>
		<para id="p8">
			<emph type="i">Persons not empowered impressing Carriages, Horses, Ships, &amp;c. Punishment as by 12 Car. II. c. 24</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p9">Provided alwaies that in case any Justice of the Peace Mayor Cheife Officer or Constable or any Person or
Persons which shall be appointed by the Lord High Admirall the principal Officers or Commissioners of His
Majesties Navy the Master of His Majesties Ordnance or the Leiutenant of His Majesties Ordnance as aforesaid
respe&bholigct;ively shall take any gift or reward to spare any person or persons from making such Carriage by Land or
by Water or shall injuriously charge or greive any person or persons through envy hatred or evil will who ought
not to make such carriage or shall impresse more carriages then the necessity of the service shall require or then
he shall be commanded to impresse by his Superiours that then upon due proofe and conviction thereof the party
so offending shall forfeit the s&bhouov;m of Ten pounds to the party thereby greived who may sue for the same to be
recovered by A&bholigct;ion of debt in any of his Majesties Courts of Record wherein no Essoign Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of
Law shall be allowed And in case any person or persons shall presume to take upon him or them to impresse any
Horses Oxen Waynes or Carriages for Land or any Ships Hoys Lighters Boates or other Vessel for the service of
his Majesties Navy or Ordnance other then the persons so impowered as aforesaid then he or they so offending
shall upon due conviction of the said Offence incur and suffer the punishment in the first recited A&bholigct;</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>VI. Certain Ships, Hoys, &amp;c. not liable.</head>
		<para id="p10">Provided alwaies and be it ena&bholigct;ed That no Ship Hoy Barque or any other Vessel whatsoever that shall be
really and bona fide [fraighted<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] by Charter party if there be other Vessels in the Port fitting for the Service nor any
Vessel quarter laden with any Goods Wares or Merchandizes outward bound shall be liable to bee impressed for
any the Services aforesaid Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VII. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p11">Provided That this A&bholigct; and the powers therein contained shall continue and be [in<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] force untill the end of the
first Session of the next Parliament and no longer Any thing herein contained to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VIII. Proviso for extra Allowance for Carriage of Timber within the Division of the New Forest.</head>
		<para id="p12">Provided neverthelesse That in regard of the more then ordinary charge and burden [with<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] the Inhabitants of the
New Forest in the County of Southampton will be liable unto by reason of the great quantities of Timber usually
felled and carried thence for the use of his Majesties Navy It shall and may be lawfull for the Justices of the
Peace who shall by Warrant summon the Carts and Carriages within the division of the New Forest in the County
of Southampton aforesaid to have power (as to the Carriage of Timber only) to allow as aforesaid to the several
Owners of such Carts and Carriages not exceeding Foure pence per mile for so many miles as any Cart or
Carriage so summoned shall go empty to the place of its lading Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary
in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">fraughted <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">which <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
	</section>
</report>


