<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47338" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act for the Punishment of unlawfull cutting or stealing or spoiling of Wood and Underwood and Destroyers of young Timber Trees. [Rot. Parl. 15 C. 11. p. 2. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 43 Eliz. c. 7. &sect; 1</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that the said A&bholigct; had not sufficiently-prevented the said Mischief.; Reasons for the same.; Constables, &amp;c. may apprehend suspicious Persons conveying Bundles of Wood, young Trees, Bark, &amp;c.; and by Warrant under the Hand and Seal of a Justice may enter and search Houses, Gardens, &amp;c. which they shall suspe&bholigct; to contain Wood, Bark, &amp;c. and if they find any such, may apprehend Persons suspe&bholigct;ed of conveying the same away; and also those in whose Premises the same shall be found.; If such Persons do not give a good Account or produce the Persons of whom they bought the Wood, &amp;c.; such Persons to be deemed convi&bholigct;ed under the said Statute 43 Eliz. c. 7.; Punishment</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in one A&bholigct; of Parliament made in the Three and fortieth yeare of the Raigne of the late
Queene Elizabeth entituled An A&bholigct; to avoid and prevent diverse misdemeanors in idle and lewd persons
among other things it is ena&bholigct;ed That all and every such lewd person and persons that shall cutt or spoyle any
Woods or Underwoods Poles or Trees standing and their Procurer or Procurers Receiver or Receivers knowing
the same, and being thereof lawfully convi&bholigct;ed by his or their owne confession, or by the testimony of one
sufficient Witnesse upon Oath before some one Justice of Peace, or other Head Officer of the County or place
where such offence was committed shall give the partie or parties satisfa&bholigct;ion for his or their Damages for the
first faulte, And if such Offender or Offenders shall by such Justice of Peace or Head Officer be thought not
able or sufficient, or if such Offender or Offenders doe not make such satisfa&bholigct;ion as aforesaid That then
the said Justice of Peace or Head Officer shall committ the said Offender or Offenders to the Constable or
other inferiour Officer to receive the punishment of Whipping, as in the said A&bholigct; more fully doth appeare,
And whereas it is found by dayly experience especially in and about London and other great Townes where a
great number of such idle and lewd persons doe shelter themselves that this A&bholigct; hath not sufficiently prevented
the said mischeife of cutting and spoyling Woods and Underwoods as was intended as well because the said
offences are committed in such a close and clandestine manner that there is none Witnesse to them but such as
are pertakers to the offence, as alsoe because the said punishment is too small for soe great a fault, which is not
onely prejudiciall and hurtfull to the Owners of the said Woods but very mischievous and damageable to the
Commonwealth Be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie
of the same That from and after the fower and twentieth day of June next ensueing every Constable Headborough
or any other person in every County Citty Towne Corporate or other place where they shall be Officers or
Inhabitants shall and may by vertue of this present A&bholigct; have full power and authoritie to apprehend or cause to be
apprehended all and every person or persons they shall suspe&bholigct; haveing or carrying or any waies conv[e']ing any
burthen or bundles of any kinde of Wood Underwood Poles or young Trees or Barke or Bast of any Trees or
any Gates Stiles Posts Pales Railes or Hedgewood Broome or Furze, and by Warrant under the hand and seale
of any one Justice of the Peace dire&bholigct;ed to any Officer, such Officer shall have power to enter into and search the
Houses Outhouses Yards Gardens or other places belonging to the Houses of all and every person or persons they
shall suspe&bholigct; to have any kinde of Wood Underwood Poles or young Trees or Barke or Baste of any Trees or
any Gates Stiles Posts Pales Railes or Hedgewood Broome or Furze, and wheresoever they finde any such to
apprehend or cause to be apprehended all and every person and persons suspe&bholigct;ed for the cutting and takeing of
the same, and them and every of them as well those apprehended carrying or any waies conveying any kinde of
Wood Underwood Poles or young Trees or Barke or Bast of any Trees or any Gates Stiles Posts Pales Railes
or Hedgewood Broome or Furze as alsoe those in whose houses or other places belonging to them any such
Wood Underwood Poles or young Trees, or Barke or Bast of any Trees, or any Gates Stiles Posts Pales Railes
or Hedgewood Broome or Furze shall be found to carry before one Justice of the Peace of the same County Citty
or Towne Corporate, And if the said person and persons soe suspe&bholigct;ed apprehended and carryed before the said
Justices doe not then and there give a good account how he and they came by such Wood or Underwood Poles
or young Trees or Barke or Baste of any Trees or Gates Stiles Posts Pales Railes or Hedgewood Broome or
Furze by the consent of the Owner such as shall satisfie the said Justice, or else shall not within some convenient
time to be sett them by the said Justice produce the partie or parties of whom they bought the same Wood
Underwood Poles or young Trees or Barke or Bast of Trees Gates Stiles Posts Pales Railes or Hedgewood Broom
or Furze or some other credible witnesse to depose upon Oath such sale of the said Wood Underwood Poles
or young Trees or Barke or Bast of Trees Gates Stiles Posts Pales Railes or Hedgewood Broom or Furze (which
Oath the said Justice hath hereby power to administer) That then the said person or persons soe suspe&bholigct;ed and
not giveing such good account, nor produceing any such witnesse upon Oath to testifie the said sale as aforesaid
shall be deemed and adjudged as convi&bholigct;ed of the said offence of cutting and spoiling of the same Woods
Underwoods Poles or young Trees or Barke or Bast of Trees Gates Stiles Posts Pales Railes or Hedgewood
Broom or Furze within the meaneing of the said Statute of Queene Elizabeth and shall be liable to the punishment
therein contained and to such other proceedings and punishments as by this present A&bholigct;shall be further constituted
and appointed on that behalfe</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. First Offence, Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Not paying the Penalty, Imprisonment.; Second Offence.; Third Offence</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every person convi&bholigct;ed of the
said offence in manner and forme before in this A&bholigct; mentioned shall for the first offence give the Owner or
Owners such recompence or satisfa&bholigct;ion for his or their damages and within such time as the said Justice shall
appoint, and over and above pay downe presently unto the Overseers for the use of the Poore of the Parish
where the said offence or offences were committed such summe of money (not exceeding Ten shillings) as
the said Justice shall thinke meete, and if such offender or offenders doe not make recompence or satisfa&bholigct;ion to
the said Owner or Owners and alsoe pay the said summe to the Poore in manner and forme aforesaid then the
said Justice shall committ the said offender or offenders to the house of Corre&bholigct;ion for such time as the said
Justice shall thinke fitt not exceeding One moneth, or to be whipped by the Constable or other Officer as in
his Judgement shall seeme expedient, And if such person or persons shall againe committ the said offence and be
thereof convi&bholigct;ed as before that then they and every of them soe offending the second time and thereof soe
convi&bholigct;ed shall be sent to the House of Corre&bholigct;ion for One moneth, and be there kepte to hard labour, And if
such person or persons shall againe committ the said offence and be thereof convi&bholigct;ed as before that then they
and every of them soe offending the third time and thereof soe convi&bholigct;ed shall be taken adjudged and deemed as
incorrigible Rogues,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Persons buying suspicious Wood</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Justices, &amp;c. may examine into the Matter upon Oath; and if they find the same was bought of a suspicious Person, may infli&bholigct; a Penalty of Treble the Value; and may levy by Distress.; If no Distress, Imprisonment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">Provided alwaies and it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That whosoever shall buy any Burthens
of Wood or any Poles or Sticks of Wood or any other the Premisses perticularly mentioned in this Bill, which
may be justly suspe&bholigct;ed to have beene stolne or unlawfully come by that it shall and may be lawfull to and
for the said Justices of [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Peace Maiors Bailiffes and Head-Officers or any one of them within their respe&bholigct;ive
Jurisdi&bholigct;ions upon complaint to them thereof made to examine the said matter upon Oath which they and every
of them respe&bholigct;ively are hereby authorized to administer And if they shall finde that the same was bought of a
person who might justly be suspe&bholigct;ed to have stolne or unlawfully come by the same, and that the same was
stolne or unlawfully come by, that in such case the said Justices of Peace Maiors Bayliffes or other Head Officers
or any one of them respe&bholigct;ively shall and may award the partie who bought the same to pay treble the value of
the same to the partie from whom the same was stolne or unlawfully taken, And in defaulte of present payment
thereof to issue forth their respe&bholigct;ive Warrants to leavy the same by distresse and sale of the offenders Goods
rendring the overplus to the partie, And in default of such distresse to committ the partie to the Goale at his
owne charge there to remaine One moneth without Baile.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. No Double Punishment.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Limitation of Suit</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">Provided allwaies That noe person or persons shall be questioned for any offence upon this Law that hath
beene punished for the same offence by any former Law, nor shall be punished by this Law unlesse he be
questioned within Six weekes after the offence committed.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


