<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47331" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXVIII. An Act for the [regulating <ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of the Pilchard Fishing in the Counties of Devon and Cornwall [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 3. nu. 13.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Benefits arising from the Fishery; and that many destru&bholigct;ive Abuses had crept in.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">No Person from 1st June to 30th Nov. to take Fish with Drift Nets, Trammels, &amp;c. Penalty and Imprisonment.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">WHEREAS the publique honour wealth and safety of this Realm as well in the maintenance of Trade and
support of Navigation as in many other respe&bholigct;s doth in an high degree depend upon the Improvement
and Incouragement of the Fishery And forasmuch as of late yeares there have divers pernicious disorders and abuses
by the licenciousnes of the times crept in and yet continue evidently distru&bholigct;ive to that Trade for prevention and
redresse whereof there is no Law hitherto particularly provided in the growing evils occasioned by Driving Nets and
other fraudulent and injurious pra&bholigct;ises to the extreme damage of the Fishery Be it therefore enacted by the Kings
most Excellent Majesty by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Commons
in Parliament assembled and it is enacted by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the Five and twentieth
day of May One thousand six hundred sixty and two no person or persons shall in any yeare from the First day
of June till the last of November presume to take Fish in the High Sea or in any Bay Port Creeke or Coast of
or belonging to Cornwall or Devon with any Drift Net Trammel or Stream Net or Nets or any other Nets of
that sort or kind unlesse it be at the distance of one League and an halfe at least from the respe&bholigct;ive shores upon
the penalty of forfeiture of the said Nets so imployed or the full value thereof and one moneths Imprisonment
without bail or mainprize.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Persons not concerned in the Craft of Fishery not to make Pilchards, &amp;c. in</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Cask, unless bought of those concerned in the Pilchard Craft, or with, their Consent; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any person or persons being neither Owners
Partners or Adventurers in the Craft of Fishery and in the Boates and Saynes thereunto belonging shall presume
from and after the day before limited to make or cause to be made any Pilchards or Fumathoes in Cask to be sold
or transported except he or they shall openly buy the aforesaid Fish of the respe&bholigct;ive Owners Partners and
[Adventures<ref idref="n2">1</ref>] in the said Pilchard Craft or with theire expresse allowance leave and consent that they shall in such
case forfeit all and singuler such Pilchards and Fumathoes so made and every Cask thereof or theire full value
the one halfe to the King and the other halfe to him or them that shall soe sue for the same by Bill Plaint or
other Information and upon legal proof recover the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Purloining, &amp;c. Pilchards out of the Nets, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any Owner Partner or Company or any other person or persons whatsoever
shall fraudulently purloyne imbezile hide convey carry away or dispose by sale or otherwise or cause to bee
purloyned imbezilled hidden conveyed carryed away or disposed out of the Nets Boats or Cellars any Pilchard
Fish without the expresse leave consent and allowance of the proper Owners and major part of the Company
respe&bholigct;ively that then every such person and persons that shall offend therein upon legal evidence shall pay treble
the value in satisfa&bholigct;ion to the parties so wronged and be sent to the House of Corre&bholigct;ion for three Monthes</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Suspicious Persons, about Boats, &amp;c. not departing on Warning;</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any idle or suspitious person or persons shall
in the night assemble and flock togeather about the Boats Nets or Sellars belonging to any Pilchard Craft upon
any of the Coasts of Cornwall or Devon having no busines there to do and being warned by the Company or
Owner of such Boats or Sellars to be gone that then upon complaint made unto any one Justice of the Peace
every such person or persons refusing so to do shall pay five shillings to the poore of the Parish where such
offence was committed or shall be set in the Stocks for the space of Five houres.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Regulation <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Adventurers <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


