<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47336" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1662</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXXIII. An Act for preventing the frequent Abuses in printing seditious treasonable and unlicensed Bookes and Pamphlets
and for regulating of Printing and Printing Presses. [Rot. Parl. 14 C. II. p. 3. nu. 17.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that the regulating of Printers is matter of public Care, and that many have been of late encouraged to print and sell seditious. Pamphlets, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">No Persons to print Seditious and Heretical Pamphlets.; or import or publish; such Pamphlets</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the well-government and regulating of Printers and Printing Presses is matter of Publique care
and of great concernment especially considering that by the general licentiousnes of the late times many
evil disposed persons have been encouraged to print and sell heretical schismatical blasphemous seditious and
treasonable Bookes Pamphlets and Papers and still doe continue such theire unlawfull and exorbitant pra&bholigct;ice to the
high dishonour of Almighity God the endangering the peace of these Kingdomes and raising a disaffe&bholigct;ion to His
most Excellent Majesty and His Government For prevention whereof no surer meanes can be advised then by
reducing and limiting the number of Printing Presses and by ordering and setling the said Art or Mystery of
Printing by A&bholigct; of Parliament in manner as herein after is expressed. The Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with
the Consent and Advise of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal &amp; Commons in this present Parliament assembled
doth therefore ordaine and ena&bholigct; And be it ordained and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no person or
persons whatsoever shall presume to print or cause to be printed either within this Realm of England or any other
His Majesties Dominions or in the parts beyond the Seas any heretical seditious schismatical or offensive Bookes or
Pamphlets wherein any Do&bholigct;rine or Opinion shall be asserted or maintained which is contrary to (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Christian Faith or
the Do&bholigct;rine or Discipline of the Church of England or which shall or may tend or be to the scandall of Religion
or the Church or the Government or Governors of the Church State or Common wealth or of any Corporation
or particular person or persons whatsoever nor shall import publish sell or [dispose<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] any such Booke or Books or
Pamphlets nor shall cause or procure any such to be published or put to sale or to be bound stitched or sowed
togeather</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. No private Person to print any Book, &amp;c. unless first entered with the Stationers' Company of London; Exceptions; and unless first duly licensed.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Common Law Books to be licensed by Lord Chancellor, &amp;c.; Books of History, Affairs of State, &amp;c. by Secretary of State.; Books of Heraldry &amp;c. by the Earl Marshal or Kings of Arms.; All other Books by Archbishop of Canterbury and Bishop of London, &amp;c.; Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Licences by the Chancellors, &amp;c. of the Universities.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further ordained and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no private person or persons whatsoever
shall att any time hereafter print or cause to be printed any Booke or Pamphlet whatsoever unlesse the same Booke
and Pamphlet togeather with all and every the Titles Epistles Prefaces Proems Preambles Introdu&bholigct;ions Tables
Dedications and other matters and things thereunto annexed be first entred in the Booke of the Register of the
Company of Stationers of London [except A&bholigct;s of Parliament Proclamations and such other Books and Papers as
shall be appointed to be printed by vertue of any Warrant under the Kings Majesties Sign Manual or under the
hand of one or both of His Majesties Principal Secretaries of State<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] and unlesse the same Booke and Pamphlet and
also all and every the said Titles Epistles Prefaces Proems Preambles Introdu&bholigct;ions Tables Dedications and other
matters and things whatsoever thereunto annexed or therewith to be imprinted shall be first lawfully licensed and
authorized to be printed by such person and persons only as shall be constituted and appointed to license the same
according to the dire&bholigct;ion and true meaning of this present A&bholigct; herein after expressed and by no other (that is
to say) That all Books concerning the Common Lawes of this Realm shall be printed by the special allowance of
the Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper of the Great Seal of England for the time being the Lords Cheife Justices
and Lord Cheife Baron for the time being or one or more of them or by theire or one or more of theire
appointments And that all Books of History concerning the State of this Realm or other Books concerning any
Affaires of State shall be licensed by the Principal Secretaries of State for the time being or one of them or by
theire or one of theire appointments And that all Bookes to bee imprinted concerning Heraldry Titles of Honour
and Armes or otherwise concerning the Office of Earle Marshal shall be licensed by the Earl Marshal for the time
being or by his appointment or in case there shall not then be an Earl Marshal shall be licensed by the Three
Kings of Armes Garter. Clarenceux and Norroy or any two of them whereof Garter Principal King of Armes
to be one And that all other Bookes to bee imprinted or reprinted whether of Divinity Phisick Philosophy or
whatsoever other Science or Art shall be first licensed and allowed by the Lord Arch Bishop of Canterbury and
[the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Lord Bishop of London for the time being or one of them or by theire or one of theire appointments or by
either one of the Chancellors or Vice-Chancellors of either of the Universities of this Realme for the time being
Provided alwaies that the said Chancellors or Vice Chancellors of either of the said Universities shall only
license such Bookes as are to be imprinted or reprinted within the limits of the said Universities respe&bholigct;ively but
not in London or else where not medling either with Bookes of the Common Lawes or matters of State or
Government nor any Booke or Bookes the right of printing whereof doth solely and properly belong to any
particular person or persons without his or theire Consent first obtained in that behalfe</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Every Person authorized to license, to have one written Copy of the Book; which is to be delivered by Licenser to the Owner for printing, and afterwards returned to the Licenser to be kept.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">If such Book be in English, Two written Copies, if required, to be delivered to Licenser.; How to be disposed of.; Licenser to testify under his Hand.; Licence to be printed at the beginning of the Book</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every person and persons who by vertue of this present
A&bholigct; are or shall be appointed or authorized to license the imprinting of Bookes or reprinting thereof with any
Additions or Amendments as aforesaid shall have one written Copy of the same Booke or Bookes which shall be
soe licensed to be imprinted or reprinted with the Titles Epistles Prefaces Tables Dedications and all other things
whatsoever thereunto annexed which said Copy shall be delivered by such Licenser or Licensers to the Printer or
Owner for the imprinting thereof and shall be safely and intirely returned by such Printer or owner after the
imprinting thereof unto such Licenser or Licensers to be kept in the publick Registrys of the said Lord Archbishop
or Lord Bishop of London respe&bholigct;ively or in the Office of the Chancellor or Vice. Chancellor of either the said
Universities or with the said Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper of the Great Seal for the time being or Lord Cheife
Justices or Cheif Baron or one of them or the said Principal Secretaries of State or with the Earle Marshall or
the said Kings of Armes or one of them of all such Books as shall be licensed by them respe&bholigct;ively and if [such
Booke so to be licensed shall be an English Booke or of the English Tongue there shall be twoe Written Copies
thereof delivered to the Licenser or Licensers (if he or they shall so require) one Copy whereof so licensed shall
be delivered back to the said Printer or Owner and the other Copy shall be reserved and kept as is aforesaid<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] to the
end such Licenser or Licensers may be secured that the Copy so licensed shall not be altered without his or theire
privity And upon the said Copy licensed to be imprinted he or they who shall so license the same shall testifie
under his or their hand or hands That there is not any thing in the same contained that is contrary to Christian
Faith or the Do&bholigct;rine or Discipline of the Church of England or against the State or Government of this Realme
or contrary to good life or good manners or otherwise as the nature and subje&bholigct; of the Worke shall require which
License or Approbation shall be printed in the begining of the same Booke with the Name or Names of him or them
that shall authorize or license the same for a Testimony of the allowance thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Merchants and Importers of Books to import the same into London only, unless special Licence;</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">and to present a true Catalogue thereof to the said Archbishop, &amp;c.; and not to open Packages, nor Officer to pass the same,; (Penalty); before a Person duly appointed, and one of the Stationers' Company, be present.; If seditious, &amp;c. Books found, to be brought to the said Archbishop, &amp;c.; Proceedings against Offenders, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every Merchant of Bookes and person and persons
whatsoever who doth or hereafter shall import or bring any Booke or Books into this Realm from any parts beyond
the Seas shall import the same in the Port of London only and not elsewhere without the special License of the
Archbishop of Canterbury and Bishop of London for the time being or one of them who are hereby authorized
to grant Licenses for that purpose and shall before such time as the same Booke or Books or any of them be
delivered forth or out of his or theire hand or hands or exposed to sale give and present a true Note or Catalogue
in writing of all and every such Booke [or<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Bookes unto the Lord Archbishop of Canterbury and Lord Bishop of
London for the time being or to one of them And no Merchant or other person or persons whatsoever which
shall import or bring any Booke or Books into the Port of London aforesaid from any parts beyond the Seas shall
presume to open any Dry Fats Bales Packs Maunds or other Fardels of Bookes or wherein Bookes are nor shall
any Searcher Waiter or other Officer belonging to the Custom house upon pain of losing his or their place or
places suffer the same to passe or to be delivered out of his or theire hands or Custody before such time as the
Lord Archbishop of Canterbury and the Lord Bishop of London for the time being or one of them shall have
appointed some Scholar or learned man with one or more of the said Company of Stationers and such others as
they shall call to theire assistance to be present at the opening thereof and to view the same And if there shall happen
to be found any Heretical Seditious Scandalous Schismatical or other dangerous or offensive Booke or Books or
any part of such Booke or Bookes printed in English they shall forthwith be brought to the said Lord Archbishop
of Canterbury and Lord Bishop of London for the time being or to one of them or to some publick place to bee
assigned and chosen by the said Lord Archbishop and Lord Bishop for the time being to the end the person
and persons which importeth or causeth the said Offensive Books to bee imported may be proceeded against as
an offender against this present A&bholigct; And alsoe that such further course may be taken concerning the same offensive
Booke or Books as by the said Lord Archbishop and Bishop for the time being shall be thought fitting for the
suppressing thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Persons to print or import Copies of Books, Books, Indentures, &amp;c. in which others have any Right by Letters Patent, &amp;c. solely to print, without the Consent of the Owners;</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">nor bind or stitch such Books or Copies without the like Consent; Penalty.; How to be disposed of.; Limitation of Suit for the same</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no person or persons shall within this Kingdome or
else where imprint or cause to bee imprinted nor shall import or bring in or cause to be imported or brought into
this Kingdome from or out of any other His Majesties Dominions nor from any other parts beyond the Seas
any Copy or Copies Booke or Bookes or part of any Book or Bookes or Forms of blanck Bills or Indentures
for any His Majesties Islands printed beyond the Seas or else where which any person or persons by force or,
vertue of any Letters Patents granted or assigned or which shall hereafter be granted or assigned to him or them
or (where the same are not granted by any Letters Patents) by force or vertue of any Entry or Entries thereof
duly made or to be made in the Register Booke of the said Company of Stationers or in the Register Booke of
either of the Universities respe&bholigct;ively have or shall have the Right Priviledge Authority or Allowance solely to
print without the consent of the Owner or Owners of such Booke or Bookes Copy or Copies Form or Forms
of such blanck Bills nor shall binde stitch or put to Sale any such Booke or Books or part of any [such<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Booke
or Books Form or Forms without the like consent upon pain of losse and forfeiture of the same and of being
proceeded against as an Offender against this present A&bholigct; and upon the further penalty and forfeiture of Six
shillings eight pence for every such Booke or Books or part of such Booke or Bookes Copy or Copies or Form
or Forms of any such blanck Bills or Indentures so imprinted or imported bound stitched or put to sale The
Moyetie of which said Forfeiture &amp; Forfeitures shall be to the use of our Soveraigne Lord the King His Heires
and Successors and the other Moyety to the use of the Owner or Owners Proprietor or Proprietors of such Copy
or Copies Booke or Bookes or Form of such blank Bills or Indentures if he or they shall sue for the same within
Six moneths next after such imprinting importing binding stitching or putting to Sale And in default of such Suit
by the Owner or Owners Proprietor or Proprietors commenced within the said Six moneths Then the same Moyety
shall be to the use and behoofe of such other person or persons as within the space of one yeare next after the
said Offence committed shall sue for the same to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any
of his Majesties Courts of Record held att Westminster called the Kings Bench Common Pleas or Exchequer
wherein no Essoign Wager of Law or Prote&bholigct;ion shall be allowed to the Defendant or Defendants</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Printers of Books, &amp;c. to set their Names thereto, and declare the Name of the Author if required.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.; No Person to print or forge the Name of the Person having sole Right to print any Book.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That every person and persons that shall hereafter print or cause to be
printed any Booke Ballad Chart Pourtra&bholigct;ure or any other thing or things whatsoever shall thereunto or thereon
print and set his or theire owne Name or Names and alsoe shall declare the Name of the Author thereof if he be
thereunto required by the Licenser under whose Approbation the licensing of the said Booke Ballad Chart or
Pourtraiture shall be authorized and by and for whom any such Booke or other thing is or shall be printed upon
paine of Forfeiture of all such Books Ballads Charts Pourtraitures and other thing or things printed contrary to
the Tenor hereof And the Presses Letters and other Instruments for printing wherewith such Book Ballad
Pourtraiture or other thing or things shall be so imprinted or sett or prepared for the printing thereof to be defaced
and made unserviceable And that no person or persons shall hereafter print or cause to bee imprinted nor shall
forge put or counterfeit in or upon any Booke or Pamphlet the Name Title Marke or Vinnet of any other person
or persons which hath or shall have lawfull Priviledge Authority or Allowance of sole printing the same without
the free consent of the person and persons so priviledged first had and obtained upon pain that every person and
persons so offending shall forfeit and lose all such Books and Pamphlets upon which such counterfeit Name or
Marke shall be imprinted and shall further be proceeded against as an Offender against this present A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. No Haberdasher of Small Wares, &amp;c. not licensed, nor being a Freeman of London, nor a Member of the Stationers' Company, to sell, &amp;c. Books, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p14">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no Haberdasher of Small Wares Ironmonger Chandler
Shopkeeper or other person or persons whatsoever not being licensed in that behalfe by the Lord Bishop of the
Diocesse wherein such Booke or Bookes shall be having been Seven yeares Apprentice to the Trade of Booke seller
Printer or Bookbinder nor being a Freeman of the City of London by Patrimonial Right as Son of a Booke seller
Printer or Booke binder nor being a Member of the said Company of Stationers shall within the City or Suburbs
of London or any other Market Towne or elsewhere receive take or buy [or<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] barter sell againe change or doe
away any Bibles Testaments Psalm books Common Prayer books Primers Abcees Licensed Almanacks Grammar
School books or other Book or Books whatsoever upon pain of forfeiture of the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. No Merchant or other Person to print beyond Sea or import English Books, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.; Aliens not to import or vend Books in any Language printed beyond Sea, (Exception) without special Licence of Archbishop, &amp;c.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And for that printing is and for many yeares hath been an Art &amp; Manufa&bholigct;ure of this Kingdom Therefore for
the better encouraging thereof and the prevention of divers Libels Pamphlets and Seditious Books printed beyond
the Seas in English and thence transported into this Realm Be it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the Authority
aforesaid That no Merchant Bookseller or other person or persons whatsoever shall imprint or cause to be imprinted
beyond the Seas nor shall import or bring nor knowingly assist or consent to the importation or bringing from
beyond the Seas into this Realm any English Booke or Books or part of any Booke which is or shall bee or the
greater part thereof is or shall be English or of the English Tongue whether the same Booke Books or part of
such Book have been here formerly printed or not upon pain of forfeiture of all such English Books so imprinted
or imported contrary to the tenour hereof And that no Alien or Forreigner whatsoever shall hereafter bring in
or be suffered to vend here within this Realm any Book or Books printed beyond the Seas in any Language
whatsoever either by himselfe or his Fa&bholigct;or or Fa&bholigct;ors except such only as bee Free Printers or Stationers of
London or such as have been brought up in that Profession without the special License of the Archbishop of
Canterbury and Bishop of London for the time being or one of them who are hereby authorized to grant Licenses
for that purpose upon like pain of forfeiture of all such Books as shall be soe imprinted or vended contrary to
the purport and true intent hereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. No Person to ere&bholigct; a Printing Press or House, or let Premises for Printing, without giving Notice to the Stationers' Company.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">No Carpenter, &amp;c. to make a Printing Press, or cast Letters, nor import Letters; without first acquainting Stationers' Company.; Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p18">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no<emph type="p">r</emph> person or persons within the City of London
or the Liberties thereof or elsewhere shall ere&bholigct; or cause to be ere&bholigct;ed any Presse or Printing House nor shall
knowingly demise or let or willingly suffer to be held or used any House Vault Cellar or other Room whatsoever
to or by any person or persons for a Printing House or Place to print in unlesse he or they who ere&bholigct; such Presse
or shall so knowingly demise or let such House Cellar Vault or Room or willingly suffer the same to be used
shall first give notice to the Master or Wardens of the said Company of Stationers for the time being of the
ere&bholigct;ing of such Presse or of such demise or suffering to worke or print in such House Vault Cellar or Room
And that no Joyner Carpenter or other person shall make any Printing Presse no Smith shall forge any Iron
worke for a Printing Presse no Founder shall cast any Letters which may be used for printing for any person or
persons whatsoever neither shall any person or persons bring or cause to be brought in from any parts beyond
the Seas any Letters founded or cast nor shall buy any such Letters for printing Printing Presses or other Materials
belonging unto printing unlesse he or they respe&bholigct;ively shall first acquaint the said Master and Wardens of the said
Company of Stationers for the time being or some or one of them for whom the same Presses Iron Worke or Letters
are to be made forged cast brought or imported upon pain that every person who shall ere&bholigct; any such Printing
Press or shall demise or let any House or Room or suffer the same to be held or used and every person who
shall make any Printing Press or any Iron worke for a Printing Presse or shall make import or buy any Letters
for printing without giving notice as aforesaid shall forfeit for every such offence the su&bhooov;m of Five pounds the one
Moyety whereof shall be to the use of our Soveraign Lord the King His Heires and Successors and the other
Moyety to the use of such person or persons as shall sue for the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. No Person to be admitted a Master Printer till the Master Printers be reduced to Twenty, (Exception) which number is to be continued, and Four Master Letter Founders.; In case of Death, &amp;c. of any Master Printer or Founder, the said Archbishop, &amp;c.; to appoint another.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Persons allowed to have a Printing Press, &amp;c. to give Security in &pound;300.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p20">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That for the time to come no man shall be admitted to
be a Master Printer untill they who are now a&bholigct;ually Master Printers shall be by death or otherwise reduced to
the number of Twenty and from thence forth the number of Twenty Master Printers shall be continued and no
more besides the Kings Printers and the Printers allowed for the Universities to have the use and exercise of
printing of Books at one time and but four Master Founders of Letters for printing The which said Master
Printers and four Master Founders of Letters for printing shall be nominated appointed and allowed by the Lord
Archbishop of Canterbury and Lord Bishop of London for the time being And in case of death of any one of
the said four Master Founders of Letters or of the said Master Printers or of Forfeiture or avoidance of any of
their Places and Priviledges to print by vertue of this A&bholigct; for any Offence contrary to the same or otherwise
that then the Lord Archbishop of Canterbury and Lord Bishop of London for the time being or one of them
shall nominate and appoint such other fit person or persons to succeed and supply the place of such Master Printer
or Founder of Letters as shall be void by Death Forfeiture or otherwise as aforesaid And every person and
persons which shall hereafter be allowed or permitted to have the use of a Printing Presse or Printing House upon
or before such his allowance obtained shall become bound with Sureties to His Majesty in the Court of Kings
Bench or before some one or more of the Justices of Assize or the Justices of the Peace at theire several Quarter
Sessions in the su&bhouov;m of three hundred pounds not to print or suffer to be printed in his house or presse any
Booke or Bookes whatsoever but such as shall from time to time be lawfully licensed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. The Number of Presses which Master Printers are allowed to keep.</head>
			<para id="p21">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That none of the said Master Printers to be allowed from
time to time as aforesaid shall keep above Two Printing Presses at once unlesse he hath been Master or Upper
Warden of the Company who are hereby allowed to keepe Three Presses and no more unlesse for some great
and special occasion for the Publique he or they have for a time leave of the said Lord Archbishop of Canterbury
or Lord Bishop of London for the time being to have or use one or more above the aforesaid. Number as theire
Lordships or either of them shall thinke fit</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. The Number of Apprentices which Printers (except the King's Printer) and Letter Founders are allowed to take and retain.</head>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Proviso respe&bholigct;ing replacing runaway Apprentices.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p23">And be it alsoe ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That no Printer or Printers (except the Kings Printers) nor
Founder or Founders of Letters for printing shall take or retain any more or greater number of Apprentices
then is herein after limited and appointed (that is to say) every Master Printer and Master Founder of Letters
for printing that is or hath been Master or Upper Warden of his Company may have three Apprentices at one
time and no more And every Master Printer and Master Founder of Letters for printing that is of the Livery of
his Company may have two Apprentices at one time and no more And every Master Printer and Master Founder
of Letters for printing of the Yeomanry of his Company may have one Apprentice at one time and no more neither
by Copartnership binding at the Scriveners nor any other way whatsoever neither shall it be lawfull for any Master
Printer or Master Founder of Letters when any Apprentice or Apprentices shall run or be put away to take another
Apprentice or other Apprentices in his or theire place or places unlesse the name or names of him or them so
gone away be rased out of the Hall Booke and never admitted againe</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Master Printers and Master Letter Founders to take care that Journeymen are employed;</head>
			<para id="p24">
				<emph type="i">and if Journeyman be out of Employ, he is on Application to be received, if Master Printer havenot a Journeyman, though himself and his Apprentices can do his Work; Penalty &pound;5; Journeymen refusing Employment, or negle&bholigct;ing Work; Imprisonment; Masters not to employ any but Englishmen and Freemen, or Sons of Freemen, and Apprentices.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p25">And because a great part of the secret Printing in corners hath been caused for want of orderly imployment
for Journey men Printers The said several Master Printers and Master Founders of Letters for Printing so to bee
allowed as aforesaid are hereby required to take special Care that all Journey men Printers and Journey men Founders
of Letters for printing who are lawfully Free of the said respe&bholigct;ive Mysteries be set to worke and imployed in
theire respe&bholigct;ive Trades And if any such Journey man Printer or Journey man Founder of Letters being of honest
and good behaviour and able in his Trade do want Imployment he shall repair to any of the said Master Printers
or Master Founders of Letters respe&bholigct;ively for the time being who thereupon shall receive him or them into Worke
If such Master Printer or Master Founder of Letters [have not a Journeyman already although such Mr Printer or
Mr Founder of Letters <ref idref="n8">8</ref>] respe&bholigct;ively with his Apprentice or Apprentices be able without the helpe of the said
Journey man to discharge his owne Work upon pain that every Master Printer and Master Founder of Letters
respe&bholigct;ively refusing to receive such Journey man repairing to him as aforesaid shall forfeit five pounds to be
recovered by Bill Plaint or Information in any Court of Record wherein no Essoign Wager at Law Priviledge or
Prote&bholigct;ion shall be admitted the Moyety of which forfeiture shall go to the Kings Majesty his Heires and Successors
and the other Moyety to the Informer who shall sue for the same within six monthes next after the said offence
committed And if any Journey man or Journey men Printers or Founders of Letters for Printing shall refuse
imployment being offered to him or them by any Master Printer or Master Founder of Letters respe&bholigct;ively or
negle&bholigct; it when he or they have undertaken it he or they so refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing shall suffer three moneths
Imprisonment at the least without Bail or Mainprize upon convi&bholigct;ion of such his said refusal or negle&bholigct; by two
Witnesses before any one or more Justice or Justices of the Peace who are hereby impowered to heare and examine
the said offence and to commit the said Offender and Offenders to the Common Gaol of the County where he or
they shall be apprehended And no Master Printer or Master Founder of Letters for Printing shall from henceforth
imploy either to worke at the Case or Press or otherwise about his Printing any other person or persons then
such only as are Englishmen and Freemen or the Sons of Free men or Apprentices to the said Trades or Mysteries
of Printing or Founding of Letters for Printing respe&bholigct;ively</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Messengers of the King's Chamber by Warrant under Sign Manual or the Hand of Secretary of State, or Master and Wardens of Stationers' Company, with a Constable, may search Houses, &amp;c. for Books, &amp;c. and may demand a Sight of Licence; and seize Books and Offenders.; Justices may imprison.; If Searchers find unlicensed Book which they suspe&bholigct;, they may seize and take it to Archbishop; &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">Proceedings</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p27">And for the better discovering of printing in Corners without License Be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority
aforesaid That [one or more of the Messengers of his Majesties Chamber by Warrant under. His Majesties Sign
Manual or under the Hand of one or both of His Majesties principal Secretares of State or<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] the Master and
Wardens of the said Company of Stationers or any one of them shall have power and authority with a Constable
to take unto them such assistance as they shall thinke needfull and att what time they shall thinke fitt to search
all Houses and Shops where they shall knowe or upon some probable reason suspe&bholigct; any Books or Papers to be
printed bound or stitched especially Printing Houses Booksellers Shops and Warehouses and Bookbinders Houses
and Shops and to view there what is imprinting binding or stitching and to examine whether the same be licensed
and to demand a sight of the said License and if the said Booke soe imprinting binding or stitching shall not be
licensed then to seize upon so much thereof as shall be found imprinted togeather with the several Offenders and
to bring them before one or more Justices of the Peace whoe are hereby authorized and required to commit such
Offenders to Prison there to remaine untill they shall be tried and acquitted or convi&bholigct;ed and punished for the
said Offences And (<ref idref="n10">10</ref>) case the said Searchers shall upon theire said Search find any Booke or Bookes or part of
Bookes unlicensed which they shall suspe&bholigct; to contain matters therein contrary to the Do&bholigct;rine or Discipline of the
Church of England or against the State and Government Then upon such suspition to seise upon such Book or
Books or part of Book or Books and to bring the same unto the said Lord Archbishop of Canterbury and Lord
Bishop of London for the time being or one of them or to the Secretaries of State or one of them respe&bholigct;ively
who shall take such further course for the suppressing thereof as to them or any of them shall seeme fit.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Printers, Letter Founders, &amp;c. working for the Trade, offending.</head>
			<para id="p28">
				<emph type="i">First Offence, Punishment.; Second Offence, Punishment.; Quarter Sessions may determine Offences; and to certify Fines to the Exchequer yearly; and may award Process and Execution.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p29">And be it ordained and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every Printer and Printers of Books
Founder and Founders of Letters for Printing and all and every other person and persons working in or for the
said Trades who from and after the Tenth day of June in the Yeare One thousand six hundred sixty and
two shall offend against this present A&bholigct; or any Article Clause or Thing herein contained and shall be thereof
convi&bholigct;ed by verdi&bholigct; confession or otherwise shall for the first offence be disenabled from exercising his respe&bholigct;ive
Trade for the space of three yeares and for the second offence shall for ever thence after be disabled to use or
exercise the Art or Mystery of Printing or of Founding Letters for Printing and shall alsoe have and receive such
further punishment by Fine Imprisonment or other Corporal Punishment not extending to Life or Limb as by the
Justices of the Court of Kings Bench or Justices of Oyer and Terminer or Justices of Assize in theire several
Circuits or Justices of the Peace in theire several Quarter Sessions shall be thought fitt to be infli&bholigct;ed The which
said Justices of the Peace in theire several Quarter Sessions shall have full power and authority to heare and
determine all and every offence and offences that shall be committed against this A&bholigct; or against any branch thereof
upon indi&bholigct;ment or information by any person or persons to be taken before them in theire Sessions of Peace
respe&bholigct;ively and shall yearely certifie into the Court of Exchequer as in other like Cases they are bound to doe
the Fines by them imposed for any the offences aforesaid and shall and may alsoe by vertue hereof award process
and execution for the taking or punishing such Offenders as in any other Case they lawfully may do by any the
Lawes and Statutes of this Realm</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Printers to reserve Three Copies of every Book, one for the King's Library, and one for each of the Universities.</head>
			<para id="p30">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every Printer shall reserve three printed Copies of
the best and largest Paper of every Book new printed or reprinted by him with Additions and shall before any
publick venting of the said Book bring them to the Master of the Company of Stationers and deliver them to
him one whereof shall be delivered to the Keeper of his Majesties Library and the other two to be sent to the
Vice-Chancellors of the two Universities respe&bholigct;ively for the use of the Publique Libraries of the said Universities</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Proviso for Universities licensing.</head>
			<para id="p31">Provided alwaies That nothing in this A&bholigct; contained shall be construed to extend to the p&bhopcrl;judice or infringing
of any the just Rights and Priviledges of either of the two Universities of this Realm touching and concerning
the licensing or printing of Books in either of the said Universities</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. No Search in Houses of Peers, or of Persons using other Trades, without special Licence.</head>
			<para id="p32">Provided alwaies That no search shall be att any time made in the House or Houses of any the Peers of this
Realm or of any other person or persons not being free of or using any of the Trades in this A&bholigct; before
mentioned but by special Warrant from the Kings Majestie under His Sign Manual or under the Hand of one or
both of His Majesties principal Secretaries of State or for any other Books then such as are in printing or shall
be printed after the Tenth of June One thousand six hundred sixty two Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary
thereof in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Booksellers may import certain Books ready bound not formerly prohibited.</head>
			<para id="p33">Provided alsoe That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein conteined shall extend to prohibit any Booke seller
who hath served seven yeares and is free of the Company of Stationers London from importing or bringing into
this Realme any Bookes ready bound not formerly prohibited which have beene printed ten yeares before the said
importation Any thing in this or any other A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Proviso for Persons who have sold Books or Papers in Westminster Hall, Palace of Westminster, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p34">Provided alsoe and be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein
contained shall be construed to prohibit any person or persons to sell Books or Papers who have sold Books or
Papers within Westminster Hall the Palace of Westminster or in any Shopp or Shopps within twenty yards of the
great Gate of Westminster Hall aforesaid before the Twentieth day of November One thousand six hundred sixty
and one but they and every of them may sell Books and Papers as they have or did before the said Twentieth
Day of November One thousand six hundred sixty one within the said Hall Pallace and twenty yards aforesaid but
not else where Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Proviso for Grantees under the Great Seal, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p35">Provided alsoe That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend to p&bhopcrl;judice the just Rights
or Priviledges granted by His Majesty or any of his Royall Predecessors to any person or persons under His
Majesties Great Seale or otherwise but that such person or persons may exercise and use such Rights and Priviledges
as aforesaid according to theire respective Grants Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Proviso for John Streater, Stationer.</head>
			<para id="p36">Provided alsoe That neither this A&bholigct; nor any (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) therein contained shall extend to prohibit John Streater Stationer
from printing Bookes and Papers but that he may still follow the Art and Mistery of Printing as if this A&bholigct; had
never beene made Any thing therein to the contrary notwithstanding<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]<?bignore?></para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Proviso for keeping and using a Printing Press in the City of York with Conditions.</head>
			<para id="p37">[Provided alsoe That neither this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend to restrain the keeping and
using of a Printing Presse in the City of Yorke so as all Bookes of Divinity there printed be first licensed by the
Archbishop of Yorke for the time being or such person or persons whom he shall appoint and all other Bookes
whatsoever there printed be first licensed by such persons respe&bholigct;ively to whom the licensing thereof doth or shall
appertain by the rules herein before mentioned and so as no Bibles be there printed nor any other Booke whereof
the Original Copy is or shall [be<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] belonging to the Company of Stationers in London or any Member thereof and
so as the Archbishop or Lord Mayor of Yorke for the time being do execute within the said City (which they are
hereby impowered to do) all the Powers and Rules in this A&bholigct; concerning Searchers for unlicensed Bookes and
impose and levy the said penalties in the like cases Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p38">[Provided That this A&bholigct; shall continue and be in force for two yeares to commence from the Tenth of June
One thousand six hundred sixty and two and no longer.<ref idref="n12">12</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p39">Item quedam Petic&bhocotil;ones privatas personas concernentes (in se formam Actus continentes) exhibite fuerunt p&bhopcrl;dicto
Domino Regi Parliamento p&bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o qua? Tituli subscribuntur</para>
			<para id="p40">1. An Act for the setling of the Estate of James late Duke of Richmond and Lenos according to Agreement
of Charles Duke of Richmond and Lenos Mary Dutchesse of Dowager of Richmond and Lenos and the Lady Mary
her daughter and the Trustees of the said Lady Dutchesse.</para>
			<para id="p41">2. An Act for confirmation of certain Letters Patents made and to be made to the Right Noble Lord George
Duke of Albemarle of several Honors Mannors and Hereditaments graunted or mentioned to be granted to him
by his Majestie</para>
			<para id="p42">3. An Act for confirming the Estate of John Marquesse of Winchester in certain Manors and Lands whereof
the Deeds and Evidences were burnt and lost at the taking of the Castle of Basing</para>
			<para id="p43">4. An Act to confirm the Sale of certain Lands sold by Ferdinando late Earle of Huntingdon for the payment
of his owne and his Fathers debts.</para>
			<para id="p44">5. An Act for the reversing the Earle of Strafford his Attainder.</para>
			<para id="p45">6. An Act for setling a Capital Messuage or Mansion House with the Appurtenances in Kensington in the
County of Middlesex upon Baptist Viscount Campden and his Heires.</para>
			<para id="p46">7. An Act for confirming an A&bholigct; for restoring to Thomas Lord Culpeper Son and Heire and sole Executor of
John Lord Culpeper Baron of Thorsway and Master of the Rolls deceased all his Honors Manors Lands and
Tenements Leases not determined and Hereditaments whatsoever whereof the said John Lord Culpeper was in
possession on the twentieth of May 1642 or att any time after which have not beene since sold or aliened by
the said John late Lord Culpeper by A&bholigct;s or Assurances to which himselfe was party and consenting</para>
			<para id="p47">8. An Act to enable the Bishop of London to Lease out the Tenements now built upon the Scite of his
Palace in London.</para>
			<para id="p48">9. An Act for the Naturalizing of Philadelphia Wife to the Right Honorable Thomas Lord Wentworth.</para>
			<para id="p49">10. An Act for confirming several A&bholigct;s therein mentioned.</para>
			<para id="p50">11. An Act for confirming two A&bholigct;s therein mentioned.</para>
			<para id="p51">12. An Act for the Endowment of several Churches by the Lord Viscount Scudamore of Sligo in the Realm
of Ireland</para>
			<para id="p52">13. An Act for the disuniting the Hundreds of Dudston and Kings Barton from the County of the City of
Gloucester and restoring them to be part of the County of Gloucester.</para>
			<para id="p53">14. An Act for the making Navigable of the Rivers of Stower and Salwerp and the Rivulets and Brookes
running into the same in the Counties of Worcester and Stafford.</para>
			<para id="p54">15. An Act for the making navigable of the Rivers of Wye and Lugg and the Rivers and Brookes running
into the same in the Counties of Hereford Gloucester and Monmouth.</para>
			<para id="p55">16. An Act for setling certain Mannors and Lands late of Sir James Enyons Baronet on Sir Henry Puckering
alias Newton Baronet and Sir Charles Aderly Knight his surviving Trustees to sell for payment of his Debts.</para>
			<para id="p56">17. An Act for confirmation of certain Decrees of Sewers made by the Commissioners for the limits of the
Level of the River of Ancholm in the County of Lincoln.</para>
			<para id="p57">18. An Act for confirming a Decree made on the behalfe of Thomas Derham Esq&bhoqesq; and the Improvements
Exchanges and Allotments therein mentioned.</para>
			<para id="p58">19. An Act for the enabling Sir Thomas Lee Baronet to exchange some Lands setled upon the Marriage of
Dame Anne Lee his nowe Wife in consideration of another Settlement of Lands of equal value in lieu thereof.</para>
			<para id="p59">20. An Act for discharging the Mannors of Stodscomb &amp; Holwell and other Lands in the County of Devon
from the trust of one hundred and fifty yeares made unto John Earle of Exeter John Earl of Bridgewater and
Oliver Earl of Bolingbrooke</para>
			<para id="p60">21. An Act for supplying a supposed defe&bholigct; of the words Stand and be seized in a Deed for setling of divers
Manors and Lands on Sir Henry Frederick Thynne.</para>
			<para id="p61">22. An Act for confirming the Copyhold Estates of divers of His Majesties Copyhold Tenants within the Honour
of Clitherow in the County Palatine of Lancaster parcell of the Dutchy of Lancaster according unto several Decrees
in the Court of Dutchy Chamber of the said County Palatine</para>
			<para id="p62">23. An Act for confirmation of the Estates of several Tenants and Copy holders of the Mannors of Rannes
Irchester Rushden &amp; several other Manors parcels of the Dutchy of Lancaster</para>
			<para id="p63">24. An Act for confirming explaining and enlarging an A&bholigct; intituled An A&bholigct; for the leavying of certain Moneys
due upon the Colle&bholigct;ion for the Protestants of Piedmont.</para>
			<para id="p64">25. An Act to inable the sale of some of the Lands of William Milward Esquire for payment of some of his
Debts.</para>
			<para id="p65">26. An Act vesting certain Lands in Bleasby in Sir John Mounson the younger Robert Thorold Esquire and
Anthony Eyre the elder Esq&bhoqesq; &amp; their heires to sell for paym&bhomsst;t of the debts of Sir Robert Dallison and William
Dallison.</para>
			<para id="p66">27. An Act to enable the Trustees of Henry Nevil Esq&bhoqesq; to sell certain Mannors Lands and Tenements in the
Counties of Yorke and Leicester for payment of his and his son William Nevils debts and likewise to confirm and
strengthen the sale of such Lands as they have already sold in the County of Yorke</para>
			<para id="p67">28. An Act for the making void certain Fines unduly procured to be leavyed by Sir Edward Powel Knight
and Baronet and Dame Mary his wife</para>
			<para id="p68">29. An Act for sale of Sir Robert Slingsby deceased his Lands for payment of his debts</para>
			<para id="p69">30. An Act to enable Sir Anthony Brown to sell Lands for payment of Debts.</para>
			<para id="p70">31. An Act to enable Anthony Etrick to sell Lands for payment of his Debts.</para>
			<para id="p71">32. An Act for the naturalizing of Anna Ferrers and several other persons named therein</para>
			<para id="p72">33. An Act for the Naturalization of Mark le Pla and others.</para>
			<para id="p73">34. An Act for the repairing of Bengworth Bridge in the County of Worcester</para>
			<para id="p74">35. An Act to enable Rowland Okeover Esq&bhoqesq; to sell certain Lands in the County of Derby</para>
			<para id="p75">36. An Act to enable M?s Clemence Rivers and M?s Rose Rivers to sell certain Lands and Houses for payment
of the Debts of Edward Rivers Esq&bhoqesq; deceased and provision for his younger children</para>
			<para id="p76">37. An Act enabling Thomas Peck Esq&bhoqesq; to sell a Manor and some Lands in the County of Norfolk for the
payment of his Debts and other uses</para>
			<para id="p77">38. An Act for confirmation of Agreements made between Thomas Bushell Esq&bhoqesq; and the Miners of Rowpits in
Somersettshire for recovering their drowned and deserted workes</para>
			<para id="p78">39. An Act for the setling certain Lands belonging unto Francis Tindal Gentleman upon Trustees to be sold
for the payment of Debts.</para>
			<para id="p79">40. An Act for confirmation of three A&bholigct;s therein mentioned.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">disperse <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">in <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">thing <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


