<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47346" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter X. An Act for confirming of Fower Subsidyes granted by the Clergy. [Rot. Parl. 15 C. II. p. I. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of Grant of Four entire Subsidies given by the Clergy of Canterbury.</head>
		<para id="p1">[Whereas the Prelates and Clergy of the Province of Canterbury for diverse weighty Considerations respe&bholigct;ing
His Majestyes extraordinary Occasions have loveingly and liberally given and granted to the Kings most
Excellent Majestie Fower whole and intire Subsidyes of Fower shillings in the pound to be taken and levyed of
all and singular their Promotions Spirituall within the same Province at such dayes and times and in such certaine
manner and forme and with such Exceptions and Provisions as are specifyed and declared in a certaine Instrument
by them thereof made, and delivered unto the Kings Majesty under the Seale of the Right Reverend Father in
God Gilbert Lord Bishop of London, which Instrument is now exhibited in this present Parliament to be ratyfyed
and confirmed, the tenoure whereof ensueth in these words.<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
		<para id="p2">
			<emph type="i">Tenor of the Instrument.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p3">Excellentissimo et Potentissimo in Christo Principi, et Domino nostro Clementissimo Domino Carolo secundo Dei
gra Anglie Sc&otilde;e Francie et Hibernie Regi Fidei Defensori &amp;c Gilbertus permissione Divina London Episcopus
presentis Sacre Synodi sive Convocationis Prelator&umacr; et Cleri Cantuariensis Provinci&aelig; Presidens sive loc&umacr; tenens
sufficienter et legitime constitutus omnimod&amacr; Obedienti&amacr; et Subje&bholigct;ion&emacr; ac Felicitat&emacr; et Salut&emacr; in Eo per quem Reges
regnant et Principes dominantur Vestre Serenissime Regie Sublimitati per &bhopcrl;&bhoaovm; public&umacr; Instrument&umacr; sive has Literas
nostras Testimoniales significamus et not&umacr; facimus, Quod Prelati et Clerus Cant Provincie in sacra Synodo Provinciali
sive Convocatione vigore et authoritate Brevis Vestri Regii Reverendissimo in Christo Patri et Domino Guilielmo
Providentia Divina Cantuar Archiepiscopo totius Anglie Primati et Metropolitano modo defunto in domo Capitulari
Vestre Ecclesie Cathedralis Divi Pauli London o&bholigct;avo die Mensis Maii A&bhonov;o D&bhomtild;i Millesimo sexcentesimo sexagesimo
primo inchoata et celebrata de die in di&emacr; et loco in loc&umacr; usq&bhoqesq; ad tricesim&umacr; di&emacr; mensis Maii A&bhonov;o D&bhomtild;i Millesimo
sexcentesimo sexagesimo tertio jam current continuata et prorogata, et a di&bholigct;o tricesimo die mensis Maii ac de die
in die et loco in loc&umacr; usq&bhoqesq; ad et in decim&umacr; terti&umacr; di&emacr; Mensis Junii A&bhonov;o D&bhomtild;i Millesimo sexcentissimo sexagesimo
tertio jam instant continuata et Prorogata et post mort&emacr; dci Reverendissimi Patrisac a dicto [decimo<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] tertio die Mensis
Junii &bhopcrl;dct vigore Brevis vestri Regii Custodi Spiritualitatis Archiepiscopatus Cant (Sede [Archiepiscopali<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Cant vacant)
direct ac vigore Commissionis a dco Custode Spualitatis Archiepiscopalis Cant nobis in hac parte eti&amacr; direct, ac de
die in di&emacr; et loco in loc&umacr; usq&bhoqesq; ad et in vicesim&umacr; di&emacr; j&amacr; instant Mensis Junii eti&amacr; continuata et prorogata et a dicto
vicesimo die instantis Mensis Junii de die in di&emacr; et loco in loc&umacr; usq&bhoqesq; ad et in vicesim&umacr; septim&umacr; di&emacr; j&amacr; instant Mensis
Junii etiam tent et continuata in Ecclesia Collegiata Divi Petri Westmonesteriens legitim&egrave; congregat pro quibusd&amacr;
magnis arduis et urgentibus causis per nos eis ppositis ac inter eos matura deliberacioe ponderatis pro defensione
Regnor&umacr; et Dominior&umacr; Vestror&umacr; necnon et pro eor&umacr; erga Vestr&amacr; Regi&amacr; Sublimitat&emacr; observantia et obsequio Quatuor
ultranea ac spontanea et voluntaria Subsidia vestre Regie Majestati unanimi eor&umacr; consensu et assensu dederunt et
concesserunt prout tenore presentis publici Instrumenti (seri&emacr; concessionis hujusmodi in se continentis) plenius liquet
et apparet; humiliter et obnixe Vestre Regie Majestati supplicantes, quatenus hec eor&umacr; quatuor Subsidia pro Vestra
solita Clementia benign&emacr; accipiatis, ac bene consulere gratiose dignemini. Tenor vero dce Concessionis de verbo in
verb&umacr; sequitur et est talis.</para>
		<para id="p4">
			<emph type="i">Prelates, &amp;c. of Province of Canterbury assembled in Convocation.; grant Four whole Subsidies of 4s. in the Pound on all Spiritual Promotions.; Benefices shall be valued according to Taxation of the Tenth under 26 H. VIII. c. 3.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p5">Most Gratious Soveraigne Your Majestyes leige and humble Subjects the Prelates and Clergy of the Province of
Canterbury called together by the Authority of Your Highnesse Writt and orderly assembled at this present in a
Provinciall Synod or Convocation maturely considering their Duty and Service which they owe to Your Majestie
as to their Soveraigne Lord, in thankfull acknowledgement of the many Blessings which they enjoy under Your
gratious Government and Protection and well weighing the great and extraordinary Expences whereat Your Majestie
now is, and hereafter is like to be for Support of Your Estate and Defence of Your Realmes and Dominions
with one agreement and uniforme consent have given and granted And by these presents doe give and grant to
Your Highnesse Your Heires and Successors Fower whole and intire Subsidyes of Fower shillings in the pound in
manner and forme following (that is to say) that every Archbishop Bishop Deane Archdeacon Provost Master of a
Colledge, Prebendary Parson or Vicar and every other person [or<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] persons of whatsoever name or degree he or they
be within the Province of Canterbury haveing and enjoying any Spirituall Promotion or other Temporall Possessions
to the same Spirituall Promotion annexed now not divided nor seperated by Act of Parliament or otherwise from
the Possession of the Clergy shall pay to Your Highnesse Your Heires and Successors for every pound that he
may yearely receave and dispend by reason of the said Spirituall Promotion the s&umacr;e of Fower shillings for every
of the said Fower Subsidyes, And for the true and certaine value of all the Promotions and every of them whereof
the payments of these Fower Subsidyes shall be made, the Rate Taxation, Valuation and Estimation now remaining
of Record in Your Majestyes Court of Exchequer for the payment of a perpetuall Disme or Tenth granted unto
King Henry the Eighth of worthy memory in the six and twentyeth yeare of his Raigne concerning such Promotions
as now be in the [possessions<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] of the Clergy shall onely be followed and observed without makeing any
other Valuation Rate Taxation or Estimation then in the said Record is comprised;</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. but shall pay Subsidy on 9-10ths only.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Manner and Form and Time of Payment of Subsidies.; Fee to Receiver.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwayes That forasmuch as the Tenth part of the said Rate and Valuation before-mentioned is yearely
paid to Your Highnesse for the said perpetuall Disme and Tenth soe as there remaine onely Nine parts yearely
to the Incumbent cleare, these Fower Subsidyes of Fower shillings of the pound shall be understood and meant
onely of every full pound of the said Nine parts and noe thing for any other [moneyes<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] not amounting to a full
pound, And Your Prelates and Clergy doe alsoe grant that these Fower Subsidyes of Fower shillings of the full
pound of the Nine parts of the yearely value of every Spirituall Promotion aforesaid within the said Province, taxed
as is aforesaid shall be paid to Your Majestye Your Heires and Successors in manner and forme following that is
to say the whole payment of the first of the said Fower Subsidyes (viz) Fower shillings of every full pound as
aforesaid to be due at and upon the fifth day of O&bholigct;ber now next ensueing, And the first Payment and Moyety
of the second of the said Fower Subsidyes viz Two shillings of every full pound as aforesaid to be due at and
upon the six and twentyeth day of March in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty fower
And the second Payment and Moyety of the second of the said Fower Subsidyes viz Two shillings of every full
pound as aforesaid to be due at and upon the fifth day of O&bholigct;ober next following, And the first Payment and
Moyety of the third of the said Fower Subsidyes viz Two shillings of every full pound as aforesaid to be due
at and upon the six and twentyeth day of March which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand
six hundred sixty five, And the second payment and Moyety of the third of the said Fower Subsidyes viz Two
shillings of every full pound as aforesaid to be due at and upon the fifth day of October next and immediately
following, And the first Payment and Moyety of the fourth and last of these Fower Subsidyes viz Two shillings
of every full pound as aforesaid to be due at and upon the six and twentyeth day of March which shall be in
the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty six, And the second and last Payment and Moyety
of the fourth and last of these Fower Subsidyes to be due at and upon the fifth day of O&bholigct;ober next following
which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty and six to be delivered and paid
by such person and persons as in this present Grant shall be appointed to have the Colle&bholigct;ion thereof to the Lord
High Treasurer or Under Treasurer of England for the time being, or to such person or persons and in such
place or places as shall please Your Highnesse to appoint to be paid viz Every one of the aforesaid Payments of
the first of the said Fower Subsidyes which shall be due at and upon the fifth day of October in any of the
aforesaid yeares to be paid at or before the last Returne of Hillary Terme next following every of the aforesaid
dayes in which every of the aforesaid Payments shall be due; And every of the aforesaid Payments which shall
be due on the six and twentyeth day of March as aforesaid to be made at or before the last Returne of Trinity
Terme next following every of the aforesaid dayes when the said Payments shall be due without paying any thing
to the Receiver or any other person or Officer to be assigned for the receipt thereof for any Acquittance or other
discharge or dispatch upon any such Payment or Receipt of the said Fower Subsidyes or any part thereof but
onely Fower pence, And that to the Clerke for writeing of the Acquittance or discharge of every of the said
Payments,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Subsidy not payable for the Year in which First Fruits are paid.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided alwayes That noe person that is or which hereafter shall be promoted to any Benefice or Spirituall
Promotion, and hath compounded or shall compound with Your Majestie Your Heires or Successors for the First
fruites of the same from the fifth day of October last past viz in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand
six hundred sixtie and two and on this side the fifth day of October now next ensueing which shall be in this
presenty eare One thousand [six hundred <ref idref="n7">7</ref>] sixty three shall be contributory or charged for the same Benefice or
Promotion to Your Highnesse Your Heires or Successors with any part of the First of the said Fower Subsidyes
due upon the fifth day of O&bholigct;ober now next ensueing, And that noe person which hereafter shall be promoted
to any Benefice or Spirituall Promotion, And shall compound with Your Majestie Your Heires or Successors for the
First fruites of the same from and after the six and twentyeth day of March which shall be in the yeare of
our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty fower, and on this side the fifth day of O&bholigct;ober which shall be
in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty six shall be contributary or charged for the same
Benefice or Promotion to Your Highnesse Your Heires or Successors with any part of the other three Subsidyes
dureing the first yeare after the time of any such compounding for his First fruites;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Archbishops, &amp;c. shall be Collectors.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Collectors offering Payment, Officer to receive the same within Four Days and give Receipt to Collector.; Auditors to take Accounts and make Allowances.; Delaying, &amp;c. so to do, Penalty &pound;10.; Imprisonment until Penalty paid.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p10">Item Your Highnesse said Prelates and Clergy doe grant That every Archbishop Bishop, and (the See being
void) every Deane and Chapter of that See void, And none other person or persons shall be Colle&bholigct;or of the said
Fower Subsidyes within their proper Diocesse dureing the time appointed for the payment of the said Fower
Subsidyes, And Your said Prelates and Clergy doe most humbly beseech Your Majestye that it may be ena&bholigct;ed by
Your Majestie and Your High Court of Parliament for the speedy payment of the said Fower Subsidyes and to
avoid delayes thereof that when and as often as any Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors chargeable with the Colle&bholigct;ion of the
said Fower Subsidyes or of any part thereof, or their or any of their Under Colle&bholigct;or or Under Collectors Deputie
or Deputyes of any of them shall offer the Payment of the said Fower Subsidyes or of any part of them to the
use of Your Majestie Your Heires and Successors to any person or persons appointed to receive the same by Your
Highnesse or by Your Lord High Treasurer, That the said person or persons soe appointed shall within Fower
dayes next after such appointment receive or cause to be received the Money soe offered to be paid without any
further delay, and deliver one sufficient Bill testifying the receipt thereof to the said Colle&bholigct;or or his Under Colle&bholigct;or
or Deputy upon every such perticular Payment, And that every such Auditor as is or shall be appointed to take
or receive the accompt of any such Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors or of their severall Under Collectors or Deputyes
shall within six dayes next after request to him to be made truely and indifferently take the said Accompt and
make allowance as by this Grant is appointed, upon paine that every such person or persons appointed to receive
the same summe or summes of Money soe offered, and every such Auditor shall loose and forfeite for every
defaulte or delay to be made to the Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors [Under Collector or <ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Under Colle&bholigct;ors Deputye or
Deputyes soe offering to make Payment or Accompt as is aforesaid the summe of Ten pounds of lawfull Money
of England, the one Moyety thereof to be to Your Majestie Your Heires and Successors, and the other Moyety
to the said Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors Under Colle&bholigct;or or Under Colle&bholigct;ors Deputy or Deputyes soe greived, the
same to be paid upon Complaint to be made to the said Lord Treasurer or Under Treasurer or to the Lord Cheife
Baron of Your Majestyes Court of Exchequer, who upon such Complaint shall presently examine the matter,
and finding the fault shall committ the Offender to Ward there to remaine untill he shall have paid the said
severall sumes soe forfeited.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Power to Collectors to levy Subsidies; may account for the same as the King and Exchequer shall appoint, as Archbishops, &amp;c. account for the Teuth.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Archbishops, &amp;c. gathering and paying what they can to be discharged for the rest.; Sixpence in the Pound allowed to Collectors.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p12">And for the better levying and recovering of these Foure Subsidyes or any of them, Your said Prelates and
Clergy doe likewise most humbly beseech Your Majestye that it may be enacted by Your Majestie and Your said
High Court of Parlyament in manner and forme following (that is to say) That every Colle&bholigct;or of the said Fower
Subsidyes and of every part and parcell of them and their lawfull Under Collector or Under Collectors Deputy
or Deputyes may have full Power and Authority to use all such wayes and meanes and Processe as be prescribed
in the A&bholigct; of perpetuall Disme, for the Colle&bholigct;ion and levying thereof, And may make Accompt of the same
before the Lord High Treasurer or Under Treasurer of England for the time being or any other Officer by Your
Highnesse or Your Court of Exchequer to be appointed for the same, And in such place as Your Majestie shall
likewise assigne in such wise and after such forme onely as the said Archbishop and Bishops be now charged to
make Accompt for the said perpetuall Disme and Tenth, Whereby is meant that the lacke and defaulte of Payment
of and for any Spirituall Promotion or Promotions shall onely charge such Incumbent or Incumbents and such
others as be bound to pay the same; And that the Archbishop Bishop Deane and Chapter gathering that which
they can receive and make[ing<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] payment thereof shall for the rest not by them received be discharged by their
Certificate to be made unto Your Highnesse Court of Exchequer for every of the aforesaid Payments which shall
be due upon the Fifth day of October in any of the aforesaid yeares at or before the last Returne of Hillary
Terme next and imediately following every of the aforesaid dayes when every of the said payments shall be due,
And for every of the aforesaid Payments which shall be due upon the Six and twentyeth day of March in any
of the aforesaid yeares at or before the last Returne of Trinity Terme next and immediately following every of
the aforesaid dayes when the said Payments shall be due, And that six pence of every pound wherewith the
Colle&bholigct;or shall be charged in this Accompt clearely to be paid into the Receipt of Your Majestyes Exchequer, or
into such other place as shall please Your Highnesse to appoint shall be allowed unto the said Colle&bholigct;or upon
his Accompt for the same at every of the aforesaid severall times of Payment for the charge of the said Colle&bholigct;ion,
portage, safe conveying and paying of the said Fower Subsidyes;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Incumbents, &amp;c. being monished and not paying Subsidies, Proceedings.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Such Default shall be certified into Exchequer.; Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p14">And moreover that it may be ena&bholigct;ed likewise That after any Payment of the said Fower Subsidyes shall be
once due by vertue of this Grant, If any Incumbent of any Benefice or Promotion Spirituall charged to the Payment
of any the said Fower Subsidyes, or any part thereof being at any time after that the same Payment shall be due,
lawfully monished either personally or at his Dignity Stall Church or Mansion House by the Archbishop or
Bishop of the Diocesse or his Under Colle&bholigct;or or Under Colle&bholigct;ors Deputy or Deputyes, or by the Deane and
Chapter (the See being void) or by any of their Under Colle&bholigct;or or Under Colle&bholigct;ors Deputie or Deputyes
authorized in that behalfe, to appeare by himselfe, or his Deputy at a certaine day and place of convenient distance
to the said Incumbent then to be signifyed and prefixed, And then and there to pay such part of the said Fower
Subsidyes for his Benefice or Promotion Spirituall or the whole as then by vertue of this Grant shall be due
doe not either at the same day and place soe to him signifyed and prefixed truely content and pay or cause to
be contented and paid such Payments of the said Fower Subsidyes as then by him shall be due to be paid unto
the same Archbishop or Bishop, or to his Under colle&bholigct;or or Under colle&bholigct;ors Deputy or Deputyes or to the Deane
and Chapter of any See being void or to their Under Colle&bholigct;or or Under Colle&bholigct;ors Deputy or Deputyes or to one
of them shewing sufficient Deputation from the said Archbishop Bishop or Deane and Chapter under his or their
seale in that behalfe being ready at the said day and place soe signifyed and prefixed to receive any Payment
of the said Fower Subsidyes then due, and openly demanding the same, or else pay every of the Payments of the
said Fower Subsidyes given by this Grant within Fifty dayes next after any such prefixed dayes of warning at the
farthest soe that open demand be made of every of the said Payments of the said Fower Subsidyes in and at the
said place and day before prefixed, That then every Incumbent soe makeing defaulte of Payment of any of the
Payments aforesaid which shall be due from him for any of the parts of the said Fower Subsidyes as aforesaid
after such defaulte thereof certifyed into Your Majestyes Exchequer in writeing under the seale and hand writeing
of any Archbishop or Bishop, or the common Seale of the Deane and Chapter (the See being void) charged with
the Colle&bholigct;ion of the said Fower Subsidies or any part thereof soe that the said Certificate shall be made according
to the forme hereafter expressed and exhibited into Your Majestyes said Court of Exchequer (viz) For every of
the aforesaid payments of the said Fower Subsidyes which shall be due the Fifth day of O&bholigct;ober in any of the
aforesaid yeares at or before the last Returne of Hillary Terme next following every of the aforesaid dayes when
every of the said payments shall be due, And for every of the aforesaid payments which shall be due upon the
Six and twentyeth day of March in any of the aforesaid yeares at or before the last Returne of Trinity Terme next
following every of the aforesaid dayes when every of the said payments shall be due as aforesaid shall forfeite and
loose unto Your Majestie Your Heires and Successors all the Proffitts which of that onely Dignitie Benefice or
Promotion, for the which he maketh such defaulte of Payment and whereof such Certificate shall be made shall
come grow and arise unto him over and above the Charges of serveing the Cure; And the annuall Tenth due to
be paid out of his said Liveing in one whole yeare next after such Certificate made and delivered unto Your
Highnesse Court of Exchequer and there admitted in case the said Incumbent shall soe long live, And that every
such Certificate of any such defaulte of payment shall be made according to the tenoure and effect ensueing
Mutatis mutandis.</para>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Form of Certificate of Default.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p16">Honorabilibus et Egregiis viris Domino Thesaurario et Baronibus de Scaccario Illustrissimi Domini nostri,
Domini Caroli secundi Dei gratia Anglie Scotie Francie et Hibernie Regis Fidei Defensoris &amp;c Vester humilis
permissione divina Authoritate et Vigore cujusdam Actus Parliamenti Anno Regni dicti Domini
Regis editi et provisi ad colligend&umacr; et levand&umacr; Subsidia eid&emacr; Domino Regi in eod&emacr; Parliamento per
Prelatos et Cler&umacr; Cantuariensis Provincie concessa viz pro prima solutione primi et integri Subsidii solvend
die Octob p[re]terit infra Dioces nostr&amacr; Deputatus et Authorizatus omnimoda reverentia tantis viris debit&amacr;
cum honore, Vestris Reverentiis har&umacr; serie annuncio et certifies, me prefat&umacr; Episcop&umacr; modo quo p[re]fertur deputat&umacr;
et authorizat&umacr; sufficienter et cum omni diligentia requisivisse per N: O, Subcollector&emacr; seu Deputat&umacr; me&umacr; in hac
parte de quovis Beneficio et Promotione Ecclesiastica in quad&amacr; Schedula presentibus annex : specificat, sumas solutionis
dci primi integri Subsidii pro dictis Beneficiis et Promotionibus debitas et solvendas dco quinto die Octobris ult
p[re]terit prout in ead&emacr; Schedula p[re]sentibus, annex : plenius liquet et apparet; sed dictas summas ex causis in ead&emacr;
Schedula allegatis recipere non potui, In cujus rei testimoni&umacr; sigill&umacr; Da&umacr; die</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>The forme of which Schedule above-mentioned ensueth</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Form of Schedule, referred to in Certificate.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p18">Civitatis L, vel Deconatus de H: A: B, Rector vel Vicarius ibidem monitus fuit apud p[re]dict
die Mensis ultimo &bhopcrl;terit per N O Subcollector&emacr; seu deputat me&umacr; ad solvend&amacr; apud Eclesi&amacr; de L. in Comit R
die mensis (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) proxime sequent, solution&emacr; sive ill&amacr; part&emacr; dictor&umacr; quatuor Subsidior&umacr; per ips&umacr; debit
die ult &bhopcrl;terit pro promotione sua &bhopcrl;dicta, sed &bhopcrl;dicus A B nec apud Ecclesi&amacr; de L. &bhopcrl;dict, eod&emacr;
nec alibi per quinqueginta dies postea sum&amacr; per ips&umacr; debit, (ut &bhopcrl;fertur) solvit vel satisfecit, neq&bhoqesq; dict&amacr; sum&amacr; de
proficuis dicte Promotionis nec de bonis et catallis dicti A. B aliquo modo levare sive recipere potui.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VII. Provise for Tender of Payment by Incumbent, &amp;c. before Certificate exhibited into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Trial of Tender.; If Issue found for Incumbent, he shall enjoy his Promotion.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p20">Provided alwayes That if any person or Incumbent chargeable by this Act or Grant to any Payment of the
said Fower Subsidyes or any part thereof shall proffer or tender Payment of any summe due to the Archbishop
or Bishop, or to the Deane and Chapter (where the See is void) or to any Under Collector or Under Colle&bholigct;ors
Deputy or Deputyes of any Arch-bishop, Bishop or Deane and Chapter aforesaid, at any time before the Certificate
exhibited into the Exchequer as is aforesaid, that then and notwithstanding the Certificate made as is aforesaid
against any such person, the said Incumbent or person against whom the Certificate was soe, made shall and may
averr the offer or tender of his Payment, as is aforesaid, And of the same shall be tryed either by sufficient
wittnesses before the Lord Treasurer and Barons of the Exchequer or by the tryall of Twelve men upon any
Issue therupon to be joyned betwixt the said Incumbent and any other person or persons that he or any for him
did offer or tender Payment of the summe due as aforesaid, which being found for the Incumbent then every such
Incumbent shall have and enjoy his Promotion or Promotions still without forfeiture or loseing to Your Majestie
Your Heires or Successors any the Profits thereof, And as though noe Certificate or defaulte of any such Payment
had beene made or exhibited, Any thing in this present Grant or Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>VIII. Quietus est to Archbishops, &amp;c. being Collectors.</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Such Quietus est a good Discharge in Law.; Fee for Quietus est.; Refusing, &amp;c. Quietus est, or taking a larger Fee.; Penalty &pound;10.; Particular Acquittance by Collector to Incumbent, &amp;c. a full Discharge in Law.; Acquitance before Certificate not good.; Names of Under collectors, &amp;c. to be certified by Archbishop, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p22">And further that it may be ena&bholigct;ed likewise That every Archbishop and Bishop and Deane and Chapter of
every See vacant and other persons chargeable to and with the collection of the said Fower Subsidyes within the
said Province of Canterbury shall and may have upon every payment of the same Fower Subsidyes made to the
Lord High Treasurer or Under Treasurer of England for the time being, or to such other person or persons in
place and places to whom and where it shall please Your Highnesse or Your Court of Exchequer to appoint for
the receipt thereof at every of the aforesaid times of Payment a sufficient Acquittance Discharge or Quietus est in
writeing of the aforesaid Lord High Treasurer or Under Treasurer or of such other person or persons as either
Your Highnesse, or Your said Court of Exchequer shall assigne for the receipt thereof or as heretofore in the
like case it hath beene accustomed, the same Acquittance Discharge or Quietus est witnessing the receipt of soe
much of the same summe of the said Fower Subsidyes as shall be soe received, And every such Acquittance
Discharge or Quietus est in writeing subscribed with the name or names of the Lord High Treasurer or Under
Treasurer for the time being, or of such Auditor or other persons as it shall please Your Highnesse or
Your said Court of Exchequer to appoint for the same Receipt, or of such others as heretofore in like cases it
hath beene used shall and may be good and effectuall in the Law and be alsoe as sufficient a discharge in Law
to all and every of the said colle&bholigct;ors to all such intents constru&bholigct;ions and purposes as if the same were made by
A&bholigct; of Parliament. And that every of the said Colle&bholigct;ors shall pay but onely Three shillings and fower pence
for every generall or finall Acquittance Discharge or Quietus est for every payment of the said Fower Subsidyes,
And if any person soe assigned shall refuse or delay to make such a generall or finall Acquittance Discharge or
Quietus est for any payment of the said Fower Subsidyes or shall require or take for the same any more then
Three shillings fower pence or if any other Officer of the Exchequer shall require or take of any Collector or
Colle&bholigct;ors or of his or their Under colle&bholigct;or or Under colle&bholigct;ors Deputy or Deputyes in respect of the colle&bholigct;ion
payment or accompt of the said Fower Subsidyes or any part thereof for expedition, or for any other cause or
pretence whatsoever concerning the same, any Fees or Summes of money other then are before in this present
Grant expressely allowed unto them shall forfeite the summe of Ten pounds of lawfull money of England to be
paid and recovered in like manner unto the same uses as is before limitted and expressed in this Grant touching
the like forfeiture of Receivours and Auditors, and alsoe that every perticular Acquittance which upon any payment
of the said Fower Subsidyes shall be made by any Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors of the said Fower Subsidyes or of any
payment of them, or by his or their Under colle&bholigct;or or Under colle&bholigct;ors Deputy or Deputyes in that behalfe to
any Incumbent of any Benefice or Promotion Spirituall, or to any person or persons contributary and chargeable
to and with the said Fower Subsidies or any part or payment of them shall be good and effectfull in Law, and
a full and sufficient Discharge to every such Incumbent and other person and his Benefice and Promotion Spirituall
of and for all such summe and summes of money as by the same Acquittance shall be acknowledged to be
received in respe&bholigct; of the same Benefice or Promotion Spirituall for any payment or any part of the said Fower
Subsidyes, And that noe Acquittance of any other person or persons made before, such Certificate shall in any
wise discharge any person or promotion for any part or payment of the said Fower Subsidies, Nor of any paine
penaltie or forfeiture specifyed in this Grant, And to the intent it may be knowne to the Court of Exchequer
who be the Under colle&bholigct;or or Under colle&bholigct;ors Deputie or Deputyes of every such Archbishop Bishop or Deane
and Chapter authorized to receive the same and to make Acquittance thereof, every Archbishop Bishop and Deane
and Chapter of every See being void shall yearely together with their Certificates aforementioned certifie the names
of every the Under colle&bholigct;ors or Deputyes to be appointed as is aforesaid,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>IX. Process not to issue within Twenty Days after Day prefixed for Payment.</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Fee to Collector on Acquittance.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p24">Provided alwayes That noe Colle&bholigct;or of these Fower Subsidyes or of any part of them shall use any Processe
or compulsary meanes, or exa&bholigct; any Fees or Summes of Money for the same or otherwise of any person or persons
for not paying the said Fower Subsidyes or any part of them at such certaine day and place as shall be by the
Colle&bholigct;or or his Under Colle&bholigct;or or Deputy prefixed in case the said person shall tender the same unto the
Colle&bholigct;or or his Under Colle&bholigct;or or Deputy within twenty dayes next after such prefixed day, And that the said
Colle&bholigct;ors shall not by themselves or any other take of any person for the receipt of any severall payment of
the said Fower Subsidyes and for his Acquittance thereupon any more then fower pence by any colour or pretext
whatsoever;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>X. Spiritual Promotions, &amp;c. not chargeable to any other Subsidy.</head>
			<para id="p25">Provided alwayes That noe Spirituall Promotions nor any Lands Possessions or Revenues annexed to the same
being charged by this Grant of the Province of Canterbury, or any Goods or Chattells growing, being or renewed
upon the same, or elsewhere appertaining to the Owners of the said Spirituall Promotions or to any of them shall
be charged or made contributary to any Fifteenth or Tenth or to any other Subsidies already granted to Your
Highnesse by the Laity or hereafter to be granted dureing the time appointed by this Grant for the payment of
the said Fower Subsidyes,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XI. Deans, Archdeacons, Prebendaries, &amp;c. of Cathedrals and Colleges, &amp;c. how chargeable.</head>
			<para id="p26">
				<emph type="i">Archbishops, &amp;c. to certify Portions chargeable and not chargeable into Exchequer.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p27">Provided alsoe That all Deanes Archdeacons Dignitaryes Masters Wardens and Prebendaryes of all Cathedrall
and Collegiate Churches and Colledges or any of them within the said Province shall be charged with the said
Fower Subsidyes for those Possessions Revenues and Promotions onely which to their severall Promotions Dignityes
and Romes are clearely and distinctly limitted, and to their onely use severed thereof to pay (the Tenth part being
dedu&bholigct;ed) for every and each of the said Fower Subsidyes Fower shillings of every full pound in manner and
forme as is above rehearsed, And that all those Rents Possessions Proffitts Portions Hereditaments and Spirituall
Promotions and every of them heretofore by Your Highnesse or any [of <ref idref="n9">9</ref>] the Kings or Queenes of this Realme or
any other person or persons whatsoever given granted bequeathed devised or impropriated unto the said Cathedrall
or Collegiate Churches or Colledges or to any of them which any wayes be assigned imployed or used either for
or towards the yearely maintenance of Readers of Divinity Poore men Schoole masters Ushers Gramarians Petty
Cannons Condu&bholigct;s Vicars Chorall Singing men Choresters Virgers Sextons or of any other necessary or dayly
Officers or Ministers in such Cathedrall or Collegiate Churches or Colledges or any of them, or for or towards
the reedifying or repairing of any of the same Cathedrall or Collegiate Churches or Colledges shall not be charged
with any part of the said Fower Subsidyes, the certainty of which Portions aswell chargeable to the said Fower
Subsidyes as not chargeable in this behalfe the Archbishop or Bishop of the Diocesse or (the See being void) the
Deane and Chapter or any other to whom the same shall or may appertaine upon due search and examination
shall certifie under his or their Seale unto Your Highnesse said Court of Exchequer at or before the severall
dayes aforesaid appointed for the payment of the said Fower Subsidyes;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XII. Proviso for Spiritual Persons paying Pensions.</head>
			<para id="p28">Provided alwayes That every Parson Vicar or other Spirituall Person paying any Pension whereof noe allowance
is made in the valuation of his Promotion or Benefice shall and may retaine to his owne Use and Reliefe soe much
of every pound of every such Pension for every payment of the said Fower Subsidyes as he standeth charged by
this Grant to pay for every part and payment of the said Fower Subsidyes out of every pound for the whole
Valuation of his Spirituall Promotion, Any Covenant Grant or Bond to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for Lands, &amp;c. formerly granted for Obits, &amp;c. and come into the Hands of King Edw. VI. under I Edw. VI. c. 14.</head>
			<para id="p29">Provided alsoe and your [said <ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Prelates and Clergy doe most humbly beseech Your [Majestie<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] That it may be
enacted by Your Majestyes Authoritie and Your High Court of Parliament That where certaine Lands Tenements
Rents Spirituall Promotions Tythes Pensions Portions Fruites and other Hereditaments lately belonging to diverse
Cathedrall Churches and to other places and persons Ecclesiasticall within the said Province of Canterbury, which
were given and assigned to be bestowed and spent in and on findeing and maintaining of certaine Chauntryes
Anniversaryes Obits Lights Lamps and other like charges intents and purposes of late came into the hands and
Possessions of the late King of famous memory Edward the sixth by force of a Statute thereof made in the first
yeare of his Raigne as by the said Statute more plainely appeareth That the Cathedrall Churches and the Bishops
Deanes or Presidents and Chapters and Prebendaryes of the same and all other places and persons Ecclesiasticall
and every of them to whom the said Lands Rents and other the Premisses or any of them did lately appertaine
shall not dureing the time appointed by this Grant for the payment of the said Fower Subsidyes be charged to
and with any payment of Subsidie of and for that part and portion of Lands Tenements Rents Spirituall Promotions
&amp; other Hereditaments or any of them, whereunto the said late King by force of the said Statute was intitled, or
possessed of, nor of any yearely Rents or Payments goeing out of the said Cathedrall Churches and other the
places and persons Ecclesiasticall aforesaid, And that deduction and allowance thereof be made to them and every
of them accordingly in and upon every payment of the said Fower Subsidyes out of the whole Taxation Valuation
and Estimation made for the payment of the said perpetuall Disme or Tenth remaining of Record in Your Highnesse
Court of Exchequer as aforesaid for the rate and portion of Lands Tenements Rents Spirituall Promotions and other
Hereditaments, and those yearely payments whereunto the said King was intituled or possessed of, or which since
the makeing of the said Statute by reason that they have beene found as Lands Tenements Rents Tythes or other
Hereditaments concealed from the said King Edward the sixth, the late King Henry the [eigth,<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] the late Queene
Mary, the late Queene Elizabeth King James and King Charles the first of glorious memory or any of them or
from Your Majestie or otherwise are severed from the possessions of the said Cathedrall Churches and other places
and persons aforesaid, or [of] any of them by force of the Statute premised or any otherwise;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XIV. Proviso for the Universities,</head>
			<para id="p30">
				<emph type="i">Colleges of Windsor, Westminster, Eaton, and Winchester, Hospitals, Free Schools, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p31">Provided alsoe That these fower Subsidyes granted by the Clergy or any part of them [or any of them<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] shall not
be demanded or levyed out of any Benefice House of Students or Colledge scituate or sett within either of the
Universityes of Oxford or Cambridge or of any Benefice Lands or other Revenues unto the said Universityes or
either of them or to any House of Students or Colledge in any of the said Universityes united appropriated or
appertaining or out of any Benefice Lands or Revenues of the Colledge of Windsor or of the Colledge of Westminster
or of the Colledge of Eaton neere Windsor, or of the Colledge, called Saint Maryes Colledge by Winchester founded
by William Wickham sometimes Bishop of Winchester or of any Hospitalls Almes houses or Grammar Schooles or
of any Church Benefice or other Revenues to the said Colledges Hospitalls Almes Houses or Grammar Schooles
or to any of them annexed appropriated or otherwise appertaining.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XV. Proviso for Livings not above &pound;6. 13s. 4d. yearly.</head>
			<para id="p32">Provided alwayes That all Parsons Vicars and all other Ecclesiasticall persons whose Benefices are not above
Six pounds thirteene shillings fower pence by the yeare after the Taxation aforesaid shall not be charged with these
Fower Subsidyes or any part of the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVI. Proviso for Livings of &pound;8 and not above &pound;10 yearly Value.</head>
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">Vicarages under &pound;8, Incumbent not to be charged.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p34">Provided alsoe That every Vicar whose Benefice is Eight pounds or above, and not above ten pounds by the
yeare after the Taxation aforesaid shall pay unto Your Highnesse Your Heires and Successors at every of the
aforesaid payments of the said fower Subsidyes afore limited Thirteene shillings fower pence for the first payment
of the said Fower Subsidyes and every other payment of the said Fower Subsidyes Six shillings eight pence at
such time and to such persons as is aforesaid for his part of the said Fower Subsidyes, And if any Vicarage be
under Eight pounds in the Taxation aforesaid the Incumbent shall not be charged with any part or payment of the
said Fower Subsidyes,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVII. Grant to be ratified by Parliament.</head>
			<para id="p35">And for the sure and true payment of these Fower Subsidyes granted by Your said Prelates and Clergy of
the Province of Canterbury according to the tenour purport effe&bholigct; and true meaneing of this present Grant Your
said Prelates and Clergy doe most humbly beseech Your Highnesse that this their said Gift Grant and Fower
Subsidyes and every Matter Summe of money Petition Clause Provisions Reservations and Sentences in this
Instrument contained concerning the said Fower Subsidyes may be ratyfyed established and confirmed by the
Authority of Your Highnesse Court of Parliament.</para>
			<para id="p36">In Quor&umacr; omni&umacr;ss et singulor&umacr; premissor&umacr; fid&emacr; et testimoni&umacr; Nos Gilbertus Lond Episcopus antedi&bholigct;us has presentes
literas nostras testimoniales sive hoc &bhopcrl;sens public&umacr; instrumentu ad humil&emacr; rogat&umacr; Prelator&umacr; et Cleri &bhopcrl;dict sigilli
nostri appensione ac Signo Nomine et Subscriptione Gulielmi Fisher Notarii publici jussimus et fecimus communiri
Datu di&bholigct;o vicesimo septimo die Mensis Junii Anno Domini millesimo sexcentesimo sexagesimo tertio Regniq&bhoqesq; Vestri
felicissimi Dei gra Anglie Scotie Francie et Hibernie Regis, Fidei Defensoris &amp;c decimo-quinto et nostre Consecrationis
Anno tertio.</para>
			<para id="p37">
				<emph type="i">The above Grant ratified.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p38">[Wherefore for the true and sure payment of the said Subsidyes granted by the said Prelates and Clergy of
the said Province of Canterbury according to the tenour effe&bholigct; and true meaning of the said Instrument Bee it
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestye with the Assent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the
Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the said Gift and Grant
and every Matter Summe of money Petition Provision Clause and Sentence in the same Instrument contained shall
stand and be ratifyed established and confirmed by the authority of this p[re]sent Parliament.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XVIII. Power to Collectors to levy Subsidies by Authority of Censures of the Church, and by Sequestration, Distress, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p39">
				<emph type="i">In what case Replevin, &amp;c. allowed.; Farmers paying for their Lessors may retain out of Rent.; Exception.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p40">And further be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every person that shall be appointed to the collecting
and gathering of the said Subsidyes shall have power and authority to levy take and perceive the said Subsidyes
by the authority of the Censures of the Church that is to say by Suspension Excommunication or Interdi&bholigct;ion and
alsoe by Sequestration of the Fruites and Proffitts of their Benefices and Promotions Spirituall in whose hands soever
they be, and to make sale of the same Fruites without danger of the Lawes of this Realme, or by Distresse upon
the Possessions of the Farmers or Occupiers of the Lands and Tenements chargeable by the said Instrument for
or to the payment of any summe or summes of money to be due by force thereof, or otherwise by the discretion
of the Colle&bholigct;or thereof; And that noe Replevy Prohibition or Supersedeas shall be allowed or obeyed for any
persons makeing defaulte of the payment, of the said Subsidyes or any of them contrary to the tenour of the Grant
thereof, untill such time as they have truely satisfyed and contented all such part and portions as to them in that
behalfe appertaineth, And that every such Farmer and Farmers their Executors and Assignes that shall fortune
hereafter to be charged to, or with the payment of the said Subsidyes or any part thereof shall by the Authoritie
aforesaid be allowed and retaine in his hands as much of his yearely Rent and Farme as the summe which he shall
fortune to pay for his Lord or Leasor shall extend unto (except that the said Farmer or Farmers their Executors or
Assignes by the Lease and Grant that they have of any part of the Lands Tythes Proffitts or Tenements chargeable
to the said Subsidyes or by force of any Covenant or Article therein contained be bound and charged to pay the
same, And thereof to discharge the Leasor and Landlord dureing the terme mentioned in the said Lease)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XIX. Subsidies may be levied by Distress on Farmers of Impropriations.</head>
			<para id="p41">
				<emph type="i">Sale of Distress.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p42">And likewise be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie of this present Parliament That whereas diverse Curates lyeable
to the Subsidyes being oftentimes removeable, doe serve aswell in diverse Impropriations belonging to the Kings
Majestie as in other Spirituall Promotions belonging to other persons That for the speedy recovery of the said
Subsidyes it may be lawfull to the said Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors of the said Subsidyes their Deputy or Deputyes
to levy the said Subsidyes upon the Farmer or Farmers or Occupiers of all such Impropriations or Spirituall Promotions
by all Censures of the Church aforesaid and every of them or by way of distresse of Tythes of the said Impropriation
or Impropriations and Spirituall Promotions, or otherwise upon the Goods and Chattells of the said Farmer or
Farmers and Occupiers, In which case noe Inhibiti&oacute;n Prohibition Replevy or other Processe awarded to the contrary
shall be obeyed, Any Lawes Statutes Priviledges or Customes to the contrary hereof heretofore made granted or used,
or hereafter to be made granted or used to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding. And that it may be lawfull
to the Collector or other Officers and Ministers of such Arch Bishop Bishop Deane and Chapter for not payment
of the said Subsidyes after the same shall be due in or at any of the said times of payment to prize and value
the said distresse and distresses by two indifferent Neighbours by him to be chosen, And the distresse and distresses
soe prized (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) and thereof to detaine soe much money as shall amount to the summe payable to the Kings most
Excellent Majestie with the reasonable charges alsoe of the said Collectors sustained in that behalfe, And the rest
of the money made of the said Distresse to be delivered and paid to the Owner and Occupier thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XX. How Lay Impropriators shall be charged for their Spiritual and Temporal Possessions.</head>
			<para id="p43">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every Lay person haveing Spirituall
Promotion chargeable by this A&bholigct;, And alsoe haveing Temporall Possessions Goods Chattells and Debts charged
to the said Subsidyes granted in this Parliament by the Temporaltie shall be taxed charged and sett for his said
Spirituall Promotions with the Clergy, and his Temporall Possessions and Chattells reall with the Temporaltie
and not otherwise, Any thing before mentioned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXI. This Act extended to the Subsidy of the Province of York.</head>
			<para id="p44">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every Grant and Grants of all and every
summe and summes of money granted or which hereafter shall be granted to the Kings Majestie by the Clergy of
the Province of Yorke shall be of the same strength force and effe&bholigct; in all things as the said Grant made by the
said Province of Canterbury and shall be taxed certified colle&bholigct;ed [gathered levyed<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] and paid according to the
tenoure forme and effe&bholigct; of this present A&bholigct; of Parliament to all intents constructions and purposes in such manner
and forme as though it were specially plainely and perticularly expressed and rehearsed in this present A&bholigct; by expresse
words termes and sentences in their severall natures and kinds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXII. Provisions in the Grants of the Clergy declared valid.</head>
			<para id="p45">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Provisions before rehearsed contained
or to be contained in the said Grant of the Prelates and Clergy of the Province of Canterbury; And the like
of the same Provisoes contained in the said Grant of the Prelates and Clergy of the Province of Yorke shall
be good and effe&bholigct;uall and to be observed and kepte in every Point and Article according to the purport and true
meaneing of the same.]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original Grant in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Architpali <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">poffeffion <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Money <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">blank in the original.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Highnesse <emph type="i">O</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Eight <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">to fell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">levyed gathered <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


