<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47348" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII. An Explanatory Act for Recovery of the Arreares of Excise. [Rot. Parl. 15c. II p. 2. nu. 11.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Sureties of Commissioners, &amp;c. not pardoned by 12 Car. 2. c. 11. declared liable.</head>
		<para id="p1">Be it declared and enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the
Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by Authoritie
of the same That where any Commissioner Sub Commissioner Treasurer and all other Officers which were heretofore
imployed in the Receipt of the Excise, Farmer, or Collector of Excise which are and standeth charged with, or
accomptable for any Dutyes of Excise by him or them received farmed or detained or any wayes due from the
persons before named or any of them and not pardoned by the late Act entituled An Act of Free and Generall
Pardon Indempnity and Oblivion that there and in such case all and every the Suretyes of such person and persons
charged or chargeable as aforesaid shall be deemed and taken to be lyable and answerable according to the nature
of their respective Securityes Any doubt or question made touching the Construction of the said late Act of Free
and Generall Pardon to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Summons by Commissioners to Persons accountable left at the House, &amp;c. deemed good.</head>
			<para id="p2">And be it further declared and enacted by the Authority aforesaid That where the Commissioners of Excise
for the time being or the major part of them have issued out any Summons or Warning which hath beene left
at the house or usuall place of residence or with the Wife Childe or meniall Servant of any the aforesaid person
or persons chargeable or accomptable as aforesaid, the same shall be deemed and adjudged a good and sufficient
Summons and as legall and effectuall a notice as if the same had beene actually delivered to the proper hands
of such person or persons to whom the same was directed, Any doubt or question thereof made to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


