<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47350" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIV. An Act for setling the Proffitts of the Post Office and Power of graunting Wyne Lycences on his Royall Highnes
the Duke of Yorke and the Heires Males of his Body. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) [O. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 12 Car. II. c. 25. &sect;1.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">&sect; 2.; &sect; 6.; and of 12 Car. II. C. 35. &sect; 1.; &sect; 4.
&sect; 15.; and that both the said Acts have been confirmed; And reciting that the King had granted and assigned to the Duke of York the Profits of licensing retailing of Wine; and the Revenues arising from the Post Office.; 
The said Duke and the Heirs Male of his Body to have all the said Powers and Profits from granting Licences to retail Wine; and a Moiety of the Penalties of 12 Car. II. c. 25.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Lords &amp; Comns being assembled at Westminster the five and twentieth Day of Aprill Anno
Domini One thousand six hundred and sixty in the twelfth Yeare of the Raigne of our most gracious
Soveraigne Lord Charles the Second by the Grace of God of England Scotland France and Ireland King
Defender of the Faith were there continued untill the nyne and twentyeth Day of December next following and
then dissolved [in which Time<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] A certaine Act was made entituled An Act for the better ordering the selling of
Wynes by retaile and for preventing abuses in the mingling corrupting and vitiating of Wynes and for settling
and limitting the Prices of the same whereby it was enacted that no Person or Persons whatsoever from and after
the five and twentieth Day of March in the Yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred sixty and one unless hee
or they should be authorized and enabled in manner and forme as by the said Act is appointed shall sell or
utter by retaile any Kind of Wyne or Wynes to be spent in his or their Mansion House or Houses or other place
by any meane whatsoever upon payne of Forfeite for every such Offence the Su[m]me of Five Pounds the one Moyety
thereof to the King and the other Moyety to him or them that will sue for the same And it was further thereby
enacted that it should be lawfull for his Majesty his Heires and Successors from Tyme to Tyme to issue out under his
or their great Seale of England One or more Comission or Comissions directed to two or more Persons thereby
authorising them to lycence and give Authority to such Person or Persons as they should thinke fitt to sell and
utter by Retayle all and every or any kind of Wyne or Wynes to bee drunke and spent aswell within the House
or Howses or other Place in the Tenure or Occupation of the Party soe lycenced as without in any Citty Towne or
other Place within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Barwicke upon Tweede and such
Comissioners are to contract for selling and uttering of Wynes by Retayle in any Citty or other Place as aforesaid
in such manner and forme and under such Provisoes as in the said Act is mentioned And it is further provided
by the said Act that the Rents Revenues and Su[m]mes of Money arising by the said Act should bee duly and
constantly paid and answered into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer and not bee charged or chargeable either
before it bee paid into the Exchequer or after with any Guift or Pention As by the said Act amongst divers
other Provisoes and Clauses may more at large appeare And also one other Act was at the same Time made
entituled An Act for crecting and establishing a Post Office whereby it [is<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] enacted That from thenceforth there should
bee one Generall Letter Office erected and established in some convenient Place within the Citty of London from
whence all Letters and Pacquetts may bee sent into any Parte of the Kingdome of England Scotland and Ireland
or other of his Majestyes Dominions or unto any Kingdome or Country beyond the Seas and that one Master of
the said Generall Letter Office shall bee from Tyme to Tyme appointed by the Kings Majesty his Heires and Successors
by his or their Letters Pattents under the great Seale of England by the Name and Stile of his Majestyes Post Master
Generall which said Post Master and his Deputy and Deputyes by him thereunto sufficiently authorised and his
and their Servants and Agents and no other Person shall have the receiving ordering or sending Post of all
Letters and Pacquetts whatsoever to bee sent to and from the Places aforesaid (except as therein and thereby is
excepted) And it was thereby provided That such Post Master Generall and his Deputy and Deputyes may
demand have receive and take for the Portage of all such Letters which he shall convey as aforesaid and for
the providing and furnishing Horses for thorough Posts according to the Rates therein mentioned And that his
Majesty his Heires and Successors may grant the said Office of Post Master Generall with the Powers and
Authorityes thereunto belonging, and the severall Rates of Portage therein mentioned And all Profitts Priviledges
Fees Perquisitts and Emoluments thereunto belonging either for Life or Terme of Yeares not exceeding One
and Twenty Yeares to such Person and Persons and under such Covenants Conditions and yearely Rents to his
said Majesty his Heires and Successors reserved as hee or they shall from Tyme to Tyme thinke fitt as by the said
Act amongst divers other Clauses and Provisoes therein conteined may more at large appeare Both which Acts
have beene confirmed by this present Parliament Now forasmuch as the Kings most excellent Majesty is graciously
pleased out of his princely Care and great Love and Affection to his most entirely beloved Brother James Duke
of Yorke for and towards the Maintenance and Support of the said Duke his State and Dignity to grant and
assigne all and every the Power and Powers Authority and Authorityes of giving Licence to any Person or Persons
to sell or utter by retaile all and every or any kind of Wyne or Wynes whatsoever with all Rents Summe and Summes
of Money Revenues Profitts and Emoluments whatsoever that shall or may arise from or out or by reason of such
Power or licencing the retayling of Wynes or Forfeitures for retayling of Wynes without such Lycences unto the
said James Duke of Yorke and to the Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten And also all the
Rents Summe and Summes of Money and revenues that shall arise grow and become due of or from the said Generall
Letter Office or Post Office or Office of Postmaster Generall unto the said James Duke of Yorke and the Heires
Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten Bee it therefore enacted and declared by the Kings most excellent
Majesty by and with the Advise and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Comons in this
present Parliament assembled and by the Authority of the same That the said James Duke of Yorke and the
Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten shall have all and every the Powers and Authorityes aforesaid
to give and grant Licences to such Person or Persons as he or they shall thinke fitt to sell and utter by Retaile all
and every or any kind of Wyne or Wynes whatsoever to be drunke and spent as well within the House and Houses
or other Place in the Tenure or Occupation of the Party soe licenced as without in any Citty Towne or other
Place whatsoever within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne and Port of Barwicke upon
Tweede, together with all Benefitts and Profitts thereof And alsoe that the said Duke and the Heires Males
of his Body begotten or to be begotten shall [have<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] that Moyety of the Forfeitures and Penaltyes which by the
said recited, Act is given to his Majesty his Heires and Successors</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Power to the Agents of the said Duke to contract for granting Licences.</head>
			<para id="p3">And it is hereby further declared That all and every other Person or Persons which from Tyme to Tyme or
at any Tymes hereafter shall bee by the said James Duke of Yorke and the Heires Males of his Body begotten
or to bee begotten appointed authorised or deputed Agent or Agents Comissioner or Comissioners to treat and
contract for giving Licences and Dispensations to any Person or Persons for the selling and utterring Wines
by retaile in any Citty or Towne or other Place as aforesaid shall have the full and sole Power and Authority
to treate and contract for giving Lycences to any person or persons for the selling and utterring Wynes by Retaile
in any Citty Towne or other place as aforesaid, Any Law Statute Grant Usage or Custome to the contrary in
anywise notwithstanding in as full and ample manner as the Kings Agents or Comissioners might doe by vertue
of the said recited Act</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Persons appointed by the said Duke to grant Licences, enabled so to do under the Seal of the Duke or his Heirs Male. No Fine to be taken.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Remedy for Rents reserved to the Duke; Discharge of the Duke or his Receiver General good Discharge.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid that such Person or Persons as shall bee appointed by the
said James Duke of Yorke or the Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten under his or their. Hand
and Seale for granting Licences for selling and utterring Wynes by Retaile are hereby enabled under such Seale
as the said Duke or the Heires Males of his Body begotten [or to be begotten<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] shall appointe to grant Licences
for the selling and utterring Wynes by Retayle to any Person or Persons or for any Tyme or Times not exceeding
One and twenty Yeares if such Persons shall soe long live and for such yearely Rents and under such conditions
as they shall thinke fitt soe as no fine bee taken for the same but that the Rents or Summes of Money soe agreed
for and reserved shall be duly paid at the Tymes and Places agreed for the Payment thereof for which Rents
soe reserved in case the same shall not bee paid the said Duke and the Heires Males of his Body begotten or
to bee begotten shall and may have Power by this Act to sue for the same by Bill Plainte or Action of Debt
in any of his Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster or elswhere in his owne Name or to sue for the same
in his Majestyes Name in the Court of the Exchequer at the Election of the said Duke and the Heires Males of
his Body begotten or to be begotten and that the Discharge of the said James Duke of Yorke and of the Heires
Males of his Body begotten [or to be begotten<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] or of his or their Receiver Generall for the Tyme being shall
be a full and effectuall Discharge to all Intents and Purposes for all such Moneyes as have or shall bee received
by vertue of the Act for Wyne Lycences</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. The King not to grant Licenses.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alwayes that the Kings Majesty his Heires and Successors shall not during the Continuance of the
said Estate Tayle by himselfe or Agents grant any Co[m]mission or Co[m]missions Licence or Lycences for the selling or
uttering of any Wynes by Retaile</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Contracts for Licenses already made by the King.</head>
			<para id="p7">And also provided that nothing in this Act conteined shall make void any Contracts Leases or Agreements
that have beene made by His Majestyes Agents for granting Licences for selling and uttering Wynes by retaile in
pursuance of the said Act but the same Contracts Leases and Agreements shall remaine in such force as they
were before the making of this Act, and that the Rents thereupon reserved, and all Arrearcs thereof shall be paid
unto the said Duke and to the Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Post Office Revenues hereby settled on the Duke of York and the Heirs Male of his Body.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">His and their Receivers General may receive the said Revenue.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further enacted by the Authority aforesaid That all the yearely Rents Summe or Summes of Money
Revenues Issues and Profitts whatsoever that shall grow due accrue or bee payable unto his Majesty his Heires
or Successors for or by reason of the said Generall Letter Office or Post Office or Office of Post Master Generall
or annexed incident or belonging to the said Post Office or Generall Letter Office or Office of Post Master Generall
or issuing out of the same or accruing or growing due for or by reason of the same shall bee and hereby are
vested and settled by vertue of this Act upon the said James Duke of Yorke and the Heires Males of his Body
begotten [or to bee begotten<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] with full and sole power from Tyme to Tyme for the said Duke and the Heires
Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten his and their Receivers Generall to receive all and every the said
Rents Issues and Profitts accruing for or issuing out of the said Office and from Tyme to Tyme to give Discharges
for the Money soe received</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. The said Post Office Revenues not to be paid into the Exchequer, but to the Duke, &amp;c. who may sue for the same.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alwayes and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That none of the said yearly Rents Issues
and Profitts arrising growing due accruing or issuing out of the [said<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Generall Letter Office or Post Office
or Office of Post master Generall shall for and during the [said<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Estate Tayle be paid into the Exchequer
but onely to the said Duke and to the Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten his or their Receivor
Generall for the tyme being, and also that it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Duke and for the
Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten in the name of his Majesty his Heires or Successors or in
his or their owne Name to sue for the same by Bill Plaint Information Action of Debt or otherwise in any
Court or Courts of Law or Equity wherein noe Protection Wager of Law or Essoigne shall lye</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for Grant to Daniel O'Neale Esquire of the Office of Post Master General.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided also that nothing herein conteined shall make void the grant made by his Majesty to Daniell Oneale
Esquier of the Office of Post master Generall or Generall Letter Office or Post Office for foure Yeares and one
Quarter of a Yeare from the [said<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] five and twentieth Day of March in the Yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred sixty and three under the yearely Rent of One and twenty Thousand five Hundred Pounds for all
the said Terme (except the last Quarter which is paid aforehand soe as the said rents bee paid unto his said
Highness James Duke of Yorke and to the Heires Males of his Body begotten or to be begotten</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Proviso for His Majesty charging not exceeding &pound;5,382. 10s. on Office of Post Master General.</head>
			<para id="p12">Provided also and it is hereby further enacted and declared That it shall and may be lawfull for the Kings
Majesty his Heires and Successors at any tyme or tymes during the said Estate Tayle by warrant under his Privy
Seale to charge any Su[m]me [or severall Su[m]mes<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of Money not exceeding [in the whole<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the Su[m]me of five thousand
three hundred fowerscore and two Pounds Tenn Shillings to be paid out of the Profitts of the Office of Post
master Generall, to the which said Su[m]me of five thousand three hundred fowerscore and two Pounds tenn
Shillings, the severall Sumes and Payments now allready charged thereupon doe in the whole amount (the grant of
which Su[m]mes are not to be avoided by this Act) [and w<emph type="p">ch</emph> said Su[m]mes of Money not exceeding the said Su[m]me
of five thousand three hundred fourescore and two Pounds ten Shillings to be granted by His Ma[jes]tie as aforesaid, are,
and shalbe by Authority of this Act confirmed and made in full Force.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. The King to have the Nomination of Post Master General at a Rent to be reserved to the Duke of York.</head>
			<para id="p13">Provided further that the Kings most excellent Majesty his Heires and Successors shall have the Nomination
of the Post Master Generall of the said Post Office, and shall from tyme to tyme nominate and appointe such
Person and Persons as he or they shall please to be Postmaster Generall of the said Office and may grant the same
Office with the Power and Authority thereunto belonging and the said Rates of Portage in the said Act mentioned
either for Life or Terme of Yeares not exceeding one and twenty Yeares to such Person or Persons as he or they
shall thinke fitt under the most improved Yearely Rent that can be reasonably had or gotten for the same by
the said Duke or the Heires Males of his Body [begotten or to be begotten<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] without Fines the said yearely rent
to be reserved and payable to the said Duke and to the Heires Males of his Body [begotten or<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] to be begotten
and also under such Covenants Conditions and Agreements as the said Duke or the Heires Males of his Body
begotten or to be begotten shall thinke fitting Any Thing in this present Act conteyned to the contrary
notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. The Duke, &amp;c. enabled to settle a Jointure on Wives out of the said Premises, and to lease the same.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said James Duke
of Yorke and the Heires Males of his Body begotten [and to be begotten<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] to settle any Part of the [said<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]
Premisses not exceeding a third Part of the cleare yearely Vallue over and above all charges and Reprises for a
Joynture for his or their Wife or Wives and also to lease any other Part of the said Premisses for any Number of
Yeares not exceeding one and twenty Yeares and not exceeding one other third Part of the cleare yearely Vallue
of [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Premisses over and above all [other<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Charges and Reprises in order to raise Portions for his or their
yonger Children</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Proviso for the Privileges of the Universities.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided also that this Act or any Thing therein conteined shall not in any wise be prejudiciall to the Priviledge
of the two Universityes of this Land or either of them or to the Chancellor or Schollars of the same or their
Successors but that they may use and enjoy such Priviledges as heretofore they have lawfully used and enjoyed
Any Thing herein to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for the Vintners of London and for other Towns Corporate.</head>
			<para id="p16">Provided also that this Act or any Thing therein conteined shall not extend or be prejudiciall to the Master
Wardens and Freemen and Cominalty of the Mistery of Vintners of the Citty of London or to any other Citty or
Towne Corporate, but that they may use and enjoy such Libertyes and Priviledges as heretofore they have lawfully
used and enjoyed Any Thing herein contayned to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Proviso for the Borough of Saint Albans, as to appointing and licensing Three Wine Taverns.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided alsoe and be it enacted by the Authority aforesaid That this A&bholigct; or any Thing therein conteined shall
not in any wise extend to debarr or hinder the Maior or Burgesses of the Borough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albans in the County
of Hertford or their Successors from enjoying using and exercising of all such Libertyes Powers and Authorityes
to them heretofore granted by severall Letters Pattents under the Great Seale of England by Queene Elizabeth and
King James of famous Memoryes for the erecting appointing and licensing of three severall Wyne Tavernes within
the Borough aforesaid for and towards the maintenance of the Free Schoole there but that the same Libertyes
Powers and Authorityes shall bee and are hereby established and confirmed and shall remaine and continue in and
to the said Maior and Burgesses and their Successors to and for the C[h<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] aritable use aforesaid and according to
the Tenor of the Letters Pattents aforesaid as though this Act had never beene made Any thing herein conteined
to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Proviso for Letters sent to and from the Universities.</head>
			<para id="p18">Provided alwayes That all Letters and other Things may bee sent or conveyed to or from the two Universityes
in manner as heretofore hath beene used, Any Thing herein to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">From the Original Act in the Parliament Office.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original Act in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


