<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47352" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XVI. An Act for regulateing the Herring and other Fisheries, and for repeale of the A&bholigct; concerning Madder [Rot. Parl. 15 C. II. p. 2. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Regulations concerning the packing of Herrings of English catching put to Sale.; Head Officers of Ports from which Ships proceed to fish, to appoint a competent number of Packers.; The Duty of such Packers.; To take an Oath.; Such Head Officers not appointing and swearing Packers; Penalty &pound;100.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">For the prevention of abuses in the packing and ordering of Herrings and bringing that Commoditie into
credit in Forreigne Parts beyond the Seas Be it enacted and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this
present Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That from and after the First day of August One
thousand six hundred sixtie fower noe white or read Herrings of English catching shall be putt to sale in England
Wales or in the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede but what shall be packed in lawffull Barrells or Vessells, and
which shall be well truely and justly laid and packed, and shall be of one time of takeing salting saveing or
drying, and equally well packed in the midst and every part of the Barrell or Vessell, and by a sworne Packer,
And the Barrell or Vessell marked or branded by such sworne Packer with a marke or brand denoteing the gage
of the Barrell or Vessell and the quantity quality and condition of Herrings packed therein, and the Towne or
Place where they were packed, And the Bailiffes of Great Yarmouth for the time being and the Maior Bailiffes or
other Head Officer for the time being of every Port Haven or Creeke out of which any Vessells or Shipps doe
proceede to fish for Herrings are hereby authorized and required before the First day of July in the yeare One
thousand six hundred sixtie fower and before the First day (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) in every yeare after to appoint for their respe&bholigct;ive
Haven Port or Creeke a competent number of able and experienced Packers to view and packe all such white
or read Herrings of English catching as shall be brought into their Port Haven or Creeke and well and truely
to marke and brand the Barrells or Vessells in which they shall be packed with such marke or brand as is above
dire&bholigct;ed and to administer to them yearely an Oath (which Oath they are hereby authorized and appointed to
give to them) for the well and true doeing thereof according to this A&bholigct;. And in case the said Bailiffes of Great
Yarmouth or the Maior Bailiffes or other Head Officer for the time being of any such Port Haven or Creeke shall
not appoint and sweare such Packers before such time in every yeare as is by this A&bholigct; required they shall for
every defaulte forfeite the Summe of One hundred Pounds of lawfull Money of England, One Moyetie to His
Majestie His Heires and Successors and the other Moyetie to him or them that shall informe or sue for the same
in any Court of Record by Bill Plaint or other A&bholigct;ion wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager in Law shall
be allowed.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. No Ship to proceed on a Fishing Voyage to Iceland and Westmony until 10th March;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the better regulateing of the Island and Westmony Fisheries and Preservation of the Spawne of Fish
there be it enacted and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That from and after the Five and twentyeth
day of December One thousand six hundred sixtie three noe Shipp or Vessell shall proceede upon a Fishing Voyage
for Island and Westmony out of any Port Haven or Creeke in England or Wales or out of the Port of Berwicke
upon Tweede untill the tenth day of March in any yeare upon the paine of the Forfeiture of every such Shipp or
Vessell with all her Furniture Tackle and Apparell and of all the Fish caught in such Shipp or Vessell.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Collecting any Tax in Newfoundland for Fish of English catching; Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Laying Nets to take the Spawn of Poor John, &amp;c. Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe person or persons whatsoever doe colle&bholigct;
leavy or take, or cause to be colle&bholigct;ed leavyed or taken in New found land any Toll or other duty of, or for any
Cod or Poore John, or other Fish of English catching under paine of the losse of double the value of what shall
be by them leavyed colle&bholigct;ed or taken or caused to be colle&bholigct;ed leavyed or taken, And that noe Planter or other
person or persons whatsoever doe cast or lay any Seine or other Net in or neare any Harbour in New found land
whereby to take the Spawne or young Fry of the Poore John, or for any other use or uses except for the takeing
of Baite onely upon paine of the losse of all such Seins or Nets and of the Fish taken in them or of the value
thereof to be recovered in any of His Majesties Courts in New-found Land or in any Court of Record in England
or Wales by Bill Plaint or other A&bholigct;ion wherein noe Essoigne Protection or Wager in Law shall be allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Destroying Boats and other Utensils of Fishing left in Newfoundland, &amp;c. or pulling down Houses of Fishers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe Planter or other person or persons whatsoever
shall burne destroy or steale any Boate Caske Salt Nets or other Utensills for fishing or makeing of Oyle or other
Goods or Merchandice left in any Harbour in New found Land or Greene land by English or burne pull downe
or destroy any House built by English in New-found Land or Greene land to live in dureing the fishing season,
or Stage built by them in either of the said places for the saveing or [or<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] ordering of Fish, or makeing of Oyle
upon paine of the losse of double the value of what shall be by them stolne burnt or destroyed to be recovered
in any of His Majesties Courts in New-found Land or Greene land respe&bholigct;ively, or in any Court of Record in England
by Bill Plaint or other A&bholigct;ion wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager in Law shall be allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">13 &amp; 14 C. II. C.30. repealed.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p10">And whereas upon the humble Petition and Complaint of the Merchants and Salters of the Citty of London it
doth appeare That some sorts of Madder very usefull for dyeing cannot be imported soe pure and cleane as by
one A&bholigct; passed the last Session of this present Parliament (Entituled An A&bholigct; for the Importation of Madder pure
and unmixed) is directed and appointed Be it ena&bholigct;ed and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That
the said A&bholigct; and every Clause and Thing therein contained be from henceforth utterly void and repealed to all
Intents Purposes and Constru&bholigct;ions whatsoever</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">of July <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


