<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47351" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1663</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XV. An Act for encourageing the Manufactures of makeing Linen Cloath and Tapistry. [Rot. Parl. 15 C. II. p. 2. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Manufactures of Foreign Hemp, &amp;c. is imported, to the Detriment of the Kingdom.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this Act.; All Persons, Natives or Foreigners, may without Fee set up and use the Trades of Hemp-dressing and other Trades herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas vast quantities of Linen Cloath and other Manufa&bholigct;ures of Hempe and Flax and of Tapistry
Hangings are dayly imported into this Kingdome from Forreigne parts to the great Detriment and
Impoverishment thereof the Moneyes and quicke-stocke of this Kingdome being thereby dayly greatly exhausted and
diminished and the poore thereof unimployed while the Materialls for the makeing of such Hangings are here more
plentifull and better and cheaper then in those places from whence they are imported, and Flax and Hempe might
be had here in great abundance and very good if by setting up the Manufa&bholigct;ures of such Commodities as are made
thereof it would be taken off the hands of such as sow and plant the same For the Encouragement therefore of
those Manufa&bholigct;ures bee it ena&bholigct;ed and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the
Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and
by the Authoritie thereof That from and after the first day of O&bholigct;ober next ensueing it shall and may be lawfull
for any person or persons whatsoever Native or Forraigner freely and without paying any Acknowledgement Fee or
other Gratuity for the same in any place of England or Wales priviledged or unpriviledged Corporate or not
Corporate to sett up and exercise the Trade Occupation or Mistery of breaking hickling or dressing of Hempe or
Flax as alsoe for makeing and whitening of Threed as alsoe of spining weaveing makeing whitening or bleching of
any sorte of Cloath whatsoever made of Hempe or Flax onely, as alsoe the Trade Occupation or Mistery of makeing
of Twine or Nets for Fishery or of stoveing of Cordage, as alsoe the Trade Occupation or Mistery of makeing
any sort of Tapistry Hangings Any Law Statute or Usage to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Foreigners using any of the said Trades for Three Years, and taking the Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy, to be considered as natural-born Subjects.</head>
			<para id="p3">And all Forreigners that shall really and bona fide sett up and use any of the Trades and Manufa&bholigct;ures aforesaid
by the space of three yeares in this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede
shall from thenceforth takeing the Oathes of Alleigiance and Supremacy before two Justices of the Peace neare
unto their dwellings who are hereby authorized to administer the same enjoy all Priviledges whatsoever as the
Naturall borne Subje&bholigct;s of this Kingdome.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Not to be liable to greater Taxes, &amp;c. Exception.</head>
			<para id="p4">And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That such Forraigners as shall exercise any of the Trades aforesaid by
vertue of this A&bholigct; shall not (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) any time be lyeable to any other or greater Taxes Payments or Impositions then
such as are or shall be paid by His Majesties Naturall borne Subje&bholigct;s unlesse in case they shall use and exercise
Merchandice into and from Forreigne parts, in which case they shall be lyeable to pay such Customes as have
usually beene paid by Aliens dureing the space of Five yeares next ensueing and noe longer.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">at <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


