<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47356" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for colle&bholigct;ing the Duty ariseing by Hearth-money by Officers to be appointed by His Majestie.[Rot. Parl. 16 C. II. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 13 (13 &#x0026; 14) Car. II. c. 10. and of 15 Car. II. c. 13;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this A&bholigct; The King may appoint Officers to colle&bholigct; this Revenue;to view and number Hearths and inspe&bholigct; Returns; who (accompanied with a Constable, &#x0026;c.) may enter and search Houses, &#x0026;c.; Search every Year. Variance in the Number of Chimnies to be certified to the Clerk of the Peace; and by him, being approved by Sessions, unto the Exchequer</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; made in the Parliament begun at Westminster the Eighth day of May in the Thirteenth
yeare of his Majestyes Raigne that now is entituled An A&bholigct; for establishing an additionall Revenue upon His
Majestie His Heires and Successors for the better support of His and their Crowne and Dignitie, And by another
A&bholigct; made in the Second Session of the said Parliament in the Fifteenth yeare of the Raigne of His said Majestie
entituled An Additionall A&bholigct; for the better ordering and colle&bholigct;ing the Revenue ariseing by Hearth money It was
ena&bholigct;ed and ordained That from and after the Five and twentyeth day of March in the yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred sixtie and two, every Dwelling and other House and Edifice, and all Lodgeings in Innes of
Court, Innes of Chancery Colledges and other Societyes that are, or hereafter shall be ere&bholigct;ed within the Kingdome
of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede (other then such as are therein excepted)
shall be and are charged with the annuall Payment to the Kings Majestie His Heires and Successors for every Fire
Hearth and Stove within every such House Edifice Chambers and Lodgeings the summe of Two shillings by the
yeare to be paid yearely at the Feasts of Saint Michaell the Arch-Angell, and of the Annunciation of the Blessed
Virgin Mary by even and equall portions an exa&bholigct; and just Account of the numbers of all which Fire Hearthes
and Stoves is thereby ena&bholigct;ed to be taken and returned into His Majestyes Court of Exchequer And the Moneyes
and Revenues due and payable for the same to be colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid to His Majestie by such persons and
Officers in manner and forme as by the said A&bholigct;s is prescribed. Neverthelesse by reason of some defe&bholigct;s in the
said [A&bholigct;s<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] and great negligence of the said Officers and other persons in not returning the exa&bholigct; numbers of the
said Fire Hearthes and Stoves, and not duely colle&bholigct;ing leavying and paying into His Majestyes Exchequer the full
Revenue due for the numbers returned at the times appointed, and by sundry fraudulent pra&bholigct;ises to elude the
said [A&bholigct;<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] the said Revenue is much diminished and not duely answered, For Remedy thereof and for the better
ascertaining and colle&bholigct;ing the said Revenue for the future Be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by
and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament
assembled and by Authoritie of the same That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Kings Majestie His
Heires and Successors from and after the Fower and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred sixtie
fower from time to time by and with the Advice of the Lord High Treasurer Chauncellour Under Treasurer and
Barons of the Court of Exchequer for the time being or any three of them, whereof the Lord High Treasurer
or Chauncellour of the Exchequer to be one to constitute and appoint such person or persons as His Majestie
His Heires &#x0026; Successors shall thinke meete to be the Officer or Officers for the receiveing and colle&bholigct;ing and
answering the duty ariseing by the said Fire-Hearthes and Stoves by vertue of the said severall A&bholigct;s, and for
viewing and numbering of the severall Chimney Hearthes and Stoves mentioned in the said A&bholigct;s, and for the
inspe&bholigct;ing and examining the severall, Rolles Certificates and Returnes thereof made, and to be made from time
to time into His Majestyes Court of Exchequer in pursuance of the said A&bholigct;s or any other thing belonging to
the same, Which Officers or any of them shall have full power to examine and supervise the Rolles and numbers
of Fire-Hearthes and Stoves already returned into the said Court of Exchequer And being accompanyed with the
Constable or the Tythingman Treasurer Under Treasurer or other publique or proper Officer of the place (who
are hereby required to attend and assist upon this occasion) and in all Parishes and, places where there are noe
Constables Tythingmen or other Publique [Officers<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] as aforesaid there without any such assistance to enter in the
day time into any dwelling or other House Edifice Lodgeings and Chambers aforesaid And to search and examine
whether there be any more Fire Hearthes and Stoves in the same then were formerly returned or certifyed, and
what Fire Hearthes or Stoves are increased or decreased since the former Certificate, After which search and
examination, the said Officer with a Constable or Tythingman or Officers as aforesaid shall have liberty to make the
like search and examination once every yeare, And if they shall finde any variance; in the number returned both
the Officer or Officers appointed by His Majestie and the Constable or Tythingman or other Officer as aforesaid
to certifie the same under his and their Hands to the Clerke of the Peace, which Certificate they are hereby
enjoyned to make, and after Approbation thereof by the Justices of the Peace at their Sessions the same to be
certifiyed to His Majestyes Remembrancer in the Exchequer and the Officer or Officers soe appointed by His Majestie
unto the same shall from and after the said Fower and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred sixtie
fower have power to colle&bholigct; and levy the Revenue and Dutyes soe given to His Majestie as aforesaid and all
Arreares of the same.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The Duty arising payable to the King's Officers.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Default of Payment.; Distress</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the said Duty shall from time to time be paid after the Feast dayes of Saint Michaell
the Arch-Angell and the Annunciation of the Virgin Mary yearely unto such Officer as shall be appointed by vertue
of this present A&bholigct; to receive the same upon demand thereof made by such Officer or his Deputy at the House
Chamber or Place where the same Duty shall arise or grow due, And that in case of refusall or default of such
payment thereof by the space of one houre after such demand the said Officer or his Deputy may at any time
with the assistance of a Constable Tythingman or other Officer as aforesaid in the day time leavy the said Duty
and all the Arrearages thereof by Distresse and Sale of the Goods of the party or partyes soe refuseing or makeing
defaulte, restoreing to the party or partyes the overplus of the value of such Goods over and above the Duty and
Arrearages thereof then behinde, and over and above the necessary charges of takeing such Distresse, which charges
shall in noe case exceede the one moyety of the Duty and Arrearages thereof soe levyed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Within what Time Arrears to be exa&bholigct;ed.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">If Violence used against Officers; Punishment; The former Officers discharged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed That noe Owners Proprietors or Occupiers of the said Fire-Hearthes or
Stoves shall be charged destrained or molested for the said Duty, or any Arrearages thereof at any time after the
space of two yeares next after the Duty hereafter shall become due to His Majestie His Heires or Successors,
[Nor for any Arrearages of the said Duty already incurred after the space of two yeares from the Fower and
twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred sixty [&amp;<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] fower<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] And in case of violent opposition or injury done
by any person or persons to any such Officer or his Deputie in the due execution of this A&bholigct;, and the same
proved by Oath before any one Justice of the Peace, or Cheife Magistrate or Magistrates of the Citty Towne or
Place dwelling neere unto the place who are hereby authorized to administer the said Oath, it shall and may be
lawfull to and for such Justice of the Peace Magistrate or Magistrates to punish such offender or offenders if he
shall finde cause by Imprisonment in the Common Goale for any time not exceeding the space of one Moneth,
And from and after the said Fower and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred sixty fower all Officers
formerly appointed to colle&bholigct; the said Duty shall be discharged from the future colle&bholigct;ing and levying the same
otherwise then as they are dire&bholigct;ed by this A&bholigct;, And the said Officer and Officers soe appointed by His Majestie
to colle&bholigct; this Duty shall pay the same into His Majestyes Exchequer to the ends in the said former A&bholigct;s
mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Colle&bholigct;ors to give Security and take Oath.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">No Fee to Officer.; Penalty.; Officer to give Acquittance to Party without Fee</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">Provided That noe person or persons shall be imployed as aforesaid unlesse he and they shall first give in
sufficient Security to His Majestie His Heires and Successors for the due colle&bholigct;ing levying and paying in of the
said Revenue or such part thereof as shall be committed to their respe&bholigct;ive trusts, and shall likewise take a
Corporall Oath before one or more of the Barons of the Exchequer or before such persons as shall be authorized
to take such Security and Oath by Commission from the said Court of Exchequer for the due and faithfull execution
thereof according to the Lawes ena&bholigct;ed [for<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] that purpose, And that they shall not exa&bholigct; or demand any Fee or
summe of money for execution thereof from any Subje&bholigct;, but onely from the Kings Majestie under paine of being
disabled to execute the said Office or Imployment, And upon legall Convi&bholigct;ion of any such Crime to render
treble damage to the party grieved, And shall signe and deliver Acquittances for Moneyes by them received without
any Fee or Reward whatsoever. And every such Acquittance shall be a finall Discharge as in the said first A&bholigct;
is provided.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. The succeeding Tenant liable for the broken Half Year.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Stopping up, or concealing Chimnies, &#x0026;c. Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any person occupying any Hearth or Stove
chargeable to His Majestie shall leave or relinquish any House, Edifice Lodgeing or Chamber before any of the
halfe yearely Feasts whereon the same is appointed to be paid [unto<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] His Majestie His Heires and Successors; In every
such case the next Occupyer thereof shall be chargeable with the same for the said halfe yeare. And (<ref idref="n7">7</ref>) if any
person shall fraudulently stopp up deface cover or conceale any Chimney Hearth or Stove chargeable by the said
A&bholigct;, and the same be proved either by Confession of the party or upon Oath before one Justice of Peace or
Cheife Magistrate or by their view he shall for such offence pay double the value of the Duty [of<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] the same
to be levyed as aforesaid,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Persons letting Houses to Poor Persons or parcelling out the same to pay the Duty.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">All Houses with more than Two Chimnies, &#x0026;c. (Exception) liable</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And bee it likewise ena&bholigct;ed That if any person within one yeare last past hath, or hereafter shall lett the
Lands Gardens Orchards or Outhouses formerly belonging to any Dwelling house or Cottage apart from the same,
or shall divide any House into severall Dwellings, or lett out the same to any such persons who by reason of
their poverty may pretend to be exempted from payment of the said Duty by any Clause or Clauses in the former
A&bholigct;s that in every such case such person shall pay the (<ref idref="n9">9</ref>) Duty in as ample manner as they ought to have done
before that time, And that noe person or persons inhabiting any Dwelling house (not being an Almes house
exempted by the former A&bholigct;) within any Citty Burrough Corporation [or<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Market Towne or Parish which hath or
shall have in it more then Two Chimneyes Fire Hearthes or Stoves shall be exempted from payment of the Dutyes
thereon imposed by colour of any exemption or pretext whatsoever,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. One Justice may decide Differences about Distresses. &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p13">And if any question or difference shall arise about the takeing any Distresse, or levying any money by vertue
of this A&bholigct; the same shall be heard and finally determined by one or more of the [Justices of the<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Peace neere
adjoyning or cheife Magistrate of the place respe&bholigct;ively upon complaint in that behalfe</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Colle&bholigct;ors to pay the Money into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p14">
				<emph type="i">Loss of Office. Justices, &#x0026;c. to give Assistance to the Officers</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p15">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That every Colle&bholigct;or who shall be authorized and appointed by vertue of this A&bholigct;
to receive any of the said Dutyes shall truely answere and pay all such moneys as he shall receive for the said
Dutyes into His Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer halfe yearely within Three monethes after the Feast of Saint Michaell
the Arch-Angell, or the Annunciation of the blessed Virgin Mary happening next after the time the [said<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] moneys
grew due to His Majestie by vertue of the said A&bholigct;s, and under the penalty of the losse of his Office, And the
Justices of Peace and cheife Magistrates Constables and other His Majestyes Officers within their severall Limitts
and Jurisdi&bholigct;ions are hereby authorized and required to give assistance from time to time to such Officers as shall
be appointed by His Majestie His Heires and Successors for the colle&bholigct;ing of the said Duty according to the true
meaning of the said former A&bholigct;s and this present A&bholigct;,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Proviso for Persons formerly exempted, or having paid, producing Certificate for Exemption.</head>
			<para id="p16">Provided That noe person or persons shall be questioned for any Arreares due on or before our Lady
day One thousand six hundred sixtie fower who shall produce to the Colle&bholigct;or a Certificate approved or to
be approved of by the two next Justices of Peace for their exemption from the said Duty for that time
according to the Rules prescribed in the said first recited A&bholigct;, nor any person who hath truely paid the said
Duty and shall if it be required make proofe thereof before any one Justice of Peace or other cheife Magistrate
of the place, Any thing therein contained or any Returne made into His Majestyes Exchequer to the contrary
thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Allowance to Constables, &#x0026;c.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided alsoe and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every such Officer or Officers as
shall (<ref idref="n13">13</ref>) at any time [be<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] appointed by His Majestie His Heires and Successors for the colle&bholigct;ing gathering and receiveing
of the severall Summes of Money now or hereafter to grow due unto His Majestie His Heires and Successors for
or in respe&bholigct; of the said Duty ariseing upon the Fire Hearthes and Stoves shall satisfie and pay unto the respe&bholigct;ive
Petty Constables and Clerks of the Peace of this Kingdome all such allowances as are by any former A&bholigct; or
A&bholigct;s given and allowed unto them aswell for their paines and labour heretofore as hereafter to be taken by them
as in and by the former A&bholigct;s concerning Fire-Hearthes and Stoves are limitted and appointed, Any thing in this
A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">A&bholigct; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">A&bholigct;s <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Officer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">that <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">for <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">same <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">bee <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


