<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47369" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664 &amp; 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An A&bholigct; to prevent Arrests of Judgement and superseding Executions.[Rot. Parl. 16 &amp; 17 C. II. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>In Verdi&bholigct;s in the Courts at Westminster, or in Chester, Lancaster, Durham, or Great Sessions in Wales,</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Judgment not to be stayed, &amp;c. for want of Form and other Matters herein mentioned.; Nor Judgments after Verdi&bholigct;, Confession by Cog. A&bholigct;. or Reli&bholigct;. Verific. reversed for Matters herein mentioned.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas great delay trouble and vexation, hath beene and still is occasioned to the People of this Realme
as well by arresting and reversing of Judgements as by staying Executions by Writts of Error and Supersedeas
For remedy thereof Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of
the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and C&bhooov;mons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the
same That if any Verdi&bholigct; of Twelve Men shall be given in any A&bholigct;ion Suite, Bill, or Demand to be commenced
from and after the Five and twentyeth day of March which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred sixtie and five in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster, or in the Courts of Record in 
the Countyes Palatine of Chester Lancaster or Durham or in His Majestyes Courts of the Great Sessions in any
of the Twelve Shires of Wales Judgement thereupon shall not be stayed or reversed for defaulte in Forme or lacke
of Forme or by reason that there are not Pledges or but one Pledge to prosecute returned upon the Originall
Writt or because the Name of the Sheriffe is not returned upon such Originall Writt, or for defaulte of entring
Pledges upon any Bill or Declaration, or for defaulte of alledgeing the bringing into Court of any Bond Bill
Indenture or other Deed whatsoever mentioned in the Declaration or other Pleading or for defaulte of Allegation
of the bringing into Court of Letters Testamentary or Letters of Administration or by reason of the &bhooov;mission of
Viet Armis or Contra Pacem, or for or by reason of the mistakeing of the Christian Name or Surname of the
Plaintiffe or Defendant Demandant or Tennant, Summe or Summes of Money, Day, Moneth or Yeare [by the
Clerke in any Bill Declaration or Pleading where the right Name Surname Sum Day Moneth or Yeare<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] in any
Writt, Plaint, Roll or Record preceding, or in the same Roll or Record where the Mistake is Committed is or
are once truely &amp; [rightly<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] alledged, whereunto the Plaintiffe might have demurred and shewen the same for Cause,
nor for want of the Averment of Hoc paratus est verificare, or Hoc paratus est verificare per Recordum, or for
not alledgeing Prout patet per Recordum, or for that there is noe right Venue, soe as the Cause were tryed by
a Jury of the proper County or Place where the A&bholigct;ion is laid : Nor any Judgement after Verdi&bholigct;, Confession by
Cognovit A&bholigct;ionem or Reli&bholigct;a Verificatione shall be reversed for want of Misericordia or Capiatur, or by reason
that a Capiatur is entred for a Misericordia, or a Misericordia is entred where a Capiatur cought to have beene
entred, Nor for that Ideo concessum est per Curiam is entred for Ideo consideratum est per Curiam, Nor for
that the Increase of Costs after a Verdi&bholigct; in any A&bholigct;ion or upon a Nonsuite in Replevin are not entred to be
at the request of the party for whom the Judgement is given, nor by reason that the Costs in any Judgement
whatsoever are not entred to be by consent of the Plaintiffe but that all such Ommissions Variances Defe&bholigct;s and
all other matters of like nature not being against the right of the matter of the Suite, nor whereby the Issue or
Tryall are altered shall be amended by the Justices or other Judges of the Courts where such Judgements are or
shall be given, or whereunto the Record is or shall be removed by Writt of Error.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Certain A&bholigct;ions not remedied.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That this A&bholigct; or any thing therein
contained shall not extend to any Writt Declaration or Suite of Appeale of Felony or Murther, nor to any
Indi&bholigct;ment or Presentment of Felony Murder Treason or other matter, nor to any Processe upon any of them,
nor to any Writt Bill A&bholigct;ion or Information upon any penall Statute other then concerning Customes and Subsidyes
of Tonnage and Poundage Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the contrary thereof in any wise not withstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. In what A&bholigct;ions Executions shall not stay by Writ of Error without Recognizance under 3 Jac. I. c. 8.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">In Dower and Eje&bholigct;ment, Plaintiff in Error to give Security for Costs, Damages, and Money awarded.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That from and after the Twentyeth day of March in
the yeare of our Lord One thousand [six hundred<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] sixty and fower noe Execution shall be stayed in any of the
aforesaid Courts by Writt of Error or Supersedeas thereupon after Verdi&bholigct; and Judgement thereupon in any A&bholigct;ion
personall whatsoever unlesse a Recognizance with Condition according to the Statute made in the Third yeare of
the Raigne of our late Soveraigne Lord King James shall be first acknowledged in the Court where such Judgement
shall be given, And further That in Writts of Error to be brought upon any Judgement after Verdi&bholigct; in any Writt
of Dower or in any A&bholigct;ion of Eje&bholigct;ione firme noe Execution shall be thereupon or thereby stayed unlesse the
Plaintiffe or Plaintiffes in such Writt of Error shall be bound unto the Plaintiffe in such Writt of Dower or A&bholigct;ion
of Eje&bholigct;ione firme in such reasonable Summe as the Court to which such Writt of Error shall be dire&bholigct;ed shall
thinke fitt with condition that if the Judgement shall be affirmed in the said Writt of Error, or that the said
Writt of Error be discontinued in defaulte of the Plaintiffe or Plaintiffes therein, or that, the said Plaintiffe or
Plaintiffes be Nonsuite in such Writts of Error that then the said Plaintiffe or Plaintiffes shall pay such Costs
Dammages and Summe and Summes of Money as shall be awarded upon or after such Judgement affirmed
Discontinuance or Nonsuite had.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Writ of Inquiry of Mesne Profits and Damages.</head>
			<para id="p6">And to the end that the same Summe and Summes and Dammages may be ascertained, It is further ena&bholigct;ed
That the Court wherein such Execution ought to be granted upon such Affirmation Discontinuance or Nonsuite
shall issue a Writt to enquire aswell of the meane Proffitts as of the Dammages by any Waste committed after
the first Judgement in Dower or in Eje&bholigct;ione firme, And upon the Returne thereof Judgement shall be given and
Execution awarded for such Mesne Proffitts and Dammages and alsoe for Costs of Suite.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Writs of Error in A&bholigct;ions by Executors, A&bholigct;ions Popular, and on Penal Statutes, except for Tithes and Indi&bholigct;ments, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided That this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall not extend to any Writt of Error to be brought
by any Executor or Administrator, nor unto any A&bholigct;ion Popular nor unto any other A&bholigct;ion which is or hereafter
shall be brought upon any Penall Law or Statute (except A&bholigct;ions of Debt for not setting forth of Tythes) nor
to any Indi&bholigct;ment Presentment Inquisition Information or Appeale, Any thing herein before expressed to the contrary
thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided alwayes That this A&bholigct; shall continue in force for Three yeares and to the end of the next Session
of Parlyament after the expiration of the said Three yeares and noe longer.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


