<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47361" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for continuance of a former A&bholigct; for regulateing the Presse.[Rot. Parl. 16 C. II. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>14 (13 &#x0026; 14) Car. II. C. 33. continued</head>
		<para id="p1">Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled That an A&bholigct; made in the Fowerteenth
yeare of the Raigne of our Soveraigne Lord the King that now is entituled An A&bholigct; for preventing the frequent
Abuses in printing Seditious Treasonable and Unlicensed Bookes and Pamphletts and for regulateing of Printing and
Printing Presses shall be continued and remaine in force untill the end of the next Session of Parlyament.</para>
		<para id="p2">ITEM qu&aelig;d? petitiones privatas personas concernentes (in se form? A&bholigct;us continentes) exhibita fuerunt predi&bholigct;o Domino
Regi in Parliamento predi&bholigct;o quar&bhouov; Tituli subscribuntur.</para>
		<para id="p3">1. An Act for vacateing certaine Conveyances made by Sir John Packington Baronet to Christopher Henn and
others.</para>
		<para id="p4">2. An Act for the sale of the Mannour of Ingoldesby and diverse Lands in Ingoldesby in the County of
Lincolne for raiseing portions for the two Daughters and Coheires of Sir William Armin the Younger Baronet
deceased.</para>
		<para id="p5">3. An Act for the sale of certaine Lands for payment of the debts of Sir Sackvile Glemham.</para>
		<para id="p6">4. An Act to enable Trustees for Sir William Keite to sell Lands for the payment of Debts.</para>
		<para id="p7">5. An Act for confirmation of the enclosure and improvement of Malverne Chase.</para>
		<para id="p8">6. An Act for setleing the charitable gift of Abraham Colfe Clerke for ere&bholigct;ing and endowing two free Schooles
and an Almes-house at Lewisham in Kent.</para>
		<para id="p9">7. An Act for naturalizing [of<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Dame Katherine Sayer and others.</para>
		<para id="p10">8. An Act to enable Francis Cottington or Charles Cottington to setle and dispose of Lands in joynture for
any wife or wives they shall take in marriage.</para>
		<para id="p11">9. An Act to enable Charles Cotton Esquire to make Leases of Lands for payment of debts.</para>
		<para id="p12">10. An Act for the makeing of the Church ere&bholigct;ed at Falmouth a Parish Church and noe part of the parish
of Oluvias or Chapelry of Saint Budocke.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>


