<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47360" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664</title>
	<subtitle>An Act against deceitfull disorderly and excessive Gameing.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that many Mischiefs arise from immoderate Use of Games.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Money won by Deceit in Gaming; Penalty.; Limitation of A&bholigct;ion; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas all lawfull Games and Exercises should not be otherwise used than as innocent and moderate
Recreations and not as constant Trades or Callings to gaine a liveing or make unlawfull Advantage
thereby And whereas by the immoderate use of them many mischeifes and inconveniencies doe arise and are dayly
found to the maintaining and encourageing of sundry idle loose and disorderly persons in their dishonest lewd and
dissolute course of life, And to the circumventing deceiveing cousening and debauching of many of the younger
sort both of the Nobility and Gentry and others to the losse of their pretious time and the [other<ref idref="n1">1</ref>
] ruine of
their Estates and Fortunes and withdrawing them from noble and laudable Imployments and Exercises Bee it
(<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That if any
person or persons of any Degree or Quality whatsoever at any time or times after the Nine and twentyeth day of
September which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred sixty and fower doe or shall
by any fraude shift cousanage circumvention deceit or unlawfull device or ill pra&bholigct;ice whatsoever in playing at or
with Cards Dice Tables Tennis Bowles Kitles Shovelboard, or in or by Cockefightings Horse-races Dog-matches
(<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) Foot-races or other Pastimes Game or Games whatsoever, or in or by beareing a share or part in the Stakes
Wagers or [Adventurers,<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] or in or by betting on the Sides or Hands of such as doe or shall play a&bholigct; ride or run as
aforesaid win obtaine or acquire to him or themselves or to any other or others any Summe or Summes of Money
or other valueable thing or things whatsoever That then every person and persons soe offending as aforesaid shall
ipso fa&bholigct;o forfeit and lose treble the summe or value of Money or other thing or things soe won, gained obtained
or acquired, The one moyetie thereof to our Soveraigne Lord the King His Heires and Successors, and the other
moyetie thereof unto the person or persons greived, or who shall lose the Money or other thing or things soe
gained, soe as every such loser and person greived in that behalfe doe or shall prosecute and sue for the same
within six Kalender Moneths [nex<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] after such Play. And in defaulte of such prosecution the same other Moyetie to
such person or persons as shall or will prosecute or sue for the same within one Yeare next after the said Six
Monthes expired, And that the said Forfeitures shall or may be sued for or recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill
Plaint or Information in any of his Majestyes Courts at Westminster wherein noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of
Law shall be allowed, And that [all and<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] all and every such Plaintiffe or Plaintiffes Informer or Informers shall in
every such Suite [and<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Prosecution have and recover his and their treble Costs against the person offending and
forfeiting as aforesaid Any Law Statute Custome or Usage to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Contra&bholigct;s and Specialties for Money won at Play, above &pound;100. at one time, void.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">The Person so winning to forfeit Treble the Money won.; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the better avoiding and preventing of all excessive and immoderate playing and gameing for the time
to come Bee it further ordained and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any person or persons shall at
any time or times after the Nine and twentyeth day of September aforesaid play at any of the said Games or any
other Pastime Game or Games whatsoever (other than with and for ready money) or shall bett on the Sides or
Hands of such as doe or shall play thereat and shall lose any summe or summes of Money or other thing or
things soe plaid for exceeding the summe of One Hundred pounds at any one time or meeting upon Ticket or
Credit or otherwise and shall not pay downe the same at the time when he or they shall soe lose the same The
partie and partyes who loseth or shall lose the said moneyes or other thing or things soe plaid or to be plaid for
above the said summe of One hundred pounds shall not in that case be bound or compelled or compellable to pay
or make good the same but the Contra&bholigct; and Contra&bholigct;s for the same and for every part thereof and all and
singular Judgements Statutes Recognizances Mortgages Conveyances Assurances Bonds Bills Specialtyes Promises
Covenants Agreements and other A&bholigct;s Deeds and Securityes whatsoever which shall be obtained made given
acknowledged or entered into for security or satisfa&bholigct;ion of, or for the same or any part thereof shall be utterly
void and of none effe&bholigct; And that the [said<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] person or persons soe wining, the said moneyes or other things shall be utterly
forfeite and lose treble the value of all such summe and summes of money or other thing and things which he
shall soe [winne<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] gaine obtaine or acquire above the said summe of One hundred pounds, the one moyetie thereof
to our said Soveraigne Lord the King His Heires and Successors, and the other moyety thereof to such person or
persons as shall prosecute or sue for the same within one yeare next after the time of such Offence committed,
And to be sued for by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of his Majestyes Courts [of Record<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] at
Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed. And that every such Plaintiffe
or Plaintiffies Informer or Informers shall in every such Suite and Prosecution have and receivee his treble Costs
against the person and persons offending and forfeiting as aforesaid, Any Law Custome or Usage to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">utter <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">therefore <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Adventures <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">next <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>

