<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47366" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664 &amp; 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An A&bholigct; to prevent Delayes in extending Statutes Judgements and Recognizances.[Rot. Parl. 16 &amp; 17 C. II. nu.4.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that the Security by Statute Merchant and Statute Staple is become of little Use by the Fraud of Conizers, and of the Consequences thereof.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">No Execution shall be stayed, though the whole Lands be not extended.; Proviso for Defendant's Remedy for Contribution.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Security by, Statute-Merchant and of the Staple is now become of litle use and benefit by
the fraude of the Conizers thereof in sundry cases who to prevent the payment of their Debts secretly
assigne small parts of their Lands to severall and unknowne. persons, And it haveing beene used that if the
Creditor take Execution on such Statute, yet if the Lands of any one or more person or persons, to whom such
Alienation was made and lyeable to such Execution be ommitted out of such Extent, the same Execution hath
beene avoided by Audita Querela and the party extending lost his Costs and was delayed of his just Debt and soe
againe upon any new Extent toties quoties, And if any one Acre or Parcell of Land happened to descend to an 
Infant the whole Execution was deferred till, full age of such Infant, And if afterwards other part of the Lands
or Tenements lyeable to such Debt descended to another Infant then alsoe a farther delay happened dureing that
Infancy alsoe, Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by Authoritie
of the same That when any Judgement Statute or Recognizance shall be extended the same shall not be avoided or
delayed by occasion that any part of the Lands or Tenements extendable are or shall be ommitted out of such
Extent, saveing alwayes to the Party and Partyes whose Lands shall be extended his and their Heires Executors
and Assignes his and their remedy for Contribution against such person and persons whose Lands are or shall
be omitted out of such Extent from time to time.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. No Contribution against an Heir within Age.</head>
			<para id="p3">[Provided alwayes that this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall not be construed to give any Exte?nt or
Contribution against any Heire within the age of one and twenty yeares dureing such Minority of such Heire for
or in respe&bholigct; of any Lands to such Heire descended farther or otherwise then might have beene before the makeing
of this A&bholigct;,<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. To extend only to Statutes for Debts, and to Extents which shall be sued within 20 Years.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided that this A&bholigct; extend onely, to such Statutes as are or shall be for payment of moneyes, And to such
Extent as shall be within Twenty yeares after the Statute Recognizance or Judgement had and obtained,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided that this A&bholigct; shall continue for the space of Three yeares and from thence to the end of the next
Session of Parlyament and noe longer</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a feparate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


