<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47362" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664 &amp; 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for granting a Royall Ayd unto the Kings Majestie of Twenty fower hundred threescore and seaventeene
thousand and five hundred Pounds to be raised leavyed and paid in the space of Three Yeares.[Rot. Parl. 16 C. II. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Grant of &pound;2,477, 500</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee Your Majestyes most dutyfull and loyall Subje&bholigct;s the Commons assembled in Parlyament takeing into
Consideration the great and apparent Dangers which now threaten this Kingdome, and that for prevention
thereof Your Majestie hath found Yourselfe obliged to equip and sett out to Sea a Royall Navy for the preservation
of Your Majestyes auntient and undoubted Soveraignty and Dominion in the Seas and the Trade of Your Majestyes
Subje&bholigct;s, And haveing duely weighed and considered the severall wayes and meanes by which Your Majestie hath
beene enforced to make these Preparations at soe vast an Expence And acknowledging with all humility and
thankfulnes Your Majestyes abundant Care for our Preservation and being deepely sensible of that extraordinary
Charge and Expence with which Your Majestyes present Engagement ought to be supported, and of those
Inconveniencies which must needs befall the Nation if we should be wanting to ourselves in this soe weighty
and important Occasion, have chearefully and unanimously given and granted, and doe hereby give and grant
unto Your most Excellent Majestie the summe of Twenty fower hundred threescore and seaventeene thousand and
five hundred Pounds to be raised and leavyed in manner following, And doe humbly beseech Your Majestie That
it may be ena&bholigct;ed, And bee it enacted by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by Authoritie
of the same That for the righting of Your Majestie and Your Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s against the Dutch the summe of
twenty fower hundred threescore and seaventeene thousand and five hundred Pounds shall be raised leavyed and
paid unto your Majestie within the space of Three Yeares in manner following that is to say The summe of
Threescore and eight thousand eight hundred and nineteene pounds and nine shillings by the Moneth for Thirty
six Moneths begining from the Five and twentyeth day of December(<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) One thousand six hundred sixty fower shall be assessed taxed, colle&bholigct;ed, levyed and paid by Twelve quarterly payments in the severall Countyes Cittyes
Burroughes Townes and places within England and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede according
to the severall rules and proportions and in such manner as is hereafter expressed that is to say for every Moneth
of the said Thirty six Moneths,</para>
		<para id="p3">For the County of Bedford the summe of Eight hundred ninety six pounds seaventeene shillings and nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p4">The County of Berks the summe of One thousand one hundred thirty two pounds six shillings and seaven
pence.</para>
		<para id="p5">The County of Bucks the summe of One thousand three hundred and fifteene pounds six shillings and five
pence.</para>
		<para id="p6">The County of Cambridge the summe of One thousand and twenty pounds.</para>
		<para id="p7">The Isle of Ely the summe of Three hundred forty nine pounds seaventeene shillings and eleaven pence,</para>
		<para id="p8">The County of Chester with the City and County of the Citty of Chester the summe of Eight hundred and
one pounds five shillings and six pence.</para>
		<para id="p9">The County of Cornwall the summe of One thousand five hundred and forty pounds eighteene shillings and
three pence.</para>
		<para id="p10">The County of Cumberland the summe of One hundred sixty eight pounds six shillings and a penny.</para>
		<para id="p11">The County of Derby the summe of Eight hundred sixty two pounds eight shillings and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p12">The County of Devon the summe of Three thousand two hundred twenty nine pounds nineteene shillings and
two pence.</para>
		<para id="p13">The Citty and County of the Citty of Exon the summe of One hundred and sixteene pounds seaven shillings
and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p14">The County of Dorset the summe of One thousand three hundred forty fower pounds ten shillings and five
pence.</para>
		<para id="p15">The Towne and County of Poole the summe of Ten pounds nineteene shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p16">The County of Durham the summe of Three hundred twenty three pounds sixteene shillings and nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p17">The County of Yorke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke and Towne and County of Kingstone
upon Hull the summe of Three thousand fower hundred sixty nine pounds five shillings and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p18">The County of Essex the summe of Three thousand ninety eight pounds eight shillings and ten pence.</para>
		<para id="p19">The County of Gloucester the summe of One thousand eight hundred and eight pounds ten shillings and
three pence.</para>
		<para id="p20">The Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester the summe of Thirty nine pounds eight shillings.</para>
		<para id="p21">The County of Hereford the summe of One thousand one hundred thirty one pounds thirteene shillings and
fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p22">The County of Hertford the summe of One thousand three hundred forty five pounds sixteene shillings and
three pence.</para>
		<para id="p23">The County of Huntington the summe of six hundred thirty three pounds fowerteene shillings and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p24">The County of Kent with the Citty and County of the Citty of Canterbury the summe of Three thousand three
hundred twenty six pounds eighteene shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p25">The County of Lancaster the summe of One thousand and six pounds thirteene shillings and six pence.</para>
		<para id="p26">The County of Leicester the summe of One thousand eighty fower pounds fowerteene shillings and three pence.</para>
		<para id="p27">The County of Lincolne with the Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne the summe of Two thousand five
hundred seaventy five pounds two shillings.</para>
		<para id="p28">The Citty of London with the Liberty of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Martins le grand the summe of Five thousand ninety one pounds
eleaven shillings and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p29">The County of Midlesex with the Citty and Liberty of Westminster the summe of Two thousand two hundred
and forty pounds ten shillings.</para>
		<para id="p30">The County of Monmouth the summe of Three hundred and ninety pounds.</para>
		<para id="p31">The County of Northampton the summe of One thousand fower hundred and thirteene pounds eighteene shillings
and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p32">The County of Nottingham with the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham the summe of Eight hundred
seaventy three pounds eight shillings.</para>
		<para id="p33">The County of Norffolke the summe of Three thousand three hundred seaventy pounds twelve shillings.</para>
		<para id="p34">The Citty and County of the Citty of Norwich the summe of One hundred and eighty pounds.</para>
		<para id="p35">The County of Northumberland with the Townes of Newcastle and Berwicke upon Tweede the summe of Three
hundred seaventy two pounds fifteene shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p36">The County of Oxon the summe of Eleaven hundred thirty five pounds ten shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p37">The County of Rutland the summe [of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] two hundred and forty pounds eight shillings and eleaven pence.</para>
		<para id="p38">The County of Salop the summe [of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] One thousand two hundred and three pounds fowerteene shillings and
two pence.</para>
		<para id="p39">The County of Stafford the summe of Eight hundred fifty two pounds eleaven shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p40">The Citty and County of the Citty of Litchfeild the summe of Thirteene pounds.</para>
		<para id="p41">The County of Somerset the summe of Two thousand seaven hundred seaventy one pound ten shillings and
eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p42">The Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll the summe of One hundred ninety nine pounds eight shillings
and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p43">The County of Southampton with the Towne and County of Southampton and Isle of Weight the summe of
Two thousand one hundred eighty nine pounds eight shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p44">The County of Suffolke the summe of Three thousand two hundred ninety eight pounds ten shillings and
eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p45">The County of Surrey with the Burrough of Southwarke the summe of One thousand five hundred ninety seaven
pound and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p46">The County of Sussex the summe of One thousand eight hundred twenty one pounds seaven shillings and
nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p47">The County of Warwicke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry the summe of One thousand
one hundred ninety two pounds eight shillings and nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p48">The County of Worcester the summe of One thousand fifty three pounds and nineteene shillings.</para>
		<para id="p49">The Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester the summe of Fifty five pounds nine shillings and six pence.</para>
		<para id="p50">The County of Wilts the summe of One thousand nine hundred sixty six pounds seaventeene shillings and seaven
pence.</para>
		<para id="p51">The County of Westmerland the summe of One hundred and sixteene pounds.</para>
		<para id="p52">The Isle of Anglesey the summe of One hundred twenty five pounds thirteene shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p53">The County of Brecknocke the summe of Two hundred eighty two pounds ten shillings and five pence
halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p54">The County of Cardigan the summe of One hundred and five pounds fifteene shillings and nine pence halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p55">The County of Carmarthen the summe of two hundred seaventy two pounds six shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p56">The County of Carnarvan the summe of One hundred forty six pounds twelve shillings and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p57">The County of Denbigh the summe of Two hundred twenty three pounds ten shillings and seaven pence.</para>
		<para id="p58">The County of Flint the summe of One hundred and eighteene pounds seaventeene shillings and fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p59">The County of Glamorgan the summe of Three hundred seaventy eight pounds seaventeene shillings and ten
pence.</para>
		<para id="p60">The County of Merioneth the summe of One hundred pounds sixteene shillings and a penny.</para>
		<para id="p61">The County of Mountgomery the summe of Two hundred seaventy six pounds twelve shillings and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p62">The County of Pembrooke the summe of Three hundred twenty six pounds and ten shillings.</para>
		<para id="p63">The County of Radnor the summe of One hundred seaventy fower pounds six shillings and eight pence.</para>
		<para id="p64">The Towne of Haverford West the summe of Fifteen pounds three shillings and five pence.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Commissioners for Counties, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p65">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every the persons hereafter named shall be
Commissioners of and for the severall and respective Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places hereafter
named that is to say.</para>
	
	<section id="s3">
		<head>Bedford</head>
		<para id="p66">For the County of Bedford William Russell Es&bhoqexc; Sir Beauchampe S<emph type="p">t</emph> John K?t Sir Samuell Browne Knight one of
the Justices of the Common Pleas, Sir John Keeling Knight one of the Justices of the Kings Bench Sir John Cotton
Sir Lodowicke Dyer Sir John Napier Sir Roger Burgoyne Sir Thomas Alstone Sir Humphry Winch Sir Humphry
Monox Sir S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Charnocke Baronets Sir Henry Chester Knight of the Bath Sir William Fleetewood Sir William
Palmer of Warden Streete Sir William Palmer of Hill, Sir John Duncombe Sir William Beecher Sir Edward Cater
Sir George Blundell Sir Clement Armiger Sir John Huxley Knights Paulet S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Richard Tayler Stephen Anderson
William Spencer Oliver Luke Francis Crawley S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Tompson Thomas Snagg William Boteler John Keeling John
Osbourne John Vaux John Alstone John Coppen Francis Wingate William Gerey Walter Carey Francis Dive William
Franklin George Wyan Gains Squire James Mountague Samuell Cotton John Neale John Cockane Thomas Cheyne
John Ventris Robert Crompton Thomas Rolt Robert Audley Mathew Denton Simon Gray Mathew Dennis William
Foster Richard Orlibere the elder Thomas Cobb Jasper Edwards Samuell Bedford Es?uirers.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>For the Towne of Bedford</head>
		<para id="p67">The Major of Bedford for the time being William Russell Es&bhoqexc; Sir Humphry Winch Sir John Napier Baronets
Paulet S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Richard Tayler William Foster John Gardiner Es?uirers Thomas Christy William Risley Simon Becket
Robert Beverley William Scott John Beaumont Thomas Fitzhugh Alderman Crawley Richard Elmes John Cobb and
John Spencer the elder Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>Berks</head>
		<para id="p68">For the County of Berks Charles Earle of Ancram in the Kingdome of Scotland Sir George Cartwright Baronet
Vice-Chamberlaine to his Majestie John Lovelace Es&bhoqexc; Sir George Stonehouse Sir George Pratt Sir Richard Braham
Sir Thomas Draper Sir Thomas Rich Sir Henry Winchcombe Sir William Backehouse Sir Anthony Craven Sir Cesar
Colclough Sir John Fettiplace Sir Thomas Clergys Baronets Sir Richard Powle Knight of the Bath Sir Edmond
Sawyer Sir Robert Pye Sir William Armorer Sir Thomas Dolman Sir John Davis Sir Richard Bishop Knights Richard
Nevill Humphry Hyde Richard Harrison William Barker George Purefoy Peregrine Hobby Robert Packer Richard
Aldworth Thomas Fettiplace George Fettiplace John Harrison Anthony Barker Henry Pro&bholigct;er John Blagrave Francis
Piggot Hungerford Dunch William Trumball William Dormer John Elwes Thomas Garret John Southby William
Wilmot William James William Barker of Hurst Edward Keate William Nelson Hartgell Baron Richard Jones
William Tayler Edward Dalby Paul Calton Thomas Saunders Charles Whitacre Humphrey Hyde senior of Hurst
Humphrey Hyde junior of Kingston Edward Hobby Richard Palmer John Hartsey Es?rs William Offley Do&bholigct;or in
Lawes Francis Hungerford Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke William Hamersley George Blagrave John Kendricke John, Allen
Robert Leigh Nicholas Hyde Peregrine Wilcox Thomas Southby William Langton John Due Francis Peacocke
Michaell Mallet Henry Murrey Es?rs, John Peacocke Robert Goston James Heron Philip Weston Henry Barker John
Powney Roger Draper Richard Lovelace William Hussey Roger Knight Charles Pierce Richard Punt Gentleman
The Major of Reading for the time being. The Maior of Abington for the time being, The Maior of Newbery for
the time being, The Maior of Windsor for the time being, The Maior of Wallingford for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>Bucks</head>
		<para id="p69">For the County of Bucks Charles Earle of Ancram in the Kingdome of Scotland Philip Lord [Waynman<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Viscount
Tuam in the Kingdome of Ireland James Herbert Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Tyrrell one of the Justices of the Common Pleas
Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir Toby Tyrrell Sir John Burlace Sir Anthony Chester Sir
Thomas Proby Sir William Bowyer Sir William Smith Sir Ralph Varney Sir William Drake Sir Thomas Hampson
Sir Henry Andrewes Sir John Croke Baronets Sir William Tirringham Sir Richard Ingoldesby Sir Robert Gayer
Knights of the Bath Sir Edmond Pye Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Lee Sir Richard Napper Sir Richard Pigg (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>)
Sir Henry Herbert Sir John Dormer Sir Thomas Cleyton Sir Robert Croke Sir Thomas Clergies Sir George Tash
Knights William Fleetewood Charles Cheyne Edmond Waller senior Edmond Waller junior William Penn Edmond
West Brett Norton Thomas Duncombe Thomas Hacket William Lane John Eglestone Richard Barringer Edward
Nicholas Thomas Ferrers senior Cesar Cranmore Thomas Risley Roger Price Peter Dorrell Thomas Saunders Francis
Ingoldesby Edmond Dorrell George Russell Richard Winwood Richard Greenvile Robert Scawen Bud Wase Thomas
Tirrell Robert Napper Edmond Hampden John Clarke Robert Croke Richard Hampden William Burlace Bazill
Brent William Hill Thomas Ferrer junior Ambrose Bennet James Low Thomas Stafford Robert Levet Charles Doe
Robert Tompkins Bernard Tourney Thomas Egleton Robert Dormer Francis Tyrringham George Wyan William
Cleaver William Abraham Captaine Robert Style John Grubbe Es?rs John Greene Henry Alnot James Perrat
George Gosnall Gentleman, The Bayliffe of Buckingham for the time being John Risley Roger Price Peter Dorrell
junior Esquiers John Smith William Lambert and John Tournour Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>Cambridge</head>
		<para id="p70">For the County of Cambridge William Lord Allington of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Dudley North Knight of
the Bath Sir Thomas Hatton Sir John Cotton Sir Thomas Willis Sir John Cutts Sir George Downeing Baronets
Sir Thomas Wendy Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas [Dayrell<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] Sir Isaac Thornton Sir Robert Cotton Knights Thomas
Chichley Levinus Bennet John Millisent Samuell Fortrey Thomas Storey Thomas Ducket William Layer Humphrey
Gardner Roger Pepis Thomas Dod Mildmay Dowman Jeoffrey Nightingall William Aloffe Pike Thomas
Bucke Dalton John Bing Thomas Martin and William Legate Esq[ui]rs.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>For the University and Towne of Cambridge</head>
		<para id="p71">The Vice Chauncellour The Maior for the time being William Lord Allington of the Kingdome of Ireland Theophilus
Dillingham James Fleetewood Richard Minshall Do&bholigct;ors of Divinity Robert King Do&bholigct;or of the Lawes Thomas Crouch
Clement Nevile Es?rs Roger Pepis Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Samuell Spalding John Ewen William Wells John Herring Aldermen
Sir Thomas Slater Baronet Robert Eade Edward Stoyte Do&bholigct;ors of Phisicke and Nicholas Jacob Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>Isle of Ely</head>
		<para id="p72">For the Isle of Ely Richard Lord Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland William Colvile Thomas March Mathew
Wren Charles Wren Edward Parterich William Fisher Thomas. Steward Robert Steward Henry Hitch Do&bholigct;or
of Law Robert Balam Thomas Castell Lawrence Oxborough John Towers Anthony Backeworth John Childe
junior William Balam Thomas Edwards William March Michaell Holman Mathew Tayler Roger Jenings and John
Delavall Es?rs.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s10">
		<head>Chester</head>
		<para id="p73">For the County of Chester Robert Lord Cholmondeley of the Kingdome of Ireland William Lord Brereton of
the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Thomas Delves Sir Willoughby Aston Sir Thomas Powell Sir George Warberton Sir
Peter Leicester Sir Thomas Manwareing Sir Thomas Smith junior Sir John Bellet Sir Peter Pinder Sir Richard
Brookes Sir William Stanley Baronets Sir John Booth Sir Philip Egerton Sir Peter Brookes Sir John Arderne Sir
Robert Cotton Sir Foulke Lucy Sir Jeoffrey Shekerley Knights Peter Venables Baron of Kinderton Thomas Needham
Thomas Cholmundeley George Vernon Robert [Patton<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Henry Bunbury Henry Leigh Thomas Leigh of Adlington
Richard Legh of Lyme John Crew of Crew Thomas Marbury Edward Warren Edward Legh Edward Hyde John
Crew of Utkinton Roger Wilbraham Nathaniell Booth Peter Dutton John Daniell Randell Dod John Leech Richard
Wathall Edward Glegg Roger King John Davenport of Widford Thomas Glasier Somerford Oldfeild Edward
Swettenham Peers Legh John Ward Ralph Wilbraham William Brocke John Hulstone John Shalcrosse Edward
Downes of Worth Ralph Baskerfeild of Winnington and Thomas Lee Esquiers.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s11">
		<head>Citty of Chester</head>
		<para id="p74">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester The Maior for the time being Sir Thomas Smith Baronet Sir
Thomas Smith Knight Richard Leiving Es&bhoqesq; Recorder of Chester John Radcliffe Es&bhoqesq;. Thomas Thrope William
Crumpton Thomas [Cooke<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Cowper William Streete and Ince Aldermen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s12">
		<head>Cornwall</head>
		<para id="p75">For the County of Cornwall Sir William Morrice Principall Secretary of State Robert Roberts Hender Roberts
Esquiers Sir Chichester Wray Sir John Trelawney Knights and Baronets Sir John Carew Baronet Sir [Edward<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Vivian
Knight and Baronet Sir John Coriton Sir William Godolphin Baronets Sir Francis Godolphin Sir Richard Edgecombe
Sir Nicholas Slanning Knights of the Bath Sir Peter Killigrew Sir Peter Courtney Sir John Arundle Sir Samuell
Cosworth Sir James Smith Sir Walter Moyle Knights Henry Seamour Jonathan Trelawney Richard Arundle Pierce
Edgecombe Hugh Boscawen Francis Buller Charles Trevanion Charles Roscarrocke John Speacket John Elliot John
Tanner Francis Edgecombe Nathaniell Moyle Bernard Greenvile John Trelawney William Pendervis William Scawen
William Travisa William Bond Edward Boscawen Christopher Cooke Nicholas Glyn Thomas Herle Viol Vivian James
Praed John Conock Samuell Trelawney John S<emph type="p">t</emph> Aubin John Nicholas of Trewane John Nicholl of Litlewood Arthur
Fortescue John Vivean Oliver Saule William Mohun Haniball Bugins Lewis Tremane Richard Hawkes Colan Blewet
John Bleigh Henry Spoure senior Jonathan Rashley senior Jonathan Rashley junior John Rashley Robert Hoblin
Christopher Bond Thomas Burell Thomas Robinson John Thomas Richard Erisey Christopher Harris Francis Grigger
Humphrey Courtney John Buller Charles Boscawen Robert Scawen Thomas Waddon Tristram Arscot William Cotton
Edward Nosworthy George Heale John Polwheele Digorie Polwheele Nicholas Arundle John Arundle of Sythney
Hugh Jones John Penrose Edmond Prideaux Joseph Tredinnam James Bond William Godolphin Edward Elliot
Richard Hoblin Richard Pendarvis Hugh Trevanion Junior Nathaniell Trevanion Francis Penrose John Fowell Ezekiell
Arundle Richard Rouse Walter Kendall John Kendall Walter Langdon senior Walter Langdon junior John Batersbye
Henry Spoure senior Joseph Nicholls Charles Grills Arthur Spry John Vacye William Spry Francis Calmadie
Humphrey Noye John Harris Edward Harris Nicholas Courtney Thomas Achim, William Painter Thomas Hawkey
Andrew Corye Michaell Hill of Wendron John Carnsewe Samuell Ennis John Kestell Thomas Treffrie Michaell Viveon
Anthony Chinoweth Francis Burgis Richard Carter John Sylly Richard Tippet Thomas Carew Christopher Billet
Chamon Greenvile Samuell Langford Reynald Hawkey Walter Vincent James Robbins Humphrey Burlace Francis
Lutterell and James Erisy Esq[ui]rs, The Maior of Truro for the time being Martin Madrin Gen&bhocent;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s13">
		<head>Cumberland</head>
		<para id="p76">For the County of Cumberland Edward Lord Morpeth sonne and heire apparent to Charles Earle of Carlisle Sir
Philip Musgrave Sir William Dalston Sir George Fletcher Sir John Lowther senior Sir John Lowther junior Sir Edward
Musgrave Baronets Sir Thomas Dacres Sir William Hudlestone Sir Wilfrid Lawson Sir William Carleton Sir Philip
Howard Sir Francis Salkeld Sir John Dalston Knights John Lamplough Richard Skelton William Musgrave William
Layton Christopher Musgrave John Agleonby Robert Scawen George Denton Thomas Denton Richard Tolson Andrew
Hudlestone Robert Highmoure George Towry and The Maior of Carlisle for the time being Daniell Fleming Edward
Stanley William Pennington Wrightington Senhouse Esq[ui]rs.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s14">
		<head>Derby</head>
		<para id="p77">For the County of Derby Henry Viscount Mansfeild sonne and heire apparent to William Marquesse of Newcastle
William Lord Cavendish sonne and heire apparent to William Earle of Devonshire Anchitall Grey George Pierpoint
Esquiers Sir Thomas Greslye Sir Francis Burdet Sir John Harper Sir John Curson Sir Edward Cooke Sir Henry
Every Sir William Boothby Baronets Sir John Harper Sir Samuell Sleigh Knights John Fretchvelle German Poole
John Ferrers George Vernon Charles Agard John Munday Richard Cooke John Milward William Fitzherbert
Charles Cotton Walter Horton Gilbert Thacker Henry Gilbert Robert Eyre William Revell Godfrey Clarke
William Bullocke William Woolly Nicholas Wilmot John Shalcrosse Ravell Ashenhurst Francis Mennell Thomas
Milward George Sitwell Henry Wigfall James Abny Esquiers George Tayler John Spateman William Wright
Francis Barker Gentleman The Maior of Derby for the time being Roger Allestre John Dalton Simon Degg Hugh
Bateman Esquiers John Shore Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Thomas Freeman Gen&bhocent; M<emph type="p">r</emph> Charles Agard of Foston and John
Daundidge Alderman.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s15">
		<head>Devon</head>
		<para id="p78">For the County of Devon Arthur Earle of Donegall in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Hugh Pollard Baronet
Comptroller of his Majestyes Household Sir George Carteret Vice Chamberlaine of his Majestyes Household Sir
William Morrice Principall Secretary of State Sir William Courtney Baronet John Ashburnham Es&bhoqesq; Sir Edward
Seymour Sir George Chudlugh Sir Peter Prideaux Sir Thomas Hele Sir Chichester Wrey Sir Courtney Poole
Sir Coplestone Bampfeild Sir John Norcote Sir John Chichester Sir Edmond Fowell Sir William Morrice Sir John
Drake Sir Thomas Carew Sir John Davy Sir Walter Younge Sir Edmond Fortescue Baronets Sir Edward Wise
Sir John Rolle Sir Edward Hungerford Sir Nicholas Slaning Knights of the Bath Sir John Chichester Sir Henry
Carew Sir Richard Prideaux Sir Peter Ball Sir James Smith Sir Robert [Cary<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Sir William Strode Sir Thomas Clifford Sir Thomas Higgons Sir John Skelton Knights Edward Seymour Peter Prideaux John Fowell Pierce Edgecombe Arthur Basset Thomas Fulford Francis Drew Robert Fortescue John Carew of Studly Edmond Tremaine
John Harris John Gifford of Brightly George Yeo Thomas Carew of Bowghill John Bury John Pollarde Richard
Cabell John Arscot Nicholas Ducke George Howard Jonathan Sparke Henry Ford Robert Duke Mathew Hele John Hale
William Bastard William Martin Samuell Trelawny George Reinolds Henry Northleigh Nicholas Dennis Josias Calmady
Richard Coffin Edmond Waldrond Thomas Bere William Walrond John Davy of Ruxford John Young of Coalbrooke
Samuell Sainthill Henry Stevens Henry Newt John Tanner John Willoughby John Tuckfeild Peter Fortescue
Christopher Clobery Shilston Calmady John Kelland Thomas Reynolds Thomas Gibbans Balthasar Beere James
Clifford John Fownes William Bogan James Rodde Esquires The High Sheriffe of Devon for the time being and
The Maiors of Totnes Barnstable Plimouth Dartmouth and Tiverton for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s16">
		<head>Citty of Exon</head>
		<para id="p79">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Exon Allen Penny Maior The Maior for the time being Sir Peter
Ball Recorder Sir James Smith Knight Robert Walker Es&bhoqesq;, John Martin Christopher Lethbridge Henry Gaudy
John Butler Anthony Salter Aldermen The Sheriffes for the time being Nicholas Isaacke John Acland Thomas
Walker Stephen Olifue John Gibbons Merchants John Bidgood Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Henry Walker Thomas Shapcot
Samuell Isaake Gentlemen and The Receivor of the Citty for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s17">
		<head>Dorset</head>
		<para id="p80">For the County of Dorset John Lord Digby sonne and heire apparent to George Earle of Bristoll Sir Edward
Nicholas one of his Majestyes most honourable Privy Councill Sir William Portman Knight and Baronet Sir John
Morton Sir Gerrard Napper Baronets Sir Richard Strode Sir John Strangwayes Sir Walter Earle Sir Ralph Banks
Sir Francis Holles Knights Sir John Nicholas Knight of the Bath Sir John Fitz James Sir John Rogers Sir Nathaniell
Napper Knights Giles Strangwayes Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Strode Sir John Lowe Sir Winston Churchhill Knights Hugh
Windham Sergeant at Law Thomas Freake of Shroton John Strangwayes John Tregonwell of Milton. John Tregonwell
of Anderson Thomas Trenchard Thomas Fownes Humphrey Bishop John Rives of Damree John Churchill James
Gould Henry Whitaker Bullen Reymes Henry Henly Robert Swayne Sheriffe Robert Coker Edward Hooper
George Fulford Robert Lawrence Thomas Baynard Henry Eyers Henry Hastings Esquiers, Collonell Francis Windham
Mathew Davis John Rieves William Thomas John Hoskins George Hussey Robert Naper William Ogden Henry
Butler George Savage John Saintlow George Gray Robert Seymour Maximilian Mohun George Browne Wolley
Miller Anthony Etricke Michaell Harvey George Trenchard Robert Tyderligh William Floyer John Ironside John
Gould of Upway John Mitchell Peter Hoskins John Abington John Jeffery George Strangewayes John Harden
John Every Arthur Fookes John Hardy William Ellesdon Thomas Hussey Thomas Thornex. Richard Greene
George Stile William Chaldecot George Johnson John Bennet and John Runnet Esquiers.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s18">
		<head>Poole</head>
		<para id="p81">For the Towne and County of Poole Sir John Morton Baronet Sir John Fitz-James Knight Anthony Etricke
Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Peter Hall Maior William Skutt Robert Lewen Gentlemen Robert Cleeves Peter Hily Edward
Man and Samuell Bramble</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s19">
		<head>Durham</head>
		<para id="p82">For the County Palatine of Durham Sir Thomas Davison High Sheriffe of the County Sir Francis Goodricke
Temporall Chauncellour of the County Palatine Do&bholigct;or Burwell Chauncellour of the Diocesse of Durham Sir Christopher
Conyers Sir Nicholas Cole Sir Gilbert Gerrard Knights and Baronets Sir James Clavering Baronet Sir Francis
Anderson Sir William Blakiston Knights John Health John Swinburn John Tempest Ralph Carr Es?rs Baron
Hilton Henry Lambton Es&bhoqesq; James Darcy John Eden Collonell Anthony Byerly Ralph Davison Ralph Cole Major
Bellasis Samuell Davison Cuthbert Carr William Blakiston Thomas Shalforth Charles Gerard Thomas Fetherstonhagh
Lodowicke Hall Es?rs, The Maior of the Citty of Durham for the time being Thomas Swinburne Es&bhoqesq; Gabriell
Jackson John [Morland John<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Arden Miles Stapleton Gentleman and Captaine Henry Barnes Thomas Haggerston
Es&bhoqesq; and John Gray of Moreton Gent for Norham and Islandshire.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s20">
		<head>Essex</head>
		<para id="p83">For the County of Essex Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the House of Commons Sir Harbotle Grimstone Baronet Master of the Rolls Robert Lord Willoughby of Earsby sonne and heire apparent to Mountague Earle of Lindsey Lord Great Chamberlaine of England Robert Bertie Edward Russell Banestree Maynard Esquiers Sir John Barrington Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Apleton Sir William Ayloffe Sir William Hicks Sir Andrew
Jennour Sir William Wiseman Sir Richard Everard Baronets Sir Capell Luckin Knight and Baronet Sir Martin
Lumley Baronet Sir Thomas Abdy [Sir Robert Abdy<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Sir William Wiseman Knights and Baronets Sir Thomas Smith Sir Thomas Cambell Baronets Sir James Altham Sir John Brampston Knight of the Bath Sir John Tyrrell Sir Erasmus De la fountaine Sir Thomas Bowes Sir Cranmer Herris Sir Henry Clarke Sir Edmond Pierce one of the Masters of the Chauncery Sir Anthony Browne Sir Richard Wiseman Sir William Battin Sir John Shaw Sir Robert Brooke Sir Richard Everard Sir Thomas Litleton Sir Robert Barrington Si Thomas Gardner Sir Moundeforde Brampston Sir William Glascocke two, of the Masters of the Chauncery Sir Thomas Fanshaw Sir Thomas Bide Sir William Hicks Sir Edward Beaucocke Knights John Bendish Charles Fitch Gamaliel Capell Richard Samms Thomas Meade Peter Soame John Tyrrell Thomas Argoll Oliver Reymond John Atwood Henry Woolaston Henry Pert John Eldred senior John Eldred Junior John Paschall John Godbolt Robert Joselyn William Glascocke
Tristram Conyers Thomas Luther William Umphrevill Thomas Roberts John James George Pert William Colecroft
William Webb Robert Leigh William Apleton John Berners Robert Clarke John Turner Richard Kirkby Carew
Harvy Mild may Robert Cheeke Francis Brampstone Edward Bullocke Stephen Smith Robert Mildmay Henry
Wight Gilbert Pierce. Hare of Lee James Norfolke Cutbert Martin Thomas Talcot Es?rs Philip Eldred
Henry Ayloffe George James Thomas King William Harris John Thorowgood William Palmer Richard Stanse
Alexander Prescot Thomas Legate John Sorrell Edward Glascocke William Ashley Gentlemen Thomas Wharton
Anthony Maxie and Thomas Garret Esq[ui]rs Anthony Knightbridge of Writle Gen&bhocent; Captaine Richard Stains Sir
Richard Browne Knight and Baronet and Jeremy Lacy.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s21">
		<head>Colchester</head>
		<para id="p84">For the Towne of Colchester The Maior for the time being Sir John Shaw Knight Recorder Sir Edmond Pierce
Knight Gilbert Pierce Thomas Talcot Esq[ui]rs Thomas Reynalds Andrew Fromanteel Henry Lamb Robert Legg
William Moore Aldermen John Robinson George Sandford James Norffolke Esq[ui]rs and Thomas Creffeild Alderman.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s22">
		<head>Maldon</head>
		<para id="p85">For the Towne of Maldon The Bayliffes for the time being Reuben Robinson Samuell Plumbe Francis Gourney
James Starling John Hart Aldermen and Bartholimew Brickewood.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s23">
		<head>Harwich</head>
		<para id="p86">For the Towne of Harwich The Maior for the time being Sir Capell Luckin Baronet George Colman Richard
Fuller Henry Wright Aldermen Gerard Daniell Smith Thomas King Anthony Woolward Samuell
Newton and Miles Hobart Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s24">
		<head>Gloucester</head>
		<para id="p87">For the County of Gloucester Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland sonne and heire apparent to Edward Marquesse of
Worcester James Earle of Newburgh in the Kingdome of Scotland John Viscount Scudamore of the Kingdome of
Ireland John Viscount Tracy of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Mathew Hale Knight Lord Cheife Baron of his
Majestyes Court of Exchequer Sir Henry Capell Knight of the Bath Sir Baynham Throckemorton Knight and
Baronet Sir Henry Fredericke Thynne Sir William Ducy Sir Richard Ashfeild Sir Edward Bathurst Sir Robert
Jenkinson Sir John Howe Sir Christopher Guise Sir Edward Fulse Sir William Keyte Sir Richard Cox Baronet Sir
William Moreton Knight one of his Majestyes Sergeants at Law Sir Robert Pointz Sir Robert Atkins Knights of the
Bath Sir William Catchmay Sir Edmond Bray Sir Edward Massey Sir Thomas Stephens Sir Thomas Overbury Sir
Gabriell Lowe Sir John Newton Sir Humphrey Howke Sir Thomas Howe Knights John Grubham Howe Es&bhoqesq; Evan
Seyes Sergeant at Law Francis Baber Do&bholigct;or of Law George Mountague William Button William Cooke John
Chamberlaine John Stephens William Cope John Codrington Richard Atkins Henry Powle William Selwin Buncombe
[Colchester<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Hen Benedicte Hall Thomas Masters Thomas Escourt John George John Smith Richard Stephens William
Morgan Edward Rich Andrew Barker Richard Whitmore William Stafford John Winter Fleetewood Dorner Samuell
Codrington Thomas Chester Henry Syms Philip Shepheard Richard Sackevile Giles Fettiplace Thomas Thynne
Robert Pleydall Thomas James Williams Stratford Richard Dowdeswell Miles Rutter Thomas Horton Silvanus Wood
William Leigh Francis Norwood David Williams John Berrow Thomas Seymour William Try William Bourchier
Charles Cox John Guyse Richard Berkley Richard Daston William Jones Robert Oldesworth Richard Baugh John
Robbins Thomas Marriot Esquiers Thomas Riche William Hinson William Lawrence William Dowdeswell Henry
Browne Robert Heydon Nicholas Veale John Wyniat Thomas Walle William Thorpe John Driver Conway
Whitterne William Winter Richard Machen John Coles Thomas Ayleway James Hawkins Christopher Woodward
and the Bayliffes of Tewkesbury for the time being Anthony Sambich William Batson Sir John Baker Knight William
Stafford junior.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s25">
		<head>Citty of Gloucester</head>
		<para id="p88">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland sonne and heire apparent
of Edward Marquesse of Worcester Robert Fielding the present Maior and the Maior for the time being Sir William
Moreton Knight one of his Majesties Sergeants at Law Recorder of the said Citty Sir Edward Massey Knight Evan
Seyes Sergiant at Law John Grubham Howe Edward Nurse Thomas Williams Esq[ui]rs Henry Cugley James Stephens
William Russell John Powell Thomas Yate Thomas Price John Woodward Anthony Arnold Henry Ockold John
Wagstaffe and Henry Fowler Aldermen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s26">
		<head>Hereford</head>
		<para id="p89">For the County of Hereford Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland sonne and heire apparent to Edward Marquesse of
Worcester John Lord Viscount Scudamore of the Kingdome of Ireland James Scudamore Wallop Brabazon Esquiers
Sir James Bridges Sir John Kerle Sir William Powell Sir Thomas Morgan Baronets Sir Thomas Hanbury Knight,
Sir Edward Harley Knight of the Bath Sir John Scudamore Baronet Sir [Herbet<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Perrot Knight Sir Edward Hopton
Sir Thomas Tomkins Sir Job Charleton Knights Fitz-William Conisby Thomas Cornwall Thomas Whitney Herbert
Aubrey senior John Price senior Thomas Price Walter Pye Roger Vaughan Herbert Westfaling Herbert Aubrey
junior John Scudamore senior Humphrey Cornwall John Scudamore junior John Barnaby de Canon Pyon Reynald
Graham Thomas Cox Edward Cornwall John Skippe Bennet Hoskins Richard Hopton Giles Bridges Thomas Geers
Thomas Carpenter John Hoskins de Harewood Humphrey Howorth William Gregory Francis Unett John Hanford
Humphrey Baskervill John Birch, John Barnaby de Brockehampton John Vaughan John Booth de Hereford Thomas
Harley Ambrose Elton Robert Pye Rudhale Gwilline Richard Wigmore John Nourse Nicholas Walwin William
Whittington Thomas Rodd John Booth de Braynton Thomas Wigmor William Westfaling Robert Rodd Richard
Reede Timothy Coles Williams Bridges Henry Milbourne Herbert Masters William Brome John Dancy John Gwyllim
de Wellington Richard Walwyn de Hellens Humphrey Taylor de Withington John Kidley de Bromley Thomas
Marret de Kings Capell Thomas Gomond de Kilpecke George Carver de Buthouse Esq[ui]rs The Bayliffe for the Burrough
of Leominster for the time being John Tomkins Richard Rodd de Rodd Edward Rodd Thomas Blaney Edward
Freeman Thomas French and Thomas Duppa de Earsley Esquiers.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s27">
		<head>Citty of Hereford</head>
		<para id="p90">For the Citty of Hereford Robert Symonds Es&bhoqesq; the present Maior and the Maior for the time being John Lord
Viscount Scudamore in the Kingdome of Ireland Roger Vaughan Herbert Westfaling Thomas Price Esq[ui]rs William
Gregorie Richard Philpotts William Phillips James Lawrence Thomas Homes Thomas Painard Thomas Bond William
Edwin Aldermen Edward Alderne Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Edward Rodd Nicholas Philpotts John Smith Mercer Hugh
Rodd Thomas Symonds Roger Boulcot and John Barnes Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s28">
		<head>Hertford</head>
		<para id="p91">For the County of Hertford Sir Edward Turner Speaker of the House of Commons Thomas Lord Viscount
Fanshaw of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Thomas Fanshaw Knight of the Honourable Order of the Bath William
Cecill Algernoun Cecill William Willoughby Esq[ui]rs Sir Harbotle Grimston: Baronet Master of the Rolls Sir Edward
Atkins one of the Barons of his Majestyes Court of Exchequer Sir Thomas Leventhorpe Sir Brocket Spencer Sir
Jonathan Keate Sir Erasmus Harby Sir Thomas Allen Baronets Sir Richard Atkins Sir Richard Francklin Sir Richard
Lucy Knights and Baronets Sir Philip Boteler Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Dacres Sir John Harrison Sir Francis
Boteler Sir Henry Cesar Sir William Godbold Sir Rowland Litton Sir John Gore Sir Harry Conisby Sir John Watts
Sir Henry Blunt Sir Humphrey Gore Sir John Hale Sir William Glascocke Sir Robert Joselyne Sir Richard Combe
Sir Walter Walker Knights Thomas Dockwra James Willimot Richard Goulstone Thomas Dacres Edward Wingate
John Coping Arthur Bolter Thomas Stanley John Heydon Robert Ashton William Glascocke William Hale Arthur
Sparkes John Fotherly Crafts of Northall John Halsey William Harbord John Jesson Edward Atkins
William Cotton Albon Cox John Briscoe Ralph Freeman senior Robert Hobotham Richard Jenings Edmond Smith
Robert Sadler Henry Chauncy Ralph Freeman junior Humphrey Shalcrosse Henry Guy William Nuce Thomas Offley
Henry Dunstar Alexander Meade Richard Gammon Esquiers Edward Cason George Needham Ralph Gore Henry
Beecher Marmaduke Roydon Edward Briscoe George Bromeley John Ellis Edmond Field William Greenhill Edward
Crosby Alexander Weild Gentlemen Captaine William Minoes Thomas Arris Robert Deane Do&bholigct;ors of Phisicke and
the Maior of Hertford for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s29">
		<head>S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albans</head>
		<para id="p92">For the Burrough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albans Algernon Cecil Es&bhoqesq; Sir Harbotle Grimstone Master of the Rolles Sir Richard
Franklin Sir Harry Conisby Sir Richard Combe Sir John Whittwrong Knights The Maior for the time being John
Simpson Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Robert Robotham Edmond Smith Thomas Dockwra Robert Sadler Richard Jenings William
Cotton John Jesson Alban Cox Esq[ui]rs Thomas Arris Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Thomas Cowley senior Thomas Cowley junior
William Marston Thomas Oxton Edward Eames John Gape John New and Robert New Aldermen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s30">
		<head>Huntington</head>
		<para id="p93">For the County of Huntington Charles Lord le de Spencer sonne and heire apparent to Mildmay Earle of
Westmerland Robert Viscount Mandevill sonne and heire apparent to Edward Earle of Manchester Lord Chamberlaine
of his Majestyes Household Sir Francis Compton Knight George Mountague Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Cotton Sir John Hewet
Sir Thomas Proby Sir Robert Bernard Baronets Stephen Anderson John Stone John Bernard Henry Williams Robert
Appreece Lyonell Waldon Nicholas Johnson Sutton Ashfeild Nicholas. Peadly Lawrence Torkenton John Heron
Robert Paine Anthony South Richard Elmes Thomas Rouse Richard Nailer Jasper Trice Gerard Cater John Ferrer
Richard Wynne Esq[ui]rs Thomas Colestone Thomas Shepherd William Sparrow Gentlemen, and Thomas Walwin Maior
of Huntington.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s31">
		<head>Towne of Huntington</head>
		<para id="p94">For the Towne of Huntington The Maior for the time being Robert Viscount Mandevill sonne and heire apparent
to Edward Earle of Manchester Lord Chamberlaine of his Majestyes Household Sir John Cotton Baronet Sir Robert
Bernard Henry Williams Lyonell Waldon Nicholas Pedley Esq[ui]rs Richard Astre Lawrence Torkinton John Barnard
Richard Weaver Thomas Judson and James Faireside Aldermen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s32">
		<head>Kent</head>
		<para id="p95">For the County of Kent Charles Lord Buckhurst sonne and heire apparent to Richard Earle of Dorset Philip
Viscount Strangford in the Kingdome of Ireland James Herbert John Tufton Richard Tufton Esq[ui]rs Sir Thomas
Twisden one of the Justices of the Kings Bench Sir Heneage Finch his Majestyes Sollicitor Generall Sir Thomas
Peyton Sir Roger Twisden Sir Edward Hales Sir Edward Monins Sir Henry Palmer Sir John Rivers Sir John Sydley
Sir William Meredith. Sir Edward Deering Sir Thomas Stile Sir Oliver Boteler Sir Norton Knatchbull Sir Peter
Heyman Sir John Tufton Sir John Reyney Sir Richard Hardres Sir Henry Wood Sir Robert Hales Sir Brazill Dixwell
Sir William Ducy Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir William Wilde Sir Stephen Leonard Sir Humphrey Miller Sir Edward
Honywood Sir John Marsham Sir John Bankes Sir Robert Barnham Baronets Sir Nathaniell Powell Sir Robert Austin
Sir John Seyliard Sir John Wroth Sir Jonathan Keale Baronets Sir George Sonds Knight of the Bath Sir John Mennes
Comptroller of his Majestyes Navy Sir Robert Honywood Sir Anthony Aucher Sir Isaac Sydley Sir William Man
Sir Thomas Godfrey Sir Richard Sandys Sir Thomas Engham Sir Arnold Braems Sir Henry Oxenden Sir Edward
Master Sir George Juxon Sir William Brodnax Sir John Darrell Sir Thomas Scot Sir Francis Clarke Sir Edward
Filmore Sir Thomas Culpeper Sir Theophilus Biddolph Sir Richard Betenson Sir William Leech Sir Edmond Pierce
Sir William Boreman Sir Bernard Hyde Sir William Swan Sir Anthony Bateman Sir Walter Vane Sir John Heath
Attourney of the Dutchy Sir Thomas Lee Sir William Hugeson Sir William de Laune Knights Sir William Cage
Knight Thomas Broome Sergeant at Law Silus Titus Groome of his Majestyes Bedchamber Thomas Hardresse
Recorder of the Citty of Canterbury Captaine John Stroude Leiutenant of Dover Castle John Boyes of Fredvill
Richard Master Thomas Culpeper of Hackington Thomas Peke Thomas Crispe of Queux Walter Braems Thomas
Brodnax Edward Master Thomas Turner William Rooke John Boyes of Hoade John Best John Cason Henry Oxenden
of Brooke Richard Aldworth Esquires Do&bholigct;or John Sabin Herbert Randolph Gentleman Nicholas Toke Henry
Thornehill John Knatchbull James Brockeman Maurice Diggs Henry Deereing Edward Hales Richard Hulse John
Nayler Esq[ui]rs Robert Lewkenor Peter Heymon John Moyle Zouch Brockman John Nowrs Gentlemen Thomas Flud
William Cage Francis Barnham Maximilion Dallison Fardinando Marsham Demetrius James George Curteis Thomas
Knatchbull Richard Wilkinson John Munn Ralph Bufkin Walter Francklin Richard Marsh Thomas English Robert
Oliver John Smith Thomas [Harlaken<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Henry Haughton Alabaster Fludd Francis Twisden Captaine John Clerke
Thomas Lake Recorder of Maidstone Richard Duke William Maddox Esq[ui]rs The Maior of Rochester for the time
being Richard Allen Recorder of Rochester George Newman Richard. Manley George May Richard Head Charles
Bickerstaffe Robert Fowler Francis Barrell Esq[ui]rs Stephen Alcocke Senior; Thomas Manley Gentleman Lawrence
Rooke Thomas Brewer Robert [Masters<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Samuell Boyes William Boyes Thomas Culpeper of Bedgebury Edward Finch
John Horsemanden Anthony Fowle Robert Fowle John Hugeson John Bunce Thomas Lambert David Polhill Philip
Packer George Polhill Henry Gilburne William Hooker John Scott Marke[Kottle<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] John Hyde Norton Curteis Robert
Heath Francis Heath John Austin John Evelin William Swann John Seyliard Nicholas Tooke senior James Fortrey
Nicholas Tooke junior William Boothby Christopher Allanson Bevin Thomas Manning Petley
John Bridger Farnaby Edward Badby John Sedley Esq[ui]rs James Thurbarne Gentleman and George
Bowerman Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Henden Knight William Campion William Hammon John Andrewes Edward [Culstone<ref idref="n16">16</ref>]
Reynald Peckham Esq[ui]rs The Maior of Sandwich for the time being Tobias Cleere Phineas Elwood John Verier
Valentine Jekin Jeoffrey Wells Jeoffrey Sacked The Maior of Dover for the time being Richard Jacob Nicholas
Eaton. William Eaton John Watson John Loome Richard Barley Walter Braems Esq[ui]rs The Maior of Rumney
for the time being Robert Wivill Jeremy Stanford Stephen Brett Thomas Chalcrosse The Maior of [Heath<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] for
the time being John Finch James Pashley The Maior of Feversham for the time being John Trouts Es&bhoqesq; John
Upton Robert Watson Thomas Southhouse The Maior of Tenderden, for the time being Edward Finch Es&bhoqesq; Captaine
Plomer Thomas Short The Bayliffe of Lydd for the time being John Bateman Thomas Beddingfeild Michael Chidwicke
The Maior of Folkestone for the time being The Maior of Fordwitch, for the time being Thomas Bigg William
Norton senior Thomas Norton junior Esq[ui]rs and John Luckin.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s33">
		<head>Canterbury</head>
		<para id="p96">For the Citty of Canterbury The Maior for the time being Sir William Man Sir Edward Master Knights Thomas
Hardresse Es&bhoqesq; Recorder of the said Citty John Best Edward Master Squire Beverton Esq[ui]rs William Stanley Henry
Twiman Avery Hills and Leonard Browne Aldermen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s34">
		<head>Lancaster</head>
		<para id="p97">For the County of Lancaster Charles Earle of Ancram in the Kingdome of Scotland William Stanley William
Spencer Esq[ui]rs Sir Richard Houghton Sir George Midleton Sir Robert [Binlosse<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] Sir Edward Stanley Sir Edward Mosely
Sir Ralph Ashton of Whaley Sir Ralph Ashton of Midleton Baronets Sir Gilbert Ireland Sir Roger Bradsheigh Sir
Henry Slater, Sir Jeoffrey Shakerley Sir John Heath Knights John Mollineux Richard Kirby Roger [Fowell<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Edward
Fleetewood Henry Banistre William Farrington Robert Holt Lawrence Rawstorne Hugh Dickenson William Redleigh
Nicholas Townley John Parker Nathaniell West Thomas Preston John Girlington Daniell Fleming Robert Rawlinson
Jeofrey Rishton Alexander Osbaldiston Alexander Rigby of Midleton John Lightboune Edward Rigby Francis Lindley
Thomas Bradell Christopher Parker Thomas Norres Richard Legh Richard Penington Richard Fleetewood of Rossell
Thomas Butler Nicholas Mossley John Halsted of Bankehouse Major John Byrom Robert Heywood James Duckenfield
Mathew Richardson Peers Legh John Entwisley John Risley Cuthbert Ogle Henry Houghton John Birch of
Ordsdall Bartholimew Hesketh Captaine Byrom Thomas Ashton George Hilton Henry Porter Thomas Carus William
Fife Thomas [Greenehagh<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Thomas Holt junior Roger Keynon William Daniell Peter Adlington Ambrose Pudsay
Thomas Ashhurst William Kirkby William Banckes junior Richard Leigh Esquiers John Ainsworth Thomas Leigh
Nicholas Fezakerly Captaine Brabin Captaine Longworth Nicholas Penington William Wall Seth Blackhurst James
Hodgkinson Joseph Rigby Luck Hodgkinson Ralph Mercer Alexander Woodward Alexander Rigby of Layton John
Tatlocke Gentleman Edward Dobson Es&bhoqesq; The Maior of Wiggan for the time being The Maior of Lancaster for
the time being, The Maior of Leverpoole for the time being The Maior of Preston for the time being John
Chaundler Gen&bhocent;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s35">
		<head>Leicester.</head>
		<para id="p98">For the County of Leicester Thomas Lord Beaumont of the Kingdome of Ireland John Lord Roos sonne and heire
apparent to John Earle of Rutland Bennet Lord Sherard of the Kingdome of Ireland John Grey Es&bhoqesq; Sir George
Villers Sir Erasmus De la Fountaine Sir Thomas Halford Sir Thomas Cave Sir Jeofrey Palmer Sir Woostan Dixie
Sir Henry Hudson Sir George Prettyman Baronets Sir William Hartop Sir John Health Knights John Crew Philip
Shererd Henry Neville George Faunt Thomas Menye Mathew Babington William Noell William Boothby Samuell
Jarvis John Fountaine Walter Rudings Thomas Armstone Roger Roe William Whalley Richard Brudenell William
Roberts Captaine Burton William Hartop Richard Orton John Needham of Osbaston John Morton Thomas Bradgate
Richard Bradgate William Streete William Halford John Turville William Belgrave John Needham William Skevington
John Hacket Thomas Staveley George Ashby Richard Verney John Cave Stanhope Whalley William Leeke John
Danvers Thomas Bennet William Bent Roger Smith William Trimnall Henry Farnham Francis Chamberlaine Robert
Barnard John Barwell Henry Bigland Neale Hewet William Cole Esq[ui]rs.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s36">
		<head>Leicester</head>
		<para id="p99">For the Burrough of Leicester William Callis Maior of Leicester Sir John Prittyman Baronet Sir William Hartopp
Knight Walter Rudeings Es&bhoqesq; Richard Palmer Richard Lincolne Alexander Cortes Thomas Freeman Thomas Overing
Thomas Browne Daniell Abney John Francks Francis Noble Gen&bhocent; and Thomas Staveley Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s37">
		<head>Lincolne</head>
		<para id="p100">For the County of Lincolne and Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne George Lord Viscount Castleton of
the Kingdome of Ireland Robert Lord Willoughby of Earsby sonne and heire apparent to Mountague Earle of
Lindsey Lord Great Chamberlaine of England William Mountague William Pierpoint Esq[ui]rs Sir Philip Tyrwhitt Sir
Edward Barkham Sir Humphrey Winch Sir Henry Massingbord Baronets Sir Francis Goodricke Sir John Moreton
Sir Charles Dallison Knights Philip Tyrwhitt Henry Fines William Metham William Marwood George Sanderson John
Ogle Edward Merberie Esq[ui]rs William Willoughby Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Mounson senior Sir John Bolles Sir Williams Hickman
Sir Robert Dallison Sir Edward Lake Sir John Anderson Baronets Sir John Mounson junior Knight of the Bath Sir
Thomas Meeres Knight Charles Pelhani senior Edward Tourney, senior Cecill Turwhitt William Godfrey William
Brownlow George Healey William Anderson John Farmery of Northrop Edward Tourney junior John Stow Es?rs
Sir Henry Bellasis Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Bernardiston Sir William Wray Sir George Winne Baronets Sir
Edward Rositer Sir Edward Aiscough Knights Charles Pelham junior Jarvis Holles Master of Requests William
Wentworth William Broxholme Marmaduke Dorrell junior William Bard Alexander Emerson John Nelthorp John
Boswell Charles Newcomen Esq[ui]rs Sir Thomas Ellis Baronet Sir Adrian Scroope Knight of the Bath Sir Martin Lister
Sir Robert Christopher Knights John South John Bolles William Fitz-Williams John Hanby Isaac Knight Charles
Radley William Woley William Ballet senior Robert Long Thomas Ely Dimocke Walpoole George Osney Henry
Midlemore Esq[ui]rs Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath George Sherard Es?r Sir Thomas Hussey Sir William Thorold
Sir John Newton Sir Richard Rothwell Baronets Sir John Walpoole Knight Charles Dymocke Lewis Palmer Anthony
Thorold Mollineux Disney Christopher Nevill Richard Brownlow Thomas Ellis William Lister John Hobson Richard
Riley Thomas Pechell Stephen Rothwell John Wilson Henry Stone Anthony Williams William Thornton William
Rivett Esquiers Robert Laming John Colthurst John Trafford Gentlemen Sir Michaell Armin Sir John Brownlow Sir
Robert Markham Sir William Brownlow Sir William Trollop Sir John Bucke Baronets Sir Thomas Orpe Sir
Christopher Clapham Knights Thomas Hatcher William Stafford Erasmus de Ligne John Hatcher Thomas Harrington
William Blyth John Saunders William Saville Edward Skipwith Francis Wingfeild Thomas Trollop Adam Cleypoole
Philip Dalloe Thomas Skipwith William Hyde William Trollop William Welby Lister Tiegh Esq[ui]rs Robert Garland
Gentleman Thomas Grantham Peregrine Berley Sir Anthony Oldfeild Baronet Sir Henry Heron Knight of the Bath
Sir Anthony Irby Sir Robert Carr Knights Sir William Humble Baronet Sir John Browne Knight Thomas Thory
Thomas Hall John Jay Charles Skipwith John Lockton Esq[ui]rs Thomas Browne Gentleman Mathew Woolmer Anthony
Oldfeild Esq[ui]rs John Empson Esquire Joseph Whiteing Charles Rushworth Samuell Jackson Anthony Hall Do&bholigct;or
Sturton Richard Balder Robert Bisle William Dickenson Gentlemen Adlard Welby David. Bonnel Esq[ui]rs John [Jelson<ref idref="n21">21</ref>]
Daniell Rhodes George Caverne Henry Morley Israel Jackson Gentlemen Thomas Marham Do&bholigct;or Richer Robert
Melish Esq[ui]rs Richard Milner Gen&bhocent; The Maior of the Citty of Lincolne for the time being and the fewer senior
Aldermen viz William Bishop Edward Blowe Richard Wetherell Robert Wrose The Maior and the three senior
Aldermen of Boston viz John Ellis George Slee Samuell Beeston The Maiors of Stamford and Great Grimsby and
the Alderman of Grantham for the time being Do&bholigct;or Thomas Saunderson William Perkins and Richard Leeming
Daniell Thorowgood Richard Butcher George Hill Gentlemen John Humphreyes Es&bhoqesq; Charles Bawds, Stephen Mason
Esquiers Samuell Burton John Wimberley Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s38">
		<head>London</head>
		<para id="p101">For the Citty of London Sir John Lawrence Knight, Lord Maior and the Lord Maior for the time being Sir
Thomas Adams Sir Richard Browne Sir Thomas Alleyn Sir John Robinson Sir William Wilde Recorder Knights
and Baronets Sir Richard Chiverton Sir John Fredericke Sir Anthony Bateman Sir Thomas Soame Sir Thomas
Bludworth Sir William Bolton Sir William Peeke Sir William Turner Sir Richard Ford Sir Richard Reeves
Sir William Thompson Sir Theophilus Biddolph Sir John Shaw Sir William Wale Knights Francis Meynell Samuell
Sterling Robert Hanson William Hooker. Thomas Boufoy Roger Hatton Nicholas Boufoy John Bence Richard
Shelbury Aldermen and the Aldermen and Recorder of the said Citty for the time being George Waterman Charles
Doe Sheriffes and the Sheriffes for the time being John Jones John Jolliffe Thomas Turgis Henry Dunstar Walter
Lap Esq[ui]rs James Abernoite</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s39">
		<head>Midlesex</head>
		<para id="p102">[For the County of Middlesex<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons Sir
Thomas Ingram Chauncellour of the Dutchy of Lancaster Hugh Lord Colraigne in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir
Orlando Bridgeman Cheife Justice of the Common Pleas Henry Lord Cornebury sonne and heire apparent to
Edward Earle of Clarendon Lord Chauncellour of England Edward Russell George Mountague Christopher Hatton
Thomas Coventry William Mounrague Robert Spencer Henry Seymour Esq[ui]rs Sir Henry Bennet Principall Secretary
of State John Ashburnham Es&bhoqesq; one of his Majestyes Bedchamber Edward Progers Es&bhoqesq; one of his Majestyes
Bedchamber Thomas Elliot Es&bhoqesq; one of his Majestyes Bed-chamber Sir Harbotle Grimstone Baronet Master of the
Rolls Sir Heneage Finch Knight and Baronet his Majestyes Sollicitor Generall Sir Gilbert Gerard Sir Thomas Fisher
Sir Henry Wood Sir John Robinson Sir Jeremy Whichcot Sir William Waller Sir Richard Franklin Sir Joseph
Ash Sir Reignald Foster Sir William Roberts Sir Hugh Smithson Baronets Sir John Brampston Sir Robert Atkins
Sir John Bennet Knights of the Bath Sir Henry Herbert Sir Thomas. Allen Sir Nicholas Crispe Sir Thomas Roe
Sir William Bateman Sir Lancelot Lake Sir Henry Wroth Sir Francis Gerard Sir John Glyn Sir John Mainard
Sir John Heath Attourney of the Dutchy Sir Winston Churchill Sir John Cropley Sir Charles Harbord Sir Robert
Hyde Lord Cheife Justice of the Kings Bench Sir Edmond Boyer Sir Thomas Clergyes Sir James Smith Sir Ellis
Leighton Sir Thomas Player junior Sir Thomas Byde Sir William Ryder Sir Clifford Clifton, Sir Gilbert Gerard
of Harrow Sir Gilbert Gerard of S<emph type="p">t</emph> James Sir John Nicholas Sir Philip Warwicke Sir Christopher Eyres Sir John
Birkenhead one of his Majestyes Masters of Requests Sir Cirill Wich Sir Robert Carr Sir Edmond Barker Sir John
Colliton Sir Edmond Pierce Sir Justinian Lewin Sir Thomas Escourt Sir Edward Wingfield Sir Henry Vernon Sir
Paul Painter Knights William Ashburnham Cofferer of his Majestyes Household Sergiant [Wynham<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Sergiant Waller Charles Cornwallis Humphrey Welde Francis Crawley Edmond Waller George Pitt Sydney Beere John Carey Henry Barker John Browne Edwin Rich Francis Bloomer Joseph Ayloffe Thomas Swallow Richard Peacocke Charles Cheyne John Trevor Francis Phillips Robert Jacob William Hill John Heydon George Day George Marsh William Page Andrew Ellis John Page William Meggs Thomas Collet Ralph Hawtree Thomas Povey Giles
Hungerford Thomas Lake Richard Dunton James Hawley Erasmus Moise Charles Pitfeild Thomas Kendall Thomas
Harrison Thomas Wharton John Jones Henry Osborne John Smith William Gouldsborough Richard Abell John
Wilford David Walter Richard Cheney Richard Pro&bholigct;or James Norffolke John James John Fotherley William
Northey John Phillips Auditor Edmond Warcup Roger Jenings. Robert Childe William Marshall Thomas Ardin
Jasper Churchill Daniell Pro&bholigct;or John Baldwin William Bolles Walter Boothy Nicholas Ranton John Gouldsmith Henry Murrey John Hutchinson Edward Rich Robert Peyton Pawlet S<emph type="p">t</emph> John William Dormer Edmond Draper Do&bholigct;or William Quarterman Esq[ui]rs Sir Thomas Bird one of the Masters of Chauncery Sir Fredericke Hyde Sergeant at Law Robert Hanson Lestrange Colthrop Esq[ui]rs Sir Charles [Cotterer<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] Sir John Birkenhead Richard Atkins James
Hambleton one of his Majestyes Bedchamber Edward Trussell Maximilian Bard William Harpham Esq[ui]rs M<emph type="p">r</emph> Bathurst
of Edmonton John Layney John Pawlet M<emph type="p">r</emph> Wood of Litleton M<emph type="p">r</emph> Roberts of Hayes John Walker M<emph type="p">r</emph> Thomas
Dickinson of Hillingdon Robert Hampton Robert Shoreditch Gentlemen Captaine Harrington of Staynes Major
John Bill Michaell Holman Henry, Row Esq[ui]rs M<emph type="p">r</emph> Leigh of Greenford M<emph type="p">r</emph> Claxton of Sudbury M<emph type="p">r</emph> Briginshall of
Hayes M<emph type="p">r</emph> Chute of Wilsdon Thomas Nevet M<emph type="p">r</emph> Farrington of Southmims William Bockenham John Thorpe John
Norwood John Lloyd Gentlemen Sir Richard Napier Robert Napier Thomas Henshaw Griffith Bodurda Es?rs
Sir Thomas Thorowgood Knight Fredericke Cornewallis Francis Cornewallis and Henry Murrey Esq[ui]rs.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s40">
		<head>Westminster</head>
		<para id="p103">For the Citty of Westminster Thomas Lord Richardson Baron Cramond in the Kingdome of Scotland Sir William
Morrice Knight Principall Secretary of State Sir Henry Bennet Principall Secretary of State Sir Edward Nicholas Knight
one of his Majestyes Most Honourable Privy Councill George Mountague Es&bhoqesq; Sir Heneage Finch Knight and Baronet
His Majestyes Solliciter Generall Sir William Playters Baronet Sir Robert Longe Sir Lancelot Lake Sir Robert Pye Sir
Charles Harbord Sir Cerill Wich Knights Sir Edmond Pye Knight and Baronet Sir John Cotton Baronet Sir Henry
[Harbord<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] Sir John Nicholas Knight of the Bath Sir Philip Warwicke Sir Richard Everard Sir Edward Filmer Sir Allen Apsley Sir Henry Wood Sir Thomas Meeres Sir John Talbot Sir Charles Cotterell Sir Thomas Higgons Knights Sir Thomas Litleton Baronet Sir William Poultney Knight Sir John Bennet Knight of the Bath Sir William Wheeler Baronet Sir Thomas Clergies Knight Sir John Birkenhead one of his Majestyes Masters of Requests Sir William Clerke Sir Anthony Irby Sir Robert Howard Knights Sir Edward Greavers Baronet Sir John Baber Knight Sir John Collaton Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Broughton Baronet John Ashburnham Bernard Greenvile Stephen Fox Cecill Tufton John Trevor Sir Richard Oateley Reignald Graham Do&bholigct;or William Quarterman Esq[ui]rs Sir Theodore [le<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] Vaux Sir Hugh
Carteret Knights Collonell Whitley George Pitts Richard Newman M<emph type="p">r</emph> Dolbin Steward of Westminster Robert Scawen
John Browne Thomas Povey Richard Atkins Richard Mason Thomas Coppin William Glascocke Bullen Reymes
Edmond Bury Godfrey Francis Lucy Thomas Morrice Robert Filmer Mathew Locke Thomas Russell Edmond
Warcup John Sibley Thomas Russell Thomas Bayles William Harbord Richard Aldworth Simon Smith George
Farewell James Norffolke Humphrey Wyrley Francis Dorrington Charles Potts Butler Kinhead William Hamond
Henry Pecke Francis Cornwallis Anthony Cogan Edward Fauconbridge William Gape Emery Hill Roger Higgs
Peter Salmon Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke George Merryfield Job Williams Gentlemen Fredericke Cornwallis Charles
Cornwallis Esq[ui]rs Sir Thomas Bird Knight and John Clarke Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke in the Strand Andrew Ellis Esquire</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s41">
		<head>Monmouth</head>
		<para id="p104">For the County of Monmouth Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland sonne and heire apparent to Edward Marquesse
of Worcester William Lord Herbert of Cardiffe sonne and heire apparent to Phillip Earle of Pembrooke and
Mountgomery Sir Baynham Throckmorton Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Morgan Sir Trevor Williams Sir Thomas
Morgan Baronets Sir George Probert Knights William Morgan of Tredgar William Jones of Treowen Thomas Lewis
of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Pecre George Probert Edward Proger Edmond Morgan Charles Van Thomas Hughes Charles Hughes James
Herbert Charles Proger Herbert Henry Morgan William Morgan of Penkrike William Morgan of Grayes Inne
Thomas Morgan of Penrose Thomas Morgan of Lawrumney Herbert Evans William Herbert Charles Price Walter
Rumsey William Jones of Abergeny Henry Baker Philip Cicill Roger Williams Thomas Williams John Walter of
[Parfield<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] Roger Oates Walter Pritchard John Parry Nicholas Kemois James Pritchard Thomas Fritchard John Grenuffe
Edmond Jones John Arnold Esq[ui]rs Edward Williams John Lewis Henry Chambre Thomas Harbert Walter Jones
Walter Morgan Edward Kemeis of Partholy Capell Hanbury Christopher Perkins Roger Aldy Charles Griffith
William Williams of Lanfoist John Rumsey William Jones of Lansanfreed Gentlemen The Maior of the Towne of
Monmouth for the time being Andrew Probert John Gubb Gen&bhocent;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s42">
		<head>Northampton.</head>
		<para id="p105">For the County of Northampton Robert Viscount Mandeville sonne and heire apparent to Edward Earle of
Manchester Lord Chamberlaine of his Majestyes Household Obrian Viscount Cullen of the Kingdome of Ireland
Charles Lord le de Spencer sonne and heire apparent to Mildmay Earle of Westmerland William Lord Fitz-Williams
of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Francis Compton Knight George Mountague Christopher Hatton Sir Thomas Crew
Robert Spencer Es&bhoqesq; Sir Richard Rainsford one of the Barons of his Majestyes Exchequer Sir Jeofrey Palmer his
Majestyes Attourney Generall William Mountague Es&bhoqesq; the Queenes Attourney Generall Sir Justinian Isham Sir
Thomas Cave Sir Henry Yelverton Sir Samuell Danvers Sir Edward Nichols Sir Roger Norwich Sir John Robinson
Sir William Dudley Sir George Buswell Baronets Sir John Holman Baronet Sir Edward Griffin Sir William Fleetewood
Sir Samuell Jones Sir John Bernard Sir James Langham Sir Edward Alstone Knights John Beaumont Ferdinando
Marsham Lewis Palmer William Haslewood Henry Robinson of Cransley Miles Fleetewood George Clarke William
Stafford Francis Lane Goddard Pemberton John Browne Thomas Chubnall George Wake Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Lawrence
Manley William Chester William Sanders Thomas Trist Thomas Elmes Toby Chauncey Thomas Catesby Richard
Rainsford Samuell Trist William Washburne Humphrey Orme Maurice Tresham William Langham William Downhall
Philip Holman John Cartwright George Tresham William Tate Richard Kinsman Edward Onely John Syers Edward
Harby junior William Adams John Colly Richard Saltinstall Maximilian Emersly Foxley Edward Palmer
Robert Clarke William Buckby Henry Edmonds William Pargiter junior Tanfield Mulso Christopher Pickering Bryan
Janson Walter Kirkham Richard Benson Anthony Shugburgh Michaell Woodhall John Thornton Richard Nailer
John Willoughby John Bagshaw William Warner of Lubnam William Lisle Christopher Thursby Bernard Walcot
Andrew Lant Francis Morgan Alexander Eakins Thomas Roane Thomas Jennison William Ward John Lynn John
Delavall William Leavins Francis Kirkham Edmond Neale Nicholas Stewart John Gardiner John Wiseman Esq[ui]rs.
The Maior of Northampton for the time being Thomas Thornton John Brafield Francis Pickmere Joseph Sergeant
John Friend Hatton Farmer Joseph Hensman John Hughes The Maior of Higham for the time being The Bayliffe of
Daventree for the time being The Maior of Brackley for the time being Henry Lucas Samuell Clerke Thomas Dove
John Bourne Robert Pergiter of Greetworth Esq[ui]rs and Richard Butler of Preston Gen&bhocent;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s43">
		<head>Nottingham</head>
		<para id="p106">For the County of Nottingham and Towne and County of the same Henry Lord Viscount Mansfeild sonne and
heire apparent to William Marquesse of Newcastle Patricius Viscount Chaworth of the Kingdome of Ireland Gilbert
Lord Hughton sonne and heire apparent to John Earle of Clare William Willoughby [Ancitill<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] Grey William Pierpoint
Arthur Stanhop William Byron Esq[ui]rs Sir Jarvis Clifton Knight and Baronet Sir George Savile Baronet Sir Francis
Mollineux Knight and Baronet Sir William Hickman Sir Thomas Williamson Sir William Willoughby Baronets
Sir Francis Leake Knight and Baronet Sir John Digby Sir Ralph Knight Sir Clifford Clifton Knights Robert Pierpoint
Anthony Eyre John Grubham-How William Palmes Isham Perkins William Stanhope William Cartwright Charles
Hutchinson William Sacheverill Cicill Cooper John Cooper William Skeffington Penniston Whalley William Herbert
Anthony Gilby Francis Sands Francis Stringer William Clearkson Robert Mcllish George Nevill Arthur Wareing
John Rainer Thomas Charlton Clifton Rodes Thomas Marshall Rason Mellish Thomas Wowen John Moseley William
Byron Esq[ui]rs Robert Thoroton Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke George Cam William Newton James Lane Gentlemen The High
Sheriffe of the County of Nottingham for the time being, The Maior of Nottingham for the time being The Bayliffes
of East Ratford for the time being and The Maior of Newarke for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s44">
		<head>Norffolke</head>
		<para id="p107">For the County of Norfolke Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the House of Commons Thomas Lord
Richardson Baron Cramond of the Kingdome of Scotland Hatton Rich Es&bhoqesq; Sir Edmond Bacon Sir John Hobart
Sir Philip Woodhouse Sir Richard Berney Sir Henry Jernegan Sir Edward Barkham Sir Nicholas le Strange Sir John
Hollond Sir Robert Paston Sir John Palgrave Sir Ralph Hare Sir John Potts Sir Robert Kempe Sir Jacob Astley
Sir Edward Ward Sir Thomas Deerham Sir William Gaudy Sir William Cooke Sir William Doyley Baronets Sir
Miles Hobart Sir John Knivet Sir Edward Walpoole Sir Christopher Calthorpe Knights of the Bath Sir Charles
Harbord Sir. John Harrison Sir Thomas Guybon Sir Allan Apsley Sir William Hovell Sir Thomas Rant Sir Joseph
Pain Sir Thomas Meadow Sir William Hewit Sir Justinian Lewin Sir William Doyley Sir Robert Yallop Sir
Nevill Catelin Knights Thomas Townshend George Townshend John Bladwell Robert London Le Strange Caltharpe
Thomas Day Robert Kedington Robert Tyrrell of Wilton. Thomas Thursby Francis Thursby Samuell Harsenet
Leonard Gooch John Warner John Fisher Hatton Bernard John Bendish Gascoyne Weld of Braconash Thomas
Garret Es&bhoqesq; Erasmus Earle Sergiant at Law John Cooke Robert Tracy James de Grey John Hobart Thomas le
Grosse Edward Barkham Thomas Holland Augustine Palgrave John Potts William Coke Francis Bickley William
Adams Anthony Gaudy Phillip Herbert Roger Spilman Philip Harbor Maurice Shelton Peter Gleane Thomas Gaudy
of Claxton Thomas Berney of Swarson William Crane Anthony Freeston Robert Suckling John Windham William
Barker Robert Gawsell Henry Repps Oliver Neeve Phillip Beddingfield (<ref idref="n29">29</ref>) [Humphrey Beddingfeild<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] Francis Bacon
Thomas Bacon Robert Long Robert Baldoch Robert Stewart John Earle Francis Cory Christopher Jay Suckling
Jay Leonard Mapes Henry Clifton Clement Herne Nathaniell Showldham Richard Nixon Edmond Doyley John
Thughton John Cocke Thomas Browne of Elsing Thomas Cory John Kendall Lawrence Oxburgh John Shadwell
Robert Coney Robert Haughton Richard Godfrey John Anguish Anthony Fisher Edward Barber Thomas Drury
Nicholas Rookewood Anthony Drury Robert Drury Thomas Talbot Nicholas Stileman Jacob Preston Bassingbourne
Gaudy Charles Gaudy William Davy of Ellingham Nathaniell Knevet Edmond Britiffe Simon Britiffe Thomas Wright
of Kilverston Munford Spelman Edmond de Grey Thomas Wright of Ovington William Brampton and Robert
Buxton Gen&bhocent;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s45">
		<head>Kings Lynn</head>
		<para id="p108">For the Burrough of Kings Lynn The Maior for the time being Robert Steward Recorder Walter Kerby John
Basset Thomas Greene John Bird Benjamin Holly Henry Bell William Wharton Thomas Robinson.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s46">
		<head>Thetford</head>
		<para id="p109">For the Burrough of Thetford The Maior for the time being Sir John Holland and Sir William Gaudy Baronets
Sir Allan Apsley Knight Maurice Shelton Es&bhoqesq; John Kendall Robert Tyrrell Edmond Hunt Burrage Martin and
Osmond Clerke Gentlemen</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s47">
		<head>Great Yarmouth</head>
		<para id="p110">For the Burrough of Great Yarmouth The Bayliffes for the time being Sir Thomas Meadow Thomas Pufflet John
Cubitt Richard Jermin John Hall Abraham Castell Thomas Gooch Nathaniell Ashby John Row George England
John Woodroffe Edmond Thaxter Arthur Bacon Aldermen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s48">
		<head>For the Citty of Norwich</head>
		<para id="p111">The Maior for the time being. Sir Joseph Paine Knight Francis Cory Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Henry Watts John Rayley
Bernard Church John Man John Salter Christopher Jay Richard Wenman John Osborne John Croshold William
Haward Esq[ui]rs The two Sheriffes for the time being Augustine Briggs Thomas Wisse Robert Bendish Richard
Couldham John Larrance Henry Hirne Francis Norris Mathew Markham John Manser Henry Woods Henry Watts
junior Thomas Thacker Thomas Chickringe.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s49">
		<head>Northumberland</head>
		<para id="p112">For the County of Northumberland Henry Lord Viscount Mansfeild sonne and heire apparent to William Marquisse
of Newcastle Thomas Gray Ralph Gray Edward Widrington Esq[ui]rs Sir William Fenwicke Sir Ralph Delavall
Baronets Sir William Forster Sir Henry Widdrington Sir Francis Liddall Knights Edward Gray of Heaton Robert
Delavall Cuthbert Heron Ralph Gray of Bradford Thomas Forster of Etherston William Widrington William
Fenwicke of Beywell Ralph Heborn of Heborn John Clarke Robert Shafto of Benwell Ralph Jenison John Sockeld
the elder of Rocke Thomas Benwicke of the Closhouse. Daniell Collingwood of Branton Richard Stote William
Delavall of Benwicke John Rodham of Litle Houghton Nicholas Whitehead and Ralph Anderson Esq[ui]rs William
Warren and Michaell Widdrington of Morpeth Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s50">
		<head>For the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede</head>
		<para id="p113">Collonell Edward Grey The Maior for the time being Thomas Watson Andrew Moore Marke Armorer John
Duglas Aldermen and Anthony Afton Bayliffe</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s51">
		<head>For the Towne and County of Newcastle upon Tyne</head>
		<para id="p114">The Maior for the time being Sir John Marley and Sir Francis Anderson Knights John Clarke and Henry Brabant Es?rs.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s52">
		<head>Oxon</head>
		<para id="p115">For the County of Oxon Thomas Earle of Downe in the Kingdome of Ireland Henry Lord Viscount Cornbury
sonne and heire apparent to Edward Earle of Clarendon Lord Chauncellour of England Philip Lord Wenman Viscount
Tuam in the Kingdome of Ireland James Herbert John Lovelace Esq[ui]rs Sir Anthony Cope Sir Henry Lee Sir Thomas
Spencer Sir Thomas Penniston Sir William Walter Sir Anthony Craven Sir Thomas Clayton Warden of Merton
Colledge Sir Thomas Chamberlaine Sir Compton Reade Baronets Sir William Fleetewood Sir William Moreton One
of his Majesties Sergiants at Law Sir John Glyn one of his Majestyes, Sergiants at Law Sir Francis Wenman Sir
Edward Norris Sir Henry Jones Sir John Robinson Leiutenant of the Tower Sir Timothy Tyrrell Sir Thomas
Typping Sir John Clarke Sir Edmond Bray Sir George Croke Sir Litleton Osbaldiston Sir Robert Jenkinson Sir
Allan Apsley Sir William Glynn Sir Philip Harcourt Sir Thomas Cob Sir Samuell Jones Knights Sir Edward
Hungerford Knight of the Bath James Herbert John Lovelace David Walter one of the Groomes of his Majestyes
Bedchamber Lewellin Jenkins Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Principall of Jesus Colledge Broome Whorwood Richard Crooke
William Cope James Hide Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke President of Magdalin Colledge Thomas Willis Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke
Thomas Saunders Anthony Libb Vincent Barry Henry Alnut John Stone Francis Martin Edmond Lenthall John
Clarke William Lenthall William Legg one of the Groomes of his Majestyes Bedchamber William Dormer John
Cartwright George Chamberline Thomas Wheate William. Sheppard William Cartwright Rowland Lacy Arthur Jones
Henry Alworth Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Richard Holloway Counsell? at Law John Clitherow Gentleman Robert Dormer
Raynald Bray William Bayley Thomas Hord John Doyley Charles Holloway Sergiant at Law Charles Holloway
Thomas Coventry Mathew Skinner Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Samuell Sandys junior William Gamcocke Robert Vesey
Robert Perror junior Sheppard of Rosewright Edward Vernon John West William Oakeley Esq[ui]rs William
Wright and John Wickham Gentlemen The Maior of Woodstocke for the time being M<emph type="p">r</emph> Alexander Johnson The
Maior of Banbury The Warden of Henley The Bayliffes of Burford and Chiping-Norton and the Cheife Magistrates
to a&bholigct; in their severall Corporations onely.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s53">
		<head>For the University and (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>) Citty of Oxford</head>
		<para id="p116">The Vice-Chauncellour and the two Pro&bholigct;ors for the time being Sir Thomas Clayton Knight Warden of Merton
Colledge, Richard Bayley Do&bholigct;or of Divinitie President of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Johns Colledge, John Fell Do&bholigct;or of Divinitie Deane of
Christ Church John Meredith Do&bholigct;or of Divinity Warden of All Soules Colledge, Thomas Barlow Do&bholigct;or of Divinity
Provost of Queenes Colledge Thomas Yates Do&bholigct;or of Divinity Principall of Brazen Nose Colledge Walter Blandford
Do&bholigct;or of Divinitie Warden of Wadham Colledge, Luellin Jenkins Do&bholigct;or of the Lawes Principall of Jesus Colledge,
Joseph Crowther Do&bholigct;or of Divinitie Principall of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Mary Hall James Hide Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Principall of Magdalen
Hall Richard Lydall Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Thomas Elliot Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Henry Alworth Do&bholigct;or of Lawes
Benjamin Cooper Master of Arts Richard Witt [Batchler<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] of Law Nicholas Vilet [Batchler<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] of Law Richard Holway
Esq[ui]rs Martin Lipyard John Crosse William Flexney John Haslewood Joseph Goodwin William Day Richard Davis
William Finch Mathew Leech The Maior of the Citty for the time being Sir Anthony Cope and Sir Francis Wenman
Baronets Sir William Morton Sir Sampson White Knights Broom Whorwood Sergeant Hollaway Charles Hollaway
Richard [Cooke<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] Recorder George Low Esq[ui]rs Francis Harris Leonard Bowman William Wright Roger Griffin and
John White Aldermen John Harris William Bayley Francis Grenoway Francis Heyward John Townsend William Cornish
Henry Mallory John Painton Towne Clerke Robert Whorwood John Lamb Thomas Rowney Richard Pratt and
Edward Astin Gentlemen</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s54">
		<head>Rutland</head>
		<para id="p117">For the County of Rutland John Lord Roos sonne and heire apparent to John Earle of Rutland Bennet Lord
Shererd of the Kingdome of Ireland Edward Noell Henry Noell Philip Sherard Esq[ui]rs Sir Thomas Mackworth
Baronet Sir Edward Heath Knight of the Bath Sir Francis Mackworth Sir Edward Maria Wingfield Sir Eusebius
Pelsant Knights William Palmes Alexander Noell Christopher Browne Beamont Bodenham Richard Halford Abell
Barker Samuell Browne William Hyde Edward Faukner Robert Mackeworth Esq[ui]rs Charles Halford Ezekiell
Johnson Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s55">
		<head>Salop</head>
		<para id="p118">For the County of Salop William Pierpoint Andrew Newport Esq[ui]rs Sir Thomas Woolrich Sir William Whitmore
Sir Francis Lawley Sir Walter A&bholigct;on Sir Henry Fredericke Thynne Sir Vincent Corbet Sir Thomas Litleton Sir
Francist Edwards Sir Henry Vernon Sir Humphrey Briggs Baronet Sir Thomas Whitmore Knight of the Bath
Sir Richard Prince Sir John Weld Sir Richard Ottley Sir William Childe and Sir Henry Herbert Knights Sir Job
Charleton Sergiant at Law and Cheife Justice of Chester Timothy Litleton Sergiant at Law William Fowler Timothy
Turnor Phillip Eyton Richard Scriven Francis Thornes Charles Mannering James Latten Robert Sandford Roger
Kinneston Thomas Bawdwin Robert Leighton Philip Prince Francis Charlton Thomas Owen of Con-Dover Edward
Kinnerston Samuell Wingfeild Thomas Whitmore George Weld George Ludlow Thomas Rocke Charles Baldwin
Robert Charlton Henry Bernard Thomas Powis Thomas Ketlesby Robert Corbet of the Hall of Hussey Thomas
Holland John Coates William Oakley Edmond Wareing of Oldbury Somerset Fox Richard Fowler John Walcot
Adam Otly Thomas Walcot Robert Cresset John Cole Robert Owen Edward Powell Thomas Lloid Thomas
Lockier Thomas Smalman John Lacon Thomas Lockard John Kinnestone William Owen of Porkington John
Newton Thomas Kinnersley of Badger William Cotton Richard Mitton Francis Forrester William Jones of Sandford
Rowland Hill Vincent Edwards Henry Goodricke John Trevor Thomas Ireland Thomas Jones Richard Creswell
Thomas Harris John Corbet of Adderley Edward Vernon Thomas A&bholigct;on Thomas Jobber Samuell Baldwin Henry
Spratt Thomas Crumpe Henry Griffiths Richard Ridley Jonathan Langley James Becke Henry Mitton of Shipton
Esq[ui]rs The Maior of the Towne of Salop for the time being The Bayliffes of Ludlow Bridge North Wenlocke and
Bishops Castle for the time being, Daniell Wicherley Francis Smith Richard Walker John Whitacre Richard
Clarke Andrew Vivers Richard Tayler John Harding Arthur Hinks John Baugh Edward Woollaston Alexander
Midleton Samuell Lloyd Richard Davis of Ludlow Roger Gough Benjamin Buckley Somerset Hall Robert Betton
Thomas Jones of Sheet? Richard Charleton Richard Hosier Captaine Phillip Jenings Andrew Hill Richard Pritchard
John Haines George Hosier John Stanier Edward Owen Roger Harris Robert Vernon Captaine Richard Phillips
Rowland Hill of Hackoston Gentlemen Richard Cooling Es&bhoqesq; Robert Gorton Sir Clement Clarke and Richard
[Jerkins<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] Gen&bhocent;</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s56">
		<head>Stafford</head>
		<para id="p119">For the County of Stafford Sir John Wirley Knight High Sheriffe Sir Edward Litleton Sir Edward Baggot Sir Thomas Wilbraharn Sir Walter Rotesley Sir Charles Woolceley and Sir Francis Lawley Baronets Sir Bryan
Broughton and Sir John Bowyer Knights and Baronets Sir Theophilus Biddolph Sir Thomas Whitgrave and Sir
Walter Litleton Knights Randolph Egerton Walter Chetwind senior William Sneyd Henry Gray John Lane Walter
Chetwynd junior George Digby Broome Whorwood Rowland Okeover Edward Manwaring John Skrimshire Gerard
Skrimshire Collonell Harvy Baggot Edward Vernon Charles Cotton Richard Congreave Robert Milward William
Chetwynd Thomas Kynnersley John Piercehouse John Swynfin Robert Levison Francis Levison Rowland Cotton
Henry Archbold Jonathan Woodnorth Jonathan Cope Henry Vernon George Parker John Shelton Francis Wightwicke
John Whitehall William Talbot George Vernon Charles Agard Richard Aderley Edward Arablaster William Orme
John Noble Edward Birch Edward Ward William Ward William Trafford and Daniell Watson Esq[ui]rs Richard
Bracegirdle William Trafford John Gough William Farmer John Colclough of Burslem John Felton Henry
Haworth and Thomas Bagnall Gentlemen The Maior of Stafford for the time being The Maior of Newcastle for
the time being The Maior of Walsall for the time being and The Bayliffes of Tarn worth for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s57">
		<head>Lichfeild</head>
		<para id="p120">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Lichfield Thomas Caterbank Bayliffe The Bayliffes for the time being
Sir Theophilus Biddolph Knight Collonell John Lane Michaell Biddulph Richard Dyot John Hill Sherington Talbot
Esq[ui]rs Doctor Hinton Do&bholigct;or Hewet James Allen Thomas Minors John Burnes William Jesson Gen&bhocent; and The
Sheriffe for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s58">
		<head>Somerset</head>
		<para id="p121">For the County of Somerset John Lord Digby some and heire apparent to George Earle of Bristoll Francis Lord Hawley of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Charles Berkley Treasurer of his Majestyes Household John Pawlet Francis Pawlet Amias Pawlet Es?rs, Sir Thomas Mallet one of the Justices of the Kings Bench Sir William Portman Sir John Sidenham Sir Maurice Berkley Sir Hugh Smith Sir William Wyndham Sir John Worton Sir George Trevillian Sir Charles Pim and Sir John Newton Baronets Sir John Coventry and Sir Edward Hungerford Knights of the Bath Sir Henry Berkley Sir Thomas Bridges Sir Hugh Windham Sir George Norton Sir John Warr Sir
Thomas Gore Sir George Horner and Sir William Basset Knights John Merefield Sergiant at Law Alexander
Popham George Scowell Edward Phillips Edmond Windham George Speake Francis Lutterell Henry Rogers
Peregrine Palmer Samuell Gorges John Mallet Francis Wyndham William Hellier of Coker William Prynne
Thomas Heale Edward Berkley Henry Waldron William Bull John Buckland Thomas Warr Robert Hunt Thomas
Piggot Francis Roll John Harrington John Tynt Warwicke Brampfield William Lacy John Churchill Henry Henley
Edward [Edurt<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] Henry Bull William Carrant Francis Baker Richard Jones George Sidenham Robert Hawley Michaell Mallet Edward Phillips junior Anthony Powlet Henry Light John Harbin Roger Bourne Edward Bampfield Angell Gray Ralph Stowell John Moore Hugh Norris William Speake William Hillier of Sea John S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albans John Fitz-herbert John How William Bacon John Cridland Kingsmell Lucy Peter Royman William Harbord Roger Newburrough Maidley Samborne Francis Vaughan John Fody William Coward John Hunt John Goodwin Henry Dunstar Edward Clarke Thomas Farwell and William Clarke James Hayes Esqu[i]rs</para>
		<para id="p122">And for the Citty of Wells and Towne of Bridgewater<br/>
The respective Maiors for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s59">
		<head>For the Citty of Bath</head>
		<para id="p123">The Maior for the time being William Pryne Es&bhoqesq; Walter Gibbs Alderman Robert Pierce Doctor in Phisicke
Walter Bayley Edward Parker John Sherstone and Simon Sloper Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s60">
		<head>Bristoll</head>
		<para id="p124">For the County and Citty of Bristoll The Maior for the time being John Lawford Es&bhoqesq; Sir Robert Atkins Knight
of the Bath Recorder Sir Henry Creswicke and Sir John Knight Knights John Lock Richard Balman Nathaniell
Cale Walter Sandy John Willoughby Thomas Langton Aldermen Ralph Olliffe John Hicks John Wright John
Bradway and Richard Streamer Gent?.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s61">
		<head>Southampton</head>
		<para id="p125">For the County of Southampton Charles Lord S<emph type="p">t</emph> John of Basing sonne and heire apparent to John Marquesse
of Winchester. The Lord Henry Pawlet Sir George Carteret Vice-Chamberlaine to the Kings Household Sir Robert
Howard Sir Henry Worseley Sir John Mills Sir John Norton Sir William Lewis Sir Hugh Steukley Sir William
Meux Sir Thomas Badd Sir Nicholas Stewart Sir Andrew Henley Sir John Trot Sir Robert Dillington Baronets
Sir Humphrey Bennet Sir John Leigh Sir Robert Mason Sir Thomas Higgons Sir John Dingley Sir Robert Worseley
Sir Mundiford Brampston Sir Thomas Tomkins Knights Richard Norton Thomas Neale Richard Goddard Lawrence
Hyde Henry Wallop John Button Thomas Knollis William Oglander Robert Dillington Thomas Jervice John
Richards Charles West William Legg Henry Whitehead George Pitt. Thomas Brooke Leonard Bilson Francis
Rolle John Hooke Thomas Cole Phillip Leigh James May Richard Compton Benjamin Ruddiard Giles Hungerford
Francis River Roger Gallop Francis Tylney Henry Bromfield William Pitt Arthur Bold William Collins Edward
Norton Daniell Norton William Wither John Worseley senior Edward Worsley Edward Cooke John Ball Edward
Hooper of Chilworth Edward Hooper of Hume Court Francis Dickins John Stewkley Bartholomew Price Daniell
Kingsmell John Kingsmell Henry Tulse Thomas Edmonds Robert Oxenbridge Robert Goffe Richard Love Gabriell
Whisler Thomas Newnham John Deane John Oglander William Wall Challoner Chute Henry Kelsey Henry
Goddard William Lisle Andrew Wall Richard Ayloffe Edward Hide Anthony Yalden Essex Pawlet Stephen Fox
John Culpeper Walter Slingsby Alexander Culpeper John Dingly Esq[ui]rs and Richard Rudyard Gen&bhocent;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s62">
		<head>For the Towne and County of Southampton.</head>
		<para id="p126">William Stanley Robert Richbill William Horne Thomas Cornelius James Clungson Henry Pitt George
Steptoe Es?rs.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s63">
		<head>For the Citty of Winchester</head>
		<para id="p127">William Tayler Richard Dennet Edmond Fifeild Benjamin Clarke John Munday John Colson The Maior of
Winton The Maior of Southampton The Maior of Portsmouth The Maior of Newport The Maior of Basingstoke
The Bailiffe of Andevour for the time being John Boureman Thomas Legg James Rice Mores Reade Gen&bhocent;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s64">
		<head>Suffolke</head>
		<para id="p128">For the County of Suffolke Sir Edward Turner Knight Speaker of the House of Commons Walter Devereux Es&bhoqesq;
Sir Edmond Bacon Sir Lionall Tolemache Sir Henry Felton Sir Robert Kempe Sir William Spring Sir John Castleton
Sir Henry Bacon Sir Henry North Sir Thomas Cullam Sir Jarvice Elwes Sir Thomas Darcy Sir Robert Cordall Sir
John Rous Sir Robert Brooke Sir Samuell Barnardiston Sir Phillip Parker Baronets Sir William Playters Sir Henry
Wood Sir Charles Gaudy Sir George Reeve Sir Edward Duke Sir William Doyley Sir Thomas Barnardiston Knights
and Baronets Sir Dudley North Sir Nicholas Bacon and Sir John Knivet Knights of the Bath Sir Henry Crofts Sir
Edmond Poley Sir John Duncombe Sir Robert Brooke Sir Thomas Harvey Sir George Weneeve Sir John Poley Sir
Nevill Catlyn Sir William Bloys Sir Thomas Smith Sir Phillip Parker Sir Jeofrey Burwell Sir Phillip Meadow Sir
William Doyley and Sir Edmond Barker Knights John Haney Thomas Walgrave Thomas Holland John Poley Richard
Cooke Charles Stutterill John Sicclemore John Southby William Gipps Clement Heigham Benjamin Cutler of the
Chauntry William Bloys Henry Warner Thomas Stewart Thomas Wright Joseph Bland John Plaiters John Cole
Robert Mattiward Hamond Claxton Robert Stile Fitz-noune Lambe Henry Copinger Thomas Avis Edward Fielder
Peregrine Doyley Thomas Dade Thomas Scrivener Henry North John Lambe Edward North William A&bholigct;on John
Weritworth Robert Butts Thomas Butts Francis Cheney Robert Maniott William Rivet Robert Nanton Gardner
Webb Robert King Charles Cornewallis John Rivet Thomas Golding Edmond Plum Edward Man junior Edmond
Clench Richard Kirkby Thomas Tyrill Francis Theobald William Beaumont Michaell Grigg Thomas Lernon Reginald
Williams Thomas Vesey Phillip Howard William Dawtree William Gouch Framblingham Gaudy Ptoleme Tolemache
William Jermy Henry Parker Thomas Bacon John Brame of Ash, Humphrey Bowen John Bedingfield Thomas Day
Miles Edgar Samuell Kenidge Edmond Sheppard William Cullam Edmond Gardner Robert Browning Henry Stebbing
John Brooke John Cornwallis William Blomfield Robert Gosnold Wiseman Bockenham John Thurston Thomas Edgar
Thomas Allen Vice Admirall Robert Wright Esq[ui]rs The Maior of Sudbury for the time being John Warner William
Byat Gen&bhocent; The Bayliffes of Dunwich for the time being</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s65">
		<head>For the Burrough of Ipswich</head>
		<para id="p129">The Bayliffe for the time being Sir Emanuell Sorells Knight William Bloys John Sicklmore Esq[ui]rs Nicholas Phillips
John Robinson John Smithier Robert Clarke Gilbert Lingfield Edward Man junior Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s66">
		<head>For the Burrough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Edmonds Bury</head>
		<para id="p130">The Alderman for the time being John Southby Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Sir Edmond Poley Sir John Duncombe Knights
James Cob Es&bhoqesq; Francis Browne Robert Sharpe Stephen Cooke Samuell Hustler Edward Bourne Gent</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s67">
		<head>For the Burrough of Aldborough</head>
		<para id="p131">The Bayliffe for the time being Sir John Holland Baronet Sir Robert Brooke Knight William Shipman Thomas
Elliot Richard Browne and John Burwood Gen&bhocent;</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s68">
		<head>For the Burrough of Orford</head>
		<para id="p132">The Maior for the time being Walter Devereux Es&bhoqesq; Sir Allen Brodericke Knight Joseph Hastings Thomas Hastings
James Coppin Edward Ewen Edward Parker Martin Folkes John Harwell and Edward Johnson Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s69">
		<head>Surrey</head>
		<para id="p133">For the County of Surrey and Burrough of Southwarke Charles Earle of Ancram of the Kingdome of Scotland
Francis Lord Angier of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Edward Nicholas Knight one of his Majestyes Most Honourable
Privy Councill Benjamin Weston Es&bhoqesq; Sir Henry Capell Knight of the Bath Sir Francis Vincent Knight and Baronet
Sir Walter S<emph type="p">t</emph> Johns Sir Adam Browne Baronets Sir Thomas Trevor Knight and Baronet Sir John Robinson Knight
and Baronet Lieutenant of the Tower Sir Richard Browne Knight and Baronet Sir William Moore Sir John
Eveling Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir Richard Stidolph Sir John Bromfeild Sir Abraham Cullen and Sir Thomas
Hooke Baronets Sir John Nicholas and Sir William Terringham Knights of the Bath Sir William Throckmorton Knight
Marshall Sir Ralph Freeman Knight one of the Masters of Request Sir John Lenthall Sir Edmond Bowyer Sir John
Shaw Sir Charles Howard Sir William Howard Sir George Aiscough Sir Robert Long Sir Edward Wingfield Sir
Thomas Bloodworth Sir Daniell Harvy Sir Robert Parkhurst Sir Richard Hatton Sir Allen Brodericke Sir Nicholas
Carew Sir Edward Bish Sir James Austin and Sir William Turner Knights Henry Hilyard Arthur Onslow George
Chute Roger James John Scot Edward Thurland Christopher Buckle Edward Evelin Thomas Foster Anthony Bower
Edward Nicholas William Hoskins George Evelin Richard Evelin William Elliot Anthony Thomas John Holmden
James Zouch Henry Weston Thomas Dalmahoy George Smith Dawes Wymondsold John Dawes George Browne
William Muschampe John Thynne George Moore George Garth Thomas Turges Mathew Carleton Roger Duncombe
George Duncombe George Woodruffe George Vernon Henry Henn George Duke Edward Knippe Jeofrey Howland
Edward Barker Samuell Rouse John H?mond John Thynne junior James Gresham Edward Eversfield Harmon
Atwood Charles Good Thomas Lee Peter Hussey Richard Heath Vincent Randall Nicholas Miller John Parker
Thomas Rogers Do&bholigct;or Windebanke Lawrence Marsh George Turner Theophilus Holman Thomas Arden Henry
Byne John Heather Richard Syms Ellis Crispe Edward Smith Edward Warcup and John Angell Esq[ui]rs John Jordon
of Ditton John Robinson John Wight William Streete. William Boothby Peter Quinnall senior John Jones William
Westbrooke Richard West Cabell Westbrooke The Maior of Guilford for the time being John Childe James Burton
Richard Lewin William Cannon John Wilkinson Otnell Maverell William Locke John Neale Simon Nicholas Hugh
Layton Peter Delanoy James Reading Edward Ball George Meggor John Luntly Jacob May Thomas Butler Thomas
Morgan Tobias Solby and Benjamin Collier Gent.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s70">
		<head>Sussex</head>
		<para id="p134">For the County of Sussex Joselin Lord Percy sonne and heire apparent to Algernon Earle of Northumberland
Thomas Leonard [&amp; John [Ashburham<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] Es?rs<ref idref="n37">37</ref>] S<emph type="p">r</emph> John Pelham Sir William Colepeper Sir Cecill Bishop Sir John
Covert Sir William Thomas Sir John Stapley Sir John Fagg Sir Denny [Washburnham<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] Sir Walter Henley Sir William
Wilson Baronets Sir John Lewkener and Sir William Morley Knights of the Bath Sir Thomas Dike Sir Edward Ford
Sir John Morley Sir Thomas Woodcocke Sir Thomas Nutt Sir George Courtop Sir Henry Peckham Sir Henry Onslow
and Sir William Craven Knights George Parker George Nevill Thomas Sackevill Henry Goreing Pierce Goreing
William Garway John May Harbert Morley. John Eversfield junior Nisell Rivers Anthony Shurley John De la
Chambers Charles Brett John Peckham John Garway Samuell Gott Edward Polhill Roger Showswell Robert
Anderson John Forrington Breween Bichley Edward Morley Allen Carr Richard Bridges Peter Courthop Edward
Keeling Henry Shelley Benjamin Colpeper Henry Bill William Spence Edward May M<emph type="p">r</emph> Symon Smith Alexander
Jermin of Luddington Robert Fowle Thomas Collins Walter Everden William Dike Sackevill Graves Nicholas
Gildridge Thomas Foster Henry Chowne Edward Paine Henry Bish Edward Michelburn Phillip Packer John Stewart
John Baker of Withiam William Gratwicke Richard Shepperd Stephen French and Thomas Henshaw junior of
Billinghurst Esq[ui]rs Richard May Abraham Chapman Thomas Palmer Richard Cooper Thomas Bebsworth Mathew
Young Thomas Levett Richard Young Alderman John Luxford of Ocley Ambrose Trayton Henry Shelley William
Lane William Vivall John Oliver Thomas Peckham John Fuller of Waldron Robert Pickering John Baker junior
John Hay of Glindborn, Roger Bish Robert Palmer Francis Gratwicke William Palmer Richard Nash William
Westbrooke Christopher Coles John Muncke Thomas Barnard Thomas Paine John Paine Arthur Lovet Thomas
Brumfeild senior Richard Alchorn Thomas Brumfeild Junior Bray Chowne Anthony Eversfeild Edward Chowney
John Gratwich of Eatons Joseph Newington John Dine William Hartridge Alexander Stapeley Robert Brooke senior
Gentlemen The respe&bholigct;ive Maiors of Chichester Arundell Hasting Rye and Winchelsey for the time being The
Bayliffes of Seaford and [Davensey <ref idref="n38">38</ref>] for the time being Thomas Midleton Gen&bhocent; John King and Henry King Esq[ui]rs.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s71">
		<head>Warwicke</head>
		<para id="p135">For the County of Warwicke Sir Francis Compton Knight Foulke Grevill Charles Leigh Esq[ui]rs Sir Robert Holt
Sir Richard Temple Sir Henry Puckering alias Newton Sir Edward Broughton Sir Roger Burgoyne Sir John Knightley
Sir Clement Fisher Sir Herbert Price Sir Thomas Norton Baronets Sir William Bromley Sir Stephen Hales Knights
of the Bath Sir George Deyereux Sir Francis Willoughby Sir Charles Adderley Sir Charles Lee Sir William Palmer
Sir Arthur Caley Sir William Underhill Sir Combe Wagstaffe Sir Richard Hopkins Sir Richard Bishop Sergiant at
Armes Knights Amos Walrond Walter Chetwin senior William Booth of Witton John Bridgeman John Ferrers
Richard Lucy Thomas Archer Clement Throckemorton William Somjervile Francis Willoughby Seabright Rippington
William Dilkes Harvey Baggot George Fielding Richard Newdigate Sergiant at Law Thomas Flint Thomas Temple
Thomas Boughton John Rous William Purifoy John Clopton Henry Ferrers Charles Newsham John Lisle of Moxell
Richard Verney of Kingston Charles Bentley Giles Palmer Nicholas Overby Edward Underhill Thomas Marriot
Humphrey Jenings Thomas Corbin John Fetherston George Sacheyerill James Prescutt Thomas Rawlins of Stratford
Esq[ui]rs The Maior of Warwicke for the time being The Maior of Stratford for the time being The Bayliffes of
Tamworth for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s72">
		<head>Coventry</head>
		<para id="p136">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry The Maior for the time being Sir Thomas Norton Baronet
Sir Clement Fisher Sir Arthur Caley Sir Richard Hopkins Sir Charles Adderley Knights Thomas Flint Edmond
Palmer Esq[ui]rs Henry Smith Mathew Smith Julius Billers Aldermen Humphrey Burton Coroner.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s73">
		<head>Worcester</head>
		<para id="p137">For the County of Worcester Sir John Packington Sir William Russell Sir Henry Litleton Sir Edward Seabright
Sir William Kite Sir Thomas Rouse Baronets Sir Ralph Clare Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Herbert Sir Rowland
Berkley Sir John Talbot Sir John Windford Knights Collonell Samuell Sandys Samuell Sandis junior William Sandis
Sherrington Talbot Thomas Savage Edward Pitts Francis Russell Francis [Fincke<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] Edward Carey Joseph Welsh William Wassburn Thomas Childe Henry Townshend Thomas Wilde John Nanfan Thomas Streete Henry Parker Leonard Simpson Theophilus Andrewes Richard Dowdeswell Henry Bromly of Upton William Mucklo Litleton Clent Edward [Russell<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] Richard Vernon Charles Cornwallis Walter Savage Thomas Jolliffe Thomas Symmons Humphrey
Litleton Thomas Foley Phillip Persons Anthony Crumpe William Baldwin Henry Evett William Hancocke John
Charlet Thomas Watson of Bengworth Henry Spiller William Ligon Henry Bromeley of Holt Edward Dingley
Henry Jefferies Broome Whorwood Phillip Brace Francis Sheldon John Bearcroft Bridges Nanfan Esq[ui]rs The Maior
of Evesham for the time being, The Bayliftes of Droytwich for the time being, The Bayliffe of Bewdley for the
time being John Barnaby of Bockleton Es&bhoqesq;</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s74">
		<head>Worcester Citty</head>
		<para id="p138">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester The Maior Aldermen and Sheriffe for the time being
Sir John Packington Baronet Sir Rowland Berkley Knight Sir William Moreton Knight one of his Majestyes Sergiants
at Law Thomas Hall Thomas Streete Thomas Wild Thomas Vernon Thomas Harris Esq[ui]rs Humphrey Wildy
Richard Beddoes Thomas Harrison Wintour Harris John Bearcroft Francis Hughes Humphrey Tyrer Gentlemen</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s75">
		<head>Wilts</head>
		<para id="p139">For the County of Wilts Henry Lord Herbert sonne and Heire apparent to Edward Marquisse of Worcester The
Lord, John Seymour William Lord Herbert of Cardiffe sonne and Heire apparent to Phillip Earle of Pembrooke and
Mountgomery Henry Viscount Cornbury sonne and heire apparent to Edward Earle of Clarendon Lord Chauncellour
of England Sir Edward Nicholas Knight one of his Majesties Most Honourable Privy Councill Sir Robert Hyde
Knight Cheife Justice of the Kings Bench Edward Howard Phillip Howard Es?s Sir Walter S<emph type="p">r</emph> John Sir Seymour
Pile Sir George Grubham How Sir Walter Ernle Sir Giles Tooker Baronets Sir John Coventry Sir John Nicholas
Sir Edward Hungerford Sir Edward Baynton Knights of the Bath Sir Wadham Windham Knight one of the Justices
of the Kings Bench Sir James Thynne Sir John Evelin Sir John Talbot Sir Edward Poole Sir George Hungerford
Sir John Weld Sir John Low Sir Thomas Escourt Sir Henry Coker Sir Thomas Ivy Sir William Cawley Sir
Thomas Mompesson Sir John Ernle Sir William Eyre Knights Alexander Popham Edward Seymour Richard
Grubham How Robert Phillips Francis Wroughton John Pleyddall William Glanvile Henry Clarke William Jordan
John Hall Esq[ui]rs (<ref idref="n41">41</ref>) John Morton Baronet Richard Lewis George Ayliffe Edward Nicholas Edward Hungerford Edward
Hyde Ralph Freake William Pawlet William Ducket Thomas Mompesson William Bronker Walter Backland
Henry Hungerford Henry Baynton Walter Long George Bond Gilbert Rawleigh Edmond Warneford Richard
Harrison Richard Aldworth Alexander Thistlewhaite junior, William Yorke Stephen Fox Edward Goddard of Standen
Thomas Bennet of Salthrop James Long Thomas Wancklin Jeoffrey Daniell John Collins John Kent Thomas Gore
William Willoughby John Foyle John Norden Henry Long James Ash Edward Topp Thomas Hawles Joseph
Stockman Giles Eyre Joseph Eyre Samuell Eyre John Long John Bowles Richard Bowie William. Kent Edward
Manning William Swanton Thomas Lambert Thomas Pile Robert Chaundler Thomas Hungerford William Bowles
John Eyre Richard Southby Seymour Bowman Richard Escourt Rowland Plott Edward Goddard of Ogbourn John
Danvers John Glanvile Henry Wallis Do&bholigct;or Hierst John Escourt Benjamine Gilfford Nevill [Masculine<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] Oliver
Nicholas Edmond Web Isaac Burgis Richard Long John Mompesson Henry Trenchard Simon Sepatchurst Richard
Davy George Ivy Samuell Ash John Dave[n<ref idref="n43">43</ref>]ant John Bennet Robert Challoner William Sadler Robert Hippesley
Ephraim Westley Mathew Bennet Richard Greene Humphrey Hyde Edmond Ansley Christopher Gardiner
Crouch Thomas Hunt Thomas Chaffin Ferrers [Gressey<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] George Parrey Thomas Clarke Henry Clarke junior Anthony Trotman John Ellot Walter Dowse John Duke junior William Cusse John Young Walter Sharpe George Sadler Thomas Escourt Thomas Gape William Levet Christopher Willoughby John Fitz-herbert Esq[ui]rs The Maior of Wilton for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s76">
		<head>New Sarum</head>
		<para id="p140">For the Citty of New Sarum Sir Robert Hyde Knight Cheife Justice of the Kings Bench Sir Wadham Windham
Knight one of the Justices of the Kings Bench The Maior for the time being Richard Coleman Recorder William
Joyce Thomas [Quiate<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] Morrice Greene Thomas Williams Edward Edmonds Thomas Gardiner Thomas Cutler
James Harwood Thomas Ray Aldermen Sir John Low Sir Thomas Mompesson Knights Thomas Hawles William
Swanton Richard Davy John Holt Thomas Chaffin Thomas Dorrell Stephen Fox Seamour Bowman Simon Spatchhurst
Francis Sambrooke Nicholas Johnson and Gyles Clutterbucke Esq[ui]rs.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s77">
		<head>Westmerland</head>
		<para id="p141">For the County of Westmerland Sir Phillip Musgrave Sir William Dalston Sir Richard Sandford Sir John
Lowther senior Sir John Lowther junior Baronets Sir Thomas Strickland Sir George Dalston Knights Richard
Musgrave John Lowther Allen Bellingham John Dalston James Ducket Daniell Fleming Richard Braithwaite
Robert Hilton Thomas Braithwaite John Otway Nicholas Fisher Edward [Nevison<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] Lancelot Machell Thomas
Gabetas Nathaniell West Edward Wilson Esq[ui]rs The Maior of Apleby for the time being, The Maior of Kendall
for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s78">
		<head>Yorke</head>
		<para id="p142">For the West Rideing of the County of Yorke George Viscount Castleton of the Kingdome of Ireland Henry
Viscount Irwin of the Kingdome of Scotland Thomas Lord Fairefax of the Kingdome of Scotland Sir Francis Fane
William Earle of Dumfreeze in the Kingdome of Scotland Knight of the Bath Conyers Darcy Es&bhoqesq; Sir Francis
Wortley Sir George Savill Sir Thomas Osborne Sir John Goodricke Sir Richard Maleverer Sir John Rersby Sir
John Key Sir John Armitage Sir William Ingleby Sir Soloman Swaile Sir William Rokesby Sir Godfrey Copley
Sir George Winn Sir Garvas Cutler Sir John Jackeson Sir John Lewis Sir Thomas Slingsby Sir George Cooke
Baronets Sir Thomas Wharton Sir Francis Fane Junior Knights of the Bath Sir Richard Tanckred Sir Jordan
Crosland Sir Thomas Beaumont Sir Thomas Wentworth Sir John Dawney Sir Miles Stapleton Sir William Lowther
Sir Francis Goodricke Sir Edmond Jenings Sir William Ingram Sir Christopher Clapham Sir Ralph Knight Sir
Thomas Yarborough Knights Richard Hutton Thomas Danby Walter Hawkesworth Henry Arthirigton Welberry
Norton Charles Tankard Ambrose Pudsey Francis Rockley Robert [Wirvell<ref idref="n47">47</ref>] Walter Strickland Anthony Adeyre
Francis Nevill Walter Calverley Henry Eyre Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke John Wentworth of Ellinshell John Savile of
Heathly Henry Goodricke John Wentworth of Wolly Bradwardin Tyndall John Vincent John Richard William
Lowther John Bilby Richard Washington Richard Mountney William Hammond William Adams Thomas Yarborough
Walter Lister William Drake Inglebert Leeds Cuthbert Wade Robert Harrison James Moseley John Stanhop
Nicholas Stable Benjamin Nortcliffe Roger Portington Edward Lewis John Thornhill William Womble Thomas
Stringer Henry Atkinson Francis White William Spencer of Attercliffe William Godfrey Thomas Lister of M?ningham
Thomas Lister of Bawtree Thomas Haber John Ottway John Major Thomas Stavely Doyley Gower Thomas Fawkes
Esq[ui]rs Henry Cooke Thomas Edmonds Jonathan Jenings John Atkinson John Preston William Witham Benjamin
Wade John Dodsworth William Roundell George Clarke Jervas Bosvile Thomas Gill Richard Graham Gen&bhocent; The
Maior of Rippon The Maior of Doncaster The Maior of Pontefra&bholigct; The Maior of Leeds for the time being
Robert Walters of Owsbourn George Fothergill Esq[ui]rs</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s79">
		<head>For the North Rideing</head>
		<para id="p143">Charles Lord S<emph type="p">t</emph> John of Basing sonne and heire apparent to John Marquesse of Winchester Conyers Darcy Es&bhoqesq;
Sir Henry Bellasis Henry Darcy James Darcy Esq[ui]rs Sir Christopher Wivell Sir Thomas Gower Sir John Goodricke
Sir Medcalfe Robinson Sir Solomon Swaile Sir Henry Stapleton Sir David Fowles Sir John Lowther Sir John
Nappier Sir Roger Langley Sir William Caley Sir George Marwood Sir Richard Graham Sir William Frankland
Sir Christopher Wandesford Baronets Sir Robert Strickland Sir Richard Tancred Sir Thomas Strickland Sir Jordan
Crosland Sir William Dalton Sir John Dawney Sir James Pennyman Sir Thomas Ingrain Chauncellour of the
Dutchy Sir Henry Chomeley Sir Thomas Heblethwaite Sir Joseph Craddocke Sir Henry Franckland Sir William
Craven Knights William Wivell Edward Gower Henry Marwood James Medcalfe Mathew Hutton Robert Layton
William Caley John How Thomas Danby Walter Strickland John Beverley Thomas Rookeby James Moyser John
Calverley Edward Croft Thomas Robinson William Weddall John Tourner Isaac Fairfax John Wivell of Osgarby
Humphrey Wharton Charles Bellasis Edward Hutchinson of Wickham Reynald Graham Major Norton Henry
Bethell Roger Talbot Charles Tancred Thomas Jackson Henry Harrison William Fielding William Robinson
Edward Trotter Robert Belt Thomas Hutton James Morley Thomas Hassell Timothy Maleverer Captaine Leonard
Robinson John Dodsworth William Thompson Thomas Wickham Anthony Lowther Thomas Norton William
Metcalfe Henry Blackson Walter Lister John Gibson Charles [Allason<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] Edward Gower William Gower John Colson
Esq[ui]rs James Moore George Norton Francis Driffield John Smith Thomas Waite. William Spinke Allen Chamber
John Hill of Thorndon John Earnley. Ralph Jackson of Lazenby junior Christopher Keld Henry, Crosland William
Lampley William Truman Francis Cumin Robert Bushell Richard Harland Major Redman Gentlemen The Aldermen
of Richmond and the Bayliffes of Scarborough for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s80">
		<head>For the East Rideing</head>
		<para id="p144">Sir Francis Cob Knight High Sheriffe of the County Charles Lord Viscount Dungarvan in the Kingdome of
Ireland Sir John Hotham Sir Francis Boynton Sir Robert Hilyard Sir John Bucke Sir Watkinson Paler Sir Thomas
Rudston Sir John Ledgard Baronets Sir Thomas Nortcliffe Sir Phillip Mountaine Sir Thomas Daniell Sir Mathew
Apleyard Sir Thomas Renington Sir Hugh Bethel Sir Thomas Heblethwait Sir William Cob Knights Tobias Jenkins
Michaell Wharton Robert Bucke Thomas Grantham Durant Hotham Hugh Lister John Constable John Lister Henry
Sandys Henry Holmes Christopher Hilyard Walter Bethell George Mountaine John Vavasor Jonathan Atkins Ralph
Warton William Osbaldston William Grimston Robert Southby Richard Robinson Thomas Crumpton Samford
Nevill William Gee Richard Ledgeard William Baynton Stephen Thompson Richard Thompson Henry Hilyard
James Moyser Edward Bernard Thomas Hesket Gregory Creyke William Harpham Thomas Anlaby Alexander
Rokeby Henry Hilyard John Stapleton Henry Portington Phillip Saltmarsh John Acraid Es?rs, Thomas Swan Leonard
Robinson William Blount John Pierson Lewis Lewins Francis Bushell Robert Constable John Belton William Dobson
William Thompson Ralph Higden Richard Graham Thomas Sytheron Christopher [Daukins<ref idref="n49">49</ref>] Gen&bhocent; The Maior of
Hedon and The Maior of Beverley for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s81">
		<head>Yorke Citty</head>
		<para id="p145">For the Citty of Yorke and the County of the same Edward Elwicke Lord Maior Thomas Lord Fairefax of the
Kingdome of Scotland Sir Metcalfe Robinson Sir Thomas Osbourne Sir Roger Langley Sir John Goodricke Sir
George Rive Sir Thomas Slingsby Baronet Sir John Lewis Knight and Baronet Sir Miles Stapleton Knight James
Brooke Christopher Topham George Lemplough George Mancklins Richard Hewet Henry Thompson Cressey
Bournet Christopher Brery Henry Tireman John Tayler James Bawtry Aldermen Edward Gale John Beares Leonard
Thompson Joseph Scott John Turner Tobias Jenkins James Moyser William Fairefax Thomas Robinson Thomas
Hutton Henry Fairefax Esq[ui]rs John Swaile Do&bholigct;or Burwell M<emph type="p">r</emph> Ethrington Phillip Prince William Roundle Thomas
Hesketh George Aisleby Phillip Harbert M<emph type="p">r</emph> Suavesdale Richard Tennant William Richardson Richard Rawlinson
Francis Price John Loftus John Thompson George Mangy Francis Chatterton Thomas Setterthwhaite Thomas Fairefax
Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s82">
		<head>Kingston upon Hull</head>
		<para id="p146">For the Towne of Kingston upon Hull The Maior for the time being Anthony Gilby Andrew Marvell Es?rs
William Dobson Robert Ripley Robert Berriar William Foxley William Ramsden Christopher Richardson George
Crowle Richard Robinson Richard Wilson William Skinner Robert Bloome Richard Francke Aldermen Hugh Lister
Esquire, The Sheriffes for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s83">
		<head>WALES</head>
	</section>
	<section id="s84">
		<head>Anglesey</head>
		<para id="p147">For the County of Anglesey Robert Lord Viscount Bulkely of the Kingdome of Ireland Marke Lord Viscount
Duncannon Thomas Bulkeley Es&bhoqesq; Sir Hugh Owen Knight and Baronet Nicholas Bagnell Thomas Woods Pierce
Lloyd senior Rowland Bulkley William Bold John Robinson Griffith Jones of Trevarthen Hugh Owen Pierce Lloyd
junior Richard Merick John Lloyed of Landegnan John Griffith of Lanvaithly John Wynne of Bodewrid William
Bulkly [Bruddy<ref idref="n50">50</ref>] John Pritherch of Llisdelas Rowland White Richard Owen Hugh Huges John Owen of [Llanvaith<ref idref="n51">51</ref>]
Esq[ui]rs John Owen of Penrhose Conisby William Owen Huges Henry Jones Henry Davies William Williams of Tre
Arthur William Lewis Griffith Lloyd of Treaseth Edward Price Bodower Edward Price Treyadog Howell Lewis
Owen Lloyd of Heubles John Williams Bodurdin John Owen Treveiler Richard Wyn of Peughkin William Hampton
William Wynn of Langold Gen&bhocent; The Maior of Bewmorris for the time being.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s85">
		<head>Brecon</head>
		<para id="p148">For the County of Brecon Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland sonne and heire apparent to Edward Marquesse of
Worcester Sir Richard Lloyd Knight Arthur Trevor Es&bhoqesq; Edward Progers Es&bhoqesq; of his Majestyes Bedchamber Sir
William Lewis Sir Henry Williams Sir Herbert Price Baronets William Morgan of Therow Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Herbert
Knight George Gwinne Milburn Williams John Jefferies Lewis Morgan Attourney Generall there Thomas Lewis
Walter Williams John Stedman Hugh Powell William Morgan of Newton Walter Vaughan Thomas Williams
Edward Powell James Watkins Henry Stedman Meredith Lewis Thomas Bowen Esq[ui]rs Lewis Gunter James Williams
William Lloyd of Wernos Edward Harbert John Morgan Daniell Winter William Saunders Gen&bhocent; The Bayliffe of
Brecon for the time being</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s86">
		<head>Cardigan</head>
		<para id="p149">For the County of Cardigan Sir Richard Price Baronet Sir Francis Lloyd Knight James Lewis [senior<ref idref="n52">52</ref>] John
Vaughan James Stedman Henry Vaughan John Jones James Lewis junior Edward Vaughan Erasmus Lloyd Morgan
Herbert Richard Herbert Reignold Jenkins David Lloyd He&bholigct;or Phillips John Lewis Thomas Jenkins Esq[ui]rs David
Evans Thomas Lloyd of Pus Abell Griffin Gentlemen</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s87">
		<head>Carmarthen</head>
		<para id="p150">For the County of Carmarthen Francis Lord Vaughon sonne and heire apparent to Richard Earle of Carbery
in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir John Vaughan Knight of the Bath Sir William Moreton one of his Majesties
Sergiants at Law Simon Deg Es&bhoqesq; Sir Edward Mansell Sir Rice Rudd Sir William Russell Baronets Sir Henry
Vaughan Knight Walter Rice John Vaughan of Llannelly Nichollas Williams William Gwynne of Talliaris John
Vaughan of Dertlis Henry Midleton James Jones Penry Vaughan John Vaughan of Whitehouse junior Morgan Jones
Phillip Vaughan Thomas Lloyd of Berllan-dowell Thomas Lloyd of Dan per Alt Owen Brickstocke Thomas Lloyd
of Llanlouthog John Powell junior Esq[ui]rs.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s88">
		<head>Towne of Carmarthen</head>
		<para id="p151">For the Towne of Carmarthen The Maior for the time being Francis Lord Vaughan sonne and heire apparent
to Richard Earle of Carbury in the Kingdome of Ireland Sir John Vaughan Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Vaughan
Knight John Vaughan of Llannelly John Vaughan of Dertlis Walter Vaughan Esq[ui]rs Thomas Rivon Anthony Jones
Thomas Jones, Dawkins Goffe Lewis Jones John Oakley Aldermen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s89">
		<head>Carnarvan</head>
		<para id="p152">For the County of Carnarvan Robert Lord Viscount Bulkley of the Kingdome of Ireland Robert Roberts Thomas
Bulkley Esq[ui]rs Sir Richard Wynne Sir Griffith Williams Sir Roger Mostin Sir Robert Williams Baronets Sir John
Owen Sir Richard Lloyd Nicholas Bagnell Griffith Jones William. Griffith Witham Vaughan Owen Griffith John
Bodurda Maurice Wynne Hugh Wynne Thomas Wynne William Wynne of Llanruda Hugh Williams William
Buckley Griffith Bodurda Edmond Glyn John Wynne Berthaur Timothy Litleton Sergiant at Law John Jones
John Wynne of Twgyn William Wynne of Glangranon Richard Angwill John Glyn Thomas Glyn Richard Glyn
Richard Thomas John Williams Thomas Vaugham William Hookes Richard Griffith Owen Wynne. of Glasgoed
Richard Ciffin John Lloyd Robert Coetmor John Wynne of Melay Esq[ui]rs John Wynne of Berthanur Jeofrey
Williams John Wynne of Pennarth Harbert Griffith John Hookes William Wynne of Pengwerne William Williams
Hugh Bodurda Owen Wynne William Spicur William Thomas of Carnarvan Edward Pierce Richard Ellis John
Jones of Trevan Robert Wynn of Keselgonarch Gentlemen</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s90">
		<head>Denbigh</head>
		<para id="p153">For the County of Denbigh John Carter Knight High Sheriffe Sir Thomas Midleton Sir Richard Wynne Sir John
Salisbury Sir Thomas Powell Sir William Meredith Baronets Sir Thomas Trevor Knight and Baronet Sir Richard
Lloyd Sir Edward Broughton Sir Robert Agbrow Sir John Wynne Knights Roger Puleston John Trevor of Trevalin
William Owen William Salisbury Hugh Wynne John Wynne Mutton Davies Robert Wynne of Voylas Thomas
Jones Edward Thelwall William Price Kenrick Eyton Thomas Vaughan Charles Salisbury John Robinson Collonell
Robert Broughton Bevis Lloyd John Thelwall John Edisbury Charles Midleton Foulke Midleton Timothy Midleton
Euball Thelwall John Jefferies Richard Midleton of Llanclin Robert Price of Geeler Edward Breariton Watkin
Kiffin Owen Thelwall John Trevor of Brinkinnalt Gabriell Goodman Humphrey Hughes of Brintanger David
Morris Richard Wynne of Garthkanan John Langford William Parry Charles Goodman John Puleston William
Williams John Lloyd of Bodidrist Hugh Roberts Francis Manley John Lloyd of Llanunis Hugh Lloyd of Foxall
Esq[ui]rs William Jones John Salisbury of Lewesog Humphrey Lloyd of Berse Robert Wynne of Garthewinn Howell
Lloyd James Thelwall Robert Griffith of Pendared John Lloyd g wrich Captaine Thomas Yale John Williams of
[Caredrividd <ref idref="n53">53</ref>] Owen Price of Nantmanze Robert Wynne of Lwyn Maurice Williams of Llannerras Edward Lloyd of
Placemado Thomas Lloyd of Barsey Ellis Lloyd of Eglewisig The two Aldermen of Denbigh John Hughes Thomas
Mathewes John Jones Thomas Shaw senior Robert Salisbury Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s91">
		<head>Flint</head>
		<para id="p154">For the County of Flint Sir Thomas Hanmer Sir John Salisbury Sir Henry Conway Sir Roger Mostin Baronets
Sir John Trevor Sir John Glyn Sir John Hanmer Knights John Trevor Thomas Ravenscroft Roger Puleston Robert
Davies Thomas Lloyd, William Hanmer Roger Whitley Mutton Davies William Mostin John Parry Robert Whitley
Andrew Ellis Evan Edwards David Penant John Eyton Richard Griffith Edward Lloyd Ellis Young Edward
Lloyd John Broughton Thomas Humphryes John Salisbury senior John Midleton Thomas Crackley Eubule Hughes
Charles Jones Owen Barton John Lloyd of Fawne Thomas Mostin Hugh Penant.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s92">
		<head>Glamorgan</head>
		<para id="p155">For the County of Glamorgan Henry Lord Herbert of Ragland sonne and heire apparent to Edward Marquesse
of Worcester William Lord Herbert of Cardiffe Sir Richard Lloyed Knight Arthur Trevor Es&bhoqesq; Sir Edward Mansell
Sir Edward Stradling Sir Edward Thomas Baronets Sir John Awbrey Knight and Baronet Sir William Lewis Sir
Thomas Lewis Sir Richard Basset Knights John Greenuffe Evan Seyes Sergiant at Law William Basset Do&bholigct;or of
Lawes Robert Thomas Miles Button Thomas Lewis William Basset of Bewpre William Harbert of Swansey Edmond
Thomas Bussy Mansell Herbert Evans Thomas Mathew Humphry Windham David Jenkins Gabriell Lewis William
Thomas Thomas Stradling Thomas Came John Van John Gibbs Thomas Thomas David Mathew Lamerocke
Stradling Thomas Evans Edmond Gammage Richard Loughers William Herbert of Killy-Bebell John Came Henry
Basset Edward Harbert of Cogan David Evans John Lewellin.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s93">
		<head>Merioneth</head>
		<para id="p156">For the County of Merioneth Maurice Williams Es&bhoqexc; High Sheriffe Sir Richard Wynne Baronet Sir John Owen
Sir Richard Lloyd Sir John Wynne Knights William Salisbury William Price William Vaughan of Corseggedall
Lewis Lloyd Howell Vaughan Maurice Wynne Vincent Corbert John Pugh John Lloyd Hugh Nanny Robert
Wynne Roger Mostin Richard Wynne Griffith. Lloyd Lewis Owen William Vaughan of Caithle John Nanny
Edmond Meirick Humphrey Hughes John Vaughan Rowland Vaughan Richard Anwill Ellis Edwards William
Tueir John Morgans Es?uirs John Owen of Havod-dowilth Richard Jones Anthony Poole Griffith John Lewis Richard
Nanny Gen&bhocent; Henry Wynne Morrice Williams Esq[ui]rs Evan Lloyd of Rhiwgech Richard Lloyd of Carrog Gentlemen</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s94">
		<head>Montgomery</head>
		<para id="p157">For the County of Montgomery Sir John Witterong High Sheriffe Sir Henry Herbert Edward Herbert Andrew
Newport Esq[ui]rs Sir Mathew Price Sir Richard Corbet Baronets Sir Edward Lloyd Knight John Pursell Richard
Harbert Richard Owen Robert Layton John Blayney John Pugh Francis Buller Charles Salisbury Edmond Wareing
John Price of Parke Roger Mostin Mathew Morgan William Penrin Junior Thomas Maurice Edward Glyn of
Glyn Edward Evans of Rhidicorrow John Whittingham David Powell Thomas Juckes John Mathews the Elder
John Mathew the younger Edward Edwards of Colffin John Bladwell Thomas Winde Thomas Corbet Robert Lee
Thomas Jones Henry Pursell William Pierce William Eyton Richard Mitton John Kiffin Francis Fitzherbert Edward
Price of Glamahely Robert Griffithes Arthur Weaver William Browne Edward Herbert Esq[ui]rs Evan Vaughan
Llodowicke Lewis John Bright of Mellington Meredith Lloyd of Brinellyn John Oakeley Rowland Oakley Edward
Wittingham Samuell Biggs Humphrey Nicholas John Lloyd of Cowney Hugh Davies of Trewilin Ellis Lloyd
John Bunner Henry Griffithes of Benthall Morgan Evans Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s95">
		<head>Haverford West</head>
		<para id="p158">For the Towne and County of Haverford West. The Maior for the time being Sir William Moreton Knight
one of his Majestyes Sergiants at Law Sir John Stepney Baronet Sir Hugh Owen Knight and Baronet Rowland
Langhorne William Phillips Richard Walter George Howard Thomas Cozens Esq[ui]rs William Williams Henry
Bowen Lewis Baron John Williams William Browne Aldermen William Davies Es&bhoqexc; John. Barlow John Thomas
Mathew Prynn William Williams junior John Lloyd Richard Jones Gabriell Wade Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s96">
		<head>Pembrooke</head>
		<para id="p159">For the County of Pembrooke Sir William Moreton Knight one of his Majestyes Sergiants at Law Sir Erasmus
Phillips Sir John Stepney Baronets Sir Hugh Owen Sir John Lort Knights and Baronets Sir Harbert Perrot Knight
Griffith Dawes Arthur Owen Essex Megrick Rowland Llanghome Hugh Owen Lewis Barlow Hugh Bowen Henry
White William Phillips Walter Cuny James Bowen Isaac Lloyd George Haward William Scourfield William Mordant
David Morgan Thomas Corbet James Lloyd George Owen Esq[ui]rs Thomas Warren Thomas Powell Hugh Langhorne
Thomas Owen John Mathias John Langhorne Thomas Wogan John Lort William Owen of Cameog Thomas Lloyd
John Thomas.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s97">
		<head>Towne of Pembrooke.</head>
		<para id="p160">For the Towne of Pembrooke The Maior for the time being Mathew Bowen Richard Browne Gentlemen</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s98">
		<head>Towne of Tenby</head>
		<para id="p161">For the Towne of Tenby The Maior for the time being Richard Wiat Rice Barrow David Palmer Gentlemen.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s99">
		<head>Radnor</head>
		<para id="p162">For the County of Radnor Sir Richard Lloyd Knight Arthur Trevor Es&bhoqexc; Sir Henry Williams Baronet Sir Edward
Harley Knight of the Bath Sir Robert Harley Knight George Gwyne Richard Fowler James Price Thomas Corbet
Henry Williams Lewis Morgan John Walcot Thomas Harley Samuell Powell Nicholas Tayler Evan Davies Andrew
Phillips Charles Lewis Henry Probert Herbert Weston James Becke one of his Majestyes Sergiants at Armes. Henry
Stedman Griffith Jones Hugh Powell Richard Meredith Thomas Ecleston Robert Cutler Esq[ui]rs Francis Rickards
John Rickards Rowland Higgens Gent? The Bayliffe of New Radnor for the time being Marmaduke Bull Gentleman.</para>
	</section></section>
	<section id="s100">
		<head>III. Commissioners to meet 10th March;</head>
		<para id="p163">
			<emph type="i">and may divide themselves</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p164">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that the severall C&bhooov;mis?ers aforesaid shall meete together at the most
usuall and c&bhooov;mon place of meeting within each of the said Countyes Cittyes Burrouphes Townes and Places
respe&bholigct;ively on or before the tenth day of March now next ensueing And the said C&bhooov;mis?ers or soe many of them
as shall be present at the said First Generall Meeting or the major part of them are hereby authorized and
required to putt this [Present <ref idref="n54">54</ref>] A&bholigct; in execution according to the best of their Judgements and Discretions and shall
then if they see cause subdivide and distribute themselves soe into lesser numbers as two or more of the said
C&bhooov;mis?ers may be appointed for the service of each Hundred or other Division and as may best conduce to the
carrying on of His Majestyes Service hereby required.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s101">
		<head>IV. Commissioners at their First Meeting to agree what Number are to a&bholigct; in each Division.</head>
		<para id="p165">And for the more effe&bholigct;uall performance thereof Bee it ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the C&bhooov;mis?ers at the aforesaid
First Generall Meeting or the major part of them shall agree and sett downe in writeing who and what number
of the said C&bhooov;mis?ers shall a&bholigct; in each of the said Divisions or Hundreds To the end that there be noe failure in
any part of the due execution of the Service by this A&bholigct; required.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s102">
		<head>V. Two Commissioners may cause Proportions charged on Divisions to be taxed, and to appoint Assessors,</head>
		<para id="p166">
			<emph type="i">The Duty of Assessors</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p167">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed and declared [by the Authority aforesaid <ref idref="n54">54</ref>] That the C&bhooov;mis?ers within the severall Divisions
or Hundreds or any Two or more of them are hereby authorized and required to cause the said severall Proportions
charged on the respe&bholigct;ive Divisions and on every Parish and Place therein for the said three yeares Assessment to
be equally assessed and taxed and to appoint two or more Assessors in each Parish or Place for the perfe&bholigct;ing thereof
who are hereby required with all care and diligence to assesse the same equally by a Pound rate upon all Lands
Tenements Hereditaments Annuities Rents Parkes Warrens Goods Chattells Stocke Merchandize Offices other then
Judiciall and Military Offices and Offices relateing to the Navy under the Command of the Lord High Admirall
and Offices within his Majestyes Household Tolls Proffitts and all other Estates both reall and personall within the
Limitts Circuits and Bounds of their respe&bholigct;ive Parishes and Places.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s103">
		<head>VI. First Payment to Receiver General, and by him into the Exchequer.</head>
		<para id="p168">
			<emph type="i">Second; Third; Fourth; Fifth; Sixth; Seventh; Eighth.; Ninth.; Tenth.; Eleventh.; Twelfth</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p169">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower
hundred fifty and eight pounds six shillings eight pence being the first of the said Twelve quarterly payments
hereby imposed shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid into the Receivour Generall of the said severall
Countyes who shall be appointed by His Majestie And who are hereby required to transmitt or cause the same to
be paid into His Majestyes Receipt of His Exchequer on or before the First day of May in the yeare of our Lord
One thousand six hundred sixty and five And the summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred and
fifty and eight pounds six shillings eight pence being the second of the said Quarterly payments on or before the
First day of August in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty five, And the summe of Two
hundred and six thousand fower hundred and fifty and eight pounds six shillings and eight pence being the third
of the said Quarterly payments on or before the First day of November in the yeare of one Lord One thousand
six hundred sixty five, And the sume of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred and fifty and eight
pounds six shillings [and <ref idref="n55">55</ref>] eight pence being the fourth of the said Quarterly payments on or before the First day of
February in the yeare of our. Lord One thousand six hundred sixty five, And the summe of Two hundred and
six thousand fower hundred and fifty and eight pounds six shillings eight pence being the fifth of the said
Quarterly payments on or before the First day of May in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty
six, And the summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred and fifty and eight pounds six shillings
eight pence being the sixth of the said Quarterly payments on or before the First day of August in the yeare of
our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty six And the summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred
and fifty and eight pounds six shillings eight pence being the seaventh of the said Quarterly payments on or before
the First day of November in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty six And the Summe of Two
hundred and six thousand fower hundred and fifty and eight pounds six shillings eight pence being the eighth
of the said Quarterly payments on or before the First day of February in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred sixty six, And the summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred and fifty and eight
pounds six shillings eight pence being the ninth of the said Quarterly payments on or before the First day of May
in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty seaven, And the summe of Two hundred and six
thousand fower hundred and fifty and eight pounds six shillings eight pence being the tenth of the said Quarterly
payments on or before the First day of August in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty seaven,
And the summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred and fifty and eight pounds six shillings eight
pence being the eleaventh of the said Quarterly payments on or before the First day of November in the yeare of
our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty seaven, And the summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred
and fifty and eight pounds six shillings eight pence being the twelfth of the said Quarterly payments on or before
the First day of February in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred sixty seaven:</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s104">
		<head>VII. Assessors to deliver a Copy of Assessment subscribed by them to Commissioners, who are to sign and seal Two Duplicates thereof, and deliver one to Sub-colle&bholigct;or,</head>
		<para id="p170">
			<emph type="i">and the other to Receiver General, who is to transmit the same to the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p171">And for the compleating of the whole summe charged upon the same, and to the end the aforesaid summes
charged upon the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and places may be equally and
indifferently assessed according to the true intent of this A&bholigct; and the money duely colle&bholigct;ed and true acompt
thereof made the said Assessors are hereby required to deliver one Copy of their respe&bholigct;ive Assesments fairly
written and subscribed by them unto the said C&bhooov;mis?ers and the said C&bhooov;mis?ers or any two or more of them are
hereby ordered and required to signe and seale two Duplicates of the said Assesments, and the one of them to
deliver or cause to be delivered to one or more honest and responsable person or persons to be Sub colle&bholigct;or or
Sub Colle&bholigct;ors which the said C&bhooov;mis?ers are hereby authorized to nominate and appoint for each Parish or place
with Warrant to the said Sub Colle&bholigct;or or Sub Colle&bholigct;ors to colle&bholigct; the said Assesment payable as aforesaid soe
as the said severall summes may be paid in to the said Receivers Generall and by them into the Receipt of his
Majesties Exchequer at the respe&bholigct;ive times aforesaid and the said C&bhooov;mis?ers are hereby required to deliver or
cause to be delivered the other of the said Duplicates of each Parish or place to the Receivour Generall of each
County Citty Towne or place respe&bholigct;ively to be by him the said Receivour Generall transmitted into the Kings
Remembrancers Office in the Exchequer which the said Receiver Generall is required to performe accordingly</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s105">
		<head>VIII. Head Colle&bholigct;or to be appointed by Commissioners.</head>
		<para id="p172">
			<emph type="i">Head Colle&bholigct;or to pay to Receiver General.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p173">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the said C&bhooov;mi?ers in their respe&bholigct;ive Divisions or Hundreds or
any two or more of them shall and are hereby impowered to nominate and appoint under their Hands and Seales
an honest able and responsable person to bee Head colle&bholigct;or unto whom the moneyes received by the Sub
colle&bholigct;or within the Division or Hundred shall from time to time be duely paid, And the said Head colle&bholigct;or is
hereby required upon the receipt thereof to pay the same forthwith to the Receivour Generall of each County
respe&bholigct;ively</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s106">
		<head>IX. Collectors to pay to the Receivers General, who are to transmit Monies to the Exchequer.</head>
		<para id="p174">
			<emph type="i">Salary to Receiver General.; What the Duplicate to be returned into the Exchequer is to contain</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p175">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the perticular Colle&bholigct;ors and Sub Colle&bholigct;ors are hereby required
to pay in all and every the summes soe received by them to the said Receivors Generall aforesaid who are
hereby required [forthwith <ref idref="n56">56</ref>] to transmitt or cause to be paid the moneyes by them received into the Receipt of his
Majesties Exchequer, And the said Lord Tre?r is hereby authorized to allow the said Receivour Generall of each
County Citty and Towne respe&bholigct;ively in case he hath returned up as aforesaid a Duplicate of the Assesment. of
each Parish or place in County Citty or Towne for which he is appointed Receivour Generall a Sallary for his
paines not exceeding one penny in the pound upon the clearing of his Accompt which Duplicate soe to be returned
into the Kings Remembrancers Office in the Exchequer is intended to containe noe more then the summes in grosse
to be colle&bholigct;ed by each Sub Colle&bholigct;or and the severall Names of the said Sub Colle&bholigct;ors.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s107">
		<head>X. Allowance to Sub-colle&bholigct;ors 1d. in the Pound, to be paid by Head Colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
		<para id="p176">
			<emph type="i">Allowance to Head Colle&bholigct;ors 1d. in the Pound, to be paid by Receiver General.; Allowance to Commissioners Clerks 1d. in the Pound, to be paid by Receiver General</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p177">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared that the Sub Colle&bholigct;ors of each Parish or place which shall
be appointed by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall (<ref idref="n57">57</ref>) upon colle&bholigct;ion of the whole Summe appointed to be colle&bholigct;ed by them
and payment thereof as is hereby and before appointed have and receive for their paines in colle&bholigct;ing and paying
the moneyes one penny in the pound which the said severall Head Colle&bholigct;ors are hereby authorized to pay unto
them, and the severall Head Colle&bholigct;ors which shall be appointed by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall upon the payment of
the whole summe due from their Hundred or Division to the Receiver Generall of each County have and receive
for their paines in receiving and paying the said moneyes one penny in the pound which each [Receiour<ref idref="n58">58</ref>] Generall
is hereby authorized to pay and allow unto them accordingly, and alsoe upon Receipt of the whole Assesment
of the County Citty or Towne for which he is appointed Receivour Generall in case he hath, received the severall
Duplicates of each Parish or place therein and not otherwise to allow and pay according to such Warrant as
shall be in that behalfe given by the said C&bhooov;mis?ers or any three of them one penny in the pound for the
C&bhooov;mis?ers Clerkes for their paines in faire writeing the Assesments Duplicates and Copies.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s108">
		<head>XI. No Head Colle&bholigct;ors to be appointed in Cities, &amp;c. where there is a Receiver General, except London.</head>
		<para id="p178">Provided That noe Head Colle&bholigct;ors shall be appointed for any Citty or Towne which is by this A&bholigct; perticularly
charged with the payment of any summe towards the Assesment hereby to be levyed and for which a Receivour
Generall is to be appointed excepting within the Citty of London.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s109">
		<head>XII. Refusing to pay Assessment ;</head>
		<para id="p179">
			<emph type="i">Distress; Colle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. in the Day-time may break open Houses, Chests, &amp;c. upon Warrant from Commissioners, calling to their Assistance Constables, &amp;c. who are to be aiding; Commissioners to settle Questions arising upon Distress.; Refusing, &amp;c. to pay, conveying away Goods, &amp;c. Imprisonment.; Proviso for Peers.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p180">And be it ena&bholigct;ed and declared That if any person shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to pay any summe of money
whereat he shall be rated or assessed That then it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Colle&bholigct;ors
Subcolle&bholigct;ors or any of them who are hereby authorized and required thereunto to leavy the summe assessed by,
distresse and sale of the Goods of such persons soe refuseing or negcle&bholigct;ing to pay dedu&bholigct;ing the summe assessed
and reasonable charges of destraining and restore the Overplus to the Owner thereof And to breake open in the.
day time any house, and upon Warrant under the Hands and Seales of two or more of the said C&bhooov;mis?ers any
Chest Trunke or Box or other things where any such Goods are and to call to their assistance the Constables,
Tythingmen and Headboroughes within the Countyes Cittyes Townes or places where any refusall negcle&bholigct; or
resistance shall be made which said Officers and Forces are hereby required to be aiding and assisting in the
Premisses as they will answere the contrary at their perrills, And if any question or difference happen upon
takeing of such Distresses betweene the partyes distressed or distrained the same shall be ended and determined by
the said C&bhooov;mis?ers or any two or more of them, And if any person or persons shall refuse or negcle&bholigct; to pay
his or their Assesment and convey his or their Goods or other personall Estate whereby the summe of money
soe assessed cannot be levyed according to this A&bholigct; then the respe&bholigct;ive C&bhooov;mis?ers or any two or more of them are
hereby authorized to imprison the person (except a Peere or Peeres of this Realme) and him and them in Prison
to detaine and keepe untill the money soe assessed and the charges for the bringing in the same be paid and
satisfied and noe longer.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s110">
		<head>XIII. Tenants may pay the Tax and dedu&bholigct; out of Rent.</head>
		<para id="p181">
			<emph type="i">Landlords to allow Dedu&bholigct;ion</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p182">And the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Tenants or Tenant of all Houses and Lands which shall be rated by vertue of
this A&bholigct; are hereby required and authorized to pay such Summe or Summes of Money as shall be rated upon such
House or Lands and to dedu&bholigct; out of the Rent soe much of the said Rates as in respe&bholigct; of the said Rents of
every such House and Lands the Landlord should or ought to pay and beare And the said Landlords' both
mediate and i&bhomov;ediate according to their respe&bholigct;ive Interests are hereby required to allow such Dedu&bholigct;ions and
Payments upon the receipt of the residue of the Rents.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s111">
		<head>XIV. Acquittance to Tenant paying.</head>
		<para id="p183">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners to decide Differences between Landlord and Tenant</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p184">And it is ena&bholigct;ed and declared That every Tenant paying the said Assessment shall be acquitted and discharged
for soe much Money as the said Assesment shall amount unto as if the same had beene a&bholigct;ually paid unto such
person or persons unto whom his Rents should have beene due and payable And if any difference shall arise
betweene Landlord and Tennant or any other concerning the said Rates the said severall Co&bhooov;mis?ers or any two or
more of them in their severall Divisions shall and have hereby power to setle the same as they shall thinke fitt,</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s112">
		<head>XV. Persons over-rated Commissioners may relieve.</head>
		<para id="p185">
			<emph type="i">If Proportions not fully assessed, or Persons charged not of Ability, or Assessment on empty House, or Assessment not paid to Receiver General; Re-assessment, &amp;c.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p186">And if any person or persons shall finde him or themselves agreved in that the Assessors have overrated him
or them and shall within six dayes after demand made of the summe of money assessed on him or them complaine
to two or more Co&bhooov;mis?ers whereof one of the Co&bhooov;mis?ers who signed or allowed his or their Assesment to be one,
the said Co&bhooov;mis?ers or any two or more of them shall have and have hereby power within Twelve dayes after the
demand of the Assessment as aforesaid to releive such person or persons and to charge the same on such other
person or persons as they shall see cause, And in case the proportions sett by this A&bholigct; upon all and every the
respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Townes and Places shall not be fully assessed leavyed and paid according to the true
meaning thereof or that if any of the said Assessments shall be rated and imposed upon any person not being of
ability to pay the same, or upon any empty or void House or Land where the same [can<ref idref="n59">59</ref>] not be colle&bholigct;ed or levyed,
or that through any wilfulnes negligence or mistake or accident the said Assesment charged upon each County
Citty Towne or Place by vertue of this A&bholigct; happens not to be paid to the Receivour Generall of the respe&bholigct;ive
Countyes as in this A&bholigct; is directed that then in all and every such cases the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Co&bhooov;mis?ers
Assessors and Colle&bholigct;ors aforesaid and every of them respe&bholigct;ively are hereby authorized and required to assesse or
reassesse or cause to be assessed or reassessed levyed and paid all and every such summe or summes of money
upon the respective Countyes Cittyes Townes and Places or upon any of the Divisions Hundreds and Parishes
therein as to the said Co&bhooov;mis?ers or such number of them as by this A&bholigct; are authorized to cause the first Assesment
hereby required to be made shall seeme most agreable to equity and justice, the said new Assesment to be made
colle&bholigct;ed and paid in such manner and by such meanes as in this A&bholigct; for this Assesment is declared and dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s113">
		<head>XVI. Officers neglecting Duty;</head>
		<para id="p187">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners may fine, not exceeding &pound;20; Fines paid to Receiver General, and by him into Exchequer.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p188">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any person or persons shall wilfully
negcle&bholigct; or refuse to performe his or their duty in the [true<ref idref="n60">60</ref>] and speedy execution of this present A&bholigct; the said
respe&bholigct;ive C&bhooov;mis?ers or any Three or more of them have hereby power to impose on such person or persons soe
refuseing or negcle&bholigct;ing their dutyes such Fine or Fines as to them shall be thought fitt and to cause the same to
be levyed by Distresse and Sale of his and their Goods Provided that noe Fine to be imposed by any of the said
Co&bhooov;mis?ers shall for any one Offence exceed the summe of Twenty pounds, And that all Fines that shall be
imposed by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be paid to the respe&bholigct;ive Receivours Generall and by them to the Receipt
of His Majestyes Exchequer</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s114">
		<head>XVII. Collector not paying Monies received by him;</head>
		<para id="p189">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners may imprison and seize Real and Personal Estate; and may appoint a general Meeting of Commissioners on Notice; and if Monies not paid, may sell the said Estates for Payment, of Commreturning Overplus,</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p190">And it is further enacted and declared That if any Colle&bholigct;or or Subcollector that shall by vertue of this Act
be appointed for the receipt of any summe or summes of money thereby to be assessed shall negcle&bholigct; or refuse
to pay any summe or summes of money which shall by him be received as aforesaid and not pay the same as in and by
this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed and shall detaine in his or their hands any money received by them or any of them and not
pay the same as by this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed, the Comissers of each County Citty or Towne respe&bholigct;ively or any Two
or more of them in their respe&bholigct;ive Divisions are hereby authorized and impowered to imprison the person and
seize and secure the Estate both reall and personall of such Colle&bholigct;or or Subcolle&bholigct;or to them respe&bholigct;ively belonging
or which shall descend or come into the hands or possession of their Heires Executors or Administrators where
ever the same can be discovered and found, And the said Co&bhooov;mis?ers who shall soe seize and secure the Estate
of any Colle&bholigct;or or Subcollector shall be and are hereby impowered to appoint a time for the Generall Meeting
of the [said<ref idref="n61">61</ref>] Co&bhooov;mis?ers of such County Citty or Towne and there to cause publique notice to be given at the place
where such Meeting shall be appointed ten dayes at least before such Generall Meeting, and the Co&bhooov;mis?ers present
at such Generall Meeting or the major part of them in case the moneyes detained by Colle&bholigct;ors or Subcolle&bholigct;ors
be not paid or satisfied as it ought to be according to the directions of this A&bholigct; shall and are hereby impowered
and required to sell and dispose of all such Estates which shall be for the cause aforesaid seised and secured or
any part of them and satisfie and pay such County and Place the Summe that shall be soe detained in the hands
of such Colle&bholigct;or or Subcollector and returne the Overplus deducting necessary charges to such Colle&bholigct;or or
Subcolle&bholigct;or their Heires Executors and Administrators respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s115">
		<head>XVIII. Commissioners to call Collectors, &amp;c; before them to account;</head>
		<para id="p191">
			<emph type="i">and in case of Failure of Monies, to levy the same forthwith.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p192">And it is hereby further enacted and declared That at the expiration of the respe&bholigct;ive times in this A&bholigct;
prescribed for the full payment of the said quarterly Assesments the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Co&bhooov;mis?ers or any
Two of them within their Division and Hundred shall and are hereby required to call before them the cheife
Colle&bholigct;ors and Subcolle&bholigct;ors within each respective Division and Hundred to examine and assure themselves of the
full and whole payment of the perticular Summe and Summes of Money charged upon the said Division Hundred
and every Parish and Place therein and of the due Returne of the same into the Hands of the Receivour Generall
of the said County Citty Towne and Place respe&bholigct;ively, And by such Receivour Generall to the Receipt of His
Majestyes Exchequer to the end there may be noe failure in the payment of any part of the Assesment by
vertue of this Act to be assessed and paid nor any Arreares remaine chargeable upon any [the said<ref idref="n62">62</ref>] Countyes
Cittyes Townes or Places respe&bholigct;ively And in case of any failure in the Premisses the said Co&bhooov;mis?ers or any Two
of them are hereby to cause the same to be forthwith leavyed and paid according to the true intent and meaning
of this A&bholigct;.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s116">
		<head>XIX. Commissioners not to vote in their own Case.</head>
		<para id="p193">And it is hereby, ena&bholigct;ed and declared That in case any Controversy arise concerning the said Assesments or
the dividing apportioning or payment thereof which concerne any of the Co&bhooov;mis?ers by this A&bholigct; appointed, that
the C&bhooov;mis?ers soe concerned in the said Controversie shall have noe Voice but shall withdraw at the time of the
Debate of any such Controversie untill it be determined by the rest of the Co&bhooov;mis?ers.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s117">
		<head>XX. Privileged Places, &amp;c. liable.</head>
		<para id="p194">
			<emph type="i">Tenants of Fee Farm Rents, &amp;c. to pay.; Indemnity to such Tenants.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p195">And bee it hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That noe Priviledge Place or Person Body Pollitique or Corporate within
the Countyes Cittyes and Townes aforesaid shall be exempted from the said Assessments and Taxes and that they
and every of them and alsoe all Fee Farme Rents and all other manner of Rents Payments Summes of Moneyes
and Annuities issueing out of any Lands within Citty or County shall be lyeable towards the payment of every
Summe by this A&bholigct; to be taxed and leavyed, And all the Tennants of any Fee Farme Rent other Rent summes
of Money or Annuityes aforesaid are hereby dire&bholigct;ed and authorized to pay them proportionably according to the
Rates and Assesments by this A&bholigct; appointed and dire&bholigct;ed And all such Tennants shall be hereby saved and
kepte harmelesse by authoritie of this A&bholigct; from any further payment of such portion of (<ref idref="n62">62</ref>) such Rent Rents Summes
or Annuityes either to the Exchequer or to any other person or persons to whom any such Rent Rents Summes
of Moneyes or Annuityes as aforesaid should or ought to be paid to all intents and purposes whatsoever as fully
and as amply as if they had paid the same into the Exchequer or to any person or persons to whom the same
is reserved or become due</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s118">
		<head>XXI. Proviso for Universities, Colleges of Windsor, Eaton, &amp;c. Hospitals, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p196">
			<emph type="i">and for Christ's Hospital, and other Hospitals in London and Southwark.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p197">Provided That noe thing contained in this A&bholigct; shall be extended to charge any Colledge or Hall in either of
the Universities or the Colledges of Windsor Eaton Winton or Westminster or any Hospitalls for or in respe&bholigct; of
the Scites of the said Colledges [or<ref idref="n63">63</ref>] Halls or Hospitalls nor any Master Fellow or Scholler of any such Colledge
or Hall or in any other Free Schooles or any Reader Officer or Minister of the said Universities Colledges or
Schooles or of any Hospitalls or Almes houses for or in respe&bholigct; of any stipend wages or proffitt whatsoever ariseing
or growing due to them in respe&bholigct; of the said severall Places and Imployments in the said Universities Colledges
Schooles Hospitalls or Almeshouses nor to charge any of the Houses or Lands belonging to Christs Hospitall
St Bartholimews Bridewell St Thomas and Bethlem Hospitall in the Citty of London and Burrough of Southwarke
or any of them for or in respe&bholigct; of any Rents or Revenues payable to the said Hospitalls being to be received
and disbursed for the immediate use and releife of the poore in the said Hospitalls.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s119">
		<head>XXII. Tenants of such Hospitals to pay.</head>
		<para id="p198">Provided That noe Tennants that hold or enjoy any Lands or Houses by Lease or any other grant from any
of the said Hospitalls doe claime and enjoy any freedome exemption or advantage by this A&bholigct; but that all the
Houses and Lands which they soe hold shall be rated and assessed for soe much as they are yearely worth over
and above the Rents reserved and payable to the said Hospitalls.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s120">
		<head>XXIII. Persons in London to be taxed in Parish where they live for Goods, &amp;c. in other Parishes, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p199">Provided alsoe That where any person inhabiting within the Citty of London hath his Dwelling house in one
of the Parishes or Wards therein and hath any Goods Wares or Merchandize in one or more of the other Parishes
or Wards within the same that then such person shall be charged taxed and assessed for such his Goods or
Merchandize in the Parish or Ward where he dweleth and not elsewhere in the said Citty.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s121">
		<head>XXIV. The whole Sum to be levied.</head>
		<para id="p200">
			<emph type="i">Commissioners to account</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p201">Provided neverthelesse That noe Clause or Provisoe in this A&bholigct; shall extend to the lessening or abatement of
the full summe by this A&bholigct; appointed to be taxed leavyed and paid but that the same be fully assessed taxed
levyed colle&bholigct;ed and paid in the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes and Townes aforesaid in such manner and
forme and to such uses as is herein before mentioned and declared. And that the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Co&bhooov;mis?ers
and every of them shall from time to time give a true and perfe&bholigct; Accompt of all their doeings and proceedings
in the execution of this A&bholigct; to the said Lord Treasurer or to other such persons as His Majestie shall appoint.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s122">
		<head>XXV. In case assessing by a Pound Rate prove prejudicial, then Commissioners to assess by an usual Rate.</head>
		<para id="p202">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That in case the way or manner of assessing by a
Pound rate shall prove any way prejudiciall or obstru&bholigct;ive to the said speedy bringing in of the Assesment or any
part thereof appointed by this A&bholigct; that then and in all such cases the respe&bholigct;ive Co&bhooov;mis?ers or any two of them
are hereby authorized to order and dire&bholigct; their respe&bholigct;ive Assessors who are hereby required to proceede accordingly
to assesse the respe&bholigct;ive summes charged on the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes and Burroughes Townes and Places
mentioned in this A&bholigct; according to the most just and usuall way of Rates held and pra&bholigct;ised in such Countyes
Cittyes Burroughes Townes and places respe&bholigct;ively Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof contained in any
wise notwithstanding</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s123">
		<head>XXVI. Proviso for Covenants, &amp;c. between Landlord and Tenant.</head>
		<para id="p203">Provided alwayes That noe thing in this A&bholigct; contained shall be construed to alter change determine or make
void any Contra&bholigct;s Covenants or Agreements whatsoever betweene the Landlord and Tennant touching the payment
of Taxes or Assesments Any thing herein before mentioned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s124">
		<head>XXVII. Places rated to pay and he assessed in such County, &amp;c. as heretofore.</head>
		<para id="p204">Provided alwayes and be it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authority aforesaid That for the avoiding of
all obstru&bholigct;ions and delayes in colle&bholigct;ing the summes by this A&bholigct; to be rated and assessed all Places Constablewicks
Divisions and Allotments which have used to be rated and assessed shall pay and be assessed in such County
Hundred Rape and Wapentake as the same hath heretofore usually beene assessed in and not elsewhere.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s125">
		<head>XXVIII. In A&bholigct;ion for executing A&bholigct; General Issue may be pleaded.</head>
		<para id="p205">
			<emph type="i">Treble Costs.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p206">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion Plaint Suite or Information shall be
commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in execution
of this A&bholigct; such person or persons [soe sued in any Court<ref idref="n63">63</ref>] whatsoever shall or may pleade the Generall Issue Not guilty And upon any Issue joyned may give this A&bholigct; and the speciall matter in Evidence And if the Plaintiffe
or Prosecutor shall become Non suite or forbeare further Prosecution or suffer Discontinuance or if a Verdi&bholigct; passe
against him the Defendants shall recover their Treble Costs for which they shall have the like remedy as in any
case where Costs by the Law are given to Defendants.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s126">
		<head>XXIX. Proviso in respe&bholigct; of a Decree in Chancery, as to Lands in Sheriff Hales in the County of Salop.</head>
		<para id="p207">Provided alwayes That noe thing in this A&bholigct; shall extend or be construed to invalidate a Decree lately made
in the High Court of Chauncery for the quieting of Suites betweene the Counties of Salop and Stafford and for
the setleing all future Payments to be imposed on certaine Lands in Sheriffe Hales with the County of Salop And
for exempting the said Lands from paying hereafter with the County of Stafford But that the said Decree shall
remaine in such (and noe other) force as it did before the makeing of this A&bholigct; Any thing herein to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s127">
		<head>XXX. Spiritual Revenues chargeable by this A&bholigct; to be discharged from the two last of the Four Subsidies granted by the Clergy, by 15 Car. II. c. 10.</head>
		<para id="p208">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Spirituall Promotions and all Lands
Possessions or Revenues annexed to and all Goods and Chattells growing or renewed upon the same or elsewhere
appertaining to the Owners of the said Spirituall Promotions or any of them which are or shall be charged or
made contributary by this A&bholigct; towards the Payments aforesaid dureing the time therein appointed shall be
absolutely freed and discharged from the two last of the fower Subsidyes granted by the Clergy to His Majestie
His Heires and Successors by an A&bholigct; made in a former Session of this present Parlyament entituled An A&bholigct; for
confirming of fower Subsidyes granted by the Clergy Any clause or thing in the said A&bholigct; to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s128">
		<head>XXXI. Head Colle&bholigct;ors to give Acquittances to Sub-colle&bholigct;ors without Fee.</head>
		<para id="p209">
			<emph type="i">Receivers General to give Acquittances to Head Colle&bholigct;ors without Fee.; Such Acquittances to be a full Discharge to such Colle&bholigct;ors, and also to Place, &amp;c. charged.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p210">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the severall Head Colle&bholigct;ors which shall
be appointed according to this A&bholigct; shall from time to time at every Payment appointed thereby give unto the
severall Sub Colle&bholigct;ors within their respe&bholigct;ive Precin&bholigct;s upon the Payment of the whole Summe due at such times
of Payment from their respe&bholigct;ive Parishes Constablewicks or places within each of their Colle&bholigct;ions severall
Acquittances under their Hands without takeing any thing for the same And that in like manner at every time of
payment appointed by this A&bholigct; the Receivour Generall of each County shall give unto the severall Headcolle&bholigct;ors
aforesaid upon the payment of the whole Summe due for their Hundred or Division respe&bholigct;ively at each time [of
payment<ref idref="n64">64</ref>] aforesaid severall Acquittances under their Hands and Seales without takeing any thing for the same which
said Acquittances of the Headcolle&bholigct;ors shall be a full and perfe&bholigct; discharge to the Sub Colle&bholigct;ors. And the said
Acquittances of the Receivour Generall shall be a sufficient discharge to the Headcolle&bholigct;ors and to such Hundred
Division Constablewicke Parish or place respe&bholigct;ively and to every person charged within the said Sub Colle&bholigct;ors or
Head Colle&bholigct;ors Charge against His Majestie His Heires and Successors for the summe or summes of money
soe acquitted</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s129">
		<head>XXXII. Remedy against Land or House void of Distress.</head>
		<para id="p211">Provided alwayes and be it further ena&bholigct;ed That in case any Lands or Houses in any Parish Place or Constablewicke
shall lye unoccupyed and noe distresse can be found on the same by reason whereof the said Parish Place or
Constablewicke are forced to pay and make good the Taxe assessed upon such Lands lyeing unoccupyed That then
it shall and may be lawfull at any time [after<ref idref="n64">64</ref>] for the Colle&bholigct;ors Constable or Tythingman of the said Parish Place
or Constablewicke for the time being to enter and destraine upon the said Lands and Houses when there shall be
any Distresse thereupon to be found, And the Distresse and Distresses being the proper Goods of the Owner or
any claiming any Estate Interest or Proffitt under him if not redeemed within fower dayes by payment of the Tax
and Charge of (<ref idref="n65">65</ref>) Distresse to sell rendering the Overplus to the Owners or Owners of such Distresse, And the said
Colle&bholigct;or Constable or Tythingman is hereby enjoyned to distribute the money raised by the said Distresse or Sale
thereof proportionably to the partyes who contributed to the Taxe of the said unoccupyed Lands</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s130">
		<head>XXXIII. When Woodlands assessed, and no Distress, Subcolle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. may cut and sell to pay Assessment.</head>
		<para id="p212">
			<emph type="i">Vendee may cut and sell.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p213">Provided alwayes and be it ena&bholigct;ed that where any Woodlands shall be assessed and noe Distresse can be had
that in such case it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Sub Colle&bholigct;or Constable [Headborough<ref idref="n64">64</ref>] or Tythingman
by Warrant under the Hands and Seales of two or more of the Co&bhooov;mis?ers in that Hundred or Division at seasonable
time of the yeare to cutt and sell to any person or persons soe much of the Wood growing on the said Woodlands
soe assessed as will pay the Assesment [and<ref idref="n66">66</ref>] Assesments soe behinde and unpaid and the Charge incident thereto,
And that it shall and may be lawfull for the person and persons and his Assignee to whom such Wood shall be
soe sold to sell cutt downe dispose and carry away the same to his owne use rendering the Overplus if any be
to the Owner Any Law to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s131">
		<head>XXXIV. Where Assessment on Tithes and other Profits not distrainable not paid, Sub-colle&bholigct;or, &amp;c. may seize and sell.</head>
		<para id="p214">Provided alwayes and be it further ena&bholigct;ed That where any Taxe or Assesment shall be charged or laid upon
any Tythes Tolls Proffitts of Markets Faires or Fishery or other Annuall Proffitts not destrainable in case the same
shall not be paid within fifteene dayes after such Assesment soe charged or laid and demanded then it shall be lawfull
to and for the Sub Colle&bholigct;or Constable or other Officer thereunto appointed by Warrant under the Hands and
Seales of any two or more of the Co&bhooov;mis?ers authorized by this A&bholigct; to seise take and sell soe much of the said
Tythes Tolls and other Proffitts soe charged as shall be sufficient for the leavying of the said Taxe and Assesment
and all Charges occasioned by such Non payment thereof rendering the Overplus to the Owner if any be.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s132">
		<head>XXXV. Commissioners for Middlesex and Westminster may appoint Assessors.</head>
		<para id="p215">
			<emph type="i">who are to ascertain and rate Offices, Townships, &amp;c. chargeable, and to return the same to the Commissioners.; Such Assessors to deliver in their Surveys signed to Commissioners.; Commissioners at General Meeting, on Perusal of Surveys, are to cast up the true Revenue of the County, &amp;c., and to apportion a Pound Rate.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p216">And whereas the County of Midlesex and Citty of Westminster are raised in the Monethly Assesment by reason
of the new buildings lately ere&bholigct;ed And that Offices are made chargeable towards the payment of such Assesment
To the end that an equall rate may be made and imposed upon the severall Divisions Parishes and Hamblets within
the said County and Citty Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by this present Parliament and by the Authority thereof That the said
C&bhooov;missers appointed for the said County and Citty of Westminster [or any Three of them<ref idref="n67">67</ref>] shall if they shall thinke
it fitt cause two or three of the honest and able Inhabitants in the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Parishes Towneshipps
and Places within the said County and Citty to be named and appointed Assessors who (or any two of them)
are to ascertaine and rate the yearely value and proffitts of all Offices belonging to the Courts of Westminster
and other Offices chargeable by this A&bholigct; towards the payment of the said summe sett upon the said County and
Citty and all Towneshipps Parishes and Places for which they be appointed Assessors and to returne the same
to the said C&bhooov;mis?sers or to such person or persons as shall be appointed to receive the same, which said Assessors are
to deliver in their severall Surveyes perfe&bholigct;ed and subscribed by them unto the said C&bhooov;mis?ners or to such [other<ref idref="n68">68</ref>]
person or persons as shall be appointed by them or any three of them to receive the same two or three dayes
at the least before the second Generall Meeting of the said C&bhooov;mis?ers to the end that the said C&bhooov;mis?ers may
deliver in all the severall Surveyes to be made throughout the said County at the said second Generall Meeting,
at which said Generall Meeting the, said Co&bhooov;mis?ers or the major part of them then present shall upon view and
perusall of the said severall Surveyes cast up the true revenue and yearely proffitts of the whole County Citty and
Offices aforesaid to the end that an equall Pound rate may be apportioned upon every Office chargeable by this
A&bholigct; Division Hundred Towneship and Parish according to the proportion and summe of money charged upon
the said County and Citty by vertue of this present A&bholigct; which the said Co&bhooov;mis?ers or the major part of them
then and there assembled are by vertue of this A&bholigct; authorized and appointed to [apportion<ref idref="n69">69</ref>] and make accordingly.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s133">
		<head>XXXVI. Proviso for Rights of Peers, Clergy, Universities, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p217">[Provided alwayes That noe thing herein contained shall be drawne into example to the prejudice of the Auntient
Rights belonging unto the Lords Spirituall and Temporall or Clergy of this Realme or unto either of the Universityes
or unto any Colledges Schooles Almeshouses Hospitalls or Cinque Ports.,<ref idref="n70">70</ref>]</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">One <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">Wenman <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">This Name is illegible on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">Dagrell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">Tatton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n7" number="7">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n8" number="8">Richard <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n11" number="11">Cholcester <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n12" number="12">Herbert.</note>
		<note id="n13" number="13">Harlakenden <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n14" number="14">Master <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n15" number="15">Cottle <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n16" number="16">Gulstone <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n17" number="17">Heith <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n18" number="18">Bindloss <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n19" number="19">Nowell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n20" number="20">Greenehalgh <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n21" number="21">Gelson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n22" number="22">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n23" number="23">Windham <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n24" number="24">Cotterell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n25" number="25">Herbert <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n26" number="26">De <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n27" number="27">Persfeild <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n28" number="28">Ancestill <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n29" number="29">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n30" number="30">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n31" number="31">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n32" number="32">Batchelour <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n33" number="33">Croke <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n34" number="34">Jenkins <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n35" number="35">Court <emph type="i">O</emph>. the name is not clearly legible on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n36" number="36">Ashburaham <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n37" number="37">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n38" number="38">Pavensey <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n39" number="39">Finch <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n40" number="40">Busshell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n41" number="41">S<emph type="p">r</emph>
			<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n42" number="42">Maskelyn <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n43" number="43">interlined on the Roil.</note>
		<note id="n44" number="44">Gresly <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n45" number="45">Oviate <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n46" number="46">Nevinson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n47" number="47">Wyvell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n48" number="48">Alanson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n49" number="49">Bankins <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n50" number="50">Brunddy <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n51" number="51">Llanvaythly <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n52" number="52">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n53" number="53">Caredvynydd <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n54" number="54">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n55" number="55">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n56" number="56">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n57" number="57">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n58" number="58">Receivor <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n59" number="59">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n60" number="60">due <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n61" number="61">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n62" number="62">any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n63" number="63">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n64" number="64">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n65" number="65">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n66" number="66">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n67" number="67">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n68" number="68">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n69" number="69">proportion <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n70" number="70">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
	</section>
</report>


