<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47374" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1665</title>
	<subtitle>An Act for granting the summe of Twelve hundred and fiftie thousand pounds to the Kings Majestie for His present further Supply [Rot. Parl. 17 C. II. nu. 1]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Recital of 16 (16 &amp; 17) Car. II. c. 1.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Wee Your Majestyes most dutyfull and Loyall Subje&bholigct;s the Commons assembled in Parlyament haveing observed
the Wayes and Meanes by which Your Majestie hath beene enforced to ingage Yourselfe in a Warr against
the States of the United Provinces for the necessary Defence of your owne Crowne and Dignitie and the Safetie
and Welfaire of Your People Doe with all humble Thankfulnes acknowledge Your Majestyes Care and Condu&bholigct; in
this great Affaire, which, as it hath beene already attended with very considerable Successe soe we shall dayly pray
that all Your Majesties Enterprizes may still be crowned with Honour and Vi&bholigct;ory And although the continuing
[Insolencies<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of Your Majestyes Enimies and the doubtfull Amity of some of Your Majesties Neighbours hath made it
necessary to provide for further and greater Expences in a time when the generall Contagion hath much interrupted
our Trade and Commerce Yet that Your Majestie may see that wee Your Majesties Loyall Subje&bholigct;s doe more
consider our Zeale and Duty to Your Majestie then any difficulties under which wee labour Wee have chearefully
and unanimously given and granted and by these presents doe give and grant unto Your most Excellent Majestie
the summe of Twelve hundred and fifty thousand pounds to be raised and leavyed in manner following And we
doe most humbly beseech Your Majestie That it may be ena&bholigct;ed And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most. Excellent
Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Commons in this
present Parliament assembled and by [the<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] Authority of the same That the summe of Twelve hundred and fiftie
thousand pounds shall be raised leavyed and paid unto Your Majestie within the space of Two yeares in manner
following That is to say Whereas in and by a certaine A&bholigct; of Parliament lately passed intituled An A&bholigct; for granting
a Royall Ayde unto the Kings Majestie of Twenty fower hundred threescore and seaventeene thousand and five
hundred pounds to be raised leavyed and paid in the space of Three yeares. It was amongst other things ena&bholigct;ed.
That the summe of Threescore and eight thousand eight hundred and nineteene pounds and nine shillings by
the moneth for Thirty six monethes begining from the Five and twentyeth day of December One thousand six
hundred sixtie [and<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] fower should be assessed taxed colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid by Twelve Quarterly payments in the
severall Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and places within England and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede according to the severall Rates and Proportions and in such [manner<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] as in the said A&bholigct; is expressed,
One yeares payment whereof that is to say Fower quarterly Payments will be fully expired upon the Five and
twentyeth day of December in the yeare of our Lord One thousand, six hundred sixtie five, and two yeares
payment more will be then to come and unexpired</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Grant of the Tax by Payments of &pound;52,083. 6s. 8d. by the Month for 24 Months.</head>
		<para id="p3">It is now further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the summe of Fifty two thousand fowerscore and
three pounds six shillings and eight pence by the moneth for Twenty fower monethes begining from the five and
twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred sixtie five shall be assessed taxed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and
paid by eight quarterly payments in the severall Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places within England
and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede over and above the summe of Threescore and eight thousand
eight hundred and nineteene pounds and nine shillings by the moneth which is to remaine and continue payable
dureing the said twenty fower monethes by vertue of the said former A&bholigct; and as an Addition to, and increase
of the said monethly Assessment according to these further Rates Rules and Proportions in such manner as herein
after is expressed that is to say for every of the said Twenty fower monethes</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s3">
		<head>Rates of Counties.</head>
		<para id="p4">For the County of Bedford the summe of Six hundred seaventy eight pounds fowerteene shillings nine pence
farthing.</para>
		<para id="p5">The County of Berks Eight hundred fifty six pounds eighteene shillings two pence three farthings.</para>
		<para id="p6">The County of Bucks Nine hundred ninety five pounds seaven shillings ten pence.</para>
		<para id="p7">The County of Cambridge the summe of Seaven hundred seaventy one pounds eighteene shillings one penny
farthing.</para>
		<para id="p8">The Isle of Ely Two hundred sixty fower pounds fifteene shillings ten pence.</para>
		<para id="p9">The County of Chester with the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester the summe of Six hundred and six
pounds seaven shillings seaven pence.</para>
		<para id="p10">The County of Cornwall the summe of One thousand one hundred sixty six pounds two shillings fower pence
farthing.</para>
		<para id="p11">The County of Cumberland the summe of One hundred twenty seaven pounds seaven shillings three pence
farthing.</para>
		<para id="p12">The County of Derby the summe of Six hundred fifty two pounds twelve shillings eleaven pence three
farthings.</para>
		<para id="p13">The County of Devon the summe of Two thousand fower hundred forty fower pounds six shillings nine pence
farthing.</para>
		<para id="p14">The Citty and County of the Citty of Exon the summe of Eighty eight pounds one shilling two pence
farthing.</para>
		<para id="p15">The County of Dorset the summe of One thousand and seaventeene pounds nine shillings nine pence
halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p16">The Towne and County of Poole the summe of Eight pounds six shillings three pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p17">The County of Durham the summe of Two hundred forty five pounds one shilling five pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p18">The County of Yorke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke and Towne (<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) of Kingstone upon Hull
the summe of Two thousand six hundred twenty five pounds eight shillings seaven pence three farthings.</para>
		<para id="p19">The County of Essex the summe of Two thousand three hundred forty fower pounds sixteene shillings one
penny three farthings.</para>
		<para id="p20">The County of Gloucester the summe of One thousand three hundred sixty eight pounds twelve shillings six
pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p21">The Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester the summe of Twenty nine pounds sixteene shillings three
pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p22">The County of Hereford the summe of Eight hundred fifty six pounds eight shillings one penny three
farthings.</para>
		<para id="p23">The County of Hertford the summe of One thousand and eighteene pounds nine shillings five pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p24">The County of Huntington the summe of Fower hundred seaventy nine pounds eleaven shillings fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p25">The County of Kent with the Citty and County of the Citty of Canterbury the summe of Two thousand five
hundred and seaventeene pounds fowerteene shillings six pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p26">The County of Lancaster the summe of Seaven hundred sixty one pounds sixteene shillings fower pence
farthing.</para>
		<para id="p27">The County of Leicester the summe of Eight hundred and twenty pounds seaventeene shillings six pence three
farthings.</para>
		<para id="p28">The County of Lincolne with the Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne the summe of One thousand nine
hundred forty eight pounds fifteene shillings two pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p29">The Citty of London with the [Liberty<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Martine Le Grand the summe of Three thousand eight hundred
fifty three pounds two shillings ten pence three farthings.</para>
		<para id="p30">The County of Midlesex with the Citty and Liberty of Westminster the summe of One thousand six hundred
ninety five pounds ten shillings ten pence.</para>
		<para id="p31">The County of Monouth the summe of Two hundred ninety five pounds two shillings nine pence three
farthings.</para>
		<para id="p32">The County of Northampton the summe of One thousand and seaventy pounds one penny farthing.</para>
		<para id="p33">The County of Nottingham with the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham the summe of Six hundred
and sixty pounds nineteene shillings two pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p34">The County of Norffolke the summe of Two thousand five hundred and fifty pounds fifteene shillings fower
pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p35">The Citty and County of the Citty of Norwich the summe of One hundred thirty six pounds fower shillings
power pence halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p36">The County of Northumberland with the Towne of Newcastle and Berwicke upon Tweede the summe of Two
hundred eighty two pounds two shillings three pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p37">The County of [Oxon<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] the summe of Eight hundred fifty nine pounds six shillings eight pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p38">The County of Rutland the summe of One hundred eighty one pounds nineteene shillings two pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p39">The County of Salop the summe of Nine hundred and ten pounds eighteene shillings six pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p40">The County of Stafford the summe of Six hundred forty five pounds fower shillings three halfe pence.</para>
		<para id="p41">The Citty and County of the Citty of Lichfield the summe of Nine pounds sixteene shillings nine pence
farthing.</para>
		<para id="p42">The County of Somerset the s&bhouov;me of Two thousand ninety seaven pounds eight shillings two pence three
farthings.</para>
		<para id="p43">The Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll the summe of One hundred and fifty pounds eighteene shillings
two pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p44">The County of Southampton with the Towne and County of Southampton and Isle of Wight the summe of One
thousand six hundred fifty six pounds seaventeene shillings and eleaven pence.</para>
		<para id="p45">The County of Suffolke the s&bhouov;me of Two thousand fower hundred ninety six pounds fower shillings seaven pence
farthing.</para>
		<para id="p46">The County of Surrey with the Burrough of Southwarke the summe of One thousand two hundred and eight
pounds eleaven shillings fower pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p47">The County of Sussex the summe of One thousand three hundred seaventy eight pounds seaven shillings fower
pence three farthings.</para>
		<para id="p48">The County of Warwicke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry the summe of Nine hundred and
two pounds seaven shillings and two pence.</para>
		<para id="p49">The County of Worcester the summe of Seaven hundred ninety seaven pounds eleaven shillings and ten pence.</para>
		<para id="p50">The Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester the summe of Forty one pounds nineteene shillings six pence
three farthings.</para>
		<para id="p51">The County of Wilts the s&bhouov;me of One thousand fower hundred eighty eight pounds nine shillings six pence
halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p52">The County of Westmerland the summe of Eighty seaven pounds fifteene shillings eight pence halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p53">The Isle of Anglesea the summe of Ninety five pounds two shillings two pence.</para>
		<para id="p54">The County of Brecknocke the summe of Two hundred thirteene pounds sixteene shillings halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p55">The County of Cardigan the summe of Eighty pounds one shilling two pence farthing.</para>
		<para id="p56">The County of Carmarthen the s&bhouov;me of Two hundred and six pounds three shillings five pence halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p57">The County of Carnarvan the summe of one hundred and ten pounds eighteene shillings ten pence three
farthings.</para>
		<para id="p58">The County of Denbigh the s&bhouov;me of One hundred sixty nine pounds three shillings three halfe-pence.</para>
		<para id="p59">The County of Flint the summe of Eighty nine pounds eighteene shillings eleaven pence three farthings.</para>
		<para id="p60">The County of Glamorgan the summe of Two hundred eighty six pounds sixteene shillings three pence
farthing.</para>
		<para id="p61">The County of Merioneth the summe of Seaventy six [pound<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] five shillings eight pence three farthings.</para>
		<para id="p62">The County of Mountgomery Two hundred and nine pounds six shillings six pence.</para>
		<para id="p63">The County [of<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] Pembrooke the s&bhouov;me of Two hundred forty seaven pounds one shilling seaven pence three
farthings.</para>
		<para id="p64">The County of Radnor the s&bhouov;me of One hundred thirty one pounds eighteene shillings six pence three
farthings.</para>
		<para id="p65">The Towne of Haverford West the summe of Eleaven [pound<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] nine shillings seaven pence.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s4">
		<head>III. Commissioners under the said A&bholigct; to be Commissioners under this A&bholigct; and to have and execute the like Powers, &amp;c.; and all Persons liable to or employed in levying, &amp;c. the Monies imposed by this A&bholigct;; shall be under and subje&bholigct; to the Regulations and Penalties of the former A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p66">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every the persons who are nominated in and
by the said former A&bholigct; to be C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers of and for the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes.
and places therein mentioned shall likewise be and soe are hereby appointed to be C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers for execution of this
present A&bholigct; within the said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and places for which
they were nominated in the aforesaid A&bholigct;, and shall have and execute the like Powers and Authorityes Rules and
Dire&bholigct;ions touching the better assessing colle&bholigct;ing levying receiving and paying the said Fifty two thousand
fowerscore and three pounds six shillings and eight pence by the moneth dureing the said Twenty fower monethes
as in and by the aforesaid A&bholigct; were given to the said C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers touching the better assessing colle&bholigct;ing levying
receiving and paying the said Threescore and eight thousand eight hundred and nineteene pounds and nine
shillings by the moneth payable as aforesaid, And all and every person or persons who shall be lyeable unto or
any waies concerned [or imployed<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] in the assessing colle&bholigct;ing leavying receiving or paying any of the moneyes.
by this A&bholigct; imposed shall have like benefitts advantages and discharges and shall be subje&bholigct; to like penalties and
forfeitures in case of any negcle&bholigct; or refusall to pay their respe&bholigct;ive Assesments or to performe their respe&bholigct;ive
Dutyes as any other person or persons lyeable unto or concerned or imployed in the assesing colle&bholigct;ing leavying
receiving or paying any of the moneyes by the said former A&bholigct; imposed ought to have or be subje&bholigct; unto as
fully and amply as if the same Clauses Matters and things had beene in this A&bholigct; perticularly repeated and ena&bholigct;ed,
To the end that the Monethly Assessments which will remaine due and payable by vertue of the said former A&bholigct;,
and the monethly Additions thereunto made by (<ref idref="n11">11</ref>) vertue of this present A&bholigct; may be duely answered and paid in
as aforesaid.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s5">
		<head>IV. Commissioners to meet 10th January next, and Three Weeks before each Quarterly Payment.</head>
		<para id="p67">
			<emph type="i">Eight Quarterly Payments to be assessed and paid to Receivers of Counties, and by them into the Exchequer as in the said A&bholigct;.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p68">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the severall C&bhooov;mis[sioners shall meete together at the most usuall and c&bhooov;mon
place of meeting as in the said A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed on or before the Tenth day of January next to putt this A&bholigct; and
the said former A&bholigct; in execution according to the best of their Judgements and Discretions, and shall then if they
see cause subdivide themselves as by the said A&bholigct; is further dire&bholigct;ed concerning the said former Assessment.
And further That they meete at least three Weekes before each quarterly Payments [for<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] the said severall Assesments
for the purposes aforesaid, And that the said Eight quarterly Payments of Fifty two thousand fowerscore and three
pounds six shillings &amp; eight pence by the Moneth amounting in each Quarter to the summe of One hundred fifty
six thousand two hundred and fifty pounds shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid to the Receivour of the
severall Countyes appointed or that shall be appointed by His Majestie and by them answered and paid into His
Majestyes Exchequer on the dayes and times mentioned and expressed in the said A&bholigct; for Payment of the said
First Assessment.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s6">
		<head>V. Book to be kept in the Exchequer, and Monies entered separate from Monies raised under the said former A&bholigct;; and also a Book for Payments to Lenders and to Persons furnishing Goods, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p69">And to the intent that all [Moneyes<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] to be lent to Your Majesty and Moneyes that shall be due upon such
Contra&bholigct;s for Wares and Goods which shall be delivered for this service may be well and sufficiently secured out
of the Moneyes ariseing and payable by this A&bholigct; Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That there be
provided and kepte in His Majestyes Exchequer (to witt) in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt one Booke
or Register in which Booke or Register all Moneyes that shall be paid into the Exchequer by this A&bholigct; shall be
entred [&amp; registred<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] apart and distin&bholigct; from the Moneyes paid or payable to Your Majestie on the before mentioned
A&bholigct; and from all other Moneyes or Branches of Your Majesties Revenue whatsoever And that alsoe there be one
other Booke or Registry provided or kepte in the said Office of all Orders and Warrants to be made by the Lord
Treasurer and Under Treasurer or by the C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers of the Treasury for the time being for payment of all and
every Summe and summes of money to all persons for moneyes lent Wares or Goods bought or other payments
dire&bholigct;ed by His Majestie relateing to the service of this Warr And that noe moneyes leavyable by this A&bholigct; be
issued out of the Exchequer dureing this Warr but by such Order or Warrant mentioning that the moneyes
payable by such Order or Warrant are for the service of Your Majestie in the said Warr respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s7">
		<head>VI. Auditor's Book.</head>
		<para id="p70">That alsoe there be the like Booke or Register provided and kepte by the said Auditor of all moneyes paid
out or issued by vertue of such Orders and Warrants.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s8">
		<head>VII. Lenders and Furnishers of Goods, &amp;c. to have free Access to Books.</head>
		<para id="p71">
			<emph type="i">Tally for Money lent. ; Interest at? &pound;6 per Cent, per Ann. to be paid every Six Months. ; Persons furnishing the Navy or Ordnance with Goods, to have Warrants for Payments forthwith, on Certificate without Fee.; Orders to be registered and paid in due Course without undue Preference.; Who shall be accounted the First Person to be paid; who the Second, and so successively,; No Fees for providing Books; or for Payment upon Orders.; Penalty.; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty.; By Deputy; Penalty.; Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller offending; Penalty.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p72">That it shall be lawfull for any person or persons willing to lend any money or to furnish any Wares
Vi&bholigct;ualls Necessaries or Goods on the credit of this A&bholigct; at the usuall times when the Exchequer is open to have
accesse unto and view and peruse all or any of the said Bookes for their Information of the state of those Moneyes
and all Ingagements upon them for their better incouragement to lend any Moneyes or furnish any Goods or
Wares as aforesaid. And that the respe&bholigct;ive Officers and their Deputyes and Clerks in whose custodie such Bookes
be or shall be, shall be assistant to such persons for their better and speedier satisfa&bholigct;ion in that behalfe, That all
and every person and persons who shall lend any moneyes to Your Majestie and pay the same into the Receipt
of the Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally of Loane strucke for the same, and an Order for his repayment
bearing the same Date with his Tally, in which Order shall be alsoe a Warrant contained for payment of Interest
for forbearance after the rate of Six per Cen? per Annum for his consideration to be paid every Six monethes untill
the repayment of his Principall, And that all person and persons who shall furnish Your Majestie, Your Officers of
the Navy or Ordnance with any Wares Goods Vi&bholigct;ualls or other necessaries for the service aforesaid shall upon
Certificate of the C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers and Officers of the Navy, or of the Master or C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers &amp; Officers of the Ordnance
or some of them without delay forthwith [have<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] made out to them Warrants or Orders for the payments of the
moneyes due or payable unto them, which Certificates the said Officers of your Navy, C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers and Officers of
the Ordnance shall make without Fee Charge or Delay, And that all Orders for [the<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] repayments of money lent shall
be registred in course according to the Date of the Tallyes respe&bholigct;ively, And that all Orders signed by the Lord
Treasurer and Under Treasurer of the Exchequer for the payment of money for Goods Wares Vi&bholigct;ualls and other
necessaries furnished to your Majestie, your Officers Master or C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers aforesaid shall be registred in course
according to the time of bringing to the Office of the Auditor of (<ref idref="n16">16</ref>) Receipt the Certificates above mentioned, And
that all Orders soe signed for payments dire&bholigct;ed by his Majestie shall be entred in course according to their respe&bholigct;ive
Dates, and none of the sortes of Orders abovementioned either for Loanes of Money, Supplyes of Wares Goods
Vi&bholigct;ualls or Necessaries or by speciall dire&bholigct;ion shall have preference one before another, but shall all be entred
in their course according to the Dates of the Tallyes, the times of bringing the Certificates and the dates of the
Orders for payments dire&bholigct;ed by his Majestye as they are in point of time respe&bholigct;ively before each other. And
that all and every person and persons shall be paid in course according as their Orders shall stand entred in the
said Register booke, be it Orders for payments dire&bholigct;ed by His Majestie or for moneyes le nt or for Wares C&bhooov;modities
or other necessaries furnished as aforesaid soe as that that person his Executors Administrators and Assignes
who shall have his Warrant or Order Warrants or Orders first entred in the said Booke of Registry shall be taken
and accounted as the first person to be paid upon the moneyes to come in by vertue of this A&bholigct;, and he or
they that shall have [his or<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] their Warrants or Orders Warrant or Order next entred shall be taken and accounted
the second person to be paid and soe successively and in course. And that the moneyes to come in by this A&bholigct;
shall be in the same order lyeable to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said respe&bholigct;ive partyes their Executors Administrators
or Assignes successively without preference of one before another and not otherwise. And that noe Fee Reward
or Gratuity dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly be demanded or taken of any of Your Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s for provideing or makeing
of such Bookes, Registers, Entryes, View, Search, Certificate in or for payment of money lent, or the interest
thereof, or for payment of any money upon any Order upon any Contra&bholigct; for Wares and goods furnished to the
use of your Majesties Navy and Ordnance as aforesaid by any of your Majesties Officer or Officers their Deputies
or Clerkes on paine of payment of treble dammages to the party grieved by the partie offending with costs of Suite,
And if the Officer himselfe take or demand any such Fee or Reward. then to lose his place alsoe. And if any
undue preference of one before another shall be made either in point of registring contrary to the true meaning of
this A&bholigct; by any such Officer or Officers, then the partie offending shall be lyeable by A&bholigct;ion of Debt or on the case
to pay the value of the Debt Damages and Costs to the partie grieved, And shall be forejudged from his Place
or Office. And if such preference be unduely made by any his Deputie or Clerke without dire&bholigct;ion or privity
of his Master then such Deputie or Clerke onely shall be lyable to such A&bholigct;ion Debt Damages and Cost and shall
for ever after be incapeable of the same, And in case the Auditor shall not dire&bholigct; the Order, or the Clerke of
the Pells record or the Teller make payment according to each persons due place and order as afore dire&bholigct;ed
then he or they shall be judged to forfeite and their respe&bholigct;ive Deputies and Clerks herein offending be lyeable
to such A&bholigct;ion Debt Damages and Costs in such manner as aforesaid</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s9">
		<head>VIII. Paying Tallies of the same Date, &amp;c. on the same Day no undue Preference.</head>
		<para id="p73">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That if it happen that severall Tallyes of Loane or Certificates for
Wares delivered or Orders for Payments from his Majestie as aforesaid beare date or be brought the same day
to the Auditor of the Exchequer to be registred Then it shall be interpreted noe undue preference which of
these he enters soe he enter them all the same day.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s10">
		<head>IX. Payments of subsequent Orders, if first demanded, no undue Preference, so as sufficient Money be reserved.</head>
		<para id="p74">Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpreted any undue preference to incurr any penalty in point of
payment if the Auditor dire&bholigct; and the Clerke of the Pells record and the Teller doe pay subsequent Orders of
persons that come to demand their money and bring their Orders before other persons that did not come to
demand their money and bring their Order in their course soe as there be soe much money reserved as will
satisfie their Orders, which shall not be otherwise disposed but kepte for them Interest upon Loane being to cease
from the time the money is soe reserved and kepte in Bancke for them,</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s11">
		<head>X. Tallies may be assigned.</head>
		<para id="p75">
			<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee.; Assignee may assign.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p76">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every person or persons to whom any money
shall be due by vertue of this A&bholigct; after Warrant or Order entred for payment thereof, his Executors
Administrators or Assignes by Indorsement of his Order or Warrant may assigne and transfer his Interest and
Benefit of such Warrant to any other, which being notified and an Entry and Memoriall thereof alsoe made in
the said Registry for Warrants (which the Officers shall on request without Fees or Charge accordingly make)
shall intitle such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the benefit thereof and payment thereon.
And such Assignee may in like manner assigne againe and soe toties quoties, and afterwards it shall not be in
the power of such person or persons who have made such Assignements to make void release or discharge the
same or the Moneyes thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s12">
		<head>XI. Interest at &pound;6 per Cent. per Ann. On Advance of the Tax.; Receiver's Acquittance a Discharge.; Money to be paid into the Exchequer.</head>
		<para id="p77">And in case any person or persons bee willing to advance the Taxe they themselves are to pay, or the Taxe
of any Tything Hundred Parish Division or County for six monethes or more unto the Receivour Generall of
that place or County, The said Receiver Generall is hereby authorized to receive the same and to make dedu&bholigct;ion
of soe much for Interest after the rate of Six per Centum per annum as the Advance amounts unto, and the
Receivers Acquittance shall be a sufficient discharge for the same which money soe advanced shall be accounted
for and paid into the Exchequer by itselfe quarterly.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">Insolence <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n5" number="5">and County <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n6" number="6">Lib[er]ties <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n7" number="7">Oxford <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n8" number="8">Pounds <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n9" number="9">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n10" number="10">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n11" number="11">by <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="
n12" number="2">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n13" number="13">Money <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n14" number="14">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n15" number="15">
			<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		<note id="n16" number="16">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n17" number="17">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>

