<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47373" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1664 &amp; 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII. An A&bholigct; for making the River Avon navigable from Christ Church to the City of New Sarum.</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">[This A&bholigct; has been called Chap. XII. in various printed Editions of the Statutes, but it is not upon the Roll; the Title
is entered on the Roll amongst the Titles of Private A&bholigct;s in the above manner, and is here inserted in order to keep
up the usual arrangement of Chapters.]</para>
		<para id="p2">Item quedam petic[i]ones privatas personas concernentes (in se formam A&bholigct;us continentes) exhibite fuerunt &bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o
Domino Regi in Parliamento &bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o quar[um] Tituli subscribuntur.</para>
		<para id="p3">1. An A&bholigct; to enable Sir Edward Hungerford Knight of the Bath to sell certaine Lands in the County of Devon.</para>
		<para id="p4">2. An A&bholigct; for the enabling of Trustees to sell part of the Estate of Samuel Sandys the elder Esquire and of
his son Samuel Sandys for payment of debts.</para>
		<para id="p5">3. An A&bholigct; for confirming a Deed of Setlement between The Earl of Thanet and his younger Brothers.</para>
		<para id="p6">4. An A&bholigct; to enable the Bishop of Winchester to convey One hundred acres of Land lying in the great
disparked Parke of Bishops Waltham in the Parish of Bishops Waltham in the County of Southampton upon the
Re&bholigct;or of the said Parish Church of Bishops Waltham and his Successors in lieu of all Tithes and Payments
for Tythes due to the said Re&bholigct;or and his Successors for Waltham Parks.</para>
		<para id="p7">5. An A&bholigct; to enable the Lord Henry Powlet George Withers and John Mompesson to sell the Mannor of
Abbots-Anne in the County of Southampton</para>
		<para id="p8">6. An A&bholigct; to enable Henry Lord Lougborough to make the River and Sewer navigable from or neere Bristowe
Causey in the County of Surrey into the River of Thames.</para>
		<para id="p9">7. An A&bholigct; to enable Trustees for the Lord Strangford to sell Lands for payment of debts.</para>
		<para id="p10">8. An A&bholigct; for restoring of Sir Charles Stanley in blood</para>
		<para id="p11">9. An A&bholigct; for the setling of several Mannors Lands and Tenements of Sir Jacob Astley lying in the Counties
of Norfolk and Warwick.</para>
		<para id="p12">10. An A&bholigct; for setling the Estate of Sir Robert Carr Baronet.</para>
		<para id="p13">11. An A&bholigct; for making the River Avon navigable from Christ Church to the City of New Sarum.</para>
		<para id="p14">12. An A&bholigct;t for making the River of Medway navigable in the Counties of Kent and Sussex</para>
		<para id="p15">13. An A&bholigct; for making divers Rivers navigable or otherwise passable for Boats Barges and other Vessels.</para>
		<para id="p16">14. An A&bholigct; for setling of differences between the Towns of Great and Little Yarmouth touching the lading
and unlading of Herrings and other Merchandises and Comodities.</para>
		<para id="p17">15. An A&bholigct; for the naturalizing Dederic alias Richard Comes and others.</para>
		<para id="p18">16. An A&bholigct; for confirming of an A&bholigct; intituled An A&bholigct; to enable Joseph Micklethwaite an Infant and his Trustees
to sell Land for payment of his Fathers debts.</para>
		<para id="p19">17. An A&bholigct; for the inabling of Thomas Luckes of Treliddan in the County of Mountgomery Esq&bhoqesq; to sell Lands
for the payment of his debts and raising of younger Childrens portions.</para>
		<para id="p20">18. An A&bholigct; to inable Francis Lee Esq&bhoqesq; to sell Lands, for payment of debts and to make provision for his
Children.</para>
		<para id="p21">19. An A&bholigct; for continuance of a former A&bholigct; for repairing the Highwayes within the County of Hertford</para>
		<para id="p22">20. An A&bholigct; for draining of the Fenn called Deeping-Fenn and other Fenns therein mentioned</para>
	</section>
</report>


