<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47379" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act for takeing away of Damage Cleere.[Rot. Parl. 17 C. 11. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Damage Cleer is an unnecessary Charge.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.; No Damage Cleer to be taken after 29th Sept. 1672</emph>;
				<emph type="i">Taking Damage Cleer; or refusing to sign Judgment till Damage Cleer paid; (Exception); Penalty.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Moneyes which are taken by Prothonotaries of Your Majestyes Courts of Kings Bench and
Common Pleas and by the Clerke, of Your Majestyes Court of Exchequer at Westminster and the
Prothpnotary of Your Majesties Court of Common Pleas at Lancaster and the Prothonotaryes and Clerkes of other
Your Majestyes Courts within the Realme of England and Dominion of Wales in the name of Damna Clericorum
or Dammage Cleere are an unnecessary charge and burden to all Your Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s who have good cause and
are putt to sue for Dammages in A&bholigct;ions where Damages are recoverable. For [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] avoiding of which inconveniencies
for the future and that Your Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s may have an easier meanes for the recovery of their damages
and just rights, which are unjustly detayned from them May it please Your most Excellent Majestie that it may
be ena&bholigct;ed. And the Kings most Excellent Majestie being willing upon all occasions to ease His Subje&bholigct;s of all
unnecessary charges and burdens is gratiously pleased That it be ena&bholigct;ed And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
Excellent Majestie With the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present
Parlyament assembled and by Authoritie of the same That immediately from and after the Twenty ninth day of
September which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy two noe Damage Cleere (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) by any Title or Pretext whatsoever be due payable taken or received from any person or persons in any A&bholigct;ion
whatsoever sued or prosecuted in any of His Majestyes Courts at Westminster or elsewhere within the Kingdome
of England or Dominion of Wales by any Prothonatory Clerke or Clerkes or other Officer or Officers of the said
Courts respe&bholigct;ively And that from and after the day and yeare aforesaid the said Fee of Damna Clericorum or
Damage Cleere shall wholly cease and he for ever abolished in the said Courts And that if any Prothonatory
Clerke or Clerkes or other Officer in any of the said Courts shall take or exa&bholigct; any summe or summes of Money
in the name of Damna Clericorum or Damage Cleere or any thing in lieu thereof after the day and yeare
abovementioned, Or if any of the said Prothonataries Clerke or Clerkes or their Deputyes at any time before the
said Twenty ninth day of September in the yeare aforesaid shall exa&bholigct; or take any Damage Cleere or summe of
Money Bond or Security in lieu thereof from any Plaintiffe or Plaintiffes Demandant or Demandants in any A&bholigct;ion
where Damages have beene, or hereafter shall be recovered in any of the said Courts or shall refuse or delay to
signe any Judgement untill Dammage Cleere be first paid by the Plaintiffe or Demandant (which are not to be
paid unlesse forth of the Moneyes leavyed from or paid by the Defendants as is herein after provided and mentioned)
he or they soe offending shall forfeite treble the summe soe taken exa&bholigct;ed or demanded to the partie or partyes
grieved to be recovered by Bill Plaint or Information in any of the said Courts wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion
or Wager of Law shall be allowed.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. Out of what Monies and how Damage Cleer to be paid until the said 29th Sept.</head>
		<para id="p3">[Provided and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That untill the Nine and twentyeth day of September which shall be in the
yeare of our Lord God One thousand six hundred seaventy and two and noe longer The Damage Clere shall be
paid answered and allowed out of such summe and summes of Money onely as shall be a&bholigct;ually levyed or
otherwise paid by or from the Defendants and onely for the proportion of the summe and summes of money
which shall be soe levyed or otherwise paid as aforesaid, and noe more, or otherwise.<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">
			<emph type="i">O</emph> omits.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">shall <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
	</section>
</report>


