<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47385" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1666</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An A&bholigct; to continue a former A&bholigct; for preventing of Thefte and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders of England. [Rot. Parl. 18 &amp; 19 C. II. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 14 13 &amp; 14 C. II. C. 22.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The said A&bholigct; continued</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an A&bholigct; was made in the fowerteenth yeare of the Raigne of Our Soveraigne Lord the King that
now is entituled An A&bholigct; for preventing of Theft and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders of England
which A&bholigct; is very neere expireing and hath beene found very necessary for the preservation of those places from
that great number of lewd disorderly [and lawless<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] persons, that usually frequented there abouts Bee it therefore
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and Commons of this present Parliament assembled That the said A&bholigct; and every Clause and Clauses
therein contained and all and every the Powers and Authorities thereby given be, continue and remaine in force
untill the end of Seaven yeares from the expiration or determination of the fore-mentioned A&bholigct;.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Clergy taken away from Thieves in Northumberland, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">or otherwise, Offenders to be transported</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Benefitt of Clergy shall be taken away from
greate knowne and notorious Theives and Spoile takers in the said Countyes of Northumberland Cumberland or
either of them dureing, the continuance of this present A&bholigct; who shall be duely convi&bholigct;ed for Theft done or committed
within the said Countyes, or either of them, Or otherwise That it shall and may be lawfull to and for the Justices
of the Assize and Co&bhooov;mis?ers of Oyer and Terminer or Goale delivery before whom such Offenders shall be convi&bholigct;ed
within the said Countyes or either of them to transport or cause to be transported the said Offenders and every
of them into any of His Majestyes Dominions in America there to remaine and not to returne Any former, Law
Statute or Usage to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlioned on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


