<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47388" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1666</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) An A&bholigct; Explanatory of the Act for raiseing Moneyes by a Poll and otherwise towards the Maintenance of this present Warr. [Rot. Parl. 18 &amp; 19 C. II. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of c. 1. ante.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Upon what Persons the Sum of 12d. in the said A&bholigct; mentioned is to be charged</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; of this present Session of Parlyament intituled An A&bholigct; for raiseing moneyes by a Poll
and otherwise towards the Maintenance of this present Warr It is ena&bholigct;ed That all and every person and
persons shall pay unto His Majestie the summe of Twelve pence over and above the other Rates charged upon
them by [this<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] A&bholigct;. To prevent all doubts that may arise in the execution thereof Bee it ena&bholigct;ed and declared by
the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the said summe of Twelve
pence shall be charged upon and be paid by every person of what age sex or condition soever within the
Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede other then such persons who
receive Almes from the Parish and the Children of any person remaining in his or her family who by reason of
their poverty doth not contribute unto the Rates for Church and Poore and which are under the age of sixteene
yeares and are therefore exempted by the said A&bholigct;.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Parents, &amp;c. to pay for Minors.</head>
			<para id="p3">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed That the respe&bholigct;ive Parents Guardians and Tutors of every person under the age of
One and twenty yeares shall upon defaulte of payment by such person and upon demand pay Twelve pence for
every such person resideing in their family or under their Tuition and not exempted as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Persons charged compellable to pay by the Rules, &amp;c. of the said A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p4">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That every person charged or appointed to make any payment by vertue of
this present A&bholigct; shall be compellable by the Co&bhooov;mi?ers appointed by the before recited A&bholigct; or any two or more
of them to pay the same according unto the Rules and Methods and under the Penaltyes for paying the Rates
expressed in the said recited A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Appeal for Persons overcharged.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That every person or persons charged by the said recited A&bholigct; for his
or their Profession Office or in respe&bholigct; of any other capacitie chargeable by this or the aforesaid A&bholigct; who shall
finde him or themselves overcharged shall and may upon his or their Appeale before the Co&bhooov;mi?ers in the said
A&bholigct; mentioned or any two or more of them upon his or their severall Oathes discharge him or themselves in such
manner and forme as persons overrated for their personall Estates are by the said A&bholigct; enabled.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Lodgers and Servants to berated where resident.</head>
			<para id="p6">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That all persons not being Householders nor haveing a certaine place of abode and all
Servants shall be taxed at the place where they shall be resident at the time of the execution of the said A&bholigct;
and not otherwise.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">This Chapter is intituled Chapter I. 19 Car. II. and the consequent Numbers observed in the Seven subsequent A&bholigct;s as of 19 Car. II. in the common printed Editions; in the Long Calendar at the Parliament Office it is entered thus, Nu. 12. Ann.
Car. II: 18&deg; et 19&deg;</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">the said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


