<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47383" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1666</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for raising Moneys by a Poll, and otherwise towards the Maintenance of the present Warr. [Rot. Parl. 18 &amp; 19 C. II. nu.1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for granting to the King a Subsidy.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Grant to the King of 20s. in every &pound;100. of Personal Estate.; Proviso for Money lent to the King upon the Security of 17 Car. II. c. 1</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Most Gratious Soveraigne Wee Your Majestyes most obedient and loyall Subje&bholigct;s the Commons now, in
Parliament assembled haveing taken into our serious Consideration the many and urgent Occasions which
at this time doe presse Your Majestie to an extraordinary Expence of Treasure for the Defence of Your Majesties
Kingdomes and Dominions, and in most thankfull Acknowledgement of Your Majestyes just and tender Care of
the Welfare of Your People Doe most humbly present unto Your Majestie a free Gift of severall Summes of
Money towards the carrying on of the present Warr to be levyed in such manner as is hereafter expressed, and
doe beseech Your Majestie to accepte thereof And that it may be ena&bholigct;ed and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most
Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Commons
in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authorise of the same That all and every person and persons
Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate Guilds or Fraternities within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or
Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede haveing any personall Estate in such Debts oweing to them within the Realme
or without, which he or they doe not account and esteeme as desperate, over and besides such just Debts as he
she or they shall bona fide owe, or in ready moneyes shall yeild and pay unto His Majestie for every hundred
pounds in such Debts and ready Moneyes the summe of Twenty shillings to be assessed, imposed leavyed and
colle&bholigct;ed in manner herein after mentioned. Provided alwayes That noe summe of money which hath beene lent
unto His Majestie upon the Securitie of the A&bholigct; passed at Oxford in the Seaventeenth yeare of His Majesties
Raigne entituled An A&bholigct; for granting the summe of Twelve hundred and fifty thousand pounds to the Kings
Majestie for his present further Supply or lent by the Citty of London upon the Securitie of His Majestyes Revenue
ariseing by Hearth money at the rate of Six per Cent&bhocent; and which at the time of the execution of this present
A&bholigct; shall be unpaid, nor any summe of money which shall be lent unto His Majestie upon the Securitie of this
present A&bholigct; or upon the Security of any other A&bholigct; of Parlyament passed or to be passed dureing this present
Session of Parlyament at the rate of Six per Cen&bhocent; shall be rated or assessed by vertue of this A&bholigct; Any thing herein
contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Public Officers taxed in the Monthly. Assessment (Exception) to pay is, in the Pound of the Profits of their Offices.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Officers not taxed in the Monthly Assessment to pay 3s. in the Pound</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every person and persons Co&bhooov;missioner or,
Co&bhooov;missioners haveing useing or exerciseing any Office Place or Publique Imployment whatsoever (such persons who
are or shall be in Muster and Pay at Land or Sea onely excepted) and all and every their Deputies Agents Clerkes
Secondaries Substitutes and other their inferiour Ministers and Servants whatsoever who are already taxed in [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
to the said Monethly Assessment for &amp; in respe&bholigct; of their Offices Agencies and Imployments shall likewise pay
unto His Majestie over and above the severall summes with which they are or shall be charged in or to the said
Monethly Assessment the summe of Twelve pence for every Twenty shillings which he or they doe receive in one
yeare by vertue of any Fees, Proffitts Perquisites or other Advantages to him or them accrueing, or by reason or
occasion of their severall Offices Agencies and Imployments, And such who are not already taxed in and by the
said Monethly Assesment for and in respe&bholigct; of their Co&bhooov;missions Offices Agencies and Imployments shall yeild and
pay unto His Majestie the full summe of Three shillings for every Twenty shillings which he or they doe receive
in one yeare by vertue of any Fees Proffitts Perquisites or other advantages to him or them accrueing or by reason
or occasion of their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Co&bhooov;missions, Offices, Agencies and Imployments The said severall summes
of Twelve pence in every Twenty shillings, and Three shillings in every Twenty shillings to be assessed imposed
leavyed and colle&bholigct;ed in such manner as is herein after mentioned, allowing to every such Officer and Co&bhooov;mis?er
one Third part of the Anuall Salary or Summe of moriey he shall soe receive, for and towards his [or<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] their charge
of executeing any such Co&bhooov;mission Office or Place before mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Pensions, &amp;c. from Government to pay 3s. in the Pound.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every other person and persons haveing or
claiming to have any Pension or yearely Stipend or Annuity by vertue of any Gifte or Grant from His Majestie
under His Great Seale or Privy Seale shall pay unto His Majestie the summe of Three shillings for every Twenty
shillings by the yeare soe given or granted as aforesaid to be assessed imployed leavyed and colle&bholigct;ed in such
manner as is herein after mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Serjeants at Law, Counsellors, Advocates, &amp;c. and Persons pra&bholigct;icing Physic, to pay 2s. for every 20s.</head>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Sergeants at Law Councellors Attourneyes
Sollicitors and Scriveners and all Advocates Pro&bholigct;ors and publique Notaries and all and every person and persons
pra&bholigct;iseing the A&bholigct; of Phisick, shall pay unto his Majestie the summe of Two shillings for every Twenty shillings
which he or they doe receive by his and their respe&bholigct;ive Pra&bholigct;ises and Professions in one yeare allowing to every
such person and persons of the severall Professions aforesaid one Third part out of such moneyes as he or they
shall soe receive in their respe&bholigct;ive Pra&bholigct;ices and Professions for and towards the charge and expence occasioned
by his or their attendance upon his or their Pra&bholigct;ise or Professions aforesaid;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Servants to pay 13. for every 20s.</head>
			<para id="p7">And all and every Servant which at the time of the execution of this A&bholigct; shall receive Wages for his, her or
their Service shall pay unto His Majestie the summe of Twelve pence for every Twenty shillings by the yeare
which shall be due or payable to him heror them for his her or their Wages except for Board wages.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Every Person to pay is above the other Rates.</head>
			<para id="p8">And all and every person and persons shall pay unto His Majestie the summe of Twelve pence over and
above the other Rates charged upon them by this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Servants refusing, Master to pay and dedu&bholigct; from Wages.</head>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That in case any Servant shall upon the demand of such Assesment or Moneyes
as are due from him or her by vertue of this A&bholigct; refuse or negcle&bholigct; to pay the same to the respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;or
in such case his or her Master or Mistresse shall pay such Servants Assessment. And it shall then be lawfull for
such Master or Mistresse to dedu&bholigct; and stop the same out of such Wages as shall or ought to be next paid
unto such Servant. Any Law or Custome to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Exceptions to the Poll.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alwayes That noe person who receives Almes from the Parish nor the Children of any person
remaining, in his or her Family who by reason of their povertie doth not contribute to the Rates for the Church
and Poore and who are under the age of Sixteene yeares shall be charged or taxed by vertue of this
present A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Aliens to pay Double.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alsoe and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That every Alien stranger borne out of this Kingdome shall pay double
the Summe which he or they ought to have paid in any capacitie whatsoever in this A&bholigct; mentioned in case he or
they had beene naturall borne Subje&bholigct;s.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Rates of Paytnents by Peers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Duke resident in the Kingdom &pound;50. Marquess &pound;40.; Earl &pound;30.; Viscount &pound;25. Baron &pound;20.; Eldest Son of Duke of 21 Years &pound;30.</emph>
				<emph type="i">Eldest Son of Marquess &pound;25.; Eldest Son of Earl of 21 Years &pound;20.; Eldest Son of Viscount of 21 Years &pound;17. 10s., Eldest Son of Baron of 21 Years &pound;15; Baronet &pound;15.; Knight of the Bath &pound;15.; Knight Batchelor &pound;10.; Serjeant at Law &pound;15.; Esquire of 21 Years &pound;5.; Widow to pay the Third Part of Rate on her late Husband's Degrees. Gentlemen above 16 Years 20s</emph>.
			</para>
			<para id="p13">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained That all and every person and persons who at the time of the
execution of this A&bholigct; shall be of the severall Rankes and Degrees hereafter mentioned shall to the purpose
aforesaid contribute and pay the severall summes of money hereafter in this A&bholigct; sett downe and appointed. That
is to say Every person of the Degree of a Duke of England Scotland or Ireland inhabiting and resideing within
this Kingdome shall pay the summe of Fifty pounds, Every person of the Degree of a Marquese of any of
the said three Kingdomes inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome shall pay the summe of Forty pounds,
Every person of the Degree of an Earle of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting or resideing within
this Kingdome the sumrne of Thirty pounds, Every person of the Degree of a Viscount of any of the said three
Kingdomes and inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome the summe of Twenty five pounds, Every person of
the Degree of a Baron of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting or resideing within this Kingdome the
summe of Twenty pounds, Every eldest Sonne of a Duke of any of the said three Kingdomes, and inhabiting 
or resideing within this Kingdome being of the age of One and twenty yeares the summe of Thirty pounds, Every
eldest Sonne of a Marquesse of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting and resideing within this Kingdome
being of the age of One and twenty yeares the summe of Twenty five pounds, Every eldest Sonne of an Earle
of any of the said three Kingdomes and inhabiting or resideing within this Kingdome being of the age of One
and twenty yeares the summe of Twenty pounds, Every eldest Sonne of a Viscount of any of the said three
Kingdomes and inhabiting or resideing within this Kingdome being of the age of One and twenty yeares the summe
of Seaventeene pounds ten shillings, Every eldest Sonne of a Baron of any of the said three Kingdomes and
inhabiting or resideing within this Kingdome being of the age of One and twenty yeares Fifteene pounds, Every
person of the Degree of a Baronet of any of the said three Kingdomes or of Nova Scotia and inhabiting or
resideing within this Kingdome the summe of Fifteene pounds, Every person that is a Knight of the Order of
the Bath inhabiting or resideing within this Kingdome the summe of Fifteene pounds, Every person who is a
Knight Batchelor inhabiting or resideing within this Kingdome the summe of Ten pounds, Every Sergeant at Law
the summe of Ten pounds, Every person of the Degree of an Esquire or soe reputed inhabiting or resideing
within this Kingdome and above the age of One and twenty yeares the summe of Five pounds, Every Widdow
respe&bholigct;ively according to her Husbands Degree shall pay the Third part rated by this A&bholigct; upon that Degree of
which the Husband of such Wife was in his life time, And every Gentleman or reputed Gentleman above the
age of Sixteene yeares the summe of Twenty shillings</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Gentlemen having Estate of &pound;300 or more, to pay 20s. though an Infant; under that Estate on Oath, not charged.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided alwayes That every Gentleman haveing an Estate of the value of three hundred pounds or more
shall be charged with the summe of Twenty shillings by vertue of this A&bholigct; though he be a Minor under the
age of One and twenty yeares; And noe Gentleman not haveing such an Estate and shall thereof make Oath
before any two or more of the respe&bholigct;ive Co&bhooov;mis?ers shall be charged with the said summe of Twenty shillings
in respe&bholigct; of his Title.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Archbishop &pound;50.; Bishop &pound;20.; Dean &pound;10; Archdeacon &pound;2.; Canons and Prebendaries not rated at above &pound;30, &pound;2. 10s; Do&bholigct;ors in Divinity, Law, and Physic, &pound;5</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained That all and every the person and persons within the Kingdome of
England Dominion of Wales and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede who at the time of the execution of this A&bholigct;;
shall be of the severall Orders Ranckes or Degrees hereafter mentioned shall to the purpose aforesaid pay the
severall summes of money hereafter in this A&bholigct; sett downe and appointed (that is to say) Every person of the Order
and Degree of an Archbishop shall pay the summe of Fifty pounds, Every person of the Order and Degree of a
Bishop the summe of Twenty pounds Every person of the Degree of a Deane of any Cathedrall or Collegiate
Church shall pay the summe of Ten pounds, Every person of the Degree of an Archdeacon shall pay the summe
of Forty shillings, Every person of the Degree of a Canon or Prebendary of any (
<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) Cathedrall or Collegiate Church,
excepting such sole Prebendary [who is a sole Corporac&bhocotil;on
<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] and his Prebend not rated in the Exchequer at above
Thirty pounds shall pay the summe of Fifty shillings Every person of the Degree of a Do&bholigct;or in Divinity, Law
or Phisicke shall pay the summe of Five pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Proviso for D.D.: not having Benefice, and for Widows of Ecclesiastical Persons.</head>
			<para id="p17">Provided alwayes That noe Do&bholigct;or of Divinity not haveing any Benefice or Ecclesiasticall preferment shall be
charged for his Title or Dignitie of Do&bholigct;or by vertue of this A&bholigct;, nor the Widow of any Ecclesiasticall person
shall be charged for the third part according to the Title or Dignitie of her late Husband,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Certains Commissioners under 16 &amp; 17 Car. II. c. I. to be Commissioners under this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p18">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That for the better assessing ordering and leavying of
the severall summes of money soe as aforesaid limitted and appointed to be paid, and for the more effe&bholigct;uall putting
of this present A&bholigct; in execution such persons shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; be Co&bhooov;mis?ers for the severall and
respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places within the Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales
and Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede as are nominated, and appointed Co&bhooov;mis?ers for putting in execution the
Powers in a former A&bholigct; of this Parlyament entituled An A&bholigct; for granting a Royall Ayde unto the Kings Majestie
of Twenty fower hundred threescore and seaventeene thousand and five hundred pounds to be raised leavyed and
paid in the space of Three yeares.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Commissioners added.</head>
			<para id="p19">And bee it further declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That these persons hereafter named shall
be added Co&bhooov;mis?ers for the severall Countyes Places and Precin&bholigct;s respe&bholigct;ively and shall exercise the same power
as if they had beene named in the said former A&bholigct; (viz<ref idref="n2">2</ref>).</para>
			<para id="p20">Bedford.</para>
			<para id="p21">For the County of Bedford Villiers Charnocke Humphrey Monox John Beecher, Thomas Daniell John Gardiner
Es?rs Horne Peter Harman Gen?</para>
			<para id="p22">Berks</para>
			<para id="p23">For the County of Berks Sir William Craven Knight John Kingsmell Esq&bhoqesq;s John Withwick Edward Keate Charles
Fettiplace William Bowles senior Es?rs John Munday William Packer Richard House Gen?. Gilly Esq&bhoqesq;
Hugh Barker Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke.</para>
			<para id="p24">Bucks</para>
			<para id="p25">For the County of Bucks Sir Charles Clever Knight Sir Timothy Tyrrell Knight and Baronet Sir Fredericke
Hyde Thomas Catesby Edward Stafford Esq&bhoqesq;s Mathew Archdel Gen&bhocotil; Sir John Busby For the Towne of Buckingham
George Robbins.</para>
			<para id="p26">Cambridge</para>
			<para id="p27">For the County of Cambridge Sir John Jacob Baronet Sir Ralph Bovey Baronet Roger Pepys Esq&bhoqesq; Gerard Russell
Esq&bhoqesq; For the Towne of Cambridge Rowland Simpson Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p28">Ely</para>
			<para id="p29">For the Isle of Ely William Legat Anthony Fisher Peter Diamond Esq&bhoqesq;rs.</para>
			<para id="p30">Chester</para>
			<para id="p31">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester Thomas Cooper Alderman Edward Bradshaw Esq&bhoqesq; Richard
Bird Alderman Richard Minshall Richard Tayler John [Pool<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Robert Harvy Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p32">Cornwall</para>
			<para id="p33">For the County of Cornwall John Trelawney of Trelawen Thomas Vivian John Moulesworth Esq&bhoqesq;rs William Inch
Abel French Nicholas Trebarfoote Edward Herle Edward Hoblin Nicholas Herle Walter Leech George Spry William
Bond Thomas Dodson John Arundell John [Tregygle<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] William Thomas Anthony Tanner John Barret Thomas
Penhallow John Tamlin John Verman Richard Williams John Williams Esq&bhoqesq;rs William Kegwin Henry Edwards
Arthur Painter Gen&bhocent;.</para>
			<para id="p34">Cumberland.</para>
			<para id="p35">For the County of Cumberland John Warwicke. Richard Lamplugh Miles Penington Joseph Patrickson John
Senhouse William Orpheur Fardinando Hudleston Leonard Dykes Hugh Ascue Richard Patrickson John Punsenbee
Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p36">Devon</para>
			<para id="p37">For the County of Devon Christopher Lord, Torrington Richard Duke Gideon Heidon Richard Lee Richard
Hillersdon Samuell Roll Arthur Ashford John Bluet William Bragg Mathew Halls Edmond Parker John Mallet Esq&bhoqesq;rs
Sir John Stowell John Chichester Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p38">Exon</para>
			<para id="p39">For the Citty and County of Exon John Mallet Esq&bhoqesq;, Do&bholigct;or Edward Masters Chauncellour of the Diocesse Eustace
Budgell Gen&bhocent;.</para>
			<para id="p40">Derby</para>
			<para id="p41">For the County of Derby George Saville Robert Ashton John Gell John Low .John Dun Esq&bhoqesq;rs Andrew Clayton
Robert Moore Gen&bhocent; Richard Merchant Alderman Edward Abney Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p42">Dorset</para>
			<para id="p43">For the County of Dorset Robert Culliford William Frampton Robert Williams Henry Henley junior Humphrey
Welde Esq&bhoqesq;rs, The High Sheriffe for the time being John Ellesdon Sollomon Andrewes (<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) John Gallop Gen&bhocent;.</para>
			<para id="p44">Poole</para>
			<para id="p45">For the Towne and County of Poole The Maior for the time being William Okeden Allen Skutt Gen&bhocent;.</para>
			<para id="p46">Durham</para>
			<para id="p47">For the County Palatine of Durham Sir George Fletcher Baronet Robert Shafto Humphrey Wharton Thomas
Craddock Christopher Saunderson John Jeffreyson Esq&bhoqesq;rs Robert Newhouse Edward Arden Gen&bhocent;.</para>
			<para id="p48">Essex</para>
			<para id="p49">For the County of Essex Sir John Archer one of the Justices of the Common Pleas Phillip Saltenston Thomas
Cullum Esq&bhoqesq;rs Timothy Midleton Esq&bhoqesq; Sir James Russett Edward Shelton Francis Mildmay.</para>
			<para id="p50">Colchester</para>
			<para id="p51">For the Towne of Colchester Sir Harbotle Grimston Baronet Master of the Rolls John Eldred senior John Eldred
junior Esq&bhoqesq;rs.</para>
			<para id="p52">Harwich</para>
			<para id="p53">For the Towne of Harwich and Dover Court The Maior for the time being Sir Cappell Luckin Knight and
Baronet John Eldred junior Esq&bhoqesq; Mr George Coleman Daniel Smith Captaine Hunter Alderman Sacke Samuell Newton
Alderman Robinson Alderman Garriot Alderman Hawks.</para>
			<para id="p54">Gloucester</para>
			<para id="p55">For the County of Gloucester Sir John Treacy Sir William Juxon Sir John Newton Baronets Sir Francis Fane
Knight of the Bath Sir John Points Knight John Meredeth John Vaughan Thomas Carpender William Oldesworth.
John Browning Thomas Veale of Simons Hall Edward Smith George Brett Roger Lingan Robert Loggin Es?rs William
Hancock Conway Whitton Thomas Smith Richard Jones of Hanham Thomas Wise Richard Hart Gen&bhocent;.</para>
			<para id="p56">Citty of Gloucester</para>
			<para id="p57">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester Sir Bainham Throckmorton Knight and Baronet Mr Thomas
Aram Merchant Mr John Marston Collonell Richard Atkins Williams Cooke Esq&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p58">Hereford</para>
			<para id="p59">For the County of Hereford James Pitts Francis Pember of Elsdon Robert Minors of Treagoe Edward Scrimshall
John Bridge of Priors Courts Es?rs John Burch of Garnston John Curver of Upton Henry Milbourne William Driver
Gilbert Hare Gen&bhocent;.</para>
			<para id="p60">Citty of Hereford</para>
			<para id="p61">Bridstocke [Hertford<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Esq&bhoqesq; Humphrey Diggs Humphrey Howarth James Wellington Gen&bhocent;.</para>
			<para id="p62">Hertford</para>
			<para id="p63">For the County of Hertford Sir Thomas Brograve Sir Robert Joselyne Baronets Sir John Witterong Knight and
Baronet Sir Charles Cleaver Knight Robert Dicer John Cesar Ralph Radclife Francis Shalcrosse Edward Chester,
Thomas Tooke Es?rs Richard Taverner King of Hempesteade Joseph Edmonds Charles Cesar George</para>
			<para id="p64">Nodes George Poyner Joseph Hatch Charles Chrouch Thomas, James John Dagnoll Gen&bhocent; William Glascocke Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p65">Saint Albons</para>
			<para id="p66">For the Borough of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albons Josua Lomax Edward Crosby Thomas Rotherham William Rugg William Ran&eacute;
Aldermen John Dogget.</para>
			<para id="p67">Huntington</para>
			<para id="p68">For the County of Huntington Sir James Beverley John Drydon Anthony Hammon Major Deane of Godmanchester.</para>
			<para id="p69">Kent.</para>
			<para id="p70">For the County of Kent Sir Thomas Monins Sir Thomas Peirse Baronets Sir John Shaw Knight and Baronet Sir
Nicholas Strode Knight Edward Master Elwin Wyat (<ref idref="n8">8</ref>) William Wiseman [Es?rs<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] The Maior of Maidstone for the
time being.</para>
			<para id="p71">Canterbury</para>
			<para id="p72">For the Citty and County of Canterbury William Kingslys Esq&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p73">Dover</para>
			<para id="p74">For the Cinque Port of Dover James Wyon Esq&bhoqesq; William Stocks Jurat.</para>
			<para id="p75">Sandwich</para>
			<para id="p76">For the Cinque Port of Sandwich William Freeman Esq&bhoqesq; James Thorben junior Gen&bhocent;</para>
			<para id="p77">Lancaster.</para>
			<para id="p78">For the County of Lancaster The High Sheriffe for the time being Edmond Ashton of Chatterton Christopher,
Banister Es?rs Mr. Richard Shutleworth of Gawthrop junior John Hartley Miles Dodding George Fell Es?rs Captaine
William Fleming Richard Kenerdine Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke.</para>
			<para id="p79">Leicester</para>
			<para id="p80">For the County of Leicester Richard Lister William Gilbert George Pochin Es?rs. John Farrington Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p81">Leicester Towne</para>
			<para id="p82">For the Burrough of Leicester Daniell Deacon William Stubbins William Callis John Clarke Gen?.</para>
			<para id="p83">Lincolne</para>
			<para id="p84">For the County of Lincolne Carr Scrope Richard Newton Richard Pell William Darwin Redman Burrell Thomas,
Browne George Lucas William Basset John Bishop John Butlar William Skipwith Henry Meller Thomas Fristin
Peregrine Bartu Es?rs Augustine Caudron Anthony Newlove William Perkins Miles Long Andrew Slee John Browne
Francis Johnson of Spaulding Charles Massingbeard John Greene of Dusby Gen&bhocent;.</para>
			<para id="p85">For the Baile of Lincolne Richard Cracroft Lawrence Stampford Gen&bholigct;.</para>
			<para id="p86">Midlesex</para>
			<para id="p87">For the County of Midlesex William Ashburnham Cofferer of His Majesties Household Sir Nicholas Strode of
S<emph type="p">t</emph> Johns Marke Cotle John Hawtry Edward Palmer Nicholas Townley junior Mathew Blucke William Richardson
Charles Porter Ralph Piggot Es?rs Sir John Dethick Do&bholigct;or Cox Thomas Stringer John Vincent William Thursby
Thomas Robinson Es?rs Sir Mundeford Brampston Knight John Jolliffe Lancelot Johnson junior Es?rs.</para>
			<para id="p88">London</para>
			<para id="p89">For the Citty of London Sir William Bolton Lord Maior Sir John Langham Sir John Lawrence Sir Richard
[Reeves<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] Sir Robert Hanson Sir William Hooker Sir George Waterman Sir Charles Doe Mathew Bluck Esq&bhoqesq; John
Moore Henry Partridge Thomas Blackerby Aldermen Sir Robert Viner Sir Joseph Sheldon Sheriffes Edward
Arris Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p90">Westminster</para>
			<para id="p91">For the Citty of Westminster Sir Thomas Clifford Comptroller of His Majesties Household Sir William Doyly
Sir Oliver [Boteler<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] Sir George Downing Baronets Sir Robert Carr Sir James Smith Thomas Exton Do&bholigct;or at Law
Lawrence Squib William Loving John Loving Henry Wynn Phillip Warwicke junior George Bennet Es?rs Do&bholigct;or
Troutbecke [Esq&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Henry Aldrich Gen&bhocent; Thomas Tyndall John Chace Phillip Hanbury Walter Bridall Bryan Barnby
John Jeffes David Walter John Carance Es?rs Samuell Barrow Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke Henry Monke Thomas Owen
Peregrine Bartu Ambrose Scudamore Thomas Milward Es?rs William Carr Esq&bhoqesq; Thomas Crompe Robert Stockdale
Gentlemen Henry Slingsby Esq&bhoqesq; Henry Pecke junior Esq&bhoqesq; Mr. Richard Padgett Mr. George Plucknett Mr. Michaell
Arnold Mr. Nicholas Edlyn Ralph Piggot Esq&bhoqesq; Henry Brunkard Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p92">Northampton</para>
			<para id="p93">For the County of Northampton Edward Palmer John Parkehurst of Catesby [Esq&bhoqesq;] <ref idref="n13">13</ref>
			</para>
			<para id="p94">Norfolke</para>
			<para id="p95">For the County of Norfolke John Bayspoole of Hadcos William Richardson Edmond Bell Francis Bell John
Bashpoole Gascoyne Weld Es?rs.</para>
			<para id="p96">Norwich</para>
			<para id="p97">For the County and Citty of Norwich John Richers Richard Wenman Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p98">Newcastle upon Tyne</para>
			<para id="p99">For the Towne and County of Newcastle upon Tyne William Blacket Esq&bhoqesq; Maior for the time being Sir
Nicholas Cole Sir James Clavering Baronets Sir. Francis Liddall Knight Robert Shaftoe Esq&bhoqesq; Recorder Marke Milbanke
John Emetson Henry Maddison Es?rs Aldermen Richard Stots Esq&bhoqesq; The Sheriffes for the time being Robert
Marley Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p100">Nottingham</para>
			<para id="p101">For the County of Nottingham Francis Lorke Esq&bhoqesq; Mr. Robert Atkinson both of Newarke Harvy Stanton of
Stanton Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p102">Oxon</para>
			<para id="p103">For the County of Oxon Sir Thomas Hampson Baronet Robert Withers James Chamberline Henry Brunkar Es?rs
Vincent Barry Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p104">Salop</para>
			<para id="p105">For the County of Salop Henry Davenport Esq&bhoqesq; Edmond Pearce of Wilcot Gen&bhotcrl;.</para>
			<para id="p106">Southampton</para>
			<para id="p107">For the County of Southampton Sir Charles Windham John Smith Esq&bhoqesq; Sir John Cloberry William Stephens
Nicholas Dorrel Es?rs James Worsley Gent. Carew Reynel Esq&bhoqesq; Henry Doyley Thomas Knight Gent..</para>
			<para id="p108">For the Towne of Portsmouth Benjamin Johnson and Hugh Salisbury Gent.</para>
			<para id="p109">Winton</para>
			<para id="p110">For the Citty of Winton Sir Robert Mason [and<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Nicholas Darel Esq&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p111">Somerset</para>
			<para id="p112">For the County of Somerset Sir John Stowel Knight James Prouse Cadwallader Jones William Strode Edward
Strode Richard Davadge James Stedman John Baber Hugh Tynt Es?rs Thomas Dyke Richard Musgrave Gent..</para>
			<para id="p113">Bristoll</para>
			<para id="p114">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll Sir Humphrey Hooke Knight Joseph Creswicke Thomas Stephens
Henry Lloyd Gent..</para>
			<para id="p115">Bath</para>
			<para id="p116">For the, Citty of Bath Henry Chapman John Pearce Gent.</para>
			<para id="p117">Stafford.</para>
			<para id="p118">For the County of Stafford Jonas Grosvenor Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p119">Suffolke</para>
			<para id="p120">For the County of Suffolke Francis Burwell William Femeley Es?rs Thomas Arris Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke Do&bholigct;or
Bryan Smith Mr. Edward Spencer Edward Man John Cordell Esq&bhoqesq; William Hamon Gent. Thomas Edger of Ipswich
Esq&bhoqesq; Barrodell Millisen of Norton Gent. John Duke Esq&bhoqesq; Ambrose Duke Gent..</para>
			<para id="p121">Sudbury</para>
			<para id="p122">For the Towne of Sudbury Nathaniell King John Cooke Christopher Petit Thomas King Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p123">Sussex</para>
			<para id="p124">For the County of Sussex John Ashburnham Edward Blaker Henry Brunkard Esq&bhoqesq;s George Edmonds Captaine
John Eversfeild John Backshall Gent. Edward Cooper Esq&bhoqesq; John Matchell Francis Gratwicke Esquiers.</para>
			<para id="p125">Hastings</para>
			<para id="p126">For the Cinque. Port of Hastings Benjamin Polsted John Hide Gent..</para>
			<para id="p127">Rye</para>
			<para id="p128">For the Cinque Port of Rye William Holman John Martin Gent..</para>
			<para id="p129">Surry</para>
			<para id="p130">For the County of Surry Sir Francis Duncomble Baronet Sir Ceril Wiche Sir Thomas Thinn Sir William
Throckmorton junior Rowland Jucks Edward Cooper William Chislet Richard Mountney Edward Freeman Esq&bhoqesq;s
Stephen Harvy Henry Houghton Es?rs.</para>
			<para id="p131">Southwarke</para>
			<para id="p132">For the Burrough of Southwarke Sir Edward Bromfield Baronet Sir Thomas Clergis Knight Edmond Clay
Thomas Lenthall John Childe Es?rs Richard How William Sherlock senior William Adams Jeremy Baines John
Apleby Richard Smith Gent..</para>
			<para id="p133">Warwicke</para>
			<para id="p134">For the County of Warwicke John Stratford Fulwood Skipwith Henry Pudsey Es?rs.</para>
			<para id="p135">Westmerland</para>
			<para id="p136">For the County of Westmerland Christopher Crackenthrope Chistopher Dalston Christopher Teasdell William Dawes
Robert Philipson William Midleton Henry Wilson Robert Braithwaite Richard Ducket William Guy Es?rs.</para>
			<para id="p137">Wilts</para>
			<para id="p138">For the County of Wilts Sir Robert Howard Knight Giles Hungerford Esq&bhoqesq; The Maior of Marleborough for the
time being The Maior of the Devises for the time being Thomas Gunter Esq&bhoqesq; Mr. Edomond James Mr. John Jacob
Mr. Thomas Vilet Mr. Giles Aleworth Mr. Charles Yorke George Johnson Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p139">Sarum</para>
			<para id="p140">For the Citty of New Sarum Thomas Gunter Esq&bhoqesq; Alderman Slaune George Vennard James Harris Do&bholigct;or Hurst.</para>
			<para id="p141">Worcester.</para>
			<para id="p142">For the County of Worcester William Washbourne Robert Staner Es?rs William Dowdeswell Gent..</para>
			<para id="p143">Worcester Citty</para>
			<para id="p144">For the Citty of Worcester The Maior and Aldermen and Sheriffes for the time being Sir John Packington Baronet
Sir Rowland Berkeley Knight Samuell Sandys senior Thomas Hall Thomas Streete Es?&bhoqesq;rs Samuell Johnsons Mathew
Skinner [Do&bholigct;or<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] of Phisicke Robert Wilde Humphrey Wildey Richard Bedoes Edward Cookesey Wintour Harris
John Bearecroft Humphrey Tirer Thomas Twitty John Tyas Gent.</para>
			<para id="p145">Yorke</para>
			<para id="p146">For the North Rideing in the County of Yorke Mr, Geldart of Wiggenthorp Richard Turner of Tunstall Roger
Tockets John Wentworth William Hustler Es? William Dawson Gent. Sir John Hewley Roger Colvel Gent. Ralph
Stepheason William Palmes Edward Chaloner Es?&bhoqesq;rs John Hill of Thornmanby Gent.</para>
			<para id="p147">Yorke East Rideing</para>
			<para id="p148">For the East Rideing in the County of Yorke John Wentworth John Herne Ralph Warton James Moyser Es?&bhoqesq;rs
Edward Gray the elder Edward Gray the younger Gent..</para>
			<para id="p149">Yorke West Rideing.</para>
			<para id="p150">For the West Rideing in the County of Yorke John Stanhope Esq&bhoqesq; Francis Carr Gent. William Ellis Henry Edmonds
John Hopton Christopher Drisfeild, Henry Slingsby Robert Wivell Robert Brandling Esq&bhoqesq;s Ralph Banister John
Cooke Gent. John Savile of Meathley Esq&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p151">Kingston upon Hull</para>
			<para id="p152">For the Towne and County, of Kingston upon Hull William Lister Esq&bhoqesq; Lambart Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p153">Brecon</para>
			<para id="p154">For the County of Brecon Sir Walter Williams Baronet Lehunt Esq&bhoqesq;. Daniell Williams of Penpont
William Bowen and David Gwen Gent..</para>
			<para id="p155">Cardigan</para>
			<para id="p156">For the Towne of Cardigan The Maior for the time being Thomas Parry Esq&bhoqesq; John Morrice Alderman.</para>
			<para id="p157">Glamorgan</para>
			<para id="p158">For the [Towne<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] of Glamorgan Sir Edward Stradlirig Baronet John Windham Edmond Lewis Richard Seyes of
Bouerton Walter Thomas Martin Button Thomas Button Es?&bhoqesq;rs.</para>
			<para id="p159">Merioneth</para>
			<para id="p160">For the County of Merioneth Captaine John Nanny Lewis Lewis John Lluid of Keavenraes Hugh Nanny, of
Festinog Gent..</para>
			<para id="p161">Monmouth</para>
			<para id="p162">For the County of Monmouth Henry Milborne Charles Milborne Bennet Hoskins John Hoskins. Herbert
of Newton Herbert Jones Gent..</para>
			<para id="p163">Pembrooke</para>
			<para id="p164">For the County of Pembrooke Thomas Phillips Esq&bhoqesq;. High Sheriffe for, the County, of Pembrooke Walter Vaughan
James Haward Es?&bhoqesq;rs Essex Merrick William Woogan Es?&bhoqesq;rs Thomas [Coxon<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] Gent..</para>
			<para id="p165">Haverford West</para>
			<para id="p166">For the Towne and County of Haverford West Walter Vaughan Esq&bhoqesq;. John Bateman Robert Prust Richard
Fowler Gent..</para>
			<para id="p167">
				<emph type="i">General Meeting of Commissioners 14th Feb, next; to dire&bholigct; Precepts to Inhabitants, Constables, &amp;c. to attend.;
and thereupon the Commissioners to read, &amp;c. the Rates openly; and prefix other Days for bringing in Certificates of Names, &amp;c. of Persons residing within certain Limits, together with the Assessments; Penalty; and also the Names of Persons to be Colle&bholigct;ors.; Payment to Head Colle&bholigct;ors.; Certificates and Assessments to be returned to Commissioners on 1st March next, who are thereupon to issue Warrants, &amp;c. for colle&bholigct;ing the Assessments, Colle&bholigct;ors to demand Payment within Six Days after Receipt of Warrant, and to levy and pay the same on 8th April 1667; and if not paid then, Distress upon Sub-colle&bholigct;or.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p168">Which said Co&bhooov;mis?sers in order to the speedy execution of this A&bholigct; Shall in their respe&bholigct;ive Counties Cittyes
Burroughes Townes and Places meete together at the most usuall or common place of Meeting within each of the
said Counties Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places respe&bholigct;ively at or before the Forwerteenth day of February
next ensueing, And the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers or soe many of them as shall be present at the first generall meeting or
the major part of them may by their consents and agreements divide as well themselves as other the Co&bhooov;mis?sers
not then present for the [Excution<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] of this A&bholigct; in Hundreds Lathes Wapentakes Rapes Wards Townes and other
Places within their Limitts priviledged or not priviledged in such manner and forme as to them shall seeme
expedient and shall dire&bholigct; their severall or joynt Precept or Precepts to such Inhabitants High Constables Pettit
Constables Bayliffes and other like Officers and Ministers and such number of them as they in their discretions shall
thinke most convenient requireing them to appeare before the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers at such time and place as they shall
appoint not exceeding Eight dayes And at such their appearances the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers or soe many of them as
shall be thereunto appointed shall openly reade or cause to be reade unto them the Rates in this A&bholigct; mentioned,
and openly declare the effe&bholigct; of their charge unto them and how and in what manner they ought and should
make their Certificates according to the Rates aforesaid, And shall then and there prefix another day to the said
persons to appeare before the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers and bring in their Certificates of the names and sirnames quallities
degrees and titles of all and every the persons dwelling or resideing within the limitts of those places with which
they shall be charged, and of the substances and values of every of them in Money Debts Annuall Fees Perquisites
Wages Proffitts Emolluments and other things chargeable by this A&bholigct; without concealement love favour dread or
mallice upon paine of forfeiture of any summe not exceeding Five pounds to be leavyed as by this A&bholigct; is appointed,
And shall then alsoe returne the names of two or more able and sufficient persons within the limitts and bounds
of those Parishes or places where they shall be chargeable respe&bholigct;ively as aforesaid to be Colle&bholigct;ors of the moneyes
due to His Majestie by this A&bholigct; For whose paying in to the Head Colle&bholigct;ors in manner following such moneyes
as they shall be charged withall the Parish or place by whom they are soe imployed shall be answerable Which
Certificates and Assesments shall be ascertained and returned into the Co&bhooov;mis?ers at or before the First day of March
next ensueing and upon the delivery and returning in of such Certificates or Assesments unto the said C&bhooov;mis?sers
they or any two or more of them shall forthwith issue out and deliver their Warrants or Estreets to such
Colle&bholigct;ors as aforesaid for the speedy colle&bholigct;ing and leavying of the said Assesments and all Moneyes and Rates
due thereupon according to the intent and subsequent dire&bholigct;ions of this present A&bholigct;. Of all which the said
Colle&bholigct;ors are hereby required to make demand of the partyes themselves, or at the places of their last abode
within six dayes after the receipt of such Warrants or Estreates and to levy and pay in the same on or before
the [eigth<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] day of Aprill One thousand six hundred sixty seaven at such place as the Co&bhooov;mis?sers shall appoint unto
their respe&bholigct;ive Head Colle&bholigct;ors who are hereby impowered and required to call upon and hasten their Sub Colle&bholigct;ors
to the said payment, and after the said [eigth<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] day of Aprill to leavy by Warrant under the Hands and Seales
of any two or more of the C&bhooov;mis?ser upon [any<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Subcolle&bholigct;or by Distresse such summe and summes. of Money as
ought by him to have beene paid and is not paid by reason of his failer in doeing. his duty according to the
dire&bholigct;ion of this A&bholigct;, soe as every Head Colle&bholigct;or may and shall make payment of the full summe by him to be
paid at or before the fifteenth day of the said Moneth of Aprill unto the respe&bholigct;ive Receivour Generall who is
likewise required to call upon and hasten the said Head Colle&bholigct;or.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Duplicate of Sum charged within every Hundred, &amp;c. to be returned into the Exchequer under the Hands and Seals of Commissioners, before 20th April next;
Appeals to be first determined; and like Duplicates to be delivered to Receivers General, and Money paid before 30th April 1667.
</head>
			<para id="p169">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may examine Presenters of Certificate, and if they have cause to suspe&bholigct; that Property is of a greater Value than represented, then to proceed against the Parties.; Commissioners may enquire, but not on Oath, into the Value of Property assessed.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p170">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That a true Duplicate of the whole summe charged within every Hundred Lath Wapentake
Parish Ward or place rated and assessed in pursuance of this A&bholigct; without nameing the persons shall under the
Hands and Seales of two or more of the Co&bhooov;mis?ers thereunto appointed be returned into His Majesties Exchequer
before the Twentyeth day of Aprill next ensueing (all Appeales being first determined) And that like Duplicates
be alsoe in convenient time made out and delivered unto the Receivers Generall and Head Colle&bholigct;ors according to
their respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;ions soe as every of them may be duely charged to answere their respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;ions
and Receipts and that the money due thereupon be paid into His Majesties Exchequer before the Thirtieth day
of the said moneth of Aprill One thousand six hundred sixty seaven, And upon returne of any such Certificate
the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers or any three or more of them shall and may if they see cause examine the Presenters thereof,
And if the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers or any three or more of them within their severall limitts shall have certaine knowledge
or vehemently suspe&bholigct; that any person or persons in the said Certificate mentioned is or are of a greater Value
or estate then in the said Certificate is mentioned The said Co&bhooov;mis?ers or any three or more of them shall have
power to warne such person or persons to appeare before them at a day and place prefixed to be examined
touching their Substance and Value, or touching other matters which may any way concerne the Premisses, And if
the person or persons warned to be soe examined shall negcle&bholigct; to appeare (not haveing a reasonable excuse for
such his Defaulte) every person soe makeing Defaulte shall pay unto His Majestie double the summe of, the Rate,
he should or ought to have beene sett at And moreover the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers or any three or more of them
shall have power by all lawfull wayes and meanes without Oath to examine and inquire into the value and
substance of such persons chargeable by this A&bholigct;, And to sett such rate or rates' upon every such person or
persons as shall be according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Commissioners may appoint Head Colle&bholigct;or; whose Receipt shall be a Discharge to Sub-colle&bholigct;or.</head>
			<para id="p171">
				<emph type="i">
2d. in the Pound to Sub-colle&bholigct;or. Head Colle&bholigct;or to pay to Receiver General; whose Receipt shall be a Discharge to Head Colle&bholigct;or.; 1d. in the Pound to Head Colle&bholigct;or.; Receiver General to pay into Exchequer.; Allowance to Receiver General.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p172">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed That the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers or any three or more of them in their respe&bholigct;ive Division or
Hundreds shall and are hereby, impowered to nominate and appoint under their hands and seales an honest able
and responsible person to be Head Colle&bholigct;or unto whom the moneyes [paid<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] by the Sub Colle&bholigct;or shall be
duely paid as aforesaid whose Receipt shall be a sufficient discharge unto every such Sub Colle&bholigct;or which
Sub Colle&bholigct;or for gathering the said perticular summes shall retaine in his hands for every Twenty shillings by
him soe paid Two pence as a reward for his paines and service, And the said Head Colle&bholigct;or is hereby required
upon the receipt thereof to pay the same [unto<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] the Receiver Generall of each County respe&bholigct;ively in manner aforesaid
And for his soe doeing the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers are hereby impowered and required to take such good Securitie as
they shall thinke fitt,. Consideration being therein had of the said Colle&bholigct;ors Receipt, And the said Receivers
Generalls Acquittance shall be a sufficient Discharge unto every such Head Colle&bholigct;or who shall retaine in his hands
for every Twenty shillings by him soe paid One penny as a reward for his paines and service, And the said
Receiver Generall shall (before the Thirtyeth day of Aprill aforesaid) pay the whole summe by him received into
His Majestyes Exchequer, and shall have an allowance of Two pence in the pound for all moneyes which shall
be by him paid into the Receipte of the Exchequer by the time prefixed in this A&bholigct;, and for soe much as shall
be by him paid in after the time prefixed One penny in the pound and noe more.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVII. Commissioners Clerks 2d. Per Pound.</head>
			<para id="p173">And for the carefull writeing and transcribeing the said Warrants Estreates and Duplicates in due time Bee it
further ena&bholigct;ed That the Co&bhooov;mis?sers Clerks who shall respe&bholigct;ively performe the same shall by Warrant under two
or more of the Co&bhooov;mis?sers hands have and receive from the respe&bholigct;ive Head Colle&bholigct;ors Two pence in the pound
of all such moneyes as he shall have received by vertue of such Warrants and Estreates who is hereby appointed
and allowed to pay the same accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Head Colle&bholigct;or not paying; Imprisonment and Real and Personal Estate to be seized.</head>
			<para id="p174">
				<emph type="i">
Commissioners seizing to give Notice of Meeting.; Commissioners at such Meeting may sell the said Estates for Payment; returning Overplus.; Persons assessed refusing to pay on Demand, Officer, may distrain.; Proceedings thereon.; Persons assessed not paying in 20 Days.; and where no sufficient Distress, Party to be imprisoned in the Common Gaol without Bail.; Person aggrieved by Rate, &amp;c. may complain to Commissioners.; Commissioners to meet to hear Complaints.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p175">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any Head Colle&bholigct;or, shall not pay into the Receiver Generall within the time
limited by this A&bholigct; all summes of money by him received by vertue of this A&bholigct; That then the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers
or any two or more, of them being informed thereof are hereby impowered and required to imprison every such
Head Colle&bholigct;or and alsoe to seise and secure the Estate both reall and personall of such Head Colle&bholigct;or or which
shall from him descend or come into the hands or possession of his Heires Executors or Administrators whereever
the same can be discovered or found, And the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers who shall soe seize and secure the Estate of any
Head Colle&bholigct;or shall be and are hereby impowered to appoint a time for the generall meeting of the Co&bhooov;mis?sers
of such County Citty or Towne and there to cause publique notice to be given [at<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] the place where such meeting
shall bee appointed ten dayes at least before such generall meeting, And the Co&bhooov;mis?sers present at Such generall
meeting or the major part of them in case the moneyes detained by such Head Colle&bholigct;or be not paid or satisfied
as ought to be according to the dire&bholigct;ions of this A&bholigct; shall and are hereby impowered and required to sell and
dispose of all such Estates or any part of them which shall be for the cause aforesaid seised and thereby to secure
and pay all the money in arreare in such Head Colle&bholigct;ors hand for His Majestyes use and returne the overplus
dedu&bholigct;ing necessary charges to such Head Colle&bholigct;or his [Heires<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Executors And Administrators respe&bholigct;ively, And if any
person or persons shall refuse to pay the severall summe and summes and proportions appointed by this A&bholigct; for
such person to pay upon demand made by the Officer or Colle&bholigct;or of the place according to the Precept or
Estreats to him delivered by the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers It shall and may be lawfull to and for such Officer or Colle&bholigct;or,
who are hereby thereunto authorized and required for non payment thereof to destraine the person or persons soe
refuseing by his or their Goods or Chattells and the distresse soe taken to keepe by the space of fower dayes at
the costs and charges of the Owner thereof. And if the said Owner doe not pay the summe of money due by this
A&bholigct; within the said fower dayes, then the said Distresse to be apprized by three or two of the Inhabitants where
the said Distresse is taken and there to be sould by the said Officer for payment of the said money and the
overplus comeing by the said Sale (if any be) over and above the charges of takeing and keeping the said Distresse
to be immediately restored to the Owner thereof And if any person or persons assessed by this A&bholigct; shall refuse
[or negle&bholigct; <ref idref="n23">23</ref>] to pay the summe or summes soe assessed by the space of twenty dayes after demand as aforesaid
where noe sufficient Distresse can or may be found whereby the same may be levyed, in every such case three
or more of the Co&bhooov;mis?sers by this A&bholigct; appointed for any such Citty County or Place are hereby authorized by
warrant under their Hands and Seales to commit such person or persons to the common Goale there to be kepte
without Baile or Maineprize untill payment shall be made, And if any person certified assessed or rated finde
him or herselfe agreived with such assessing or rateing, and doe within ten dayes after demand thereof made
complaine to the Co&bhooov;mis?sers, The said Co&bhooov;mis?sers or any two or more of them, whereof one of the Co&bhooov;mis?sers who
signed or allowed his or her Rate to be one shall and may within Fowerteene dayes next after such Complaint
particularly examine the person soe complaining upon his or her Oath of his or her personall Estate aforesaid,
And upon due examination or knowledge thereof abate defalke increase or inlarge the said Assessment, And the
same soe abated increased or inlarged shall be estreated by them into the Exchequer in manner aforesaid, And to
that end the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers are hereby required to meete together for the determining of such Complaints and
Appeales accordingly</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Officers to be rated where their Office executed.</head>
			<para id="p176">
				<emph type="i">Other Persons, not being Housholders, &amp;c. and Servants, where they live.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p177">And bee it; further ena&bholigct;ed That every person rated for his Office shall be rated and pay for his said Office
in the place where the said Office is executed, And every person to be otherwise rated shall be rated and the
summe or summes on him or her sett and levyed at such places where he or she and with his or her Family shall
be resident at the time of the execution of this A&bholigct;, And that all persons not being Householders nor haveing
a certaine place of abode and all Servants shall be taxed at the place where they are resident at the time of the
execution of this A&bholigct;, three moneths before the execution of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. If Persons having several Mansions be doubly charged.</head>
			<para id="p178">
				<emph type="i">How such Persons to be discharged.; Persons out of the Realm to be rated at last Place of Abode.; Persons escaping from Taxation to be charged at double Value.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p179">Provided alwayes That if any person haveing severall Mansion houses or places of Residence shall be doubly
charged by vertue of this A&bholigct; That upon Certificate made by two or more of the Co&bhooov;mis?sers for the County
Citty or Place (which Certificate the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers are required to give without delay fee or reward) of his or
their last personall Residence under their Hands and Seales of the summe or summes there charged upon him
or them and in what capacitie or respe&bholigct; he or they were soe charged and upon Oath made of such Certificate
before the Co&bhooov;mis?sers to whom such Certificate shall be tendred which Oath the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers are hereby authorized
to administer, Then the person and persons soe doubly charged shall (for soe much as shall be soe certified) be
discharged in every other County Citty or Place, And if any person at the time of the Assessing shall be out of
the Realme such person shall be rated where such person was last abideing within the Realme. And if any person
that ought to be taxed by vertue of this A&bholigct; by changing his place of residence or by fraude or coven shall escape
from the Taxation and not be taxed and the same proved before the Co&bhooov;mis?sers or two of them, or two Justices
of the Peace of the County where such person dwelleth or resideth at any time within Six moneths next ensueing after
such Taxe made, Every person that shall soe escape from the said Taxation and payment shall be charged upon
proofe thereof at the double value of soe much as he should or ought to have beene taxed by the A&bholigct;, The
said double value upon Certificated thereof made into the Exchequer by the Co&bhooov;missers or Justices before whom
such proofe shall bee made to be levyed of the Goods Lands and Tenements of such persons towards the Supply
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Commissioners may assess other Commissioners and Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p180">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Co&bhooov;mis?sers which shall be within any County or Place within their respe&bholigct;ive
limitts or the major part of them shall taxe and assesse every other Co&bhooov;mis?ser joyned with them and the Co&bhooov;mis?sers
within their Division shall assesse every Assessor within their Division And as well all summes upon every the
said Co&bhooov;missers and Assessors as the Assessments made and presented by the Presenters as aforesaid shall be written
estreated leavyed and gathered as it should and ought to have beene as if the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers had not beene named
Co&bhooov;mis?sers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Colle&bholigct;or for Peers.</head>
			<para id="p181">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That the severall Rates and Taxes to which the Lords and Peeres
of this Realme shall be lyeable by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be received by a Colle&bholigct;or to be nominated by the
Peeres which said Colle&bholigct;or shall cause the same to be paid into His Majestyes Receipted of Exchequer at Westminster
upon or before the aforesaid thirtyeth day of Aprill,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Proviso for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey and Guernsey.</head>
			<para id="p182">Provided That this A&bholigct; shall not extend to the Inhabitants of Scotland Ireland Jersey or Guernsey for or
concerning any such personall Estate as aforesaid which they or any other to their use have within the places
aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. Treasurers of Navy and Ordnance to retain id. in the Pound out of Monies paid to and issued by them.</head>
			<para id="p183">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the respe&bholigct;ive Treasurers of His Majestyes Navy and
Ordnance are hereby authorized and required to take and retaine unto themselves and such as shall be respe&bholigct;ively
imployed by and under them One penny in the pound and noe more out of the moneyes, raised by vertue of this
A&bholigct; and paid unto and issued out by them to any person or persons in pursuance thereof to be allowed unto
them in their respe&bholigct;ive Accompts.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Assessors and others appointed by Comissioners, negle&bholigct;ing Duty, Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p184">
				<emph type="i">To be certified into Exchequer.; Commissioners from time to time to require Accounts from Receiver General, and in case of Failure Money to be levied.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p185">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That if any Assessor Colle&bholigct;or Receiver or other person appointed by the Co&bhooov;mis?sers
shall willfully negcle&bholigct; or refuse to performe his Duty in the due and speedy Execution of this present A&bholigct;, the
said respe&bholigct;ive Co&bhooov;mis?sers or any three or more of them may and shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; impose on such
person or persons soe refuseing or negcle&bholigct;ing their Dutyes any fine not exceeding the summe of Twenty pounds
for any one offence the same to be leavyed and certifyed as aforesaid into His Majestyes Court of Exchequer and
charged upon the respe&bholigct;ive Receiver Generall amongst the rest or the Rates aforesaid, and the said Co&bhooov;mis?sers or
any two or more of them may or shall from time to time call for and require an Accompt from the respe&bholigct;ive
Receiver Generall of all the Moneyes received by him of the said Head Colle&bholigct;ors and of the payment thereof
into His Majestyes Receipte of Exchequer according to the dire&bholigct;ion, of this A&bholigct; And in case of any failer in the
premises the said Co&bhooov;is?sers or any two or more of them are hereby required to cause the same to be forthwith
leavyed and paid according to the true intend and meaning of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. If any Controversy between Commissioners concerning Rates, Proceedings.</head>
			<para id="p186">
				<emph type="i">Questions touching the Rates to be determined by Two or more Commissioners.; Receiver General to give Acquittances to Head Colle&bholigct;ors, and Head Colle&bholigct;ors, to Sub-colle&bholigct;ors gratis.; Sub-colle&bholigct;ors to deliver to Head Colle&bholigct;ors a Schedule of Names, &amp;c. of Persons making Default, to be returned into the Exchequer.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p187">And in case of any controversie ariseing betweene the [said<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] Co&bhooov;mis?sers concerning the said Rates or Assessments;
the Co&bhooov;mis?ers that shall be concerned therein shall have noe voice but shall withdraw the dureing the debate of such
controversy untill it be determined by the rest of the Co&bhooov;mis?sers And all questions and differencies that shall arise
touching any of the said Rates Taxes Assesments or Leavyes shall be heard and finally determined by two or more
of the Co&bhooov;mis?sers upon complaint thereof to them made by any person or persons thereby grieved without further
trouble or Suite in Law And the said Receiver Generall shall give Acquittances gratis to the said [Head<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] Colle&bholigct;ors,
for all moneys of them received &amp; the said Head Colle&bholigct;ors shall alsoe give Acquittances gratis to the Sub Colle&bholigct;ors,
for all such moneys as shalbe ?pd by them in pursuance of this A&bholigct;, which Acquittances shall be a full Discharge
to the said Head Colle&bholigct;ors and Subcolle&bholigct;ors respe&bholigct;ively. And the said Sub Colle&bholigct;ors shall make and deliver to
the said Head Colle&bholigct;ors a perfe&bholigct; Schedule fairely written in Parchment under their hands and seales signed and
allowed by any two or more of the respe&bholigct;ive Co&bhooov;mis?sers containing the names sirnames and places of abode of
every person within their respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;ion that shall make defaulte of payment of any of the summes that
shall be rated or assessed on such person by vertue of this A&bholigct; and the summe and summes charged on every
such person. The same Schedule to be delivered by the Head Colle&bholigct;or to the Receiver Generall of that County
Citty Towne or Liberty respe&bholigct;ively to be by him returned into His Majestyes Exchequer Whereupon every
person soe makeing defaulte of payment may be charged by Processe, of the Court according to the course thereof
in that behalfe</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Proviso against Double Charge in respe&bholigct; of Titles.</head>
			<para id="p188">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That noe person shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; be doubly charged for or in
respe&bholigct; of severall [Honours Titles<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] or Degrees but that every such person shall be charged and assessed for such
Title Honour or Degree onely as is highest rated by this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Letters Patent from the Crown of Privileges, &amp;c. or Non obstantes not to exempt from Payment of Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p189">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe Letters Patents granted by the Kings Majestie
or any of His Royall Progenitors or to be granted by His Majestie to any person or persons Cittyes Burroughes
or Townes corporate within this Realme of any manner of Libertyes Priviledges or Exemptions from Subsidyes Tolls
Taxes Assessments or Ayds shall be construed or taken to exempte any person or persons Citty Burrougli or
Towne corporate or any the Inhabitants of the same from the burthen and charge of any summe or summes of
money granted by this A&bholigct; or any other A&bholigct; of this Parlyment now in force to the Aid and Supply of His
Majestie in the present Warr, And all Non obstantes in any such Letters Patents made or to be made in barr of
any A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s of Parliament for the supply or assistance of His Majestie are hereby declared to be void and of
none effe&bholigct;, Any such Letters Patents Grants or Charter or any Clause of Non obstante or other matter or thing
therein contained or any Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Former Receiver in Arrear a&bholigct;ing,</head>
			<para id="p190">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;500</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p191">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any person being a Receiver of
money due upon any former A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament not haveing accompted for all the moneyes by him
received and to be accompted for upon such A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s before Michaelmas One thousand six hundred sixty six
shall be appointed Receiver for any the moneyes due by this A&bholigct; and shall intermedle therein, every such person
shall forfeite the summe of Five hundred pounds to be recovered by any person or persons that will sue for the
same in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill, Plaint or other Information wherein noe
Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion Wager of Law Aid Prayer Priviledge Injun&bholigct;ion or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise
prayed granted or allowed nor any more then one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. &pound;30,000 to the King's Guards.</head>
			<para id="p192">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That thirty thousand pounds and noe more of the money to be raised
by this A&bholigct; may be applyed for the payment of His Majesties Guards.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. By whom Peers to be rated for their Offices and Personal Estate.</head>
			<para id="p193">[Provided neverthelesse And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the Peeres who are to be rated by
vertue of this A&bholigct; for their Offices and personall Estates shall be rated by John Lord Roberts Lord Keeper of
the Privy Seale George Duke of Buckingham George Duke of Albemarle Generall of His Majestyes Forces by
Sea and Land Edward Earle of Manchester Lord Chamberlaine of His Majestyes Household Anthony Earle of Kent
Richard Earle of Dorset John Earle of Bridgewater James Earle of Northampton Oliver Earle of Bolingbrooke
Thomas Earle Rivers Arthur Earle of Essex Arthur Earle of Anglesey Charles Earle of Carlisle William Earle of
Craven Richard Lord Archbishop of Yorke Humphrey Lord Bishop of London George Lord Bishop of Winchester
Benjamin Lord Bishop of Lincolne Seth Lord Bishop of Exeter Edward Lord Bishop of Carlisle John Lord Bishop
of Rochester Henry Lord Arlington one of His Majestyes Principall Secretaryes of State George Lord Berkley of Berkley
Castle Phillip Lord Wharton Charles Lord Howard of Charleton William Lord Grey of Warke Francis Lord Newport
John Lord Lucas John Lord Bellasyse Charles Lord Gerard of Brandon Charles Lord Cornwallis and Anthony Lord
Ashley Chauncellour and Under Treasurer of His Majestyes Exchequer or any five of them and not otherwise
and shall not be subje&bholigct;ed to the Imprisonment of his or their Persons Any thing in this A&bholigct; contained to the
contrary in any wise notwithstanding.<ref idref="n27">27</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Repayment of Monies lent how to be secured.</head>
			<para id="p194">
				<emph type="i">Books to be provided.; Monies not to be issued out of Exchequer but by Warrant as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p195">And to the intent that all Moneyes to be lent to Your Majestie and the Moneyes that shall be due upon
Contra&bholigct;s for Wares Shipps Goods Vi&bholigct;ualls or other Necessaries which shall be delivered for this Service may be
well and sufficiently secured out of the Moneyes ariseing and payable by this A&bholigct; Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the
Authoritie aforesaid That there shall be provided and kepte in Your Majestyes Exchequer (to witt) in the Office of
the Auditor of the Receipt One Booke or Register in which all Moneyes that shall be paid into the Exchequer
shall be entred and registred apart and distin&bholigct; from all other Moneyes paid or payable to Your Majestie or to
Your Heires or Successors upon any other Branch of Your Revenue or upon any other Accompte whatsoever.
And that there be one other Booke or Registry provided and kepte in the said Office of all Orders and Warrants
to be made by the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer or by the Co&bhooov;mis?ers of the Treasury for the time being,
for payment of all and every summe and summes of Moneyes to all persons for Moneyes lent Wares Goods or
Vi&bholigct;ualls or other Necessaryes bought or Shipps hired, or other payments dire&bholigct;ed by Your Majestie relating
to the service of this Warr. And that noe Moneyes levyable by this A&bholigct; be issued out of the Exchequer dureing
this Warr but by such Order or Warrant mentioning That the Moneyes payable by such [Order or<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] Warrant are
for the service of Your Majestie in the said Warr respe&bholigct;ively. That alsoe there be the like Booke or Registry
provided and kepte by the said Auditor of all Moneyes paid out or issued by vertue of such Orders and
Warrants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. Lenders of Money and Furnishers of Wares, &amp;c. under this A&bholigct; to have free Access to Books.</head>
			<para id="p196">
				<emph type="i">Tally of Loan to Lender, and Warrant for Interest at &pound;6 per Cent. per Ann. to be paid every Three Months. Persons furnishing the Navy and Ordnance to have Warrant for;
Payment on Certificate, which is to be had without Fee.; Orders for Re-payment to be registered according to Date of Tally, and paid in course; ; without Preference.;Whether for Payment of Moniei lent or for Goods, &amp;c. furnished to the Navy, &amp;c.; Monies to come in by this A&bholigct; liable to satisfy such Loans.; No Fee for providing or making Books, &amp;c.; or for Payment of Money lent; Penalty.; Punishment. ; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty.
</emph>;
<emph type="i">
Undue Preference by Deputy; Penalty. ; Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or. Teller not making Payments in due Order; Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p197">And that it shall be lawfull for any person or persons willing to lend any money, or to furnish any Wares
Vi&bholigct;ualls Shipps Goods or other Necessaries on the Credit of this A&bholigct; at [the<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] usuall times when the Exchequer is
open to have accesse unto and [review<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] and peruse all or any of the said Bookes for their Information of the state
of those Moneyes and all ingagements upon them for their better incouragement to lend any moneyes or furnish
any Goods Wares Vi&bholigct;ualls Shipps or other Necessaries as aforesaid. And that the Auditor of the Receipte his
Deputyes and Clerkes shall be assistant to such persons for their better and speedier satisfa&bholigct;ion in that behalfe,
And that all and every person and persons who shall lend any Moneyes to Your Majestie and pay the same into
the [Receipt of the<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally of Loane strucke for the same and an Order for
his Repayment beareing the same Date with his Tally, in which Order shall be alsoe contained a Warrant for
payment of Interest for forbearance after the Rate of Six per Cent. per Ann&bhouov; for his consideration to be paid
every three Moneths untill the repayment of his Principall. And that all person and persons who shall furnish
Your Majestie, Your Officers of the Navy or Ordnance with any Wares Goods Shipps Vi&bholigct;ualls or any other
Necessaries for the Service aforesaid shall upon Certificate of the Co&bhooov;mis?ers and Officers of the Navy or of the
Master or Co&bhooov;mis?ers and Officers of the Ordnance or some of them without delay forthwith have made out to
them Warrants or Orders for the payment of the Moneyes due or payable unto them, which Certificates the said
Officers of Your Navy Co&bhooov;mis?ers and Officers of the Ordnance shall make without Fee Charge or Delay And that
all Orders for Repayment of Money lent shall be registred in course according to the Date of the Tallyes respe&bholigct;ively.
And that all Orders signed by the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer of the Exchequer for payment of moneyes
for Goods Wares Vi&bholigct;ualls and other Necessaries furnished to Your Majestie Your Officers Master or Co&bhooov;miss?ers as
aforesaid shall be registred in course according to the time of bringing to the Office of the Auditor of Receipte
the Certificates above-mentioned. And that all Orders soe signed for payments dire&bholigct;ed by His Majestie shall be
entred in course according to their respe&bholigct;ive Dates and none of the sortes of Orders above mentioned either for
Loanes of Money; Supplyes of Wares Goods Vi&bholigct;ualls or other necessaries or by speciall dire&bholigct;ion shall have
preference one before another but shall all be entred in their course according to the dates of the Tallyes the
times of bringing their Certificates and the dates of the Orders for Payments dire&bholigct;ed by His Majestie as they are
in pointe of time respe&bholigct;ively before each other, And that all and every person and persons shall be paid in
course according as their Orders shall stand entred in the said [Register<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] Booke be it Orders for Payments dire&bholigct;ed
by His Majestie or [of<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] moneyes lent, or for Wares Commodities Shipps Vi&bholigct;ualls or other necessaries furnished as
aforesaid soe as that the person Native or Forreyner his Executors Administrators and Assignes who shall have his
Warrant or Order Warrants or Orders first entred in the said Booke of Registry shall be taken and accounted
as the first person to be paid upon the moneyes to come in by vertue of this A&bholigct;, And he or they that shall
have his or their Warrants or Orders Warrant or Order next entred shall be taken and accounted the second
person to be paid and soe successively and in course And that the moneyes to come in by this A&bholigct; shall be in
the same Order lyeable to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said respe&bholigct;ive partyes their Executors Administrators or Assignes
successively without preference of one before another and not otherwise and not be divertable to any other use
intent or purpose whatsoever, And that noe Fee Reward or Gratuity dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly be demanded or taken
of any Your Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s for providing or makeing of any such Bookes Registers Entries View Search or
Certificate in or for payment of money lent or the Interest thereof, or for payment of any money upon any Order
upon any Contra&bholigct; for Wares and Goods furnished to the use of Your Majesties Navy and [Ordinance
<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] as aforesaid
by any of Your Majestyes Officer or Officers their Clerkes or Deputyes on paine of payment of treble damages to
the party greived by the partie offending with Costs of Suite, And if the Officer himselfe take or demand any such
Fee or reward then to loose his place alsoe, And if any undue preference of one before another shall be made
either in point of Registring contrary to the true meaning of this A&bholigct; by any such Officer or Officers then the
partie offending shall be lyeable by A&bholigct;ion of Debt or on the Case to pay the value of the Debt Damages and
Costs to the partie grieved and shall be forejudged from his Place or Office, And if such preference be unduely
made by any his Deputy or Clerke without dire&bholigct;ion or Privity of his Master then such Deputie or Clerke onely
shall be lyeable to such A&bholigct;ion Debt Damages and Costs and shall be for ever after uncapeable of his Place or
Office, And in case the Auditor shall not dire&bholigct; the Order or the Clerke of the Pells record or the Tellar,
make payment according to each persons due place and order as afore[said
<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] dire&bholigct;ed then he or they shall be
judged to forfeite, and their respe&bholigct;ive Deputyes and Clerks herein offending to be lyeable to such A&bholigct;ion Debt
Damages and Costs in such manner as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. How all such Penalties to be recovered.</head>
			<para id="p198">All which said Penaltyes Forfeitures Dammages and Costs to be incurred by any of the Officers of the Exchequer
Navy or Ordnance or any their Deputies or Clerkes shall and may be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill, Plaint or
Information in any of His Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoyne Prote&bholigct;ion Priviledge
Wager of Law Injun&bholigct;ion or Order of restrainte shall be in any wise granted or allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p199">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That if it happen that severall Tallyes of Loane or Certificates for
Wares delivered, or Orders for Payments dire&bholigct;ed by Your Majestie as aforesaid beare date or be brought the
same day to the Auditor of the Receipte to be registred then it shall be interpretted noe undue Preference which
of these he enters first soe he enters them all the same day.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded, no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Orders.</head>
			<para id="p200">Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpreted any undue preference to incurr any penaltie in point of payment
if the Auditor dire&bholigct; and the Clerke of the Pells record and the Tellar doe pay subsequent Orders of persons
that come and demand their money and bring their Orders before other persons that did not come to demand their
money and bring their Order in their course soe as there be soe much money reserved as will satisfie their Orders
which shall not be otherwise disposed but kepte for them Interest upon Loane being to cease from the time the
money is soe reserved and kepte in banke for them</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. Orders for Payment of Money lent may be assigned by Indorsement.</head>
			<para id="p201">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee</emph>; 				<emph type="i">Assigeec may in like Manner assign.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p202">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every person or persons to whom any moneyes shall
be due by vertue of this A&bholigct; after Warrant or Order entred in the Booke of Register aforesaid for payment
thereof his Executors Administrators or Assignes by Indorsement of his Order or Warrant may assigne and
transferr his Right Title Interest and Benefitt of such Warrant or Order or any part thereof to any other
which being notified in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt aforesaid and an entry and memoriall thereof alsoe,
made in the Booke of Registry aforesaid for Warrants (which the Officers shall on request without [Fee<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] or charge
accordingly make) shall intitle such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the benefitt thereof 
and payment thereon, And such Assignee may in like manner assigne againe and soe Toties quoties and afterwards
it shall not be in the power of such person or persons who have made such Assignements to make void, release
or discharge the same or the moneyes thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>In A&bholigct;ions brought touching Execution of this A&bholigct;, General Issue may be pleaded.; Treble Costs.</head>
			<para id="p203">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion Plaint Suite or Information shall be
commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in execution
of this A&bholigct; such person or persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall or may pleade the generall Issue not
guilty, and upon any issue joyned may give this A&bholigct; and the speciall matter in Evidence. And if the Plaintiffe or
Prosecutor shall become Nonsuite or forbeare further prosecution or suffer Discontinuance or if a Verdi&bholigct; passe
against him, the Defendant and Defendants shall recover their treble Costs for which they shall have the like
remedy as in any Case where Costs by the Law are given to [the<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] Defendants.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">of any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Poolie <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">Tregaygle <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Gent <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Herford <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Rives <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Botler <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">Esqrs <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Do&bholigct;o's <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">County <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">Cozen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">Execu?tion <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">eight <emph type="i">O.</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">received <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">Titles Honnors <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a feparate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">veiw <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">Registred <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">for <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">Ordnance <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">Fees <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


