<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47382" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1665</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IX. An Act for granting One Months Assessment to His Majestie.[Rot. Parl. 17 C. II. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
				<head>Recital of the Vi&bholigct;ory obtained by the Duke of York over the Dutch Fleet.</head>
			<para id="p1">
				<emph type="i">Grant to the Duke of &pound;120,902. 15s. 8d. to be raised as by; 16 &amp; 17 C.II. c. 1.; Recital of c. 1. ante.; The said Sum of &pound;120,902. 15s. 8d. to be assessed on the several Counties herein-after mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p2">Wee Your Majestyes most dutyfull and loyall Subje&bholigct;s the Co&bhooov;mons assembled in Parlyament takeing notice
of that heroicke Courage with which Your Majesties Royall Brother exposed his owne Person for the
Defence of Your Majestie and Your People against the Dutch Fleete and of the glorious Vi&bholigct;ory through the
blessing of Almighty God by him obtained are humble Suiters [to<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Your Majestie That we may have leave to make
some expressions of our humble Thanks to his Royall Highnesse for the same, and that for this end Your Majestie
would gratiously please to accepte from us Your loyall Subje&bholigct;s the summe of money herein after mentioned and
to bestow the same upon Your Majesties Royall Brother, Wherefore we Your Majestyes said dutyfull and loyall
Subje&bholigct;s have given and granted and by these presents doe give and grant unto Your most Excellent Majestie
(whom God long preserve) The Summe of One hundred and twenty thousand nine hundred and two pounds
fifteene shillings and eight pence to be raised and leavyed in manner following (that is to say) Whereas in and by
a certaine A&bholigct; lately passed for granting a Royall Ayde unto his Majestie of Twenty fower hundred threescore and
seaventeene thousand and five hundred pounds to be raised levyed and paid within the space of Three yeares. It
was amongst other things ena&bholigct;ed That the summe of Threescore and eight thousand eight hundred and nineteene
pounds and nine shillings by the Moneth for Thirty six Monthes begining from the Five and twentyeth day of
December One thousand six hundred sixty fower should be assessed taxed leavyed and paid by Twelve Quarterly
Payments in the severall Counties Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places within England and Wales and Towne
of Berwicke upon Tweede according to the Rates and Proportions therein expressed. And whereas in and by
another A&bholigct; passed in this present Session of Parlyament It is further ena&bholigct;ed That the summe of Fifty two thousand
fowerscore and three pounds six shillings eight pence by the Moneth for Twenty fower Moneths begining from the
Five and twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred sixty five shall be likewise assessed taxed colle&bholigct;ed
leavyed and paid by eight quarterly payments in the severall Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places within England
and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede over and above the said summe of Threescore and eight
thousand eight hundred and nineteene pounds and nine shillings as an addition to, and increase of the same monethly
Assessment Both which Summes together amount unto the summe of One hundred and twenty thousand nine
hundred and two pounds fifteene shillings and eight pence by the Moneth. It is now further ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings
most Excellent Majestie and by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
of the Co&bhooov;mons in this present Parliament assembled That the summe of One hundred and twenty thousand nine
hundred and two pounds fifteene shillings and eight pence for one Monethes Assesment more begining upon the
Six and twentyeth day of December One thousand six hundred sixty seaven and ending upon the Six and
twentyeth day of January in the same yeare shall be assessed taxed colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid in the severall
Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places within England and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon
Tweede according to the Rates and Proportions following That is to say</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>Rates of Counties.</head>
			<para id="p3">For the County of Bedford the su&bhouov;m of One thousand five hundred seaventy and five pounds twelve shillings
six pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p4">[For the County of Berks the su&bhooov;m of One thousand nine hundred eighty nine pounds four shillings nine pence
three farthings.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p5">The County of Bucks the summe of two thousand three hundred and ten pounds fowerteene shillings and
three pence.</para>
			<para id="p6">The County of Cambridge the summe of One thousand seaven hundred ninety and one pounds eighteene
shillings three halfe pence.</para>
			<para id="p7">The Isle of Ely the summe of Six: hundred and fowerteene pounds thirteene shillings, and nine, pence.</para>
			<para id="p8">The County of Chester with the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester the summe of One thousand fower
hundred and seaven pounds thirteene shillings and one penny.</para>
			<para id="p9">The County of Cornwall the summe of Two thousand seaven hundred and seaven pounds seaven pence
farthing.</para>
			<para id="p10">The County of Cumberland the summe of Two hundred ninety and five pounds thirteene shillings fower pence
farthing.</para>
			<para id="p11">The County of Derby the summe of One thousand five hundred and fifteene pounds one shilling and three
pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p12">The County of Devon the summe of Five thousand six hundred seaventy and fower pounds five shillings eleaven
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p13">The Citty and County of the Citty of Exon the summe of Two hundred and fower pounds eight shillings six
pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p14">The County of Dorset the summe of Two thousand three hundred sixty and two pounds two pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p15">The Towne and County of Poole the summe of Nineteene pounds five shillings eleaven pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p16">The County of Durham the summe of Five hundred sixty and eight pounds eighteene shillings two pence
farthing.</para>
			<para id="p17">The County of Yorke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke and Towne of Kingstone upon Hull
the summe of Six thousand ninety and fower pounds thirteene shillings nine pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p18">The County of Essex the summe of Five thousand fower hundred forty and three pounds fower shillings
eleven pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p19">The County of Gloucester the su&bhouov;me of Three thousand one hundred seaventy and seaven pounds two shillings
nine pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p20">The Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester the summe of Sixty and nine pounds fower shillings three
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p21">The County of Hereford the summe of One thousand nine hundred eighty and eight pounds one shilling five
pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p22">The County of Hertford the summe of Two thousand three hundred sixty and fower pounds five shillings and
eight pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p23">The County of Huntington the summe of One thousand one hundred and thirteene pounds five shillings and
six pence.</para>
			<para id="p24">The County of Kent with the Citty and County of the Citty of Canterbury the summe of Five thousand eight
hundred forty and fower pounds thirteene shillings two pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p25">The County of Lancaster the summe of One thousand seaven hundred sixty and eight pounds nine shillings
and ten pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p26">The County of Leicester the summe of One thousand nine hundred and five pounds eleaven shillings and nine
pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p27">The County of Lincolne with the Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne the summe of Fower thousand
five hundred twenty and three pounds seaventeene shilling and two pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p28">The Citty of London with the Liberty of St Martin Le Grand the summe of Eight thousand nine hundred forty
and fewer pounds fowerteene shillings two pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p29">The County of Midlesex with the Citty and Liberty of Westminster the sumnie of Three thousand nine hundred
thirty and six pounds and ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p30">The County of Monmouth the summe of six hundred eighty and five pounds two shillings nine pence three
farthings.</para>
			<para id="p31">The County of Northampton the summe of Two thousand fower hundred eighty and three pounds eighteene
shillings three pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p32">The County of Nottingham with the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham the summe of One
thousand five hundred thirty and fower pounds seaven shillings two pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p33">The County of Norffolke the summe of five thousand, nine hundred twenty and one pounds seaven shillings
fower pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p34">The Citty and County of the Citty of Norwich the summe of Three hundred and sixteene pounds fower
shillings fower pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p35">The County of Northumberland with the Townes of Newcastle and Berwicke upon Tweede the summe of Six
hundred fifty and fower pounds seaventeene shillings eleaven pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p36">The County of Oxo? the summe of One thousand nine hundred ninety and fower pounds seaventeene shillings
fower pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p37">The County of Rutland the summe of Fower hundred twenty and two pounds eight shillings one penny
farthing.</para>
			<para id="p38">The County of Salop the summe of Two thousand one hundred and fowerteene pounds twelve shillings eight
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p39">The County of Stafford the summe of One thousand fower, hundred [ninety<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] and seaven pounds fifteene shillings
nine pence. halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p40">The Citty and County of the Citty of Litchfield the summe of Two and twenty pounds sixteene shillings nine
pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p41">The County of Somerset the summe of Fower thousand eight hundred sixty and eight pounds eighteene shillings
ten pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p42">The Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll the summe of Three hundred and fifty pounds six shillings
six pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p43">The County of Southampton with the Towne and County of Southampton and the Isle of Wight the summe of
Three thousand eight hundred forty and six pounds six shillings and seaven pence.</para>
			<para id="p44">The County of Suffolke the summe of Five thousand seaven hundred ninety and fower pounds fifteene shillings
three pence farthing.</para>
			<para id="p45">The County of, Surrey with the Burrough of Southwarke the summe of Two thousand eight hundred and five
pounds eleaven shillings six pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p46">The County of Sussex the summe of Three thousand one hundred ninety and nine pounds fifteene shillings one
penny three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p47">The County of Warwicke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry the summe of Two thousand
ninety and fower pounds fifteene shillings eleaven pence.</para>
			<para id="p48">The County of Worcester the summe of One thousand eight hundred fifty and one pounds ten shillings
ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p49">The Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester the summe of Ninety seaven pounds nine shillings and three
farthings.</para>
			<para id="p50">The County of Wilts the summe of Three thousand fower hundred fifty and five pounds seaven shillings one
penny halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p51">The County of Westmerland the summe of Two hundred and three pounds fifteene shillings eight pence
halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p52">The Isle of Anglesey the summe of Two hundred and twenty pounds fifteene shillings and ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p53">The County of Brecknocke the summe of Fower hundred ninety six pounds six shillings six pence.</para>
			<para id="p54">The County of Cardigan the summe of One hundred eighty five pounds sixteene shillings eleaven pence three
farthings.</para>
			<para id="p55">The County of Carmarthen the summe of Fower hundred seaventy eight pounds ten shillings three halfe
pence.</para>
			<para id="p56">The County of Carnarvan the summe of Two hundred fifty and seaven pounds eleaven shillings three
farthings.</para>
			<para id="p57">The County of Denbigh, the summe of Three hundred ninety and two pounds thirteene shillings eight pence
halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p58">The County of Flint the summe of Two hundred and eight pounds sixteene shillings three pence three
farthings.</para>
			<para id="p59">The County of Glamorgan the summe of Six hundred sixty and five pounds fowerteene shillings one penny
three farthing.</para>
			<para id="p60">The County of Merioneth the summe of One hundred seaventy and seaven pounds one shilling and nine pence
three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p61">The County of Montgomery the summe of Fower hundred eighty and five pounds eighteene shillings and
eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p62">The County of Pembrooke the summe of Five hundred seaventy and three pounds eleaven shillings seaven pence
three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p63">The County of Radnor the summe of Three hundred and six pounds five shillings two pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p64">The Towne of Haverford West: the summe of Twenty and six pounds thirteene shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>II. The Commissioners under the said A&bholigct;, 16&amp; 17 C. II. c. 1. to be Commissioners under this A&bholigct;, and to have the like Powers, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p65">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the persons who are appointed to a&bholigct; as Co&bhooov;mis?ers for execution
of the said former A&bholigct; shall likewise be, and soe are hereby constituted and appointed to be Co&bhooov;mis?ers for execution
of this present A&bholigct; within the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places for which
they were formerly appointed and shall have and execute like Powers and Authorities Rules and Dire&bholigct;ions touching
									<emph type="i">Assessors, &amp;c. to have the like Benefits and to be liable to the like Penalties as under the said A&bholigct;</emph>.
the better assessing colle&bholigct;ing leavying receiving and paying the said One hundred and twenty thousand nine hundred
and two pounds fifteene shillings and eight pence And all and every person or persons who shall be lyeable to, or
any wayes concerned or imployed in the assessing colle&bholigct;ing leavying receiving or paying (<emph type="p">1</emph>) of the moneyes by this
A&bholigct; imposed shall have like Benefitts Advantages and Discharges and shall be subje&bholigct; to like Penaltyes and
Forfeitures in case of any negcle&bholigct; or refusall to pay their respe&bholigct;ive Assesment or to performe their respe&bholigct;ive
Dutyes as any other person or persons lyeable unto or concerned or imployed in the assessing colle&bholigct;ing levying
receiving or paying any of the said former Assessments ought to have or be subje&bholigct; unto as fully and amply
as if all and every the Clauses Matters and Things to the said former Assesments relateing had beene againe in
this A&bholigct; repeated and ena&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>III. Commissioners to meet. The said &pound;120,902. 15s. 8d. to be raised and paid on or before the 15th Feb. 1667.</head>
			<para id="p66">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the severall Co&bhooov;mis?ers shall meete together at the most usuall and common
place of Meeting upon or before the Tenth day of January One thousand, six hundred sixty seaven to putt this
A&bholigct; in execution, And that the said One hundred and twenty thousand nine hundred and two pounds fifteene
shillings and eight pence shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid unto the Receivers of the severall Countyes
appointed or to be appointed by His Majestie and by them answered and paid into His Majestyes Exchequer upon
or before the Fifteenth day of February One thousand six hundred sixty and seaven.</para>
			<para id="p67">ITE queda? Petitio privatas Personas concernens (in se form? A&bholigct;us continens) exhibita fuit predi&bholigct;o D?o Regi in
Parliamento &bholigct;di&bholigct;o cujus Titulus subscribitur.</para>
			<para id="p68">1. An Act for the naturalization of Lewis Blanquefort and others.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
</report>


