<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47400" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1667 &amp; 1668</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter V. An Act for setling Freedome and Intercourse of Trade between England and Scotland [Rot. Parl. 19 &amp; 20 C. II. nu. 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Twelve English Commissioners to meet certain Commissioners from Scotland, to treat concerning Liberty and Freedom of Trade; who may suspend Duties, and Penalties.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The Agreement between them drawn into Writing, and, being ratified, to be of force</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas your most excellent Majesty was pleased on the first day of this Sessions of Parliament to
recommend to your two Houses of Parliament the due setling of the Trade between your Subjects of this
Kingdome and your Subje&bholigct;s of Scotland your said [two<ref idref="n1">1</ref>
] Houses having taken the same into theire serious Consideration
do for the better intercourse and freedome of Trade between your said Kingdoms most humbly beseech your
most excellent Majesty that it may be ena&bholigct;ed And be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majesty by and
with the advice and consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal and the Commons in this present Parliament
assembled and by authoritie of the same That twelve persons to be nominated by your Majestie be Commissioners
for this Kingdome or any five or more of them shall by force of this A&bholigct; from and after the tenth day of
January One thousand six hundred sixty seaven have full Power Commission and Authority at any time or times
before the twenty fifth day of March One thousand six hundred sixty eight and so from time to time to assemble
and meet att any place by the Kings Majesty to be appointed within the Kingdom of England and thereupon to
treat and consult as alsoe to conclude and determine with certaine sele&bholigct;ed Commissioners to be nominated and
sufficiently authorized of and for the Realm of Scotland of and concerning the Freedome and Liberty of Trade
between the Kingdom of England and the Kingdome of Scotland by suspending all or any of the Duties and
Impositions or any part of them or of any of them which have att any time since the five and twentieth day of
March in the twelfth yeare of his Majesties Reigne been charged setled laid or imposed upon all or any the
Comodities of the Growth Produ&bholigct;ion or Manufa&bholigct;ure of either of the said Kingdomes or upon any Comodities of
any of the Planta&bhocotil;ns or Dominions belonging to the Kingdome of England or any other Forreign C&bhooov;modities
exported out of the said Kingdom into the Kingdom of Scotland and likewise by suspending any Penalties or Forfeitures
or any part of them for not due payment of the said Duties and Impositions And what shall be concluded and
determined by and betweene the said C&bhooov;missioners for the Realm of England or any five of them with the said
Commissioners for the Realm of Scotland according to the tenour or purport of theire Authority or Commission
in that behalfe the same being reduced in Writing under the Hands and Seales of the said Commissioners of both
Kingdomes and being alsoe approved of ratified and confirmed by the Kings most excellent Majestie shall be in
full force and effe&bholigct; for the term of one whole yeare to be accounted from the date of such Ratification and
Confirmation by the Kings most excellent Majesty or untill the end of the next Session of Parliament which shall
first happen and no longer Any Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>


