<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47416" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VIII. An Act for ascertaining the Measures of Corne and Salt. [Rot. Parl. 22 C. II. nu. 8.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that there is a great Variety of Measures contrary to Law;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and of 17 (16) Car. I. c. 19. ?6.; The said Clause repealed.; Winchester Measure only to be used.; Penalty 40s.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas there is a great variety of Bushells and other Measures of different Contents and Gauges used
in several Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Ports and other places of this Realme for the measureing buying
and selling of all sorts of Graine, Salt and other Commodityes usually bought and should by the Bushell to the
great defrauding and oppressing of the people contrary to the Great Charter and sundry of the good Lawes
formerly made and ena&bholigct;ed That there shall be but one Measure to be used throughout all the Realme. For
future redresse whereof Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by authoritie of the
same That this ensueing Clause contained in a Statute made in the Seaventeenth yeare of King Charles the First
Entituled An A&bholigct; for the better ordering and regulateing of the Office of Clerke of the Market, allowed and
confirmed by this Statute, and for the Reformation of false Weights and Measures (by way of Proviso viz) That
such Measure as is commonly called Water measure in any Ports Maritine Townes or other places shall be still
used and continued as formerly the same hath beene)<?bignore?> Any thing in this Statute contained to the contrary hereof
in any wise notwithstanding, shall from and after the Nine and twentyeth day of September One thousand six
hundred and seaventy be and stand nulled and repealed as to the measureing selling or buying of any sort of
Corne or Grain ground or unground or Salt within the Kingdome of England, Dominion of Wales or Towne
of Berwicke upon Tweede, And that if any person or persons after the time aforesaid shall sell any sort of
Corne or Grain ground or unground, or any kinde of Salt usually sould by the Bushell either in open Market
or any other place by any other Bushell or Measure then that which is agreeable to the Standard marked in
his Majestyes Exchequer commonly called the Winchester Measure containing Eight Gallons to the Bushell and
noe more or lesse, and the said Bushell strucken even by the Wood or brim of the same by the Seller and
sealed as this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;s, he or they shall forfeite for every such Offence the summe of Forty shillings to be
leavyed in such manner and such other penaltyes for want of Distresse to be infli&bholigct;ed as in and by the said
former A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed by the Warrant or Order of any one or more of his Majestyes Justices of the Peace
within the County, City or place where such Offence shall be committed; which said Justices respe&bholigct;ively are
hereby required and enabled to see this Statute duely executed.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Mayors and other Officers permitting the Use of any other Measure, or not punishing;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it likewise further ena&bholigct;ed by authoritie aforesaid That if any Maior or other Head Officer of any
City, Burrough or Corporation or Liberty within this Kingdome of England Dominion of Wales or Towne
of Berwicke upon Tweede shall knowingly and wilfully permitt or suffer any person or persons within their
respe&bholigct;ive Limitts or Jurisdi&bholigct;ions to sell or buy any sort of Corne or Grain ground or unground, or Salt by
any other Bushell or Measure or strucken in any other manner then is hereby prescribed, or shall suffer within
their respe&bholigct;ive Limitts or Jurisdi&bholigct;ions any other Measure to be used then is of the Contents aforesaid and sealed
as this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;s, or if upon complaint of the breach of this. Statute, he or they shall not duely punish and
reforme the same according to the purporte thereof then he or they soe offending for every such Offence upon
due proofe and convi&bholigct;ion thereof by Presentment or Indi&bholigct;ment before the Justices of the Peace of the County
where such Offence shall be committed at the Generall Sessions of the. Peace held for the same shall forfeite the
summe of Five pounds, the one moyty thereof to the Informer or Prosecutor the other moyty to the use of the
Poore of the Parish where such Offence shall be committed to be leavyed by Distresse and Sale of the Offenders
Goods and Chattells, And for defaulte of such Distresse by Imprisonment of the person or persons soe offending
till payment thereof made by Warrant of the said Justices</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Clerk of the Market, &amp;c. negle&bholigct;ing or refusing to seal or mark any Measure; First Offence, Penalty &pound;5. Other Offence, Penalty &pound;10.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Exa&bholigct;ing undue Fees; Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That if the Clerke of the Market of his Majestyes House within the Verge or the
Maior or other Head Officer, Lord of the Liberty or other person authorized by the Lawes of the Realnie to
marke or seale Measures within their respe&bholigct;ive Jurisdi&bholigct;ions shall negcle&bholigct; or refuse being required to seale or
marke any Bushell, Halfe bushell or Pecke duely gauged as is hereby before dire&bholigct;ed and appointed shall forfeite
for the first offence Five pounds and for every other Offence Ten pounds to be leavyed as aforesaid; or if the
Clarke of the Market of his Majestyes House within the Verge shall take more then the lawfull and accustomed
Fees; or if any other person or persons shall exa&bholigct; or take from any person more then one penny for the sealeing
and markeing of a Bushell, or more then one halfe penny for the sealeing or markeing of a Halfe bushell or Pecke,
or more then one farthing for the sealeing or markeing of any measure containing one Gallon, Potle, Quart, Pinte
or Halfe pinte he or they shall for every such offence upon due proofe and convi&bholigct;ion thereof incurre the penaltyes
mentioned and contained in the aforenamed Statute for the said offence made in the seaventeenth yeare of King
Charles the First.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. A Measure of Brass to be chained in every public Market-place;</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">And to the end that there may be a just and certaine Measure (to determine all Controversies) gauged as
this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;s Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That at the charge of such person or persons respe&bholigct;ively who shall have
the Toll, or Proffit of the Market where Toll is not taken within any City Corporation or Market Towne within
this Realme in their respe&bholigct;ive Jurisdi&bholigct;ions there shall be before the said Nine and twentyeth day of September
One Measure of Brasse provided and chained in the publique Market place upon paine to forfeite and loose for
every Person soe negcle&bholigct;ing respe&bholigct;ively the summe of Five pounds to be recovered and leavyed as is by this
A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ed, One moyety to the Poore of the Parish where such offence shall be committed, the other moyty
to him or them that shall sue for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Constables to search if any Persons use other Measures or Strike unduly; and to break Measures, and present Offender at Sessions.</head>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That all and every Constable or Constables within this
Realme of England in their respe&bholigct;ive Precin&bholigct;s are hereby impowered and required to search and examine if any
person or persons use any other measure then according to the proportions aforesaid, or shall strike the same in
any other manner then this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;s, or sell or buy by a measure unsealed, And in case he or they shall finde
any such unsealed measure to seise and breake the same, and for that and every other offence against this A&bholigct; shall
present such Offender at the next private or quarterly Sessions to be held for such County or place where such
offence shall be committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. No Double Punishment.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That noe person or persons punished for any Offence by vertue of this A&bholigct;
shall be againe questioned or punished for the same offence by vertue or colour of any other A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Toll taking regulated.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That noe person or persons whatsoever shall take
any Toll or any thing in lien thereof, but respe&bholigct;ively according to such proportion as the measures in this A&bholigct;
limited and appointed beare unto the measures whereby the same have beene heretofore usually taken. Any Law,
Custome or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


