<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47411" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for granting unto his Majestie an Imposition upon all Wines and Vinegar imported betweene the Fower
and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred seaventy and the Fower and twentyeth day of June One
thousand six hundred seaventy eight.; [Rot. Parl. 22 C. 11. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>An Imposition upon French Wine, Spanish Wine, and all other Wines and Vinegar, from the 24th June 1670 to the 24th June 1678.</head>
		<para id="p1">Wee your Majestyes most dutyfull and loyall Subje&bholigct;s the Commons assembled in Parlyament for a supply
of your Majestyes weighty and important occasions and with an humble and thankfull acknowledgement of
your Majestyes favourable and tender reguard of us your Commons have chearfully and unanimously given and
granted unto your Majestie an Aid and Assistance to be raised and leavyed upon all Wines and Vinegar to be
imported into this your Majestyes Kingdome according to such Rates, and dureing such time, and in such manner
and forme as herein after followeth : And wee doe humbly beseech your Majestie that it may be ena&bholigct;ed, and bee
it enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and of the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That for
all French Wines, Spanish Wines or other Wines whatsoever, as alsoe for all Vineger which at any time after the
Fower and twentyeth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and seaventy, and before
the Fower and twentyeth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy eight shall be
imported into England or Wales or the Towne and Port of Berwicke upon Tweede there shall be duely answered
and paid to his Majestie the further Rates and Dutyes hereafter mentioned (that is to say) For every Tunn of
French Wine and of Vineger which shall be imported within the time aforesaid the summe of eight pounds by the
Tunn and soe after that Rate for any greater or lesser quantity ; And alsoe for every Tunn of Spanish Wines,
or of any other Wines, which shall be imported within the time aforesaid the summe of Twelve pounds by the
Tunn, and soe after that Rate for any greater or lesser quantity.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Importers before landing to pay the Duty, or give Security, at Discretion of Commissioners, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p2">
				<emph type="i">Times of Payment on Security.; Importers for private Use, on Entry, and before landing, to pay Duty down without Discount.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p3">And for the better and more sure colle&bholigct;ing and receiveing of all and singular the Dutyes hereby imposed
Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any person or persons within the time aforesaid shall
import or cause to be imported by way of Merchandize any of the Liquors aforesaid, such Importer shall upon
the Entry made of such Liquors and before the landing thereof pay downe the Dutyes hereby imposed in ready
money, dedu&bholigct;ing the Allowances hereafter mentioned, or otherwise become bound unto his Majestie with two or
more sufficient Suretyes, or procure three other persons to become bound to his Majestie to answere and pay
unto his Majestie the whole Rates and Dutyes hereby imposed by three severall and equall payments; The first
payment thereof to be made within three moneths after the Date of the said Obligation; The second payment to
be made within six moneths after the Date of the said Obligation; And the third and last payment to be made
within nine moneths after the Date of the said Obligation; the takeing which Bonds and the Approbation of the
Suretyes therein to be named is hereby left to the discretion of such Farmers or other Commissioners for the time
being as shall be intrusted with the receipt and management of his Majestyes Customes and Subsidyes of Tonnage
and Poundage or their Deputy Colle&bholigct;ors in the severall Ports, or such other person or persons as his Majestie
shall authorize and appoint to colle&bholigct; the Dutyes ariseing by this A&bholigct; And if any person or persons shall import
any of the Liquors aforesaid within the time aforesaid not by way of Merchandice nor with intent to sell the
same againe, but for his owne private use or occasions, such person soe importing the same shall upon Entry
thereof made immediately and before landing thereof pay downe the whole Dutyes by this Act imposed in ready
money without any further time given, or any Security to be accepted for the same, or any Abatement or
Discount to be therefore made upon any pretence whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Abatement to Merchant upon paying ready Money.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared and enacted That all and every person and persons importing any
of the Liquors aforesaid within the time aforesaid by way of Merchandise who shall pay the Dutyes which by this
Act are due and payable in ready moneyes shall be allowed and abated out of the said Dutyes after the rate of
Ten pounds per Cent for a yeare in consideration of such ready money soe paid downe and advanced.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Landing Goods without paying or giving Security for Duty;</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Penalty; But such Persons importing or landing still liable to Duty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any of the said Liquors shall be imported within
the time aforesaid and landed without present payment made of the Rates and Dutyes by this A&bholigct; imposed in cases
where this A&bholigct; requires present payment to be made, or without Security given for payment thereof in cases
where this A&bholigct; admitts of Security to be taken That then and in every such case all and every the Liquors soe
imported and landed, or the value thereof shall be forfeited; One moity thereof to his Majestie and the other
moyty to him or them that shall or will sue for the same, And shall and may be recovered in any Court of
Record by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Information, wherein noe Essoyne, Prote&bholigct;ion, or Wager of Law shall
be allowed, nor any more then one Imparlance. And yet neverthelesse the person soe importing and landing any
of the said Liquors shall notwithstanding such Forfeiture soe as aforesaid incurred remaine and continue lyeable
unto, and shall answere and pay unto his Majestie the Rates and Dutyes for such Liquors which by this A&bholigct;
are due and payable.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Recital of 12 Car. II. c. 4. Duty only upon neat Liquors.</head>
			<para id="p7">And whereas by the A&bholigct; for Tonnage and Poundage and the Instru&bholigct;ions and Rules for colle&bholigct;ing his Majestyes
Dutyes ariseing thereby it is directed that certaine Allowances be made upon Importation of Wines and other
Liquors; Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That noe Importer thereof shall be chargeable by vertue of this A&bholigct; to pay the
Duty hereby required for any greater proportion of Wines, or other Liquors duely entred at the Custome House
then what shall remaine neat after all such Allowances and Abatements.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Abatements to Importers not Vintners or Retailers for Accidents, &amp;c. upon Oath.</head>
			<para id="p8">And whereas this present A&bholigct; gives noe Abatement to any person upon Exportation of any the Liquors aforesaid
Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That all Importers not being Vintners or Retailers (who are hereby declared
shall pay ready money for the whole Duty) who shall import any of the aforesaid Liquors within the time aforesaid,
and shall make Oath that the same are imported by way of Merchandise and with intent to sell againe (which
Oath the Farmers or Commissioners of his Majestyes Customes for the time, being, or in their absence the Colle&bholigct;or
of his Majestyes Customes in each severall respe&bholigct;ive Port, or such other person or persons as his Majestie shall
authorize and appoint to colle&bholigct; the Dutyes ariseing by this A&bholigct; have hereby power to administer) That then and
in every such case for and in consideration of any defe&bholigct; or dammage that may happen by any of the aforesaid
Liquors lyeing longer on the [said<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Importers hands then heretofore, or by reason of any other Accident there shall
be allowed and abated to every such Importer the further allowance of Eight pounds per Cen? and noe more.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Prizage Wine.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided That noe Merchant shall be charged with any Duty imposed by this A&bholigct; for the Prizage Wine
which he imports in any Shipp or Vessell, nor shall any Security be by him given for the same, but that it be
received and taken from the person who hath or enjoyeth the benefitt of the said Prizage Wine, who is hereby
appointed to pay the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. No Exporter to receive back Duties paid or secured, or to have his Security lessened or discharged.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared and ena&bholigct;ed That if any of the said imported Liquors for which
any of the Rates and Dutyes [by this Act imposed<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] shall be paid downe and advanced or otherwise secured as
aforesaid shall at any time after such Importation be againe exported into parts beyond the Seas That then and
in every such case the person or persons soe exporting the same shall be wholly barred and excluded from
haveing or receiveing backe the Dutyes of this A&bholigct; soe paid downe and advanced or any part thereof, Nor shall
the Securitie formerly given by such person exporting for the true payment of the Dutyes by this A&bholigct; imposed
be any wayes eased, lessened or discharged by reason of such Exportation, but the same Securityes shall remaine
and continue in full force untill the Duty thereby secured be fully and wholly satisfyed and paid, Any such
Exportation to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Power to Officers of Customs to search on board Ships, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Defrauding His Majesty of the said Duties; Penalty.; Onus probandi as to Duty paid or secured on Claimant.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p12">And for the better prevention of all such Frauds which at any time hereafter may be committed to the
prejudice of his Majestie in the due colle&bholigct;ing and receiveing of the Dutyes hereby imposed upon such Liquors to
be imported as aforesaid Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the Officers of his Majestyes
Customes or such other person or persons as his Majestie shall authorize and appoint to colle&bholigct; the Dutyes
ariseing by this A&bholigct; shall have like Power and Authoritie to enter on board Shipps and Vessells and make
Searches and to doe all other matters and things which may tend to secure the true payment of the Dutyes by
this A&bholigct; imposed, and the due and orderly Colle&bholigct;ion thereof, which any Customers Colle&bholigct;ors or other Officers of
any his Majestyes Ports can or may doe touching or concerning [the colle&bholigct;ing or secureing<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] his Majestyes Customes
[and Subsadies<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of Tonnage and Poundage and all the said Liquors to be imported within the time aforesaid and
landed without doeing and performing what by this A&bholigct; is required to be done and performed before the Landing
thereof, And all Officers of his Majestyes Customes and all persons importing any of the said Liquors and all others
imployed by his Majestie in the Colle&bholigct;ion of the Dutyes ariseing by this A&bholigct;, who shall be found guilty of any
a&bholigct; or negcle&bholigct; tending to defraude his Majestie of any the Dutyes hereby imposed shall be subje&bholigct; and lyeable to
the same Seizures, Penaltyes and Forfeitures which by vertue of any former A&bholigct; can or may be infli&bholigct;ed in
such cases, where his Majestie is defrauded or endeavoured to be defrauded of any his Customes or Subsidyes, as
fully and amply as if the same Clauses of Seizures, Penaltyes and Forfeitures and the same distribution of such
Forfeitures and the same remedy for recovery thereof had beene againe in this A&bholigct; perticularly repeated, applyed and
ena&bholigct;ed, And if any liquors seised for any offence committed against this A&bholigct; shall be claimed by any person as the
Importer thereof, the proofe whether the dutyes thereof be duely paid or secured shall lye upon such claimer
and shall not be incumbent on His Majestie or any Prosecutor or Informer on behalfe of His Majestie and
himselfe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Until the Duties under 19 &amp; 20 Car. II. c. 6. (20 Car. II. c. 1.) be raised, Securities by Retailers before 24th June 1670 to remain.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for the King, and all claiming under him, levying Arrears of Duties, &amp;c. under the said A&bholigct;.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p14">And it is hereby further declared and ena&bholigct;ed That untill the whole moneyes intended to be raised by an A&bholigct;
entituled An A&bholigct; for raiseing Three hundred and ten thousand pounds by an imposition upon Wines and other
Liquors, be fully raised and satisfyed all Entryes Obligations and Securityes made or entred into by any retayler
before the fower and twentyeth day of June One thousand six hundred and seaventy, [for payment of any of the
dutyes by the said A&bholigct; imposed shall remaine and continue in full force although the liquors the dutyes whereof
are soe secured shall be uttered by retaile after the said fower and twentyeth day of June 1670<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] And alsoe
that His Majestie and all others claimeing by from and under His Majestie shall have the same power and authority
for leavying all arrearages of the rates, dutyes, fynes or forfeitures which already are or hereafter shall grow due
by vertue of the said [former<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] A&bholigct; as fully and amply as he or they might have had if this present A&bholigct; had
never beene had nor made;</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Recital that Persons had advanced Monies on the said former A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">The Authority of the Commissioners under this A&bholigct; for Execution of 19 &amp; 20 Car. II. c. 6. (20 Car. II. c. 1.) transferred to such other Persons as the King shall appoint who may examine, &amp;c.; Importers refusing to be examined how to be charged.; Oath of Importer to be a Convi&bholigct;ion of Retailer as to Quantity sold to him, and Retailer charged accordingly.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p16">And whereas severall persons have advanced great Summes of money for His Majestyes Service [after<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the rate of
six pounds per cen? upon the security of the former A&bholigct; and in order to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of their debts are registred
in course in His Majestyes Court of Exchequer as by the said A&bholigct; was required To the end therefore that all
and every the rates and impositions by the said former A&bholigct; made due and payable may be fully answered dureing
such time as the said A&bholigct; is to continue in force, and the said Security made effe&bholigct;uall by a discovery of such
Wines and other liquors aforesaid chargeable by the said A&bholigct; which have beene or before the fower and twentyeth
day of June One thousand six hundred and seaventy shall be delivered out to any retailer without due payment
made, or security given for the dutyes by the said A&bholigct; imposed. Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the authority given
to the present Commissioners for execution of the said former A&bholigct; shall continue in force untill the first day of
O&bholigct;ober next ensueing, and shall be transferred to and putt in execution by such other persons as the Kings
Majestie shall for that purpose appoint, and such other persons soe to be appointed shall have power to informe
themselves by the entryes at the Custome house or otherwise what quantityes of Wines have beene imported since
the first day of O&bholigct;ober last past, and what quantity of other liquors have beene imported since the first day of
February One thousand six hundred sixty and nine, and to examine each Importer upon oath to what retailer
the same were sold or delivered; and all importers refuseing to be soe examined shall be and are hereby charged
with the payment of soe much money as the said Wines or other liquors entred by such Importer at the Custome
house would have amounted to, in case the same had beene sold to any retailer; and the oath of every [such<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]
Importer shall be and is hereby declared a sufficient convi&bholigct;ion of every retailer touching the quantities of Wines
or other Liquors to him sold or delivered to retaile, and all and every retailer shall be, and is hereby charged
with soe much money as the dutyes of such liquors soe sworne to be delivered doe amount unto by the said
former A&bholigct;, and His Majestie shall and may cause the same to be leavyed accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Recital that great Quantities of Wines imported by Retailers since 1st O&bholigct;. 1668 have not paid the Duty.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Retailer to pay such Duty; and Customhouse Book, and his Entry a Charge as to so much as he shall not discharge himself of by Oath.; Proviso as to travelling to take the Oath.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p18">And forasmuch as great quantities of Wine have beene imported since the first day of O&bholigct;ober One thousand
six hundred sixty and eight by persons being retailers of Wine which Wines or a great part thereof have not paid
the duty as by the said A&bholigct; ought to have beene done Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That
all and every such retailer shall pay the duty for all such wine as was by him soe imported, and the Custome
house booke and his entry thereof shall be a charge upon such retailer, and the said retailer shall pay for all
such Wines soe entred as he shall not discharge himselfe [of<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] either by his owne corporall oath or by the oath of
two other credible witnesses that he hath already paid the said duty or secured the same, or hath sold such Wine
to some other retailer. Provided that noe person be compellable to travell out of the [Country<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] where he dweleth
to take the said oath.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Liquors not having paid Duty in the Stores of Merchants or Retailers on the 24th June 1670, charged.</head>
			<para id="p19">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that all liquors aforesaid which upon the fower and twentyeth day of June One
thousand six hundred and seaventy shall remaine in the Cellars or Storehouses of any Merchant Importer
Wine-Cooper or other tradeing person or retailer (unlesse the said retailer hath paid or secured the duty) shall be
lyeable unto and charged with the duty imposed by this A&bholigct; and shall pay or secure to His Majestie the duty
[due<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] for the same haveing allowance of the same abatements and defalcations to all intents and purposes as if
the said Wine had beene imported within the time limited by this present A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Persons appointed by the King to search for and take an Account of such Liquors.</head>
			<para id="p20">
				<emph type="i">Unduly removing such Liquors; Penalty.; How Monies received by virtue of this Clause to be applied.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p21">And to the end there may be an accompt taken of all such Wines soe remaining Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That
it shall and may be lawfull for His Majestie to appoint one or more persons to search for the same and take an
accompt thereof; and if any Importer or other person aforesaid shall sell, remove or otherwise dispose any such
Wines before the securitie given or money paid as in this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed in case of importation all such Wines soe.
sould removed or disposed or the value thereof shall be forfeited and lost together with the value of the duty which
ought to have beene paid His Majestie for the same, one halfe to His Majestie and the other halfe to him or them
that shall sue for the same in any Court of Record to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of debt; bill, plaint or information,
And all moneyes to be received or recovered by vertue of this Clause shall in the first place be applyed for and
towards the satisfa&bholigct;ion of such creditors as have advanced money upon the credit of the said former A&bholigct; in such
order and course as they now stand registred in His Majestyes Court of Exchequer.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">at <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">County <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


