<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47414" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act for advanceing the Sale of Fee-Farme Rents and other Rents.; [Rot. Parl. 22 C. II. nu. 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that Advantages should be granted to Purchasers of Fee Farm Rents, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Grant of Fee-farm Rents, Rent Service, Chantry Rents, &amp;c. to Trustees for Sale; except Quit Rents, Copyhold Rents, Tenths, First Fruits, &amp;c.; and except Rents incident to Reversions in the Crown, &amp;c.; Letters Patents granted by the King of certain Rents before the 24th June 1672, (Exception) confirmed.; The said Letters Patent to be expounded most beneficially for the Patentees.; Proviso for Misnamings, Misrecitals, &amp;c.; and for any other Defe&bholigct;.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas his Majestie is seised of severall Fee Farme Rents and other Rents in Right of his Crowne; some
whereof are Parcell of his Highnesse Dutchy of Cornwall, and is alsoe seised of severall Fee Farme Rents
and other Rents in Right of his [Highnesse<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Dutchy of Lancaster. And whereas it is convenient that some speciall
Priviledges and Advantages should be granted unto the Purchasers, which cannot well bee transferred unto them
without Authority of Parlyament. And whereas the better to enable his Majestie to pay such Debts oweing at
Interest, whereof his Majestie shall finde Reason to hasten the Discharge, his Majestie is minded to grant and convey
to certaine Persons and their Heires and Assignes for ever as Trustees for Sale thereof diverse Fee-Farme Rents,
Rents Service, Rents Secke, or Dry Rents, Chauntry Rents, Rents reserved, Guild Rents, Pensions, Vicontiel Rents;
Assart-Rents, Rents for Purprestures arented, Rents certaine or diverse other Rents of what Nature or Kinde soe
ever they be due and payable to his Majestie his Heires and Successors as his Majestie shall thinke fitt to
mention and expresse in the said Letters Patents, whether the same be due to his Majestie in Right of his Crowne
of England, or in Right of his Dutchy of Lancaster, or be Parcell of, or annexed unto the Dutchy of Cornwall,
except &amp; alwayes reserved and foreprized out of such Letters Patents all Quitt Rents and Copyhold Rents standing
in Charge as Parcell of, or belonging to any Mannour or reputed Mannour, and alsoe all Tenthes and First-Fruites
and Rents reserved nomine Decime due and payable by any Archbishop, Bishop, Deane, Deane and Chapter,
Archdeacon, Prebendary, Parson, Vicar, or any other Spirituall or Ecclesiasticall Corporation. And alsoe all Rents
reserved upon any Leases or Estates whereof the Reversion is now in his Majestie, and which are incident to such
Reversion, and alsoe all Rents reserved upon any Lease or Farme made or granted, or to be made or granted of
his Majestyes Customes or Excise. And alsoe except all Rents or Summes of Money due and payable to his
Majestie his Heires and Successors for or in respe&bholigct; of any Fire-Hearthes or Stoves. Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the
Kings most excellent Majestie with the Advice and Assent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons
in this present Parlyament assembled and by authoritie of the same That all and every Letters Patents to be granted
by his Majestie before the fower and twentyeth Day of June in the Yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred
seaventy two under his Great Seale, or under the Seale of his Dutchy of Lancaster, or under the Seale of the
County Palatine of Lancaster of all or any of the Rents aforesaid (except before excepted) shall be and are hereby
declared and ena&bholigct;ed to be good, sufficient and effe&bholigct;uall in the Law for the granting and assureing the severall
Rents aforesaid or any of them (except before excepted) and for vesting the same in such Persons and their
Heires as shall be therein nominated as Trustees for the Sale thereof against his Majestie his Heires and Successors,
and against the Dukes of Cornwall for the Time being, and against all Person and Persons that shall have or
inherite or enjoy the Dukedome of Cornwall by Force of any A&bholigct; of Parlyament or other Limitation whatsoever
according to the Tenour and Effe&bholigct; of the said Letters Patents, and the same shall be expounded, construed,
deemed and adjudged most beneficially for the Patentees and Grantees of the same: and their Heires, Successors,
Executors Administrators and Assignes according [to<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] the Words and Purporte of the said Letters Patents without
any Confirmation, Licence or Toleration of his Majestie his Heires or Successors any misnameing misrecitall or
non recitall of any the Honours, Mannours, Castles, Lands, Tenements or Hereditaments subje&bholigct; and lyeable to,
or charged with the Payment of such Rents, or any Mis-recitall or Non-recitall of any Estate taile formerly
made, or of the Reversion thereupon expe&bholigct;ant, or any misnameing or not true nameing of the Townes, Hamblets,
Parishes or Countyes where the same Honours, Mannours, Lands, Tenements or Hereditaments charged or
chargeable with the said Rents doe lye, or any lacke of the true nameing of the Corporation, or any lacke of
Attornment, or any misnameing or not nameing of any of the Tenants or Farmers of the Lands charged or
chargeable with such Rents or any Part thereof to the contrary notwithstanding. And notwithstanding any other
Defe&bholigct; or Imperfe&bholigct;ion which shall happen therein of what Nature or Kinde soever it shall be. And the said
Rents soe to be granted shall be afterwards conveyed and disposed by the said Patentees and Trustees according
to the Dire&bholigct;ions and Instru&bholigct;ions herein after mentioned.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Patentees and Trustees may sell the same Rents to any Purchaser by Indenture of Bargain and Sale enrolled.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Such Rents how to be described and conveyed in Deeds.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the said Patentees and Trustees and the Survivours
and Survivour of them shall make and execute to all and every Person and Persons Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate
their Heires Successors and Assignes who shall become Purchaser or Purchasers of the said Rents or of any Part
thereof an Indenture [or Indentures<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] of Bargaine and Sale which shall be inrolled in any of the Fower Courts at
Westminster within six Monethes after the Date thereof, and shall containe a Conveyance and Assurance of the
Rents soe purchased, and transferr the same by Words of Bargaine and Sale, or by Words of Grant, Release or
Confirmation, or by such other apt Words and Clauses as by the said Purchaser or Purchasers their Heires
Successors or Assignes shall be reasonably devised or required and shall be thought most suitable and convenient
to and for the severall Cases and Titles of such Purchaser or Purchasers respe&bholigct;ively, and such Conveyance or
Assurance shall alsoe recite the Consideration in Money paid or given, and thereof and of every Part and Parcell
thereof shall acquitt, exonerate and discharge the said Purchaser or Purchasers his and their Heires Executors
Successors and Assignes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Purchasers by virtue of such Deed peaceably to enjoy against all Claims as herein mentioned;</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all and every Person and Persons
Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate his and their Heires Successors and Assignes haveing and takeing any such Conveyance
and Assurance as aforesaid and causeing the same to be inrolled as aforesaid within the Space of six Moneths
next after the Date thereof shall be, and is hereby adjudged in a&bholigct;uall Seisin and Possession of the Rents soe
purchased and conveyed and shall hold and enjoy the same in perfe&bholigct; Peace freed and discharged of and from all
Claimes and Demands which can or may be made by his Majestie his Heires or Successors either in Right of his
Crowne, or any the Dutchyes aforesaid or otherwise howsoever, or by any Dukes of Cornwall for the Time
being, or by any Person or Persons that shall have, inherite or enjoy the Dukedome of Cornwall by force of any
A&bholigct; of Parlyament or other Limitation whatsoever, and alsoe freed and discharged of and from any Breach of
Trust, which can or may be pretended to be committed by the said Trustees in not stri&bholigct;ly pursueing the Powers
given by this A&bholigct; or the Instru&bholigct;ions herein after mentioned or any other Instru&bholigct;ions whatsoever, or the Orders to
them dire&bholigct;ed at the Time of the makeing and executeing such Conveyance, and shall alsoe holde and enjoy all
and every the Rents soe purchased as fully freely and amply as his Majestie at the Time of the passeing of this
A&bholigct; did or might have held or enjoyed the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. And to sue for and recover the same as His Majesty might have done.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Except by Prerogative Process.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every Person and Persons Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate who shall
purchase any of the said Rents and their and every of their Heires Successors and Assignes respe&bholigct;ively shall be
and are hereby enabled to have, sue for, and recover the same by such and the like lawfull Wayes and Meanes
as his Majestie or any of his Royall Progenitors could or might have recovered the same bee it by distraining in
all or any of the Lands of the Tenant or Tenants for the Time being that shall hold any Lands charged with
the said Rent, or by haveing Power to detaine or sell all such Distresses after the space of fifteene Dayes after
such Distresse taken in case the said Rent shall not be then or before paid returning the Overplus of what shall
be soe sould to the Partie destrained, or by haveing the full Benefit and Advantage of all Summes of Money reserved
nomine Pene, or as a Penaltie for Non-payment of the said Rent, or by useing the like. A&bholigct;ion or Suite as his
Majestie might have used for the Recovery of the same before such Patent granted, soe as the same extend not to
any such Processe of Extent, or other Prerogative Processe out of the Court of Exchequer as his Majestie might
have had before such Patent granted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Recital that divers Patents of Manors, &amp;c. have been granted upon Commissions of defe&bholigct;ive Titles, &amp;c. whereupon Rents have been reserved although nothing passed.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Fee-farm and other Rents not paid for Forty Years last past, not to be inserted in Patents to be hereafter made; ; and Tenant may hold the Land discharged in Cases herein mentioned.; If Letters Patent of Manors, Lands, &amp;c. heretofore granted, on which Rents so sold have been reserved, shall be cancelled, and so return to the Crown, the Purchasers may hold as against the Crown and others in manner herein mentioned.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">And forasmuch as upon diverse Commissions of defe&bholigct;ive Titles, Inquisitions or Suggestions of Concealments
diverse Patents have formerly passed the Greate Seale of England, or under the Seale of the Dutchy of Lancaster,
or under the Seale of the County Palatine of Lancaster of diverse Mannours Lands Tenements and Hereditaments
whereupon diverse Fee Farme Rents or other Rents have beene reserved, and sometimes putt in Charge where
in trueth noe thing hath passed by the said Letters Patents, nor have the Mannours Lands and Tenements Libertyes
or Hereditaments mentioned to have beene granted, beene enjoyed or held under the said Letters Patents but
under other Titles, or by vertue of other Letters Patents whereupon other Rents are reserved. Bee it therefore
ena&bholigct;ed That such Fee Farme Rents or other Rents which have not beene usually paid by the Owners or Occupiers
of the Mannours Lands or Tenements charged or mentioned to be charged therewith by the greater space of forty
Yeares now last past shall not be inserted or mentioned in any such Letters Patents to be hereafter granted to
Trustees as aforesaid. And further That where any Person or Persons Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate have held
any Mannours Lands Tenements or Hereditaments subje&bholigct; to the Payment of any Fee Farme Rent or other Rent
which hath beene usually paid or answered by the Owners or Occupiers of such Lands soe charged, and that by
Colour or Pretence of some Patent of Concealement, or by Pretence of Commissioners for defe&bholigct;ive Titles passed
of the same Lands some other or greater Rent hath beene reserved or putt in Charge, but the same hath not beene
usually answered or paid by the Owners or Occupiers of the said Lands by the greater Space of forty Yeares
before mentioned That then and in such Case the Tennant of the Lands shall hold the same discharged of the
said Rent soe reserved by vertue of the said Patent of Concealement or by Commission of defe&bholigct;ive Titles, and
alsoe discharged of all Seisures and Distresses for the same untill the same shall have beene recovered by due
Course and Proceedings of Law; And if any Letters Patents of any Mannours, Lands, Tenements or Hereditaments
have beene heretofore granted whereupon any Fee Farme Rents or other Rents have beene reserved which at any
time after the passing of this A&bholigct; shall be sould to any Purchaser or Purchasers, if such Letters Patents wherupon
such Rents soe sould have beene reserved shall at any time hereafter be adnulled, defeated, repealed, cancelled,
avoided or otherwise determined whereby the Lands shall returne to his Majesty his Heires or Successors, then
and in every such Case all and every the Purchaser and Purchasers of such Rents their Heires Successors and
Assignes shall have and receive out of the same Lands, Tenements and Hereditaments the like Rent, and for the
like Estate therein with that which was by them soe purchased and shall enjoy such like Rent dureing such
Estate against his Majestie his Heires and Successors, and against all Persons Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate
claimeing by from or under his Majestie his Heires and Successors by any Grant or Conveyance made or granted
by his Majestie his Heires or Successors subsequent to such Purchase made and shall have like Remedy for recovery
thereof (any such adnulling, defeateing, repeale, cancelling, Avoidance or other Determination of such Letters
Patents to the contrary notwithstanding)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Recital that divers Fee-farmers before the 23d O&bholigct;. 1642, and since the 29<emph type="p">th</emph> May 1660, have been discharged, their Discharges confirmed.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for the Queen and others.; Exception of Dukes of Cornwall.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p11">And whereas by certaine Covenants or Agreements on the Kings Part contained in the originall Reservation of
some of the said Fee Farme Rents or by the true Intent thereof, or by some Decrees in the Court of Augmentation
or Exchequer made before the three and twentyeth Day of O&bholigct;ober in the Yeare of our Lord one thousand six
hundred forty and two, or since the nine and twentyeth Day of May in the Yeare of our Lord one thousand
six hundred and sixty diverse Fee-Farmers were to be discharged, and Allowances to be made of diverse Pensions,
Portions, Rents Resolute or other Things of the like Nature, and the Charge thereof hath beene since allowed by
his Majestie out of the said Fee Farme Rents upon the Accompts of Bayliffes Ministers and Receivers; it is hereby
provided and declared That this A&bholigct; or any Thing herein contained shall not be construed to annull or avoid any
such Covenants or Decrees, but that the same shall be allowed against the said Purchaser or Purchasers as it
should have beene against his Majestie his Heires and Successors if the Letters Patents or Grants of such Fee
Farme Rents hereby intended to be confirmed had not beene made; Saveing unto the Queenes Majestie and to
all and every other Person and Persons Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate their Heires and Successors and every of
them (other then the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors, and other then the Dukes of Cornwall for the
Time being, and other then such Person as shall have, inherite or enjoy the said Dukedome of Cornwall by
force of any A&bholigct; of Parlyament or other Limitation whatsoever) all such Right, Title and Interest, Possession,
Leases or Estates as they or any of them had or should or might have, or of right ought to have had in or
to the said Rents or any of them, or any of the Lands charged or chargeable with them or any of them as fully
and amply as they should or might have had before the Letters Patents thereof made as if this A&bholigct; had never
beene had or made; Any Thing herein before contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Bodies Corporate may bay and enjoy Rents notwithstanding the Statutes of Mortmain.</head>
			<para id="p12">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate
to purchase any the Fee Farme Rents or other Rents soe to be conveyed as aforesaid, and the same Rents soe
purchased to retaine and keepe to them and their Successors; Any Statutes of Mortmaine to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for certain Rents arising in the Principality of Wales.</head>
			<para id="p13">(<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) Provided alwayes That neither this A&bholigct; nor any Thing therein contained, shall extend or be construed to extend
to the Sale of any the Fee Farme Rents, Tenths Chauntry Rents, Rents Secke or any dry or other Rents
whatsoever due or payable to his Majestie, or the Prince of Wales for the time being, issueing or ariseing within
the Principality &amp; Dominion of Wales; This A&bholigct; or any Thing therein contained to the contrary in any
wise notwithstanding.</para>
			<para id="p14">Instru&bholigct;ions ena&bholigct;ed to be observed in the Sale of Fee-Farme Rents; yet soe as the Breach or Non pursuance of
these Instru&bholigct;ions shall not invalidate or weaken the Title of any Purchaser.</para>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">Contra&bholigct;s to be signed by Treasurer.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p16">1. All Contra&bholigct;s touching the Sale of any Fee Farme Rents or other Rents before mentioned shall be signed
by the Lord Treasurer or Lords Commissioners of the Treasury for the Time being or any two of them.</para>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">Trustees to convey.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p18">2. The Trustees shall convey to such Persons as by Order from the Lord Treasurer or Lords Commissioners
of the Treasury or any two of them they shall be dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Purchase Money how to be paid.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p20">3. Every Contra&bholigct;or shall at or before the Time of the sealeing of his Conveyance pay downe one Moyty at
least of his Purchase; Money into the Exchequer, and shall alsoe before he shall receive his Deed of Conveyance
give Security such as the Lord Treasurer or Lords Commissioners of the Treasury shall approve for the Payment
of the second Moyty at the time appointed.</para>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Allowance on prompt Payment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p22">4. Such Contra&bholigct;ors as will pay downe their whole Purchase Money shall receive such Allowance for their
present Payment of their second Moyty as shall be thought fitt, soe as the same exceede not the Rate of ten
per Cent.</para>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">Tenants contra&bholigct;ing within Six Months to be preferred in point of Purchase.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p24">5. The immediate Tennant lyable to the Payment of any Rent shall be preferred in the Purchase of it before
any other, soe as such immediate Tennant tender himselfe to the Lord Treasurer or Lords Commissioner of the
Treasury to contra&bholigct; within six Moneths after the passing of the said Patent and Notice thereof published by his
Majestyes Proclamation, and perfe&bholigct; his Contra&bholigct;, and pay or secure his Money, as aforesaid, within six Moneths
after, at such Rate as shall be agreed not exceeding twenty Yeares Purchase.</para>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Proviso.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p26">6. If the immediate Tennant or some on his Behalfe doe not tender and perfe&bholigct; his Contra&bholigct; as in the last
precedent Article, all Benefit of Preference, or Preemption is to be lost.</para>
			<para id="p27">
				<emph type="i">Conveyance to whom made.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p28">7. The Purchaser may have his Conveyance in the Names of any Person or Persons he shall desire.</para>
			<para id="p29">
				<emph type="i">Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Incumbrances.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p30">8. If any Fee Farme Rent or other Rent be subje&bholigct; to, or charged with any Payment or other Incumbrance,
Consideration shall be had of it at the Time of the Contra&bholigct;, and a Reprize allowed for it accordingly, and where
such Reprize is allowed, the Purchaser is to convenant to take upon him such Incumbrance soe reprized.</para>
			<para id="p31">
				<emph type="i">Trustees to hold for the Crown until Sale.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p32">9. The Trustees are to hold the Rents conveyed to them for the Benefit of his Majestie his Heires and Successors
until Sale.</para>
			<para id="p33">
				<emph type="i">Trustees to convenant against Incumbrances by them.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p34">10. The Trustees in all Conveyances to be made by them shall covenant with the Purchasers in usuall For Forme
to free the Premisses and save the Purchaser harmelesse from any A&bholigct; done or suffered by them, which may
any way incumber the Premisses.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Proviso for Fee-farmers of Mills formerly belonging to the Crown.</head>
			<para id="p35">[Provided alwayes, and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Fee-farmers of any Mills
formerly belonging to the Crowne, or Parcell of his Majestie Dutchy of Lancaster shall have the Prote&bholigct;ion and
Privilledge of his Majestyes Courts of Exchequer and Dutchy of Lancaster and all Suites to Mill and Aides of the
said Courts, and enjoy all other former Priviledges and Advantages notwithstanding the Sale of the said Fee-farme
Rents issueing out of the said Mills to all Intents and Purposes, and in as. large and beneficiall manner as when
the said Fee-farme Rents or any of them were payable to his Majestie his Heires and Successors.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. All Sums of Money, Rents, &amp;c. to be allowed to maintain a School, &amp;c. to remain as heretofore.</head>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">Trustees may convey to such Persons as they think fit for the Performance of such charitable Uses.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p37">[Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That such and soe much of the said Fee Farme
Rents and Premisses and such Summes of Money, Rents resolute, Pensions, Stipends, Sallaryes, Annuityes, Almes,
Corodyes, Proffitts and Allowances as are due and payable, or which are chargeable upon have beene or ought to
be paid or allowed to or for the Maintenance of any Grammar Schoole or Schollars, or for or towards the
Reparation of any Church, Chappell, Highway, Cawsey Bridges, Schooles, Almeshouses, Castles or any other Uses,
upon, out of, or for the Premisses or any of them to be setled upon Trustees according to this A&bholigct; as aforesaid
shall be and continue to be paid and allowed as they were and have beene heretofore. And the said Trustees
are hereby authorized and required to sett out, convey and assure [to<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] such Person and Persons and their Heires,
Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate and their Successors and Assignes as they the said Trustees shall thinke fitt in
Trust for the Performance of the Uses aforesaid or any of them, such of the said Fee Farme Rents Dutyes or
Summes of Money payable as aforesaid, as shall amount to any of the Summes soe charged, limitted or allowed to,
or for the Uses or Purposes aforesaid. Any Thing in this A&bholigct; or Instru&bholigct;ions, to the contrary notwithstanding.
And after such Conveyance the Purchasers of the Residue of the said Fee-farme Rents shall be discharged of the
said Dutyes and Payments.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">unto <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


