<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47415" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act to enable the Kings Majestie to make Leases, Grants and Copyes of Offices, Lands Tenements and
Hereditaments Parcell of his Highnesse Dutchy of Cornwall, or annexed to the same. [Rot. Parl. 22 C. II. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">All Leases, Grants, &amp;c. of Land, &amp;c. in the Dutchy of Cornwall made within Three Years confirmed.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas many of the Lands belonging to the Dutchy of Cornwall have beene granted by Lease to the
Tennants some for the terme of one two or three Lives, and some for diverse yeares determinable upon
one two or three Lives and others for thirty one yeares or under; which Leases are desired to be renewed by
many of the said Tennants; And whereas of late yeares diverse increased Rents have beene reserved aswell upon
the said leased Lands as upon many Copyhold Estates of the said Dutchy for the Improvement of that Revenue,
whereof the Tennants have complained to the Kings Majestie who is gratiously pleased that they may compound
with his Officers for the Discharge of the said increased Rents and be restored to be old Rents formerly paid
for their respe&bholigct;ive Tenements and Lands; Now to the end the same may be accordingly effe&bholigct;ed, and the said
Tennants may be encouraged to renew their Leases and Estates, and thereby the better enabled to repaire their
Houses and provide for their Families and to improve their Lands holden of the said Dutchy. Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by
the King's most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by authoritie of the same That all Grants made or to be
made by Copy of Court Roll according to the custome of the respe&bholigct;ive Mannour or Mannours of the said Dutchy,
or thereunto annexed or belonging, and all Leases and Grants made or to be made within three yeares next
ensueing by our said Soveraigne Lord the King by Letters Patents or Indentures under the Great Seale of England,
or the Seale of the Court of Exchequer of any Offices, Parkes, Lands Tenements or Hereditaments other then
Honours Lordshipps or Mannours parcells of the Possessions of, or annexed or belonging to the said Dutchy of
Cornwall, shall be good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law according to the purport &amp; [contents<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of the same Copyes Leases
and Grants against our said Soveraigne Lord the King his Heires and Successors, and against all and every other
person and persons that shall at any time hereafter have inherite or enjoy the said Dutchy by force of any A&bholigct;
of Parlyament, or by any other Limitation whatsoever.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. The Term for such Leases and Grants.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Rents to be reserved.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes That every such Lease or Grant soe made, or to be made [shall not be made<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] for more then
one, two or three Lives or for thirty one yeares or under, or for some terme of yeares determinable upon one,
two or three Lives and not above; And if such Leases or Grants be made in Reversion or expe&bholigct;ancy that then
the same together with the Estates in possession doe not exceede three Lives or the terme of Thirty one yeares
and not in any wise dispunishable of Waste and soe as upon every such Lease shall be reserved the auntient or
most usuall Rent or more, or such Rent as hath beene reserved, yeilded or payd for the same Lands for the
greater part of Twenty yeares next before the yeare of Our Lord one thousand six hundred and sixtie and shall
be reserved due &amp; payable to him or her that shall have the Inheritance or other Estate of the said Dutchy;
And where, noe [such<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Rent hath beene reserved or payable that then upon every such Lease there shall be reserved
a reasonable Rent not being under the twentyeth part of the cleare yearely value of the Parks, Lands, Tenements
or Hereditaments contained in such Lease, and all Leases and Grants otherwise made or to be made shall be null
and void.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Covenants, Conditions, and Reservations good as if the King had been seised at the making thereof.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">General Saving.; Except the King and the Dukes of Cornwall.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And bee it further ordained and ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That all Covenants, Conditions, Reservations,
and other Agreements contained in every Lease Grant or Copy of Court Roll made or to be made as aforesaid
shall be good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law according to the Words and Contents of the same as well for and against
them to whom the Reversion of the same Lands Tenements or Hereditaments shall come, as for and against them
to whom the Interest of the said Leases, Grants or Copies shall come respe&bholigct;ively as if our Soveraigne Lord the
Kings Majestie at the time of the makeing of such Covenants Conditions and Reservations and other Agreements
were seised of an absolute Estate in Fee simple in the same Lands Tenements or Hereditaments Saveing alwayes
to all and every person and persons Bodyes pollitique and corporate their Heires and Successors Executors
Administrators and Assignes other then to our said Soveraigne Lord the King and His Heires and the Duke and
Dukes of Cornwall for the time being and his and their Heires and all and every person and persons that shall
hereafter have inherite or enjoy the said Dukedome of Cornwall by force of any A&bholigct; of Parlyament or other
Limitation whatsoever All such Rights, Titles, Estates, Customes Interests Tenures Claimes and Demands whatsoever
of what nature, kinde or qualitie soever of, in, to, or out of the said Offices Lands Tenements or Hereditaments
or any of them as they or any of them had or ought to have had before the makeing of this A&bholigct; to all intents
and purposes and in as large and ample manner and forme as if this A&bholigct; had never beene had or made. This
A&bholigct; or any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Where Compositions for increased Rents;</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">upon such Composition paid and enrolled, increased Rent to cease.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That in case any of the Copyhold Tenants of the said
Dutchy shall at any time within Three yeares next ensueing compound or agree with the Lord High Treasurer
of England or the Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being, or with the Chauncellour &amp; Under Treasurer
of the Exchequer, or with any such person or persons as the Lord High Treasurer Commissioners of the Treasury
or Chauncellour and Under Treasurer of the Exchequer for the time being shall authorize, nominate and appointe
for the takeing of, and dischargeing of any increased Rent reserved as aforesaid according to such Rules and Dire&bholigct;ions
as in that behalfe shall be given in Writeing under the Hands of the said Lord Treasurer or Co&bhooov;mis?ioners of the
Treasury or Chauncellour and Under Treasurer of the Exchequer for the time being. Then upon such Composition
soe made and the money thereby ariseing duely paid to the Receiver Generall of the said Dutchy according to
the tenoure and contents of such Composition and Agreement, and accordingly inrolled before the Auditor of the
Premisses; And from thenceforth such increased Rents shall cease and become void, and the old Rent onely, or
such other Rent as in pursuance of this A&bholigct; shall be dire&bholigct;ed in or by such Composition &amp; Agreement shall be
charged upon all and every such Tenements Lands and other Hereditaments for which such Composition, Agreement,
Payment and Inrolment shall be soe made and none other; Any reservation, condition or other matter whatsoever
to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


