<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47421" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIII. An A&bholigct; for Improvement of Tillage and the Breede of Catle. [Rot. Parl. 22 C. II. nu. 13.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Corn and Grain may be exported at certain Times, although the Prices exceed the Rates of 15 Car. II. c. 7,</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i"> paying Duty as by 12 Car. II. c. 4</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">For the further Incouragement of Tillage for the common good and welfaire of this Kingdome Bee it ena&bholigct;ed
by the Kings most excellent Majesty by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall
and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by authoritie of the same That from and after the
twenty fourth day of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord, one thousand six hundred and seaventy and
from thence forward It shall be lawfull for all and every person or persons Native or Forreigne at any time or
times to shipp, lade carry and transport as Merchandize all sorts of Corne and Graine although the Prices thereof
shall exceede the Rates sett downe in one A&bholigct; of this present Parliament made in the fifteenth yeare of his
Majestyes Reigne entituled An A&bholigct; for the Encouragement of Trade, The said A&bholigct; or any other Law Statute
Usage or other Prohibition to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding, paying for the same such Rates
as are to be paid when the same might have beene transported by one A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament entituled
A Subsidie granted to the King of Tonnage and Poundage, and none other.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. When Corn does not exceed the Rates herein mentioned certain Duties as herein mentioned to be paid.</head>
			<para id="p3">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That when the Prices of Corne and Graine at the
times, Havens and places when and where the said Corne or Graine shall be imported into this Kingdome exceede
not the Rates hereafter following there shall be answered and paid for the Custome and Poundage thereof these
Rates That is to say</para>
			<para id="p4">For every Quarter of Wheate when the same shall not exceede the Price of Three and fifty shillings and
fower pence the Quarter there shall be paid for the Custome and Poundage thereof the summe of sixteene shillings,
And when the same shall exceede the summe of three and fifty shillings and fower pence the Quarter, and yet not
above fower pounds the Quarter, That then there shall be answered and paid for the Custome and Poundage of
every Quarter of Wheate the summe of eight shillings;</para>
			<para id="p5">For every Quarter of Rye when the same doth not exceede the price of forty shillings the Quarter there shall
be answered and paid for the Custome and Poundage thereof the summe of sixteene shillings the Quarter.</para>
			<para id="p6">For every Quarter, of Barley or Malt when the same doth not exceede the price of two and thirty shillings the
Quarter, there shall be answered and paid for the Custome and Poundage thereof the summe of sixteene shillings
the Quarter.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


