<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47425" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An Act for granting a Subsidy to his Majestie for Supply of his Extraordinary Occasions. [Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 1. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Rates hereby granted to be paid into the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Most gratious Soveraigne.<br/>
Wee your Majestyes most duty full and loyall Subje&bholigct;ts the Commons assembled in Parlyament haveing entred
into a due and serious consideration of the extraordinary Occasions which oblige your Majestie to a great
and present Expence for the necessary Defence of your Realmes, and considering your Majestyes great Debts and
being desireous to raise such Aydes and Supplyes as may be proportionable to these Occasions Doe humbly present
your Majestie with the free gift of the Rates Subsidies and Assesments here [in<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] after mentioned, which wee humbly
beseech your Majestie gratiously to accept of as a Testimony of the dutyfull affe&bholigct;tions of us your Subje&bholigct;ts, and
that your Majestie would be pleased that it may be ena&bholigct;ed, And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majestie the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the
authoritie of the same That our Soveraigne Lord the King his Heires and Successors shall have and receive the
Rates Subsidyes and Assesments hereafter mentioned, of and from every person Spirituall and Temporall of what
Estate or Degree soever he or they be of; which said Rates Subsidyes and Assesments shall be taxed, assessed,
leavyed and paid into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer according to the tenour of this A&bholigct; and in manner
and forme following, That is to say,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. 15s. forevery &pound;100 on Personal Estate to be paid by Bankers.</head>
			<para id="p3">Whereas severall persons being Goldsmiths and others by takeing or borrowing great summes of money, and
lending out the same againe for extraordinary lucre and proffitt have gained and acquired [unto <ref idref="n2">2</ref>] themselves the
Reputac&bhocotil;on and Name of Bankers. It is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every such persons haveing any
personall Estates in Debts oweing to them or to any others in trust for them within the Realme or without or
haveing any ready moneys shall yeild or pay unto his Majestie for every one hundred pounds of such debts or
ready moneys the summe of fifteene shillings, and soe after that rate for any greater summe then an hundred
pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Monies owing by His Majesty 1st May 1671 at above &pound; 6 per Cent, to pay 15s.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Auditor of Receipt and Imprest Accountants to make Certificates by whom such Money has been lent; to be delivered to Alderman of Ward of Cheap before 20th May, on Loss of Office; and by him within Six Days to Assessors, who are to return Assessment to Commissioners, who are to cause same to be levied</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further enacted That all moneys lent to his Majestie for which above six pounds per Cent shall
be oweing or payable by his Majestie upon the first day of May One thousand six hundred and seaventy one,
either as Interest Consideration Gratuity or otherwise shall pay per Cent fifteene shillings, And the Auditor of the
Receipt and the severall Imprest Accomptants for the time being are hereby required to deliver severall Certificates
of all such moneys and by whome they are severally lent (that is to say) the Auditor of the Receipt to certifie
the Names of all such persons to whome such Reward is then payable in the Exchequer, and the respe&bholigct;tive
Imprest Accomptants to certifie the Names of the respe&bholigct;tive persons of whome they have borrowed any summe
of money for which such gratuity or reward is then payable over and above the usuall Interest of six pounds
per Cen? per Ann?, and to deliver or cause to be delivered such their severall Certificates to the Alderman of
of the Ward of Cheape in the Citty of London before the twentyeth of May One thousand six hundred and
seaventy one on penalty of the losse of the respective Offices and Places which they respe&bholigct;tively holde for any
wilfull default herein, Which Alderman of the Ward is within six dayes after receipt of such Certificates to deliver
the same over to the Assessors appointed for the said Ward, or within six dayes after such Assessors shall be
appointed, which Assessors are accordingly to assesse the same and to returne to the respe&bholigct;ive C&bhooov;missioners the
assesment by them made of all such moneys, which said C&bhooov;missioners are hereby impowered and required to
cause all such assesments to be leavyed and paid to his Majestie by the power of this A&bholigct;, and in case of failer
of payment to leavy such Forfeitures as are due, and doe all other things to be done in the like case according
to the tenour or vertue of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Bankers may stop 10s. forevery &pound;100 upon Repayment to Creditors;</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">and to bear remaining 5s. themselves</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ted That in every case as aforesaid where fifteene shillings shall be paid for
one hundred pounds and after that rate for a greater summe, it shall be lawfull for every such Banker Goldsmith
or other person as aforesaid to make stopp or dedu&bholigct;t ten shillings and noe more of every such fifteene shillings
soe by him paid for moneys which he shall have soe borrowed or taken up, when he shall pay backe all such
moneyes soe by him borrowed or taken up, and it shall be allowed him upon account by all and every such
[his<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Creditor or Creditors their Executors Administrators or Assignes accordingly, and the remaineing five shillings
shall be borne and paid by the said Banker, Goldsmith and other person as aforesaid and upon their owne
accompt onely.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing Bankers paying more than once 15s. on every &pound;100.</head>
			<para id="p8">Provided alwayes That noe such Banker, Goldsmith or other person as aforesaid shall by vertue of this A&bholigct;
pay to his Majesty more then fifteene shillings for one and the same Hundred pound Any thing in this A&bholigct; to
the contrary notwithstanding. But if it shall happen that any of them shall be twice assessed for the same
money, then the Certificate under the respe&bholigct;tive Colle&bholigct;tor and two C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers Hands of the due payment thereof
in one place shall for soe much discharge every of them in all other places.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Money lent to His Majesty upon the Credit of this A&bholigct; to have Interest at 7 per Cent.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">No Money so lent to be assessed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">Provided allwayes and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ted That it shall and may be lawfull to and for any person and
persons to advance and lend unto his Majestie upon the security of this A&bholigct;t any summe or summes of money,
and to have and receive for the forbearance thereof after the rate of seaven pounds per Cen? for one whole
yeare, Any other Law or Statute to the contrary notwithstanding, and noe more dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;tly either for
Interest, Gratuity or Reward. And moreover that noe money soe lent upon the Security of this A&bholigct;t, or upon
the Security of any other A&bholigct;t of Parlyament passed or to be passed dureing this present Session of Parlyament
att the rate of seaven pounds per Cent. shall be rated or assessed by vertue of this A&bholigct;t Any thing herein contained
to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Personal Estates not otherwise charged to pay Six Shillings per Cent.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Exception</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the authoritie aforesaid That all and every person and persons Bodyes Pollitique
and Corporate, Guilds or Fraternityes within this Kingdome of England, Dominion of Wales, or Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede haveing any personall Estate in Goods, Wares, Merchandizes Stocke, or other Chattells personall
whatsoever not otherwise charged by this A&bholigct; either in their owne possession or in the possession of others in
trust for them, except and out of the Premisses dedu&bholigct;ted such summes of money as he and they doe owe, and
in his or their Conscience intend truely to pay, the Stocke upon Land or the Produ&bholigct;t thereof in the Hands of
the Occupyer or first Owner, and such Goods as are used for Household stuffe, Money and Debts excepted shall
yeild and pay unto his Majestie for every Hundred pounds worth of such Goods, Wares Merchandizes Stocke or
other Chattells personall the Summe of six shillings and soe after that rate for every greater quantity of such
Goods and Chattells to be assessed leavyed and colle&bholigct;ed in manner herein after mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Public Officers to pay 2s. in the Pound.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Dedu&bholigct;ting the Third Part for Charges</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the authoritie aforesaid That all and every person and persons C&bhooov;mis?er and
C&bhooov;mis?ers haveing useing or exerciseing any Office or Place of publi? imployment whatsoever (such persons who
are or shall be in Muster or Pay at Land or Sea onely excepted) and all and every their Deputyes, Agents,
Clerkes Secondaries Substitutes and other their inferiour Ministers and Servants whatsoever shall yeild and pay
unto his Majestie the summe of Two shillings for every Twenty shillings which he or they doe receive in one
yeare by vertue of any Fees, Proffitts, Perquisits, or other advantages to him or them accrueing, or by reason or
occasion of their severall Offices, Agencies or Imployments, the third part being dedu&bholigct;ted for the Charges for
the manageing of the said Offices to be assessed imposed, leavyed and colle&bholigct;ted in such manner, as is herein after
mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Lands, Mines, &amp;c. to pay 12d. in the Pound of the yearly Value for one Year;</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">to be rated as now worth, if let at a Rack Rent, and without respe&bholigct; to present Rents or former Taxes.; The said Assessments to be paid in Four Quarterly Payments; the First to be made 24th June 1671</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And to the end a further Ayde and Supply of his Majestyes Occasions may be raised and leavyed by a Charge
upon all Lands and Tenements and that the same may be laid with asmuch equality and indifferency as is possible,
and by a Pound Rate of Twelve pence for every Twenty Shillings of the cleare yearely Value (for one yeare onely
and noe longer) and soe upwards : Therefore it is further ena&bholigct;ted by the authority aforesaid That all and every
the Messuages, Mannours Lands and Tenements aswell Freehold as Copyhold, all and every the Mines of Coale
Tynne or Leade, all Allom-mines or Workes, all Parkes, Chases, Warrens, Woods, Underwoods and Coppices,
Fishings, Tythes, Tolls and all other yearely Proffitts and Hereditaments of what nature or kinde soever they be,
scituate, lyeing and being within the Kingdome of England, Dominion of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede
or within any the Countyes, Cittyes Burroughes Townes Divisions Hundreds Rideings Lathes Wapentakes Parishes
and places thereof aswell within auntient Demesne and other Liberties and priviledged places as without shall be,
and are hereby charged for one yeare onely and noe longer with the Summe of Twelve pence for every Twenty
Shillings of the cleare yearely Value and soe upwards, And all and every person and persons Bodyes Pollit?
and Corporate Guilds Misteryes Fraternityes and Brotherhoods whether Corporate or not Corporate haveing or
holding any Messuages [Mannors<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Lands Tenements Hereditaments or any other the Premisses shall yeild and pay
unto his Majestie the Summe of Twelve Pence for every Twenty Shillings by the yeare, which the said Messuages
Mannours Lands Tenements and Hereditaments and other the Premisses are now worth to be leased, if the same
were truely and bona fide leased or demised at a Racke Rent and according to the full true reall and cleare
yearely Value thereof without any respe&bholigct;t had to the present Rents therefore reserved if the same have beene reserved
upon such Leases or Estates made for which any Fyne or Income hath beene paid or secured, and without any
respe&bholigct; had to any former Rates or Taxes thereupon imposed, Which said Summe of Twelve Pence for every
Twenty Shillings by the yeare of the said full and cleare yearely Value of the Premisses shall be assessed leavyed
and colle&bholigct;ted in manner hereafter mentioned, and shall be paid into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer by fower
equall and successively Quarterly Payments, The first Payment thereof to beginne and to be made upon the Twenty
fourth day of June which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy one.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Recital that divers of the Lands, &amp;c. charged are incumbered with Rent Charges, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p17">
				<emph type="i">The Proprietor of any Land so incumbered may dedu&bholigct; 12d. in the Pound out of every Fee-farm Rent or other annual Rent.; Persons indebted upon Contra&bholigct; for Interest may dedu&bholigct; 12d. in the Pound out of Interest growing due, from 25th March 1671 to 25th March 1672.; Persons entitled to such Rents, &amp;c. to allow such Deduction.; Indemnity to Tenants</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p18">And whereas many of the Messuages Mannours Lands Tenements Tythes Hereditaments or Premisses intended
by this A&bholigct;t to be charged with the Pound Rate as aforesaid stand incumbred with, or are subje&bholigct;t and lyeable to
the Payment of severall Rent Charges or Annuityes issueing out of the same, or to the payment of diverse Fee
farme Rents, Rents Services or other Rents thereupon reserved, by reason whereof the true Owners and Proprietors
of such Messuages Mannours Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses doe not in trueth receive to their owne
use the full yearely value of the same, For which neverthelesse they are by this A&bholigct;t charged to pay the full
Pound-rate of twelve pence for every twenty shillings of the true yearely value, It is therefore declared and ena&bholigct;ted
by the authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull [to and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] for the Landlords Owners and Proprietors
of such Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses as are charged with the Pound Rate as aforesaid
to abate and dedu&bholigct; and to retaine and keepe in his and their Hands Twelve pence in the pound out of every
Fee farme Rent and other annuall Rent and Payment charged upon, or issueing out of the Premisses or any part
thereof or thereupon reserved, And all and every person or persons Bodyes Pollitique or Corporate being indebted
in any Summe or Summes of Money upon Contra&bholigct; for Interest shall for the better enableing them to pay and
beare the Subsidyes and Charges herein before respe&bholigct;tively imposed upon them bee allowed by vertue of this A&bholigct;t
after the rate of Twelve pence in the pound out of all such Interest money which shall be paid and grow due for
any time betweene the five and twentyeth day of March One thousand six hundred seaventy and one, and the five
and twentyeth day of March One thousand six hundred seaventy and two by his or their respe&bholigct;tive Creditor or
Creditors out of the Debts soe by them oweing as aforesaid and may and are hereby enabled to dedu&bholigct;t retaine and
discount the same Any Contra&bholigct;t or Agreement Mortgage Bond Condition Provision or other Assurance to the
contrary in any wise notwithstanding. And all and every person and persons who are or shall be any way entituled
to such Rents and Annuall Payments are hereby required to allow such Dedu&bholigct;ions and Payments upon the Receipt
of the residue of such Moneyes as shall be due and payable [unto<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] them as aforesaid And all Tennants are hereby
saved harmelesse from [any further payment of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] the Twelve pence in the pound soe dedu&bholigct;ted, as fully and amply
as if the same had beene paid into his Majestyes Exchequer or to such Creditor or other person to whome the
same would otherwise have become due and payable.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. His Majesty to appoint Commissioners by Commissions under the Great Seal.</head>
			<para id="p19">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to meet in the several Counties, &amp;c. at or before the 10th May 1671; and may subdivide themselves.; Commissioners to direct Precepts to Inhabitants, &amp;c. requiring them to appear, then to read the Rates, and charge them how to make Certificates, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p20">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the Authority aforesaid That for the better assessing, ordering, leavying and
colle&bholigct;ting of the severall Summes of Money soe as aforesaid limitted and appointed to be paid, and for the more
effe&bholigct;tuall putting of this present A&bholigct;t in Execution it shall and may be lawfull for his Majestie to issue out or
cause to be issued out under the Great Seale of England such and soe many Commissions as his Majestie shall
thinke fitt, and therein, and thereby to nominate constitute and appointe such and soe many persons to be
Commissioners for putting this present A&bholigct;t in Execution, and alsoe soe many of them to be a Quorum as his
Majestie shall thinke convenient for the Service of this A&bholigct;t, Which said Co&bhooov;mis?ers soe as aforesaid to be
nominated and appointed shall in their respe&bholigct;tive Countyes, Cittyes, Burroughes, Divisions Townes and Places in
their respe&bholigct;tive Commissions mentioned meete together at the most usuall or common place of Meeting within each
of the said Countyes, Cityes, Burroughs Divisions Townes and Places respe&bholigct;tively at or before the tenth day of
May which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and one or such other day as
his Majestie by his Commission shall appointe, And the said C&bhooov;mis?ers or soe many of them as shall be present
at the first generall Meeting or the major part of them may by their Consents and Agreements divide aswell
themselves as other the C&bhooov;mis?ers not then present for the Execution of this A&bholigct; in Hundreds Lathes Wapentakes
Rapes Wards Townes and other places within their Limitts priviledged or not priviledged in such manner and
forme as to them shall seeme expedient; And shall dire&bholigct; their severall or joynt Precept or Precepts to such
Inhabitants, High-Constables Petty-Constables Bayliffes and other like Officers and Ministers and such number of
them as they in their Discretions shall thinke most convenient requireing them to appeare before the said Com&bhooov;is[sion]ers at
such time and place as they shall appoint not exceeding ten dayes And at such their Appearances the said C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers
shall openly reade or cause to be reade unto them the Rates and Assesments in this A&bholigct;t mentioned, and alsoe
openly declare the Effe&bholigct;t of their Charge unto them, and how and in what manner they ought and should make
their Certificates and how they ought to proceede in the Execution of this A&bholigct;t according to the Rates
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Persons to whom Precept dire&bholigct;ed absenting or refusing;</head>
			<para id="p21">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p22">And if any High Constable Petty Constable Bayliffe or other Officer or Minister to whom any Precept shall be
dire&bholigct;ed shall absent themselves without lawfull Excuse, to be witnessed by the Oathes of two credible Witnesses,
Or if any person appeareing shall refuse to serve, Then every such person soe makeing Defaulte or refuseing to
serve shall for every time of such Defaulte or Refusall forfeite and loose unto the Kings Majestie such Summe
as the Com&bhooov;is?ers shall thinke fitt, not exceeding the Summe of forty shillings.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. At or after such General Meeting Commissioners to direct Warrants for Assessors;</head>
			<para id="p23">
				<emph type="i">and to prefix a Day and Place to bring in Certificates of Names of Persons, and of Personal Estate, Offices, &amp;c. Assessors to inform themselves by all lawful Ways of the full yearly Value of Manors, &amp;c. and other Hereditaments; and then to assess 12d. per Pound of full yearly Value; and to bring at time prefixed a Certificate of Assessment, and to return Colle&bholigct;ors, for whose Payment to the Head Colle&bholigct;ors Parish to be answerable</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p24">And after such generall Meeteing had and Charge given as aforesaid, the said Com&bhooov;is?ers shall take care that
Warrants be issued forth and dire&bholigct;ted to two at the least of the most able and sufficient Inhabitants of each
Parish Towneship or Place within their respe&bholigct;ive Divisions thereby appointing and requireing them to be Assessors
of all and every the Rates and Dutyes by this A&bholigct;t imposed, and shall therein alsoe [appoint and<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] prefix a certaine
day and place for the said Assessors to appeare before them and to bring in their Certificates in Writeing of the
Names and Surnames of every person dwelling and resideing within the Limitts of those places with which
they shall be charged, and of the Substances and Values of every of them, or in Goods or Chattells (Stocke
upon Land, or the Produ&bholigct; thereof in the Hands of the Occupier or first Owner and Householdstuffe excepted)
or in Offices or publique places and imployments; And the said Assessors are therein alsoe to be required, and
are hereby enjoyned to ascertaine and informe themselves by all lawfull wayes and meanes they can of the
true and full Rate and Valuation of the cleare yearely Rents and Proffitts of all Messuages Mannours Lands
Tenements Mines of Coale Tynn or Leade, all Allom mines or Workes Parks Chases Warrens Woods Under-woods
and Coppices Fishings Tythes Tolls or other Hereditaments of what nature or kinde soever scituate lyeing and
being within the limitts of those places with which they shall be charged. And being soe thereof ascertained
they are to assesse all and every the said Messuages Mannours Lands Tenements and Premisses before charged
after the rate of twelve pence for every twenty shillings of the cleare yearely value as the same are lett for, or
are worth to be lett at the time of the assessing thereof as aforesaid and to bring with them at the time and
place soe as aforesaid prefixed for their appearance a Certificate in Writeing of the said Assesments, and shall then
alsoe returne the Names of two or more able and sufficient persons liveing within the Limitts and Bounds of
those Parishes Towneshipps Constebleries or places where they shall be chargeable respe&bholigct;ively to be Colle&bholigct;tors of
the Monyes due to his Majestie by this A&bholigct;t, for whose paying in to the Head Colle&bholigct;tors in manner hereafter
mentioned such Monyes as they shall be charged withall the Parish or place wherein they are soe imployed shall
be answerable.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Assessors negle&bholigct;ing or refusing to serve or making Default;</head>
			<para id="p25">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p26">And if any Assessor soe as aforesaid appointed or to be appointed shall negcle&bholigct; or refuse to serve, or shall
make Default at the time appointed for his Appearance not haveing a lawfull Excuse to be witnessed by the
Oathes of two credible Witnesses, every such Assessor shall for every such Negcle&bholigct; Refusall or Defaulte forfeite
and lose unto the Kings Majestie such summe as the C&bhooov;mis?ers shall thinke fitt not exceeding the Summe of
ten pounds.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Every Assessor before he a&bholigct;s to take the Oath following.</head>
			<para id="p27">And every Assessor soe as aforesaid appointed or to be appointed shall before he take upon him the Execution
of the said imployment take an Oath to be administred in these words following.</para>
			<para id="p28">You shall sweare well and truely to execute the Duty of an Assessor, and to cause the Rates and Dutyes
imposed by an A&bholigct;t entituled An A&bholigct;t for granting a Subsidy to his Majestie for Supply of his extraordinary
Occasions to be duely and impartially assessed according to the best of your Skill and Knowledge, and therein
you shall spare noe person for Favour or Affe&bholigct;ion, nor any person greive for Hatred or ill Will Soe helpe
you God.</para>
			<para id="p29">Which Oath any two C&bhooov;is?ers in the County where the said Assesment is to be made have hereby power to
administer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Certificates of Assessments upon Goods, &amp;c. returned to Commissioners before 27th May 1671, unless they give further Time.</head>
			<para id="p30">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the Rates and Assesments upon all Goods Chattels
Offices and publique Places and Employments charged by this A&bholigct; shall be ascertained and the Certificates thereof
returned to the C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers upon or before the seaven and twentyeth day of May aforesaid unlesse the C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers
shall thinke fitt to give further time.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. The like as to Assessments upon hand.</head>
			<para id="p31">And alsoe the Taxation and Assesment of the Pound rate of twelve pence in the pound for every twenty
shillings of the yearely value of all Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses charged by this A&bholigct;
shall be made and ascertained and the severall and respe&bholigct;tive Certificates thereof returned into the Com&bhooov;mis[sion]ers upon
or before the seaven and twentyeth day of May which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred seaventy and one unlesse the C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers shall thinke fitt to give further time.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Assessors to give one Copy of Assessments to Commissioners, who are to sign and seal Duplicates, one to be delivered to Sub-collectors, others to Head Colle&bholigct;ors and Receivers General.</head>
			<para id="p32">And the said Assessors are hereby required to deliver one Copy of their Certificates or Assesments fairely
written and subscribed by them unto the said C&bhooov;mis?ers by whom they were appointed, And the said C&bhooov;mis?ers
or any two or more of them are hereby ordered and required to cause the said severall and respe&bholigct;ive Assesments
soe to them delivered (if by them approved of) to be fairely written, and to signe and seale severall Duplicates
or Copies of the said Assesments, And one of them soe signed and sealed forthwith to deliver or cause to be
delivered unto the said Sub Colle&bholigct;ors, and shall likewise deliver or cause to be delivered other Copyes thereof
soe signed and sealed unto the Head Colle&bholigct;ors and Receivers Generall according to the severall and respe&bholigct;tive
Colle&bholigct;tions and Receipts.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Commissioners to cause Extra&bholigct;ts of Sums charged, &amp;c. to be certified into Exchequer under Hand and Seal before 23d June, or within 30 Days after Appeals being first determined.</head>
			<para id="p33">And moreover the C&bhooov;mis?ers shall cause a true Copy or Extra&bholigct; of the whole Summes assesed and charged
within every Hundred, Lath, Wapentake Parish Ward or Place rated or assessed in pursuance of this A&bholigct;t and of
the whole Summes rated or assessed upon personall Estates or Offices to be certifyed and transmitted into his
Majestyes Court of Exchequer under the Hands and Seales of any two or more of the C&bhooov;mis?ers but without
nameing the persons in such their Certificates, And this the said Com&bhooov;mis[sion]ers shall cause to be done upon or before
the three and twentyeth day of June then next ensueing or within thirty days after All Appeales to them made
being first determined.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Commissioners to issue Warrants to Sub-colle&bholigct;tors for levying, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p34">
				<emph type="i">Subcolle&bholigct;tors to levy and colle&bholigct;t according to their Duplicates, and to make Demand of Rates of Parties.; Head Colle&bholigct;tors to hasten Sub-colle&bholigct;tors.; In case of Negle&bholigct;t of Sub-colle&bholigct;tors, Levy by Distress.; Receiver General to hasten Head Colle&bholigct;tors, and to pay into Exchequer on or before the 24th of June, or within 30 Days after</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p35">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the authoritie aforesaid That the Co&bhooov;mis?ers or any two or more of them shall
issue out, and deliver their Warrants or Estreats to the Subcolle&bholigct;tors under their Hands and Seales thereby
requireing them to leavy and colle&bholigct;t all and every the Assesments and all Moneys and Rates due thereupon
according to the Duplicate thereof by them received, and according to the intent and subsequent Dire&bholigct;tions of this
present A&bholigct;t. Which said Sub Colle&bholigct;tors are hereby required to demand all and every the Rates and Assesments
therein mentioned, which are laid upon persons in respe&bholigct;t of their Goods or Offices, and to make such Demands
of the partyes themselves within six dayes after the Receipt of such Warrants and to leavy and pay in the same
upon or before the twelfth day of June [in the yeare of our Lord<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] One thousand six hundred seaventy and one
or within twenty dayes after at such place as the Co&bhooov;mis?ers shall appoint unto their respe&bholigct;tive Head Colle&bholigct;tors
who are hereby required to call upon and hasten their Sub Colle&bholigct;tors to the said payment, And after the
nineteenth day of June then next ensueing, or within twenty dayes after to leavy by Warrant under the Hands
and Seales of any two or more of the said Co&bhooov;mis?ers by Distresse upon the Sub Colle&bholigct;tors respe&bholigct;tively such
summe and summes of money as by him or them ought to have beene paid and is not paid by reason of his
failer in doeing his Duty according to the dire&bholigct;tions of this A&bholigct;t, soe as every Head Colle&bholigct;tor may or shall make
payment unto the Receivour Generall of the said County Citty or Place the full sum[m]es by him to be paid
on the three and twentyeth day of June aforesaid or within twenty dayes after, And the Receiver Generall is
likewise required to call upon and hasten the said Head Colle&bholigct;tors, and to pay what he shall soe receive from
the said Head Colle&bholigct;tor into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the fower and twentyeth day of
June aforesaid or within thirty dayes after to the end that all and every the Rates and Assesments which by
this A&bholigct;t are imposed upon any person or persons in respe&bholigct;t of his or their Goods and Chattells or Offices and
Imployments may be speedily brought into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer and there paid in upon or before
the Fower and twentyeth day of June aforesaid or within thirty dayes after at one entire Payment.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. Times of the First Payment.</head>
			<para id="p36">
				<emph type="i">Head Collector to hasten Sub-Colle&bholigct;tor.; Distress.; Head Colle&bholigct;tors to pay to Receiver General, who is to hasten Head Colle&bholigct;tor and pay into the Exchequer on or before the 24th of June</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p37">And the said Sub Colle&bholigct;tors are alsoe required and enjoyed to leavy one fourth part of the Pound rate
charged upon all Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses as aforesaid within six dayes after the
receipt of such Warrants and to pay the same unto their respe&bholigct;tive Head Colle&bholigct;tors on or before the twelfth
day of June aforesaid or within twenty dayes after And the said Head Colle&bholigct;tor is to hasten the said Sub
colle&bholigct;tors, And in case the same shall not be colle&bholigct;ted by reason of the negcle&bholigct;t of failer of Duty [in<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] the [said<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]
Sub colle&bholigct;tor, the said Head colle&bholigct;tor is to proceede against him by Distresse in like manner and by like Warrant
as aforesaid, And every Head colle&bholigct;tor is hereby required to make payment of what shall be soe leavyed or
received, unto the Receiver Generall of the said County Citty or Place upon or before the three and twentyeth
day of June aforesaid or within thirty dayes after, And the Receiver Generall is likewise required to call upon
and hasten the said Head colle&bholigct;tor and to pay what he shall soe receive from the said Head-colle&bholigct;tor into his
Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the twenty fowerth day of June aforesaid or within thirty dayes
after, to the end that the first quarterly payment of the said Pound rate of twelve pence in every twenty shillings
yearely may by that time be [fully<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] answered and paid [unto<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] his Majesty.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Times of the Second Payment.</head>
			<para id="p38">
				<emph type="i">Head Colle&bholigct;tors to pay to Receiver General, who is to pay into the Exchequer on or before the 29th of September</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p39">And the Sub colle&bholigct;tors shall alsoe leavy one other fourth part of the said Pound rate charged as aforesaid
upon or before the three and twentyeth day of August then next ensueing or within twenty dayes after, and
shall alsoe pay the same unto the said Head colle&bholigct;tors upon or before the thirtyeth day of August aforesaid or
within twenty dayes after And the said Head Colle&bholigct;tors shall make payment thereof to the Receiver Generall of the
said County Citty or Place upon or before the seaventh day of September then next ensueing or within twenty
dayes after, And the said Receiver Generall is alsoe required to make payment of all which he shall soe receive
into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the twenty ninth day of September aforesaid or within
twenty dayes after to the end that the second quarterly payment of the said Pound rate soe charged as aforesaid
may by that time be fully answered and paid into his Majestie</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Times of the Third Payment.</head>
			<para id="p40">
				<emph type="i">Head Colle&bholigct;tors to pay to Receiver General, who is to pay into the Exchequer on or before the 1st of January</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p41">And the said Sub colle&bholigct;tors shall alsoe leavy one other fourth part of the said Pound rate soe charged as
aforesaid upon or before the three and twentyeth day of November then next ensueing or within twenty dayes
after, and shall alsoe pay the same unto the said Head colle&bholigct;tors upon or before the seaventh day of December
then next ensueing or within twenty dayes after And the said Head [colle&bholigct;tor<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] shall make payment thereof to the
Receiver Generall upon or before the five and twentyeth day of December then next ensueing or within twenty
dayes after, And the said Receiver Generall is alsoe required to make payment of all that he shall soe receive
into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the first day of January then next ensueing or within
twenty dayes after to the end that the third quarterly payment of the said Pound rate soe charged as aforesaid
may by that time be fully answered and paid into his Majestie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Times of the Fourth Payment.</head>
			<para id="p42">
				<emph type="i">Head Colle&bholigct;tors to pay to Receiver General, who is to pay into the Exchequer on or before the 25th of March 1672</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p43">And the said Sub colle&bholigct;tors shall alsoe levy one other fowerth part of the said Pound rate soe charged as
aforesaid upon or before the three and twentyeth day of February then next ensueing or within twenty dayes
after and shall alsoe pay the same unto the said Head colle&bholigct;tors upon or before the seaventh day of March then
next ensueing or within twenty dayes after, And the said Head colle&bholigct;tors shall alsoe make payment thereof to
the Receiver Generall upon or before the foure and twentieth day of March then next ensueing or within twenty
dayes after, And the said Receiver Generall is alsoe required to make payment of all that he shall soe receive
into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the five and twentyeth day of March which shall be in
the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred seaventy two or within twenty dayes after to the end that the
fourth and last quarterly payment of the said Pound rate soe charged as aforesaid may by that time be fully
answered and paid into his Majestie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. All Persons concerned in the Execution of this A&bholigct;t to use Diligence, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p44">And all Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers Assessors Colle&bholigct;tors and Receivers are hereby required and enjoyed to apply themselves
with all diligence to the most speedy and effe&bholigct;tuall execution of their severall and respe&bholigct;tive Dutyes that soe his
Majestyes Service herein may not be delayed or hindred through any of their wilfull neg&bholigct;lect or default.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Head Colle&bholigct;or's Receipts a Discharge to Sub-colle&bholigct;or.</head>
			<para id="p45">
				<emph type="i">Sub-colle&bholigct;or to have 3d. in the Pound.; Head Colle&bholigct;or to pay, to and be appointed by Receiver General.; Sub-colle&bholigct;or travelling.; Receiver General's Acquittance a Discharge.; Allowance to Head Colle&bholigct;or.; Receiver General to pay into Exchequer; Allowance to him</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p46">And it is further ena&bholigct;ted and declared by the authoritie aforesaid That the moneys received, by the Sub
colle&bholigct;ors within the respe&bholigct;tive Divisions or Hundreds shall from time to time be duely paid a Head colle&bholigct;tor
whose Receipt shall be a sufficient discharge unto every such Sub colle&bholigct;tor, which Sub colle&bholigct;tor for gathering
the said perticular Siynmes shall retaine in his [hands<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] for every twenty shillings by him soe paid three pence as
a reward for his paines and service, And thes Head colle&bholigct;tor shall accordingly pay over the said Moneyes unto the
Receiver Generall of each County Citty or Place respe&bholigct;tively in manner aforesaid which Head colle&bholigct;tor or Colle&bholigct;tors
shall be nominated and appointed by the Receivers Generall of the respe&bholigct;tive Countyes, which said Receivers
Generall shall be answerable for all such Summes of money as shall be by him or them colle&bholigct;ted or received,
And that noe Sub colle&bholigct;tor shall be enforced to travell above the space of ten miles for the payment of the said
moneys that shall be by him colle&bholigct;ted or received, And the said Receivers Generall Acquittance shall be a
sufficient Discharge unto every such Head colle&bholigct;tor, who shall retaine in his Hands for every twenty shillings [so<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] by
him paid one penny as a reward for his paines and service, and the Receiver shall pay, the whole Su&bhooov;mes by
him received into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer in such manner and at or before such dayes and times
as are herein before limitted, and shall have an allowance of two pence in the pound for all moneys which, shall
be by him paid into the Receipt of Exchequer upon or before the time prefixed in this A&bholigct;t.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Commissioners Clerks to have 1d. in the Pound for writing Warrants, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p47">And for the carefull writeing and [ranscribeing<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] the said Warrants Estreats and Duplicates in due time It is
further enacted That the Co&bhooov;missioners Clerkes who shall respe&bholigct;tively performe the same shall by Warrant under two
or more of the Co&bhooov;mis?ers hands have and receive from the respe&bholigct;tive Head colle&bholigct;tors one penny in the pound
of all such moneys us he shall have received by vertue of such Warrants and Estreats who is hereby appointed
and allowed to pay the same accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Persons negle&bholigct;ting to pay Rates;</head>
			<para id="p48">
				<emph type="i">Colle&bholigct;ors to distrain.; The Distress to be kept Four Days, then to be appraised and sold, and Overplus restored</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p49">And if any person or persons shall negcle&bholigct;t or refuse to pay the severall Rates and Assesments wherewith he
is charged by this A&bholigct;t for or in respe&bholigct;t of his Goods and Chattells Offices or imployments and which he ought
to pay ; or if the Pound rate or any quarterly payment thereof soe as aforesaid charged upon any Messuages
Mannours Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses shall be negcle&bholigct;ed or refused to be paid then upon
demand made by the Officer or Colle&bholigct;tor of the Place according to the Precept or Estreats to him delivered by
the said Co&bhooov;missioners, It shall and may be lawfull to and for such Officer or Colle&bholigct;tor, and they are hereby required
for non payment thereof to destraine the person or persons soe refuseing or negcle&bholigct;ting to pay, by his or their
Goods or Chattells, or to destraine in and upon the Messuages Lands and Tenements soe charged, and the
Goods and Chattells then and there found and the distress soe taken to keepe by the space of fower dayes at
the costs and charges of the Owner thereof, And if the said Owner doe not pay the summe of money due by
this A&bholigct;t within the said; fower dayes, then the said Distresse to be apprized by two or three of the Inhabitants
where the said Distresse is taken, and there to be sold by the said Officer for the payment of the said money
and the overplus comeing by the said Sale (if any be) over and above the charges of takeing; and keepeing the,
Distresse to be immediately restored to the Owner thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Power to breakopen Houses, Chests, &amp;c. calling, to Assistance Constables, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p50">And moreover It shall be lawfull to breake open in the day time any House And upon; Warrant under the
Hands and Seales of any two or more of the said Co&bhooov;mis?ers any Chest, Trunke or Box or other things where
such Goods are, and call to their Assistance the Constables Tythingmen or Headburrbughs within the Countyes
Cittyes Townes or Places where any refusall negclect or resistance shall be made, Which said Officers are hereby
required to be aiding and assisting in the Premisses.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Parents and Guardians to pay Rates imposed on Infants, and upon Negle&bholigct;, &amp;c. to be proceeded against as other Defaulters.</head>
			<para id="p51">
				<emph type="i">Sums paid to be allowed upon their Accounts.; Tenants to pay Rates and dedu&bholigct;. out of Rent.; Landlord to allow such Dedu&bholigct;ions.; Tenant paying acquitted</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p52">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the authoritie aforesaid That where any person or persons chargeable with any
Rates or Assesments by this A&bholigct;t imposed shall be under the Age of one and twenty yeares There, and in every
such case the Parents, Guardians or Tutors of such Infants respe&bholigct;tively upon default of payment by such Infants
shall be and are hereby made lyeable to, and chargeable with the payments which such Infants ought to have
made, And if such Parents, Guardians or Tutors shall negcle&bholigct; or refuse to pay as aforesaid It shall and may
be lawfull to proceede against them in like manner as against other person or persons makeing default of payment
as herein before appointed, And all Parents Guardions or Tutors makeing payment as aforesaid shall be allowed
all and every the Summes soe paid for such Infants upon his and their Accompt, And the severall and respe&bholigct;ive
Tennants of all and every the Messuages Mannours Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses which by vertue
of this A&bholigct;t shall be charged with any Pound rate as aforesaid are hereby required and authorized to pay such
Summe or Summes of Money as shall be rated upon such Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments and Premisses,
and to dedu&bholigct;t out of the Rents soe much of the said Rates as in respe&bholigct;t of the said Rents payable for such
Messuages Lands Tenements Hereditaments or Premisses the Landlord should and ought to beare, And all Landlords
both mediate and immediate according to their respe&bholigct;tive Interests are hereby required to allow such Dedu&bholigct;tions
and Payments upon receipt of the residue of the Rents, and every Tennant paying the said Assesment of, the
Pound rate shall be and is hereby acquitted and discharged for soe much money as the said Assesment shall
amount unto, as if the same had beene a&bholigct;tually paid unto such person or persons, unto whome his Rent should
have beene due and payable.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Persons to berated for Offices at Places where executed; and for Personal Estates where resident.</head>
			<para id="p53">
				<emph type="i">Persons not being Householders to be rated where resident.; Persons out of the Realm to be rated where last resident within the Realm.; Persons to be rated for Lands, &amp;c. in Place where situate</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p54">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted That every person rated or assessed for his Office or imployment shall be rated
and pay for his said Office or imployment in the County Citty or Place where, such Office or imployment is
executed. And every person who is or shall be rated for or in respe&bholigct;t or any Personall Estate to him any way
belonging, shall be rated, and the Summe or Summes on him or her sett shall be leavyed at such places where
he or she with his or her Family shall be resident at the time of the Execution of this A&bholigct;t. And all persons
not being Householders nor haveing a certaine place of residence shall be taxed at the place where they are resident
at the time of the Execution of this A&bholigct;t. And if any person who ought to be taxed by vertue of this A&bholigct;t
shall at the time of his Assesment for or in respe&bholigct;t of his ready Moneys or Personall Estate be out of the Realme
such person shall be rated therefore in such County Citty of Place where he was last abideing within the Realme,
And every person who shall be rated [or<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] assessed for or in respe&bholigct; of any Messuages Mannours Lands Tenements
Hereditaments or other the Premisses according to the Pound rate of Twelve pence in every Twenty shillings yearely
as aforesaid shall be rated and assessesd in the place where such Messuages Mannours Lands Tenements Hereditaments
and Premisses respectively doe lye and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Persons in respect of several Places of Residence being doubly charged for Personal Estate, upon Certificate and Oath thereof, to be discharged for so much.</head>
			<para id="p55">Provided alwayes That if any person or persons haveing severall Mansion Houses or Places of Residence shall
be doubly charged by vertue of this A&bholigct; for or in respe&bholigct;t of his or their personall Estate That then upon
Certificate made by two or more of the C&bhooov;mis?ers for the County Citty or Place, which Certificate the said
C&bhooov;mis?ers are required to give without Delay Fee or Reward of His or their last personall Residence under their
Hands and Seales of the summe or summes charged upon him or them, and in what capacitie or respe&bholigct;t he or
they were soe charged, and upon Oath made of such Certificate before the C&bhooov;mis?ers to whom such Certificate
shall be tendred (which Oath the said C&bhooov;mis?ers are hereby authorized to administer) Then the person and
persons soe doubly charged shall for soe much as shall be soe certified, be discharged in every other County
Citty or Place.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Persons who by Fraud shall escape being taxed Doubly charged.</head>
			<para id="p56">And if any person that ought to be taxed by vertue of this A&bholigct; for or in respe&bholigct;t of his personall Estate shall
by changing his place of Residence or by any other Fraude or Covin escape from the Taxation and not be
taxed, and the same be proved before the C&bhooov;mis?ers or any two of them, or before any two Justices of Peace
of the County where such person dweleth or resideth at any time within Six Moneths next ensueing after such
Taxe made, every person that shall soe escape from the [said<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Taxation and Payment shall be charged upon proofe
thereof at the double value of soe much as he should or ought to have beene taxed at by this A&bholigct;t, The said
double, value upon Certificate thereof made into the Exchequer by the C&bhooov;mis[sion]ers or Justices before whom such
proofe shall be made to be leavyed of the Goods Lands and Tenements of such persons towards the Supply
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. Commissioners within their Division to rate each other for their. Personal Estates and Offices.</head>
			<para id="p57">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to assess the Assessors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p58">And bee it further enacted by the authority aforesaid That the C&bhooov;mis?ers which shall be within any County
Citty or Place within their respe&bholigct;ive Limitts or the major part of them shall rate taxe and assesse every other
C&bhooov;mis?er joyned with them for and in respe&bholigct; of the Goods Chattells and personall Estate whereof such C&bhooov;mis?er
shall be possessed, And alsoe for and in respe&bholigct;t of the Offices and publique Places and imployments which at
the time of such Taxation shall be held and enjoyed by such C&bhooov;mis?er soe as the Residence and usuall Dwelling
place of such C&bhooov;mis?er soe to be taxed, be within the Division of such C&bhooov;mis?ioners by whom he is taxed; and
soe as the Office or imployment held [and enjoyed<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] by such C&bhooov;misser soe to be taxed, be likewise to be exercised
within the Division or Limitts of such C&bhooov;mis?rs by whom he is to be taxed, And the C&bhooov;mis?ers within their
Division shall alsoe assesse every Assessor within their Division who shall be possessed of any Goods &amp; Chattells
or other personall Estate for which by this A&bholigct; he ought to be rated and assessed, And aswell all Summons
upon every the said C&bhooov;missers and Assessors as the Assesments made and sett by the Assessors aforesaid shall
be written, entreated; leavyed and gathered as it should and ought to have beene if the said C&bhooov;missers had not
beene named C&bhooov;missers.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. Rates on Peers to be received by a Colle&bholigct;or nominated by them.</head>
			<para id="p59">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That the severall Rates and Taxes to which the Lords and Peeres
of this Realme shall be lyable by vertue of this A&bholigct;t, for or in respect of their personall Estates and Offices
shall, be received by a Colle&bholigct;tor to be nominated by the Peeres, Which said Colle&bholigct;tor shall cause the same to
be paid into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer at Westminster upon or before the fewer and twentyeth day of
June now next ensueing or within thirty dayes after.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Proviso, as to Personal Estate, for Scotland, Ireland, Jersey, and Guernsey.</head>
			<para id="p60">Provided alsoe That this A&bholigct;t shall not extend to the Inhabitants of Scotland Ireland Jersey or Guernsey for
or concerning, any such personall Estate aforesaid which they or any to their use have within the Places
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. Persons aggrieved may complain to Commissioners, who may examine on Oath; and may abate or increase Assessment</head>
			<para id="p61">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to meet to determine Appeals</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p62">And if any person or persons certified assessed or rated for or in respe&bholigct;t of any reall or personall Estate [or
for or in respe&bholigct;t of any matter or thing<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] for which by this A&bholigct;t he or they is or may be rated or charged, doe
finde him or themselves agreived with such assessing or rateing, and doe within ten dayes after Demand thereof
made complaine to the Co&bhooov;;mis?ers, the said Co&bhooov;;mis?ers or any two or more of them whereof one of the Co&bhooov;;mis?ers
who signed or allowed his or their Rate to be one shall or may within fowertecne dayes next after such Complaint
Perticularly examine any person or persons upon his or their Oath other than the partie complaineing touching
the vallue of his or their reall or personail Estate and other the matters aforesaid, And upon due examination or
knowledge thereof abate, defalke, increase or enlarge the said Assesment. And the same soe abated, increased or
inlarged shall be certifyed or estreated by them into the Exchequer in manner aforesaid. And to that end
the said Co&bhooov;mis?ers are hereby required to meete together for the determining of such Complaints and Appeales
accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. Assessors, &amp;c. negle&bholigct;ting or refusing to do their Duty;</head>
			<para id="p63">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to fine, not exceeding &pound;5 for any one Offence</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p64">And it is further ena&bholigct;ted by the authoritie aforesaid That if any Assessor, Colle&bholigct;tor, Receiver or other persons
appointed by the Co&bhooov;;missioners shall wilfully negcle&bholigct;t or refuse to performe his Duty in the due and speedy
execution of this A&bholigct;t, the said respective Co&bhooov;mis?ers or any three or more of them may and shall by vertue of
this A&bholigct;t impose on such person and persons soe refuseing or negcle&bholigct;ting their Dutyes any Fine not: exceeding
the summe of five pounds for any one Offence, the same to be leavyed and certifyed as aforesaid into his
Majestyes Court of Exchequer, and charged upon the respe&bholigct;tive Receiver Generall amongst the rest of the Rates
aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXIX. Commissioners to call for Accounts from Receiver General of Monies received by him, and the Payment of it into Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p65">And the said Co&bhooov;;mis?ers or any two or more of them may or shall from time to time call for and require an
accompt from the respe&bholigct;tive Receivers Generall of all the Moneys received by him of the said Head Colle&bholigct;tors,
and of the payment thereof into his Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer according to the Dire&bholigct;tion of this A&bholigct;t, And
in case of any failer in the Premisses the said Co&bhooov;;mis?ers or any two or more of them are hereby required to cause
the same to be forthwith leavyed and paid according to the true intent and meaneing of this A&bholigct;t.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. If Controversy concerning assessing Commissioners, Commissioners concerned to withdraw.</head>
			<para id="p66">And in case of any Controyersie ariseing betweene the said Co&bhooov;;mis?ers concerning any Rates or Assesments to be
laid by vertue of this A&bholigct;t, the Co&bhooov;;mis?ers that shall be concerned therein shall have noe Voice but shall withdraw
dureing the Debate of such Controversies untill it be determined by the rest of the Co&bhooov;;mis?ers, and all Questions
and Differences that shall arise touching any of the said Rates, Taxes, Assesments or Leavyes shall be heard and
finally determined by two or more of the Co&bhooov;;mis?ers upon complaint thereof to them made by any person or persons
thereby greived without further Trouble or Suite in Law.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Receiver General to give Receipts to Head Colle&bholigct;tors, and Head Colle&bholigct;tors to Sub-colle&bholigct;tors gratis.</head>
			<para id="p67">And the said Receiver Generall shall give Acquittances gratis to the said Head colle&bholigct;tors for all moneys of them
received, And the said Head colle&bholigct;tors shall alsoe give Acquittances gratis to the Sub colle&bholigct;tors for all such moneys
as shall be paid by them in, pursuance of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. Sub-colle&bholigct;tors to deliver a Schedule to Head Colle&bholigct;tors of Defaulters where there is no Distress, which Schedule is to be delivered to, Receiver General, and returned by him into the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p68">And the said Sub colle&bholigct;tors shall make and deliver to the said Head colle&bholigct;tors a perfe&bholigct;t Schedule fairely writt
in Parchment under their Hands and Seales signed and allowed by any two or more of the respe&bholigct;tive Co&bhooov;;mis?ers
containing the Names, Surnames and Places of abode of every person within their respe&bholigct;tive Colle&bholigct;tion that shall
make default of payment of any of the summes that shall be rated or assessed on such person by vertue of this
A&bholigct; where noe sufficient Distresse is to be found and not otherwise. And the summe and summes charged on
every such person, the same Schedule to be delivered by the Head colle&bholigct;tor to the Receiver Generall of the County,
Citty or Place respe&bholigct;tively to be by him returned into his Majestyes Court of Exchequer, whereupon every person
soe makeing defaulte of payment may be charged by Processe of the Court according to the course of the Court
of Exchequer in such cases.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>XLIII. No Privilege of Exemption from Subsidies, &amp;c. shall extend to Rates granted by this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p69">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the authoritie aforesaid That noe Letters Patents granted by the Kings Majestie
or any of his Royall Progenitors to any person or persons Cittyes Burroughes or Townes Corporate within this
Realme of any manner of Libertyes, Priviledges or Exemptions from Subsidyes, Tolls, Taxes, Assesments or Ayds
shall be construed or taken to exempt any person or persons, Citty, Burrough or Towne corporate or any the
Inhabitants of the same from the burthen and charge of any summe or summes of money granted by this A&bholigct;t,
But that all and every [such<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] person and persons Citty Burrough and Towne corporate shall pay their proportion of
all Rates and Assesments by this present A&bholigct;t imposed. Any such Letters Patents Grants or Charters or any Clause
of Non obstante or other matter or thing therein contained, or any Law, Statute, Custome or Prescription to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>XLIV. Inhabitants, &amp;c. in Cities, &amp;c. not compellable to be Assessors, &amp;c. out of Limits.</head>
			<para id="p70">Provided alsoe That noe person inhabiting in any [Citty<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] Burrough, or Towne Corporate shall be compelled to
be any Assessor or Colle&bholigct;tor of or for any part of the Rates and Assesments hereby granted in any place or places
out of the Limitts of the said Burrough or Towne corporate.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>XLV. Proviso for Colleges, &amp;c. in the Universities, the Colleges of Windsor, Eton,</head>
			<para id="p71">
				<emph type="i">Winchester and Westminster, and for Hospitals in respe&bholigct;t of Scites of Colleges, &amp;c. and for Almshouses</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p72">Provided alsoe That nothing in this A&bholigct;t contained shall be extended to charge any Colledge or Hall in either
of the Universityes or the Colledges of Windsor, Eaton, Winton or Westminster or any Hospitalls or Almeshouses
or any Free Schoole for or in respe&bholigct;t of the Scites of the said Colledges or Halls or Hospitalls or Almeshouses
or any Free Schoole, Nor any Master Fellow or Scholler of any such Colledge or Hall or in any other Free
Officers therein and for Christ's Hospital, and other Hospitals and Almshouses. Schooles, or any Reader, Officer or Minister of the said Universityes, Colledges or Schooles or of any Almesmen
of any Hospitalls or Almeshouses for or in respe&bholigct;t of any Stipend Wages or Proffitts whatsoever ariseing or
growing due to them in respe&bholigct;t of the said severall Places and imployments in the said Universityes, Colledges,
Halls, Schooles Hospitalls or Almeshouses. Nor to charge any of the Houses or Lands belonging to Christs
Hospitall, or the Hospitalls of Saint Bartholomew, Bridewell, Saint Thomas and Bethlehem Hospitall within the
Citty of London and Burrough of Southwarke or any of them, or to any Colledge or Hall in either of the
Universityes, or to the Colledges of Eaton Winchister or Westminster, or to any Hospitall Almeshouse or Free
schoole whatsoever for or in respe&bholigct;t of any Rents or Revenues payable to the said Hospitalls, being to be received
and disbursed for the immediate use and releife of the Poore in the said Hospitalls.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>XLVI. Tenants of Hospitals to be rated for what the Lands are worth above Rents reserved.</head>
			<para id="p73">Provided That noe Tennants of any Lands or Houses by Lease or Grant from any the said Hospitalls
Colledges Halls Almeshouses or Free Schooles shall claime or enjoy any freedome or exemption by this A&bholigct;t, but that
all the Houses and Lands which they soe hold shall be rated for soe much as they are yearely worth over
and above the Rents reserved and payable to the said Hospitalls Colledges Halls Almeshouses or Free Schooles.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>XLVII. Persons dwelling in one Parish, &amp;c. having Goods in another, to be assessed where they dwell.</head>
			<para id="p74">Provided alsoe That where any person inhabiting within the Citty of London or any other Citty or Towne
corporate hath his Dwelling house in one of the Parishes and Wards therein, and hath any Goods Wares or
Merchandices chargeable by this A&bholigct;t in one or more of the other Parishes or Wards in the same Citty, That
then such person shall be charged, taxed and assessed for such his Goods or Merchandices in the Parish or
Ward where he dweleth and not elsewhere in the said Citty.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>XLVIII. Places to be assessed in the County, &amp;c. where usually assessed.</head>
			<para id="p75">Provided alwayes and bee it further declared and ena&bholigct;ted by the authority aforesaid That for the avoiding
of all Obstru&bholigct;tions and Delayes in assessing and colle&bholigct;ting the Summes which by this A&bholigct;t are to be rated and
assessed all Places Constablewicks Divisions and Allotments which have used to be rated and assessed shall pay
and be assessed in such County, Hundred, Rape Wapentake Constablewicke Division Place and Allotment as the
same hath heretofore usually beene assessed in and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>XLIX. Where Lands, &amp;c. unoccupied, and no Distress nor Person of Owner found, the Name of Owner to be certified into Exchequer;</head>
			<para id="p76">
				<emph type="i">which Certificate is to be a Charge, and Process to issue</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p77">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ted That in case any Lands or Houses in any Parish, Place or
Constablewicke shall lye unoccupyed and noe Distresses can be found on the same nor the person of the true
Owner or Proprietor can be found within the said County, by reason whereof the Rate and Assessment upon
such unoccupyed Lands cannot be leavyed, That then upon complaint thereof made to the Co&bhooov;issers for the
County where such case shall happen to be, the said Com&bhooov;issers or any two or more of them shall certifie
into his Majestyes Court of Exchequer the Name of the person whose Land or House [so<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] lyeth unoccupyed
together with the summe thereupon assessed, and the Parish or Place where such Land lyeth, which Certificate is
hereby declared to be a sufficient charge upon the person and Land therein named, and shall make the person
Debitor to his Majestie for the summe soe assessed, and the Court of Exchequer shall issue out Processe thereupon
against the Body, Goods and all other the Lands of such Debtor untill the said summe soe assessed be fully and
effe&bholigct;tually leavyed and paid to his Majestie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s50">
			<head>L. Commissioners to call before them Colle&bholigct;tors, and examine touching full Payment of Assessments;</head>
			<para id="p78">
				<emph type="i">and in case of failure, to levy</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p79">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ted and declared That at the expiration of the respe&bholigct;tive times in this A&bholigct;t prescribed
for the full payment of the severall and respe&bholigct;tive Rates and Assessements herein before granted, the severall and
respective Com&bhooov;issers or any two or more of them within their Division and Hundred shall and are hereby required
to call before them the cheife Colle&bholigct;tors and Sub colle&bholigct;tors within each respe&bholigct;tive Division and Hundred to examine
and assure themselves of the full and whole payment of the perticular summe and summes of money charged
within and upon the said Division and Hundred and every Parish and Place therein and of the due returne of
the same into the hands of the Receivers Generall of the said County Citty Towne and Place respe&bholigct;tively, And
by such Receiver Generall to the Receipt of his Majestyes Exchequer, to the end there may be noe failer in (<ref idref="n17">17</ref>) any
part of the rates and assessments which by this A&bholigct;t ought to be leavyed and paid; and in case of any failer
in the Premisses the Com&bhooov;issers or any two of them are to cause the same forthwith to be leavyed and paid
according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s51">
			<head>LI. Repayment of Monies lent how to be secured.</head>
			<para id="p80">
				<emph type="i">Books to be provided.; No Monies issued out of Exchequer but by Order as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p81">And to the end that all moneys which shall be lent unto his Majestie upon the Credit of this A&bholigct;t may be
well and sufficiently secured" out of the moneys ariseing and payable by this A&bholigct;t Bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the
authoritie aforesaid That there shall be provided and kept in his Majestyes Exchequer that is to say in the Office
of the Auditor of the Receipt one Booke or Register in which all moneys that shall be paid into the Exchequer
by vertue of this Act shall be entred and registred apart and distin&bholigct;t from all other moneys paid or payable to
his Majestie or to his Heires and Successors upon any other Branch of his Majestyes Revenue or upon any other
account whatsoever. And that there be one other Booke or Registry provided and kept in the said Office of
all Orders to be signed by the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer or by the [Lors<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] Com&bhooov;issers of the Treasury
for the time being for payment of all and every summe and summes of money to all persons for moneys lent
or other payments dire&bholigct;ted thereupon, And that noe moneys leavyable by this A&bholigct;t be issued out of the Exchequer,
but by such Order mentioning that the moneys payable by such Order are for moneys lent or other the occasions
aforesaid. And that alsoe there be the like Booke or Registry provided and kept by the same Auditor of all
moneys paid out or issued by vertue of such Orders.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s52">
			<head>LII. Persons lending Money may inspect the Books.</head>
			<para id="p82">
				<emph type="i">Tally of Loan to Lender, and Warrant for Interest.; Orders for Repayment registered according to Date of Tally, other Orders entered and paid in course; Monies to come in by this Act liable to satisfy such Loans.; No Fee for providing or making Books, &amp;c. or for Payment of Money lent; Penalty.; Punishment.; Undue Preference by Officer.; Penalty; Undue Preference by Deputy; Penalty.; Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller, not making Payments in due Order; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p83">And that it shall be lawfull for any person or persons willing to lend any money for his Majestyes Service
on the Credit of this A&bholigct;t at the usuall times when the Exchequer is open to have accesse thereunto, and reveiw
and peruse all or any the Bookes for their Information of the state of those moneys and all Engagements upon
them for their better encouragement to lend any moneys as aforesaid. And that the Auditor of the Receipt his
Deputyes and Clerkes shall be assistant to such persons for their better and speedier satisfa&bholigct;tion in that behalfe.
And that all and every person and persons who shall lend any moneyes [unto<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] his Majestie and pay the same
into his Receipt of Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally of Loane strucke for the same and an Order for
his Repayment beareing the same date with his Tally, In which Order there shall be alsoe contained a Warrant
for payment of Interest for forbearance at the rate of seaven pounds per Cen? per Ann&bhouov; for his consideration and
neo more, nor any Gratuity, Reward or other Consideration whatsoever to be paid every six moneths untill the
repayment of his principall, And that all Orders for [repayment of<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] money lent shall be registred in course according
to the date of the Tallyes respe&bholigct;tively, And that all other Orders shall be entred in course according to their.
respe&bholigct;tive dates, And neither of the sorts of Orders above mentioned either for Loanes of money or other
uses shall have preference one before another, but shall all be entred in their course according to the dates of
the Tallyes and the dates of the Orders for other payments as they are in point of time respe&bholigct;tively before each
other, And that all and every person and persons shall stand entred in the said Register Booke soe as that the
person his Executors Administrators and Assignes who shall have his Order first entred in the said
Booke of Registry shall be taken and accounted as the first person to be paid upon the moneys to come in by
vertue of this A&bholigct;t, and soe successively and in course according to the priority of Entry, And the moneys to
come in by this A&bholigct;t shall be in the same Order lyeable to the satisfa&bholigct;tion of the said respective partyes their
Executors Administrators or Assignes successively without preference of one before another, and not otherwise, nor
shall the same be diverted to any other use intent or purpose whatsoever. And noe Fee Demand or Gratuity
shall dire&bholigct;tly or indirectly be taken by any of his Majestyes Officers theire Clerkes or Deputies of any of his
Majestyes Subje&bholigct;ts for providing or makeing of any such Bookes Registers Entryes View Search or Certificate
in or for payment of money lent or the Interest thereof on paine of payment of treble Dammages to the partie
greived by the partie offending with Costs of Suite. And if the Officer himselfe take or demand any such Fee
or Reward then the Officer to loose his place alsoe. And if any undue preference of one before another shall
be made either in point of Registring contrary to the true meaning of this A&bholigct;t by any such Officer or Officers
then the party soe offending shall render the value of the Debt soe postponed together with Costs and Dammages
to the partie greived to be recovered by A&bholigct;tion of Debt or on the Case Bill, Plaint or Information in any of
his Majestyes Courts of Record wherein noe Essoine, Prote&bholigct;tion, Priviledge Wager of Law Injun&bholigct;tion or Order of
Restraint shall be in any wise allowed or granted. And if such preference be unduely made by any Deputy or
Clerke to such Officer without the privity or dire&bholigct;tion of his Master Then such Deputy or Clerke onely shall
be lyeable to such A&bholigct;tion Debt Dammages and Costs and shall be for ever after incapeable of his Place or Office.
And in case the Auditor shall not dire&bholigct;t the Order or the Clerke of the Pells record; or the Teller make payment
according to each persons due Place and Order as afore dire&bholigct;ted; then he or they shall be judged to forfeite
and their respe&bholigct;tive Deputyes and Clerkes herein offending to be lyable to such A&bholigct;tion of Debt Dammages and
Costs in such manner as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s53">
			<head>LIII. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date and are entered the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p84">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That if it happen that severall Tallyes of Loane or Orders for
Payments as aforesaid beare date or be brought the same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be registred then
it shall not be interpreted an undue preference to enter any of these first soe as they all be entred the same day.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s54">
			<head>LIV. Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded, no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Orders.</head>
			<para id="p85">Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpreted any undue preference to incurr any penaltie in point of payment
if the Auditor dire&bholigct;t and the Clerke of the Pells record and the Tellers doe pay subsequent Orders of persons.
that come and demand their money, and bring their Orders before other persons that did not come to demand.,
their moneys and bring their Order in their course soe as there be soe much money reserved as will satisfie their
Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon Loane being to cease from the
time the money is so reserved and kept in banke for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s55">
			<head>LV. Orders for Payment of Money lent may be assigned by Indorsement.</head>
			<para id="p86">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee.;Assignee may in like manner assign</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p87">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the authoritie aforesaid That every person or persons to whom any moneys
shall be due by vertue of this A&bholigct;t after Order entred in the Booke of Register aforesaid for payment thereof
his Executors Administrators or Assignes by Endorsment of his Order may assigne and transfer his Right, Title
Interest and Benefit of such Order or any part thereof to any other, which being notifyed in the Office of the
Auditor of the Receipt aforesaid, and an Entry and Memoriall thereof alsoe made in the Booke of Registry
aforesaid for Orders which the. Officers shall on request accordingly make without Fee or Charges for moneys
lent unto his Majestie as aforesaid shall entitle such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the
benefit thereof and payment thereon; and such Assignee may in like manner assigne againe and soe toties quoties.
And afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person or persons who have made such Assignement to make
void release or discharge the same or any the moneys thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s56">
			<head>LVI. In Action for executing Act, General Issue.</head>
			<para id="p88">
				<emph type="i">Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p89">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the authoritie aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;tion Suite Plaint or Information shall be
commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in execution
of this A&bholigct;t, such person or persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall or may pleade the Generall Issue, Not guilty and upon any Issue joined may give this A&bholigct;t and the speciall Matter in Evidence, And if the Plaintiffe
or Prosecutor shall become Nonsuite or forbeare [further<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] prosecution, or suffer discontinuance, or if a Verdi&bholigct;t passe
against him the Defendant [and Defendants<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] shall recover their treble Costs for which they shall have the like
remedy as in (<ref idref="n22">22</ref>) case where Costs by Law are given to the Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s57">
			<head>LVII. Landlords to pay on Houses where Foreign Ministers reside.</head>
			<para id="p90">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ted That every Rate [Tax<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] or Assessment which shall be made or imposed by
yertue of this A&bholigct;t of Parlyament in respe&bholigct;t of any House or Tenement which an Embassador Resident Agent or
other publique Minister of any Forreigne Prince or State now doth or shall hereafter inhabite or occupy shall be
paid by the Landlord or Owner of the said House or Tenements respe&bholigct;tively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s58">
			<head>LVIII. Proviso for Ground unbuilt on, and for Houses in London burnt down and yet unbuilt, and new Houses that stand empty.</head>
			<para id="p91">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the authoritie aforesaid That noe person or persons Bodyes
Pollitique or Corporate shall be [taxed or<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] charged by vertue of this A&bholigct;t for any toft or parcell of Ground lyeing
unbuilt and yeilding noe proffit, nor for any House or Houses now built and standing empty or uninhabited at
the time of makeing the Assessment or Assessments which since the building thereof have not beene inhabited
within any part of the Citty of London and Liberties thereof burnt downe in the late dismall Fire But that
all such Ground and Houses shall be freed and exempted from the payment of the Rate and Summes of Money
before imposed or charged to be taxed and paid for Lands and Houses for soe many of the quarterly payments
as they shall continue unlett and uninhabited, Any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s59">
			<head>LIX. Proviso respecting Nomination of Assessors and Collectors in extra parochial and privileged Places.</head>
			<para id="p92">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ted by the authority aforesaid That in all priviledged and other places being Extra
parochiall or not within any the Constablewicks or Precincts of the respe&bholigct;tive Assessors to be appointed by vertue
of this A&bholigct;t although in any monethly or other Tax they have not beene assessed or rated heretofore the said
Co&bhooov;mis?ers or any two or more of them shall and are hereby required to nominate and appointe two fitt persons
liveing in or neare the said priviledged or other places as aforesaid to be Assessors for the said places and
to make and returne their Assessments in like manner as by this A&bholigct;t is appointed in any Parish, Tything
or Place, and alsoe to appointe one or more Colle&bholigct;tors who are hereby required to colle&bholigct;t and pay the same
according to the Rules appointed by this A&bholigct;t for collecting and paying all summes of money payable by
this A&bholigct;t.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s60">
			<head>LX. Proviso for ancient Rights of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, Clergy, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p93">[Provided alwayes That nothing herein contained shall be drawne into Example to the prejudice of the auntient
Rights belonging to the Lords Spirituall and Temporall or Clergy of this Realme or unto either of the
Universityes or unto any Colledges Schooles Almeshouses Hospitalls or Cinque Ports.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s61">
			<head>LXI. and for any Covenants between Landlord and Tenant touching Payment of Taxes.</head>
			<para id="p94">Provided alsoe That nothing in this Act contained shall be constred to alter change determine or make void
any Contra&bholigct;ts Covenants or Agreements whatsoever betweene the Landlord and Tennant touching the payment of
Taxes or Assesments. Any thing herein before mentioned to the contrary notwithstanding.<ref idref="n23">23</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">to <emph type="i">O.</emph>
			</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">into <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">Colle&bholigct;ors <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">hand <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">transcribing <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">the Payment of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">Lords <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">interlined on the Roll <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">any <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">annexed to the Original A&bholigct;t in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


