<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47422" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XIV. An Act for settling the drayneing of the Fennes in Lincolnshire called Deepeing Fennes.(<ref idref="n1">1</ref>)[O. nu. 28.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 16 &amp; 17 Car. II. c. 11. &sect; 2.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">But that by reason of some Inconveniencies in the said A&bholigct;, and other Discourage-ments, the Trustees had delayed to proceed till by a Decree of Sewers made at a General Sessions of Sewers at Spalding, in the County of Lincoln, 14th April 21 C. II. it was decreed as herein mentioned; and that the said, Trustees had been encouraged to proceed by the said Decree until an A&bholigct; of Parliament could be obtained, and that in Confidence there of they had expended great Sums of Money in the said Work; If the Trustees should be delayed by the Weather, &amp;c. and so adjudged by six or more Commissioners; and should within Half a Year from the passing of this A&bholigct; repair Douzens and Hawthorne Banks, then Three Years further allowed for finishing</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by an A&bholigct; of this present Parliament made at a Session held in the Sixteenth and Seaventeenth
yeare of His Majesties Raigne entituled An A&bholigct; for drayneing the Fenns called Deeping Fenns and other
Fenns therein menc&bhocotil;oed It is amongst other things ena&bholigct;ed, That the Trustees therein named their Heires and
Assignes should drayne the said Fenns in manner as is therein expressed within the Space of seaven yeares then
next ensueing But by reason of some inconveniencies in the said A&bholigct; and other discouragements the said Trustees
have delayed to proceed in the said worke; till by a Law Order and Decree of Sewers made at a Generall Sessions
of Sewers holden at Spalding in the County of Lincolne the Foureteenth Day of Aprill in the One and twentieth
yeare of his said Majesties raigne, it was adjudged ordered and decreed That in case the tyme remaineing and
then yet to come of the seaven yeares aforesaid by reason of the unseasonablenesse of the weather or other
unavoidable accident should not be sufficient for the compleateing and finishing the said worke, and should be
soe adjudged and declared by six or more of the Comissioners of Sewers of the County of Lincolne, whereof
three to be of the Hundred of Nesse at their Publique and open Sessions to be holden at Spalding aforesaid
And the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes should within one halfe yeare after makeing the said Order and
Decree of Sewers sufficiently maintaine and repaire the Banck called Hawthorn Banck and the Banck called the
Douzens and soe from tyme to tyme should maintaine and preserve the same then the space or time of three
yeares should be added and granted to the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes for the better effe&bholigct;ing and
finishing the said worke; And further it was then adjudged ordered and decreed by the said Comissio?: of Sewers
That from thenceforth it should and might be lawfull for the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes to take
Earth and Manure for the makeing and repaireing any the Bancks made or to be made for the drayneing and
preservac&bhocotil;on of the said Fenns on the River or Washside in such propor&bhocotil;n as need should require and where
Earth sufficient could not be had on that side that it should and might be lawfull for the said Trustees their
Heires and Assignes to take Earth and Manure on the Land side or inside of any the said Banks not exceeding
sixscore foote distance from any the said Banks without payeing any satisfac&bholigct;on: for the same, except for cutting
or covering such Grounds as were then severall for which satisfac&bholigct;on should be made and given by the Comissioners
of Sewers appointed by the said A&bholigct; in such manner as by the said A&bholigct; of Parliament is limitted and dire&bholigct;ed
And it was then alsoe adjudged ordered and decreed by the said Comissioners of Sewers that noe satisfac&bholigct;on should
be made or given to any person or persons for any losse or damage which by reason of any breach or overflowing
hath or shall hereafter happen to any the Fenns [c&bhooov;only<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] called Deepeing Fenns or other the Fenns by the
said A&bholigct; of Parliament intended to be drayned, for as much [as<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes
would be the greatest sufferers thereby By which said Law Order and Decree of Sewers the said Trustees their
Heires or Assignes haveing been encouraged to proceed in the drayneing of the said Fenns untill an A&bholigct; of
Parliament might be obtained for their better assureance and security, And in confidence thereof haveing already
expended great sumes of money in the said worke Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie
by and with the Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and C&bhooov;ns in this present Parliament assembled
and by the Authority of the same That in case the tyme remaineing and yet to come of the seaven yeares afore
menc&bhocotil;oed by reason of the unseasonablenesse of the weather or other unavoidable accidents shall not be sufficient to
compleate and finish the said worke and shall be soe adjudged and declared by six or more of the Comissioners
of Sewers of the County of Lincolne whereof three to be of the Parts of Kesteven not interested in the said
undertakeing at their publique and open Sessions to be holden at Spalding aforesaid And the said Trustees their
Heires and Assignes shall within one halfe yeare after the passing of this A&bholigct; sufficiently [maintaine and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] repaire
the said Bank called the Douzens and the said Bank called Hawthorne Bank and soe from tyme to tyme shall
maintaine and preserve the same then the space or tyme of three yeares shall be added and granted unto the said
Trustees their Heires and Assignes for the better effe&bholigct;ing and finishing the said worke,</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Trustees may take Earth and Manure for Repairs;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">and if need be, from the Land Side or inside of the Banks, without paying, except as herein mentioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And further, bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That from henceforth it shall and may be lawfull for
the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes to take Earth and Manure for the makeing and repaireing any the
Banks made or to be made for the dreyneing and preservac&bhocotil;n of the said Fenns on the River or Wash side of
any the said Banks in such proporc&bhocotil;on as need shall require, and where Earth sufficient cannot be had on that side
it shall and may be lawfull for the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes to take Earth and Manure on the
Land side or inside of any the said Banks not exceeding sixscore foote distance from any of the said Banks without
paieing any satisfac&bhocotil;on for the same except for cutting and covering such Grounds as now are severall for which
satisfac&bhocotil;on shall be made and given by the Comissioners of Sewers appointed by the said A&bholigct; in such manner as
[in and<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] by the said A&bholigct; of Parliament is limitted and dire&bholigct;ed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. No Satisfa&bholigct;ion for; overflowing, &amp;c. as the Trustees will be the greatest Sufferers.</head>
			<para id="p5">And further be it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That noe satisfacon shall be made or given to any p&bhopubr;son
or p&bhopubr;sons for any losse or d?mage which by reason of any breach or overflowing hath or shall hereafter happen
to any the Fenns now co&bhooov;only called Deeping Fenns or other the Fenns by the said A&bholigct; intended to be drayned,
forasmuch as the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes will be the greatest sufferers thereby Any thing in the
said A&bholigct; to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Recital that by the said A&bholigct; 3,500 Acres, and 1,500 Acres were added to the Trustees, to be set out as therein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">The said Trustees to hold the same</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p7">And whereas by the said A&bholigct; Three thousand five hundred Acres, and One thousand Acres and Five hundred
Acres are added and allotted to the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes Which said Three thousand five
hundred Acres One thousand Acres and Five hundred Acres were to be admeasured by Statute Measure by two
Artists and sett out by them at the charge of the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes or the Survivor of them
one to be chosen by the Comissioners of Sewers for Kesteven and Holland and one other by the said Undertakers;
Which said Three thousand five hundred Acres, and One thousand Acres and Five hundred Acres have been
since admeasured and sett out according to the direcc&bhocotil;ons in the said A&bholigct; Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority
aforesaid That the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes shall hold and enjoy the same as they are soe sett forth
or now enclosed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Persons stopping Rivers or Drains, cutting Banks, &amp;c. (Exception) to make Satisfa&bholigct;ion to Party, or punished.</head>
			<para id="p8">And for the better security and preservac&bhocotil;on of the said works Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority afores? That
if any person or persons except such as shall be authorized by the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes shall
wilfully or maliciously stopp any River or Drayne cutt breake or throw downe any Bank Sluce or other worke
made or to be made, within or without the said Fenns except as in the said A&bholigct; is limitted and permitted such person
or persons offending as afores[ai]d shall make full satisfac&bhocotil;on to the person and persons as shall be injured thereby
to be recovered by an Acc&bhocotil;on in any of His Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne
Protecc&bhocotil;on or Wager of Law shall be allowed and in case he or they soe offending shall not be able to give or
make satisfac&bhocotil;on as aforesaid then such person or persons shall and may be prosecuted and punished for the same
as in the case of cutting the Poe Dik in Marsland is provided</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Undertakers, Owners of 250 Acres or upwards, may meet at the Times and Place herein mentioned, and impose an Acre Tax on the 10,036 Acres;</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">and also a Penalty,; If Tax not paid, then such Penalty to be levied.; Proceedings if Tax and Penalty be unpaid until the Thursday next after the Second Sunday in April.; Receiver on Warrant may enter Lands and take the Rents, &amp;c. till Tax and Penalty satisfied. Proceedings if Tax and Penalty with such other Tax and Penalty not paid before the Thursday next after the Second Sunday in the next April</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And for the more convenient layeing and leavying of Taxes, and for the better security of all such persons as
shall become Participants and Adventurers in the said work under the said Trustees their Heires and Assignes Bee
it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority afores? That the Undertakers in the said A&bholigct; menc&bhocotil;oed their Heires and Assignes or
any three or more of them each of them being Owner of Two hundred and fifty Acres or more part of the
Tenn thousand thirty six Acres by the said A&bholigct; made chargeable with Taxes for carrying on the dreyneing of the
said Fenns shall and may at a Publique Meeting of the said Undertakers to be holden at the Towne of Spalding
in the County of Lincolne on [the<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] Thursday next after the second Sunday in Aprill yearely (at which tyme
and place the said Undertakers are hereby enjoyned to hold their publique meeting once in every yeare for ever
hereafter) assesse and rate an equall Acre Tax on all and every the said Tenn thousand thirty six Acres to be
paid on the Tenth Day of O&bholigct;ober then next following and alsoe impose a Penaltie not exceeding the third part
of the said Tax, and if the said Tax be not paid by the respe&bholigct;;ive Undertakers at or before the Tenth Day of
November then next following then such Undertakers soe faileing shall forfeit the Penaltie imposed to be leavyed
together with the said Tax by sequestrac&bhocotil;on and sale of the Land of such Undertakers in such manner as is herein
after expressed (that is to say) if the said Tax and Penaltie or any part thereof be unpaid untill the Thursday
after the second Sunday in Aprill then next following that it shall and may be lawfull for the said Undertakers
or any three or more of them qualified as afores[ai]d at their publique meeting on the last menc&bhocotil;oed Thursday at the
Towne of Spalding aforesaid by a Writeing under their Hands and Seales to that purpose made and dire&bholigct;ed
to their Receivo<ref idref="n3">3</ref> for the tyme being to cause to be seized and sequestred the Lands for which such Tax and
Penaltie shall be soe in arreare, And the said Receivo<emph type="p">r</emph> is hereby enabled upon receipt of such Writeing to enter
upon the said Lands and to take receive and leavy the Rents Issues and Profitts thereof till the said Tax and
Penalty due as aforesaid be fully satisfied the same to be imployed for the dreyneing and preserving the said
Fenns without any accompt to be given thereof to the Owner or Owners of such Lands And if the said Tax
and Penaltie with such other Tax and Penaltie as shall be due dureing the said Sequestrac&bhocotil;on shall not be fully
satisfied before the Thursday next after the second Sunday in Aprill then next following that it shall and may be
lawfull for any three or more of the said Undertakers qualified as afores? at their then publique meeting at the
Towne of Spalding aforesaid by Deed under their Hands and Seales duely executed and enrolled or entred within
three moneths then next following with the Register of the said Undertakers in his Register Booke for entering
Conveyances to bargaine and sell to any p&bhopubr;son or p&bhopubr;sons such or soe much of the said Lands for which such
Tax and Penaltie shall be in arreare as shall be sufficient to satisfye the said Tax or Taxes and Penalties in
arreare and to returne the Overplus of the money (if any be) to the Owners of the said Lands Which Deed soe
executed and enrolled or entered is hereby ena&bholigct;ed to be a sufficient Conveyance of the said Lands to such
person or persons to whom the same shall be bargained and sold as aforesaid</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. No Tax laid at any other Time.</head>
			<para id="p11">And be it ena&bholigct;ed that noe Tax for dreyneing or preserveing the said Fenns shall at any tyme hereafter be
taxed or leavyed at any other tyme or in any other manner then is herein before expressed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. If Money raised on Lands, &amp;c. of Undertakers, or their Tenants, by Authority given to Commissioners of Sewers, and Treasurer to the Undertakers do not satisfy the same, with Damages, within 20 Days from Demand;</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">then Persons damnified may divide such Monies and Damages, and charge Owners of the 10,036 Acres proportionally. Such Owners not paying in 20 Days from Demand, A&bholigct;ion for Persons damnified</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p13">And be it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any sume or s&bhouov;es of money shall be raised
or leaved by vertue of the Authority given by the said A&bholigct; to the Comissioners of Sewers upon the Lands Goods
or Chattells of the Adventurers or Owners of the said Tenn thousand thirty six Acres or any of them or upon
the Lands Goods or Chattells of any their respe&bholigct;ive Ten<emph type="p">a</emph>nts Farmo<emph type="p">rs</emph> : or Occupiers for any the matters or things
in the said A&bholigct; menc&bhocotil;oed if the Tre&atilde;r for the tyme being to the said Undertakers shall not within Twenty Dayes
after demand made pay and satisfye the same with such Da&amacr;ages as such person or persons shall susteyne
thereby to such person or persons on whose Lands Goods or Chattells any sume or s&bhomov;mes of money shall be
raised or leavyed as aforesaid that then the person and persons soe dampnified shall and may devide the said
s&bhouov;me or s&bhouov;es of money leavyed on him or them as aforesaid together with his or their D?mages susteyned
thereby into equall proporc&bhocotil;ons to be charged on every the Owners of the said Ten thousand thirty six Acres in a
rateable way according to their respe&bholigct;ive number of Acres, and if any such Owner shall not within Twenty
Dayes after demand pay to the partyes soe dampnified his respe&bholigct;ive part or proporc&bhocotil;on thereof such person or
persons soe dampnified shall and may recover the same by Acc&bhocotil;on of Debt against the person or persons soe
negle&bholigct;ing or refuseing to pay the same in any of His Majesties Courts of Record at Westminster in which Ac&bhocotil;on
noe Essoigne Protecc&bhocotil;on or Wager of Law shall bee admitted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Six or more Commissioners of Sewers for the County of Lincoln may dire&bholigct; cutting of Banks for laying down Tunnels as herein mentioned, but not to charge Trustees.</head>
			<para id="p14">Provided alwaies and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed that it shall and may bee lawfull for six or more of the
Comission&bhopubr;s of Sewers for the County of Lincolne to dire&bholigct; the cutting of any the Bankes in the said Parts of
Holland without the said Fenns for the laying downe any Tunnell or Tunells in such place or manner as to them
shall seeme meete for the takeing in or letting out of Water to any the Lands of Spalding Pinchbeck or Weston
but the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes shall not stand chargeable therewith nor shall be lyable to make or
give any satisfacc&bhocotil;on for any damage hapning thereby</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Proviso respe&bholigct;ing taking Waters out of the Rivers of Glean and Welland.</head>
			<para id="p15">
				<emph type="i">A&bholigct;ion against Offenders</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p16">And bee itt further ena&bholigct;ed that it shall not be lawfull for any person or persons whatsoever to lett or take
any Waters out of the Rivers of Glean or Welland into any other place or places then into the places afore
mentioned or into the Fenns c&bhooov;monly called Deeping Fenns but the said Trustees their Heires or Assignes their
Servants or Agents or any other person shall have power imediatly to stop the same and alsoe shall or may
recover D?mages against such person or persons soe offending by Acc&bhocotil;on in any of His Ma&bhojties;ties Courts at Westminster
in which Acc&bhocotil;on noe Essoigne Protecc&bhocotil;on or Wager of Law shall bee admitted. Any Law Statute Costome or
Usuage to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>ITEM qu&aelig;dam petitiones privatas personas concernentes (in se formam A&bholigct;us continentes) exhibite fuerunt, predi&bholigct;o
Domino Regi in Parliamento predi&bholigct;o, quarum tituli subscribuntur.</head>
			<para id="p17">1. An A&bholigct; for John Mannors, called Lord Roos, to marry againe.</para>
			<para id="p18">2. An A&bholigct; for setleing certaine charitable Uses devised by John late Bishop of Rochester.</para>
			<para id="p19">3. An Act for to enable Anthony Ashley Esquire Sonne of the Lord Ashley to acknowledge Fines and suffer
Recoveries of Lands and Hereditaments whitest he is under the age of twenty and one yeares.</para>
			<para id="p20">4. An Act for setleing part of the estate of Dame Susan Bellasis Widdow late Wife of Sir Henry Bellasis
deceased.</para>
			<para id="p21">5. An Act for confirmeing Purchasers Estates and for setleing the differences betweene the Lady Elizabeth Lee,
and the daughters and Coheires of the late Earle of Downe.</para>
			<para id="p22">6. An Act to enable the Trustees for the Lord Viscount Strangford of the Kingdome or Ireland to sell certaine
Lands for the payment of the remainder of his debts.</para>
			<para id="p23">7. An Act for the enableing Sir William Gostwicke Knight to make a Joynture to Dame Mary his wife.</para>
			<para id="p24">8. An Act for confirmeing the Estate of Sir Ralph Bankes in the Mannour of Thesbestet alias Thirsbestet and
other Lands in the County and County and Burrough of Carmarthen.</para>
			<para id="p25">9. An Act for sale of Lands to pay the debts and raise portions for the younger children of Sir Cuthbert
Heron Baronet.</para>
			<para id="p26">10. An Act to enable Dame Elizabeth Routh Mother (and Executrix of the last Will and Testament) of
Dorothy Farewell Widdow deceased late the Reli&bholigct; and Executrix of John Farewell late of the Inner Temple
London Esquire, to sell certaine Lands for the payment of debts.</para>
			<para id="p27">11. An Act for setleing the Mannour or Lordshipp of Firbecke in the County of Yorke and other Lands
therein mentioned on Trustees to enable them to sell the same for the payment of debts.</para>
			<para id="p28">12. An Act for the building of a Mansion House for the Deane of Saint Pauls Church London.</para>
			<para id="p29">13. An Act concerning the disposeing of a house and Lands belonging to the Sisters and Coheires of Margaret
Strode.</para>
			<para id="p30">14. An Act for endowment of a Church at Shadwell now in the Parish of Stepney in Midlesex and makeing
of it Parochiall distin&bholigct; from Stepney</para>
			<para id="p31">15. An Act for setleing the draining of the Fenns in Lincolnshire called Deeping Fenns.</para>
			<para id="p32">16. An Act for makeing navigable the Rivers commonly called Brandon and Waveney.</para>
			<para id="p33">17. An Act to enable Thomas Hord Esquire to make Leases of his Estate.</para>
			<para id="p34">18. An Act to enable Richard Beckham and others to sell Lands to pay his Fathers debts and to raise portions
for his younger brothers.</para>
			<para id="p35">19. An Act to enable John Bill Esquire to sell certaine Lands in Kent and Surrey.</para>
			<para id="p36">20. An Act for enableing Thomas Leigh Esquire to sell part of his Lands for payment of debts.</para>
			<para id="p37">21. An Act to enable Robert Hotchkin to sell Lands to pay debts and raise portions for daughters.</para>
			<para id="p38">22. An Act to enable Henry and Jane Perkins to ensure to Do&bholigct;or Wharton Lands purchased in the County
Palatine of Durham.</para>
			<para id="p39">23. An Act to enable Thomas Davison to sell Lands to pay debts and provide for younger Children.</para>
			<para id="p40">24. An Act for the naturalization of Captaine Christopher Gunman and others.</para>
			<para id="p41">25. An Act for the naturalizing of Horatio Woodhouse and others.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">From the Original A&bholigct; in the Parliament Office.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


