<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47434" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XII. An Additionall Act for ascertaining the Measures of Corne and Salt.[Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. I. nu. 12.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 22 C. II. c. 8.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">No Corn or Salt to be bought or sold by the Bag without measuring.; Penalty</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas notwithstanding there hath beene great care taken in a late A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>]
ascertaining the Measures of Corne and Salt throughout the Realme. Yet the same is in great measure
avoided by selling in private places aswell as in publique Markets by the Bagg, or without measureing by the
Buyers shakeing of the Bushell before it be strooke, soe that those places who have given Obedience to the
said A&bholigct; are greatly prejudiced, and their Markets likely to be lost by such undue pra&bholigct;ices. For prevention
whereof Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and Consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by authorise of, the same That
every person or persons who shall from and after the five and twentyeth day of March next sell, or buy any
Corne ground or unground or Salt by the Bagg or without Measureing being thereunto required, or in any other
manner then as is by the said A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ed, and that without shakeing the said Bushell or Measure by the Buyer,
shall forfeite and lose beside the Penalty of the former A&bholigct; appointed, all Corne, Graine, or Salt bought or sold
contrary to this A&bholigct;, or the Value thereof to the person or persons complaining.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proof of duly buying and selling, &amp;c. to lie upon the Defendant.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.; How to be disposed of</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And whereas a great cause of the mischeife hereby intended to be prevented doth arise by the selling in
private places, and soe avoiding not onely the intention of the said A&bholigct;, but to the great damage of publique
Markets Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That upon Complaint made to any one or more Justices of the Peace That any
kinde of Corne ground or unground or Salt hath beene sold or bought or delivered contrary to this A&bholigct; the
proofe shall lye upon the Defendant to make it appeare by the Oathes of one or more credible Witnesses That
he or they did sell or buy the same in every respe&bholigct; according to this and the said farmer A&bholigct;. Wherein if
such person complained of shall faile, he or they shall forfeite and lose as is by this A&bholigct; before dire&bholigct;ed to be
leavyed by Distresse and Sale of his or their Goods or Chattells restoreing the Overplus, by Warrant under the
Hand and Seale of one or more Justices before whome he or they shall be soe convi&bholigct;ed. Which Penalties by
this A&bholigct; appointed to be leavyed shall by the said Justice or Justices be distributed, one halfe to the Poore of
the Parish where such Offence was committed and the other halfe to the Informer or Prosecutor.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Where there is no Clerk of the Market, Mayors, Bailiffs, &amp;c. to seal the Measures.</head>
			<para id="p5">And whereas in all places where Markets are holden there is not a Clerke of the Market to seale all Measures
as by the former A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed Bee it therefore further ena&bholigct;ed That in every such case it shall and may be
lawfull for the Maior, Bayliffes or Head-Officer or other person or persons who hath the Benefit of such Market,
And they and every of them are hereby authorized and required to seale or cause to be sealed all Measures duely
gauged, that shall be brought unto them for that purpose, which Sealeing shall be as effe&bholigct;uall in the Law to all
intents and purposes as if such Measure had beene sealed by any Clerke of the Market, every such Maior, Bayliffe
or Head-Officer takeing noe more for soe doeing then is by the said A&bholigct; appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Proviso for Rent-Corn, Tythe-Corn, and Salt, reserved by Lease, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p6">[Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for
every person or persons Bodyes Politique or Corporate or any of them, to whome any Salt Rent corne or TythCorne is reserved or due by any Lease, Grant, Contra&bholigct;, Custome or Usage to receive and take all such Rent or
other Dutyes of Salt and Corne as is, or shall be soe reserved or due, or the just and full value thereof in ready
money according to the proportion and quantity and by the like measures, and in such manner as the same were
due, and paid before the begining of this Parlyament. Any thing herein or in any other Law or Statute to the
contrary in any wise notwithstanding.<ref idref="n2">2</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


