<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47448" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXVI. An Act to &bhopcrl;vent the planting of Tobacco in England, and for regulateing the Plantation Trade.[Rot. Parl 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 2. nu. 14.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that the planting of Tobacco continues notwithstanding;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">12 Car. II. c.34.; 15 Car. II. c. 7.; Justices of the Peace to issue their Warrants to Constables, &amp;c. to make a Return to them of what Tobacco is planted, and by whom and upon what Land; and to make a Presentment in Writing upon Oath to the next Quarter Sessions; Such Presentment being filed by Clerk of the Peace to be a sufficient Conviction; except upon Notice it shall be traversed.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the sowing, setting, planting and cureing of Tobacco within diverse parts of the Kingdome of
England doth continue and increase to the apparent Losse of his Majestyes Customes, and the discouragement
of his Majestyes Plantations in America, and great prejudice of the Trade and Navigation of this Realme, and the
vent of its Commodityes thither notwithstanding an A&bholigct; of Parlyament made in the twelfth yeare of his Majestyes
Raigne that now is for the prevention thereof entituled An A&bholigct; for prohibiting the planting, setting or sowing of
Tobacco in England and Ireland. And alsoe one other A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament made in the fifteenth yeare
of his said Majestyes Raigne intituled An A&bholigct; for the incouragement of Trade. And forasmuch as the remedies
and provisions by those Lawes are found not large enough to obviate and prevent the planting thereof, Bee it
therefore enacted by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authorise of the same That from
and after the first day of May which shall be in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred seaventy and
one all Justices of the Peace within their severall Limitts and Jurisdi&bholigct;ions, shall and doe a moneth before every
Generall Quarter Sessions to be holden for their respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, issue forth their Warrants to all HighConstables, Petty Constables and Tythingmen within their severall Limitts thereby, requireing the said High
constables, Petty-constables and Tythingmen and every of them, to make diligent search and inquiry what Tobacco
is then sowne, sett, planted, growing, cureing, cured or made within their, severall and respe&bholigct;ive Limitts and
Jurisdi&bholigct;ions and by whome; And to make a true and lawfull presentment in Writeing upon Oath at the next
Generall Quarter Sessions to be holden for such County, of the names of all such persons as have sowne, sett,
planted, cured or made any Tobacco, and what the full quantity of Land is, or was sowne, sett or planted
therewith, and who are the immediate Tennant or Tennants, or present Occupiers of the Land soe sowne, sett
or planted, who are and shall be deemed planters thereof to all intents and purposes. Which said presentment
upon oath shall be received and filed by the Clerke of the Peace of the said County in open Sessions, and after
such receipt and fileing shall be a sufficient Convi&bholigct;ion in Law to all intents and purposes of all such persons, as
shall be soe presented for the sowing, setting, planting, improveing to grow, makeing or cureing Tobacco, either
in Seede, Plant, Leafe or otherwise, contrary to the said recited A&bholigct;s or either of them, unlesse such person or
persons, soe presented (haveing notice given to him or them of such presentment made, by the delivery of a
Copy of such presentment to him or them, or by leaveing a Copy of such presentment at his or their Dwelling
House or Houses, or usuall place of aboade in the presence of one or more credible [Witnesse,<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] ten dayes at the
least before the next Quarter Sessions) shall at the Quarter Sessions next after such notice shall be given to
him or them, traverse such presentment, and finde sufficient Sureties for the prosecuteing and trying such
Traverse at the Quarter Sessions to be holden for the said County next after such Traverse shall be entred
or made.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Power to Officers, &amp;c. to pull up, &amp;c. and destroy all the Plants, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Officers not doing their Duty in destroying of it; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p4">And it is hereby further enacted That all Constables, Tythingmen, Bayliffes and other publique Officers shall
and doe within their respective Jurisdictions from time to time as often as occasion shall require within fowerteene
dayes after Warrant from two or more of the Justices of the Peace within such County, Towne, Citty or place
to them, calling to their assistance such person or persons as they and every [one<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of them shall finde convenient
and necessary, plucke up, burne, consume teare in pieces, and utterly destroy all Tobacco seede, Plant, Leafe,
planted, sowed or growing in any Field, Earth or Ground. And if any such Tobacco shall be suffered or permitted
to grow or be unconsumed in Seede, Plant or Leafe in any Towneship, Tything, Parish, Hamlet or place by the
space of fowerteene dayes after the receipt of such Warrant or Warrants by the said Constables, Tythingmen,
Bayliffes or other publique Officers of the respective Towneshipps, Tythings, Parishes or Hambletts as aforesaid,
That then such Constables, Tythingmen, Bayliffes, or other publique Officers respe&bholigct;ively shall for every such
offence forfeite and pay the summe of five shillings for every Rod, Perch or Pole of Ground soe sett, planted
or sowed with Tobacco, and soe proportionably for a greater or lesser quantity of Ground, the one moyety thereof
to the Kings Majestie, and the other moyety thereof to him or them that shall sue for the same, to be recovered
by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Information in any of his Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Refusing.; &amp;c. to assist Officers;</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 5s. Distress or Imprisonment.; Resisting Officers; Penalty &pound;5.; If no Distress, Imprisonment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That in case any person or persons [or persons<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to
ayde or assist (being thereunto required) any Constable, Bayliffe or other publique Officer in the due execution
of this A&bholigct;, That every such person or persons, for every such offence, upon convi&bholigct;ion thereof, made before
two Justices of the Peace of the said County, where such offence shall be committed, shall forfeite and pay the
summe of five shillings to be leavyed by Warrant from the said Justices by distresse and sale of the offenders
Goods, And in case noe distresse can be found then every such offender shall be committed to the common
Goale of the said County, there to remaine for the space of one weeke without Baile or Mainprize. And if any
person or persons whatsoever shall forceably resist any Constable, Bayliffe or other publique Officer or other person
or persons whatsoever in the due execution of this A&bholigct;, That then every such person for every such offence,
upon convi&bholigct;ion thereof made before two Justices of the Peace of the said County, where such offence shall be
committed, shall forfeite and pay the summe of five pounds to be leavyed by Warrant from the said Justices
by distresse and sale of the offenders Goods, And in case noe distresse can be found, then every such offender
shall be committed to the common Goale of the said County there to remaine for the space of three monethes
without Baile or Mainprize.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. In A&bholigct;ion brought for executing this and the former A&bholigct;s, General Issue may be pleaded.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Costs.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion, Plaint, Suite or Information shall be
commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or execution
of this A&bholigct; or either of the recited A&bholigct;s, such person or persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall or may
pleade the Generall Issue, Not Guilty, and upon any Issue joyned, may give this A&bholigct;, or the said recited A&bholigct;s on
either of them, and the speciall matter in Evidence, and if the Plaintiffe or Prosecutor shall become Nonsuite, or
forbeare further prosecution, or suffer discontinuance, or if a Verdi&bholigct; shall passe against him, the Defendant or
Defendants shall recover their Costs, for which they shall have the like remedy as in case where Costs are given
by the Law to the Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Tobacco planted in Physic Gardens.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alwayes and it is hereby enacted That this A&bholigct; nor any thing therein contained shall extend to the
hindring of the planting of Tobacco in any Phisicke Garden of either University, or in any other private Garden
for Phisicke or Chirurgery onely, soe as the quantity soe planted exceede not one halfe of one Pole in any one
place or Garden.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Recital of 15 C.II. c.7. &sect;4.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">and that Advantage had been taken of the Omission of repealing the Word Ireland in 12 C.II. c.18, &sect;19. The Word Ireland to be left out of all Bonds taken for Ships setting sail out of or from England, Ireland, Wales, &amp;c. for any English Plantation in America, &amp;c. The Governors of the English Plantations to take Bond as herein dire&bholigct;ed before Ship is permitted to load.; Ship loading before such Bond given, or Certificate that Bond hath been given in England.; Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p11">And whereas by one A&bholigct; of Parlyament in the fifteenth yeare of his Majestyes Raigne Entituled An A&bholigct; for
the encouragement of Trade. It is declared That inasmuch as his Majestyes Plantations beyond the Seas are inhabited
with his Subje&bholigct;s of England for the maintaining a better correspondency betwixt them, and keeping them in a
firmer dependence upon it, and rendering them yet more beneficiall and advantagious unto it, in the further
imployment and increase of English Shipping and Seamen, vent of Woollen and other manufa&bholigct;ures, rendering the
Navigation to and from the same more safe and cheape, and makeing this Kingdome a Staple not onely of the
Commodityes of those Plantations, but alsoe of the Commodities of other Countryes for the supplying them (it
being the usage of other Nations to keepe their Plantation trades to themselves) It was therefore ena&bholigct;ed That
noe Goods or Commodityes of Europe shall be carryed into any the Plantations of Asia, Africa or America,
but what shall bona fide be laden and shipped in England and in English built Shipps, or Shipps made free and
navigated with English according to an A&bholigct; of Parlyament on that behalfe; And that noe Officer of the Customes
in England or Wales shall give any Warrant, or suffer any Sugar, Tobacco and other Plantation goods therein
perticularly named to be carryed into any other Country or place whatsoever untill they have beene first bona
fide unladen in England, as by the said A&bholigct; doth more at large appeare. Notwithstanding which, some persons
takeing advantage of the not mentioning the repealeing of the word Ireland in one Clause in an A&bholigct; of Parlyament
made in the twelfth yeare of his Majestyes Raigne Entituled An A&bholigct; for the encourageing and encrease of Shiping
and Navigation. where Bonds are directed to be taken for all Shipps that shall lade any Sugar or other Commodities
therein particularly mentioned in any of the said Plantations, That the same Commodities shall be by the said Shipp
brought to some Port, of England, Ireland, Wales or Towne or Port of Berwicke, and shall there unlode, and putt
the same on shore, the said persons having either refused to give Bond for the returne of their Shipps in such
case to England, Wales or Towne or Port of Berwicke onely, or haveing given such Bonds have neverthelesse
gone with their Shipps to Ireland, By which meanes (although this Kingdome hath and doth dayly suffer a great
prejudice by the transporting great numbers of the people thereof to the said Plantations for the peopleing of
them) yet that the Trade of them would thereby in a great measure be diverted from hence, and carryed elsewhere,
his Majestyes Customes and other Revenues much lessened, and this Kingdome not continue a Staple of the said
Co&bhooov;modities of the said Plantations, nor that vent for the future of the Vi&bholigct;tuall and other native Commodities of
this Kingdome; Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed, and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the word Ireland
shall from and after the twenty fowerth day of May in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred and
seaventy one be left out of all such Bonds, which shall be taken for any Shipp or Vessell which shall sett saile
out of, or from England, Ireland, Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede for any English Plantation in America,
Asia or Africa; And that in case the said Shipp or Vessell shall lode any of the said Commodities at any of
the said English Plantations, That the said Commodities shall be by the said Shipp or Vessell brought to some
Port of England or Wales, or to the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede, and shall, there unlode and putt on shore
the same (the danger of the Seas onely excepted) and in like manner for all Shipps comeing from any other
port or place to any of the aforesaid Plantations, who by the aforesaid A&bholigct; for encouraging and encrease of
Shipping are permitted to trade there; That from and after the nine and twentyeth day of September in the
yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred seaventy and one the Governour of such English Plantations shall
before such Shipp or Vessell be permitted to lode on board any of the said Commodities take Bond in manner,
and to the value mentioned and dire&bholigct;ed in the above mentioned A&bholigct; for the encourageing and encrease of
Shipping and Navigation for each respective Shipp or Vessell, That such Shipp or Vessell shall carry all the
aforesaid Goods that be laden on board in the said Shipp to some other of his Majestyes English Plantations, or
to England, Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede, And that every such Shipp or Vessell which from and
after the said nine and. twentyeth day of September In the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred seaventy
and one shall lode, or take on board any of the said Commodities, untill such Bond given to such Governour,
or Certificate produced from the Officers of some Custome house of England, Wales or of the Towne of Berwicke
that such Bond hath beene there duely given, or which contrary to the Tenour of such Bond shall carry the





said Goods to any Land, Island, Territory, Dominion, Port or Place whatsoever, other then to such other English
Plantations as doe belong to his Majestie his Heires and Successors, or to the Kingdome of England, Principality
of Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede, and there lay the same on shore, That every such Shipp or
Vessell shall be forfeited with all her Guns, Tackle, Apparell, Ammunition, Furniture and Ladeing, the one moyety
to the Kings Majestie, his Heires and Successors, and the other moyety to him or them that shall seize and sue
for the same in any of the said Plantations, in the Court of the High Admirall of England, or of any of his
Vice-admiralls, or in any Court of Record in England, wherein noe Essoyne, Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager at Law shall
be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Governors of American Plantations to return yearly to Customhouse in London a List of all Ships lading any Commodities therein, and also a List of Bonds taken.</head>
			<para id="p12">
				<emph type="i">Ships unlading Sugar, &amp;c. in any Port except in England, to be forfeited.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p13">And whereas many complaints have beene made of shipping and Vessells belonging to some of his Majestyes
Collonies in America that contrary to the intent and meaneing of this and other aforementioned Lawes they have
brought and transported the said Commodities to diverse parts of Europe and there unloded the same, Bee it
further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the Governours or other Commanders in Cheife of his Majestyes
respe&bholigct;ive Plantations doe once a yeare at least make a Returne to his Majestyes Officers of his Customes in the
Port of London, or to such other person or persons as his Majestie shall appoint to receive the same a List of
all such Shipps or Vessells as shall lade any of the said Co&bhooov;odities in such Plantations respe&bholigct;ively; as alsoe a List
of all the Bonds taken by them; And in case any Shipp or Vessell belonging to any of his Majestyes Plantations,
which shall have on board her any Sugars, Tobacco, Cotten Woole, Indicoes, Ginger Fusticke or. other dying
wood shall be found to have unladed in any port or place of Europe other then England, Wales, or the Towne of
Berwicke upon Tweede, That such Shipp or Vessell shall be forfeited with all her Guns, Tackell, Apparell,
Ammunition, Furniture and ladeing to be recovered and divided as aforesaid. And that it shall and may be lawfull
for any person or persons to prosecute such Shipp or Vessell in any Court of Admiralty in England, the one moyety
of the forfeiture in case of condemnation to be to his Majestie his heires and successors, and the other moyety to
such prosecutor or prosecutors thereof.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Tangier not a Plantation within the Meaning of this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p14">And lastly it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed, and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That Tangier shall not be
deemed or taken to be a Plantation to his Majestie belonging in Asia, Africa or America within the intent or
meaneing of this A&bholigct;, or any of the aforementioned A&bholigct;s soe as to enjoy any right, priviledge or benefitt of
tradeing to, or from the said Plantations or any of them, Any Law, A&bholigct;, Usage or Declaration to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That this A&bholigct; shall continue in force for nine yeares, and from thence to
the end of the next Session of Parlyament and noe longer.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Witnesses <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


