<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47447" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXV. An Act for the better preservation of the Game, and for secureing Warrens not inclosed, and the severall Fishings
of this Realme.[Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23 C. II. p. 2. nu. 13.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that disorderly Persons steal Game, &amp;c.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Lords of Manors not under the Degree of Esquires may appoint Gamekeepers. What such Game- keepers may seize.; Power to Game-keepers to search Houses, &amp;c.; for Guns, &amp;c. and the same to seize and detain.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas diverse disorderly persons laying aside their lawfull Trades and Imployments doe betake themselves
to the stealing, takeing and killing of Conies, Hares, Pheasants, Partridges and other Game, intended to
be preserved by former Lawes, with Guns, Dogs, Tramells, Lowbells, Hayes, and other Netts, Snares, Hare-pipes
and other Engines, to the great dammage of this Realme, and prejudice of Noblemen, Gentlemen and Lords of
Mannours and others Owners of Warrens; For remedy thereof Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent
Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this
present Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That all Lords of Mannours or other Royaltyes
not under the degree of an Esquire may from henceforth by Writeing under their Hands and Seales authorize
one or more Game-keeper or Game-keepers within their respective Mannours or Royalties, who being thereunto
soe authorized may take and seize all such Gunns, Bowes, Grayhounds, Setting-dogs, Lurchers or other Dogs
to kill Hares or Conies, Ferretts, Tramells, Lowbells, Hayes or other Netts, Harepipes, Snares or other Engines
for the takeing and killing of Conyes, Hares, Pheasants Partridges or other Game as within the precincts of such
respe&bholigct;ive Mannours shall be used by any person or persons, who by this A&bholigct; are prohibited to keepe or use
the same. And moreover That the said Game-keeper or Game-keepers or any other person or persons (being
thereunto authorized by Warrant under the Hand and Seale of any Justice of the Peace of the same County
Division or Place) may in the day time search the Houses Outhouses or other places of any such person or
persons by this A&bholigct; prohibited to keepe or use the same, as upon good ground shall be suspe&bholigct;ed to have or
keepe in his or their Custody any Guns, Bowes, Grey hounds Setting-dogs, Ferretts, Cony dogs or other Dogs
to destroy Hares or Conyes, Hayes, Tramells or other Netts, Lowbells, [Hare pipes<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Snares or other Engines
aforesaid, and the same and every or any of them to seize, detaine and keepe, to and for the use of the Lord
of the Mannour or Royalty where the same shall be soe found or taken, or otherwise to cutt in pieces or destroy
as things by this A&bholigct; prohibited to be kept by persons of their degree.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. What Persons are prohibited the keeping of Guns, Bows, Dogs, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That all and every person and persons, not haveing Lands and
Tenements or some other Estate of Inheritance in his owne or his Wifes right of the cleare yearely value of one
hundred pounds per ann? or for terme of life, or haveing Lease or Leases of ninety nine yeares or for any
longer terme, of the cleare yearely value of one hundred and fifty pounds, other then the Sonne and Heire
apparent of an Esquire, or other person of higher degree, and the Owners and Keepers of Forrests, Parks,
Chases or Warrens, being stocked with Deere or Conies for their necessary use in respe&bholigct; of the said Forrests,
Parks, Chases or Warrens, are hereby declared to be persons by the Lawes of this Realme, not allowed to have
or keepe for themselves or any other person or persons any Guns, Bowes, Grey hounds, Setting-dogs, Ferretts,
Cony-doggs, Lurchers, Hayes, Netts, Lowbells, Hare-pipes, Ginns, Snares or other Engines aforesaid, But shall
be, and are hereby prohibited to have, keepe or use the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Recital that Warrens and Grounds not inclosed are used for breeding Conies, and that disorderly Persons destroy such conies.</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">Entering wrong-fully into such Warrens a or Grounds; Penalty and Punishment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p5">And forasmuch as diverse Warrens and Grounds not inclosed are used for the breeding and keepeing of
Conyes in severall parts of this Kingdome, and that sundry desolute and disorderly persons have beene much
incouraged to kill and destroy the Conies in such Warrens and Grounds not enclosed, in the night time, for that
the same is not prohibited or punishable by the Statutes in that behalfe made and provided, which extend onely
to the stealing and killing of Conies in Warrens or Grounds enclosed, For remedy thereof Bee it enacted and
declared That if any person or persons shall at any time enter wrongfully into any Warren or Ground lawfully
used or kept for the breeding or keeping of Conyes (although the same be not enclosed) and there shall chase,
take or kill any Conyes against the will of the Owner or Occupier thereof, not haveing lawfull Title or Authority
soe to doe, and shall be thereof lawfully convi&bholigct;ed in manner hereafter following, the parties soe offending shall
yeild to the party grieved treble damages and costs, and suffer Imprisonment by the space of three moneths, and
after till they shall finde Suretyes for their good abeareing.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">Persons killing Conies in the Night on the Borders of Warrens, except the Owner of the Ground; Satisfa&bholigct;ion and Penalty; and on Non-payment of Penalty, and not making Satisfa&bholigct;ion, Imprisonment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">And forasmuch as diverse idle and disorderly persons liveing neere unto Warrens have of late time used to
kill and take the Conies upon the borders of the same, and under colour thereof doe of time enter into the said
Warrens and there take and kill Conyes in the night time when they cannot easily be discovered. It is further
provided and ena&bholigct;ed That noe person or persons shall at any time hereafter kill or take in the night time any
Conyes upon the borders of any Warrens or other Grounds lawfully used for the breeding or keeping of Conies
excepting onely such person or persons as shall be Owner of the Soile, or lawfull Occupier or Possessor of the
Ground, or any person or persons imployed by him, her or them, whereupon such Conyes shall be soe killed
or taken, upon paine that every person soe offending and being thereof lawfully convi&bholigct;ed in manner hereafter
following, shall give the party or partyes injured such recompence or satisfa&bholigct;ion for his or their damages, and
within such time as shall be appointed by the Justice, before whome such Offender shall be convi&bholigct;ed, and over
and above pay downe presently [un<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to the Overseers for the use of the Poore of the Parish where such Offence
shall be committed such summe of money not exceeding ten shillings as the said Justice shall thinke meete,
And if such offender or offenders doe not make recompence or satisfa&bholigct;ion to the said party or partyes injured,
and alsoe pay the said summe to the Poore in manner and forme aforesaid, then the said Justice shall committ
the said offender or offenders to the house of Corre&bholigct;ion for such time as the said Justice shall thinke fitt,
not exceeding [one<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] moneth,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Setting, &amp;c. Snares for Hares, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p9">And whereas diverse idle and disorderly persons have of late time taken up a pra&bholigct;ice to take and kill Hares
and Conyes with Snares, Harepipes (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) and other Engines in or neere Woods, Warrens and other places, It is
hereby further ena&bholigct;ed, and declared by the authority aforesaid That if any person or persons from and after the
first .day of May which shall be in the yeare of our Lord (<ref idref="n4">4</ref>) One thousand six hundred seaventy and one shall
be found or apprehended setting or useing any Snares, Harepipes or other like Engines, and shall be thereof
convicted in manner following, The person or persons soe offending shall be lyable to the penalties in the
immediate foregoeing Clause of this A&bholigct; in manner as aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Fishing in the Pond of any Person without his Consent with Nets or other Engines.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Limitation of Prosecution; Satisfa&bholigct;ion and Penalty.; to be levied by Distress.; If no Distress, Imprisonment, or Security not to offend again.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p11">And whereas diverse idle, disorderly, and meane persons doe from time to time betake themselves to the
stealing, takeing and killing of Fish out of Ponds, Pooles, Motes Stewes and other severall Waters and Rivers
to the great damage of the Owners thereof, Bee it therefore further ena&bholigct;ed by the authorise aforesaid That if
any person or persons from and after the first day of May which shall be in the yeare of our Lord God One
thousand six hundred seaventy and one shall at any time use any Casting nett, Theife nett, Dragg nett, Tramell,
Shove-nett or other Nett whatsoever, or any Angle, Haire, Noose, Troll or Speare, or shall lay any Waers,
Potts, Nets, Fish-hoodkes or other Engines, or shall take any Fish by any meanes or devise whatsoever in any
River, Stew, Pond, Mote, or other Water as aforesaid, or shall be aiding or assisting thereunto without the
Licence or Consent of the Lord or Owner of the said Water, and be thereof, or of any other the, Offence or
Offences mentioned in this A&bholigct; convi&bholigct;, by Confession of the Offender, or by Oath of one sufficient Witnesse,
within one moneth, after the Offence committed before any Justice of the Peace of such County, Rideing, Division
or Place wherein such Offence as aforesaid, shall be committed; which Oath the said Justice of Peace is hereby
impowered to administer, Every such Offender or Offenders in stealing, takeing or killing Fish, shall for every
such Offence give to the party or partyes injured such recompence or satisfa&bholigct;ion for his or their damages and
within such time as the said Justice shall appoint, not exceeding treble dammages, and over and above pay downe
presently unto the Overseers for the use of the Poore, where the said Offence shall be com&bhooov;itted such summe of
money not exceeding ten shillings as the said Justice shall thinke meete. And in default of payment as aforesaid
the. same to be leavyed by Distresse and Sale of the Offenders Goods, by Warrant under Hand and Scale
of such Justice, before whome the Offender shall be convi&bholigct;ed, rendring the Overplus if any be, And for want
of Distresse the Offender or Offenders shall be committed to the House of Corre&bholigct;ion for such time as the Justice
shall thinke fitt, not exceeding one moneth, unlesse the party offending shall enter into Bond with one
competent Surety or Suretyes to the party injured, not exceeding the summe of ten pounds never to offend in
like manner.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Justice of the Peace convicting Offender may cut the Nets, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p12">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That it shall and may be lawfull for every Justice of Peace, before whome such
Offender as aforesaid shall be convi&bholigct;, to take, cutt in pieces, and destroy all and every such Angles, Speares,
Hares, Nooses, Trolls, Wears, Potts, Fish-hookes, Netts or other Engines whatsoever, wherewith such Offender as
aforesaid shall be taken or apprehended.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Appeal to Quarter Sessions;</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">Judgment thereon final, unless Title to Land, &amp;c. concerned.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p14">[Provided alwayes and bee it [further<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] enacted by the authority aforesaid That if any [any<ref idref="n5">5</ref>] person or persons
shall finde him or themselves agrieved by any Judgement, which shall happen to be given by any Justice of the
Peace by vertue of this A&bholigct;, it shall and may be lawfull for such person or persons soe agrieved to appeale
unto the Justices of Peace in their Generall Quarter Sessions which shall happen to be held next after such
Judgement given, Who, or the greater number of them are hereby authorized and impowered to give such
Releife, and make such Order therein as shall be agreable to the Tenor of this A&bholigct; And such Judgement,
Order or Determination, as by the said Justices shall be made upon the said Appeale shall be finall to all
intents and purposes whatsoever, if noe Title to any Land, Royalty or Fishery be therein concerned.<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Proviso for Royalties and Prerogatives to His Majesty; and for the Forest Laws.</head>
			<para id="p15">[Provided alwayes [and be it further ena&bholigct;ed<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] That neither this A&bholigct;, nor any thing therein contained shall extend,
or be construed to extend to the takeing away or abridgeing of any Royalty or Prerogative Royall of his Majestie,
nor to abridge, change or alter any part of the Forrest Lawes of this Realme, but all and every such Lawes,
Rights, Powers, Royaltyes and Prerogatives Royall shall remaine and be in as full and ample force and vertue as
the same ought to have beene in, if this A&bholigct; had not beene made. Any thing herein before contained to the
contrary notwithstanding.<ref idref="n6">6</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">Harepipes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">God <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Sehedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


