<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47444" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter; XXII. An Act for the better and more certaine Recovery of Fines and Forfeitures due to his Majestie.[Rot. Parl. 22 &amp; 23. C. II p.2. nu. 10.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of ancient Statutes as to Estreats of Fines, and that Abuses had arisen in respe&bholigct; thereof.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">All Fines, Post Fines, Issues, and other Sums of Money forfeited in the K.B., C. P., or Exchequer, to be certified twice every Year into the Exchequer; from the beginning of Hilary Term to the beginning of Trinity Term; from the beginning of Trinity Term, to, the beginning, of Hilary Term.; Penalty &pound;50</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by diverse Statutes in old time made, it was provided That the Estreats of Fines, Issues,
Amerciaments and other Forfeitures should be certified and delivered into the Exchequer yearely, and
that from thence the Estreates of the Summons should goe forth through all Shires for leavying thereof, Since
the makeing of which Lawes many are [the<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] abuses and mischeifes arisen and pra&bholigct;ised, not onely by the not timely
certifying and estreating the said Fines and Forfeitures, but alsoe by the sinister pra&bholigct;ice, amongst Officers in
spareing, dischargeing and not certifying at all, or if they doe certifie, yet by miscertifying and estreating the said
Fines and Forfeitures, in, and into the said Court of Exchequer. For remedy whereof, and mischeifes of like
kinde Bee it ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the Kings most excellent Majestie, by and with the advice and consent
of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in Parlyament assembled, and by the authoritie of the
same That from henceforth all Fines, Post Fines, Issues, Amerciaments forfeited, Recognizances, Summe and
Summes of Money paid, or to be paid in liew or satisfa&bholigct;ion of them or any of them, and all other Forfeitures
whatsoever which already are, or hereafter shall be sett, imposed, lost or forfeited in his Majestyes Courts of
Kings Bench, Common Bench or Exchequer, shall be certifyed and estreated in, and into the said Court of
Exchequer twice in every yeare yearely (that is to say) All Fines, Post-Fines, Issues, Amerciaments forfeited,
Recognizances, Summe and Summes of money paid, or to be paid in liew or satisfa&bholigct;ion of them or any of them,
and all other Forfeitures whatsoever ariseing in any of the said Courts from the begining of every Hillary Terme
in every yeare to the begining of every Trinity Terme in every yeare, shall be, and are hereby ordained to
be certyfyed and estreated in, and into the said Court of Exchequer the last day of every Trinity Terme in
every yeare. And all Fines, Post Fines, Issues, Amerciaments forfeited, Recognizances, Summe and Summes of
Money paid, and to be paid in liew or satisfaction of them or any of them, and all other Forfeitures whatsoever
ariseing in any of the said Courts from the begining of every Trinity Terme in every yeare to the begining of
every Hillary Terme in every yeare shall be in like manner certifyed and estreated in and into the said Court of
Exchequer the said last day of every Hillary Terme in every yeare on paine that every Officer and Minister, of,
or belonging to the said Courts or any of them, to whome it doth, ought, or shall belong or appertaine, to
make Certificate, or Estreate of any of the said Fines or Forfeitures, makeing defaulte, or offending [therein,<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] to
forfeite and pay fifty pounds for every such defaulte or failer that shall be made in certifying and estreating as
aforesaid; The one moyety to the use of his Majesty his Heires and Successors, and the other moyety to such
person or persons that shall or will sue for the same in any Court of Record by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill or
Information wherein hoe Wager of Law, Essoine or Prote&bholigct;ion shall be allowed.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Proviso for the Course now used in certifying, &amp;c. Issues from C. P., &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p3">Provided alwayes That noe thing in this A&bholigct; contained shall alter or change the course now used in the certifying
and estreating of Issues from the said Court of Common Bench, nor of Fines Pro licentia concordandi, co&bhooov;monly
called Post Fines, being Termly certifyed and estreated into the said Court of Exchequer, nor the Termly estreating
of Issues certifyed out of the Office of Pleas belonging to the said Court of Exchequer to the Clerke of the
Estreats there.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. All Fines, &amp;c. before Judges of Assize, &amp;c. from Michaelmas to Easter, to be in like Manner certified,</head>
			<para id="p4">
				<emph type="i">before Trinity Term; From Easter to Michaelmas.; before Hilary Term.; Penalty &pound;50.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the authority aforesaid That all Fines, Issues, Amerciaments forfeited,
Recognizances, Summe and Summes of Money paid or to be paid in liew or satisfa&bholigct;ion of them or any of them,
and all other Forfeitures whatsoever which already are or hereafter shall be sett, imposed, lost or forfeited by or
before any Judge or Judges of Assize, Clerke of the Market, or Co&bhooov;mis[sion]ers of Sewers throughout the Kingdome
of England, shall be, and are hereby ordained to be certifyed and estreated into the said Court of Exchequer
twice in every yeare yearely (that is to say) all Fines, Issues, Amerciaments forfeited, Recognizances, Summe
and Summes of Money paid or to be paid in liew or satisfaction of them, or any of them, ariseing or
happening in any of the said Courts last mentioned, or before any Judge or Judges of the same from the
Feast of Saint Michaell the Arch Angell in every yeare, to the Feast of Easter in every yeare shall be certifyed
and estreated in, and into the said Court of Exchequer, before the first day of Trinity Terme in every yeare;
And all Fines, Issues, Amerciaments forfeited, Recognizances, Summe and Summes of Money paid, or to be
paid in liew or satisfa&bholigct;ion of them or any of them, ariseing or happening in any of the said Courts last mentioned,
from the said Feast of Easter in every yeare to the said Feast of Saint Michaell the Arch Angell in every yeare
shall be certifyed and estreated into the said Court of Exchequer before the first day of Hillary Terme in every
yeare, on paine that every such person and persons, to whome it doth, ought, or shall belong or appertaine, to make
Certificate; or Estreates of the said Fines or Forfeitures makeing defaulte herein, to forfeite and pay fifty pounds
for every such default or failer, that shall be made in certifying and estreating as aforesaid, the one moyety to the
use of his Majestie his Heires and Successors, and the other moyety to such person or persons that shall or will
sue for the same in any Court of Record, by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill or Informacion wherein noe Wager of Law,
Essoine or Prote&bholigct;ion shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Clerks of the Peace and Town Clerks to deliver to Sheriff a Schedule of Fines, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p6">
				<emph type="i">And return a Duplicate of such Schedules into the Exchequer.; Penalty &pound;50.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p7">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the authority aforesaid That all and every the Clerke and Clerkes
of the Peace and all Towne Clerks and every of them within the Kingdome of England doe, and shall make and
deliver to the Sheriffe or Sheriffes of the County, City or Towne-Corporate where the Sessions of the Peace is or shall
be kept within twenty dayes after the nine and twentyeth day of September in every yeare yearely, a true or perfect
Estreate or Shedule of all Fines, Issues, Amerciaments forfeited, Recognizances, Summe and Summes of Money, and other
Forfeitures whatsoever that are, or shall happen to be imposed, sett, lost or forfeited in any of the said Sessions of the
Peace respe&bholigct;ively, which shall be held before Michaelmas by or upon any person or persons whatsoever due to his
Majesty. And also doe and shall [yearely and every<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] yeare on or before the second Monday after the morrow of All
Souls make and deliver into the said Court of Exchequer a true and perfe&bholigct; Duplicate Certificate and Estreate of all
such Estreats and Schedules soe delivered to the respective Sheriffes [as<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] aforesaid, that soe the respe&bholigct;ive Sheriffes
on their Apposalls in the said Court of Exchequer may be charged with the moneys leavyed and received by him
or them respe&bholigct;ively, upon such Schedules delivered as aforesaid, on paine that every such person and persons
offending herein for every such defaulte or failer made to forfeite and pay fifty pounds, the one moyety to the use
of his Majesty his Heires and Successors, and the other moyety to such person or persons that shall or will sue for
the same, to be recovered in any Court of Record by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill, or Information, wherein noe Essoyne,
Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Officers not to withhold or conceal Fines, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p8">
				<emph type="i">nor miscertify, &amp;c. Fines, &amp;c. into the Exchequer; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the authority aforesaid That noe Officer or Minister of or belonging
to any of his Majesties Courts of Kings Bench, Common Bench, or Exchequer, nor any Clerke of Assize, Clerke
of the Peace, Towne-Clerke, nor any Officer or Minister under them or any of them, nor other person or persons
whatsoever doe, or shall spare, take of, discharge, or wittingly or willingly conceale any Indi&bholigct;ment, Fine, Post fine,
Issue, Amerciament forfeited, Recognizance, or other Forfeiture whatsoever exhibited, sett, imposed, lost or forfeited,
[or to be exhibited sett imposed lost or forfeited<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] in any of the said Courts before mentioned of before any Judge
or Judges of or belonging to the same, or any Summe or Summes of money paid or to be paid to any Officer
or Officers in liew or satisfa&bholigct;ion of any Fine or Forfeiture, unlesse it be by Rule or Order in Court where such
Indi&bholigct;ment, Fine, Post fine, Issue, Amerciament forfeited, Recognizance or other Forfeiture is or shall be exhibited,
sett, imposed, lost or forfeited; Nor shall any of the said Officers or Ministers aforesaid or any of them, [or <ref idref="n4">4</ref>] any
other wittingly or willingly miscertifie or estreate in, or into the said Court of Exchequer any Fine, Post fine,
Issue, Amerciament forfeited, Recognizance or other Forfeiture whatsoever whereby the Processe of the said Court
of Exchequer for the leavying of the same may be made invalid and of none effe&bholigct; but every such Officer and
Officers and all and every other person and persons offending herein, shall for every such Offence forfeite and
pay treble the value of such Fine, Post fine, Issue, Amerciament forfeited, Recognizance, Summe and Summes of
money and other Forfeiture soe spared, taken of, discharged, concealed, not certifyed or estreated, or miscertifyed
or estreated as aforesaid; the one moyety thereof to the use and behoofe of his Majestie his Heires and Successors,
and the other moyety to such person or persons as shall or will sue for the same in any Court of Record, by A&bholigct;ion
of Debt, Bill or Information wherein noe Wager of Law, Essoigne or Prote&bholigct;ion shall be allowed. And alsoe shall
lose his and their Office and Place and be for ever incapeable to be imployed in any Office or Place where any part
of his Majestyes Revenue is to be managed or paid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Upon all Certificates, &amp;c. of Fines. &amp;c. into the Exchequer, the Summons of Green Wax to go forth for the levying of the same.</head>
			<para id="p10">And lastly Bee it ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the authority aforesaid That where any Fine or Fines Summe or Summes
of money or other Forfeitures due to his Majestie his Heires or Successors shall from henceforth at any time or times
be paid to any Sheriffe, Clerke of Assize, Clerke of the Peace or other Officer or Minister whatsoever, belonging to
any Court or Courts, and be according to the intent and dire&bholigct;ions of this A&bholigct; certifyed and estreated, in or into
the said Court of Exchequer, there and in such case the Summons or Processe of the Greene wax shall goe forth,
and be awarded to the respe&bholigct;ive Sheriffes against such Officer and Officers and other persons, to whome such Fine
or Fines, Summe or Summes of Money or other Forfeiture is or shall be soe paid for the leavying and receiveing of
the same, That soe it may appeare, when, to whome, and how such moneys are received, answered and paid to his
Majestie his Heires and Successors, Any Custome or Usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Proviso for Rights and Liberties.</head>
			<para id="p11">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That nothing in this A&bholigct; contained shall in any
sort extend, or be construed to extend to the prejudiceing of the Rights and Priviledges of any Bodyes Politique or
Corporate or their Successors, or of any Lord or Lords of any Mannour, Liberty, or Franchise whatsoever, Any thing
herein to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for the City of London.</head>
			<para id="p12">[Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That nothing in this A&bholigct; contained shall extend
to, or be any wayes prejudiciall to the Rights, Customes, Priviledges, Liberties, Charter or Charters of the City of
London, But that the said City may enjoy the same accordingly as they formerly have enjoyed the same in all respe&bholigct;s
and to all intents and purposes whatsoever in the same manner and forme as they before this A&bholigct; had enjoyed the
same, Any thing herein contained to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.<ref idref="n5">5</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Continuance of A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p13">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That this A&bholigct; shall continue for three yeares, and from thence
untill the end of the next Session of Parlyament, and noe longer.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">herein <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">nor <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


