<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47449" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXVII. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) An Act for explaining of a Proviso conteyned in an A&bholigct;, entituled An A&bholigct; for setling the Profitts of y<emph type="p">e</emph> Post-Office
and Power of granteing Wine-Licences on His Royall Highnes y<emph type="p">e</emph> Duke of Yorke and the Heyres Males of his
Body.[O. nu. 44.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 15 C. II. c. 14. &sect; 4.; and that it was intended that the Sums therein mentioned should be paid yearly, and had been accordingly answered; and yet Doubt was made whether the same could be charged as a continuing yearly Payment; and whether any Grant thereof by the King could be good during the Estate Tail.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The said Power declared to be a Power of charging the Profits of the Post Office with the said annual Payment, and that all former Grants thereof should be good against the Duke, &amp;c.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in and by an A&bholigct; of Parliament passed in the fifteenth yeare of His Majesties Raigne entituled,
An A&bholigct; for settling the Profitts of the Post Office, and Power of granting Wine Licences on His Royall
Highnesse the Duke of Yorke, and the Heyres Males of his Body : It is amongst other things ena&bholigct;ed, That all the
Yearely Rents, S&bhouov;me or S&bhouov;mes of Money, Revenues, Issues, and Profitts whatsoever, that shall grow due, accrew,
or be payable unto His Majesty his Heyres or Successors, for, or by reason of the Generall Letter Office, or Post
Office, or Office of Postmaster Generall or annexed, incident, or belonging to the said Post-Office, or Generall
Letter-Office, or Office of Postmaster Generall, or issueing out [of<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] the same, or accrewing or growing due for,
or by reason of the same, should be, and thereby were vested and settled upon James Duke of Yorke, and the
Heyres Males of his Body begotten, or to be begotten, Neverthelesse with, and under this Provisoe, That it should
and might be lawfull, for the Kings Majesty, his Heyres and Successors, at any time or times dureing the said
Estate-Taile, by Warrant under his Privy Scale, to charge any S&bhouov;me or severall S&bhouov;mes of Money, not exceeding
in the whole the S&bhouov;me of Five thousand, three hundred fourscore and two Pounds ten shillings, to be paid out
of the Profitts of the Office of Postmaster Generall, to the which said S&bhouov;me of Five thousand three hundred
[fourescore<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and two Pounds ten shillings, the severall S&bhouov;mes and Payments then already charged thereupon,
did in the whole amount (The Grant of which S&bhouov;mes were not to be avoided by the said A&bholigct;) and which said
S&bhouov;mes of Money, not exceeding the said S&bhouov;me of Five thousand three hundred fourescore and two Pounds ten
shillings, to be granted by His Majesty, as aforesaid, were and should be by Authority of the said A&bholigct; confirmed,
and made in full force, as in and by the said A&bholigct; more at large appeares. And whereas it was intended, that
the S&bhouov;mes of Money soe as aforesaid to be charged, should be annually paid though not soe expressed in the
said Act, and the S&bhouov;mes of Money charged upon the Profitts of the said Office, at the time of the making the
said Act, were made payable yearly, and have been ever since accordingly answered, and yet neverthelesse some
doubt is made, whither the said S&bhouov;me of Five thousand three hundred fourscore and two Pounds ten Shillings
can, or may be charged upon the Profitts of the said Office of Postmaster-Generall, as a continuing yearly payment,
					
and whither any Disposition Grant, or Assignement thereof, or of any part thereof heretofore made by His Majesty,
can or may be good, and effectuall in Law, against the said James Duke of Yorke, and the Heyres Males of his Body,
dureing the said Estate-Tayle by reason of the doubtfull penning of the said A&bholigct;, Bee it therefore declared, and
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majesty, by and with the Advice, and Consent of the Lords Spirituall, and
Temporall and of the C&bhooov;mons in this present Parliament assembled, and by the Authority of the same, That the
said Summe of Five thousand three hundred fourescore and two Pounds ten Shillings in, and by the said A&bholigct;
allowed, to be charged upon the Profitts of the said Office, and the Power thereby given His Majestie, for charging
the same is, and at the time of the said A&bholigct; was intended, and soe for ever hereafter shalbe construed, and
taken to be a Power of charging the Profitts of the said Office, with the annuall and perpectuall paym<emph type="p">t</emph>.of
Five thousand three hundred fourscore and two Pounds ten Shillings a yeare, And that all former Grants,
Dispositions, or Assignements thereof, or of any part thereof, shalbe good and effe&bholigct;uall in Law, against the said
James Duke of Yorke, and the Heyres Males of his Body begotten, and against all and every other person and
persons, claiming by, from or under him them, or any of them, And such Grants Dispositions or Assignements
thereof, or of any part thereof shalbe held, and enjoyed according to the Tenor, Effe&bholigct;, and Purport of the same,
Any Doubt, or Question made, or to be made upon the penning of the said former A&bholigct; to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="s2">
		<head>II. The said Profits not to be charged doubly.</head>
		<para id="p3">Provided alwaies, that nothing in this A&bholigct;, or in any former Grant, Disposition, or Assignem<emph type="p">t</emph> of the said
Sum[m]e of Five thousand three hundred fourescore and two Pounds ten Shillings, or any part thereof contained,
shall extend to charge the Profitts of the said Office doubly, or with any other or greater S&bhouov;mes, then the
annuall and perpetuall payment of Five thousand three hundred fourescore and two Pounds ten Shillings, Any thing
herein, or in any former Grant, made by His Majesty, to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		<para id="p4">ITEM qu&aelig;d&amacr; Petitiones, privatas personas concernentes in se forma A&bholigct;us continentes exhibite fuerunt &bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o
D&bhomtild;o Regi in Parliamento predi&bholigct;o, quar&umacr; tituli subscribuntur.</para>
		<para id="p5">1. An Act to enable Christopher Duke of Albemarle to recovery severall Mannours and Lands mortgaged to
George late Duke of Albemarle his father.</para>
		<para id="p6">2. An Act to enable the Guardians of Charles Earle of Shrewsbury and John Talbot Esquire Infants to dispose
of certaine Mannours Lands and Tenements for the benefitt of the said Infants.</para>
		<para id="p7">3. An Act for confirmeing Agreements betweene the Lord Viscount of Stafford and his Lady, and their
customary Tenants and Copy-holders.</para>
		<para id="p8">4. An Act to enable the makeing Conveyances of part of the Estate of James Lord Norreys dureing his
Minority.</para>
		<para id="p9">5. An Act to enable Robert Lord Bishop of Bangor, and Isaac Lord Bishop of Saint Asaph, and their
respective successors for ever, to lett for one and twenty yeares all Leade-Mines in their soyle.</para>
		<para id="p10">6. An Act for impowering the executors and trustees of Henry late Lord Ingram, Viscount Irwin in the
Kingdome of Scotland deceased to sell certaine Lands for the payment of debts and legacies.</para>
		<para id="p11">7. An Act for granting to Sir Philip Howard and Francis Watson Esquire the sole use of a manufa&bholigct;ure, art
or invention for the benefit of shipping.</para>
		<para id="p12">8. An Act to enable Francis Courtney Esquire to joyne with Sir William Courtney his father in a conveyance
for setleing their estate.</para>
		<para id="p13">9. An Act for the better payment of the debts of Sir Clifford Knight deceased, and raiseing portions for
his daughters.</para>
		<para id="p14">10. An Act for setleing an Agreement betweene Sir William Smith and Sir Thomas Hooke Baronets, German
Poole and others.</para>
		<para id="p15">11. An Act to enable the Daughters and Co-heires of Sir John Fitz-James to joyne in a sale of Lands for
payment of his debts.</para>
		<para id="p16">12. An Act for the better explanation of an A&bholigct; made in this present Parlyament, entituled An A&bholigct;: for the
makeing of the Church ere&bholigct;ed at Falmouth a Parish-Church, and noe part of the parish of Gluvias, or Chapelry
of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Budocke.</para>
		<para id="p17">13. An Act to enable Elizabeth, Mary and Letitia Hammond to sell certaine Lands in the Bill mentioned.</para>
		<para id="p18">14. An Act for the re&bholigct;ifying a mistake of Dates of Deeds mentioned in an A&bholigct; [of Parliament<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] entituled, An
A&bholigct; to enable John Bill Esquire to sell certaine Lands in Kent, and Surrey.</para>
		<para id="p19">15. An Act for an exchange and sale of Lands for payment of the debts of Benedi&bholigct; Hall Esquire.</para>
		<para id="p20">16. An Act for [the<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] setleing the Mannour of Portswood and other Lands late of John Knight Gent. in the
county, and towne and county of Southampton, in John Parker Sergeant at law, M<emph type="p">r</emph> William Morgan, and William
Blennerhasset of London Gent., to be sold for payment of debts.</para>
		<para id="p21">17. An Act for vesting and setleing the fee simple of certaine Lands of his Majestie his heires and successors
which have beene taken into, and spoiled, by makeing new fortifications about the towne of Portsmouth.</para>
		<para id="p22">18. An Act for explaining [of<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] aprovisoe contained in an A&bholigct;, entituled An A&bholigct; for setleing the proffitts of the
Post-Office, and power of granting Wine-Licences on his Royall Highnesse the Duke of Yorke, and the heires
males of his body.</para>
		<para id="p23">19. An Act for building Arundell-House, and the Tenements thereunto belonging.</para>
		<para id="p24">20. An Act to enable Charles Howard Esquire and Mary his wife to leavy a fine, and suffer a recovery of
their estate in the Mannour of Darkeing.</para>
		<para id="p25">21. An Act to enable Henry Booth Esquire to leavy Fines, and suffer Recoveries.</para>
		<para id="p26">22. An Act to enable Sir Andrew Hacket Knight to setle a portion of money on Mary Hacke't his daughter.</para>
		<para id="p27">23. An Act for setleing the Mannour of Shabbington for payment of the debts of Sir William Clarke Baronet.</para>
		<para id="p28">24. An Act to enable Trustees to sell the Mannours, Lands and Leases of Sir Thomas Ogle Knight, deceased,
for raiseing a portion, and present maintenance for his daughter and heire, and payment of his debts.</para>
		<para id="p29">25. An Act for improveing the Navigation betweene the Towne of Boston, and the River of Trent.</para>
		<para id="p30">26. An Act for setleing and preserveing the Navigation of the River Wey in the County of Surrey.</para>
		<para id="p31">27. An Act for uniteing the Vicarage and Parsonage of Rosse in the county of Hereford.</para>
		<para id="p32">28. An Act for makeing the Mannour of Parisgarden a Parish and to enable the parishioners of Saint
Saviours Southwarke to raise a maintenance for Ministers, and for repaire of theire Church.</para>
		<para id="p33">29. An Act for sale of part of the Estate of Thomas Herlackenden Esquire, for satisfaction of a debt due to
his Majestie.</para>
		<para id="p34">30. An Act for setleing Lands, intended by John Sams for charitable uses.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">From the Original A&bholigct; in the Parliament Office.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined.</note>
		<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
		<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>


