<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47446" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1670 &amp; 1671</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter XXIV. An Act for vesting certaine Fee-Farme Rents and other small Rents in Trustees.[Rot. Part. 22 &amp; 23 C.II. p.2. nu. 12.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that in pursuance of 22 Car. II. c. 6. by Letters Patent. 13th June, and 11th November, 22 C. II. Certain Rents had been granted to Lord Hawley and others;</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that many small Rents had been left out of the said Letters Patents, which were meant to be conveyed by the said A&bholigct; and that the Collection thereof was very chargeable.; All Rents (Exception) within the Survey; of the Exchequer and Duchy of Lancaster vested in the said Lord Hawley and others, as Trustees, as herein mentioned.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas his Majestie in pursuance of a late A&bholigct; entituled, An A&bholigct; for advanceing the Sale of Fee-Farme Rents and other Rents. hath by severall Letters Patents, one beareing date the thirteenth day of
June in the two and twentyeth yeare of his Raigne, and the other beareing date the eleaventh day of November
in the two and twentyeth yeare of his Raigne)<?bignore?> granted and conveyed diverse Fee-Fanne Rents and other Rents
unto Francis. Lord Hawley, Sir Charles Harbord Knight, Sir William Haward Knight, Sir John Talbot Knight,
Sir Robert Stewart Knight and William Harbord Esquire and their Heires as Trustees for Sale thereof, most of
which Rents are of the yearely value of forty shillings per annu[m] and upwards, And whereas there are yet
remaining very many small Rents left out of the said Letters Patents, which were intended by the said A&bholigct; to
be sold and conveyed away, the collection of which small Rents is very chargeable to his Majesty, and very
troublesome to the Subject by meanes of Under Sheriffes, Bayliffes and Messengers necessarily imployed therein.
And yet if the said small Rents should be conveyed by Letters Patents to Trustees for sale thereof, the said
Letters Patents would be of extraordinary length, and require a multitude of recitalls of many small summes,
which besides the charge in Writeing, would alsoe be an occasion of great hindrance and delay to his Majestyes
Service, Bee it therefore enacted by the Kings most Excellent Majesty by and with the advice and consent of
the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by authoritie thereof
That all Fee-Farme Rents, Rents service, Rents secke, or Dry rents, Chauntry Rents, Guild Rents, Castle-guard
Rents and other Rents within the Survey of the Exchequer or Dutchy of Lancaster, due and payable to his Majestie
his Heires and Successors in Possession, Reversion or Remainder (other then such Rents and Summes of Money
as are specially saved [and excepted<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] out of the said Act) be and are hereby vested and setled in the said Francis
Lord Hawley, Sir Charles Harbord, Sir William Haward, Sir John Talbot, Sir Robert [Steward<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] and William Harbord
and their Heires as fully and absolutely to all intents and purposes whatsoever as if the same had beene perticularly
granted unto them by Letters Patents by vertue of the said Act, and in such manner as is hereby directed in that
behalfe, and the said Rents hereby vested in the said Trustees shall be by them conveyed and disposed according
to the Directions and Instructions mentioned in the said Act to any person or persons Bodyes, Politique or Corporate
who shall desire to purchase the same Rents, or any of them upon a particular or certificate thereof made
by the Auditor or other Officer of Record, before whome the same doe or shall stand in charge respectively;
which Conveyance of the said Trustees and the Survivours and Survivour of them shall be as good and effectuall
in Law to all intents and purposes as if the Rents soe conveyed had beene particularly, imediately and well and
sufficiently granted by his Majesty under the Great Seale of England, or the Seale of the Dutchy or County Palatine
of Lancaster.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. All Purchasers of Fee-Farm Rents to be kept harmless from all Incumbrances made by the Trustees.</head>
			<para id="p3">And, for the better security and satisfaction of the Purchasers of any the said Rents Bee it enacted by the authority
aforesaid That all and every person or persons Bodyes Pollitique and Corporate their Heires, Successors and Assignes,
who have already beene, or hereafter shall become Purchaser or Purchasers of any of the said Rents granted by the
said (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) Letters Patents, or mentioned or intended to be vested in or conveyed by these Presents, to the said Trustees,
shall quietly hold and enjoy the same according to their severall and respective Purchases, and shall be and are hereby
saved and indempnifyed and kept harmelesse of and from all and all manner of Incumbrances whatsoever, heretofore had,
made or done, or hereafter to be had, made or done by the said Trustees or any of them to charge or incumber the said
Rents with any Incumbrances whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. The Receivers General may receive the said, Rents till Sale made.</head>
			<para id="p4">Provided alwayes, and it is the true intent and meaneing of these Presents That untill Sale shall be made of the
[said<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] severall Rents by the Trustees afore mentioned, or the Survivours or Survivour of them their Heires, Executors
or Administrators that the Receiver or Receivers Generall of his Majestyes Revenue shall and may receive, collect and
gather the same and every part thereof as fully to all intents and purposes as if the said Letters Patents or this present
Act had not beene made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Advantages of former A&bholigct; allowed to Purchasers.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Printed Copies of this and the former A&bholigct;, and of the Deed enrolled, to be Evidence.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And lastly bee it enacted That all such persons as shall purchase any of the said Rents by vertue of this Act shall
have and enjoy all the Benefitts and Advantages given or allowed to Purchasers by the said former A&bholigct; and the shewing
of the printed Copyes of this and the said former A&bholigct;, and of the Conveyance made by the said Trustees and enrolled
according to the direction of the said former A&bholigct; shall be sufficient Evidence in any Court of Justice, to entitle the
Purchaser and Purchasers their Heires and Assignes to any Rent by him, her or them purchased and contained in such
Conveyance without, any further Proofe or Evidence in that behalfe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. No Tenant in Tail of the said Rents hereby enabled to bar the Remainder.</head>
			<para id="p7">Provided That noe Tenant in Taile of any the said Rents shall be enabled [by this A&bholigct;<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to suffer any Recovery,
or doe any other Act or Deed to barr the Remainder hereby vested in the said Trustees and their Heires, nor shall,
such Tennant in Taile have any other or greater power over the said Rent then he had before the passing of this A&bholigct;.
Any thing herein before contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. The Trustees duly executing their Authority, discharged against His Majesty, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p8">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the said Trustees and the Survivours and Survivour of them, conveying and
disposeing of the said Rents according to such contracts and agreements as shall be signed by the Lord Treasurer
of England and Chauncellour of the Exchequer or the Lords C&bhooov;mis?ers of His &bhomties; Treasury for the time being
pursuant to the said former or this present A&bholigct;, and the Heires, Executors or Administrators of the said Trustees
shall be, for soe doeing, and are hereby freed and discharged against his Majesty his Heires and, Successors
for ever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. Purchasers may make a general Avowry, &amp;c. by allegling that the Trustees were seized in Fee, &amp;c. and so granted the .same Rents.</head>
			<para id="p9">And bee it further by ena&bholigct;ed by authority aforesaid That every Purchaser of any of the Rents and Premisses by
the intent of this or any former A&bholigct; sold or appointed to be sold their Heires and Assignes, and all person and
persons their Heires Executors Administrators and Assignes claimeing by, from, or under such Purchaser or Purchasers
may sue for, make Avowry, Justification or Conuzance as the case shall require for such Rent or Rents and Premisses
and Arreares thereof, without setting forth how his Majestie or his Progenitors became entituled to such Rents or other
the Premisses, or setting forth or produceing in Court any Letters Patents, or other matter whereby such Rents or
Premisses had commencement, or the said Letters Patents whereby the Premisses were granted, or intended to be
granted to the said Francis Lord Hawley, Sir Charles Harbord, Sir William Haward, Sir John Talbot, Sir Robert
Stewart and William Harbord; But it shall be sufficient in every such Suite Avowry, Conuzance, or Justification where
occasion shall be to sett forth the Title of such Purchaser to declare or alledge that the said Francis Lord Hawley Sir
Charles Harbord, Sir William Haward Sir John Talbot, Sir Robert Stewart and William Harbord were seised in Fee
or in Demesne, as of Fee of such Rent or Premisses in Possession or Reversion, as the case requires, and soe seised,
granted the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Liberty to Trustees to convey by the Words expressed in the Letters Patent, or by Particulars made out by the Auditors, or by Grants from the Crown.</head>
			<para id="p10">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Rights of the Queen.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p11">[Whereas many of the Rents, vested in the said Trustees by the two Patents herein before mentioned, are
either misrecited or not soe fully and particularly expressed, as may be reasonably desired by some Purchasers.
Bee it therefore further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the said Trustees and the Survivour and Survivours
of them, and the Heires of such Survivour shall and may convey the said Rents or any of them to the respective
Purchasers, either by the words expressed in the said Letters Patents, or by Particulars to be made out by the
respective Auditors, or by the originall Grants from the Crowne, whereon those Rents are reserved, as the said
Trustees shall finde most convenient for the satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said Purchasers;<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] [Saveing unto the Queens Majestie
all such Right, Title, Interest, Possession or Estate as her Majestie had, should or might have, or of right ought
to have had in or unto the Rents hereby vested, or any of them as fully and amply as her Majestie should or
might have had before this present A&bholigct;, and as if this A&bholigct; had never beene had or made. Any thing herein before
contained to the contrary notwithstanding.<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Stewart <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">recited <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


