<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47458" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1672</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IX. An Act to enable the County Palatine of Durham to send Knights and Burgesses to serve in Parlyament.[Rot. Parl.25 C.II. nu. 9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital that C. P. of Durham hath not hitherto sent Members to Parliament.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The C. P. of Durham to send Two Knights, and the City of Durham to send Two Burgesses, to Parliament.; How the Elections are to be made, and by whom.; Members to be returned by the Sheriff.; Privileges of the Knights and Burgesses so returned</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas the Inhabitants of the County Palatine of Durham have not hitherto had the liberty and priviledge
of ele&bholigct;ing and sending any Knights and Burgesses to the High Court of Parlyament, although the Inhabitants
of the said County Palatin? are lyable to all Payments, Rates and Subsidies granted by Parlyament equally with
the Inhabitants of other Counties Cities and Burroughes in this Kingdome, who have their Knights and Burgesses
in the Parlyament; and are therefore concerned equally with others the Inhabitants of this Kingdome to have Knights
and Burgesses in the said High Court of Parlyment of their owne ele&bholigct;ion to represent the Condition of their
County as the Inhabitants of other Countryes, Cittyes and Burroughes of this Kingdome have, Wherefore may it
please your Majestie that it may be ena&bholigct;ed and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with
the advice and [consent<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled
and by the authority of the same That from time to time and at all times from and after the end of this present
Session of Parlyament, the said County Palatine of Durham may have two Knights for the same County, and the
City of Durham two Citizens to be Burgesses for the same Citty, for ever hereafter to serve in the High Court
of Parlyament to be ele&bholigct;ed and chosen by vertue of your Majestyes Writt, to be awarded by the Lord Chauncellour
or Lord Keeper of the Great Seale of England for the time being, in that behalfe to the Lord Bishop of Durham,
or his Temporall Chauncellor of the [said<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] County of Durham and a Precept to be thereupon grounded and made
by the Lord Bishop of Durham, or his Temporall Chauncellor for the time being; to the Sheriffe of the said
County for the time being, and the same Ele&bholigct;ion from time to time be made in manner and forme following,
that is to say, the Ele&bholigct;ions of the Knights to serve for the said County Palatine from time to time hereafter to
be made by the greater number of Freeholders of the said County Palatine of Durham which from time shall
be present at such Ele&bholigct;ions accordingly as is used in other Countyes in this your Majesties Kingdome, and
that the Ele&bholigct;ion of the said Burgesses from time to time to serve in the High Court of Parlyament for the City
of Durham to be made from time to time by the major part of the Maior, Aldermen and Freemen of the said
City of Durham which from time to time shall be present at such Ele&bholigct;ions; which said Knights and Burgesses
and every of them soe ele&bholigct;ed and chosen shall be returned by the said Sheriffe into the Chauncery of England
in due forme and upon the like paines as be ordained for the Sheriffe or Sheriffe of any other County of this
Kingdome, to make his or their Returns in the like cases, and that the said Knights and Burgesses and every of
them soe ele&bholigct;ed and returned, shall be by authoritie of this present A&bholigct;, Knights and Burgesses of the High Court
of Parlyament to all intents and purposes, and have and use the like Voice, Authority and Places therein to all
intents and purposes, as any other the Knights and Burgesses of the said High Court of Parlyament have, use and
enjoy, and likewise shall and may by vertue of this present A&bholigct; take, have, use and enjoy all such and the like
Liberties, Advantages, Dignities and Priviledges concerning the said Court of Parlyament to all intents, constru&bholigct;ions
and purposes, as any other the Knights and Burgesses of the said High Court of Parlyament have taken, had, used
or enjoyed, or shall, may or ought hereafter to have, take or enjoy.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">Assent <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		<note id="n2" number="2">interlined on the Roll.</note>
	</section>
</report>


