<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47455" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1672</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VI. An Act; for takeing off Aliens Duty upon Commodities of the Growth, Product and Manufa&bholigct;ure of the Nation. [Rot. Parl. 25 <emph type="i">C. II. nu.</emph> 6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 11 H. VII. c. 14.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">12. C. 4. ? 6. 13 C. II. c. 7.; 12 C. II. c. 4 ? 2.; Part of 11 H. VII. c. 14. 12 C. II. c. 4. and of other A&bholigct;s concerning Customs upon Native Commodities (except Coals) repealed</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas by a Statute made in the eleaventh yeare of King Henry the Seaventh, it is ena&bholigct;ed That all
Merchant-Strangers and others that be made Denizons by the Kings Letters Patents or otherwise shall
pay such Customes and Subsidies for their [Goods and<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Merchandize Inwards and Outwards as they should have
paid if such Letters Patents had never to them beene made. And whereas by one other Statute made in the twelfth
yeare of the Raigne of our Soveraigne Lord the King that now is Intituled A Subsidy granted to the King of
Tonnage and Poundage and other Summes of Money payable upon Merchandices exported and imported; and
afterwards confirmed by an A&bholigct; of Parlyament made in the thirteenth yeare of his said Majestyes Raigne It is
ena&bholigct;ed That every (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) naturall-borne Subject Denizen and Alien shall pay the Summe of Twelve pence for all
manner of Goods or Merchandize to be carryed out of this Realme or to be brought into the same by way
of Merchandize amounting to the value of Twenty shillings according to the Booke of Rates, whereto Reference
is made by the said Statute; and that every Merchant Alien shall pay the Summe of Twelve pence over and above
the Twelve pence aforesaid for all manner of the Native Commodities of this Realme, or Manufa&bholigct;ures wrought of any
such native Commodities of the value of Twenty shillings to be carryed out of this Realme by such Merchants Aliens.
And whereas by another Clause of the said Statute of the twelfth yeare of his Majestyes Raigne that now is It
is ena&bholigct;ed That all Strangers and Aliens shall pay Six shillings and eight pence per Piece for every short Cloath
to be carryed out of this Realme by such Strangers or Aliens. And whereas by the twelfth Article of Rules,
Orders, Dire&bholigct;ions and Allowances annexed to the said Booke of Rates, it is recited, ordered and dire&bholigct;ed That
Merchant Strangers should pay double Petty Custome for Leade, Tynn, Woollen Cloath and for Native Manufa&bholigct;ures
of Wooll or part of Wooll and for all other Goods aswell inwards as outwards rated to pay the Subsidy of
Poundage three pence in the pound and other Dutyes payable by Charta Mercatoria besides the Subsidy, Bee it
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That soe
much and such Clauses onely of the said Statutes of the eleaventh yeare of Henry the Seaventh; and of the
twelfth yeare of our Soveraigne Lord the King that now is, and of the said twelfth Article of Rules, Orders,
Dire&bholigct;ions and Allowances and of Charta Mercatoria therin mentioned, and all other Clauses contained in any other
A&bholigct; or Statutes of this Realme whatsoever as doe any ways concerne any Custome or Subsidie upon any of the
Native Commodityes of this Kingdome (except Coales) or Manufa&bholigct;ures wrought or made in this Kingdome, or
Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede, to be exported out of this Realme, payable by any Merchant, Alien made Denizon,
or other Stranger or Alien, over and above the Custome and Subsidie payable by his Majestyes naturall borne Subje&bholigct;s
and noe more be hereby repealed.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Denizens and Aliens to pay no more on Exportation of Native Commodities than natural born Subjects, except for Coals.</head>
			<para id="p3">And for the further explanation hereof Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That from and after
the first day of May which shall be in the yeare one thousand six hundred and seaventy three every such Merchant,
Denizon, Stranger or Alien shall pay for all Merchandize consisting of any the Native Commodities of this Realme
(except Coales) or Manufa&bholigct;ures wrought or made in the Kingdome of England or Towne of Berwicke upon
Tweede to be carryed out of this Realme by any such Merchant, Denizon Stranger or Alien such Customes and
Subsidies onely and noe other, or greater then Merchants being the Kings naturall borne Subje&bholigct;s doe by vertue
of the said Statute of the twelfth yeare of his Majestie that now is, pay for any Merchandize of the Native Commodityes
of this Realme (except Coales) or Manufa&bholigct;ures wrought or made in this Kingdome, or Towne of Berwicke upon
Tweede to be exported out of this Realme by such naturall-borne Subje&bholigct;s, Any Law, Custome or Statute to the
contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Nor for Fish of English catching and exported in English Shipping.</head>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That from and after the first day of May which shall be
in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred seaventy and three, every Merchant, Denizen or Alien shall
pay for all sorts of Fish caught by English men and exported in English Shipping, and whereof the Master and
three fourths of the Marriners shall be English, such Customes and Subsidies onely and noe greater, or other then
Merchants, being Natives of this Realme doe pay for the same.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Merchant <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


