<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47456" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1672</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act for the incouragement of the Greeneland and Eastland Trades, and for the better secureing the Plantation Trade. [Rot. Parl. 25 C. II. nu. 7.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this Act.</head>
		<para id="p1">Forasmuch as the Whale-fishing is a very considerable and profitable Trade, giveing imployments to great
numbers of Seamen and Shipping; And whereas neighbouring Nations doe yearely make great advantage
thereby, not onely supplying themselves with that sort of Oyle and Finns, but vending into other parts great
quantities thereof and particularly into this Kingdome, where the said Trade is in a manner quite decayed and lost; For
remedy thereof and encouragement of such as shall be willing to employ themselves and their Estates in this Trade
Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That it shall
and may be lawfull for all his Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s of this his Realme of England and Wales and Towne of Berwicke
upon Tweede and for every other person or persons of what Nation soever resideing and inhabiting here dureing
the time of such their Residence freely to trade into and from Greenland and those Seas, and [there<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] to take
Whales and all other sorts of Fish, and to import in this Kingdome all sorts of Oyle, Blubber and Finns thereof,
and to use and exercise all other Trade to and from Greenland and those parts.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Natives and Foreigners may trade to Greenland, and import Oil, &#x0026;c. without paying Duty for such Goods imported by English Ships; if by Shipping of the Colonies, then the several Rates therein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p2">And for the further encourageing of the said Trade Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That it shall be
lawfull for any person or persons Native or Forreigner to importe Train-oyle or Blubber of Greenland and parts
adjacent, and those Seas or of Newfoundland or of any other his Majestyes Colonies and Plantations made of Fish
or of any other Creature liveing in the Seas, and Whale finns caught in any Shipps or Vessells truely and properly
belonging to England or Wales or Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede and imported in such Shipps without paying
any Custome or other Duty for the same;</para>
			<para id="p3">And for the Tunn of such Oyle taken by any Shipping belonging to any of his Majestyes Colonies and Plantations
and imported in such Shipping there shall be paid the summe of six shillings;</para>
			<para id="p4">And for every Tunn of Whale-finns taken and imported in such Shipping the summe of fifty shillings.</para>
			<para id="p5">And for the Tunn of such Oyle taken by the said shipping, but imported in shipping belonging to England
Wales or the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede the summe of three shillings,.</para>
			<para id="p6">And for every Tunn of Whale-fins taken and imported in such shipping the summe of five and twenty shillings,</para>
			<para id="p7">And for the Tunne of all such Oyle and Blubber of Forreigne Fishing the summe of nine pounds,</para>
			<para id="p8">And for every Tunne of Whale-finns of Forreigne Fishing the summe of eighteene pounds and noe more.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Liberty given to have one Moiety of Harpiniers and one Moiety of English Mariners in an English Vessel, without paying further Duty.</head>
			<para id="p9">And in reguard there are at present great want of Harpinieres and Seamen skilled and exercised in the Trade
of Whale-fishing Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That it shall and may be lawfull for any Shipp
or Vessell truely belonging to England Wales or the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede, and whereof the Master
shall bee an English man and inhabiting within the places aforesaid from and after the first of May which shall
be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and three and untill the five and twentyeth [Day<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] of
March which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred eighty and three employed for the
catching of Whales dureing such Voyage to bee navigated with one moyety of the Harpinieres, and one
moyety of the rest of the Marriners onely English, and yet to pay noe further or other Custome for the Oyle,
Blubber or Finns caught and imported in such Shipp or Vessell, then if such Shipp or Vessell had beene
navigated with three fourths of the Marriners English, Any Law, Statute or Usage to the contrary in any wise
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. English-built Ships taking the Benefit of this Act to proceed from England to Greenland, and victualled accordingly.</head>
			<para id="p10">Provided alwayes, and it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That noe English built Shipp
or other Shipp or Vessell belonging to England, Wales or the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede importing
Whale oyle or Blubber or other Fish, Oyle or Whale-finns of Greenland or those Seas shall enjoy any benefitt
or priviledge by this A&bholigct; unlesse such Shipp or Vessell did proceede on her Voyage for Greenland and those Seas
from England or Wales or the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede, and was vi&bholigct;ualled for the said Voyage in some
of those places to be attested by the Colle&bholigct;or of the Port where the said Shipp or Vessell was vi&bholigct;ualled.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Recital of 12 C. II. c.18. ? 18.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">22 &#x0026; 23 Car. II. c.26 ? 8.; If Bond shall not be given to bring Plantation Goods to England</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p12">And whereas by one A&bholigct; passed in this present Parlyament in the twelfth yeare of your Majestyes Raigne
entituled An A&bholigct; for (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) encouragement of Shipping and Navigation, and by severall other Lawes passed since that
time it is permitted to shipp, carry, convey and transport Sugar, Tobacco, Cotton-wooll, Indicoe, Ginger, Fusticke
and all other Dying wood of the Growth, Produ&bholigct;ion and Manufa&bholigct;ure of any of your Majestyes Plantations in
America, Asia or Africa from the places of their Growth Produ&bholigct;ion and Manufa&bholigct;ure to any other of your
Majestyes Plantations in those Parts (Tangier onely excepted) and that without paying of Custome for the same
either at the ladeing or unladeing of the said Commodityes by meanes whereof the Trade and Navigation in
those Commodityes from one Plantation to another is greatly increased, and the Inhabitants of diverse of those
Colonies not contenting themselves with being supplyed with those Commodities for their owne use free from
all Customes (while the Subje&bholigct;s of this your Kingdome of England have paid great Customes and Impositions
for what of them hath beene spent here) but contrary to the express Letter of the aforesaid Lawes have brought
into diverse parts of Europe great quantities thereof, and doe alsoe [dayly<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] vend great quantities thereof to the
shipping of other Nations who bring them into diverse parts of Europe to the great hurt and diminution of your
Majestyes Customes and of the Trade and Navigation of this your Kingdome; For the prevention thereof Wee
your Majestyes Commons in Parliament [assembled<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] doe pray that it may be ena&bholigct;ed And bee it enacted by the
King's most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by authoritie of the same That from and after the first day
of September which shall bee in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and three If any
Shipp or Vessell which by Law may trade in any of your Majesties Plantations shall come to any of them to
shipp and take on board any of the aforesaid Commodities, and that Bond shall not be first given with one
sufficient Surety to bring the same to England or Wales or the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede and to noe other
place, and there to unloade and putt the same on shoare (the danger of the Seas onely excepted) that there
shall be answered and paid to your Majestie your Heires and Successors for soe much of the said Commodities
as shall be laded and putt on board such Shipp or Vessell these following Rates and Dutyes, That is to say</para>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">there shall be paid the following Duties.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p14">For Sugar White the hundred Weight containing one hundred and twelve pounds five shillings;</para>
			<para id="p15">And Browne Sugar and Muscavadoes the hundred weight containing one hundred and twelve pounds one shilling
[and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] six pence;</para>
			<para id="p16">For Tobacco the pound one penny;</para>
			<para id="p17">For Cotton-wooll the pound one halfe-penny;</para>
			<para id="p18">For Indicoe the pound, two pence;</para>
			<para id="p19">For Ginger the hundred weight containing one hundred and twelve pounds one shilling;</para>
			<para id="p20">For Logwood the hundred Weight containing one hundred and twelve pounds, five pounds;</para>
			<para id="p21">For Fusticke and all other Dying-wood the hundred Weight containing one hundred and twelve pounds
six pence;</para>
			<para id="p22">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p23">And alsoe for every pound of Cacao-nutts one penny, to be leavyed, colle&bholigct;ed and paid at such places, and to
such Colle&bholigct;ors and other Officers as shall be appointed in the respe&bholigct;ive Plantations to colle&bholigct;, leavy and receive
the same before the ladeing thereof, and under such Penalties both to the Officers and upon the Goods as for
non-payment of, or defrauding his Majestie of his Customes in England.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Duty to be levied by Commissioners of the Customs in England.</head>
			<para id="p24">And for the better collection of the severall Rates and Dutyes aforesaid imposed by this A&bholigct;, Bee it ena&bholigct;ed
and it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That this whole busines shall bee ordered and
mannaged, and the severall Dutyes hereby imposed shall be caused to be leavyed by the Commissioners of the
Customes in England, now and for the time being by and under the authoritie and dire&bholigct;ions of the Lord
Treasurer of England or Commissioners of the Treasury for the Time, being.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. If Party have not ready Money, Commissioners may take a Proportion of the Commodities.</head>
			<para id="p25">And in case any person or persons lyable by this Law to pay any of the Duties aforementioned, shall not
have moneyes wherewith to answere and pay the same Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That
the Officers appointed to colle&bholigct; the same shall accept instead of such moneyes such a proporation of the Commodities
to be shipped as shall amount to the Value thereof according to the currant Rate of the said Commodities in
such Plantation respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Free Trade to Sweden, Denmark, and Norway.</head>
			<para id="p26">(<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) For encouragement of the Eastland Trade Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the
advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled
and by the authority of the same That it shall and may be lawfull to and for every Person and persons Native
or Forreigner from and after the first day of May which shall be in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred seaventy and three at all times to have free liberty to trade into and from Sweden, Denmarke and
Norway; Any thing in the Charter of the Governour, Assistants and Fellowship of Merchants of Eastland, or
any other Charter, Grant, A&bholigct; or any thing else heretofore made or done, or hereafter to be done to the
contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Natives may be admitted into the Eastland Company, paying 40s.</head>
			<para id="p27">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That whatsoever person or persons Subje&bholigct;s of this
Realme shall desire to be admitted into the said Fellowshipp of Merchants of Eastland, That every such person
shall bee admitted into the said Fellowshipp paying for his Admission the summe of forty shillings and noe more.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">their <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">&#x0026; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


