<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47461" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Act for raising the Summe of Five hundred eighty foure thousand nine hundred seaventy eight pounds two
shillings and two pence halfe-penny for the speedy building Thirty Shipps of Warr. [Rot. Parl. 29 C.II. p. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
			<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
<para id="p1">
<emph type="i">Grant of a Land Tax.; &pound; 584,978. 2s. 2&frac12;d. to be raised within Seventeen Months, on the several Counties, 
&amp;c. and in the Proportions herein mentioned</emph>.
</para>
		<para id="p2">Most Gratious Soveraigne<br/>
				</para>
			<para id="p3">Wee Your Majesties most loyall and dutyfull Subje&bholigct;s the C&bhooov;mons of England assembled in Parliament
being highly sensible how necessary the Increase of Your Majesties Navall Force is at this time for the
Defence of this Your Realme and for the Preservation of Your Majesties auntient and undoubted Right unto and
Dominion over the Narrow Seas. For the doeing of which wee have therefore now granted a Taxe and Charge
upon our Lands for the speedy building and furnishing Thirty Shipps of Warr, And wee doe humbly present
Your most Gracious Majestie with the Rates and Assesments herein after mentioned, which wee doe beseech
Your Majestie to accept as a testimony of our great Care for the Defence and Honour of Your Majestie and of
Your Kingdome, And wee doe humbly beseech your Majestie That it may be ena&bholigct;ed and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the
Kings Most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
of the Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the Summe of
Five hundred eighty fower thousand nine hundred seaventy eight pounds two shillings and two pence halfe peny
shall be raised leavyed and paid unto your Majestie within the space of Seaventeene Moneths in manner following.
that is to say The summe of Thirty fower thousand fower hundred and ten pounds nine shillings and six pence
halfe peny by the moneth for Seaventeene Moneths begining from the Five and twentyeth day of March One
thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven shall be assessed, taxed, collected, levyed and paid by Five Quarterly
and Two Moneths Payments in the severall Countyes Cittyes Burrough Townes and Places within England and
Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede according to the severall Rates and Proportions and in such
manner as is hereafter expressed That is to say For every Moneth of the said Seaventeene Moneths.</para>
			<para id="p4">For the County of Bedford the summe of Foure hundred forty eight pounds eight shillings ten pence
halfe-penny.</para>
			<para id="p5">For the County of Berks the summe of Five hundred sixty six pounds three shillings three pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p6">The County of Bucks the summe of Six hundred fifty seaven pounds thirteene shillings two pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p7">The County of Cambridge the summe of Five hundred and ten pounds.</para>
			<para id="p8">The Isle of Ely the summe of One hundred seaventy foure pounds eighteene shillings and eleaven pence
halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p9">The County of Chester the summe of Three hundred seaventy three pounds eighteene shillings and seaven
pence.</para>
			<para id="p10">The Citty and County of the Citty of Chester the summe of Twenty six pounds fowerteene shillings and
two pence.</para>
			<para id="p11">The County of Cornwall the summe of Seaven hundred and seaventy pounds nine shillings one penny
halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p12">The County of Cumberland the summe of Eighty fower pounds three shillings one halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p13">The County of Derby the summe of Fower hundred thirty one pounds fower shillings and two pence.</para>
			<para id="p14">The County of Devon the summe of One thousand six hundred and fowerteene pounds nineteene shillings and
seaven pence.</para>
			<para id="p15">The Citty and County of the Citty of Exon the summe of Fifty eight pounds three shillings and eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p16">The County of Dorset the summe of Six hundred seaventy two pounds five shillings two pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p17">The Towne and County of Pool the summe of Five pounds Nine shillings (
<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p18">The County of Durham the summe of One hundred sixty one pounds eighteene (<ref idref="n2">2</ref>) ngs fower pence
halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p19">The County of Yorke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke and Towne and County of Kingston
upon Hull the summe of One thousand seaven hundred thirty fower pounds twelve shillings and seaven pence.</para>
			<para id="p20">The County of Essex the summe of One thousand five hundred forty nine pounds fower shillings and
five pence.</para>
			<para id="p21">The County of Gloucester the summe of Nine hundred and fower pounds five shillings one penny halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p22">The Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester the summe of Nineteene pounds fowerteene shillings.</para>
			<para id="p23">The County of Hereford the summe of Five hundred sixty five pounds sixteene shillings eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p24">The County of Hertford the summe of Six hundred seaventy two pounds eighteene shillings one penny
halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p25">The County of Huntingdon the summe of Three hundred and sixteene pounds seaventeene shillings one penny.</para>
			<para id="p26">The County of Kent with the Citty and County of the Citty of Canterbury the summe of One thousand six hundred
sixty three pounds nine shillings and fower pence.</para>
			<para id="p27">The County of Lancaster the summe of Five hundred and three pounds six shillings and nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p28">The County of Leicester the summe of Five hundred forty two pounds seaven shillings one penny halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p29">The County of Lincolne with the Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne One thousand two hundred eighty
seaven pounds eleaven shillings.</para>
			<para id="p30">The Citty of London with Liberty of Saint Martins Le Grand the summe of Two thousand one hundred forty
five pounds fifteene shillings and eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p31">The County of Midlesex with the Citty and Liberty of Westminster the summe of One thousand five hundred
and twenty pounds and five shillings.</para>
			<para id="p32">The County of Monmouth the summe of One hundred ninety five pounds.</para>
			<para id="p33">The County of Northampton the summe of Seaven hundred and six pounds nineteene shillings one penny.</para>
			<para id="p34">The County of Nottingham with the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham the summe of Fower
hundred thirty six pounds fowerteene shillings.</para>
			<para id="p35">The County of Norffolke the summe of One thousand six hundred eighty five pounds six shillings.</para>
			<para id="p36">The Citty and County of the Citty of Norwich the summe of Ninety pounds.</para>
			<para id="p37">The County of Northumberland with the Townes of Newcastle and Berwicke upon Tweede the summe of One
hundred eighty six pounds seaven shillings and ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p38">The County of Oxon the summe of Five hundred sixty seaven pounds fifteene shillings fower pence.</para>
			<para id="p39">The County of Rutland the summe of One hundred and twenty pounds fower shillings five pence halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p40">The County of Salop the summe of Six hundred and one pound seaventeene shillings one penny.</para>
			<para id="p41">The County of Stafford the summe of Foure hundred twenty six pounds five shillings and ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p42">The Citty and County of the Citty of Litchfield the summe of Six pounds ten shillings.</para>
			<para id="p43">The County of Somerset the summe of One thousand three hundred eighty five pounds fifteene shillings and
foure pence.</para>
			<para id="p44">The Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll the summe of Ninety nine pounds fowerteene shillings and
two pence.</para>
			<para id="p45">The County of Southampton with the Towne and County of Southampton and the Isle of Wight the summe of
One thousand ninety fower pounds fowerteene shillings and fower pence.</para>
			<para id="p46">The County of Suffolke the summe of One thousand, six hundred forty nine pounds five shillings and fower
pence.</para>
			<para id="p47">The County of Surrey with the Burrough of Southwarke the summe of Seaven hundred ninety eight pounds ten
shillings and one penny.</para>
			<para id="p48">[The County of Sussex the su&bhouov;e of Nine hundred and ten pounds thirteen shillings and tenn pence halfe penny.<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p49">The County of Warwicke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry the summe of Five hundred
ninety six pounds fower shillings fower pence halfe peny.</para>
			<para id="p50">The County of Worcester the summe of Five hundred twenty six pounds nineteene shillings six pence.</para>
			<para id="p51">The Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester the summe of Twenty seaven pounds fowerteene shillings and
nine pence.</para>
			<para id="p52">The County of Wilts the summe of Nine hundred eighty three pounds eight shillings nine pence halfe peny.</para>
			<para id="p53">The County of Westmorland the summe of Fifty eight pounds.</para>
			<para id="p54">The County of Anglesey the summe of sixty two pounds sixteene shillings and ten pence.</para>
			<para id="p55">The County of Brecknocke the summe of One hundred forty one pounds five shillings two pence three
farthings.</para>
			<para id="p56">The County of Cardigan the summe of Fifty two pounds seaventeene shillings ten pence three farthings.</para>
			<para id="p57">The County of Carmarthen the summe of One hundred thirty six pounds three shillings and fower pence.</para>
			<para id="p58">The County of Carnarvan the summe of Seaventy three pounds six shillings one penny.</para>
			<para id="p59">The County of Denbigh the summe of One hundred eleaven pounds fifteene shillings three pence halfe peny.</para>
			<para id="p60">The County of Flint the summe of Fifty nine pounds eight shillings eight pence.</para>
			<para id="p61">The County of Glamorgan the summe of One hundred eighty nine pounds eight shillings and eleaven pence.</para>
			<para id="p62">The County of Merioneth the summe of fifty pounds eight shillings and one halfe peny.</para>
			<para id="p63">The County of Montgomery the summe of One hundred thirty eight pounds six shillings and one peny.</para>
			<para id="p64">The County of Pembroke the summe of One hundred sixty three pounds five shillings.</para>
			<para id="p65">The County of Radnor the summe of Eighty seaven pounds three shillings and fower pence.</para>
			<para id="p66">The Towne and County of Haverford West the summe of Seaven pounds eleaven shillings eight pence halfe peny.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners named.</head>
			<para id="p67">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all and every the persons hereafter named shall be
C&bhooov;issioners of and for the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes, Cittyes, Burroughs, Townes and Places hereafter named
That is to say</para>
			<para id="p68">For the County of Bedford.</para>
			<para id="p69">William Russell Sir George Carteret Sir John Duncombe Charles Leigh Sir John Napier Sir John Cotten Sir
Roger Burgoine Sir Thomas Alston Sir Anthony Chester Sir Humphry Winch Sir Humphry Monox Sir St John
Charnock Sir Stephen Anderson Sir William Gostwick Sir John Osbourne Baronets Sir William Palmer Sir
William Beecher Sir George Blundell Sir Francis Wingale Sir William Francklin Knights Paulet St John
Thomas Hillersdon Oliver Luke Francis Crawley William Duncombe William Palmer Thomas Browne William Dyer
Thomas Palmer Villers Chernocke Richard Stone Sir John Thompson senior William Boteler John Keeling John Vaux
William Spencer John Coppin William Gery Walter Gary George Wyan Gaius Squire Robert Montague Humphry
Fish John Neale John Cockaine John Ventris Robert Crompton Robert Audley Samuell Bedford Mathew Denton
Mathew Dennis Richard Orlibeare Jasper Edwards Richard Edwards William Foster William Daniell John Smith
St John Thompson junior Rowland Alston Henry Mountague John Harvie Esquires Thomas Halfpeny senior Gent..</para>
			<para id="p70">For the Towne of Bedford.</para>
			<para id="p71">The Maior of Bedford for the time being William Russell Sir John Napier Sir Humphry Winch Sir William
Beecher Paulet St John Edmund Gardiner William Foster Thomas Cristie William Beckett John Beamont William
Scott Alderman Crawley Paul Cobb John Spencer Robert Audley Simon Becket.</para>
			<para id="p72">For the County of Berks.</para>
			<para id="p73">Henry Earle of Sterling of the Kingdome of Scotland Charles Earle of Ancram of the Kingdome of Scotland
Sir George Carteret Vice Chamberlaine to His Majestie, Thomas Howard Esq[uire], Sir Humphry Forrester Sir John
Stonehouse Sir Henry Henn Sir Thomas Draper Sir William Rich Sir Thomas Clergis Sir Edmund Fettiplace
Baronets Sir Henry Fane Knight of the Bath Sir Richard Powle Knight of the Bath Sir Robert Pye Sir William
Craven Sir William Jones His Majestyes Attourney Generall Sir Thomas Dolman Sir John Elwes Sir Richard Harrison
Sir Algernoon May Sir Giles Hungerford Sir William Armorer Sir Edward Norris Sir William Paule Knights Robert
Packer Edward Mansfield John Nevile George Porter Peregrine Hobby William Chiffinch Richard Aldworth Edmond
Fettiplace Thomas Vachell Francis Pygott Robert Sawyer John Kingsmill Edward Keat Charles Gerard William
Trumball William Nelson Hungerford Dunch John Blagrave Thomas Fettiplace Samuell Brightwell William Wilmet
Humphry Hyde John Finch Paul Colton William Barker of Hurst Henry Proctor Edmond Wiseman William
Ball Roger Draper John Breedon John Pouny senior William Kendrick John Hippesley William Ruddier Thomas
Medlicote Richard Southby John Southby junior Richard Hyde of Blagrave Phillip Jemmet Thomas Holt Richard
May Thomas Staples Esquires Thomas Stamp Thomas Seymour Richard Brotherwick William Angell John Collins
Henry Due Richard Fincher William Hammerley Philip Weston Gentlemen Richard Lightfoot Gent. William Oftley
Do&bholigct;or at Law Charles Perret Doctor at Law John Whitwick Henry Barker Hugh Barker Do&bholigct;or of Phisick Robert
Leigh Richard Aldworth John Howse John Hersey William Smith James Smith Symon Smith Charles Whitacre
William Cherry Richard Brickenden George Blagrave John Peacock Nicholas Hyde Thomas Southby John Due
Bolton James John Biggs John Whitfield James Heron Captaine Henry Barker John Pouny junior Richard Lovelace
Roger Knight John Topham of Windsor Charles Pierce Richard Pierce William Bowles Bartholimew Yate Nathaniell
Knight Valentine Crome George Bishop of Bruy Gentlemen The Maior of Reading The Maior of Abingdon The
Maior of Windsor The Maior of Wallingford, The Maior of Newberry for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p74">For the County of Bucks.</para>
			<para id="p75">Charles Earle of Ancram of the Kingdome of Scotland Phillip Lord Waynman Viscount Tuern in the Kingdome
of Ireland Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir Thomas Tyrrell Sir John Burlace Sir Anthony
Chester Sir Thomas Proby Sir William Bowyer Sir William Smith Sir Ralph Verney Sir William Drake Sir Henry
Andrews Sir John Crooke Sir Humphry Winch Sir Thomas Lee Sir Dennis Hampson Baronets Sir William Terringham
Sir Richard Ingoldesby Sir Robert Gayer Knights of the Bath Sir Francis Wainman Sir Richard Piggot Sir Robert
Cleyton Sir Robert Crooke Sir Thomas Clergis Sir Peter Terreil Sir Roger Hill Sir John Trevor Sir John
Tompson Sir John Seymore Knights Daniell Finch Charles Cheyney Thomas Waller Edmond Waller senior Edmond
Waller junior William Perm Robert Sawyer Edmond West George Jeffreys Brett Norton Thomas Hacket John
Duncombe of Great Brickhill Robert Lovet Thomas Barrenger Edward Lee Edward Backwell Thomas Butler
William Serjeant junior Edward Nicholas of Hitcham Thomas Farrer senior Thomas Farrer junior Cesar Cranmer
John Risley Knightley Purefoy Roger Price Thomas Nappier Richard Hampden John Witherangle Thomas Sanders
of Haddenham George Russell William Jepson Richard Winwood Richard Greenvill Bud Wayes Bazill Brent
William Hill John Hamden Thomas Stafford Bernard Turney Christopher Eggleton Francis Terringham Robert
Dormer John Loggins Joseph Alston Henry Bartue Thomas Doyly John Hobart George Wyan William Clever
William Abraham Nicholas Salter junior Henry Seymour Robert Stiles John Grubb John Greene Henry Alnutt
Joseph Mainard William Bowyer Thomas Owen Andrew Duffield Edmond Mellicot Marmaduke Darrell Edmund
Verney Edmund Dorrell William Coleing John Dormer John Borlace William Farrer junior Francis Knowles Symon
Mayne William Fleetwood Thomas Eccleson William Hill senior Henry Herbert George Evelin Esq[ui]rs.</para>
			<para id="p76">For the Towne of Buckingham</para>
			<para id="p77">The Bayliffe for the time being Sir Richard Temple Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir William Smith Baronet
John Risley Edmund Verney Edmund Andrews Edmund Dorrell junior Esquires Hugh Ethersey George Danser John
Rogers Pelham Sandwell Walter Alnutt John Grove William Robinson William Hartley.</para>
			<para id="p78">For the Towne of Wickham</para>
			<para id="p79">The Maior for time being Charles Elliot Edward Bedder Henry Bigg Samuell Wells Alexander Parmum
Jonathan Randall John Wheeler Thomas Wells Robert Fayer.</para>
			<para id="p80">For the County of Cambridge</para>
			<para id="p81">Richard Lord Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland William Lord Alington of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir
Thomas Chichley Sir Thomas Hatton Sir John Cotton Sir Thomas Willis Sir Henry Pickering Sir Thomas Slater
Sir Levinus Bennet Sir George Downing Sir Robert Cotton Knights Francis Buller Thomas Steward Phillip Cotton
John Millicent Gerrard Russell Jeffery Nightingale Humphry Gardner William Layer Thomas Duckett Roger
Pepys Mildmay Dowman Tyrrell Dalton William Ayloffe Thomas Buck senior Devereux Martyn Edward Pickering
Henry Slingsby Humphry Weld Doctor. John Pepys Christopher Hatton Ralph Pemberton Samuell Bedford Samuell
Fortrey junior Samuell Pepys John Holdman Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p82">For the Isle of Ely.</para>
			<para id="p83">William Mountague Lord Cheife Baron of the Exchequer Richard Lord Gorges of the Kingdome of Ireland
William Russell Es&bhoqexc; Sir Thomas Chichley Sir John Norton Sir Lyonell Walden Lawrence Hewer Oxborough
Charles Wren William Wren Edward Partrich William Colvile Thomas Steward Anthony Fisher Robert Hampson
Esquires Henry Brunsell Henry Hitch Do&bholigct;ors of Law William Balam Thomas Edwards Hugh Underwood Peter
Diamond George Farewell Roger Jennings John Childe Richard Marriott John Fincham Richard Reade William
March Henry Goodrick Thomas Towers Ralph Pemberton Robert Swaine George Dymond Thomas Docwre
Sigismond Williamson Maximilian Waltham John Bridgeman senior Edmund Williamson Samuell Fortrey junior
George Farewell junior.</para>
			<para id="p84">For the University and Towne of Cambridge.</para>
			<para id="p85">The Vice Chauncellor of the University for the time being, The Maior of the Towne for the time being
William Lord Allington of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Thomas Chichley Sir Thomas Page Sir Charles Wheeler
Baronet James Duport Theophilus Dillingham Isaac Barrow Robert Maplet[h<ref idref="n4">4</ref>]oft Joseph Beaumont Doctors in
Divinity Thomas Crouch Clement Nevile Esquires Roger Pepys Es&bhoqexc; Nathaniell Crabb Robert Mircell Samuell
Newton Owen May field Edward Miller Andrew Hart Francis Jermin Aldermen of the Towne Sir Thomas Slater
Thomas Stevens Do&bholigct;or of Divinity Samuell Moody Edward Stoyt Do&bholigct;or in Phisick, Nicholas Jacob Es&bhoqesq;
Edward Story.</para>
			<para id="p86">For the County of Chester.</para>
			<para id="p87">Robert Lord Cholmondeley of the Kingdome of Ireland, William Lord Brereton of the Kingdome of Ireland
Charles Gerard Henry Booth Thomas Needham Esquires Sir Thomas Grosvenour Sir Thomas Wilbraham Sir
Thomas Delves Sir Willoughby Aston Sir Thomas Powell Sir Peter Warburton Sir Peter Leicester Sir Thomas
Mainwaring Sir Richard Brookes Sir Thomas Bellott Sir Peter Pinder Sir Peter Standley Baronets Sir Robert Cotton
Sir Jeffery Shakerley Sir Peter Brookes Sir John Booth Sir Foulke Lucy Sir John Arderne Sir Phillip Egerton Sir
John Trevor Sir John Crew Knights Peter Venables Baron of Kinderton John Crew Collonell Thomas Legh senior
Collonell Thomas Legh junior Henry Legh Richard Legh Thomas Cholmondeley William Venables Nathaniell Booth
Edward Legh Randall Dodd Peter Wilbraham William Marbury Edward Warren John Leach John Manwairing
of Perver Edward Glegg Roger Wilbraham Edward Minshall Edward Jodrell Charles Brereton William Lawton
Thomas Delves John Daniell John Manwaring Roger Whitley Do&bholigct;or Peter Gerrard Thomas Legh of Lyme Edward
Lutchwich Esquires John Warren William Davenport Thomas Whitley Robert Pickering Robert Cholmondeley of
Hotford Thomas Daniell Peter Legh of Booths Henry Mainwaring Roger Mainwaring Thomas Minshall Ralph
Wilbraham Richard Walthall Anthony Eyre Collonell Werden William Cotton Henry Davis John Davis John
Hurlston Thomas Dutton Thomas Bunbury Edward Downes John Ward John Davenport of Widford Leftwick
Oldfield William Stopford Hugh Grosvenour Edward Wright John Starkey Thomas Hollingshed Esquires Phillip
Ward Thomas Swetenham of Haveley Christopher Berron of Cloud Gentlemen Do&bholigct;or Wainright M<emph type="p">r</emph> Greenhaugh
M <emph type="p">r</emph> Bispham Lord Colchester.</para>
			<para id="p88">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Chester.</para>
			<para id="p89">The Maior for the time being William Williams Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Robert Werden Es&bhoqesq; William Ince Richard Bird
John Poole Randall Oulton William Streete Robert Murry William Wilson Gawen Hudson Thomas Simpson
Richard Wright Henry Lloyd John Maddox Robert Caddick William Harvey William Ince junior William Wilme
George Manwairing Peter Edwards Aldermen Sir Thomas Gravener Sir Robert Williams Sir Peter Pindar Baronets
Sir John Booth [Ralph Whitley Kenricke Eyton Sir Phillip Egerton Sir James Bradshaw Knights<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Edward Lutwich
John Brerewood George Booth Thomas Swinton Esquires Giles Vanburgh Merchant William Wright The Sheriffes
for the time being Peter Gerrard M<emph type="p">r</emph> Anderson Captaine Thomas Baker.</para>
			<para id="p90">For the County of Cornwall.</para>
			<para id="p91">Francis Trefusis Es&bhoqesq; Vicecom. Robert Roberts Es&bhoqesq; John Arundell Es&bhoqesq; Hender Roberts Es&bhoqesq; Francis Roberts
Es&bhoqesq; Barnard Greenville Es&bhoqesq; Sir Bowcer Wray Sir Jonathan Trelawny Sir John Carew Sir John Coriton Sir Violl
Vivion Sir William Godolphin Sir Peter Killigrew Sir John Sintaubin Sir William Morris Baronets Sir Nicholas
Slaning Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Edgecombe Knight of the Bath Sir John Arundell Sir Joseph Tredenham
Sir James Smith Sir John Godolphin Knight Sir Walter Moyle Knight Sir John Malsworth Collonell Trevanion John
Trelawney junior John Trelawney senior Francis Buller senior Francis Buller junior John Speccot John Tanner Chamond
Roscarrock Jonathan Rashleigh John Elliot John Buller John Harris John Corriton William Scawen Edmond
Prideaux Walter Kendall Walter Langdon William Bond Joseph Sawle Thomas Dorrell Nicholas Glyn Edward
Boscowen Thomas Herle John Vivian Thomas Vivian Edward Herle John Conocke John Sintaubin Humphrey Nicholls
of Penvos William Courtney Arthur Fortescue Nicholas Courtney Edward Elliott Nathaniell Mohune William Mohune
Edward Nosworthy: Edmond Prideaux John Prideaux John Rashleigh Richard Trevanion of Verone Richard Scoble
of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Austell John Kendall Charles Trevanion of Gerrancce Richard Moyle John Treffry Robert Rashleigh Francis
Calmady Richard Ereley Charles Kendall Gent. Ambrose Manaton Es&bhoqesq; Nicholas Herle Es&bhoqesq; Arthur Sprye Es&bhoqesq;
James Praied senior and James Praied junior Es&bhoqesq; William Painter Gent. Humphry Courtney Gent. John Blyth Gent.
Charles Grills Es&bhoqesq; Francis Grills Gent. Robert Hoblin Richard Hoblin George Robinson William Keigwin Arthur
Painter John Polwheele John Penrose Es&bhoqesq; Collonell Godolphin Es&bhoqesq; Sidney Godolphin Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Piper Gent.
John Kelliowe Es&bhoqesq; John Pendarvis Es&bhoqesq; Richard Pendarvis Christopher Harris Charles Boscowen Thomas Wadden
Es&bhoqesq; Humphry Noy Es&bhoqesq; Ezekiell Arundell Charles Smith Es&bhoqesq; Edward Harris Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Aychim Es&bhoqesq; William
Arscott Es&bhoqesq; Lewis Tremaine John Nichols of Litlewood Humphry Hill of Guendron John Fowell Samuell Ennis
Henry Erisey Es&bhoqesq; Anthony Chenowith William Silly Humphry Burlace Es&bhoqesq; Christopher Billet Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Carew
Es&bhoqesq; Samuell Langsford John Verman Humphry Lower John Arundell Samuell Rouls John Arundell junior John
Barret of Killegreene Thomas Penhallow Richard Williams John Williams Stephen Robins of (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) Winow Hugh Tompkin
of Trevownance John Murths senior John Murths junior Esquires Humphry Langsford Gent. James Bond of Aerth
Es&bhoqesq; Nicholas Wills Samuell Cabell Es&bhoqesq; M<emph type="p">r</emph> Handcock of Hendra Roger Porter Jonathan Trelawney of Coldrunck
Es&bhoqesq; George Spry of Brisland Nicholas Kempt Christopher Porter Francis Penrose William Jolly of Pencost
Emanuell Piper Phillip Piper William Martin senior and William Martin junior William Bond of Holliwood Abell
French John Cotton of Boscastle Es&bhoqesq; John Pierce of Deustow Hugh Jones Edward Kneebone senior Edward
Kneebone junior John Lampen Reinold Hawkey John Hawkey The Maiors for Truro Bodwin Lanceston and Liscard
for the time being Hugh Tonkin of Trevownance Thomas Kelly Edward Nosworthy junior Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Hicks of
Kerryes John Courtney Hugh Trevanion Thomas Cossens Robert Pearse Nicholas Archer M<emph type="p">r</emph> Martin of S
<emph type="p">t</emph> Guines
Edward Hoblin John Waddon Walter Norris.</para>
			<para id="p92">For the County of Cumberland</para>
			<para id="p93">Edward Lord Morpeth sonne and heire to Charles Earle of Carlisle Sir Joseph Williamson Principall Secretary
of State Sir Phillip Musgrave Sir Richard Graham Sir William Dalston Sir George Fletcher Sir John Lowther senior
Sir John Lowther junior Sir William Pe[n]nington Sir Richard Musgrave Baronets Sir Wilfrid Lawson Sir Phillip
Howard Sir George Dalston Sir John Dalston Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir John Ballentine Knights Richard
Musgrave Fardinando Hudleston John Lamplugh Daniell Fleming Robert Carleton Christopher Blinkow John</para>
			<para id="p94">Aglionby William Musgrave Thomas Denton Richard Tolson Andrew Hudleston Richard Patrickson Thomas Dalston
Thomas Warwick Henry Dacres Richard Lamplugh Anthony Hutton William Blenerhasset Christopher Richmond
Miles Pennington Bernard Kirkbride [Wilfrid<ref idref="n6">6</ref>] Lawson Darcey Curwen Edward Stanley Henry Foster Leonard Dykes
Henry Brougham William Orpheur William Feilding Henry Fletcher The Maior of Carlisle for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p95">For the County of Derby.</para>
			<para id="p96">William Lord Cavendish sonne and heire apparent to William Earle of Devonshire Sir Thomas Greisley Sir John
Curson Sir John Gell Sir Francis Burdet Sir Robert Shirley Sir John Harpur Sir Robert Coke Sir Henry Every
Sir William Boothby Baronets Sir Francis Leeke Knight and Baronet Sir Samuell Sleigh Sir John Harpur Sir Gilbert
Clarke Sir. Edward Abney Knights Sir Nicholas Wilmott Knight Sergeant at Law Sir Simon Degg Sir John Shore
Knights Anchitell Grey John Ferrers German Pole John Coke Henry Gilbert Henry Cavendish George Vernon Robert
Burdett Willoughby Gray William Fitzherbert Charles Agard Charles Cotton John Stanton Henry Milward John
Mundey Robert Eyre John Low Gilbert Thacker Adrian Mundey Phillip Gell George Pole Robert Cooke William
Eyre Francis Revell Robert Wilmott Cornelius Clarke Thomas Milward Francis Leeke John Curson Francis Burton
of Drunfield Walter Horton Francis Parker Edward Pegg Samuell Saunders junior John Moorewood John Spademan
junior John Every William Allestrey Henry Meller Nicholas Wilmott Thomas Gladwin Samuell Holden Samuell
Hallowes Anthony Fitzherbert John Low of Denbeigh Henry Keyes Robert Ashton James Abney William Bage
Walter Woolsley Henry Kendall John Smithson William Hopkinson Thomas Eyre Esquires Adam Eyre Henry
Polgey Robert Wandall Andrew Cleyton Robert Haywood Hugh Bateman Edward Osborne Maior of Derby for
the time being Humphry Yates Policarpus Dakin James Ward John Dalton John Brookehouse Edward Walker
George Blackwell Samuell Goodwin Joseph Parker Gent. The Maior of Chesterfield for the time being Richard Clarke
Peter Dowker Thomas Britland.</para>
			<para id="p97">For the County of Devon.</para>
			<para id="p98">The Right Honourable Edward Seymour Es&bhoqesq; Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons Sir George Carteret
Vice Chamberlaine of his Majestyes Household Sir Edward Seamour Sir Peter Prideaux Sir Henry Hele Sir
George Chudleigh Sir Amos Pollard Sir Francis Drake Sir Courtney Poole Sir Copleston Banfield Sir Arthur
Northcote Sir John Davey Sir William Courtney Sir Hugh Ackland Sir Nicholas Slaning Sir Henry Ford Sir John
Drake Sir William Morrice Sir Walter Young Sir Henry Carew Sir Peter Lear Sir Arthur Harris Sir Peter Fortescue
Sir Thomas Putt Baronets Sir John Rolle Sir Richard Edgecombe Sir Symon Leach Sir Henry Vane Knights of the
Bath Sir Henry Carew Sir John Mainard Sir Peter Ball Sir James Smith Sir Thomas Carew Sir John Mallet Sir
William Waldron Sir Thomas Bury Knights Robert Lord Londonderry of the Kingdome of Ireland Arthur
Earle of Dunegall of the Kingdome of Ireland Peter Prideaux George Chudleigh Francis Courtney John Pole John
Rolle John Northcote of Uton Samuell Roll John Basset Richard Strode Edmond Parker John Courtney Mathew
Hele Nicholas Morris Richard Coffin John Harris Richard Duke William Bragg Josias Calmady Nicholas Denys
Edmond Waldron John Tanner Henry Norsey Arthur Harris Thomas Walker John Specot Hugh Piper William
Drake Joseph Drake William Bruton Arthur Berry William Eveley John Harris of Wortham Bamfield Roed
Phillip Harris of Tarrington Hugh Vaughan Ambrose Mannington James Calwodleigh Henry Carew Thomas Shapcott
John Worth William Cockaine Martin Rider Arthur Pine Simon Hele Michaell Brighouse Phillip Harris of Haine
Warrick Pollexfen Robert Pollexfen Jonathan Rashley Gilbert Yard of Bradleigh John Chichester of Hall John Fry
of Yarty Gideon Haydon John Crocker William Savery John Gifford of Brightley George Carew John Kelland
Samuell Sainthill Richard Hillardson Samuell Tanner Thomas Weare Richard Lee John Chichester of Widworthy
John Ashford John Blewet John Raymond Elias Bartlet senior Leonard Yeo John Drake of Ivy-Bridge William
Drake Thomas Drew Edmond Prideaux of Ford Jonathan Prideaux Henry Stevens James Clifford John Beare of
Bearescoombe John Upton Roger Pomery John Halle Roger Woollacoombe Sebastian Isaac James Huish Edward
Yard Edward Lovett Lewes [Inchden<ref idref="n7">7</ref>] Bartholimew Gidley James Clifford Aaran Baker John Hore James Rodd John
Vaughan William Boggan Thomas Reynell Henry Fry John Arscott Arthur Tremaine Henry Walter William Kelly
Phillip Champernoone Shilston Calmady Thomas Pine Jonathan Sparke William Jennings John Sparke William
Fortescue Phillip Shapcott Anthony Salter John Willoughby John Davey of Carrow Ten John Davey of Ruxford
Rawlin Mallock William Stowell Henry Worth Thomas Beare of Huntsen Samuell Foote John Quash George
Southcote of Dulces Phillip Harris of Great Torrington Gilbert Burrington John Quick junior Elias Crunes John
Elford James Fortescue William Trevill William Bastard George Treby Christopher Globery Hugh Stofford Esquires
The High Sheriffe for the time being The Maiors of Plymouth Barnstable Tornes Tiverton Torrington and
Dartmouth for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p99">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Exon</para>
			<para id="p100">The Right Honourable Edward Seymour Es&bhoqesq; Speaker of the honourable House of Commons The Maior for
the time being Sir James Smith Knight Sir Thomas Carew Knight Sir John Mallet Knight Henry Gaudy Nicholas
Issack Thomas Walker George Tuthill William Sanford Isaac Maudy Christopher Brodridge John Parr Aldermen
The Sheriffe for the time being The Reciever for the time being Captaine Glyde Mr John Collins Mr Andrew
Quash Mr Henry Smith Mr Thomas Bale John Bidgood Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Edmond Davies Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke
Edward Masters Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Major James Walker.</para>
			<para id="p101">For the Towne of Plymouth</para>
			<para id="p102">The Maior for the time being Collonell Hugh Piper Robert Pollard Lewis Stewkley Sir Gilbert Talbott Jonathan
Sparke Es&bhoqesq; Mr John Sparke John Martin John Dell Aldermen Mr Isaac Tillard Mr Phillip Andrewes William
Jennings William Cotton.</para>
			<para id="p103">For the County of Dorset.</para>
			<para id="p104">Anthony Lord Ashley sonne and heire apparent of Anthony Earle of Shaftesbury Sir Hugh Windham Knight
one of the Justices of his Majestyes Court of Common Pleas Sir Francis Holles Sir William Portman Sir John
Moorton Sir Nathaniell Naper Baronet Sir John Nicholas Knight of the Bath Sir John Strode Sir Winston Churchill
Sir George Strode Knights Thomas Strangwayes Thomas Freke Humphry Welde Thomas Browne John Tregonwell
of Milton John Tregonwell of Anderston Robert Naper George Fulford Edward Miller James Long Wadham Strangwayes
Henry Butler William Uvedall William Okenden Robert Coker George Browne Henry Whitacre Mathew Daves
George Rives Robert Culliford Robert Seymour Anthony Etterick John Rives James Gould Thomas Chafe Robert
Williams William Strode Thomas Earle Thomas Baynard George Savage John Hoskins Michaell Harvey John
Hurding Nathaniell Heymore Hugh Hodges William Floyer John Gould Henry Henley Thomas Bennet Robert
Browne John [Gallop<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] Thomas, Chafin Henry Constantine George Strangewayes John Still John Lawrence John
Ironside William Bowles John Hardy Richard Greene Thomas Turbervill Seymour Bowman John Cradock Joseph
Seward John Churchill William Churchill Robert Oxenbridge Francis Mohun George Stile Edward St Low Robert
Fry senior Richard Swaine Joseph Hussey Henry Bower Robert Larder George Dabeney William Wake John
Craddock Joseph Seward Anthony Floyer junior.</para>
			<para id="p105">For the Towne and County of Poole.</para>
			<para id="p106">Anthony Lord Ashley sonne and heire of Anthony Earle of Shaftesbury Sir John Morton Baronet Thomas
Strangwayes Anthony Etrick Esquires Mr William Orchard John Carter Nicholas Efford Robert Lewen Moses
Durell Henry Jubber Isaac Hart Allen Scutt William Streete Merchants.</para>
			<para id="p107">For the County Palatine of Durham</para>
			<para id="p108">Nicholas Conyers Es&bhoqesq; High Sheriffe of the County Sir John Otway Spirituall Chauncellor Sir Christopher Conyers
Sir Ralph Cole Sir Thomas Liddell Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir James Clavering Sir James Pennyman Sir Robert Eden
Sir William Cheater Sir William Blacket Baronets Sir Francis Anderson Sir George Vane Sir Francis Bowes Sir
Robert Shafto Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir Henry Calverley Sir Ralph Carr Sir Marke Milbanke Knights Henry
Liddell John Tempest Christopher Vane Daniell Collingwood Esquires Henry Lampton James Darcey John Clavering
of White house William Bellasis Ralph Davison Thomas Craddock Francis Bowes Lyonell Vane Collonell Strodder
Thomas Lyddell William Blakeston [Baldwin Pitts D<emph type="p">r</emph>
Lloyd Nath Johnson Isaac Basire Lionel Madison Cuthbert
Carr Thom. Carnaby Thom. Sanderso[n] Will. Lilburne John Morland John Blakeston
<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] William Davison John Parkhurst
Humphrey Wharton William Tempest Nicholas Conyers Richard Neale William Christian Robert Wharton George
Morland Christopher Sanderson Miles Stapleton Collonell Foulthorpe John Foulthorpe George Baker Thomas
Watson William Ord of Beele John Jefferson Thomas Fetherston Esquires Marmaduke Allanson William Garth
of Headlam Cuthbert Sanderson Walter Ethericke Henry Barnes Thomas Wright Thomas Watson of Cockfield
Robert Roper Robert Jackson of Stockton James Coke of the same <?bignore?>[William Atkinson of the same The Maior
of the Citty of Durham for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p109">For the County of Yorke, The West Rideing of the said County.</para>
			<para id="p110">Edward Lord Latimer sonne and heire apparent of Thomas Earle of Danby Lord High Treasurer of England
George Viscount Castleton of the Kingdome of Ireland Charles Lord Clifford sonne and heire apparent to the
Earle of Burlington Henry Lord Fairfax of the Kingdome of Scotland Conyers Darcy Es&bhoqesq; Sir Henry Goodrick
Sir Thomas Mauleverer Sir John Reresby Sir John Kay Sir Thomas Armitage Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir William
Ingleby Sir William Rokeby Sir Godfrey Copley Sir Edmond Jennings Sir Edmund Winne Sir John Jackson Sir
Thomas Slingsby Sir George Cooke Sir William Franckland Baronets Sir Thomas Wharton Sir Jervase Cutler Sir
John Hewley Sir John Dawney Sir William Lowther Sir Mathew Wentworth Sir William Wentworth Sir Christopher
Clapham Sir Henry Tomson Sir George Dalston Sir Ralph Knight Sir Thomas Yarborough Sir William Rookeby
Knights Thomas Fairefax Phillip Wharton John Ramsden Richard Hutton Walter Hawkesworth Welbury Norton
William Palmes John Vavasour Francis Nevill William Horne Walter Calverley Henry Eyre Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke
John Savill John Wentworth Bradward Tindall Francis Folyombe Thomas Vincent Willoughby Robeby Major Francis
Reresby William Lowther James Stockdale Christopher Tancred John Bilby Richard Washington William Hamond
John Boynton Thomas Yarbrough Walter Lister [Arthur Ingram Henry Stapleton
<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] William Stockdale William Drake
Inglebert Leeds Thomas Fairefax of Menston, Cuthbert Wade Richard Weston John Stanhope George Stanhope
William Ellis Charles Osborne Tobias Jennings John Adams John Goodricke Roger Portington John Clarke John
Garland William Dawson Francis White John Lister George Thornhill John Adams of Rockliffe Thomas Habor
Jonathan Jenings junior Ralph Lowther Miles Stavelcy Richard Beaumont of Whitley-hall Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Fawks,
Henry Hich Jonathan Jenings senior William Roundale Henry Edmonds Thomas Gill Thomas Parker John
Mattrum Thomas Dodson John Hatfield William Johnson Thomas Lister of Maingham Lyonell Copeley William
Farrer Es&bhoqesq; Henry Marsden William Beckwith William Drake Henry Slingsby John Batty Robert Walter Thomas
Jackson George Eothergill Thomas Craven Christopher Driffield Thomas Dawney Charles Richards George Rayson
Richard Aldbrough Esquires Cuthbert Chambers The Maior of Rippon Captaine John Atkinson The Maior of
Doncaster Richard Atkinson The Maior of Pontefra&bholigct; William Laughton The Maior of Leeds for the time being
John Loughton Anthony Fletcher Lawrence Wharton Charles Rickard Henry Cooke.</para>
			<para id="p111">For the North Rideing in the said County of Yorke.</para>
			<para id="p112">Edward Lord Morpeth sonne and heire apparent to the Earle of Carlisle Conyers Darcy Marmaduke Darcy
Sir Christopher Wivell Sir Hugh Cholmley Sir Metcalfe Robinson Sir Gilbert Gerrard Sir Henry Stapleton Sir
Thomas Slingsby Sir David Fowlis Sir William Franckland Sir John Lowther Sir John Napier Sir Roger Langley
Sir William Caley Sir George Marwood Sir Richard Graham of Numington Sir Richard Graham of Norton Sir
Christopher Wandsford Sir William Chator Sir James Pennyman Sir John Hotham Baronets Sir John Brooke Sir
John Hewley Sir Marmaduke Dalton Sir Gervase Elwes Sir Edward Challener Sir John Dawney Sir Phillip Huwood
Sir Phillip Muncton Sir John Dalston Sir Henry Thompson Sir Henry Calverley Sir Robert Layton James Darcy Es&bhoqesq;
Sir Joseph Craddock Knights Phillip Darcy William Wivell William Levison-Gower Thomas Dodsworth Henry
Marwood Thomas Gill William Caley Thomas Laughe John Howe John Beverley John Wilson Roger Beckwith
Thomas Rokeby Bryan Layton Roger Talbott John Dodsworth Richard Peares Barrington Bourcher Robert
Walters of Cundell Francis Wivill Henry Guy Edward Croft Anthony Franckland Wilbury Norton Thomas Norton
Christopher Norton Sergeant Turner Isaac Fairefax Thomas Wakefield William Langley Thomas [Gowger<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] George
Metcalfe Humphry Wharton Robert Wharton William Asquish George Norton John Gibson Edward Hutchinson
William Thompson Reinald Graham Francis Prisfield Charles Tankard Thomas Jackson-Couling William Fielding
William Palmes Christopher Darcy James Heblethwaite William Robinson Edward Trotter Anthony Lowther Hugh
Bethell James Morley Timothy Malevorer Thomas Harle Thomas Worsley William Metcalfe Walter Lister John
Colston Thomas Waite Henry Crosland Charles Bellasis William Bellarns of Alar John Chapman Roger Lee
William Dawson William Trewman John Geldard Thomas Fairfax Phillip Prince Robert Bushell Thomas Lascelles
Thomas Dodsworth Thomas Gill Trisham Fish Timothy Ford Do&bholigct;or Smith of Esby John Knowesley Walter Bethell
Christopher Percyhay The Maior of Richmond and The Bayliffe of Scarborough for the time being James Clayton
Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Layton Gent. John Blackston Gent..</para>
			<para id="p113">For the East Rideing of the said County of Yorke.</para>
			<para id="p114">Charles Lord Clifford sonne and heire apparent to the Earle of Burlington, Sir John Hotham Sir Francis
Boynton Sir Robert Hilliard Sir Watkinson Pailer Thomas Rudston Sir Henry North. Sir John Legard Sir Henry
S<emph type="p">t</emph>
Quintin Sir Thomas Strickland Baronets Sir Phillip Monckton Sir Thomas Daniell Sir Thomas Remington Sir
Hugh Bethell Sir William Cobb Sir Ralph Wharton Sir Henry Thompson Sir Edward Bernard Sir Michaell
Wharton Sir Mathew Peirson Sir Jonathan Atkins Knights Michaell Wharton Tobias Jenkins Robert Buck Durand
Hotham John Lister Henry Holmes Christopher Hilliard John Vavasour William Osbaldeston William Thompson
William Grimston Robert Southaby Richard Robinson Richard Robinson junior Captaine Tomlinson Thomas
Crompton Francis Thompson William Gee William. Gee junior Richard Legard William Boynton Henry Guy
Walter Bethell Robert Constable Richard Thompson Henry Hilliard John Stapilton John Herne Phillip Saltmarsh
John Clarke William S<emph type="p">t</emph> Quintin James Moiser Thomas Hesketh William Bethell James Heblethwaite Hugh Bethell
Marmaduke Constable Richard Remington Mathew Allured Esquires Thomas Allured Thomas Langley William
Blunt William Lewins Tobias Hodgson Edward Gray John Belton Ralph Higdon Richard Graham Robert Hollis
Ellis Cooper Edward Gray Robert Pricket Timothy Remington The Maior of Beverley and [The<ref idref="n12">12</ref>] Maior of Headon
for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p115">For the Citty of Yorke and County of the same.</para>
			<para id="p116">The Lord Maior The Aldermen, The Sheriffes for the time being Henry Lord Fairfax of the Kingdome of
Scotland Sir Metcalfe Robinson Sir Thomas Slingsby Sir Henry Goodricke Sir George Reeves Baronets Sir John
Brooke John Turner Sergeant at Law Doctor Watkinson George Pricket Henry Stapleton James Moyser Thomas
Hutton John Swaile William Roundale M<emph type="p">r</emph> Snasdale Sir Stephen Thompson Knight Thomas Nesbet John Peckett
George Ramsdon Andrew Parrott Robert Waller Edward Thompson Lawrence Toyle Gowen Hodgson Charles
Hall John Thompson Thomas Langley Thomas Fairfax Phillip Prince Gent..</para>
			<para id="p117">For the Towne and County of Kingston upon Hull.</para>
			<para id="p118">The Maior and Aldermen for the time being The Recorder for the time being Anthony Gilby Es&bhoqesq; Andrew
Marvell Es&bhoqesq; The Sheriffe for the time being Christopher Hildiard Es&bhoqesq; Robert Hollis Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Thorneton Es&bhoqesq;
The Wardens of Trinity House for the time being Edmond Pople John Lister John Field Robert Mason William
Hayes Gent..</para>
			<para id="p119">For the County of Essex.</para>
			<para id="p120">Robert Bertie Banistre Mainard Henry Fanshaw Richard Barret and William Mainard Esquires Sir Harbotle
Grimston Master of the Rolls Sir William Scrogs one of the Justices of the Common Pleas Sir John Barrington
Knight and Baronet Sir John Cotton Sir John Bendish Sir Henry Appleton Sir Benjamin Ayliffe Sir Francis Massam
Sir William Hicks Sir Andrew Jenour Sir William Wiseman Sir Thomas Nightingall Sir Richard Everard Baronets
Sir Capell Luckin Knight and Baronet Sir Martin Lumley Baronet Sir Thomas Abdy Knight and Baronet Sir Francis
Lawley Baronet Sir John Abdy Baronet Sir Thomas Litleton Baronet Sir William Wiseman Knight and Baronet
Sir Gervas Elwes Sir Benjamine Wright Sir James Rushout Sir Edward Smith Sir Phillip Mathewes Sir Thomas
Garret Sir Robert Smith Baronets Sir Francis Leake Knight and Baronet Sir William Adams Baronet Sir Richard
Browne Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Rich Baronet Sir John Brampston Knight of the Bath Sir Henry Clerke
Sir Richard Wiseman Sir Anthony Browne Sir Mundeford Brampston Sir Thomas Meeres Sir Richard Everard Sir
John Shaw Sir Thomas Fanshaw Sir William Holecroft Sir Gobart Barrington Sir Eliab Harvey Sir Edward Turner
Sir Edward Farmer Sir Marke Guyen Sir Thomas Midleton Knights Sir John Peake Knight Sir James Smith Knight
Francis Bramston Tristram Conyers Sergeants at Law Samuell Grimston Richard Samms Thomas Meade Robert
Cheeke Thomas Cheeke Peter Soame John Wroth Robert Clerke Oliver Raymond Thomas Argoll John Symonds William
Glascocke John Fanshaw John Lemott Honey wood Thomas Bowles Aurelius Percie Wiseman William Dawtree William
Mainard of Waltamstow John Tyndall Thomas Luther Thomas Turner John Turner Will: Humphreville John Pennington
Thomas Roberts William Appleton John Berners Robert Wood Do&bholigct;or of Lawes Richard Kirby William Cummins
Edward Bullocke John Higham Robert Bateman Francis Mildmay Thomas Smith Robert Mildmay senior Robert
Mildmay junior Henry Wright Samuell Hare Josiah Childe Alexander Prescot William Pert John Everard Brabason
Aylmer Francis Osbiston Thomas Weely William Vernon Henry Glascocke William Palmer Cuthbert Martin [Francis
James Roger Bradbury<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] Henry Ayloffe Giles Dent Richard Staines William Gore Mundiford Brampston Anthony
Godbolt John Eldred junior Anthony Knightbridge Samuell Reynolds George Scott William Nutt John Rotheram
John Marshall George Dashwood George Walton James Milbourne William Lingwood Richard Rich Richard
Luther William Webb John Cooke of Chishall Robert Sheffield Charles Hancocke Edward Rudge Richard Lightfoot
Tho: King Tho: Talcot Tho: Bland George Gent Edward Pascall Robert Cole Francis Leeke William Wade
Haynes Barley Esquires Zacariah Gee George James William Herris Jeremiah Lacey Thomas Cullam Henry
Southcott Richard Collins Richard Godbolt Charles Wale Richard Hyde Edward Thorowgood John Austin
Josuah Gallard Thomas Dawtree Gent. John Greene Gamaliell Capell Samuell Vincent and John Parsons Esquires
John Kirke.</para>
			<para id="p121">For the Burrough of Maulden.</para>
			<para id="p122">The Bayliffes for the time being Sir John Brampston Knight of the Bath High Steward Sir William Wiseman
Knight and Baronet Alderman Sir Richard Wiseman Knight Francis Brampston Sergeant at Law Recorder Anthony
Brampston Es&bhoqesq; Abell Hawkes Francis Gourney Samuell Pond Robert Jennies William Vernon Aldermen Robert
Page Gent..</para>
			<para id="p123">For the Burrough of Colchester</para>
			<para id="p124">The Maior for the time being Sir Harbotle Grimston Baronet Steward Sir John Shaw Knight Sambell Renolds
Thomas Talcott John Shaw William Mott Esquires Henry Lambe William Moore Jonathan Merry Ralph Creffield
William Flanner George Hammon John Reyner Nathaniell Laurence Aldermen Joseph Thurston Thomas Ruse
John Rebow Andrew Fromantell Thomas Greene Samuell Mott and Alexander Hindmers Gentlemen John Viccars
Customer John Viccars Surveyour of the Customs Jeremiah Molyne and Samuell Grent Gent. Abraham Heighton
Robert Moore.</para>
			<para id="p125">For the Burrough of Harwich.</para>
			<para id="p126">The Maior for the time being Sir Capell Luckyn Knight and Baronet Thomas King Es&bhoqesq; Sir Charles Litleton
Sir Anthony Deane Knights John Eldred Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Daniell Smith Towne Clerke Captaine Langley and Samuell
Newton Gent..</para>
			<para id="p127">For the County of Gloucester</para>
			<para id="p128">Charles Lord Herbert of Ragland sonne and heire apparent to the Marquesse of Worcester John Lord Viscount
Scudamore of the Kingdome of Ireland John Lord Viscount Tracy of the Kingdome of Ireland William Viscount
Downes of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Robert Atkins Knight of the Bath one of the Justices of the Court of
Common Pleas George Mountague Es&bhoqesq; Sir Charles Berkley Sir Henry Capell Knights of the Bath Sir John Tracy
Baronet Sir Bainham Throckmorton Knight and Baronet Sir William Hicks Sir Richard Ashfeild Sir Henry Fredericke
Thynne Sir Richard Howe Sir Richard Franklyn Sir William Juxon Sir William Keite Sir John Guise Sir John
Newton Sir John Fusse Sir Richard Cox Sir Robert Cann Baronets Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath Sir William
Catchmaid Sir Edmond Bray Sir Thomas Stephens Sir Thomas Overbury Sir Gabriell Lowe Sir Humphrey Hooke
Sir Thomas Howe Sir John Pointz Sir Scroope Howe Sir Robert Atkins junior Sir Duncombe Colchester Knights
Sir Giles Hungerford Sir Edward Bathurst Sir William Rich Baronets Evan Seyes Sergeant at Law John Grubham
Howe Henry Norwood Thomas Thynne Thomas Price Richard How William Cooke Thomas Master Ralph Dutton
John Winter Thomas Escourt Reginald Bray Giles Fettiplace Robert Codrington William Trye Miles Sandis John
Higford John Dennis John Bridgeman John Chamberlaine William Bourchier Thomas Chester Richard Atkins Richard
Stephens John Stephens Fleetwood Dormer Robert Pleydell William Leigh William Stratford Thomas Horton George
Pitt John Sackvile John Dalabere Thomas Barrow Edward Rich Anthony Sambach Benjamine Barret Thomas Jennings
Thomas Veele of Symonds Hall William Strafford William Cope John George William Morgan David Williams
Robert Bromage Thomas Marriott William Selwin John Smith Miles Rutter Henry Browne Thomas Rich Andrew
Barker James Stephens John Guise of Ablods-Court Robert Loggan Henry Powle John Meredeth Richard Baugh
Thomas Smith Phillip Sheppard Richard Norwood Robert Qldsworth William Oldsworth John Robins Edward
Smith William Guyse Robert Gonning William Woozley Henry Syms John Dowle Christopher Cole John Holmes
Paul Foley James Hawkins William Player Poole Pauncefoot William Wall John Lanegley Nicholas Veele Paul
Castleman Esquires James Thynne Francis Creswick John Seymour Thomas Cutler Thomas Rawlins Joseph Creswick
Henry Heylin John Coles John Stafford William Dowdeswell Charles Dowdeswell Henry Izard Richard Browne
Thomas Browne of Cortslawn Roger Lingen Hanger of Driffield Samuell Astry Hugh Browne Richard
Jones of Hanham Richard Hart Paul Dowdeswell Thomas Wise John Driver Edward Nott senior Edward Nott
junior William Banister William Gough Edmond Maddock John Pryor Edward [Macher<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Christopher Woodward
Thomas Pyrke George Bond of Redbrooke Conway Whitterne Roger Haverd Thomas Nanfan The Bayliffes of
Tewksbury for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p129">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester.</para>
			<para id="p130">William Russell Maior of the said Citty The Maior for the time being Evan Seyes Sergeant at Law Henry
Norwood Es&bhoqesq; Sir Duncombe Colchester Knight William Cooke William Selwin John Stanion Esquires Robert
Fielding Do&bholigct;or of Phisick Thomas Price John Wagstaffe Henry Fowler Thomas Aram John Geethings John Rogers
John Webbe Aldermen James Stephens Laurence Singleton Nicholas Webb Daniell Lysons John Marston Thomas
Pury Anthony Arnold William Scudamore William Hodges John Cromwell William Lambe Robert Payne William
Jordan Richard Boseley John Lugg Benjamine Hyett Cittizens.</para>
			<para id="p131">For the County of Hereford.</para>
			<para id="p132">John Lord Viscount Scudamore of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir John Kirle Sir William Powell Sir Thomas
Morgan Sir John Scudamore Sir John Holman Sir Herbert Croft Sir Thomas Williams Sir Bennet Hoskins Baronets
Sir Edward Harley Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Hanbury Sir Job Charleton Sir John Barnaby Sir Herbert
Perrott Sir John Payne Sir John Finely Sir John Hoskins Knights Sir Francis Winington His Majestyes Sollicitor
Generall Udall Tomkins Thomas Thynne Thomas Cornwell of Stepleton Castle Somerset Fox Thomas Price
Humphrey Cornwall John Birch Herbert Westfailing Reginald Graham Thomas Conningsbey of Hampton Court Es&bhoqesq;
John Morgan of Kinersley Wallop Brabason Walter Pye Robert Pye John Scudamore of Kenchurch Herbert Aubery
Richard Reede William Gregory Thomas Cox Thomas Harley James Pitt Edward Cornwall John Skipp Edward
Freeman Richard Hopton Thomas Geeres Humphrey Baskerville Humphrey Howorth Francis Unett John Arnold Es&bhoqesq;
Henry Milbourne John Barnaby of Brockhampton John Booth of Letton Paull Foley William Lambe John Nourse
Bridgstocke Harfford Robert Rodd George Skipp Marshall Bridges Younger Cooke Thomas Baskerville of Earsley
Francis Pember of Elsdon James Good Gent. Edwin Skrimsher Richard Williams of Cabalva Ambrose Elton Thomas
Delahay of Urrishay Francis Pemper of Nuperd Thomas Duppa Richard Barnby of Brockhampton Robert Cornwall
Herbert Perrott John Darnall junior Ferdinando Gorge James Lloyd of Kingston Edward Morgan John Williams
John Parrey of Dulesse Thomas Delahay of Alterynis Standasse Lloyd Edward Jones Lanwarne James Gregory
Esquiers George Cliffe of Wormbride John Dansy William Dansy Richard Snead High Sheriffe Guyles Rawlins
William Guyllim of Laneston George Carver of Battus Samuell Birch of Whitbourne Anthony Rowden Nicholas
Walwin Richard Walwyn of Hellens Thomas Rodd Martin Sandys of Cradley John Booth of Brainton Richard
Guyllim Es&bhoqesq; Robert Dobbins John Arnold William Mathews William Dansey of Greet William Westfaling Herbert
Masters Thomas Howorth of the Whitehouse Thomas Wigmore Thomas Berrington of Bishopston Thomas Berrington
of Litle Pyon John James Higgons James John Kirle of Rosse William Broome John Goodier of Burhope Thomas
Hopwood of Milton Michaell Braughton Essex Sherbourne Humphrey Tayler Thomas Carpenter of Tillington
Edward Lloyd of Batch Es&bhoqesq; Henry Hyett John Cornwall Francis Geeres of Garmons The Bayliffe of the Burrough
of Lemster John Tomkins Gent..</para>
			<para id="p133">For Lemster</para>
			<para id="p134">Peter Daunser Gent. William [Bedeler<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] William Bissell of Ledbury James Winston of Blackmore John Carver of
Upton Edward Ketleby John Gilbert Gentlemen Giles Bridges of Wilton Es&bhoqesq; Richard Marret of Pittow Thomas
Bridges of Brisbery James Good of Willocbridge Phillip Parrey of Brunton Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p135">For the Citty of Hereford</para>
			<para id="p136">The Maior for the time being John Lord Viscount Scudamore of the Kingdome of Ireland Herbert Westfaling
Thomas Price William Gregory Bridstocke Hartford Esquires Robert Symonds [Thom. Holmes Thom. Paynard Thom.
Clerk Thom. Bond Hugh Rodd Thomas Symonds<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] William Edwin Edward Rodd Richard Williams Roger Boulcott
John Cooke William Maylard John Barnes Abraham Seward Richard Wadley, Thomas Mathews Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p137">For the County of Hertford</para>
			<para id="p138">Sir Harbotle Grimston Master of the Rolls Sir Richard Francklin Knight and Baronet Sir John Mounson Sir Thomas
Leventhorpe Sir John Reede Sir Richard Spencer Sir John Witterongle Sir Richard Anderson Sir Jonathan Keate
Sir John Austin Sir Robert Joslin Sir Richard Atkins Sir William Leman Baronets Sir Phillip Boteler Knight of the
Bath Sir John Gore Sir Francis Boteler Sir Henry Blount Sir William Glascock Sir Edward Alston Sir Francis
Leigh Sir Charles Cesar Sir John Watts Sir Humphrey Gore Sir John Boteler Sir Thomas Byde Sir Charles Cleaver
Sir Robert Viner Sir Ralph Radcliffe Sir Robert Dacres Sir Benjamin Tichbourne Sir George Walker Knights Henry
Mounson Samuell Grimston William Lytton Thomas Lewis John Garrard Thomas Dockwra Richard Harrison
Richard Francklyn Ralph Freeman Thomas Preistley Thomas Pope Blount James Witterongle Mathew Blucke Richard
Goulston Henry Guy Silas Tytus Thomas Weeden James Goulston Nicholas Miller Skinner Byde Thomas Arris
Do&bholigct;or in Phisick George Cooper Edward Atkins Francis Shalcrosse Arthur Pulter Henry Baldwin Thomas Stanley
Thomas Chatterton Edward Wingate Thomas Carpenter Daniell Sheldon Thomas Atkins Richard Blackwell Thomas
Field George Nodes George Loe Edward Watts Richard Crofts Thomas Halsey James Willimot Edward Chester
William Hutchinson Edward Briscoe William Greenhill Arthur Sparks William Cotton Henry Childe John Eccleston
Edmund Smith John Briscoe Edmond Colles Ralph Gore Robert Robotham John Fotherley Edmund Prideaux Thomas
Nicholl of Bushy Thomas Saunders Henry Chauncy Anthony Farringdon John Weatherhead George Hadley George
Throckmorton Marmaduke Rawden senior Henry Dunstar Will: Nuce Richard Reeves Joshua [Lemax<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] John Ellis
Henry Meaux Marmaduke Rawden junior Francis King Rowland Litton Ralph Je[n]nings George Needham Thomas
Bird Thomas Arris Alexander Weld John Dios William Pecke Humphrey Hall William Crowley John Piott junior
The Maior of Hertford for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p139">For the Towne of Saint Albans</para>
			<para id="p140">Ralph Pollard Maior of the Towne for the time being Sir Harbotle Grimston Baronet Master of the Rolls Do&bholigct;or
Arris Samuell Grimston John Simpson Recorder Ralph Jennings Es&bhoqesq; Robert Robotham William Cotton Anthony
Farrington Thomas Arris Lewis Montgomery junior Thomas Cowley William Marston Thomas Oxten John New
John Cape John Doggett William Oxten William Rugg Thomas Eccleston John New junior William Marston junior
John Ellis Edmund Cotles George Lowe Josuah Lomax.</para>
			<para id="p141">For the County of Huntington</para>
			<para id="p142">Sir Francis Compton Knight George Mountague Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Cotton Sir John Hewet Sir Thomas Proby Sir John
Bernard Baronets Sir Nicholas Pedley Sir Lyonell Walden Knights John Cotton Stephen Anderson Robert Apprice
Silus Tytus John Dreydon John Heron Samuell Pepis Anthony Hammond Richard Nailer Sutton Ashfield Charles
Cesar John Trice Richard Elmes John Ferrar Nicholas Pedley Lyonell Walden Castell Sherrard Lewis Ethrington
William Connyers Esquires Robert Baldwin Albian Throgmorton John Bigg Robert Caveney Thomas Audley
Richard Winds William Nayler Simon Mason Thomas Shepherd William Moseley Robert Clarke.</para>
			<para id="p143">For the Towne of Huntington</para>
			<para id="p144">The Maior for the time being Sir John Cotton Baronet Sir Nicholas Pedley Sir Lyonell Walden Knights Nicholas
Pedley Lyonell Walden Esquires William Fulwood Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke Richard Astry Samuell Poynt James Faireside
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p145">For the County of Kent</para>
			<para id="p146">Phillip Viscount Strangford of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Vere Fane Knight of the Honourable Order of the
Bath John Tufton Richard Tufton Sackvile Tufton Esquires Sir Thomas Twisden one of the Justices of the Kings
Bench Sir William Wilde one of the Justices of the Kings Bench Sir Phillip Howard Knight Sir Thomas Peyton Sir
William Twisden Sir Edward Hales Sir Henry Palmer Sir John Rivers Sir Richard Meridith Sir Edward Deereing
Sir Oliver Butler Sir Norton Knatchbull Sir John Tufton Sir John Raney Sir Robert Hales Baronets William
Viscount Downe of Ireland Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir Stephen Leonard Sir Humphrey Miller Sir John Marsham
Sir John Bancks Sir William Honywood Sir Robert Barnham Sir Thomas Pierce Sir Nathaniell Powell Sir John
Austin Sir Thomas Seylard Sir Jonathan Keete Sir Anthony Aucher Sir Henry Oxenden Sir Francis Clerke Sir
Thomas Godfrey Sir Thomas Engham junior Sir Richard Powell Knight of the honourable Order of the Bath Sir
Phillip Warwicke Sir John Darrell Sir Thomas Scott Sir Thomas Culpeper Sir William Wiseman Baronet Sir
Theophilus Biddulph Baronet Sir William Boreman Sir Bernard Hyde Sir William Swan Baronet Sir Robert Filmer
Baronet Sir John Heath Attourney of the Dutchy of Lancaster Sir Thomas Lee Sir William Boothby Baronet Sir
Thomas Whitmore Sir James Oxenden Sir Thomas Hardresse His Majestyes Sergeant at Law Edward Hales of
Tunstall Es&bhoqesq; John Stroud Es&bhoqesq; Lieftenant of Dover Castle Sir James Rushout John Boys of Fredvill Thomas
Hales of Beaksborne Thomas Peake John Cropley Thomas Crispe of Queaks Thomas Hardresse Esquires Walter
Breames Christopher Vane Es&bhoqesq; James Masters of Langdon James Masters of Yokes Thomas Turner William Rooke
Henry Oxindin of Brooks Richard Aldworth Herbert Randolph Nicholas Tooke of Goddington Henry Thornhill
of Allanty John Knatchbull James Brockman Henry Deering Edward Hales Richard Hulse John Nailer Robert
Lutkner Peter Hamond John Moyle Zouch Brockman Phillip Warwick Thomas Flood William Cage Francis
Barnham Sir Demetrius James Anthony Irby Esquier Ferdinando Marsham Es&bhoqesq; Sir George Curtis Richard Kilbourne
Es&bhoqesq; Edward Gresham Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Knatchbull Richard Wilkenson Thomas Mun Ralph Buskin Walter Francklin
Richard Marsh Thomas English Thomas Harlackendon Henry Hawdon Alabaster Flood Captaine John Clerke
Richard Duke William Maddox William Stonywood The Maior of Rochester for the time being George Newman
Es&bhoqesq; Richard Manley Es&bhoqesq; Sir Richard Head Baronet Sir Charles Bickerstaffe Knight Francis Barrell Sergeant at
Law Francis Head Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Style Baronet Thomas Manley Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Brewer Samuell Boyce [Esq[ui]rs<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] Edward
Finch Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Bunch Baronet Phillip Packer George Polhill Henry Gilbourne Marke Cottle Esquires John
Hyde Sir William Hooker Knight Northon Curtis Edward Curtis Robert Heath Francis Heath John Eveling Sir
Eliab Harvey Knight Thomas Papillon of Aucridge William Swan Thomas Selyard Christopher Allison Es&bhoqesq; Ralph
Petley John Bridger Francis Farnaby Edward Bagby George Gifford Paul Eps Robert Clerkson Sir John Williams
Humphrey Withwick Sir Anthony Maney Thomas Petley Es&bhoqesq; John Sydney James Thurbone George Boreman Es&bhoqesq;
Sir John Hinden Knight William Hammond of St Albanes Esq[ui]rs William Campian Thomas Andrews Edward Gulston
Reynold Peckham Edward Short Robert Austin Richard Breton Sir Henry Boswell Knight Mr Henry Sandys Sir
Percivall Hart M<emph type="p">r</emph> Edward Manning Edmond Tooke Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Shaw Baronet John Luckin Michaell Chidwick
Piercy Goreing William Kingsley Roger Paine Es&bhoqesq; Sir Robert Faunce Knight Sir Nicholas Strode Sir Richard Ford
Archibald Clinkard John Henley Edward Dcering Edwyn Wyatt Cressell Draper George Duke Es&bhoqesq; Samuell Plummer
John Cooke Sir Francis Leake Sir Francis Leigh Sir Leoline Jenkins Thomas Fane Es&bhoqesq; Anthony Nowers Julius
Deeds Edward Master Es&bhoqesq; Charles Wheeler Joseph Finch John Marsham Es&bhoqesq; Mr Thomas Gombledon Sir George
Moore Baronet William Trumball Do&bholigct;or of Laws John Plummer Es&bhoqesq; Henry Frere Es&bhoqesq; Christopher Wade
Gent. Cresheild Draper Thomas Gifford Edward King Richard Mathews [Heny
<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Querman John Coney Phillip
Bartlemew Gentlemen Francis Leake Es&bhoqesq; James Codd Thomas Hooper Es&bhoqesq; Edmond Steed of Bidenden William
Ash Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Cutler Knight and Baronet Peter Godfrey Es&bhoqesq; The Bayliffe of Rumney Marsh for the time being
The Expenditers of Rumney Marsh for the time being Humphrey Wightwick Gent. John Buggin Es&bhoqesq; John Bloome
Es&bhoqesq; Christopher May Gent. The Maior of Maidstone for the time being Henry Parker Es&bhoqesq; James Cripps Gent. Sir
John Fagge Baronet George Cowper Es&bhoqesq; James Paine John Hunt John Murall Gent. Roger Twisden Sir John
Griffith Francis Withens Sir Phillip Honywood John Smith of Chart Es&bhoqesq;, Roger Luckyn of Winderton Captaine
Gratian Linch Captaine Courthop John Ady Christopher Mason Richard Hopkins Es&bhoqesq; Paul Barrett Es&bhoqesq; William
Lambard Es&bhoqesq; Richard Betonson Es&bhoqesq; John Thurbourne Es&bhoqesq; Sir Stephen Leonard Baronet William Hugeson Es&bhoqesq;
Gideon Delawne Es&bhoqesq; Nathaniell Darrell Es&bhoqesq; John Rusfen James Tong Nicholas Cooke Gent. John Piercevall Robert
Cage Mathew Tomlinson Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p147">For the Citty and County of Canterbury.</para>
			<para id="p148">The Maior for the time being Sir Edward Master Knight Sir Thomas Hardresse His Majestyes Sergeant at Law
Recorder Thomas Hindon William Man Edward Master Edward Nutt Captaine Kingleys Captaine Hilles Esquires
Squire Beverton Thomas Elwin Thomas Knowler John Lott Aldermen John Knowler Thomas Turner Es&bhoqesq;.</para>
			<para id="p149">For the Towne and Port of Sandwich</para>
			<para id="p150">The Maior for the time being John Thurburne Water Bayliffe Phineas Eldwood James Thurburne John Verrier
Valentine Jenkin Jeffery Wells Jeffery Sackett Edward Elsted John Pantry Peter Nowell.</para>
			<para id="p151">For the Towne and Port of Dover</para>
			<para id="p152">The Maior for the time being Thomas Tiddeman Captaine Edward Roberts John Matson Richard Jacobs Walter
Breams Es&bhoqesq; Do&bholigct;or Goulder George West Edward Wivell William Richards Nichollas Cullen John Bullocke
Nathaniell Denew Richard Breton Fredericke de Vinck Symon Yorke William Stokes Charles Valey Francis
Bastinck Aaran Wellard senior.</para>
			<para id="p153">For the Towne and Port of Rumney.</para>
			<para id="p154">The Maior for the time being William Lancaster John Bryan Peter Lancaster John Shoesmith James Paine John
Hunt John Maskell.</para>
			<para id="p155">For the Towne and Port of Hith.</para>
			<para id="p156">The Maior for the time being Robinson Beane William Knight Elias Bassett John Bassett George Thurburne
Robert Johnson.</para>
			<para id="p157">For the Towne of Fordwich.</para>
			<para id="p158">The Maior for the time being Thomas Norton Samuell Short.</para>
			<para id="p159">For the Towne of Feversham</para>
			<para id="p160">The Maior for the time being Robert Watson Es&bhoqesq; Marke Trouts Thomas Southerest Thomas Napleton Simon
Steede Thomas Sowthon.</para>
			<para id="p161">For the Towne of Folkeston</para>
			<para id="p162">The Maior for the time being Clement Pregle Captaine Jenkin.</para>
			<para id="p163">For the Towne of Lid</para>
			<para id="p164">The Bayliffe of Lid for the time being John Bateman John Barton William Sudell John Bateman Thomas
Beddingfield Henry Potter Michaell Chidwick William Glover.</para>
			<para id="p165">For the Towne of Tenterden.</para>
			<para id="p166">The Maior for the time being Sir Edward Hales Robert Austin Es&bhoqesq; Edward Short Edward Finch.</para>
			<para id="p167">For the County of Lancaster</para>
			<para id="p168">Sir Rob: Carr Chauncellour of the Dutchy Charles Earle of Ancram of the Kingdome of Scotland Richard Lord
Gorge of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir William Egerton Knight of the Bath William Spencer the elder Es&bhoqesq;
Charles Gerrard Es&bhoqesq; Henry Booth Es&bhoqesq; Sir Richard Haughton Sir John Mollineux Sir Robert Bindlosse Sir Garvase
Elwes Sir Ralph Ashton of Midleton Sir Richard Standish Baronets Sir Edward Moore Sir Roger Bradshaigh Sir
John Arderne Sir Jeffery Shackerley Sir John Heath Sir Peter Brooke Sir Thomas Stringer Sir Edward Chisnell Sir
John Otway Knights Alexander Rigby Es&bhoqesq; High Sheriffe Thomas Preston the elder Richard Leigh Edward
Rigby Sergeant at Law Richard Kirkby Richard Atherton John Harrison Mathew Richardson John Birch Daniell
Fleming Miles Dodding William Spencer the younger Thomas Preston the younger William Kirkby Curwin
Rawlinson Edward Wilson junior Thomas Cole Esquires The Maior of Lancaster for the time being Christopher
Carnes William Fleming Roger Fleming William Knipe Roger Towlinson Thomas Sheirson Josua Partington William
Waller John Greenwood Francis Medcalfe John Kirkby Gentlemen Charles Houghton Edward Warren Richard
Fleetwood John Warren Alexander Rigby at Layton Christopher Parker Thomas Butler Alexander Johnson Allen
Pricket Esquires William Lemon Maior of Preston William Langton Captaine Ralph Longworth George Sharples
James Lowd Thomas Hodgkinson Thomas Winckley Do&bholigct;or Cuerden William Wall John Kellet Luke
Hodgkinson William Werden Gent. Richard Shutleworth Roger Nowell Thomas Bradyll Thomas Parker
Nicholas Townley John Parker George Halstead Richard Asheton of Cuerdall Ralph Livesay Christopher
Wilkinson Thomas Lacey Thomas Holden Henry Marsden Esquires The Bayliffes of Clidderow for the time being
Edward Richton William Appleton Peers Starkey William Crombock John Lister William Yates Abraham Townley
Robert Hamond Nicholas Cuncliffe Ambrose Barcroft Gentlemen Henry Haughton Edward Fleetwood Henry
Farrington Christopher Banistre Richard Brooke Hugh Cooper John Crosse Stephen Rodley Peter Adlington Esquires
Edward Dickenson Gentlemen M<emph type="p">r</emph> Wilson of Tunley Peter Bold Thomas Hescath Thomas [Nones
<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] Henry Sclatter
John Rishley Roger Bradshaigh James Dockinfield John Antwisely Edward Doboson Thomas Bishpham Edward Herle
John Ashton William Daniell Jeffery Holdcroft Thomas Latham Esquires The Maior of Wiggam for the time being
The Maior of Leverpoole for the time being Silvester Richmond Oliver Lyme John Chaundler Thomas Bicksteth
John Bretherton Paul Moreau Robert Roper Nicholas Fazackerly Thomas Turner Alexander Radcliffe John Widdowes
Richard Molineux of Hawkley Thomas Johnson Peter Lurtinge James Vernon Es&bhoqesq; James Holt Thomas Leigh
Alexander Butterworth Lawrence Rostorne Thomas Greenhalgh William Hilton Leonard Egerton John Hartley
Edward Moseley James Lightbowne William Hulme of Kersley William Hulme of Davids-Hulme Oswald Mosely
John Byrom Roger Kenyon Ralph Browne William Northington James Chetham of Turton James Chetham of
Smedley Robert Heywood John Hopwood Richard Holt Thomas Levor Ferdinando Stanley Esquires Ralph Eddowes
William Leigh John Birch Gent..</para>
			<para id="p169">For the County of Leicester</para>
			<para id="p170">William [Sheffington<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] Es&bhoqesq; High Sheriffe of the County Thomas Lord Beaumont of the Kingdome of Ireland
John Lord Roos sonne and heire apparent of the Earle of Rutland Bennett Lord Sherrard of the Kingdome of
Ireland Anchitall Gray John Gray Esquires Sir George Villiers Sir Robert Sherley Sir Thomas Halford Sir Wolston
Dixie Sir Lewis Palmer Sir Henry Hudson Sir Edward Smith Sir Henry Beaumont Sir Thomas Helebridge Baronets
Sir William Hartopp Sir William Ellis Sir Thomas Meeres Sir Thomas Dolman Sir William Hatford Sir John Heath
Knights Phillip Sherrard William Villiers George Faunt Jeffery Palmer Richard Lister John de-la-Fountaine Richard
Verney Thomas Boothby William Boothby Beaumont Dixie William Hartopp Thomas Babington Henry Kendall Silas
Tytus Saint John Bennett Thomas Caldicott John Hartopp William Cole John Hacket Samuell Cotton Thomas Pochin
John Crew William Beaumont William Streete John Stafford Thomas Stanley Walter Rudeings William Whaley
Stanhop Whaley Roger Roe George Pochin Christopher Pack Henry Hastings Jeremy Dove Mathew Johnson
William Francks George Hewett Richard Brudnell Edward Needham John Needham Francis Needham Richard
Orton William Frimnell Robert Bernard Richard Halford Thomas Food Richard Bradgate Francis Chamberlaine Henry
Farnham William Bainbrigg John Bainbrigg John Benskin John Fowler John Barwell Esquires and Gentlemen Cassibitan
Burton Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Goddard Gent. Sir John Hartop Baronet Randall Middlecure Sir William Knight.</para>
			<para id="p171">For the Burrough of Leicester.</para>
			<para id="p172">Edmund Sutton Maior and the Maior for the time being Alexander Baker John Cley Francis Noble William Alsop
Edmond Townsend William Southwell Thomas Overinge Andrew Freeman William Deane Robert Hartshorne and
George Becket Aldermen William Francks Esquire John Herrick Edward Palmer senior Edward Browne William
Mayor and Laurence Carter Gent William Billiers Gent.</para>
			<para id="p173">For the County of Lincolne.</para>
			<para id="p174">George Lord Viscount Castleton of the Kingdome of Ireland John Lord Rods sonne and heire apparent of the
Earle of Rutland John Lord Burleigh sonne and heire apparent to the Earle of Exeter Robert Lord Willoughby
sonne and heire apparent of the Earle of Lindsey Bennet Lord Sherwood of the Kingdome of Ireland Henry Lord
O Bryan of the Kingdome of Ireland William Peirpoint Peregryne Bartue Richard Bartue Charles Bartue Esquires
Sir Francis Fane Knight of the Bath Sir Robert Carr Knight and Baronet Chauncellour of the Dutchy and County
Pallatine of Lancaster William Mountague Lord Cheife Baron [Henry<ref idref="n22">22</ref>] Noell Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Munson Sir Thomas
Hussey Sir William Thorold Sir John Newton Sir John Bromlowe Sir Robert Markham Sir William Trollop Sir
William Hickman Sir Richard Rothwell Sir Humphrey Winch Sir Christopher Wray Sir Carr Scroope Sir John
Bolles Sir William Ellis Baronet Sir Richard Earle Baronet Sir Thomas Meeres Knight Sir John Bennet Knight of
the [Bennet Knight of the<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Bath Sir John Morton Sir William Ellis Knight Sergeant at Law Sir Edward Ascough
Sir Henry Massingberd Sir Thomas Skipwith Sergeant at Law Sir Drayner Massingberd Sir Will: Yorke Sir Charles
Dymmock Sir Christopher Clapham Sir Christopher Menille Sir Edmund Turner Knights Sir Henry Heron Knight
of the Bath Sir William Humble Baronet Sir Anthony Irby Knight Sir Phillip Harcourt Baronet Rutland Sanderson
Henry Moverson Es&bhoqesq; John Hatcher William Marwood senior Michaell Lister William Godfrey Cesill Tyrwhitt Charles
Pelham Charles Sanderson William Broxholme Henry Fane William Lister Richard Ryley Thomas Farmer Edward
Payne Thomas Hatcher John Saunders Redmayne Burrell Francis Wingfeild Anthony Tredway William Welby Lister
Teigh John Newton Francis Stringer Anthony Palmer Edmund Syler Charles Bates Esquires The Maior and the six senior
Aldermen of the Citty of Lincolne for the time being The Maior of Stamford for the time being The Maior of Great
Grimsby for the time being The Maior of Boston for the time being The Alderman of Grantham for the time being
Mountague Cholmley William Trollop Henry Hall William Saville Stephen Rothwell Peregrine Buck Richard Pell
George Sanderson Edward Marbury Stephen Mason George Hearley Darcy Stanhope John Farmery of Morthorpe
Edward Tourney Robert Sanderson Marmaduke Darrell William Fitzwilliams George Neville George Midlemore
Charles Woolley Christopher Pym Thomas Hall of Ketlthorpe Francis Grantham Vincent Grantham William
Berrisford Bever Cornwallis Esquires Anthony Eyre Es&bhoqesq; Henry Stone Anthony Williams Robert Laning John
Colthurst Thomas Harrington Miles Long Augustin Conedron Cornelius Hall Gent. Edward Browne of Horbling
Gent. Anthony Irby Es&bhoqesq; Samuell Browne John Bolt William Wilson John Empson Joseph Whiteing Adlard Welby
David Bonnell Henry Burrell Bever Wimberley Israell Jackson Richard Milner William Howell Doctor of Lawes
Edward Sturton Doctor of Phisick Charles Bawes John Shaw Daniell Wigmore Daniell Thorowgood, William Dickenson
John Burton of Spalding Gent William Mallett Martin Forster Es&bhoqesq; John Oldfield Peter Balder John Butler Francis
Johnson of Spalding Lawson Lawrence Stamford Christopher Aiscough John Eely Richard Curst Edward
Nelthorpe John Boswell Charles Newcomen George Knight Charles Radley George Langton Christopher Clayton
William Popple John Smith William Hooten William Marwood junior Robert Sandis Thomas Coventry George
Whitchcote James Harrington John South Charles Anderson Samuell Ludington Robert Long of Kirkby William
Hall of Lincolne Nicholas Smith of Thetlethorpe Francis Auscough Thomas Auscough John Freeson George Fairefax
William Pirkins Thomas Grant Robert Goodall Mr Woodrofe of Corby Robert Hurst of Barrowby Gent William
Goodall Gent John Greene of Dunsby Mr Ashton of Grantham.</para>
			<para id="p175">For the Citty of London.</para>
			<para id="p176">The Right Honourable Sir Thomas Davies Knight Lord Maior and the Lord Maior for the time being Sir
William Wilde Knight and Baronet Sir Richard Cheverton Knight Sir Thomas Allen Knight and Baronet Sir
John Fredericke Knight Sir John Robinson Knight and Baronet Sir John Lawrence Sir Thomas Bludworth Sir
William Turner Sir Richard Ford Sir George Waterman Sir Robert Hanson Sir William Hooker Knights Sir
Robert Viner Knight Baronet Sir Joseph Sheldon Knight Sir William Dolben Knight Recorder and The Recorder
for the time being Sir Francis Chaplin Sir James Edwards Sir Robert Clayton Sir Patience Ward Sir John Moore
Sir William Pritchard Sir Henry Tulse Sir James Smith Sir Nathaniell Herne Sir Robert Jeffers Sir John Shorter
Sir Thomas Gould Knights Aldermen Sir John Peake Sir Thomas Stampe Knights Sheriffes Sir John Lethuillieur
Sir William Thompson Sir Theophilus Biddulph Sir Thomas Plaier Sir Thomas Meeres Sir Arthur Ingram Sir
Andrew King Knights John Joliffe Henry Dunstar William Love John Jones John Bence Thomas Papillon George
Jefferies Erasmus Smith James Hayes Esquires Richard Mills William Gibbons John Short Gent John Nicholas
Es&bhoqesq; Henry Loads Josiah Childe Sir Samuell Bernardiston Edward Turgis John du Boys Thomas Pilkington Sir
Eliab Harvey James Houblon Sir John Cope Sir Thomas Clergis Sir Phillip Mathews John Jefferis Es&bhoqesq; Sir
Leolyne Jenkins Sir Robert Wiseman Francis Warner William Williams Humphrey Cliffe Allen Cliffe Charles
Thorold Richard Lightfoote John Bathurst Mr Ralph Boxe Edward Waldoe Gervase Price Walter Lapp Lawrence
Blomley John Lane Esquires Sir Francis Pemberton Knight His Majestyes Sergeant at Law Sir John King Knight
Thomas Jenner Es&bhoqesq; Samuell Pepys Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Cox Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke.</para>
			<para id="p177">For the County of Midlesex.</para>
			<para id="p178">The Right Honourable Edward Seymour Es&bhoqesq; Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons Sir George Carteret
Knight and Baronet Vice-chamberlaine of His Majestyes Household Henry Coventry and Sir Joseph Williamson
Principall Secretaries of State Sir John Erneley Chauncellor of the Exchequer Sir Robert Carr Knight and Baronet
Chauncellor of the Dutchy of Lancaster Sir John Duncombe Knight Sir Richard Rainsford Lord Cheife Justice
of the Kings Bench Sir Harbotle Grimston Baronet Master of the Rolls Sir Francis North Lord Cheife Justice
of the Common Pleas William Montague Lord Cheife Baron Sir Thomas Twisden Baronet one of the Justices of the
Kings Bench Sir William Wilde Knight and Baronet one of the Justices of the Kings Bench Sir Timothy Litleton
Knight one of the Barons of the Exchequer Sir Hugh Windham Knight one of the Justices of the Common Pleas
Sir Robert Atkins Knight of the Bath one of the Justices of the Common Pleas Sir Edward Thurland one of the
Barons of the Exchequer Vere Bertue one of the Barons of the Exchequer, Sir Thomas Jones one of the Justices
of the Kings Bench Sir William Scroggs one of the Justices of the Common Pleas George Montague Daniell Finch
Henry Brunkard Thomas Killigrew Edward Progers Henry Seymore Esquires Sir William Hicks Baronet Sir Francis
Gerrard Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Litleton Baronet Sir John Mainard Knight one of His Majestyes Sergeants
at Law Sir William Jones Knight His Majestyes Attourney Generall Sir Francis Winnington Knight His Majestyes
Sollicitor Generall Sir James Butler Attourney Generall to the Queenes Majestie Sir John Trevor Sir William
Boyer Baronet Sir John Robinson Knight and Baronet Lieutenant of the Tower of London Sir Jeremy Whichcott
Baronett Sir John Lowther Baronet Sir Joseph Ash Baronet Sir John Cutler Knight and Baronet Sir Robert Viner
Knight and Baronet Sir Reginald Foster Baronet Sir William Roberts Baronet Sir Thomas Wolstenholme Baronet
Sir Phillip Mathews Baronet Sir John Bennet Knight of the Bath Sir John Bramston Knight of the Bath
Sir Edmond Windham Knight Marshall of His Majestyes Household Sir Charles Harbord Knight His Majestyes
Surveyour Generall Sir Anthony S<emph type="p">t</emph> Legar Sir Charles Lee Sir William Palmer Sir Thomas Allen Sir Allen Apsley
Sir John Talbot Knights Sir Thomas Meeres Sir Fredericke Hyde Knight and Sergeant at Law to Her Majestie
Sir Phillip Warwicke Knight Sir John Howell Knight Sir Lancelott Lake Sir William Poultney Sir John Babor Sir Phillip
Howard Sir James Smith Sir Thomas Player Sir Allen Broderick Sir Thomas Byde Knight Sir Thomas Escourt
Knight one of the Masters of Chauncery Sir Robert Hanson Sir Gilbert Gerrard of Harrow Sir Paul Whitchcott
Sir James Griffith Sir George Charnocke Sir Robert Southwell Clerke of His Majesties most Honourable Privy
Councill Sir Thomas Foster Sir Thomas Oftley Sir Jeremy Smith Sir Edmund Godfrey Sir William Bowles Sir
Thomas Stringer Sir John James Sir John Churchill Attourney Generall to the Duke of Yorke Sir Edward Rich
Christopher Wren Do&bholigct;tor of Lawes Surveyour of His Majesties Workes Humphrey Weld William Ashburnham
George Pitt Francis King Charles Cheney George Marsh Charles Bennet George Jefferies Francis Crawley Henry
Barber Clerke of the Crowne John Philip one of His Majestyes Auditors of the Exchequer John Tuppett Mathew
Bluck Roger Jennings John Bill Thomas Midleton Samuell Pepes Richard Peacocke Nicholas Townley William
Wardow Thomas Baler John Trevor Es&bhoqesq; Nicholas Rainton Ralph Hawtry Thomas Roe Thomas Robinson Humphrey
Worley John Carew Thomas Povery Sir Robert Filmore Baronet James Clitherow Richard Dunton Thomas Rosse
John Hawtry Edward Walcop Richard Adams Sir Charles Pitfield Henry Hawley James Smith Henry Elwes William
Goldsborough Thomas Thomlins John Harvey John Ball William Glascock Martin Clifford Henry Renwell Richard
Lightfoote Auditor Richard Mountney George Hill John Baker William Wood Henry Hodges Leonard Hamond
Christopher Blake Peter Sabbs John Swanley Richard Bayley Josian Rycroft John Jones Richard Morley Sir
Cerill Wich Sir John Bernard Baronet Sir Richard Francklin Knight and Baronet Pawlet Saint-John John
Wolstenholme Esquires Francis Brampston Sergeant at Law Sir William Smith Baronet Thomas Owen William
Wogan Daniell Waldoe Edward Waldoe John Thoope Esquires Thomas Nappier Es&bhoqesq; Sir William Bolton Knight
Richard Harrison Es&bhoqesq; Symon Smith George Day John Pulford Erasmus Smith John Pawlet John Jolley John
Lloyd Richard Cheney William Fenn Jasper Churchill Charles Hencock Anthony Collins Henry Collins William
Northey Sir Roger Langley Baronet Thomas Lewis Es&bhoqesq; David Walter Es&bhoqesq; John Bathurst Es&bhoqesq; Josua Beale Es&bhoqesq;
Thomas Austin Es&bhoqesq; Lawrence Blomley Es&bhoqesq; Sir Edward Deering Baronet Sir William Beversham one of the Masters
of Chauncery Edmund Draper Thomas Owen Henry Devenish John Elwes Knight John Parsons Henry Parker
Sir Edward Abney Knight Mathew Bluck Robert Forsett Nicholas Courtney Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Trevor Knight John
Trevor Esquire John Walker Gentleman Roger Gardiner Roger Stoughton Esquires Sir John Burkenhead Thomas
Arain Richard Morley Henry Slingsby Esquires Sir Theodore De vaux Sir, Gilbert Talbott (<ref idref="n24">24</ref>) Edward Law Robert
Blaney Edward Lee Esquires Josua Beale Sir Edward Carteret Sir William Thompson James Cooper Richard May
Justinian Pagitt John Hutchinson Es&bhoqesq; William Page Sir Thomas Allen Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Clergis
Sir James Rushout Baronet Sir Thomas Cooke Sir Thomas Marsh Sergeant Newdigate James Houbland Robert
Sawyer Simon Parry John Shalem William Prettiraan Edward Byde Henry Sawyer [Es&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] William Meggs Josua
Gallard Robert Clerkson William Richards Roger Gillingham Joseph Dawson Thomas Monck Edward Bascowen
Es&bhoqesq; Sir William Wanon Henry Johnson Es&bhoqesq; Captaine Isaac Woodgreene Humphrey Nicholson Esquires Richard
Cheney Joseph Lowden Robert Houlden Richard Bolt Friend John Sharpe Edward Alsop Thomas Johnson Esquires
Henry Till Arnold Browne Rainsford Waterhouse Thomas Lewis Es&bhoqesq; Nicholas Osborne Es&bhoqesq; John Swanley Es&bhoqesq;
Thomas Thomlins Roberts Es&bhoqesq; of Brumley Sir Edmond Bowyer Baronet Anthony Row William
Rawlinson Thomas Bromhall Roger Gardiner Esquires Thomas Cox junior Es&bhoqesq; William Wood Sir Charles
Cotterell Phillip Froud Esquire Sir John Bancks Baronet Robert Forsett Abraham Nelson Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p179">For the Citty of Westminster and the Liberties thereof.</para>
			<para id="p180">Henry Lord Cavendish Sonne and heire apparent to the Earle of Devonshire Charles Lord Clifford sonne and
heire apparent to the Earle of Burlington George Mountague Es&bhoqesq; Edward Sackville Es&bhoqesq; Sir Edward Carteret
Sir Kingsmill Lucy Sir John Nicholas Sir Allen Apsley Sir Thomas Litleton Sir Charles Cotterell Sir John Bennet
Sir Phillip Warwicke Sir Richard Everard Sir Michaell Heneage Sir Robert Howard Sir Phillip Howard Sir Robert
Carr Sir Phillip Mathews Sir George Carteret Sir Edmond Windham Sir William Haward Sir John Trevor
Sir William Pountney Sir Peter Colliton Sir Theodore De vaux Sir Richard Wiseman Sir John Griffith Sir Edward
Brett Sir Edmund Bury Godfrey Sir Walter Clergis Sir John Cotton Sir Phillip Meadowes Sir Charles Harbord
Sir Francis Hollis Sir Thomas Meeres Sir George Downing Sir William Doyley senior [Sir William Doyley junior
Sir John Talbott<ref idref="n26">26</ref>] Sir Thomas Mompesson Sir Anthony Irby Sir James Smith Sir Cerill Wich Sir Foulke Lucy
Sir John Cutter Sir Richard Mason Sir Richard Dolbin Sir Robert Filmore Sir Robert Pye Sir Thomas Clergis
Sir Richard Graham Sir John Copleston Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir Edward Graves Sir John Birkenhead Sir
William Orby Sir Thomas Woodcocke Sir William Gerrard Sir William Boreman Sir Robert Southwell Clerke of
His Majestyes most Honourable Privy Councill Sir Phillip Lloyd Sir Christopher Wrenn Sir Gilbert Talbott Sir
James Hayes Sir Richard Blake Lawrence Hyde Es&bhoqesq; Sir Richard Langley Sir John Hinton John Harvey Es&bhoqesq;
Do&bholigct;or Sydenhain Peregrine Bartue David Walter Henry Bronkard Edwin Sandys William Ashburnham Edmond
Waller Phillip Packer William Harbord Bernard Greenvile John Tregonwell Samuell Pepis Christopher Vane
Reynald Graham Thomas Thynnc John Strod Governour of Dover Hugh Biscowen Edmond Warcup Richard
Newman Essex Strode Mathew Locke Henry Progers John Browne Edward Boscowen Richard Lucy George
Legg Francis Lucy Henry Herbert Roger Higgs Edward Griffin John Currance Do&bholigct;or Warner George Jefferies
William Clascocke George Nicholas George Farewell Hugh May Francis Knowles James Dewye Humphrey
Worley senior Michaell Mallet Thomas Bayles Do&bholigct;or Samuell Barrowe Thomas Morrice Walter Brydell Butler
Kinkead Bevis Lloyd John Baggeley Es&bhoqesq; Simon Smith John Mann Richard Pagett Michaell Brighouse Lancelott
Thornton Hugh Squire Charles Hinton John Baynes Captaine Boheye Emery Hill Humphrey Worley junior
George Hill John Russell Thomas Haywood William Wardour Edward Clarke Thomas Bayley Robert Harcourt
John Walker Thomas Russell Ambrose Scudamore Do&bholigct;or Barwicke David Lloyd John Clutterbucke Richard Smith
Nicholas Baxter Thomas Crumpe Abraham Harrison John Ball Do&bholigct;or Clarke Bartholimew Vermuden Henry
Slingsby William Blake Jasper Churchill John Chase George Cooper William Morgan Henry Shalcrosse William
Bookey Ralph Marshall John Lugg Richard Wheeler Richard Bull John Minshen John Lesson Michaell Arnoll
George Plucknet Nicholas Edlyn Maurice Hunt Thomas Halfepenny Richard Mill Thomas Tyndall Thomas Warner
John Greene Nehemiah Arnold Ralph Halsey Henry Symonds Miles Mitchell Richard Farthing Christopher Sheene
William Wheeler Peter Griffith Charles Rampayne William Austin John Fisher Samuell Baker Maurice Kingwell
George Browne Thomas Butler Edmond Doyley Henry Montague John Lockier John Watts Robert Blaney Job
Williams Thomas Symonds Robert Newman Arthur Pryor Robert White William Williams John Dunn John Snell
Edward Younger Henry Pecke and Giles Masters Gentlemen Captaine Graham Francis Stevens John Lawrence and
John Lovying Esquires Maurice Hunt and Samuell Baker Gentlemen Nathaniell Stoughton Es&bhoqesq; William Hawkins
Pagitt Henry Aldridge Edward Gawen Robert Nott and James Smithsby Esquires George Bennett
Richard May Daniell Finch Sir William Walter Baronet Sir William Jones his Majestyes Attourney Generall Sir
John Bankcs Baronet Sir Thomas Daniell William Thoresby Baptist May Bevis Lloyd Thomas Gilbert Henry
Fanshaw and Arthur Sparke Esquires Samuell Vincent John Trevor and Francis Gwyn.</para>
			<para id="p181">For the County of Monmouth</para>
			<para id="p182">Charles Lord Herbert sonne and heire apparent to the Marquesse of Worcester Henry Herbert Es&bhoqesq; Sir Bainham
Throckmorton Baronet Sir Edward Morgan Baronet Sir Charles Kemes Baronet Sir Trevor Williams Baronet Sir
Thomas Morgan Barronet Sir Herbert Evans Knight William Morgan of Tredegar Es&bhoqesq; Richard Lewis Es&bhoqesq; Edmond
Thomas Es&bhoqesq; Edward Morgan Es&bhoqesq; Trevor Williams Es&bhoqesq; Henry Probert Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Lewis Es&bhoqesq; Charles Van Es&bhoqesq;
William Kemys Es&bhoqesq; James Herbert of Colbrooke Es&bhoqesq; John Arnold Es&bhoqesq; Edward Proger Es&bhoqesq; Collonell Charles
Proger Thomas Morgan of Llanrumney Es&bhoqesq; John Cary Es&bhoqesq; David Lewis Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Folio Es&bhoqesq; Charles Price
Es&bhoqesq; Edmund Morgan of Penloynsarth Es&bhoqesq; Collonell William Morgan Thomas Morgan of Llansore Es&bhoqesq; William
Herbert Es&bhoqesq; Richard Lester Es&bhoqesq; Henry Milbourne Es&bhoqesq; Edmund [Jone<ref idref="n27">27</ref>] Es&bhoqesq; Henry Baker Es&bhoqesq; William
Jones Es&bhoqesq; Roger Oates Nicholas Kemeis Edmund Gammage Walter Rumsey Charles Milbourne Rowland Gwynn
Thomas Pritchard Roger Williams John Williams George Kemeys of Llanvaire John Morgan John Price Caple
Hanbury Trevor Morgan Thomas Herbert John Walter of Persfield Thomas Jones of Uske Phillip Cecill Thomas
Hughes John Rumsey James Morgan and Rowland Pritchard Esquires William Herbert Barrester at Law Roderick
Gwynn Es&bhoqesq; Henry Chambers Gentleman William Blethin Edward Kemeys of Burtholey and John Lewis of IftonHill David Morgan of Llanwenarth Walter Evans of [Llangattocke Robert Gunter Lewis Morgan John Walter of
Howicke John Catchmey George Kemeys of Caldicott Charles Morgan of<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] Llangattocke-Lingod William Williams of
Carlyon John Rumsey of Wolesnewton Rowland Williams of Slow John Bird John Floyre William Lewis of
Llanmellin Robert Jones Walter Aldy John Mathews Ezra Watters Thomas Powell Nicholas Parker Thomas Morgan
of Riskah Trevor Probert Francis Spaldin Charles Williams of Newport Isaac Tompkins Theophilus Reynolds James
Jones John Curr Charles Morgan of Llansore Henry Morgan of Penrose William Jones of Uske George Harrice
Rice Jones of Court Blethin John Jones of Llantrissent John Roth Henry Morgan of Bedwelty Herbert Williams
Christopher Price Roger Williams James Harris Hopkin Vaughan William Powell of Bedwelty John Harris Leonard
Mericke Richard Vaughan Morgan Thomas Isaac Williams Charles Baker John Watkins of Tregare William Evans
Thomas Jones of Trenthin Richard Roberts Herbert Jones Francis Williams Francis Pritchard William Powell of
Uske and Nathan Rogers Gentlemen The Maior of Monmouth for the time being The Maior of Newport for the
time being The Portrieve of Uske for the time being and the Bayliffe of Abergavenny for the time being John
Arnold John Scudamore Esquires Walter Scudamore Thomas Patricke James Williams of Llanggattogg-Lingood
James Hughes of the Gelly William George of Comyoye Martin Boothby and David Thomas of Abergenny
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p183">For the County of Northampton.</para>
			<para id="p184">John Lord Burleigh sonne and heire apparent to the Earle of Exeter Bryen Viscount Cullen of the Kingdome
of Ireland Henry Lord O Bryan Baron of Ibrachan of the same Kingdome William Lord Fitzwilliams of the
same Kingdome William Mountague Lord Cheife Baron of the Exchequer Sir Francis Compton George Montague
Es&bhoqesq; Sir Thomas Crew Knight Sir Roger Norris Sir Samuell Danvers Sir William Farmer Baronets Sir Edward
Nicholls Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Griffin Sir John Robinson Sir William Wake Sir John Holman Baronets
Sir William Haslewood Knight Sir James Langham Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Alston John Beaumont Edward
Griffin Francis[Laud<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] Henry Stafford Richard Rainsford William Alton John [Parkhurst<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] William Harbord John
Browne Sir Lewis Palmer Baronet Edward Hales Thomas Chubnalls Esquires George Wake Do&bholigct;or in Lawes
Lawrence Manly William Chester William Sanders Thomas Trist Thomas Elmes Toby Chauncey Thomas Catisby
Samuell Trist William Washbourne Sir William Craven Knight Sir Samuell Clarke Devereux Knightley Sir
William Langham William Tate Edward Harby William Adams of Welthon Richard Saltonstall Edward Palmer
Maximilian Emerley John Creswell Henry Edmunds Robert Clerke William Bugby Sir William Pargiter Sir John
Pickering Bryan Johnson Anthony Shugburgh Walker Kirkham Michaell Woodhall John Thornton John Willoughby
John Bagshaw William Lisle William Warner Christopher Thursby Andrew Lant Francis Morgan Thomas Jennison
Thomas Ward John Lyn George De la vall William Levins Neale Nicholas Steward John Gardiner John
Wiseman The Maior of Northampton for the time being John Braffield Richard Massingberd Francis Pickmer Joseph
Sergeant William Vaughan Joseph Hinchman John Howes Edward Knighton The Maior of Higham for the time
being The Bayly of Daventree for the time being The Maior of Brackley for the time being Henry Lucas John
Borne Richard Butler Richard Plowman Jeremiah Dove Salathiell Lovell John Briges William Thursby John
Hanbury John Combs Esquires Richard Reeve Francis Crane Francis Arundell Tryan George Quarles
Richard Willoughby Sir Robert Drydon Baronet Edward Stratford Henry Rushton Phillip Lord Wenman of the
Kingdome of Ireland Sir Thomas Samuell Thomas Andrews George Clerke Gerrard Gore Esquires Sir Roger
Cave Sir John Egerton Baronets Goddard Pemberton Edmund Bacon Lewis Watson William Mountague Arthur
Brookes Robert Mansell Thomas Freeman Bernard Walcott Esquires Edward Montague Thomas Newton William
Adams of Cherwelton Francis Watson Esquire Sir Robert Shirley Sir Ralph Vane Daniell Finch Es&bhoqesq; John
Ekins.</para>
			<para id="p185">For the County of Nottingham.</para>
			<para id="p186">Patritius Viscount Chaworth of the Kingdome of Ireland Anchitell Grey William Pierpoint Arthur Stanhope
William Byron Robert Pierpoint Esquires Sir Francis Leeke Knight and Baronet Sir John Mollineux Sir Edward
Dearing Sir Richard Earle Sir Thomas Williamson Sir William Hickman Sir Edmund, Wastinge Sir Edward
Nevill Sir John Newton Baronets Sir Scroope How Sir Ralph Knight Knights Francis Leeke William Gray
Charles Stanhope John Digby Francis Sandys Samuell Sandys (<ref idref="n31">31</ref>) Samuell Sandys junior William Sandys John
Sandys John Grubham How William Palmes William Toler William Stanhope Thomas Perkins William Cartwright
John Thornegh John White Charles Hutchinson Thomas Marshall William Skeffington Penniston Whaley Francis
Stringer George Nevill Arthur Warren senior Arthur Warren junior Thomas Charleton senior Thomas Charlton
junior Reason Mellish Anthony Gilby William Godfrey Thomas Wauen John Millington Francis Jessop John
Yarbourgh, Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke William Lane John Rolston Darcy Mollineux Peter Broughton Edward Bigland
The high Sheriffe for the time being The Maior of Nottingham The Bayliffes of Eastredford The Maior of Newarke
Thomas Shipman William Wharton Edward Ward Mathew Jennison Samuell Ellis John [Dougloffe<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] Anthony
Collingfood Robert Atkinson Gervisse Piggott William Cartwright William Cartwright Norminton Richard Slater
Rowland Dann John Dann John Hacker of Flintam John Hacker of Trowell Henry Plumtree Richard Mansfield
Harvey Stanton George Gregory Thomas Rosfill William Pinckney William Wamundsole William Savile Henry
Savile Esquires [<ref idref="n33">33</ref>] Linley of Skegby Robert Thoroton Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Robert Newton Anthony Tate
John Musters Es&bhoqesq; Charles Lawcocke George Chamberlaine Thomas Dickonson Ralph Edge Christopher Hall
William Graves John Parker William Fowler Robert Westbrooke William Welby Thomas Porter Lancelott Rolleston
Tempest Brighouse William Waters William Clarkson John Clarkson John Baines Clifton Rodes Gent..</para>
			<para id="p187">For the County of Northumberland.</para>
			<para id="p188">Edward Lord Morpeth sonne and heire apparent of the Earle of Carlisle Sir John Fenwicke Baronet Sir Ralph
Dalavill Sir Cuthbert Heron Sir William Blacket and Sir Thomas Loraine Baronets Sir George Downing Knight
and Baronet Sir Thomas Horsley Knight Utricke Whitfield Es&bhoqesq; Daniell Collingwood Edward Villers Ralph
Jennison William Strother Ralph Hebron Thomas Bewicke Francis Blake Robert Mitford Francis Addison Thomas
Collingwood John Ridley James Howard Henry Ogle William Dallavill William Widdrington Robert Jennison
William Ogle John Shaftoe William Carnaby and John Forster of Cornwall Esquires William Carr John Forster
of Etherston Thomas Burrell Patritius Crow Tristram Fenwicke and Edward Collingwood Gentlemen John Gray
John Blakiston and William Lilburne Esquires.</para>
			<para id="p189">For the Towne and County of Newcastle upon Tyne.</para>
			<para id="p190">Sir Ralph Carr Maior Sir James Clavering and Sir William Blackett Baronets Sir Francis Anderson Sir Robert Shaftoe
and Sir Richard Scott Knights Marke Milbankes Henry Maddison Henry Brabant Ralph Jennison Timothy Davison
Robert Jennison Robert Roddam and Mathew Jefferson Aldermen Michaell Blacket Sheriffe William Lilburne John
Blakeston and Anthony Isaackson Esquires Captaine John Wetwang Robert Ellison John Watson Ambrose Barnes
George Moreton Henry Jennison William Hutchinson Robert Fenwicke Abraham Drake Ralph Fell Robert Wetwang
Nicholas Fenwicke John Phillipson John Squire William Huntley and Gilbert Dobson Merchants Henry Kirkhouse
Edward Greene John Vary and Thomas Neale Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p191">For the Burrough of Barwick upon Tweede.</para>
			<para id="p192">Richard Claxon and the Maior for the time being The Lord Dumblayne of the Kingdome of Scotland Thomas
Watson Elias Pratt James Cattrell and Andrew Moore Aldermen Mr Elias Pratt junior Mr Marke Scott and
M<emph type="p">r</emph> Stephen Jackson Daniell Collingwood William Strother senior and William Strother junior Esquires and Sir
John Fenwick Baronet Sir Richard Stott The Bayliffes for the time being Mr. John Lucke Ralph Hebron. Es&bhoqesq;
Mr. Thomas Dickinson Mr. Richard Winloe Mr. Roger Weddall Mr. Edward Nelson Mr. Selby senior Mr. Selby
junior Mr. Ferdinando Forster Mr. Anthony Compton Mr. Robert Watson Mr. George Watson Mr. Edward Ord and
Mr. Roddam.</para>
			<para id="p193">For the County of Norffolke.</para>
			<para id="p194">Lord Fitzwilliams of the Kingdome of Ireland Henry Lord Richardson of the Kingdome of Scotland Sir Joseph
Williamson one of His Majestyes Principall Secretaries of State William Paston Es&bhoqesq; Sir William Coventry Knight
Sir Edmond Bacon Sir John Hobert Sir Phillip Woodhouse Sir Edward Barkham Sir John Hollond Sir Augustine
Palgrave Sir John Potts Sir Robert Kempe Sir Jacob Astley Sir Edmond Bacon of Gillingham Sir Edward Ward
Sir Henry Deerham Sir William Cooke Sir William Doyley Sir Peter Gleane Sir Francis Buckley Sir Thomas
Garrard Sir John Pettus Sir. Henry Purefoy Sir William Adams Sir John Mordant Baronets Edward Progers Es&bhoqesq;
Sir John Bennet Knight of the Bath Sir Christopher Colthorpe Knight of the Bath Sir Charles Harbord Knight
His Majestyes Surveyour Generall Sir Allen Apsley Knight Sir John Trevor Knight Sir. Lestrange Colthrope
Serjeant at Law Sir William Doyley junior Knight Sir Nevill Catlin Knight Sir Thomas Allen Knight Sir Thomas
Hares Sir Thomas Meadowes Sir. John Bladwell Sir Robert Baldock Sir William Rant Sir John Petus Knights Sir
James Johnson Sir Robert England Knights Robert Coke Es&bhoqesq; John Harvey Es&bhoqesq; Robert Walpoole William
Windham Thomas Holland William Cooke Esquires Sir. William Heningham Sir Roger Pratt Sir William Godbold
Knights Roger Potts Christopher Layer Thomas Townesend Phillip Harbered John Hobart Robert Long Roger
Spilman William de Gray Robert Suckling John Barny John Pell Es&bhoqesq; Francis Guybon William Rant Francis
Bacon Es&bhoqesq; James Hobart Thomas Bacon Robert London Oliver Neve Thomas Gaudy Robert Day Edmond
Woodhouse Edmond Doyley John Harboard Suckling Jay Francis Lane Jacob Peeston Phillip Bedingfield Humphrey
Bedingfield Anthony Fisher Robert Houghton Robert Cony Francis Bell Phillip Bell Charles Wren Lawrence
Oxburgh Thomas Knivett Richard Godfray Nicholas Rookwood Symon Britiffe Edmond Britiff Lawrence
Oxburgh junior John Anguish Christopher Crow Munford Spilman Clement Spilman Leonard Mapes Edward
Ward Edmond de Gray Christopher Bedingfield Nicholas Wilton John Fisher Hatton Barnards Thomas Thorsby
Francis Thorsby George Townesend Gascoine Weld Leonard Gooch John Warner Anthony Freestone Francis
Cory Christopher Jay Clemen Herne John Cock Thomas Browne Tho: Cory Tho: Talbott John Buxton Tho
Wright Will Brantwight William Cropley Gabrell Arminger John Thurston John Lestrange Robert Wright
Thomas Richmond Esquires Peter Dyamond Richard Barney junior James Hoast Robert Pepper Do&bholigct;or of Lawes
John Norris William Barker Henry Farrer Samuell Pepys Edmond Osborne Francis Creamer George Ward Henry
Heynes Edward Beadle Thomas Bramsby Robert Suckling junior Robert Wood Gardner Hewett John Paynell
John Knivett Thomas Wood Edward Barber Richard Marriott John Richmond Do&bholigct;or Owen Hughes Riches
Browne John Aide Henry Marsham John Mingay Thomas Weld William Sydley John Herne Israeli Long Martin
Cobb John Greene Robert Doughty John Garnish Isaac Preston Hugh Harvey James Tenant William Tubbing
Edward Lestrange Edward Leigh Isaac Mootham Roger Pepyes Samuell Vincent Es&bhoqesq; Ralph Pierson Gent. James
Ward Nicholas Stileman Es&bhoqesq; Roger Jenings Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p195">For the Towne of Great Yarmouth.</para>
			<para id="p196">The Bayliffes for the time being Sir Thomas Meadows Sir James Johnson Sir George England Knights George
England Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Gooch John Woodroffe Abraham Castle senior John Hall Edmund Thaxter Richard
Huntington Peter Caulier Mitchell Mew Samuell Fenn Benjamin England Aldermen Thomas Bramsby Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p197">For the County and Citty of Norwich.</para>
			<para id="p198">The Maior for the time being Francis Cory Es&bhoqesq; [Recorder<ref idref="n34">34</ref>] Francis Bacon Esquire Steward, Bernard Church
Es&bhoqesq; John Mann Es&bhoqesq; Christopher Jay Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Wisse Es&bhoqesq; Richard Wenman Es&bhoqesq; Roger Harries Es&bhoqesq; John
Lawrence Es&bhoqesq; Augustine Briggs Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Thacker Es&bhoqesq; Robert Bendish Es&bhoqesq; Henry Herne Es&bhoqesq; John Manser
Es&bhoqesq; Henry Watts Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Chickring Es&bhoqesq; John Richers Richard Wenman John Wiggott Henry Crow John
Wrench Marke Cockey Ad: Paine Peter Wiggott John Low Aldermen William Helvis William Parmiter
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p199">For Kings Lynn</para>
			<para id="p200">The Maior for the time being Henry Ferrour Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Benjamin Holly Henry Bell Thomas Robinson
Edmund Abbott Simon Tailer Thomas Thetford Giles Bridgeman John Turner Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p201">For Thetford</para>
			<para id="p202">The Maior for the time being Thomas Povey Es&bhoqesq; Recorder Sir Joseph Williamson Knight Sir John Holland
Sir Phillip Woodhouse Sir Thomas Garrard Baronets Sir Allen Apsley Knight Burage Martine John Thurston
William Croples Esquires Robert Terrell Warmsley Hethersett Thomas Gooch Principall Burgesses.</para>
			<para id="p203">For the County of Oxford</para>
			<para id="p204">Phillip Lord Wenman Viscount Tuan of the Kingdome of Ireland Thomas Howard Es&bhoqesq; Brother to the Earle of
Suffolke Henry Bertie Es&bhoqesq; Sir William Coventry Knight Sir Thomas Spencer Sir William Walter Sir Compton Reads
Sir William Glynne Sir Edmond Fettyplace Sir Francis Wenman Sir Litleton Osbaldeston Sir Anthony Craven Sir
Robert Jenkinson Sir Thomas Chamberlaine Sir John Robinson Sir John Holman Sir Richard Temple Sir John Doyley
Sir Thomas Cobb Sir John Cape Sir Thomas Peniston Sir Phillip Harcourt Baronets Sir Edward Hungerford Knight
of the Bath Sir Edward Norreys Sir Timothey Tyrrell Sir Edmond Bray Sir Thomas Tipping Sir George Croke Sir
Allen Apsley Sir James Hayes Sir Llewelline Jenkins Sir Thomas Clayton Sir Nicholas Pelham Sir Thomas Woodcocke
Sir John Rowe Knights David Walter Esquire one of the Groomes of His Majestyes Bedchamber Broome Whorwood
Robert Dormer Esquires Charles Holloway Serjeant at Law Richard Croke Serjeant at Law William Cope Anthony
Hungerford Anthony Libbs Vincent Barris John Stone Henry Alnutt Francis Martine John Clerke William Lenthall John
Lenthall William Dormer William Barber Henry Heylin George Chamberlaine Reynald Bray Thomas Hord William
Bayley John Croke Samuell Sandys junior George Cole Thomas Coventry William Gannocke Robert Perrot junior John
Gower Edmond Warcupp Robert Warcupp Thomas Whorwood Richard Powell George Pudsey William Whitlock
Bartholimew Hall Thomas Goghill Robert Knollis Henry Hall Alexander Denton Robert Huntington Thomas Wise
Esquires James Hyde Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Henry Ailworth Do&bholigct;or of Law Arthur Jones Charles Holloway Richard
Holloway Edward Vernon John West William Oakeley William Wright Humphrey Wickham John Gunn Samuell
Trotman John White Sebastian Smith Edmond Gregory James Paul Esquires Mathew Skinner Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke
Mr Shiphard of Rolwright Mr Blague of Coggs Bartholimew Harris John Parsons George Woodward John
Wickham Robert Withers Robert Whorwood John Cary Thomas Rowney James Perrott Bartholimew Harris Thomas
Clayton Robert Parsons Henry Streete Richard Stephens Gilbert Jackson John Perrott junior of Northleigh
Gentlemen, The Mayor of Woodstocke for the time being and the Aldermen of the Towne The Maior of Banbury
for the time being The Warden of Henley upon Thames for the time being The Bayliffes of Chiping Norton for
the time being The Bayliffes of Burford for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p205">For the University of Oxford</para>
			<para id="p206">The Vice Chauncellor and the two Pro&bholigct;ors for the time being Lawrence Hyde Thomas Thynne Esquires Sir Thomas
Clayton Knight [Werdon<ref idref="n35">35</ref>] of Merton Colledge Thomas Yates Do&bholigct;or in Divinity and Principall of Brazen-Nose Colledge
Robert Say Do&bholigct;or in Divinity and Provost of Oriell Colledge Richard Allestrey Do&bholigct;or in Divinity and Cannon of
Christ Church Thomas Marshall Do&bholigct;or in Divinity and Re&bholigct;or of Lincolne Colledge John Nicholas Do&bholigct;or in
Divinity and Warden of New Colledge Thomas James Do&bholigct;or in Divinity and Warden of All Saints Colledge
Benjamin Woodruffe Do&bholigct;or in Divinity and Cannon of Christ Church James Hyde Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke and Principall
of Magdalen Hall Jo: Lamphire Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke and Principall of Hart Hall Richard Lydall Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke
Edward Eaton Do&bholigct;or in Phisicke and Fellow of Magdalen Colledge Do&bholigct;or John Edisbury Richard Holway Es&bhoqesq;
Robert Withers Es&bhoqesq; Richard Witt [Batchlour<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] of Law Benjamin Cooper Master of Arts Jo: Crosse Richard Davies
Jo: Haclewood William Flexney Richard Pleydall William Hopkins Gent. Do&bholigct;or Haughton.</para>
			<para id="p207">For the Citty of Oxford</para>
			<para id="p208">The Maior of the said Citty for the time being Sir Francis Wenman Knight and Baronet Sir Edward Norreys Sir
Sampson White Knights Broome Whorwood Richard Croke Serjeant at Law Recorder George Low Charles Halloway
John White Esquires William Wright Roger Griffin William Baileo John Townesend Aldermen John Lambe Francis
Haward Francis Greenoway William Cornish William Walker Tobias Browne Thomas Fifield William Morrell
Gentlemen John Painton Towne Clerke Robert Whorwood Charles Haynes Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p209">For the County of Rutland</para>
			<para id="p210">The Right Honourable Bennet Lord Sherrard of the Kingdome of Ireland The Honourable [Henry Noell Edward<ref idref="n37">37</ref>]
Noell Phillip Sherrard Esquires Sir Thomas Mackworth Sir Abell Barker Baronets Sir Thomas Transhaw Knight William
Palmes John Wingfield Christopher Browne Richard Verney Samuell Browne Edward Fawkener Andrew Noell Cornelius
Burton Charles Halford Thomas Barker Esquires William Colby Gent George Bynyon Es&bhoqesq; John Lord Burleigh.</para>
			<para id="p211">For the County of Salop</para>
			<para id="p212">William Pierpoint Richard Newport Andrew Newport Esquires Sir Henry Litleton Sir Henry Fredericke Thynne Sir
Humphrey Briggs Sir William Whitmore Sir Francis Lawley Sir John Corbett Sir Vincent Corbet Sir Richard Corbett
Sir Francis Edwards Sir Edward A&bholigct;on Baronets Sir Clement Clarke Sir Thomas Vernon Sir Thomas Whitmore
Knight of the Bath Sir John Weld Sir Job Charleton Sir William Childe Sir Timothy Litleton Sir John Trevor Sir
Thomas Jones Sir Richard Mason Sir Samuell Baldwin Knights Thomas Thynne William Leweson Gower Richard
Scriven Richard Fowler Francis Charleton Charles Manwaring John Walcutt Esquires Francis Thormes Francis
Forrester Robert Leighton Richard Lister Edward Kynaston of Oatly Edward Kinaston of Aberclee Roger Kinaston
Thomas Baudewin Phillip Prince [Somesett<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] Fox Henry Herbert William Forester Thomas Owen of Condover John
Wolrich Thomas Thomas Thomas Whitmore George Weld George Ludlow Thomas Rocke William Owen Robert
Corbett of Bosses-Hall John Coates William Oakeley Thomas Walcott Robert Cressett Robert Owen Roger Pope
Thomas Floyd Richard Creswell John Lacon William Williams Vincent Edwards Thomas Oatly Litleton Powis
Thomas Crumpe Richard More John Newton Thomas Kinnersly of Badger William Cotton Humphry Briggs Thomas
A&bholigct;on William Jones of Sandford Thomas Hill Thomas Ireland William Hanmer Edward Leighton Edward Kerry
Edward Whitcott Henry Griffiths Edward Vernon Henry Davenport Rowland Niccolls Henry Mitton of Skipton
Humphrey Cornwall Thomas Corbett of Stanardine Edward Agborough Bevis [Lloyd<ref idref="n39">39</ref>] Thomas Cornwall Henry Langley
Roger Evans William Herbert of Wotton Robert Clowes Thomas Vernon Richard Cowling John Seaverne Thomas
Smallman James Beck Owen Baron Richard Pope Rotchly Prince Arthur Ward Thomas Owen of Duntharke John
Wood Thomas Jobber John Edwards of Rorington Richard Corbett Edward Lutwich William Dansey Henry Powell
of Wortham John Powell Esquires The Maior of Salop for the time being The Bayliffes of Ludlow Bridgenorth
Bishops-Castell and Wenlock for the time being The Maior of Oswestry for the time being Francis Smith Robert
Smith John Tayler Ralph Wareing George Hosier John Whitacre Samuell Floyd Thomas Mason Arthur Hinkes
Alexander Midleton John Langley of the Amies George Gough Edward Owen Roger Griffiths Richard Wareing
Edward Woolaston Roger Harris Robert Vernon John Woodhouse Adam Wareing Richard Davis of Whitchurch
William Gravenor Richard Jenkins John Stanniers Edward Powell John Bright Rowland Midleton William Owen of
Whitby Edward Pulley Walter Bagott Thomas Hawkes William Griffies Richard Davies Richard Bradley Richard
Ridley William Brigien Samuell Boudler Gentlemen John Edwards of the Heath Edward Lloyd of Llanvorda Owen
Barton Morgan Wynne Edward Jennings [Esquires<ref idref="n40">40</ref>] William Crompton William Jones George Chambers Edward Owen
Christopher Braine Roger Trevor Francis Harris John Kenett Henry Griffith Daniell Wicherley and Richard Lloyd
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p213">For the County of Stafford</para>
			<para id="p214">Sir Robert Shirley Sir Thomas Wilbraham Sir Walter Pagott Sir Edward Litleton Sir Walter Wrotesly Sir Charles
Wolsley Sir Francis Lawley Sir John Bowyer Sir Thomas Bellet Baronets Sir Bryan Broughton Sir Theophilus Biddulph
Knights and Baronets Sir John Whyrley Sir Thomas Whitgreave Sir Rowland Oakeover Sir Henry Archbold Knights
Randolph Egerton Henry Gray Thomas Thynne Walter Chetwin Edward Litleton William Sneyd William Ward
George Legg Brome Whorwood William Leveson Gower Robert Leveson Thomas Lane Richard Dyott William
Chetwynd Charles Cotton Richard Congreave Edward Vernon Thomas Kinnersley Ralph Snead John Swinfen Edwin
Skrimsier Charles Skrimsier William Wedgwood Arthur Fleetwood Henry Vernon Daniell Watson Charles Agard
Francis Wightwick Jonathan Woodnoth John Pyott Walter Aston Thomas Rudiard Edward Alblaster William Parker
Henry Gough Edward Birch Thomas Orme William Whitby Michaell Noble John Turton Edward Moorton John
Whitehall Ferrers Fulke Thomas Whitby William Trafford Walter Fowler Zachariah Babington Mathew Kellett
Mathew Flyer Esquires Thomas Palmer Thomas Scott Thomas Rugeley Thomas Villers Leicester Barbour Sampson
Birch Timothy Edge John Felton John Offley William Crompton John Leigh Gentlemen The Maior of Stafford and
Newcastle Underline for the time being The Bayliffes of Tamworth for the time being Nicholas Parker Charles
Bainton Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p215">For the Citty of Lichfield</para>
			<para id="p216">The Bayliffes and Sheriffe for the time being Sir Theophilus Biddulph Knight and Baronet Sir Henry Archbold
Knight Richard Dyott Esquire Thomas Minors Thomas Caterbanck Simon Martin senior John Rawlins Ralph Minors
William Jesson Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p217">For the County of Somerset</para>
			<para id="p218">The Right Honourable Edward Seymour Es&bhoqesq; Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons Ralph Stawell Es&bhoqesq;
High Sheriffe of the County Lord Viscount Fitzharding of the Kingdome of Ireland Lord Halley of the Kingdome of
Ireland Francis Pawlett Sir William Portman Sir Hugh Smith Knight of the Bath and Baronet Sir William Wyndham
Sir John Wroth Sir Halswell Tynt Sir Thomas Windham Sir John Coventry Sir Thomas Bridges Sir Edward
Hungerford Sir William Bassett Sir Edward Phillips Sir Francis Rolle Sir John Mallet Sir Stephen Fox Sir John
Churchill Sir Humphrey Sidenham Sir John Coplestone Sir James Hayes Knights Thomas Thynne Edward Phillips
George Speake Peregrine Palmer George Horner Edward Gorges John Carry Edmond Wyndham Edward Barkley
Henry Bridges Thomas Wyndham of Witham William Helyer John Buckland Thomas Warr Robert Hunt Henry of
Shapwick John Piggott William Lacy the elder John Harrington [Henr
<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] Waldron George Dodington of Dodington
Henry Bull of Midsummer-Norton Warwicke Bampfield William Strode Edward Strode William Lacy the younger
Edward Clarke Robert Halley Henry Henley Thomas Strode Edward Court Richard Jones Edmond Carrant John
Hunt Peter Roynon William Speake John S<emph type="p">t</emph> Albanes Henry Light William Harbord John Prows Thomas Lyvenham
John Bayly Chauncellor of Wells William Coward George Stedman Thomas Jennings George Long Richard Morgan
William Harbin William Clarke Humphrey Sydenham of Delverton Richard Musgrave Coplestone Horton Richard
Crosse William Orange John Hody Henry Bridges Joseph Langton Richard Landsdowne Charles Stennings George
Dodington Anthony Stocker junior John Tooker of Norton Hall Thomas Saunders Edward Hobbs John Wynne
George Clarke.</para>
			<para id="p219">For the Citty of Wells</para>
			<para id="p220">The Maior for the time being, The Recorder Maurice Berkley Nicholas Niblett John Davis John Davage John Day
Francis Symmonds William Saumon.</para>
			<para id="p221">The Towne of Bridgewater</para>
			<para id="p222">The Maior for the time being Humphrey Steer Francis Harvey William Macy John Liney.</para>
			<para id="p223">For the Citty of Bath</para>
			<para id="p224">The Maior for the time being, The Recorder John Bush Walter Gibbs Henry Chapman Robert Peace Do&bholigct;or of
Phisicke Robert Chapman John Masters.</para>
			<para id="p225">For the County and Citty of Bristoll.</para>
			<para id="p226">The Maior and Sheriffe for the time being Sir Robert Atkins Knight of the Bath one of his Majesties Justices of the
Common Pleas Sir Humphry Hooke Knight Sir John Knight Knight John Lowford Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Stephens Es&bhoqesq; Sir
Robert [Yeomans<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] Baronet John Knight Es&bhoqesq; John Hicks Es&bhoqesq; Richard Streamour Es&bhoqesq; Ralph Olive Es&bhoqesq; William Crabb
Es&bhoqesq; Richard Crumpe Es&bhoqesq; Aldermen John Lloyd Es&bhoqesq; Joseph Creswick Es&bhoqesq; Richard Harte Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Earle
Es&bhoqesq; William Colston Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p227">For the County of Southampton.</para>
			<para id="p228">The Right Honourable Edward Seymour Speaker of the Honourable House of Commons The Honourable Edward
Noell Lieutenant of the County James Lord Annesley sonne and heire apparent to the Earle of Anglesey William Russell
Es&bhoqesq; Sir Robert Howard Knight Sir George Carteret Knight and Baronet Charles West Es&bhoqesq; Sir Kinsman Lucy Baronet
Sir John Norton Baronet Sir Hugh Stuckely Baronet Sir William Lewis Baronet Sir Robert Dillington Baronet Sir
William Meux Baronet Sir Thomas Badd Knight and Baronet Sir Nicholas Stuart Baronet Sir Mundiford Brampston
Baronet Sir John Saintbarb Baronet [Sir John Oglander Baronet<ref idref="n43">43</ref>] Sir Thomas Hooke Sir Robert Holmes Sir Thomas
Higgons Sir Francis Rolle Sir Robert Henly Sir Richard Knight Sir Charles [Lee Sir James<ref idref="n43">43</ref>] Worseley [Sir Edward
Worseley <ref idref="n43">43</ref>] Sir John Cloebury Sir Charles Windham Sir John Holmes Sir John Biggs Knights Edward Pile High Sheriffe
of the County Francis Powlett Charles Powlett Richard Norton Thomas Neale Lawrence Hyde Thomas Knolis George
Legg Governour of Portsmouth Richard Lucy Thomas Gervoice Henry Whitehead George Pitt James May Leonard
Bilson John Hooke Thomas Cole Roger Gallop Francis Tilney Henry Bromfield senior Arthur Hold White Tichburne
John Stewkeley Oliver S<emph type="p">t</emph> John Bartholomew Price Henry Tulse Richard Tulse Richard Ayliffe William Wither John
Hawkoner Roger Clavell Williams Stephens Esquires Edward Norton Edward Leigh John Leigh John Richards
Robert Oxenbridge John Paulin Gabriell Whistler John Deane John Smith Edward Dillington John Butten Richard
Love senior Francis Dickens John Dingley Robert Gough Peter Bettesworth William Smith Richard Cobbe Richard
Love junior William Stanley Robert Richvell Daniell Kingsmill John Kingsmill Edward Hooper Henry Doyley James
Rudyard James Halsell Henry Bromfield junior Ralph Hastings William Pitt Esquires George Browne Henry Perrin
Henry Kelsey John Man Thomas Dawse John Kelsey John Mathew Richard Richards Benjamin Newland Richard
Bishop Robert Roll Thomas Edmonds Thomas Knight Francis Guydott William Goddard John Reaves of Bramsberry
Thomas Urrey of Freshwater William Bulkley of S<emph type="p">t</emph> Ellens Bartholimew Bulkley of Limington and John Burrard of
the same Gentlemen The Maior of Portsmouth for the time being Richard Morley Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Steventon Hugh
Salisbury Phillip James Thomas Mills Nicholas Hedger Nicholas Peirson Aldermen of the same The Maior of Newport
The Maior of Yarmouth The Maior of Basingstoke and The Bayliffe of Andover for the time being Richard Harris.</para>
			<para id="p229">For the Citty of Winchester</para>
			<para id="p230">The Maior of the said Citty for the time being John Warner William Tailer Thomas Muspratt Nicholas
Purdue Edmond Fifeild William Cradock Thomas Wavell and Godson Penton Aldermen of the said Citty.</para>
			<para id="p231">For the Towne and County of Southampton.</para>
			<para id="p232">The Maior of the said Towne and County for the time being Roger Gallop Es&bhoqesq; Recorder of the same William
Standley Robert Richvell James Crosse Thomas Cornelius James Clungeon Richard White Peter Guyllam Edward
Richards Arthur Fulks Aldermen of the said Towne and County John Speede of the same Doctor in Phisicke Thomas
Knollys Es&bhoqesq; William Drake Peter Blake Robert Culliford Es&bhoqesq;</para>
			<para id="p233">For the County of Suffolke.</para>
			<para id="p234">Lyonell Lord Huntingtowre of the Kingdome of Scotland Sir John Duncombe Walter Devereux Es&bhoqesq; Sir Edmond
Bacon Sir Henry Felton Sir John Holland Sir Robert Kemp. Sir Henry Bacon Sir John Barker Sir William Spring Sir
Willoughby Deves Sir John Castleton Sir Thomas Cullom Sir William Doyley Sir Jervice Elwes Sir Thomas Darcy
Sir Robert [Gordell<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] Sir Henry North Sir Robert Brooke Sir John Duke Sir Phillip Parker Sir Thomas Bernardiston
Sir Samuell Bernardiston Baronets Sir Charles Gaudy Sir George Reeve Sir Thomas Allen Knights and Baronets Sir
Nicholas Bacon Knight of the Bath Sir John Pettus Baronet Sir John Pooley Sir Thomas Harvey Sir George Winiffe
Sir Nevill Catlin Sir John Hanmer Sir Thomas Smith Sir Jeoffrey Burwell Sir Francis Theobalds Sir Phillip Meadowes
Sir Thomas Meadows Sir Phillip Skippon Sir William Soames Sir John Coale Master of Chauncery Sir Richard Gipps
Sir John Peake Sir John Shaw Knights John Harvey Treasurer to Her Majestie Robert Cooke Edward Proger John
Playters Thomas Holland William Duncombe Adam Felton Thomas Jermin John Castleton junior John Cordall
Robert Reeve Thomas Allen Thomas Cool Thomas Walgrave Thomas Glemham Thomas Walgrave junior John
Wright of Ipswich John Bence of Rinsfield Thomas Tyrrell Anthony Gaudy Henry Parker Nathaniell Parker John
Thirston Giles Barnardiston Benjamin Cutler of the Chauntry Maurice Shelton William Soames Richard Norton Francis
Warner Edmond Warner Henry Warner Reginold Williams Edward Hubbard Robert Russell Joseph Brand Lyonell Playters
Francis Barker Thomas Dade Robert Gourdon John Southerby John Clarke Thomas Clarke William Gipps Hamond
L'Estrange. John Scrivener Robert King William A&bholigct;on Edward North William Rivett Clement Heigham Thomas
Edgar William Gooch William Gibbs Samuell Gibbs John Cornwallis John Hodges Henry Johnson Edward Mann
Thomas Blackerby Robert Maltiward Robert Wright Thomas Wright Henry Edgar Barnaby Bowtell John Lane
Lawrence Rouse Mathew Leman John Leman Joseph Hull William Glover Thomas Goulding Francis Burwell Thomas
Bacon John Breame of Ash John Beddingfield Henry Stebbing Samuell Kerridge William Guavas Francis Horney
Thomas Love Esquires Thomas Avas Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Edmond Bedingfield John Spencer Phillip Gourdon Thomas
Vesey Allen Cotton Edward Plumb Richard Kirkby Thomas Steward Stephen Morley John Smith of Parkfield John
Lane John Hall Charles Cock Edward Bence Thomas Roper William Brand of Polstead Richard Vesey Edmond
Sheppard Edmond Gardener Robert Browning of Brandiston John Brooke Paul Buckenham William Cullum Adam
Budle Nicholas Bradge Joseph Beamont John Lambe Phillip Haward William Jermye John Jermye Thomas Dye John
Buxton Thomas Colvell alias Covell Thomas and Thomas Rivett Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p235">For the Towne of Sudbury.</para>
			<para id="p236">The Maior of Sudbury for the time being Sir Robert Cordell Baronet Thomas Walgrave and John Cordell Esquires
Do&bholigct;or Butcher Joseph Wood John Cooke Daniell Cooke John Warner John Gibbon Richard Hobart Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p237">For the Towne of Dunwich</para>
			<para id="p238">The Bayliffes of Dunwich for the time being Sir John Pettus Knight William Wood Esquire John Benefice Thomas
Tookely Gray Thomas Goddard Henry Bedingfield Samuell Driver Jonas Munnings Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p239">For the Towne of Ipswich</para>
			<para id="p240">The Bayliffes of Ipswich for the time being John Wright Gilbert Linfield Esquires Thomas Edgar Recorder Miles
Wallis Luke Jowers William Cullam Charles Wright Henry Gosnold John Pimberton Lawrence Stistead Richard
Phillipps Robert Clarke Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p241">For Saint Edmondsbury.</para>
			<para id="p242">The Aldermen of Bury for the time being Sir John Duncombe Sir Thomas Harvey William Duncombe John
Southerby Recorder Thomas Holland Thomas Coell John Clarke Esquires James Cobb Francis Browne Robert Sharpe
Mathew Warren Samuell Husler Thomas Burrowes Nicholas Batley and Martin Spencer Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p243">For the Towne of Aldborough</para>
			<para id="p244">The Bayliffes for the time being Sir John Holland Baronet John Bence Es&bhoqesq; John Bedingfield Recorder John
Burrowes Thomas Elliott John Browne Thomas Wall Ralph Rabbitt Walter Garfort and Alexander Osbourne
Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p245">For the Burrough of Orford</para>
			<para id="p246">The Maior for the time being Walter Devereux Es&bhoqesq; Sir Allen Brodericke Knight Henry Parker Es&bhoqesq; Recorder
Henry Parker junior Thomas Hastings Joseph Hastings Edward Edwyn Thomas Johnson Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p247">For the County of Surrey.</para>
			<para id="p248">M<emph type="p">r</emph> Sanders High Sheriffe for the County of Surrey Charles Earle of Ancram of the Kingdome of Scotland Francis
Viscount Longford of the Kingdome of Ireland Lord Huntingtowre of the Kingdome of Scotland Sir Edward Thurland
one of the Barons of the Exchequer Bernard Grenvile Es&bhoqesq; Francis Coventry Esquire Collonell Edward Villars Sir
Henry Capell Knight of the Bath Sir Walter Saint Johns Baronet Sir Francis Vincent Sir Adam Browne Sir William
More Sir Stephen Lennard Sir Marmaduke Gresham Sir Edward Bromfield Sir John Werden Sir Phillip Mathews
Baronets Sir William Terringham Knight of the Bath Sir John Nicholas Knight of the Bath Sir Edmond Bowyer Sir
George Freeman Knight of the Bath Sir William Haward Sir William Morley Knight of the Bath Sir Thomas Foster
Sir Richard Mason Sir Thomas Bludworth Sir Nicholas Carew Sir Thomas Clarges Sir William Hoskins Sir Allen
Brodericke Sir Edward Evelin Sir Mathew Andrews Sir Henry Tulse Sir Edward Bish Sir Dennis Gawden Sir Robert
Knightley Knights William Montague Ambrose Browne junior of Bechworth-Castle Arthur Onslow George Chute
Christopher Buckle William Ellyott Edward Proger Thomas Dalmahoy Francis Howard George Woodroffe Thomas
Dalmahoy George Evelin of Wootton George Evelin of Nutfield Roger James Touch Anthony Thomas Sir
James Butler Edward Gresham [Sigimond<ref idref="n45">45</ref>] Stidolph John Weston of Ockham Edward Thurland Richard Onslow
George Vernon James Gresham Anthony Bowyer Esquires Morgan Randall Denzell Onslow Ambrose Muschamp
Phillip Hildiyerd George Smith John Thynne Roger Duncombe William Hayward Robert Cooke Robert Hatton
Edward Woodward Daniell Sheldon William Vanburgh Henry Lloyd William Harvey Stephen Harvey Samuell Rouse
Thomas Lee George Chute junior James Clarke Richard Heath Peter Hussey Charles Good Samuell Howland
Walter Howland Francis Brend Robert Packhurst Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Turgis Es&bhoqesq; Thomas Jenner Thomas Arden John
Jorden Esquires John Parker Henry Byne John Heather Es&bhoqesq; Francis Gerrard William Hawkins Gentlemen Anthony
Covert John Glynne John Sandis [Es&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n46">46</ref>] Giles Dunstar Gentleman Robert Gavell Richard Dalton Samuell Wall
Gentlemen John Wight Thomas Bridges Esquires Richard Coldham of Downe farme Es&bhoqesq; The Maior of Guilford for
the time being Thomas Foster Es&bhoqesq; Captaine Perry Captaine Caleb Westbrooke Alderman Freeman James Reading
Joseph Nicholson William Castles Thomas Locke Richard How Peter Rich Richard Holman Joseph Colinge Richard
Simms of Guilford Nicholas Fenn John Spencer Thomas Benson Henry Hampson John Bind of Camerwell George
Smith late of Wandsworth Robert Wilson Gentlemen Sir Robert Clayton Richard Garth Es&bhoqesq; Sir John Shorter
Captaine Holdich Henry Goreing Es&bhoqesq; Richard May Es&bhoqesq; William Salmon Gent. John Snell Gent. Thomas Sydderfin
[Es&bhoqesq;<ref idref="n47">47</ref>] John Thynne junior Es&bhoqesq; Edmond Sherman Nathaniell Reading Es&bhoqesq; Symon Smith Gent. Richard Brett Es&bhoqesq;
Francis Buller Es&bhoqesq; William Lenthall Es&bhoqesq; Edward Ball Gent John Covert Es&bhoqesq; John Cresset Gent. Sir Edward Winter
Sir James Rushout.</para>
			<para id="p249">For the County of Sussex</para>
			<para id="p250">Edward Sackville John Tufton Richard Tufton Thomas Tufton Esquires Sir John Pelham Sir William Culpeper
Sir Cisill Bishop Sir Adam Browne Sir James Bowyer Sir John Covert Sir William Thomas Sir John Staply Sir
John Fagg Sir Denny Ashburnham Sir Anthony Shirley Sir William Wilson Sir Robert Parker Sir Thomas Dyke
Sir Richard Ashfeild Baronets Sir William Morley Knight of the Bath Sir Nicholas Stroude Sir Thomas Woodcocke
Sir George Courthop Sir Nicholas Pelham Sir James Morton Knights Thomas Pelham Thomas Sackvile John
Lewkner Henry Gowring senior Walter Bartlett Robert Edmonds Baptist May William Board Henry Goring junior
John Ashburnham Nisell Rivers Percy Goreing Robert Fagg William Morley Richard Bridger Edward Michelbourne
Thomas Midleton junior Anthony Eversfield Edward Blaker John Eversfield John Alford Simon Smith John Midleton
Robert Palmer William Westbrooke Ralph Mills John May Richard May Robert Anderson James Butler Thomas
Smith John Steward Thomas Gray Henry Shelley John Millington Walter Double Peter Courthop Thomas Beard
Nicholas Selwin Henry Bishop William Spence Sackville Graves William Dyke John Browne Edward Payne John
Baker senior Edward Polhill Richard Paine Roger Shoiswell Walter Everden Robert Fowle Thomas Frewen John
Busbridge Tho: Pierce Tho: Collins Nicholas Townley Will: Peckham Joseph King Christopher May Phillip Packer
Timothy Burrell Esquires Nicholas Eversfield Edward Chowne John Gratwick William Serate John Blacksell Thomas
Midleton senior John Michell Robert Michell Bray Chowne John Machell William Palmer Thomas Garroway Richard
Nash Thomas Pain&egrave; Francis Mose Richard Mills Walter Cole Thomas Betsworth Thomas Palmer Es&bhoqesq; Richard
Cooper Thomas Young George Gunter Captaine Bickley Richard Peckham John Peckham of Crockerhill Thomas
Peckham Richard Young Edward [Troyson<ref idref="n48">48</ref>] William Lane John Oliver John Baker junior Edward Sheppard John
Fuller Peter Farnden Peter Jott Thomas Briggs Robert Johnson William Young John Cobden William Bishop John
Wicks John Dyne Thomas Mums Thomas Bromfeild senior Thomas Bromfeild junior John Cheale senior (<ref idref="n49">49</ref>) John
Cheale junior Lawrence Alcock John Cooke William Harden Thomas Burrell of Cookfeild Gentlemen The Maior
of Chichester The Maior of Arundell The Maior of Hastings The Maior of Rye The Maior of Winchelsea for the
time being The Bayliffe of Seaford and the Bayliffe of P&eacute; for the time being Edward Cooper of Strowde
Es&bhoqesq; Oliver Weekes Es&bhoqesq; Peregrine Palmer Es&bhoqesq; William Peachey of Petworth John Peachey of Petworth John
Polhill of Frenches Henry Apsley John Lanford George Elfered Thomas Ellis William Elson senior William Elson
junior Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p251">For the County of Warwicke.</para>
			<para id="p252">Charles Lord Clifford sonne and heire apparent to the Earle of Burlington William Lord Allington of the Kingdome
of Ireland Lord Digby of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Francis Compton Knight Anchetell Grey Thomas Coventry
Charles Leigh Esquires Sir Robert Shirley Sir John Mordent Sir Robert Holt Sir Richard Temple Sir Henry Puckering
alias Newton Sir John Tufton Sir Edward Boughton Sir Clement Fisher Sir Francis Lawley Sir Roger Burgoyne Sir
John Bridgeman Sir John Knightley Sir Herbert Price Sir Thomas Norton Sir Theophilus Biddolph Sir John Huband
Sir John Hales Sir Charles Wheeler Sir Orlando Bridgeman Sir Fuller Skipwith Baronets William Bromley Knight of
the Bath Sir Charles Adderley Sir Charles Lee Sir William Palmer Sir Thomas Doleman Sir Arthur Caley Sir William
Underhill Sir Richard Hopkins Sir John Clopton Sir Andrew Hackett Knights, Richard Nudigate Serjeant at Law
Thomas Thynne Richard Lucey John Ferrars Thomas Archer Richard Nudigate Rich: Hopkins Seabrett Reppington
Henry Pudsey John Rouse Richard Boughton of Bilton Richard Verney senior of Kingston Richard Verney junior
of Kingston Robert Somervile Josiah Childe Walter Chetwin Aden Bagott Henry Ferrars William Combe Thomas
Marriott Thomas Rawlins Charles Newsham Hastings Ingram Thomas Wagstaffe George Devereux Charles Bentley
Humphrey Jennings Thomas Corkin George Secheverell John Stratford William Palmer Edward Hinton William
Bishop William Colemer Nathaniell Stoughton William Perkins John Snell Richard Leds John Newsham James
Prescott Henry Parker William Loggins Henry Mathews Esquires Thomas Keate Gent. The Maior of Warwicke for
the time being The Maior of Stratford for the time being The Bayliffes of Tamworth for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p253">For the County of the Citty of Coventry.</para>
			<para id="p254">The Maior for the time being Sir Clement Fisher Sir Thomas Norton Sir John Hales Sir Orlando Bridgeman
Baronets Sir Richard Hopkins Sergeant at Law Sir Robert Townsend Sir Arthur Caley Sir William Jesson Knights
Richard Hopkins Humphrey Lowe Henry Greene John Bowater John Dugdale Esquires William Jelliffe Joseph Chambers
James Nailor Ralph Phillips Nathaniell Harriman John Wooldrige Aldermen Robert Beake Thomas Whagstaffe Henry
Smith Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p255">For the County of Worcester</para>
			<para id="p256">M<emph type="p">r</emph> Secretary Coventry, The Lord Follyott of the Kingdome of Ireland Mr Other Windsor Mr John Coventry Sir
John Packington Sir Henry Litleton Sir Francis Russell Sir Edward Seabright Sir Edward Rouse Sir William Keyte
Sir Thomas Cookes Baronets Sir Rowland Berkley Sir John Winford Sir John Talbott Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir
John Hanmer Sir James Rushout Sir John Barnaby Sir Francis Winnington Knights Collonell Samuell Sandys John
Packington Samuell Sandys junior Thomas Savage senior Sherrington Talbott Thomas Savage junior Henry Herbert
James Pitts Henry Jefferies William Bromley Robert Berkley Francis Finch Edward Carew Joseph Walsh Thomas
Childe Henry Townsend senior Richard Couling Es&bhoqesq; William Swift John Nanfan Thomas Streete Edward Dinley
Leonard Simpson Litleton Clent Richard Vernon Richard Ligon Edward Partridge William Sheldon Walter Savage
Thomas Jolliffe Thomas Symonds Giles Persons Anthony Sambage John Sandys Edmond Lechmore Henry Evett
William Washbourne Henry Spiller Thomas Watson William Lygon Brome Whorwood Thomas Bushell Nicholas
Barnaby Francis Sheldon Thomas Haslewood Thomas Stephens John Bearecroft Bridges Nanfan Thomas Vernon
Henry Parker Gerrard Dannett Martin Sandys Richard Nash of Powicke Thomas Turvey William Dowdeswell Thomas
Barker Marke Dynely Thomas Foley Richard Dowedeswell Es&bhoqesq; Humphrey Patrett John Newporte John Glutton William
Gerratt Robert Foley The Bayliffes of Droitwick for the time being The Maior of Evesham for the time being The Bayliffe
of Bewdley for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p257">For the Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester.</para>
			<para id="p258">The Maior Aldermen and Sheriffe for the time being Sir John Packington Baronet Collonell Samuell Sandys Sir
Francis Winnington Knight his Majestyes Sollicitor Generall Sir Rowland Berkeley Knight Thomas Streete Thomas
Vernon Robert Wild Esquires Richard Beddoes Henry Tailer John Bearcroft William Norris William Swift Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p259">For the County of Wilts.</para>
			<para id="p260">The Right Honourable Edward Seymour Es&bhoqesq; Speaker to the Honourable House of Commons Richard Lord Gorges
of the Kingdome of Ireland Henry Lord Coleraine of the same Kingdome Anthony Lord Ashley sonne and heire
apparent to the Earle of Shaftsbury Edward Howard Es&bhoqesq; Sir Robert Howard Knight Sir John Ernely Knight
Chauncellor of the Exchequer Sir Walter St John Sir Robert Button Sir Seymour Pile Sir William Estcourt Sir
Richard Grobham How Sir James Long Sir Walter Ernie and Sir Walter Long Baronets Sir John Coventry Sir Edward
Hungerford Sir John Nicholas and Sir Edward Baynton Knights of the Bath Sir John Evelin Sir John Talbott Sir
George Hungerford Sir Thomas Estcourt senior Sir Thomas Estcourt junior Sir Henry Coker Sir George Speake Sir
Thomas Mompesson Sir Stephen Fox Sir Richard Harrison Phillip Howard Es&bhoqesq; Sir Francis Chaplin Sir Giles
Hungerford Knight Sir Joseph Ash Baronet Sir John S<emph type="p">t</emph>
-Loe Sir Edward Low Knights Thomas Thynne George Pitt
Richard Lewis Henry Poole Henry S<emph type="p">t</emph> John George Cooper Francis Wroughton senior Robert Hyde Richard Howe
Francis Pile John Pleydall Nevill Poole William Glanvill John Hall William Eyre William Brunker William Duckett
Ralph Freake George Ayliffe Thomas Bennett George Bond [Edmond
<ref idref="n50">50</ref>] Waynford Edmond Nicholas of Maningford
Thomas Mompassion Bernard Pawlett William Ash Alexander Thislethwayte Maurice Buckland Oliver Calley Thomas
Lambert John Harrison John Windham John Smith de Tydworth Richard Aldworth Charles Ralegh John Collins
George Low Jeffery Daniell Edward Goddard de Standen William Willoughby Thomas Gore William Trenchard
William Hodges George Johnson Giles Eyre senior Samuell Eyre William Swanton Henry Clarke junior Giles Eyre
junior Thomas Chamberlaine Thomas Hawles Henry Eyre Giles Estcourt John Scroope Nevill Masklyne Francis
Goddard Robert Drew John Bowles Thomas Penrudock Robert Chaundler Thomas Pile Peter Dove John Hungerford
Oliver Nicholas Richard Bowie Henry Wallis Edmond Webb Richard Chaundler John Danvers John Ash Michaell
Ernie Samuell Ash Thomas Goddard de Swindon Thomas Clerke John Deane Edward Nott John Mervin William
Chaffin William Norborne John Hawkins John Mompesson Francis Hill Lawrence Swanton Edward Goddard de
Ogborn Abjohn Stoakes Charles Tooker Benjamin Gifford John Fitzherbert Thomas Bennett Edmond Hungerford
Gabriell Ashley of Cheerebury John Brooke William Herst John Wallis of Westwood Charles Yorke Ephraim Westley
William Bronker Richard Greene John Hippesley John Young Hope Longe Thomas Harris Thomas Harris of Colerne
Richard Poore John Jacobi Thomas Dennet senior Francis Stonehouse Robert Foile Richard Goddard Mathew Bennett
Christopher Pitt Edward Duke George Duke of Sarum George Duke of Lake Henry Chivers Thomas Long Giles
Litcott Thomas Dove Walter Perkin of Lyshill William Levett John Bigg George Sadler William Grinfield Michaell
Beach Richard Hunt William Turner Edward Hoborough James Phipps Edward Nicholas Thomas Michell Mr Hancocke
with the Maiors of Wilton and the Devizes and Malborough for the time being Christopher Poticar Jonathan Rogers
of Chippenham Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p261">For the Citty of New Sarum.</para>
			<para id="p262">Giles (<ref idref="n51">51</ref>) Nash Maior and The Maior for the time being William Swanton Recorder Sir Thomas Mompesson Sir
Stephen Fox Knights Gyles Eyne Deputy Recorder Edward Edmonds Thomas Cutler Maurice Greene William Viner
senior Thomas Williams Thomas Batter Christopher Gardiner James Bennett William Smith Thomas Keynton Aldermen
John Windham Esquire Thomas Harris Es&bhoqexc; William Hearst Es&bhoqexc; Gabriell Ashley Es&bhoqexc; John Stevens Es&bhoqexc; Francis Hill
Es&bhoqexc; George Vennard Es&bhoqexc;</para>
			<para id="p263">For the County of Westmorland.</para>
			<para id="p264">John [Tusfren<ref idref="n52">52</ref>] Thomas [Tusfren<ref idref="n52">52</ref>] Esquires Sir Phillip Musgrave Sir William Dalston Sir George Fletcher Sir John
Lowther Sir John Lowther junior Baronets Sir Christopher Musgrave Sir John Otway Knights Richard Musgraye John
Dalston James Bellingham Daniell Fleming Richard Loucher Robert Hilton Edward Wilson Henry Wilson Thomas
Flecher Allen Bellingham Christopher Dalston Christopher Phillipson Edward Musgrave William Sandford Lancelott
Muchell Thomas Gabetis Thomas Lamplugh Allen Pricker Richard Duckett Robert Bruichwaich John Fisher Gentlemen
The Maiors of Appleby and Kendall for the time, being.</para>
			<para id="p265">For the County of Anglesey.</para>
			<para id="p266">Robert Lord Bulkley Viscount Cassells of the Kingdome of Ireland Sir Hugh Owens Baronet Thomas Bulkley
Nicholas Bagnall John, Glynne Peirce Lloyd John Robinson William Meirick John Griffith of Llanvaithley Robert
Roberts William Williams Thomas Holland David Lloyd Lloydiart William Bulkley of Brinddo Conisby Williams
Owen Hughes John Owens of Penrosse Edward Wynne Rowland White Howell Lewis Esquires Henry Jones Henry
Davies John Price of Trevadog John Wood John Owen of Llanvaethly Hugh Williams David Williams William
Roberts of Caere Owen Williams John Hughes William Griffith Gentlemen, The Maior of Bewmaris for the time being
Richard Edwards.</para>
			<para id="p267">For the County and Towne of Brecon.</para>
			<para id="p268">Lord Herbert of Ragland sonne and heire apparent to the Marquesse of Worcester The Judges of Assize for the
time being Sir William Lewis Sir Herbert Price Sir Walter Williams Sir Thomas Williams Baronets William Morgan
of Threow Edward Proger Knight of the Shire John Jefferies Thomas Lane Thomas Mansell Marmaduke Lloyd
Thomas Lewis Lewis Morgan Attourney Generall Henry Proger William Le Hunt Thomas Walker Daniell Williams
Walter Vaughan Richard Williams of Cabalva William Morgan Edward Games John Williams Hugh Powell Edward
Powell Thomas Williams John Gunter Hugh Powell of the Glyin John Guynne Robert Lucy Marmaduke Guynne
Henry Vaughan Do&bholigct;or of Phisicke Edward Williams Jasper. Meller John Stydman Thomas Bowen Edward Herbert
Barzilla Jones John Morgan Walter Williams Edward Gwynn Lodowick Lewis Rees Prees William Vaughan Henry
Powell Edmond Jones John Powell Esquires Lewis Gunter John Walbeiff Phillip Parry Samuell Pitchard William
Bowens junior Richard Williams Edward Williams Henry Williams of Llanmider William Lloyd of Llandewyrcum
Lewin Jenkins John Walters. Thomas Vaughan William Morgan of Llangeny William Morgan of Penderen Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p269">For the Towne of Brecon</para>
			<para id="p270">John Jeffereys Es&bhoqexc; Rees Penren High Sheriffe Henry Stidman Richard Jones Charles Roberts William Thomas
Gentlemen The Bayliffe Recorder and Aldermen for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p271">For the County of Cardigan.</para>
			<para id="p272">Sir Thomas Price of, the Lodge Baronet Edward Vaughan of Trowescoed Hector Phillips of Cardigan Morgan
Herbert of Havod Thomas Price of Llanfread Hugh Griffith of Urglawdd James Jones of Abermaid Thomas Lloyd
of Ruarthan Erasmus Lloyd of Mabus Thomas Lloyd of Llewydyris Cornelius Lebrune of Nantees Watkyn Lloyd
of Werne John Lewis of Gervas Thomas Jenkins of Diffryn Lynod Nicholas Lewis of Pantyr-Odin John Lloyd
of Killgwynne Thomas Lloyd of Castle-Howell John Williams of Abernant Bichan Esquires Francis Vaughan of
Llanlery John Herbert of Gogerthan Richard Lloyd of the Mabus John Prise of Rhandir Thomas Lewis of Coedmore
Morgan Lloyd of Foes-Heligge Gentlemen The Maior for the Towne of Cardigan for the time being Arthur
Batman Mathew Griffith Barthplimew Young Robert Lloyd Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p273">For the County of Carmarthen.</para>
			<para id="p274">John Lord Vaughan sonne and heire apparent to the Earle of Carbery Sir Edward Mansell Sir Sackvile Crow
Sir Rice Rudd Sir William Russell Baronets Sir Rice Williams Knight Althom Vaughan Richard Vaughan of
Jorwood Walter Vaughan of Elanelly John Vaughan of Coderlis John Vaughan of Place Gwinn William Gwynne
of Taliares Thomas Lloyd of Berllandowell Owen Pristock Christopher Midleton Morgan Jones John Powell
Theophilus Lloyd Edward Vaughan of Penybanke Richard Bloome Thomas Williams James Jones of Dolethothy
William Bevans of Pencoed Roger Manwairing John. Phillipps of Dolehaydd John Morgans Richard Gwynne of
Gwenpa Richard Brett Esquires Thomas Lloyd of Alticadno John Williams of Abercothy Walter Jones of
Eloydeyforten John Lloyd of the Frood William Brickstocke of Lechtunny Arthur Gwynn of Pyode Charles
Phillips of Lletigaryad John Evans of Treventy Gentlemen Thomas Gwynne of Cynghordu Francis Price of
Llanedy Gentlemen.</para>
			<para id="p275">For the Towne of Carmarthen.</para>
			<para id="p276">The Maior for the time being John Lord Vaughan Altham Vaughan Walter Vaughan John Vaughan of Coderlis
John Vaughan of Place Gwynne Jonathan' Ockley Esquires John Lloyd Towne Clerke Thomas Jones Daukin Goffe
Richard Thomas John Scurlock Thomas Bynon John Ockley Robert Lewis William Brickstoke John Williams
Richard Lee Aldermen Henry Vaughan Gent..</para>
			<para id="p277">For the County of Carnarvarn.</para>
			<para id="p278">Richard Wynne Es&bhoqexc; High Sheriffe of the said County Robert Lord Viscount Bulkley of the Kingdome of
Ireland Robert Roberts Thomas Bulkley Esquires Sir John Wynne Sir Roger Mostin Sir Robert Williams Baronets
Thomas Mostyn Nicholas Bagenall William Griffith William Owen Lewis Anwill Griffith Vaughan Robert Wynne
Thomas Vaughan John Wynne of Melay Robert Coytmore Griffith Wynne Hugh Williams William Bulkley
Griffith Bodurda John [Wynn<ref idref="n53">53</ref>] Berthaur Thomas Madrin John Wynne Tygwin Richard Anwill John Glynne
Richard Griffith Robert Hookes Owen Wynne Richard Kiffin William Pritherch Lewis Mericke Robert Wynne
Keselgoferch William Wynne Llanunda Holland Williams Hugh Bodurda William Spicer William Thomas Thomas
Wynne William Glynne Randall Wynne Esquires William Arthur Hugh Lewis Owen Parry Richard Edwards
Evan Lloyd John Owen of Varchell Hugh Owen Gentlemen William Wynne of Glanravon Es&bhoqexc;</para>
			<para id="p279">For the County of Denbigh.</para>
			<para id="p280">John Langford Es&bhoqexc; High Sheriffe Sir John Winne Knight and Baronet Sir John Salisbury Sir Walter Baggott
Sir Thomas Powell Sir Evan Lloyd Sir Thomas Midleton Baronets Sir Roger Mostin Knight and Baronet Sir
William Neale Baronet Sir Thomas Jones one of His Majestyes Justices of the Kings Bench Sir Robert Agborough
Sir John Trevor and Sir Kenricke Eyton Knights William Owen Thomas Powell Thomas Cartar William Salisbury
John Wynne John Trevor of Trevalin Edward Thelwall of Plas y Ward Edward Vaughan of Lloydiarth John
Robinson Mutton Davies Edward Brereton Cadwallader Wynne John Thelwall Eubule Thellwall William Williams
Thomas Vaughan John Jeffreys John Edisbury Robert Wynne of Berthee William Price David Maurice of Penn
y Bont Edward Maurice of Lloran Richard Midleton of Chirke Charles Midleton Francis Manley Owen Wynne
William Parry Bevis Lloyd Owen Thelwall Mathew Price Robert Price of Geeler Joshua Edisbury William Lloyd
of Halton John Midleton Richard Midleton of Llanselin Charles Goodman [Charles<ref idref="n54">54</ref>] Lloyd of Llanynus Richard
Lloyd of Segroit Roger Mostin of Brimbo Hugh Roberts John Dolbin John Maesmore Pierce Foulkes of
Meriedog John Price of Vanoll Hugh Merideth John Lloyd of Bodidrist John Lloyd of Gwreck Hedd Lloyd
Thomas Holland William Vaughan of Bronhilog William Jones Peter Foulkes of Erriviat Ellis Lloyd of Plas Eignion
John Chambers Richard Parry Thomas Rosindole Ellis Lloyd of Ruabon Edward Lloyd of Plas Madocke and
Jesper Pecke Esquires Robert Wynne of Garthewinne Howell Lloyd Eubule Lloyd Robert Turbridge Thomas Lloyd
of Wrexam Meredith Wynne Edward Williams Robert Holland Ellis Sutton David Lloyd Craes Owen Henry
Vaughan of Glynne John Lloyd of Rossa John Griffith John Edwards of Stansti Thomas Griffith Owen Lloyd
of Wickwer John Lloyd of Brin Keyar David Lloyd of Llangollen Vawr John Madocks John Ashpoole Edward
Chambers David Williams Edward of Holt Parke Robert Cawley William Mores The two Aldermen
and two Bayliffes of Denbigh for the time being Edward Davies Robert Roberts Foulke Davies Thomas Roberts
Robert Edwards of Plas Yolyn Edward Lloyd of Dwyvaen Robert Wynne of Llangwyn David Lloyd of Kum
and Roderick Lewis Gentlemen The Maior of the Towne of Holt for the time being.</para>
			<para id="p281">For the County of Flint</para>
			<para id="p282">John Royden Es&bhoqexc; High Sheriffe of the County Sir Thomas Hanmer Sir John Salisbury Sir Thomas Grosvenor
Sir Evan Lloyd Sir Roger Mostyn Sir William Glynne Baronets Sir John Hanmer Sir John Trevor Sir Kenricke
Eyton Sir Richard Lang-ley Knights Thomas Ravenscroft Thomas Hanmer of Fens John Trevor Mutton Davies
Thomas Mostyne Tho: Lloyd Robert Whitley Roger Whitley Thomas Carter Edward Ravenscroft John Salisbury
senior Thomas Evans William Williams Ralph Whitley John Broughton Thomas Eaton Thomas Griffith Edward
Morgan William Griffith Thomas Pindar Pierce Pennante Kenricke Eyton Owen Wynne William Hanmer William
Mostyne John Price Ellis Younge Thomas Humphres John Salisbury junior John Parry Thomas Whitley Charles
Jones William Lloyd Luke Lloyd senior Edward Lloyd Thomas Whitley Thomas Crachley Owen Barton
Edward Evatt Jesper Pecke Esquires John Lloyd of Knollton John Lloyd of Wellington Luke Lloyd junior Edward
Lloyd Edward Wynne Thomas Edwards John Whitley Josiah Jones William Phillips Thomas Price Thomas Hanmer
Walter Clapton John Salisbury of Erbistocke William Rutter Roger Jones of Abinbury.</para>
			<para id="p283">For the County of Glamorgan.</para>
			<para id="p284">Charles Lord Herbert of Ragland sonne and heire apparent to the Marquesse of Worcester Robert Lord Lisle
sonne and heire apparent to the Earle of Leicester Thomas Streete Owen Wynne Esquires His Majestyes Justices
of the Great Sessions Sir Edward Mansell Sir Edward Stradling Sir Robert Thomas Sir Charles Kennish Baronets
Sir. John Awbrey Baronet Sir Leoline Jenkins Sir Herbert Evans Sir John Jones Knights William Morgan
Edmond Thomas Bussey Mansell Richard Lewis David Jenkins Sergeant Seys Humphrey Windham William Herbert
Martin Button Thomas Stradling John Carne Thomas Mansell Button Ferrey Phillip Hobby Thomas Carne John
Windham Richard Bassett John Awbrey Edward Mathews of Aberamant Thomas Bassett of Llanvithan William
Thomas of Ruperra Marmaduke Gibbs Walter Evans William Thomas of Llanbradocke Francis Gwynn Thomas
Lewis Richard Sayes Richard Laugher Esquires William Thomas of Danny Gragge George Bowen Jeremy Dawkins
John Van David Mathew Es&bhoqexc; Edward Mathews of Llandaffe Edmond Gammage Esquire James Gwyn Thomas
Mansell James Turbervill John Lluellin Corr William Lewis of Criga William Edwards of Stenbridge Thomas
Laugher of Cornely Miles Button Edward Thomas Lewis Thomas Edward Mansell of Hentlas George Williams
David Evans Rowland [Dowkins<ref idref="n55">55</ref>] Richard Jenkins of Panty Nowell William Awbrey of Pencoedd Edward Turbervill
George Lucas Roger Powell of Enar Glynn Robert Bidder Iltid Nicholl Miles Button of Miskin William Says
Thomas Williams John Greene Bayliffes of Cardiffe.</para>
			<para id="p285">For the County of Merioneth.</para>
			<para id="p286">Griffith Vaughan Es&bhoqexc; High Sheriffe of the County Sir John Wynne Knight and Baronet Sir Thomas Midleton
William Salisbury William Owen William Price Edward Vaughan Owen Wynne of Glynne John Lloyd of Maesy
Pandy Lewis Anwill Ellis Edwards Richard Anwill William Pugh Lewis Owen William Williams of Glascoed Vincent
Corbet William Vaughan of Caethley John Vaughan of Caergas John Lloyd junior Humphrey Hughes Owen Anwill
Richard Anwill John of Comin Nathaniell Jones John Lloyd of Rhiwedog Richard Mostin John Naney of
Llanvendegedd Hugh Tudor John Maesmore Edmond Meiricke Esquires Owen Eyton John Price Oliver Thomas
William Vaughan of Caergas Anthony Thomas Evan Evans William Williams Captaine William Humphreys William
Humphreys of Maerdy Griffith Vaughan of Dolymelinllin Robert Price Yskernetha Rowland Ellis Edward Wynne
Gentlemen The Maior of Bala for the time being Evan Lloyd Rhiwgrch Gentleman.</para>
			<para id="p287">For the County of Montgomery.</para>
			<para id="p288">Henry Herbert Andrew Newport Esquires Sir Richard Corbett Sir John Price Baronet Sir John Whitterong Sir
Francis Lawley Sir Charles Lloyd Sir Thomas Jones Sir Richard Mason Henry Herbert [Richard Owen<ref idref="n56">56</ref>] of
Rhusacson Edward Vaughan of Lloydiarth Edward Vaughan of Gwernygo William Pugh of Mathaverne Robert
Leighton Edward Lloyd of Berth-Lloyd William Okeley George Devereux Richard Mostyne of Dolicostin Edmund
Wareing Mathew Price of Parke Francis Buller junior David Maurice Vice Comes Thomas Corbett Thomas Winde
Arthur Weaver William Williams Mathew Morgan Esquires Edmond Lloyd of Tevenant David Powell Richard
Stedman Rowland Hunt John Mathewes Esquires Richard Mitton William Eyton Robert Lee John Wynne of
Dolarthen Charles Herbert of Aston Es&bhoqexc; John Whittingham John Kiffin Esquire Edward Lloyd of Mathravall
Captaine Richard Griffiths of Sutton John Lloyd of Llanavon John Williams Edward Price of Glanmahely
Edward Barrett Richard Herbert of Kerrey Evan Glynn Esquires Thomas Mason John Okely Edward Whittingham
Thomas Hudson Edward Evans of Rhidicarrow Vincent Pierce Evan Vaughan Evan Evans of Coome Yr Annell
James Penrhyn Hugh Davies of Colfrin Edward Herbert John Bright of Millington Meredith Lloyd of Brynellen
Richardus Lloyd of Cowny John Bunner Henry Griffiths of Benthall Morgan Evans Robert Owen of Woodhouse
Richard Ingram of Llainedles William Penrhin Arthur Vaughan John Edwards of Llanvaire William Biggs Edward
Price Richard Owen junior of Rhusacson John Edwards of Rerington William Mathews of Gwerndee Evan
Jones of Little Hem John Reade of Penrithlan Thomas Lloyd of Trouscott John Griffiths of Llanavron Humphres
Jones of Poole Edmond Jones of Llanvellen William Pierce of Crew Henry Blayney Edward Lloyd of Llandrinio
Thomas Maurice Nathaniell Kynaston Daniell Whittingham Nicholas Wareing George Robinson Humphrey Jones
David Price Thomas Davies Griffith Robinson Charles Jones of Leighton Roger Jones John Vaughon of Mivod
Humphrey Lloyd of Goetree Roger Trevor Gent. Andrew Newport Morris Lloyd of Hemblasse Richard Glynne
of Gwystrid.</para>
			<para id="p289">For the County of Pembrooke.</para>
			<para id="p290">Sir Erasmus Phillips Sir John Stepneth Sir Hugh Owen Sir John Barlowe Baronets Sir Herbert Perrott Knight
David Maurice High Sheriffe Arthur Owen senior Essex Meyricke Lewis Barlow Rowland Langharne Hugh
Bowin Arthur Owen junior He&bholigct; Phillips Lewis Wogan of Bowlston William Owen<ref idref="n57">57</ref> Griffith Dawes Walter
Midleton William Phillipps William Wogun William Mordaunt William Scourfield Lewis Wogun of Wiston John
Owen of Trefoone John Cannon David Williams Thomas Howard John Elliot Arthur Langharne Thomas Lort
Thomas Lloyd Nathaniell Powell Richard Phillips John Thomas Thomas Bowen John Williams James Lloyd
William Owen of Cameogg David Morgan Nicholas Adams Hugh Langharne John Barlowe John Mathias George
Bowen Lewis John William Warren William Meare Esquires Thomas Cosens William Forde Richard Cuney
Thomas Symins Morgan Vaughan Thomas Jones William Bowen of Williamston Jenkin Jones John Jordon John
Meiricke Captaine William Williams Barrett Bowen John Lewis Thomas Jones William Lloyd of Trewent Gentlemen
William Skirme John Bell The Maior of Pembrooke for the time being George Powell Francis Rogers Aldermen
The Maior of Tenby for the time being Henry Jones Devereux Homond Aldermen.</para>
			<para id="p291">For the County of Radnor.</para>
			<para id="p292">Sir Edward Harley Sir Thomas Williams Baronet Samuell Powell junior Edward Davis John Davies Esquires
William Lloyd Gent. Robert Sawyer John Morgan Richard Fowler John Walcott Rowland Gwynne Richard
Williams Thomas Corbett Thomas Harley Samuell Powell Thomas Lewis of Haepton Griffith Jones Henry Probert
Henry Bull Edward Freeman Robert Cutler High Sheriffe of the County of Radnor for the time being Thomas
Lewis of Monaughtee Richard Crowther Thomas Hughes Thomas Vaughan Edward Price John, Fowler Marmaduke
Gwynne Nicholas Meredeth James Lloyd John Valsam Esquires Herbert Weston John James Nicholas Taylor
Thomas, Lewis junior Hugh Powell Esquires James Becke Serjeant at Armes Jonas Stephens William Taylor
Francis Richards Gabriell Taylor Evan Vaughan Gent. Griffith Jones junior John Lewis of Gladestrie Lloyd Weston
Thomas Williams Thomas Griffith.</para>
			<para id="p293">For the Towne and County of Haverford West.</para>
			<para id="p294">The Maior for the time being, The Sheriffe for the time being Sir Erasmus Phillipps Sir John Stepnethe Sir
Hugh Owen Baronets Sir [Federicke<ref idref="n57">57</ref>] Hyde Sir Herbert Perrott Knights William Phillipps John Barlowe John
Thomas Esquires William Williams Thomas Cousins Gentlemen Lewis Barron Balthasar Wolford John Williams
Roger Davies John Lloyd William Browne John Bateman Robert Pruste Thomas Bowen Aldermen Richard Jones
William Bowin Gentlemen.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Meetings of Commissioners to execute A&bholigct; 10th May next; may divide themselves</head>
			<para id="p295">And bee it further en&bholigct;ed and declared That the severall Commissioners aforesaid shall meete together at the
most usuall and common place of Meeting within each of the said Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and
Places respectively on or before the Tenth day of May now next comeing and the said Commissioners or soe
many of them as shall be present at the [said<ref idref="n58">58</ref>] first generall Meeting or the major part of them are hereby
authorized and required to putt this present A&bholigct; in Execution according to the best of their judgements and
discretions and shall then if they see cause subdivide and distribute themselves into lesser numbers as Two or
more of the said Commissioners may be appointed for the Service of each Hundred or other Division and as may
best conduce to the carrying on of his Majestyes Service hereby required.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. to set down in Writing what Number shall a&bholigct; in each Division.</head>
			<para id="p296">And for the more effectuall performance thereof bee it en&bholigct;ed and declared That the Commissioners at their
aforesaid first generall meeting or the major part of them shall agree and sett downe in writeing who and what
number of the said Commissioners shall a&bholigct; in each of the said Divisions or Hundreds and shall deliver a true
Copy of such writeing to the Receiver Generall to the end that there be noe failer in any part of the due
execution of the service by this A&bholigct; required</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Receiver General to give to Commissioners Receipts for Payments made to them.</head>
			<para id="p297">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That every Receiver Generall from time to time within
the space of one moneth next after he shall have received the full summe that shall be charged upon any
Hundred or Division for each perticular payment that is to be made to such Receiver Generall by vertue of this
A&bholigct; shall give to the Commissioners that shall a&bholigct; in such Hundred or Division a Receipt under his hand and
seale acknowledging his Receipt of the full summe charged upon such Hundred or Division for such perticular
payment which Receipt shall be a full discharge of such Hundred or Division for such perticular payment both
against his Majestie his Heires and Successors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Commissioners to cause Assessment to be equally made, and to appoint Assessors,; who are to assess by a Pound Rate.</head>
			<para id="p298">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid That the Commissioners within the severall
Divisions or Hundreds or any Two or more of them are hereby authorized and required to cause the said
severall proportions charged on the respe&bholigct;ive Divisions and on every Parish and Place therein for the said
seaventeene moneths Assesment to be equally assessed and taxed and to appoint Two or more Assessors in each
Parish or Place for the perfecting thereof who are hereby required with all care and diligence to assesse the same
equally by a Pound Rate upon all Lands Tenements Hereditaments Annuities Rents Parks Warrens Goods Chattells
Stock Merchandices Offices (other then Military Offices and Offices relateing to the Navy under the Command of
the Lord High Admirall and Offices within his Majestyes Household) Tolls Proffitts and all other Estates both
reall and personall within the Limitts Circuits and Bounds of their respe&bholigct;ive Parishes and Places.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII.&pound;103,231.8s. 7&frac12;d. the First Payment, to be paid to Receiver General; on or before 24th June 1677; Second Payment, 29th Sept. 1677;</head>
			<para id="p299">
				<emph type="i">Third Payment, 25th Dec. 1677; Fourth Payment, 25th March 1678; Fifth Payment, 24th June 1678; Last Payment, 24th August 1678</emph>; 
				<emph type="i">
Assessors to deliver Copy of Assesment to Commissioners who are to sign and seal Two Duplicates, and deliver one to Collector, whom they are to appoint, together with a Warrant to colle&bholigct; the Assessments.; Monies to be paid to Receiver General, and by him into the Exchequer</emph>.
</para>
			<para id="p300">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the summe of One hundred and three thousand
two hundred thirty one pounds eight shillings seaven pence halfe penny being the first of the said Five quarterly
and two moneths payment hereby imposed shall be assessed collected leavyed and paid unto the Receiver Generall
of the said severall Countyes who shall be appointed by his Majestie on or before the Fower and twentieth day
of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven And the summe of One hundred
and three thousand two hundred thirty one pounds eight shillings seaven pence halfe penny being the second of
the said Five quarterly and two moneths payments on or before the twenty nineth day of September in the yeare
of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven, And the summe of One hundred and three thousand
two hundred thirty one pounds eight shillings seaven pence halfe penny being the Third of the said Five quarterly
and two moneths payments on or before the Twenty fifth day of December in the yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven, And the summe of One hundred and three thousand two hundred
thirty one pounds eight shillings seaven pence halfe penny being the Fourth of the said Five quarterly and Two
moneths Payments on or before the Twenty fifth day of March in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six
hundred seaventy and eight, And the summe of One hundred and three thousand two hundred thirty one
pounds eight shillings seaven pence halfe penny being the Fifth of the said Five quarterly and two moneths
payments on or before the Twenty fourth day of June in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred
seaventy and eight And the summe of Sixty eight thousand eight hundred and twenty pounds nineteene shillings 
one penny being the said Two moneths payment and the last of the respe&bholigct;ive payments above mentioned on
or before the Twenty fourth day of August in the said yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy
and eight. And for the compleating of the whole summe charged upon the same and to the end the aforesaid
summes charged upon the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Burroughes Townes and Places may be equally
and indifferently assessed according to the true intent of this A&bholigct; and the money duely colle&bholigct;ed and true
Accompt thereof made the said Assessors are hereby required to deliver one Copy of their respe&bholigct;ive Assesments
fairely written and subscribed by them unto the said Commissioners and the said Commissioners or any two (
<ref idref="n59">59</ref>) of
them are hereby ordered and required to signe and seale Two Duplicates of the said Assesments and the one
of them to deliver or cause to be delivered to one or more honest and responsible person or persons to be
Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors which the said Commissioners are hereby authorized to nominate and appointe for each
Parish or Place with Warrant to the said Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors to colle&bholigct; the said Assesment payable as aforesaid
soe as the said severall summes may be paid in to the said Receivers Generall at the respe&bholigct;ive times aforesaid.
And the said Commissioners are hereby required to deliver or cause to be delivered a Schedule or Note containing
the perticular summes assessed upon each Parish or Place to the Receiver Generall of each County Citty Burrough
Towne or Place respe&bholigct;ively to be by him the said Receiver Generall transmitted into the Kings Remembrancers
Office in the Exchequer which the said Receiver Generall is required to performe accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Collectors to pay Money received by them to Receiver General.</head>
			<para id="p301">
				<emph type="i">Receipt of Receiver General a Discharge.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p302">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid That the money received by the said Colle&bholigct;ors
within the respe&bholigct;ive Divisions or Hundreds shall from time to time be duely paid to the Receiver Generall or
to his Deputy or Deputyes to be appointed under his Hand and Seale whereof Notice under the Hand and Seale
of the Receiver Generall shall be given unto the Commissioners or any two of them within the respe&bholigct;ive
Divisions or Hundreds within Ten dayes after the first generall meeting and soe from time to time within
Ten dayes after every death or removeall of any Deputy if any such shall happen, and the Receipt of such
Receiver Generall his Deputy or Deputyes or any of them shall be a sufficient discharge unto every such
Colle&bholigct;or.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Particular Colle&bholigct;ors to pay in Money received by them to Receiver General.</head>
			<para id="p303">
				<emph type="i">Not obliged to travel more than Ten Miles to pay Money; Salary to Receiver General 2d. in the Pound.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p304">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the particular Colle&bholigct;ors are hereby required to pay in all and
every the summes soe received by them unto the said Receivers Generall aforesaid or their Deputy or Deputyes
for Payment whereof the said Colle&bholigct;ors shall not be obliged to travell above Ten miles from the places of their
habitations, which said Receivers Generall are hereby required forthwith to transmitt or cause to be paid the
moneyes by them received into the Receipt of his Majestyes Exchequer, And the said Lord Treasurer is hereby
authorized to allow the said Receiver Generall of each County Citty and Towne respe&bholigct;ively in case he hath
returned up as aforesaid a Duplicate of the Assesment of each Parish or Place in the County Citty or Towne
for which he is appointed Receiver Generall a Salary for his paines not exceeding Two pence in the pound upon
the clearing [of<ref idref="n60">60</ref>] his Accompt, which Duplicate soe to be returned into the Kings Remembrancers Office in
the Exchequer is intended to containe noe more then the summes in grosse to be collected by each Colle&bholigct;or
and the severall Names of the said Colle&bholigct;ors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Collectors to receive 4d. in the Pound.</head>
			<para id="p305">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners Clerks 1d. in the Pound.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p306">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the Colle&bholigct;ors of each Parish or Place which shall be
appointed by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall upon colle&bholigct;ion of the whole summe appointed to be colle&bholigct;ed by them
and payment thereof as is hereby before appointed have and receive for their paines in colle&bholigct;ing and paying the
moneys Fower pence in the Pound which the said Colle&bholigct;ors are impowered to detaine out of the last payment
of the money of their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Five quarterly and Two monethes payments, and the said Receiver
Generall upon the Receipt of the whole Assesment of the County Citty or Towne for which he is appointed
Receiver Generall in case he hath received the severall Duplicates of each Parish or Place therein and not
otherwise shall allow and pay according to such Warrant as shall be in that behalfe given by the said Commissioners
or any Three of them One Penny in the Pound for the Commissioners Clerks for their paines in faire Writeing
the Assesments Duplicates and Copyes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Persons rated refusing to pay, Distress.</head>
			<para id="p307">
				<emph type="i">Collectors may break open Houses, Chests, &amp;c. in the Day-time, calling to their Assistance Constables, &amp;c.; Questions upon Distresses to be determined by Commissioners; Refusing to pay, or conveying Goods, &amp;c. away.; Imprisonment, (except Peers)</emph>;
<emph type="i">Tenants to pay Rate on Houses or Land, and dedu&bholngs; out of Rent.; Landlords to allow such Deductions</emph>.
</para>
			<para id="p308">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That if any person shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to pay any summe of
money whereat he shall be rated and assessed that then it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Colle&bholigct;ors
or any of them who are hereby authorized and required thereunto to leavy the summe assessed by Distresse and
Sale of the Goods of such person soe refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing to pay dedu&bholigct;ing the summe assessed and reasonable
charges of destraining and restoreing the Overplus to the Owner thereof and to breake open in the day time
any House and upon Warrant under the Hands and Seales of Two or more of the said Commissioners any Chest
Trunke Box or other things where any such Goods are and to call to their Assistance the Constables Tythingmen
and Headburroughes within the Countyes Cittyes Townes and Places where any refusall negle&bholigct; or resistance shall
be made which said Officers are hereby required to be aiding and assisting in the Premisses as they will answere
the contrary at their perrills. And if any question or difference happen upon takeing of such Distresses upon the
partyes distressed or destrained the same shall be ended and determined by the said Commissioners or any Two
or more of them, And if any person or persons shall negle&bholigct; or refuse to pay his or their Assesment or convey
his or their Goods or other personall Estate whereby the summes of money soe assessed cannot be leavyed
according to this A&bholigct; then the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any Two or more of them are hereby authorized to
imprison the person (except a Peere or Peers of this Realme) and him and them in Prison to detaine and keepe
untill the moneyes soe assessed and the charges for the bringing in the same be paid and satisfyed and noe longer.
and the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Tennant or Tennants of all Houses and Lands which shall be rated by vertue of
this A&bholigct; are hereby required and authorized to pay such summe or summes of money as shall be rated upon
such Houses or Lands and to deduct out of the Rent soe much of the said rates as in respe&bholigct; of the said Rents
of every such House and Lands the Landlord should or ought to pay and beare, And the said Landlords both
mediate and immediate according to their respe&bholigct;ive Interests are hereby required to allow such dedu&bholigct;ions, and
payments upon the receipt of the residue of their Rents.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Tenant so paying acquitted for Amount of Payment.</head>
			<para id="p309">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may settle Differences between Landlords and Tenants.; Persons aggrieved by Assessment may complain to Commissioners, who may relieve</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p310">And it is ena&bholigct;ed and declared That every Tenant paying the said Assesment shall be acquitted and discharged
for soe much money as the said Assesments shall amount unto as if the same had beene a&bholigct;ually paid unto such
person or persons unto whome his Rents should have beene due and payable. And if any differences shall arise
betweene Landlord and Tenant or any other concerning the said Rates, the said severall Commissioners or any
two or more of them in their severall Divisions shall and have hereby power to setle the same as they shall thinke
fitt, and if any person or persons shall finde him or themselves agrieved in that the Assessors have overrated
him or them and shall in six dayes after demand made of the summe of money assessed on him or their
complaine to two or more Commissioners whereof one of the C&bhooov;miss[ion]ers who signed or allowed his or their
Assesments to be one, the said Commissioners or any two or more of them shall have and have hereby power
within Twelve dayes after the demand of the Assesment as aforesaid to relieve such person or persons and to
charge the same on such other person or persons as they shall see cause.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. If Assessment be not fully paid, or laid on Persons unable, or on empty Houses, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p311">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners, &amp;c. may re-assess; and the new Assessment to be paid accordingly</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p312">And in case the proportions sett by this A&bholigct; `` upon all and every the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Townes and
Places shall not be fully assessed leavyed and paid according to the true meaning hereof or that if any of
the said Assesments shall be rated and imposed upon any person not being of ability to pay the same or upon
any empty or void House or Land where the same cannot be colle&bholigct;ed or leavyed or that through any wilfulnes
negligence mistake or accident the said Assesment charged on each County Citty Towne or Place by vertue of
this A&bholigct; happens not to be paid to the Receiver Generall his Deputy or Deputyes of the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes as
in this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed, That then in all and every such cases the severall and respe&bholigct;ive C&bhooov;miss[ion]ers Assessors and
Colle&bholigct;ors aforesaid and every of them respe&bholigct;ively are hereby authorized and required to assesse or reassesse or
cause to bee assessed or reassessed leavyed and paid all and every such summe and summes of money upon the
respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes Townes and Places or upon any the Divisions Hundreds and Parishes therein as to
the said Commissioners or such number of them as by this A&bholigct; are authorized to cause the first Assesment
hereby required to be made shall seeme most agreable to Equity and Justice, the said new Assesment to be
made colle&bholigct;ed and paid in such manner and by such meanes as in this A&bholigct; for this Assesment is declared and
dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. Persons refusing to execute A&bholigct; Commissioners may fine them, not exceeding &pound; 20. for One Offence.</head>
			<para id="p313">
				<emph type="i"> Fines how to be paid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p314">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authority aforesaid That if any person or persons shall wilfully
negle&bholigct; or refuse to performe his or their duty in the due and speedy execution of this present A&bholigct;, the said
respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any three or more of them have hereby power to impose on such person or persons
soe refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing their Dutyes such Fine or Fines as by them shall be thought fitt and to cause the
same to be leavyed by Distresse and Sale of his and their Goods. Provided that noe Fine to be imposed by any
of the said Commissioners shall for any one Offence exceede the summe of Twenty pounds, and that all Fines
that shall be imposed by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be paid to the respe&bholigct;ive Receivers Generall and by them to
the Receipt of His Majestyes Exchequer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Colle&bholigct;ors not paying, or detaining Monies received by them, Commissioners may imprison them and seize their Estates Real and Personal;</head>
			<para id="p315">
				<emph type="i">and thereupon call a Meeting by Public Notice, and thereat may proceed to Bell Estates and satisfy thereout the Monics so detained, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p316">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That if any Colle&bholigct;or that shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; be appointed for
the Receipt of any summe or summes of money thereby to be assessed negle&bholigct; or refuse to pay any summe
or summes of money which shall by him be received as aforesaid, and to pay the same as in and by this A&bholigct; is
dire&bholigct;ed and shall detaine in his or their hands any money received by them or any of them and not pay the
same as by this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed, the Commissioners of each County Citty or Towne respe&bholigct;ively or any Two or more
of them in their respe&bholigct;ive Divisions are hereby authorized and impowered to imprison the person and seize and
secure the estate both reall and personall of such Colle&bholigct;or to him belonging or which shall descend or come into
the hands or possession of his Heires Executors or Administrators wherever the same can be discovered and found,
and the said Commissioners who shall soe seize and secure the Estate of any Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors shall be and
are hereby impowered to appoint a time for the generall meeting of the Commissioners for such County Citty
Towne or Place and there to cause publique notice to be given at the place where such meeting shall bee appointed
Ten dayes at least before such generall meeting, and the Commissioners present at such generall meeting or the
major part of them in case the moneyes detained by any Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors be not paid or satisfyed as it ought
to be according to the dire&bholigct;ions of this A&bholigct; shall and are hereby impowered and required to sell and dispose of
all such Estates which shall be for the cause aforesaid seized and secured or any part of them and satisfie and
pay such County and Place the summe that shall be soe detained in the hands of such Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors
their Heires Executors and Administrators respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. At the Expiration of times for the said Payments Commissioners to; 
call Colle&bholigct;ors before them, and assure themselves of Payments of Monies charged.;
</head>
<para id="p317">
<emph type="i">
In case of Failure Commissioners to levy the same.
</emph>
</para>
			<para id="p318">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That at the expiration of the respe&bholigct;ive times in this A&bholigct; prescribed
for the full payment of the said Five quarterly and two moneths Assesments the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners
or any two of them within their Division and Hundred shall and are hereby required to call before them the
				
Colle&bholigct;ors within each respe&bholigct;ive. Division and Hundred to examine and assure themselves of the full and whole
payment of the particular summe and summes of money charged upon the same Division Hundred and every.
Parish and Place therein and of the due returne of the same into the hands of the Receivers Generall their Deputy
or Deputyes of the said County Citty Towne and Place respe&bholigct;ively and by such Receiver Generall into the Receipt
of His Majestyes Exchequer to the end there may be noe failer in the payment of any part of the Assesment by
vertue of this A&bholigct; to be assessed and paid nor any Arreares remaine chargeable upon any the said Countyes
Cittyes Townes or Places respe&bholigct;ively and in case of any failer in the premisses the said Commissioners or any Two
of them are hereby to cause the same to be forthwith leavyed and paid according to the true intent and meaning
of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. If Controversies arise in which Commissioners interested, such Commissioners to withdraw.</head>
			<para id="p319">And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That in case any Controversie arise concerning the said Assesment or
the dividing apportioning or payment thereof which concerns any the Commissioners by this A&bholigct; appointed that
the Commissioners soe concerned in the said Controversie shall have noe voice but shall withdraw at the time of
the debate of any such controversie untill it be determined by the rest of the Commissioners.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Privileged Places, Fee Farm Rents, &amp;c. liable.</head>
			<para id="p320">
				<emph type="i">Proviso for Tenants thereof paying</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p321">And bee it hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That noe priviledged place or person Body Pollitique or Corporate
within the Countyes Cittyes and Townes aforesaid shall be exempted from the said Assesments and Taxes and
that they and every of them and alsoe all Fee farme Rents and all other manner of Rents Payments Summes of
money Annuities issueing out of any Lands within Citty or County shall be lyable towards the payment of
every summe by this A&bholigct; to be taxed and leavyed and all the Tenants of every Fee farme Rent, other Rent
Summes of money or Annuities aforesaid are hereby dire&bholigct;ed and authorized to pay them proportionably according
to the Rates and Assesments by this A&bholigct; appointed and dire&bholigct;ed, and all such Tenants shall be hereby saved and
kept harmlesse by authority of this A&bholigct; from any further payment of such portion of any such Rent, Rents
Summes or Annuities either to the Exchequer or to any other person or persons to whome any such Rent, Rents
Summes of moneyes or Annuities as aforesaid should or ought to be paid to all intents and purposes whatsoever
as fully and amply as if they had paid the same into the Exchequer or to any person or persons to whom the
same is reserved or become due.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Proviso for the Universities and the Colleges of Winchester, Eton, Westminster, Free Schools ; Hospitals of Saint Bartholomew, Bridewell, Saint Thomas, and Bethlehem, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p322">
				<emph type="i">But Tenants under Lease from said Hospitals to pay</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p323">Provided That nothing contained in this A&bholigct; be extended to charge any Colledge or Hall in either of the two
Universityes or of the Colledges of Windsor Eaton Winton or Westminster or any Hospitall for or in respe&bholigct; of
the Scites of the said Colledges Halls or Hospitalls nor any Master Fellow or Scholler of any such Colledge or
Hall or in any other Free Schooles or any Reader Officer or Minister of the said Universityes Colledges or
Schooles or of any Hospitalls or Almeshouses for or in respe&bholigct; of any Stipend Wages or Proffitts whatsoever ariseing
or growing due to them in respe&bholigct; of the said severall places and imployments in the said Universityes Colledges
Schooles Hospitalls or Almeshouses nor to charge any of the Houses or Lands belonging to Christs Hospitall Saint.
Bartholimews Bridewell Saint Thomas and Bethlehem Hospitall in the Citty of London and Burrough of Southwarke
or any of them for or in respe&bholigct; of any Rents or Revenews payable to the said Hospitalls being to be received,
and disbursed for the immediate use and reliefe of the Poore in the said Hospitalls. Provided That noe Tenants
that hold and enjoy any Lands or Houses by Lease or other Grant from any of the said Hospitalls doe claime
and enjoy any freedome exemption or advantage by this A&bholigct; but that all the Houses and Lands which they soe
hold shall be rated and assessed for soe much as they are yearely worth over and above the Rents reserved
and payable to the said Hospitalls.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Person dwelling in London in one Parish, &amp;c. and having Goods in other Parishes, &amp;c. to be charged where he dwells.</head>
			<para id="p324">Provided alsoe That where any person inhabiting within the Citty of London hath his Dweling house in one
of the Parishes or Wards therein and hath any Goods Wares or Merchandices in one or more of the other Parishes
or Wards within the same that then such person shall be charged taxed and assessed for such his Goods or
Merchandices in the Parish or Ward where he dwelleth and not elsewhere within the said Citty.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. No Clause in this A&bholigct; to lessen Payment.</head>
			<para id="p325">Provided neverthelesse That noe Clause or Provisoe in this A&bholigct; shall extend to the lessening or abatement of
the full summe by this A&bholigct; appointed to be taxed, leavyed colle&bholigct;ed and paid but that the same be fully assessed
taxed leavyed colle&bholigct;ed and paid in the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes and Townes aforesaid in such
manner and forme and to such uses as herein before is mentioned and declared.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. If Pound Rate be found prejudicial Commissioners may assess in the manner usual in respe&bholigct;ive Counties, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p326">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That in case the way or manner of assessing by a
Pound Rate shall prove any wayes prejudiciall or obstru&bholigct;ive to the said speedy bringing in of the Assesment or
any part thereof appointed by this A&bholigct; that then and in all such cases the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any two
of them are hereby authorized to order and dire&bholigct; their respe&bholigct;ive Assessors who are hereby required to proceede
accordingly to assesse the respe&bholigct;ive summes charged on the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cittyes and Burroughes Townes and
places mentioned in this A&bholigct; according to the most just and usuall rates held and pra&bholigct;ised in such Countyes
Cittyes Burroughes Townes and places respe&bholigct;ively Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof contained in any
wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. Proviso for Agreements as to Taxes between Landlord and Tenant.</head>
			<para id="p327">Provided alwayes That nothing in this A&bholigct; contained shall be construed to alter change determine or make
void any Contra&bholigct;s Covenants or Agreements whatsoever betweene the Landlord and Tenant touching the payment,
of Taxes and Assesments Any thing herein before mentioned to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Places to be assessed in such Hundreds, &amp;c. as heretofore.</head>
			<para id="p328">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the authority aforesaid That for the avoiding
of all obstru&bholigct;ions and delayes in colle&bholigct;ing the summes by this A&bholigct; to be rated and assessed all Places
Constablewicks Divisions and Allotments which have used to be rated and assessed shall pay and be assesed
in such County Hundred Rape and Wapentake as the same have heretofore beene usually assessed in and not
elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXXV. In A&bholigct;ions brought for executing A&bholigct;, General Issue may be pleaded.</head>
			<para id="p329">
				<emph type="i">Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p330">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion, Plaint Suite or Information shall be
commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in execution
of this A&bholigct; such person or persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall and may plead the Generall Issue (Not
Guilty) and upon any Issue joyned may give this A&bholigct; and the speciall matter in evidence and if the Plaintiffe or
Prosecutor shall become nonsuite or forbeare further Prosecution or suffer a Discontinuance or if a Verdi&bholigct;
passe against him the Defendants shall recover their Treble Costs for which they shall have the like remedy as
in any case where Costs by the Law are given to Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Proviso in respe&bholigct; of a Decree in Chancery as to Lands in Sheriff Hales, in the County of Salop, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p331">Provided alwayes That nothing in this A&bholigct; shall extend or be construed to invalidate a Decree lately made in
the High Court of Chauncery for the quieting of Suites betweene the Countyes of Salop and Stafford and for
the setleing all future Payments to be imposed on certaine Lands in Sheriffe Hales with the County of Salop
and for exempting the said Lands from paying hereafter with the County of Stafford but that the said Decree
shall remaine in such (and noe other) force as it did before the makeing this A&bholigct; Any thing herein to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Receivers General to give Acquittances to Colle&bholigct;ors without Fee.</head>
			<para id="p332">
				<emph type="i">Such Acquittances to be a full Discharge to Colle&bholigct;ors, and also to Place, &amp;c. charged</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p333">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the severall Receivers Generall which shall
be appointed according to this A&bholigct; their Deputy or Deputyes shall from time to time at every payment appointed
thereby give unto the severall Colle&bholigct;ors within their respe&bholigct;ive Precin&bholigct;s upon the payment of the whole summe
due at such times of payment from their respe&bholigct;ive Parishes Constablewicks or places within each of their
Colle&bholigct;ions severall Acquittances under their Hands without takeing any thing for the same, and that in like manner
at every time of payment appointed by this A&bholigct; the Receiver Generall of each County his Deputy or Deputyes shall
give unto the several. Colle&bholigct;ors aforesaid upon the payment of the whole summe or any part thereof due for
their Parish or Place respe&bholigct;ively at each time of Payment aforesaid severall Acquittances under their hands and
seales without takeing any thing for the same which said Acquittance of the Receiver Generall his Deputy or
Deputyes shall be a full and perfe&bholigct; Discharge to the Colle&bholigct;ors. And the said Acquittances of the Receiver
Generall his Deputy or Deputyes shall be a sufficient Discharge to the Colle&bholigct;ors and to such Parish and Place
respe&bholigct;ively and to every person charged within the said Colle&bholigct;ors charge against His Majestie His Heires and
Successors for the summe or summes of money soe acquitted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Remedy for Parish, &amp;c. against Land or Houses void of Distress for which they have paid.</head>
			<para id="p334">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That in case any Lands or Houses in any Parish, Place or
Constablewick shall be unoccupyed and noe Distresses can be found on the same by reason whereof the said
Parish Place or Constablewicke are forced to pay and make good the Taxe assessed upon such Land lyeing
unoccupyed That then it shall and may be lawfull at any time after for the Colle&bholigct;ors Constable or Tythingman
of the said Parish place or Constablewicke for the time being to enter and destraine upon the said Lands or Houses
when there shall be any Distresse thereupon to be found and the Distresse and Distresses being the proper Goods
of the Owner or any claiming any Estate interest or proffitt under him if not redeemed within Fower Dayes by
payment of the Tax and Charge of the Distresse to sell rendering the Overplus to the Owner or Owners of such
Distresse And the said Colle&bholigct;or Constable or Tythingman is hereby enjoyned to distribute the money raised by the
said Distresse or Sale thereof proportionably to the partyes who contributed to the Tax of the said unoccupyed
Lands.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. When Wood Lands assessed and no Distress, Colle&bholigct;ors, Sec. may cut and sell to pay Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p335">
				<emph type="i">Vendee may cut and sell</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p336">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That where any Woodlands shall be assessed and noe Distresse can be
had That in such case it shall and may be lawfull to and for any Colle&bholigct;or Constable Headborough or Tythingman
by Warrant under the Hands and Seales of two or more of the Commissioners of that. Hundred or Division at
seasonable times of the yeare to cutt and sell to any person or persons soe much of the Wood growing on the
Woodlands soe assessed as will pay the Assesment or Assesments to be behinde and unpaid and the Charge incident
therunto and that it shall and may be lawfull for the person and persons and his and their Assignes to whome such
Woods shall be sold to sell cutt downe dispose and carry away the same to his owne use rendering the overplus
(if any be) to the Owner, Any Law to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Where Assessment on Tithes, and other Profits not distrainable, not paid, Colle&bholigct;or, &amp;c. may seize and sell.</head>
			<para id="p337">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That where any Tax or Assesment shall be charged or laid upon any
Tythes Tolls Proffitts of Marketts Faires or Fishery or other annuall proffitts not distrainable in case the same shall
not be paid within Fifteene dayes after such Assesment soe charged or laid and demanded, then it shall and
may be lawfull to and for the Colle&bholigct;or Constable or other Officer thereunto appointed by Warrant under the
hands and seales of any two or more of the Commissioners authorized by this A&bholigct; to seize take and sell soe
much of the said Tythes Tolls and other proffitts soe charged as shall be sufficient for the leavying of the said
Taxe and Assesment and all charges occasioned by such non payment thereof rendering the overplus to the owner
(if any be)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Commissioners for Middlesex and Westminster may; appoint Assessors, who are to ascertain and rate Offices, Townships, &amp;c. chargeable, and to return the same to the Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p338">
<emph type="i">
Such Assessors to deliver in their Surveys signed to Commissioners.; Commissioners at General Meeting, on Perusal of Surveys, are to cast up the true Revenue of the County, &amp;c. and to apportion a Pound Rate</emph>.
</para>
		<para id="p339">And whereas the County of Midlesex and Citty of Westminster are raised in the monethly Assesments by reason
of the new buildings lately ere&bholigct;ed and that Offices are made chargeable towards the payment of such Assesments,
To the end that an equall Rate may be made and imposed upon the severall Divisions Parishes and Hambletts within the said County and Citty Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by this present Parlyament and the authority thereof That the; said
Commissioners appointed for the said County and Citty of Westminster or any three of them shall (if they shall thinke
it fitt) cause two or three of the honest and able Inhabitants in the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Parishes Towneshipps and
places within the said County and Citty to be named and appointed Assessors who (or any two of them) are to ascertaine
and rate the yearely vallue and proffitts of all Offices belonging to the Courts at Westminster and other Offices
chargeable by this A&bholigct; towards the payment of the said summe sett upon the said County and Citty and all Towneshipps
Parishes and Places for which they are appointed Assessors and to returne the same to [y<emph type="p">e</emph>
<ref idref="n61">61</ref>] said Commissioners or to
such person or persons as shall be appointed to receive the same, which said Assessors are to deliver in their severall
Surveyes perfe&bholigct;ed and subscribed by them unto the said Commissioners or unto such person or persons as shall be
appointed by them or any three of them to receive the same two or three dayes at least before the second generall
meeting of the said C&bhooov;missioners to the end that the said C&bhooov;missioners may deliver, in all the severall Surveyes to
be made throughout the said County at the said second generall meeting at which said generall meeting the said
Commissioners or the major part of them then present shall upon view and perusall of the said severall Surveys
cast up the true revenue and yearely proffitts of the whole County Citty and Offices aforesaid to the end that an equall
Pound rate may be apportioned upon every Office chargeable by this A&bholigct; Division Hundred Towneshipp and Parish
according to the proportion and summe of money charged upon the said County and Citty by vertue of this present
A&bholigct; which the said Commissioners or the major part of them then and there assembled are by vertue of this A&bholigct;
authorized and appointed to proportion and make accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. Proviso for Rights of Peers, Clergy, Universities, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p340">Provided alwayes That nothing herein contained shall be drawne into [Exemple<ref idref="n62">62</ref>] to the prejudice of the auntient
Rights belonging to the Lords Spirituall and Temporall or Clergy of this Realme or unto either of the Universityes
or unto any Colledges Schooles Almeshouses Hospitalls or Cinque-ports.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Receivers General making unjust Certificate or Return, or setting insuper;</head>
			<para id="p341">
				<emph type="i">Penalty to the Party.; Penalty to the King.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p342">And for the better preventing of such unjust vexations as might be occasioned by such persons as shall be appointed
Receivers Generall of any of the summes of money granted by this A&bholigct;, And to the intent that the said Receivers
Generall may returne a true accompt into His Majestyes Court of Exchequer of such summes of money as shall be
received by them and every of them their and every of their Deputy and Deputyes Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the
authority aforesaid That if any [such<ref idref="n61">61</ref>] Receiver Generall shall returne or certifie into the said Court any summe or
summes of [money<ref idref="n63">63</ref>] to be in arreare or unpaid after the same have beene received either by such Receiver Generall or
by his Deputy or Deputyes or any of them or shall cause any person or persons to be sett insuper in the said Court
for any summe or summes of money that hath beene soe received that then every [such<ref idref="n61">61</ref>] Receiver Generall shall forfeite
to every person and persons that shall be molested vexed or damaged by reason of such unjust Certificate, returne or
setting insuper treble the dammages that shall be thereby occasioned, the said damages to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion
of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in which noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed nor any
more then one Imparlance and shall alsoe forfeite to His Majestie His Heires and Successors double the summe that
shall be soe unjustly certified or returned or caused to be sett insuper.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. The several Payments to be paid to Receiver General, and by him into the Exchequer, within 20 Days after the times herein mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p343">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the said Five quarterly and Two moneths payments, of
Thirty fower thousand fower hundred and ten pounds nine shillings and six pence halfe penny per mensem amounting
in each quarter of the Five quarters to the summe of One hundred and three thousand two hundred thirty one
pounds eight shillings and seaven pence halfe peny and of the two remaining moneths to the summe of Sixty eight
thousand eight hundred and twenty pounds nineteene shillings and one peny shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid
to the Receiver Generall of the severall Countyes that shall be appointed by times mentioned and expressed in this A&bholigct;
and shall be paid by the said Receivers Generall into His Majestyes Receipt of Exchequer within Twenty dayes after the
said times mentioned and expressed in this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. Money to be appropriated to building, rigging, &amp;c. 30 Ships of War.</head>
			<para id="p344">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That all moneyes colle&bholigct;ed leavyed and paid by vertue of this
A&bholigct; except the allowances therein made to the respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;ors and Receivers Generall and the usuall Fees of the
Officers of the Exchequer shall be applyed and appropriated and are hereby appropriated for the building and for the
Gunns, Rigging and other Furnishing of Thirty Shipps of Warr whereof one to be of the First Rate and to containe
and measure Fowerteene hundred Tunns and not under Nine to be of the Second Rate and to containe and measure
each of them Eleaven hundred Tunns and not under and Twenty of them to be of the Third Rate and to containe and
measure each of them Nine hundred Tunns and not under and to noe other intent use or purpose whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. To be completed within Two Years from 24th June next.</head>
			<para id="p345">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the said Thirty Shipps of Warr hereby dire&bholigct;ed
to be built as aforesaid shall bee and are hereby dire&bholigct;ed to be built and compleated with Gunns Rigging and
other Furniture within the space of two yeares to be accompted from the Fower and twentyeth day of June next
ensueing,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. Colle&bholigct;ors of Parishes, &amp;c. keeping Monies colle&bholigct;ed in their Hands unduly, or unduly paying away the same; Penalty &pound;5.</head>
			<para id="p346">
<emph type="i">Receiver General or Deputy unduly paying Monies received under this A&bholigct;, &amp;c.; Penalty &pound;500</emph>.
			</para>
			<para id="p347">And for the more effe&bholigct;uall; doeing thereof and that the said moneyes hereby given may be applyed to the uses
aforesaid Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and it is ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any Colle&bholigct;or of any Parish or
place shall keepe in his hands, any part of the money by him colle&bholigct;ed for any longer time then is by this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ed
(other then the allowance made unto him by this A&bholigct;) or shall pay any part thereof to any person or persons other
then the Receiver Generall of such County or place or his Deputy that every such Colle&bholigct;or shall forfeite for every
such Offence the summe of Five pounds And in case any Receiver Generall or his Deputy shall pay any part of the moneyes paid to him or them by any Colle&bholigct;or by vertue of this A&bholigct; to any person or persons whatsoever other
then the Receipt of His Majestyes Exchequer and that at or within the respe&bholigct;ive times limitted within this A&bholigct; or
in case such Receiver Generall shall pay any part of the said moneyes by any Warrant of the Lord Treasurer Under
Treasurer or either of them or Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being or by any Tally of Pro or Tally
of Anticipation or other way or device whatsoever whereby to divert or hinder the a&bholigct;uall payment thereof into the
Receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid that such Receiver Generall shall for every such Offence of himselfe or his
Deputy forfeite the summe of Five hundred pounds to him or them that shall sue for the same in any Court of
Record by Bill Plaint or other Information wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager in Law is to be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. No Warrant for Payment of Monies to be dire&bholigct;ed to any Person other than into Receipt of Exchequer, nor for striking of any Tally of Pro or Anticipation. Teller not to throw down any Bill, &amp;c. till he shall have received Monies.</head>
			<para id="p348">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer and
Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being or any of them doe not dire&bholigct; any Warrant to any of the said
Colle&bholigct;ors or Receivers Generall or their Deputyes for the payment of any part of these moneyes to any person or
persons other then into the Receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid nor shall they or any of them dire&bholigct; any Warrant
to the Officers of the Exchequer for the strikeing of any Tally of Pro or Tally of Anticipation nor doe any other
matter or thing whereby to divert the a&bholigct;uall payment of the said moneyes into the Receipt of the Exchequer nor
shall the Officers of the Exchequer strike or dire&bholigct; or record the strikeing of any Tally of Pro or Tally of Anticipation
upon any of the said moneys upon any accompt or Warrant whatsoever nor shall the Teller throw downe a Bill
whereby to charge himselfe with any of the said moneys untill he shall have a&bholigct;ually received the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. Officers of Exchequer to keep distin&bholigct; Accounts;</head>
			<para id="p349">
				<emph type="i">and Treasurer, &amp;c. not to sign Warrants, &amp;c. other than to Treasurer of the Navy, &amp;c.; Auditor not to draw Order for issuing to any other than Treasurer of the Navy, &amp;c.; Clerk of the Pells or Teller not to make Payment otherwise than as mentioned in Warrant</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p350">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the Officers of the Receipt of His Majestyes
Exchequer shall keepe all the moneys which shall be paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer by vertue of this A&bholigct;
and the Account thereof distin&bholigct; from all other moneyes and Accounts whatsoever and shall keepe a perticular Account
of the charge of the Building Gunns Rigging and other Furnishing of each of the said Thirty Shipps of Warr hereby
dire&bholigct;ed to bee built as aforesaid And that the Lord Treasurer Under Treasurer or either of them or Commissioners
of the Treasury for the time being doe not signe any Warrant or Order or doe any other matter or thing for the
issueing of any of the said moneys to any person or persons other then the Treasurer of the Navy Treasurer or
Paymaster of the Ordnance for the time being and expressing therein that the same is for the Building or for the Gunns
Rigging or other Furnishing of the Thirty Shipps of Warr above mentioned, nor shall the Auditor of the Receipt
draw any Order for the issueing of any part of the said moneys to any person or persons other then the Treasurer
of the Navy Treasurer or Paymaster of the Ordnance as aforesaid nor shall he dire&bholigct; or the Clerke of the Pells record
or the Teller make payment of any of the said moneys by vertue of any Warrant or upon any Order or other way
or device whatsoever other then to the persons and to the uses aforesaid and to be soe mentioned and expressed in
such Warrant and Order</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. Orders for money to be entered, &amp;c. according to Dates.</head>
			<para id="p351">
And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That all Orders for issueing any of the said moneys shall
be entred in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt in course according to their respe&bholigct;ive dates and be paid
accordingly and not otherwise and that the moneys to come in by this A&bholigct; shall be in the same order lyable to the
payment of the said Orders without preference of the one before the other and not otherwise.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p352">
				<emph type="i">Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded no undue Preference if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Orders</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p353">Provided alwayes and it is hereby declared That if it shall happen that severall Orders for payment of the said
moneyes beare date the same day that then such of them shall be first entred and preferred in payment which shall be
first delivered into the said Office of the Auditor of the Receipt and it shall not be interpretted any undue preference to
incurr any penalty in point of payment if the Auditor dire&bholigct; and the Clerke of the Pells record and the Tellers doe pay
subsequent Orders of persons that come to demand their money and bring their Orders before such as did not come
to demand their money and bring their Orders in their course soe as there be soe much money reserved as will satisfie
their Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. Orders for Payment of Money lent may be assigned by Indorsement.</head>
			<para id="p354">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee.; Assignee may in like manner assign</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p355">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the Treasurer of the Navy and the Treasurer or Paymaster
of the Ordnance respe&bholigct;ively may assigne and transferr any part of the said moneys due and payable unto them upon
any Order by Indorsment upon such Order which being notified and an Entry and memoriall thereof alsoe made in
the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt (which on request he shall accordingly make without Fee or Charge) shall
intitle such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the benefitt of such Order or Orders or any part
thereof and payment thereon and such Assignee may in like manner assigne againe and soe toties quoties and
afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person or persons who have made such Assignments to make void
release or discharge the same or the moneys thereby due or any part thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>XLIII. Treasurer of Navy to keep such Monies diftin&bholigct;, and issue and pay the same by Warrant of Principal Officers, &amp;c. of the Navy.</head>
			<para id="p356">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That the Treasurer of the Navy Treasurer or Paymaster
of the Ordnance for the time being shall keepe all moneys paid to them respe&bholigct;ively by vertue of this A&bholigct; distin&bholigct; and
apart from all other moneyes and issue and pay the same by Warrant of the Principall Officers and Commissioners of
the Navy and Principall Officers of the Ordnance respe&bholigct;ively or any three or more of them and mentioning and
expressing that it is for the Building for the Gunns Rigging or other Furnishing of the Thirty Shipps of Warr as
aforesaid and to noe other intent use or purpose whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>XLIV. Commissioners, &amp;c. of the Navy not to sign Warrant for any other Purpose than as Money is appropriated, and the Uses to be expressed in such Warrant.</head>
			<para id="p357">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid that the principall Officers and Commissioners of
the Navy and principall Officers of the Ordnance respe&bholigct;ively or any three or more of them shall not signe any
Warrant or Navy Bill or doe any other A&bholigct; or thing for the issueing and paying any of the said moneys to
any use intent or purpose whatsoever other then for the building or for the Gunns Rigging or other Furnishing
of the Thirty Shipps of Warr as aforesaid and to be soe mentioned and expressed in such Warrant or Navy Bill,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>XLV. Auditor of Receipt and Treasurer of Navy and Ordnance to render an Account to the Commons of Monies raised under this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p358">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That the Auditor of the Receipt of the Exchequer
for the time being shall transmitt to the Commons in Parlyament assembled an Account of all moneys which
shall be paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer by vertue of this A&bholigct; and to whome the same are issued and
paid and by whose Warrant and for what uses and that the Treasurer or Treasurers of the Navy Treasurer or
Treasurers Paymaster or Paymasters of the Ordnance to whome any part of these moneys shall be issued and
paid shall in like manner give an account to the Commons in Parlyament assembled of soe much of the said
moneys as shall be by them and every of them respe&bholigct;ively received and to whome the same are issued and paid
by them respe&bholigct;ively and by whose Warrant and for what uses</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>XLVI. Officers appointed to receive misapplying Monies;</head>
			<para id="p359">
				<emph type="i">Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p360">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any of the Officers aforesaid which are appointed
by this A&bholigct; to receive the moneys hereby granted shall after Receipt of the said money divert or misapply the
same or any part thereof by vertue of any Warrant from the Lord Treasurer for the time being or other Superior
Officer contrary to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct; that then such Officer or Officers soe diverting or
misapplying the said money shall forfeite the like summe soe diverted or misapplyed which said forfeiture shall
be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster
wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed the one moyety of which forfeiture soe to
be recovered shall be to the Informer or him that shall sue for the same and the other moyety thereof to be
distributed to the poore of the Parish where such Offence shall be committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>XLVII. The like Offence by any Officer of the Exchequer, Navy or Ordnance; Penalty.</head>
			<para id="p361">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any Officer or Officers mentioned in this A&bholigct; of
or belonging to the Exchequer Navy or Ordnance shall willingly and wilfully offend against this Law or any
Clause thereof by diverting or misapplying any moneys whatsoever contrary to the true intent and meaning of
this A&bholigct; that for any and every such offence such Officer and Officers soe offending shall forfeite his Office and
is and are hereby disabled and made incapeable to hold or execute the said Office or any other Office whatsoever
for the future.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>XLVIII. No Stay of Prosecution admitted in any Suit for Recovery of Penalties.</head>
			<para id="p362">Provided alsoe and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That noe stay of Prosecution upon any Command Warrant Motion Order
or Dire&bholigct;ion by Non vult ulterius prosequi shall be had made admitted received or allowed by any Court whatsoever
in any Suite or Proceeding by A&bholigct;ion of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Information or otherwise for the Recovery of all
or any of the Paines Forfeitures or Penalties upon any person or persons by this A&bholigct; infli&bholigct;ed or therein mentioned
or for or in order to the convi&bholigct;ion or disability of any person offending against this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>XLIX. Commissioners not liable to Penalties of 25. Car. II. c. 2.</head>
			<para id="p363">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That noe Commissioner or Commissioners or any other
Officer that shall be imployed in the execution of this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall be lyable for or
by reason of their a&bholigct;ing or proceeding as Commissioners by vertue of this A&bholigct; to any of the penalties mentioned
in an A&bholigct; Entituled An A&bholigct; for preventing dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants for not takeing
the Oathes or Declaration in the said A&bholigct; expressed in case such Commissioner or Commissioners Officer or
Officers have before that time taken the said Oathes and subscribed the Declaration in the recited A&bholigct; mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s50">
			<head>L. How &pound;400 per Month, Part of the &pound;1,520. 5s. per Month on Middlesex and Westminster, to be assessed.</head>
			<para id="p364">
				<emph type="i">How &pound;1,120. 5s. the Residue to be assessed</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p365">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That the summe of Foure hundred Pounds per mensem being part of the
summe of Fifteene hundred and twenty pounds and five shillings to be assessed by vertue of this A&bholigct; on the
County of Midlesex with the Citty and Liberty of Westminster for every Moneth of the said Seaventeene Monethes
Assesment shall be assessed and taxed on the said Citty and Liberty of Westminster and the Out-Parishes within
the weekely Bills of Mortality in the said County and on the Offices and Officers hereby taxable belonging to
the Courts at Westminster and other the Offices and Officers in the said County or Citty and the Liberties thereof
which were not heretofore taxed and that the summe of Eleaven hundred and twenty pounds and five shillings
being the residue of the said Monethly Assesment shall be assessed and taxed on the said County and the Citty
and Liberties of Westminster according to the same proportions and distributions in respe&bholigct; to this present Assesment
as they were assessed and taxed by the late A&bholigct; for granting a Royall Aide to His Majestie.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s51">
			<head>LI. Receiver General or Deputy not to a&bholigct; as Commissioners for County or Place for which he is appointed.</head>
			<para id="p366">Provided alwayes and it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed That noe Receiver Generall or his Deputy who shall be soe appointed
according to this A&bholigct; shall a&bholigct; or have power to a&bholigct; as a Commissioner for any County or place where he shall
be soe appointed a Receiver or Deputy Receiver Any thing herein to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">The Record torn, "and" in Original.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">The Record torn, "Shillings" in Original.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">r<emph type="p">r</emph>	Phillip Egerton<emph type="p">r</emph>
James Bradshawe Knights Ralph Whitley Kenrick Eyton <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">Wilford <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">Incledon <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">Gollop <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Henry Stapleton Arthur Ingram <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">Gowyer <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">they <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">Roger James Francis Bradbury <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">Machen <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">Bodeler <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">Lomax <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">Henry <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">Norres <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">Skeffington <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">Henry <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">S<emph type="p">r</emph>
							<emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">S<emph type="p">r</emph>
John Talbott S<emph type="p">r</emph>William Doyley junior <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">Jones <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">Lane <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">Packhurst <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">Senior <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">Douglasse <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">No blank in Orig.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">Warden <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">Batchelor <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">Edward Noel Henry <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">Somersett <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39">Floyd <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">Esquire <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41">Henry <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n42" number="42">Yeamans <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n43" number="43">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n44" number="44">Cordell <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n45" number="45">Sigismond <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n46" number="46">Esquires <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n47" number="47">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n48" number="48">Trayson <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n49" number="49">senior <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n50" number="50">Edward <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n51" number="51">Nash <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n52" number="52">Tuffren <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n53" number="53">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n54" number="54">John <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n55" number="55">Dawkins <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n56" number="56">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n57" number="57">Frederick <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n58" number="58">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n59" number="59">or more <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n60" number="60">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n61" number="61">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n62" number="62">Example <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n63" number="63">Monyes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
</report>


