<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47467" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter VII. An Act for the better Observation of the Lords day commonly called Sunday.[Rot. Parl. 29 C. II. p. 2. nu.6.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Tradesmen, &amp;c. working on Sunday,; Exception.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Penalty 5s.; exposing to sale Wares, &amp;c.; Penalty.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">For the better observation and keeping holy the Lords day commonly called Sunday Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the
Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and
of the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the authoritie of the same. That all the Lawes
ena&bholigct;ed and in force concerning the observation of the Lords day and repaireing to the Church thereon be carefully
putt in execution. And that all and every person and persons whatsoever shall on every Lords day apply
themselves to the observation of the same by exerciseing themselves thereon in the dutyes of Piety and true
Religion publiquely and privately And that noe Tradesman, Artificer Workeman Labourer or other Person whatsoever
shall doe or exercise any worldly Labour, Busines or Worke of their ordinary Callings upon, the Lords day or any.
part thereof (Workes of Necessity and Charity onely excepted) And that every person being of, the age of fourteene yeares
or upwards offending in the Premisses shall for every such Offence foreit the, summe of, five shillings, And that noe
person or persons whatsoever shall publickly cry shew forth; or expose to sale any Wares Merchandizes, Fruit,
Herbs Goods or Chattells whatsoever upon the Lords day or any part thereof upon paine that every person soe
offending shall forfeite the same Goods soe cryed or shewed, forth or exposed, to sale.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Drovers, &amp;c. travelling, &amp;c. Penalty 20B.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Using Boats, Barges, &amp;c.; Penalty 5s.; Proceedings on Convi&bholigct;ion.; Goods cryed may be seized.; Penalties how to be levied.; In case of Insufficiency, Stocks.; Penalties how to be disposed of.; Reward to Informer.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed That noe Drover Horsecourser Waggoner Butcher Higler their or any of their Servants
shall travell or come into his or their Inne or Lodgeing upon the Lords day or any part thereof upon paine that
each and every such offender shall forfeite twenty shillings for every such offence, And that noe person or persons
shall use imploy or travell upon the Lords day with any Boate Wherry Lighter or Barge except it be upon
extraordinary occasion to be allowed by some Justice of the Peace of the County or Head officer or some Justice
of the Peace of the Citty Burrough or Towne corporate where the Fa&bholigct; shall be committed upon paine that every
person soe offending shall forfeite and lose the summe of five shillings for every such offence, And that if any
person offending in any of the premisses shall be thereof convi&bholigct;ed before any Justice of the Peace of the County
or the Cheife Officer or Officers or any Justice of the Peace of or within any Citty Burrough or Towne Corporate
where the said Offences shall be committed upon his or their view or confession of the party or proofe of any
one or more Witnesses by Oath (which the said Justices Cheife Officer or Officers is by this A&bholigct; authorized to
administer) the said Justice or Cheife Officer or Officers shall give Warrant under his or their Hand and Seale to
the Constables or Churchwardens of the Parish or Parishes where such Offence shall be committed to seize the
said Goods, cryed, shewed forth or putt to sale as aforesaid and to sell the same and to levy the said other
Forfeitures or Penaltyes by way of distresse and sale of the Goods of every such Offender distrained rendering to
the said Offenders the overplus of the moneys raised thereby and in default of such distresse or in case of
insufficiency or inability of the said Offender to pay the said forfeitures or penalties that then the party offending
be sett publickly in the Stocks by the space of two houres, And all and singular the forfeitures or penaltyes
aforesaid shall be imployed and converted to the use of the Poore of the Parish where the said [Offence<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] shall be
committed saveing onely that it shall and may be lawfull to and for any such Justice Maior or Head Officer or
Officers out of the said forfeitures or penalties to reward any person or persons that shall informe of any
Offence against this A&bholigct; according to their discretions soe as such Reward, exceede not the third part of the
Forfeitures or penalties.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Proviso for private Families, Inns, &amp;c. and for crying Milk.</head>
			<para id="p5">Provided That nothing in this A&bholigct; contained shall extend to the prohibiting of dressing of Meate, in Families
or dressing or selling of Meat in Inns Cookeshops or Vi&bholigct;ualling Houses for such as otherwise cannot be,
provided nor to the crying or selling of Milke before nine of the clocke in the morning or. after foure of the
clocke in the afternoone.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Limitation of Prosecution.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided alsoe that noe person or persons shall be impeached prosecuted or molested for any offence
before mentioned in this A&bholigct; unlesse he or they be prosecuted for the same within ten dayes after the offence
committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Hundred not responsible for Robberies committed on the Lords Day; But shall make fresh Suit after the Offenders. 27 Eliz. c. 13.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">Provided and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authoritie aforesaid That if any person or persons whatsoever which
shall travell upon the Lords Day shall be then robbed That noe Hundred nor the Inhabitants thereof shall be
charged with or answerable for any Robbery soe committed but the person or persons soe robbed shall be barred
from bringing any A&bholigct;ion for the said Robbery, Any Law to the contrary, notwithstanding. Neverthelesse the
Inhabitants of the Countyes and Hundreds (after notice of any such Robbery to them or some of them given, or
after Huy and Cry for the same to be brought) shall make or cause to be, made, fresh Suite and Pursuite, after
the Offenders with Horsemen and Footemen according to the Statute made in the twenty seventh, yeare of the
Raigne of Queene Elizabeth upon paine of forfeiting to the Kings Majestie his Heires and Successors as much money
as might have beene recovered against the Hundred by the partie robbed if this Law had not beene made.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Service of Process on the Lord's Day (Exception) void.</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">Persons serving the same liable to Action</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">Provided alsoe That noe person or persons upon the Lords Day shall serve or execute or cause to be served
or executed any Writt, Processe, Warrant, Order Judgement or Decree (except in cases of Treason Felony or breach
of the Peace) but that the service of every such Writt, Processe, Warrant, Order Judgement or Decree shall be void
to all intents and Purposes whatsoever And the person or persons soe serveing or executeing the same shall be as
lyable to the Suite of the Partie grieved and to answere damages to him for doeing thereof as if he or they had
done the same without any Writt, Processe Warrant Order Judgement or Decree at all.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">Offences <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


