<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47475" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677 &amp; 1678</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter III. An A&bholigct; for burying in Woollen.[Rot. Parl. 30 C. II. p. 1. nu. 3.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 18 (18 &amp; 19) C. II. c.4.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">and that the same was inadequate to the Purposes thereof.; The said A&bholigct; repealed</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an A&bholigct; made in the Eighteenth yeare of His Majestyes Raigne that now is entituled An A&bholigct;
for burying in Woollen onely was intended for the lessening the Importation of Linnen from beyond the
Seas and the Encouragement of the Wollen and Paper Manufa&bholigct;ures of this Kingdome had the same beene
observed but in respe&bholigct; there was not a sufficient Remedy thereby given for the discovery and prosecution of
offences against the said Law the same hath hitherto not had the effe&bholigct; thereby intended For remedy whereof
Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authoritie of the same That the
said, A&bholigct; and all the Clauses and Provisoes therein shall be and are hereby annulled and repealed to all intents
constru&bholigct;ions and purposes whatsoever</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Burying in any other than Woollen;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That from and after the First day of August One thousand
six hundred and seaventy eight noe Corps of any person or persons shall be buryed in any Shirt Shift Sheete
or Shroud or any thing whatsoever made or mingled with Flax Hempe Silke Haire Gold or Silver or in any Stuffe
or thing other then what is made of Sheeps Wooll onely or be putt into any Coffin lined or faced with any sort
of Cloath or Stuffe or any other thing whatsoever that is made of any Materiall but Sheeps Wooll onely upon
paine of the Forfeiture of Five pounds of lawfull Money of England to be recovered and divided as is hereafter
in this A&bholigct; expressed and dire&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Persons in Holy Orders, &amp;c. to keep a Register of Burials.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Affidavit that the deceased was buried in Woollen only to be brought to the Parsons.; If no such Affidavit, Goods of the deceased liable to the said Penalty.; If no Distress Goods of Person where Party died, or of Persons a&bholigct;ing contrary to this A&bholigct;, liable to Distress.; Master, &amp;c. or Relations of deceased liable.; Penalty to be paid before Debts</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p6">And it is ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all persons in Holy Orders Deanes Parsons Deacons Vicars
Curates and their or any of their Substitutes doe within their respe&bholigct;ive Parishes Precin&bholigct;s and Places take an
exa&bholigct; Account and keepe a Register of all and every person or persons buryed in his or their respective Parishes
or Precin&bholigct;s or in such common Buryall places as their respe&bholigct;ive Parishioners are usually buryed and that some
one or more of the Relations of the party deceased or other credible person shall within eight dayes next after
such Interrment bring an Affidavit in writeing under the hands and seales of two or more credible Wittnesses
(and under the hand of the Magistrate or Officer before whome the same was sworne for which nothing shall
be paid) to the Minister or Parson That the said person was not putt in wrapt or wound up or buryed in any
Shirt Shift Sheete or Shround made or mingled with Flax Hempe Silke Haire Gold or Silver or other then what
is made of Sheeps Wooll onely or in any Coffin lined or faced with any Cloath Stuffe or any other thing whatsoever
made or mingled with Flax Hempe Silke Haire Gold or Silver or any other Materiall but Sheeps Wooll onely
And if noe Relation of the party buryed or other person shall bring an Affidavit as aforesaid to the Parson or
Minister within the time aforesaid That then the Goods and Chattels of the party deceased shall be and are hereby
made lyable to the aforesaid Forfeiture of Five pounds to be levyed by way of Distresse and Sale thereof by
Warrant of the Cheife Magistrate in any Towne Corporate or any Justice of the Peace or in default thereof
by like Distresse and Sale of the Goods of the person in whose House the said partie dyed or of any that had a
hand in putting such person into any Shirt Shift Sheete Shround or Coffin contrary to this A&bholigct; or did order or
dispose the doeing thereof and in case such person were a Servant and that he or she dyed in the Family of
his or her Master or Mistresse That the same be levyed on the Goods or Chattells of his or her Master or
Mistrisse and if such person dyed in the Family of his or her Father or Mother That then the same be levyed
upon the Goods and Chattells of his or her Father or Mother in Manner and by Warrant as aforesaid which
said Forfeiture or Forfeitures shall be levyed paid and allowed out of the Estate of the said deceased person
before any Statute Judgement Debt Legacy or any other Duty whatsoever due oweing or payable from the
said Deceased.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Before whom Affidavit to be made.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">No Fee.; If no Affidavit, then Parson to give Notice thereof to Churchwardens; Proceedings thereon.; Forfeitures how disposed of</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p8">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed That the said Affidavit shall be made or taken before some one Justice of the
Peace or Master of Chauncery ordinary or extraordinary Maior Bayliffe or other Cheife Officer of the City County
Burrough Corporation or Market Towne in the County where the said partie was buryed who are hereby authorized
and required to administer the said Oath and to attest the same under their hands upon such Affidavit Gratis
And in case noe such Affidavit shall be brought to the Parson or Minister where the said Partie was buryed as
aforesaid within the said Eight dayes That such Parson or Minister shall forthwith give or cause notice thereof to
be given in writeing under his hand to the Churchwarden or Overseers of the Poore of such Parish who shall
within Eight dayes after such notice repaire to the Cheife Magistrate in any Towne Corporate if such party was buryed
in such City or Towne Corporate or else to any Justice of the Peace who upon the Certificate thereof from the
said Parson Minister or Curate officiating in the said Parish shall forthwith grant a Warrant for the levying of
the said Forfeiture on the Goods and Chattells of the Partyes before mentioned rendering the overplus to the partyes
whose Goods were soe distrained upon all reasonable Charges being dedu&bholigct;ed one moyety of which Forfeitures shall
be to the use and benefitt of the Poore of the Parish where such Party shall be buryed contrary to the dire&bholigct;ions
of this A&bholigct; and the other moyety thereof to the use of the person that shall informe and sue for the same to be
recovered by Warrant of the Cheife Magistrate or any Justice of the Peace in the City Towne Corporate or
County where such party was buryed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Parson negle&bholigct;ing to give Notice to Churchwardens of Affidavit not brought;</head>
			<para id="p9">
				<emph type="i">or Churchwardens not a&bholigct;ing thereupon; or Justice negle&bholigct;ing his Duty; Penalty &pound;5; Prosecutor to have his Costs. Limitation of A&bholigct;ions</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p10">And in case any parson or minister shall negle&bholigct; to give notice to the Churchwardens or Overseers of the
Poore as aforesaid or not give unto them a Note or Certificate under his hand testifying that such an Affidavit and
Certificate was not brought to him within the time limitted by this A&bholigct; concerning the partyes being interested
according to the dire&bholigct;ions thereof or that the Churchwardens or Overseers of the Poore shall not within Eight
dayes after the Receipt of such Certificate repaire to such Cheife Magistrate or to some other Justice of the Peace
with such Certificate and shew the same to him and demand his Warrant thereupon for levying the Forfeiture by
this A&bholigct; before appointed and in case such Cheife Magistrate or Justice of the Peace shall negle&bholigct; his Duty in
not issueing his Warrant for the levying the said Forfeiture he or they soe negle&bholigct;ing or offending shall forfeite
for every such offence the Summe of Five pounds of lawfull Money of England to be recovered by such person
as shall sue for the same by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information wherein noe Essoigne Wager of Law or
Prote&bholigct;ion shall be allowed and wherein alsoe the Prosecutor shall recover his full Costs soe as the Suite be
commenced within Six monthes after the offence shall be committed One fowerth Part of which said Forfeitures shall
be to the use of His Majestie His Heirs and Successors Two other fourth parts thereof shall be to the use of
the Poore of the Parish where the person soe offending or negle&bholigct;ing his Duty shall dwell And one other fourth
part to the person that shall informe and sue for the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Parson to keep a Register at the Charge of the Parish, and make Entry of Burials and Affidavits.</head>
			<para id="p11">
				<emph type="i">Memorial of Affidavit not brought</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p12">And it is hereby, further ena&bholigct;ed That the Parson or Minister of every Parish shall keepe a Register in a
Booke to be provided at the charge of the Parish and make a true Entry of all Buryalls within his Parish
and of all Affidavits brought to him as aforesaid within the time limitted as aforesaid And where noe such
Affidavit shall be brought to him within such time that he enter a Memoriall thereof in the said Registry against
the Name of the Party interred and of the time when he notified the same to the Churchwardens or Overseers
of the Poore</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. What First Account given by Overseers is to contain.</head>
			<para id="p13">
				<emph type="i">What future Accounts are to contain; No Accounts allowed without containing Account of Burials</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p14">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That [in the [firt<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] Account to be given in by any
Overseers of the Poore after the First day of August One thousand six hundred seaventy eight they doe and
shall give an Account as by this A&bholigct; is hereafter dire&bholigct;ed of all Buryalls within their [Parish<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] from the said First
day of August One thousand six hundred seaventy eight to the time of the giveing in the said Account and that
for the future<ref idref="n3">3</ref>] when and as often as the Overseers of the Poore doe give up their Accounts to the Justices of
the Peace at the Quarter Sessions or Petty Sessions or any two Justices of the Peace in their Monethly Meetings
that they doe and shall give an Account of the Name and Quality of every person interred within their Parish
from the time of their former Account and of such Certificates as came to their hands from the Parson or
Minister of the said Parish that the persons therein mentioned were interred contrary to the dire&bholigct;ions and true
intent of this A&bholigct; and of their levying the Penalty on the Offenders according to this A&bholigct; and alsoe a true
Account of the disposall of the same under the Penalty of Five pounds to be levyed by Distresse and Sale of
the Goods of such Churchwardens [and<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] Overseers by Warrant from the said Justices of the Peace or any two of
them [And that noe Account of any Overseers of the Poore shall be allowed after the first day of August One
thousand six hundred seaventy eight untill they shall therein account for the Burialls within the respe&bholigct;ive Parishes
as is before dire&bholigct;ed<ref idref="n3">3</ref>]</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. Proviso for dying of the Plague.</head>
			<para id="p15">Provided That noe Penalty appointed by this A&bholigct; shall be incurred for or by reason of any person that shall
dye of the Plague although such persons shall not be buryed as by this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Judges, &amp;c. to give A&bholigct; in charge;</head>
			<para id="p16">
				<emph type="i">and to be publicly read yearly for Seven Years</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p17">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That from and after the said First day of August the said
Judges at their respe&bholigct;ive Assizes and the Justices of the Peace at their respe&bholigct;ive Quarter Sessions shall give
this A&bholigct; in charge And moreover that this A&bholigct; shall be publiquely read upon the first Sunday after the Feast
of Saint Bartholimew every yeare for seaven yeares next following presently after Divine Service</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. In A&bholigct;ions for executing A&bholigct;, General Issue.</head>
			<para id="p18">
				<emph type="i">Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p19">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion Bill Plaint Suite or Information shall
be commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or execution
of this A&bholigct; such person or persons soe sued shall and may pleade the Generall Issue Not guilty and upon Issue
joyned may give this A&bholigct; in evidence And if the Plaintiffe or Prosecutor shall become Non suite or suffer Discontinuance
or if a Verdi&bholigct; passe against him or if upon a Demurrer Judgement passe against him the Defendant shall recover
his Treble Costs for such molestation.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">first <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Parishes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">annexed to the Original A&bholigct; in a separate Schedule.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


