<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47472" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677 &amp; 1678</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter II. An Act for continuance of two former A&bholigct;s for preventing of Theft and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders
of England. [Rot. Parl. 29 &amp; 30 C.II. nu. 2.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Recital of 14 (13 &amp; 14) C.II. c, 22. 18 (18 &amp; 19) C. II. c.3. and that they are expired.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">The said Two A&bholigct;s continued for Seven Years, &amp;c.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas an A&bholigct; was made in the Fowerteenth yeare of the Raigne of our Soveraigne Lord the King
that now is Entituled An A&bholigct; for preventing of Theft and Rapine upon the Northerne Borders of England
And whereas alsoe another A&bholigct; was made in the Eighteenth yeare of the Raigne of our said Soveraigne Lord
the King Entituled An A&bholigct; to continue a former A&bholigct; for preventing of Theft and Rapine upon the Northerne
Borders of England Both which A&bholigct;s are expired and have beene found very necessary for the preservation of
those Places from that great number of lewed disorderly and lawlesse persons that usually frequented thereabouts
Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords
Spirituall and Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by Authoritie thereof That the
said two, former A&bholigct;s and either of them and every Matter Clause and Clauses therein contained and all and
every the Powers and Authorities thereby given shall be continue and remaine in full force from henceforth for and
and dureing the space and time of Seaven yeares and alsoe from thence untill the end of the first Session of the
next Parlyament.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Quarter Sessions of the said Counties to take Security of Persons employed in the Border Service for the Preservation of the said Counties.</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Stolen Goods to be entered in Books to be kept in Market Towns within, 48 Hours after the same are stolen.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And for the better management of the Powers and Authorityes in or by the said two former A&bholigct;s given Bee
it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the said severall Justices of the Peace of the said respe&bholigct;ive
Countyes shall from time to time at the respe&bholigct;ive Quarter Sessions take good and sufficient Security of the person
or persons by them imployed in the said Service for the preservation of the said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes from Theft
and Rapine to answere the Dammages sustained by any person or persons by his or their negle&bholigct; or default
therein and to pay and satisfie the same within Fower months after that proofe thereof shall be made by the
Oath of one or more credible Witnesses before the Justices of the Peace of the said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes at the
next Quarter Sessions in the respe&bholigct;ive County which Oath or Oathes the said Justice or Justices are hereby
authorized to administer soe as the Goods stolne be entred in one of the Bookes to be kept for that purpose
within the space of forty eight houres after the same shall be stoln or gone and that Bookes shall be kept for
that end in every Market Towne of the said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes and at such other convenient places therein and
by such person or persons as the said Justices of the Peace in the said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes at their Generall
Sessions of the Peace shall order or appoint.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Quarter Sessions, yearly or every Two Years, in open Court, to appoint Persons for the said Service.</head>
			<para id="p5">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the said severall Justices of the Peace of the said
respe&bholigct;ive Countyes at the Generall Quarter Sessions of the Peace for the said Countyes respe&bholigct;ively shall yearely
or every two yeares at the farthest in open Court make choice of and appoint such person or persons as they
shall respe&bholigct;ively thinke fitt for the said Countyes respe&bholigct;ively to be employed in the said Service.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Persons so employed to receive the Sacrament
and deliver a Certificate to the next Quarter Sessions, and take the Oaths of Allegiance and Supremacy, and subscribe the Declaration of 25 C.II. c. 2. s.8.</head>
			<para id="p6">Provided That every person and persons employed for the preservation of the said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes from
Theft and Rapine or as Treasurer for the said Service doe receive the Sacrament of the Lords Supper according
to the Usage of the Church of England in some Publicke Church upon some Lords day commonly called Sunday
within the space of three moneths after they shall enter upon such Employment and deliver a Certificate thereof
to the next Quarter Sessions in the respe&bholigct;ive County where they shall be soe imployed and take the Oathes of
Allegiance and Supremacy and make and subscribe the Declaration appointed to be made and subscribed in and by
one A&bholigct; of this present Parlyament Entituled An A&bholigct; for preventing dangers which may happen from Popish
Recusants under the Penaltyes and Forfeitures by the said A&bholigct; appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>Item quaeda[m] Petitiones privatas personas concernentes (in se forma A&bholigct;us continentes) exhibita fuerunt &bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o Domino
Regi in Parliamento predi&bholigct;o quoru[m] Tituli subscribuntur (videlicet)</head>
			<para id="p7">3. An Act for the ascertaining and establishing of the Interest of the Lord and Copyhold Tenants of the Mannours
of West Derby and Wavertree in the County Palatine of Lancaster in relation to their Fines and Commons.</para>
			<para id="p8">4. An Act to enable the Guardian of the Right Honourable Edward Earle of Warwicke and Holland to make
Leases of several Messuages herein after mentioned dureing his Minority rendering the improved Rent.</para>
			<para id="p9">5. An Act to enable the Right Honourable Thomas Lord Morley and Mounteagle Baron of Rye to make Sale
of the Mannour of Farlton and certaine Lands and Hereditaments in Farlton in the County of Lancaster for payment
of Debts.</para>
			<para id="p10">6. An Act to enable the Trustees of Bryan Viscount. Cullen of the Realme of Ireland to sell or dispose
of Lands in Elmesthorp in the County of Leicester for the payment of Debts and raiseing a Portion for his
Daughter.</para>
			<para id="p11">7. An Act to enable Trustees to raise Money upon Cobham House and Parke.</para>
			<para id="p12">8. An Act to enable Sir John Cotton Baronet to dispose of a Messuage called St Jermans and Lands therewith
used neere St Albans in the County of Hertford and to setle other Lands in lieu thereof.</para>
			<para id="p13">9. An Act for Confirmation of a Decree made in the Court of Chauncery the fower and twentyeth day of
February Anno Regni Regis Caroli Secundi Vicesimo septimo in a Cause betweene Sir Francis Rodes Baronet
since deceased and Dame Martha his Wife Plaintiffes and William Thornton and Infant by Ciprian Thornton his
Guardian and John Thornton and the said Ciprian Thornton Defendants and of severall Conveyances and Assurances
made by the said Sir Francis Rodes in pursuance thereof as well for payment of his Debts as for provision for
his Wife and Children.</para>
			<para id="p14">10. An Act to supply the defe&bholigct;s in a Deed of Setlement made by John Coke Esquire deceased and for
altering a Trust in part of the Estate of Robert Coke Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p15">11. An Act to enable Thomas Thynne of Longleat in the County of Wilts Esquire to setle a Joynture on a
Wife of certaine Lands Tenements and Hereditaments therein mentioned.</para>
			<para id="p16">12. An Act for dischargeing the Mannour of Winsteed in the County of Yorke from a Setlement in Taile
and chargeing other Mannours and Lands in the County of Lincolne of a greater value with the same uses.</para>
			<para id="p17">13. An Act for the setleing certaine Lands belonging to William Gery of Bushmeade in the County of Bedford
Esquire upon Trustees to be sold for the payment of Debts.</para>
			<para id="p18">14. An Act for the vesting of certaine Mannours and Lands of Edward Bedell of Woodriseing in the County
of Norffolke Esquire in certaine Trustees to be sold, for payment of his Debts and for raiseing of Portions for
Diana Bedell Isabella Bedell and Anne Bedell Infants Daughters of the said Edward Bedell and for such other
Children as shall hereafter be begotten by the said Edward Bedell upon the body of Isabella Bedell his
now Wife.</para>
			<para id="p19">15. An Act to enable Francis Brend Esquire the surviveing Sonne and Issue Male of Sir Mathew Brend Knight
deceased to sell certaine Lands for the raiseing of Three thousand pounds for the Portions of Frances and Elizabeth
Brend the Daughters of Thomas Brend Esquire deceased late elder Brother of the said Francis Brend.</para>
			<para id="p20">16. An Act for the naturalizeing of Jane De Galiere. Countesse of Lincolne and others.</para>
			<para id="p21">17. An Act for restoreing the Honour of Baron Audley of Hely to James Lord Audley and others herein
mentioned.</para>
			<para id="p22">18. An Act for the appropriating the Re&bholigct;oryes of Llanrhayader in Mochuant in the Countyes of Denbigh and
Mountgomery and of Skeviog in the County of Flint for Repaires of the Cathedrall Church of St Asaph and the
better maintenance of the Choire there and alsoe for the uniteing severall Re&bholigct;oryes sine cura and the Vicarages
of the same Parishes within the Diocesse of St Asaph aforesaid.</para>
			<para id="p23">19. An Act to enable the Trustees of Sir Ralph Banks to sell Lands for payment of Debts.</para>
			<para id="p24">20. An Act for, setleing diverse Mannours Farmes and Lands in the County of Hertford now in the Possession
of Francis Shalcrosse Esquire and for makeing provision for younger Children and payment of Debts.</para>
			<para id="p25">21. An Act to enable Trustees to sell Lands for the raiseing of Money to pay the Debts of John Samine
Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p26">22. An Act to enable Trustees to sell Lands for payment of the Debts of John Herring deceased.</para>
			<para id="p27">23. An Act to enable Trustees to sell Lands for payment of the Debts of Sir William Thorold late of Hough
in the County of Lincolne Knight deceased.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


