<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47473" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677 &amp; 1678</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) An Act for granting a Supply to His Majestie of Six hundred nineteene thousand three hundred eighty eight pounds
eleaven shillings and nine pence for disbanding the Army and other, uses therein mentioned. [Rot. Parl. 30 C.II. p. I. nu. 1.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Grant of &pound;206, 463, 179. 3d.; 29 Car. II. c. I.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">Most Gratious Sovereigne<br/>
Wee, your Majestyes most loyall and obedient Subje&bholigct;s the Commons now in Parliament assembled perceiveing
that there is noe further occasion for the Forces raised since the Nine and twentyeth of September last and
being sensible that the continuance of them must be a great burthen and unnecessary charge to your Majestie To
the intent therefore that the said charge may not continue and to enable your Majestie compleatly to pay and to
disband all the said Forces as hereafter is mentioned and expressed Wee. your Majestyes said loyal Subje&bholigct;s have
given and granted and by these Presents doe give and. grant for the ends and purposes aforesaid unto your most
Excellent Majestie (whome God long preserve) the Summe of Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred sixty
two pounds seaventeene shillings and three pence to be raised and levyed in manner following (that is to say)
Whereas in and by a certaine A&bholigct; lately passed entituled. (An A&bholigct; for raiseing the Summe of Five hundred eighty
fower thousand nine hundred seaventy eight pounds two shillings two pence halfe penny for the speedy building
Thirty Shipps of Warr) It was amongst other things ena&bholigct;ed That the Summe of Thirty fower thousand fower
hundred and ten pounds nine shillings six pence halfe penny by the moneth for seaventeene moneths begining from
the five and twentyeth day of March One thousand six hundred seaventy seaven should be assessed taxed colle&bholigct;ed
levyed, and paid, by five quarterly and two months payment in the severall Countyes Cittyes Burroughs Townes
and Places within England and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede according to the Rates and
proportions therein expressed. It is now further ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the
Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and Temporall and of the Co[i]mmons in this present Parlyament assembled
and by the Authoritie of the same That the summe of Thirty fower thousand fower hundred and ten pounds nine
shillings and six pence halfe penny by the Moneth for six Months, the first of the said Months begining from the
[fower and twentyeth<ref idref="n2">2</ref>] day of August in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy eight shall be
assessed taxed levyed and paid by two Quarterly payments in the severall Countyes Cityes Burroughs Townes and
Places within England and Wales and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede for the ends and purposes aforesaid
according to the Rates and Proportions following (That is to say) For each Moneth of the said six Moneths</para>
		<para id="p3">For the County of Bedford The summe of Fower hundred forty eight pounds eight shillings ten pence
halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p4">For the County of Berks the summe of five hundred sixty six pounds three shillings three pence halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p5">For the County of Bucks the summe of six hundred fifty seaven pounds thirteene shillings two pence
halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p6">The County of Cambridge the summe of five hundred and ten pounds.</para>
		<para id="p7">The Isle of Ely the summe of One hundred seaventy fower pounds eighteene shillings and eleaven pence
halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p8">The County of Chester the summe of Three hundred seaventy three pounds eighteene shillings and seaven pence</para>
		<para id="p9">The Citty and County of the Citty of Chester the summe of twenty six pounds fowerteene shillings and
two pence.</para>
		<para id="p10">The County of Cornwall the summe of seaven hundred and seaventy pounds nine shillings one penny
halfe penny</para>
		<para id="p11">The County of Cumberland the summe of eighty fower pounds three shillings one halfe penny</para>
		<para id="p12">The County of Derby the summe of fower hundred thirty one pounds fower shillings and two pence</para>
		<para id="p13">The County of Devon the summe of One thousand six hundred and fowerteene pounds nineteene shillings and
seaven pence</para>
		<para id="p14">The Citty and County of the Citty of Exon the summe of fifty eight pounds three shillings and eight pence</para>
		<para id="p15">The County of Dorset the summe of six hundred seaventy two pounds five shillings two pence halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p16">The Towne and County, of Poole the summe of five pounds nine shillings and ten pence</para>
		<para id="p17">The County of Durham the summe of One hundred sixty one pounds eighteene shillings fower pence
halfe penny</para>
		<para id="p18">The County of Yorke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Yorke and Towne and County of Kingston
upon Hull the summe of One thousand seaven hundred thirty fower pounds twelve shillings and seaven pence</para>
		<para id="p19">The County of Essex the summe of One thousand five hundred forty nine pounds fower shillings and
five pence.</para>
		<para id="p20">The County of Gloucester the summe of nine hundred and fower pounds five shillings one penny halfe
penny.</para>
		<para id="p21">The Citty and County of the Citty of Gloucester the summe of nineteene pounds fowerteene shillings</para>
		<para id="p22">The County of Hereford the summe of five hundred sixty five pounds sixteene shillings eight pence</para>
		<para id="p23">The County of Hertford the summe of six hundred seaventy two pounds eighteene shillings one penny
halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p24">The County of Huntingdon the summe of three hundred and sixteene pounds seaventeene shillings one penny.</para>
		<para id="p25">The County of Kent with the Citty and County of the Citty of Canterbury the summe of One thousand six
hundred sixty three pounds nine shillings and fower pence</para>
		<para id="p26">The County of Lancaster the summe of five hundred and three pounds six shillings and nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p27">The County of Leicester the summe of five hundred forty two pounds seaven shillings one penny halfe
penny</para>
		<para id="p28">The County of Lincolne with the Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne the summe of One thousand
two hundred eighty seaven pounds eleaven shillings</para>
		<para id="p29">The Citty of London with the Liberty, of Saint Martins Le Grand the summe of Two thousand one hundred
forty five pounds fifteene shillings and eight pence</para>
		<para id="p30">The County of Midlesex with the Citty and Liberty of Westminster the summe of One thousand five hundred
and twenty pounds and five shillings</para>
		<para id="p31">The County of Monmouth the summe of One hundred ninety five pounds</para>
		<para id="p32">The County of Northampton the summe of Seaven hundred and six pounds nineteene shillings one penny.</para>
		<para id="p33">The County of Nottingham with the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham the summe of Fower
hundred thirty six pounds fowerteene shillings</para>
		<para id="p34">The County of Norfolke the summe of One thousand six hundred eighty five pounds six shillings</para>
		<para id="p35">The Citty and County of the Citty of Norwich the summe of ninety pounds</para>
		<para id="p36">The County of Northumberland with the Townes of Newcastle and Berwicke upon Tweede the summe of One
hundred eighty six pounds seaven shillings and ten pence</para>
		<para id="p37">The County of Oxon the summe of five hundred sixty seaven pounds fifteene shillings fower pence</para>
		<para id="p38">The County of Rutland the summe of One hundred and twenty pounds fower shillings five pence halfe penny</para>
		<para id="p39">The County of Salop the summe of Six hundred and one pounds seaventeene shillings one penny</para>
		<para id="p40">The County of Stafford the summe of Fower hundred twenty six pounds five shillings and ten pence.</para>
		<para id="p41">The Citty and County of the Citty of Litchfield the summe of Six pounds and ten shillings</para>
		<para id="p42">The County; of Somerset the summe of One thousand, three hundred eighty five pounds fifteene shillings: and
fower pence.</para>
		<para id="p43">The Citty and County of the Citty of Bristoll the summe of Ninety nine pounds fowerteene shillings and
two pence</para>
		<para id="p44">The County of Southampton with the Towne and County of Southampton and the Isle of Wight the summe
of One thousand ninety fower pounds forwerteene shillings and fower pence</para>
		<para id="p45">The County of Suffolke the summe of One thousand six hundred forty nine pounds five shillings and fower
pence</para>
		<para id="p46">The County of Surrey with the Burrough of Southwarke the summe of Seaven hundred ninety eight pounds
ten shillings and one penny.</para>
		<para id="p47">The County of Sussex the summe of Nine hundred and ten pounds thirteene shillings and ten pence
halfe peny</para>
		<para id="p48">The County of Warwicke with the Citty and County of the Citty of Coventry the summe of Five hundred
ninety six pounds fower shillings fower pence halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p49">The County of Worcester the summe of Five hundred twenty six pounds nineteene shillings six pence</para>
		<para id="p50">The Citty and County of the Citty of Worcester the summe of Twenty seaven pounds fowerteene shillings and
nine pence.</para>
		<para id="p51">The County of Wilts the summe of Nine hundred eighty three pounds eight shillings nine pence halfe penny</para>
		<para id="p52">The County of Westmorland the summe of Fifty eight pounds</para>
		<para id="p53">The County of Anglesey the summe of Sixty two pounds sixteene shillings and ten pence</para>
		<para id="p54">The County of Brecknocke the summe of One hundred forty one pounds five. shillings two pence three
farthings</para>
		<para id="p55">The County of Cardigan the summe of Fifty two pounds seaventeene shillings ten pence three farthings.</para>
		<para id="p56">The County of Carmarthen the summe of One hundred thirty six pounds three shillings and fower pence</para>
		<para id="p57">The County of Carnarvan the summe of Seaventy three Pounds six shillings one penny.</para>
		<para id="p58">The County of Denbigh the summe of One hundred and eleaven pounds fifteene shillings three pence
halfe peny</para>
		<para id="p59">The County of Flint the summe of Fifty nine pounds eight shillings eight pence</para>
		<para id="p60">The County of Glamorgan the summe of One hundred eighty nine pounds eight shillings (<ref idref="n3">3</ref>) eleaven pence</para>
		<para id="p61">The County of Merioneth the summe of Fifty pounds eight shillings and one halfe penny.</para>
		<para id="p62">The County of Montgomory the summe of One hundred thirty eight pounds six shillings and one penny.</para>
		<para id="p63">The County of Pembroke the summe of One hundred sixty three pounds five shillings</para>
		<para id="p64">The County of Radnor the summe of eighty seaven pounds three shillings and fower pence</para>
		<para id="p65">The Towne and County of Haverford West the summe of Seaven pounds eleaven shillings eight pence
halfe penny.</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Commissioners under 29 C. II. c. I. to be Commissioners for executing this A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p66">
				<emph type="i">Persons concerned in levying, &amp;c. under this A&bholigct; to have the Benefits and subje&bholigct; to the Penalties as Persons levying the former Assessments.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p67">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all and every the persons who are appointed to a&bholigct; as Commissioners for the
Execution of the said former A&bholigct; shall likewise be and soe are hereby constituted and appointed to be
Commissioners for the Execution of this present A&bholigct; within the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cityes Burroughs
Townes and Places for which they were formerly appointed, and all and every the Commissioners aforesaid or
before mentioned shall have and execute like Powers and Authorities Rules and Dir&bholigct;tions touching the better
assessing colle&bholigct;ing levying receiveing and paying the said Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred sixty
two pounds seaventeene shillings and three pence And all and every. Person or persons who shall be lyable unto
or any wayes concerned or imployed in the assessing colle&bholigct;ing levying receiving disposeing or paying any of the
Moneys by this A&bholigct; imposed shall have like Benefitts Advantages and Discharges and shall be subje&bholigct; to the like
Penaltyes and Forfeitures in case of misapplying the Money hereby given or any negle&bholigct; or refusall to pay their
respe&bholigct;ive Assesment or to performe their respe&bholigct;ive Dutyes as any other person or persons lyable unto or
concerned or imployed in the assessing colle&bholigct;ing levying receiving disposeing or paying any of the said former
Assesments ought to have or be subje&bholigct; unto as fully and amply as if all and every the Names Persons Officers
Clauses Matters and Things to the said former Assesments relateing had respe&bholigct;ively beene againe in this A&bholigct;
sett downe repeated and ena&bholigct;ed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Commissioners for the City of Lincoln and Town of Nottingham.</head>
			<para id="p68">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the Maior and six senior Aldermen and Recorder of the Citty of Lincolne
for the time being shall be Commissioners to execute all the said Powers and Rules of the said mentioned A&bholigct;
and this present A&bholigct;; within the Citty and County of the Citty of Lincolne, And that the Maior and Aldermen
for the time being of the Towne of Nottingham shall be Commissioners to execute all the Powers and Rules of
the said mentioned A&bholigct; and likewise of the A&bholigct;: entituled An A&bholigct; for raiseing money by a Poll and otherwise to
enable His Majestie to enter into an a&bholigct;uall Warr against the French King and for prohibiting severall French
Commodities, and of this present A&bholigct; within the Towne and County of the Towne of Nottingham.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. Commissioners to meet on or before the 4th Day of Sept. 1678.</head>
			<para id="p69">
				<emph type="i">Time of First Quarterly Payment.; Second Quarterly Payment.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p70">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That the severall Commissioners shall meete together at the most usuall and
common Place of meeting upon or before the Fowerth day of September in the yeare of our Lord One thousand
six hundred seaventy eight to putt this A&bholigct; in Execution and that the first quarterly Payment amounting to the
Summe of One hundred three thousand two hundred thirty and one pounds eight shillings seaven pence halfe
penny shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid unto the Receivers of the severall Countyes appointed or to
be appointed by his Majestie. upon or before the Fower and twentyeth day of November in the yeare of our
Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy eight, And that the second quarterly Payment amounting to the Summe
of One hundred and three thousand two hundred thirty one pounds eight shillings seaven pence halfe peny
shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid unto the [Receivers<ref idref="n4">4</ref>] of the severall Countyes appointed or to be appointed
by His Majestie upon or before the Fower and twentyeth day of February in the said yeare of our Lord One
thousand six hundred seaventy eight.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Persons lending Money to have Tally of Loan;</head>
			<para id="p71">
				<emph type="i">and Order for Payment of Interest at &pound;8 per Cent, per Ann. payable every Three Months. Repayment of Principal.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p72">And whereas it will be necessary for the more speedy disbanding and paying of the said Forces soe raised that
money should be borrowed upon the Credit of the Two hundred six thousand fower hundred sixty two pounds
seaventeene shillings and three pence given by this A&bholigct; Bee it therefore ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the Authoritie
aforesaid That all and every person and persons who shall lend any money to Your Majestie upon the Credit of
the aforesaid Summe of Two hundred six thousand fower hundred sixty two pounds seaventeene shillings three
pence given by this A&bholigct; (not exceeding the summe of One hundred and fifty thousand pounds) and pay the
same into the Receipt of Your Majestyes Exchequer shall immediately have a Tally of Loane for the same and
an Order for repayment bearing the same date with the Talley with a Clause therein inserted for the payment
of Interest for such moneys at the rate of eight pounds per Cent per Ann&bhouov; to be paid every three Moneths
untill the repayment of the Principall.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. Such Orders to be registered according to Date of Tally.</head>
			<para id="p73">
				<emph type="i">Orders for Repayment of Money lent to be registered in course according to Date of Tally.; and Persons paid in course as Orders stand entered.; Monies raised under Act liable in the same Order for such Repayment, and not to be divertible to any other Use.; No Fee for providing such Books, or making Entries, &amp;c. or for Payment of the Money so lent; Penalty. Undue Preference by Officer; Action by Party grieved, and Loss of Place.; The like as to Deputy.; Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller offending liable to Forfeiture, and Deputies to A&bholigct;ion.; Penalties, &amp;c. how to be recovered.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p74">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That after Orders shall be, registred for the
repayment of (<ref idref="n5">5</ref>) Loanes on this A&bholigct; not exceeding one hundred and fifty thousand pounds with Interest as aforesaid
and the Forces a&bholigct;ually disbanded that others Orders of the Lord Treasurer to the Paymaster of the Land Forces
for payment for Cloathes and other Necessaries for the Forces to be disbanded by this A&bholigct; shall be registred in
course according to their respe&bholigct;ive dates and that all Orders for repayment of Money lent shall be registred in
course according to the date of the Talley respe&bholigct;ively and that all other Orders after the a&bholigct;uall disbanding of
the said Forces shall be entred in course according to their respe&bholigct;ive dates and none of the Orders above
mentioned shall have preference one before another but shall be entred in their course according to the dates of
the Talleys and the times of bringing their other Orders as they are in point of time respe&bholigct;ively before each
other And that all and every person and persons shall be paid in course according as their Orders shall stand
entred in the said Register Booke soe as that the person Native or Forreigner his Executors Administrators and
Assignes who shall have his Warrant or Order Warrants or Orders first entred in the said Booke of Register
shall be taken and accounted as the first person to be paid upon the Two hundred six thousand fower hundred
sixty two pounds seaventeene shillings three pence to come in by vertue of this A&bholigct;, And he or they that
shall have his or (<ref idref="n6">6</ref>) their Warrants or Orders Warrant or Order next entred shall be taken and accounted to be
the second person to be paid and soe successively and in course And that the Two hundred six thousand fower
hundred sixty two pounds seaventeene shillings three pence to come in by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be in the
same order lyeable to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said repe&bholigct;ive partyes their Executors Administrators or Assignes
successively without preference of one before another and not otherwise and not be divertible to any other use
intent or purpose whatsoever And that noe Fee or Reward or Gratuity dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly be demanded or taken
of any Your Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s for provideing or makeing any such Bookes Registers, Entryes View Searches
or Certificate in or for Payment of Money lent or the Interest thereof or for Payment of any Money upon any
Order by any of Your Majestyes Officer or Officers their Clerks or Deputyes on paine of payment: of treble
damages to the party grieved by the party offending with Costs of Suite, or if the Officer himselfe take or
demand any such Fee or Reward then to lose his place alsoe, And if any undue preference of one [befoe<ref idref="n7">7</ref>]
another shall be made either in point of Registry or of Payment contrary to the true meaneing of this A&bholigct; by any
such Officer or Officers then the Party offending shall be lyable by A&bholigct;ion of Debt or on the Case to pay the
value of the Debt Damages and Costs to the party grieved and shall be forejudged from his Place or Office.
And if such preference be unduely made by any his Deputy or Clerke without dire&bholigct;ion or privity of his Master
then such Deputy or Clerke onely shall be lyable to such A&bholigct;ion Debt Damages and Costs and shall be for
ever after [incapeable<ref idref="n8">8</ref>] of his Place or Office. And in case the Auditor shall not dire&bholigct; the Order or the Clerke
of the Pells record or the Teller make Payment [accoding<ref idref="n9">9</ref>] to each persons due Place and Order as aforedire&bholigct;ed then he or they shall be adjudged to forfeite and their respe&bholigct;ive Deputyes and Clerks herein offending
to bee lyable to such A&bholigct;ion Debt Damages and Costs in manner as aforesaid All which said Penaltyes
Forfeitures Damages and Costs to be incurred by any of the Officers of the Exchequer or any their Deputyes or
[Clers<ref idref="n10">10</ref>] shall and may be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in any of His Majestyes
Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne, Prote&bholigct;ion Priviledge Wager of Law Injun&bholigct;ion or
Order of Restraint shall be in any wise granted or allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s7">
			<head>VII. What not interpreted undue, Preference where Tallies brought the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p75">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby declared That if it happen that severall Talleys of Loane beare date or
be brought the same day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be registred then it shall be interpreted noe undue
preference which of those he enters first soe he enters them all the same day.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s8">
			<head>VIII. The like Ena&bholigct;ment when Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, and Teller pay</head>
			<para id="p76">
				<emph type="i">subsequent Orders when first demanded.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p77">Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpreted any undue preference to incurr any penalty in point of
Payment if the Auditor dire&bholigct; and the Clerke of the Pells record and the Teller doe pay subsequent
Orders of persons that come and demand their Money and bring their Orders before other persons that did
not come to demand their Money and bring their Order in their course soe as there be soe much Money
reserved as will satisfie their Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon
Loane being to cease from the time the Money is soe reserved and kept in Bank for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s9">
			<head>IX. Persons having Money due to them may assign their Interest in Warrants, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p78">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee.; Assignee may assign.; Assignments not to be released, &amp;c. by Assignor.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p79">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That every person [and<ref idref="n11">11</ref>] persons to whome any Money
shall be due upon the Two hundred six thousand fower hundred sixty two pounds seaventeene shillings and
three pence given by vertue of this A&bholigct; after Warrant or Order entered in the Booke of Register aforesaid for
Payment thereof his Executors Administrators or Assignes by indorsement of his Order or Warrant may assigne
and transferr his Right Title Interest and Benefitt of such Warrant or Order or any part thereof to any other
which being notified in the Office of the Auditor for the Receipt aforesaid and an Entry and Memoriall thereof
alsoe made in the Booke of Registry aforesaid for Warrants which the Officers shall upon request without Fee or
Charge accordingly make shall entitle such Assignee his Executors Administrators and Assignes to the benefitt
thereof and payment thereon, and such Assignee may in like manner assigne againe and soe toties quoties and
afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person or persons who have made such Assignements to make
void release or discharge the same or any the Moneys thereby due or any part thereof</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s10">
			<head>X. Where A&bholigct;ion, &amp;c. commenced against Persons executing A&bholigct;.</head>
			<para id="p80">
				<emph type="i">General Issue.; Treble Costs.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p81">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion Plaint Suite or Information shall be
commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in Execution
of this A&bholigct; such person or persons soe sued in any Court whatsoever shall or may pleade the Generall Issue
Not guilty and upon any issue joyned may give this A&bholigct; and the speciall matter in evidence and if the Plaintiffe
or Prosecutor shall become non suite or forbeare further prosecution or suffer discontinuance or if a Verdi&bholigct; passe
against him the Defendant and Defendants shall recover their treble costs for which they shall have the like
remedy as in any case where Costs by law are given to Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s11">
			<head>XI. Receivers under former A&bholigct;s not having accounted, appointed under this A&bholigct;, and intermeddling;</head>
			<para id="p82">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;500.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p83">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any person haveing beene a Receiver
of Money due upon any A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s passed before the begining of this present Session of Parlyament and not
haveing accompted for all the Moneys by him received and which ought to have beene accompted for upon such
A&bholigct; or A&bholigct;s shall be appointed Receiver for any the Moneys due upon this A&bholigct; and shall intermedle therein every
such person shall forfeite the summe of Five hundred pounds to be recovered by any person or persons that will
sue for the same in any of his Majestyes Courts of Record by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or other Information
wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion Wager of Law Ayd Preyer Priviledge Injun&bholigct;ion or Order of Restraint shall be
in any wise prayed granted or allowed nor any more than one Imparlance.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s12">
			<head>XII. Commissioners executing A&bholigct; not liable to Penalties of 25 Car. II. c. 2.</head>
			<para id="p84">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That noe Commissioner or Commissioners or any other
Officer that shall be imployed in the Execution of this A&bholigct; or any thing therein contained shall be lyable for or
by reason of their a&bholigct;ing or proceeding as Commissioners by vertue of this A&bholigct; to any of the Penaltyes mentioned
in an A&bholigct; entituled An A&bholigct; for preventing Dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants for not takeing the
Oathes or Declaration in the said A&bholigct; expressed in case such Commissioner or Commissioners Officer or Officers
have before that time taken the said Oathes and subscribed the Declaration in the recited A&bholigct; mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s13">
			<head>XIII. Regulations as to Payment and disbanding the Forces within the Kingdom.</head>
			<para id="p85">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all the respe&bholigct;ive Forces Regiments Troops and Companies Officers and
Soldiers whether in Garrison or out of Garison within this Kingdome of England and Dominion of Wales and
the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede and the Islands of Guernsey and Jersey raised at any time since the said
Twenty nineth of September One thousand six hundred (<ref idref="n12">12</ref>) seaven be paid disbanded and discharged at or before
the Thirtyeth day of July One thousand six hundred seaventy and eight in such manner and by such Orders and
Dire&bholigct;ions as His Majestie shall appoint and by such other Rules and Dire&bholigct;ions as shall be herein limitted
and provided.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s14">
			<head>XIV. The like as to Forces in the Spanish Netherlands.</head>
			<para id="p86">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That all other Regiments Troops and Companyes Officers and Soldiers being His
Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s whether in Garison or out of Garison in any part of the Spanish Netherlands raised at any time
since the said Twenty ninth day of September be paid disbanded and discharged on or before the Six and twentyeth
day of August in the said yeare One thousand six hundred seaventy eight in such manner and by such Orders
and Dire&bholigct;ions as His Majestie shall appoint and by such other Rules and Dire&bholigct;ions as are herein limitted and
appointed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s15">
			<head>XV. Monies appropriated to Payment and disbanding of the Forces, Exception of Allowances, Fees, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p87">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That all Moneys herein before named and mentioned
colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid by vertue of this A&bholigct; except the Allowances therein made to the respe&bholigct;ive Colle&bholigct;ors
Clerks and Receivers Generall and the usuall Fees of the Officers of the Exchequer and what shall be issued
thence for the repayment of Loanes made in pursuance of this A&bholigct; upon the Credit of the said Two hundred six
thousand fower hundred, sixty two pounds seaventeene shillings and three pence into the Exchequer and Interest
for the same shall be applyed and appropryated and are hereby appropriated to and for the speedy and compleate
paying and disbanding the Forces Officers and Soldiers raised since the Nine and twentyeth of September One
thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven and to noe other intent use or purpose whatsoever.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s16">
			<head>XVI. Colle&bholigct;ors keeping Monies colle&bholigct;ed in their Hands, or unduly paying away the same.</head>
			<para id="p88">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5.; Receiver General or his Deputy unduly paying Monies received under this A&bholigct;.; Penalty &pound;500.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p89">And for the more effe&bholigct;uall doeing thereof and that the said Moneys hereby given may be applyed to the use
and service aforesaid Bee it further ena&bholigct;ed And it is ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any Colle&bholigct;or
of any Parish or Place shall keepe in his hands any part of the said Money by him colle&bholigct;ed for any longer
time then is by this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ed (other then the allowance made unto him by this A&bholigct;) or shall pay any part
thereof to any person or persons other then the Receiver Generall of such County or Place or his Deputy. That
every such Colle&bholigct;or shall forfeite for every such offence the summe of Five pounds And in case any Receiver
Generall or his Deputy shall pay any part of the Moneys paid to him or them by any Colle&bholigct;or by vertue of
this A&bholigct; to any person or persons whatsoever other then the Receipt of His Majestyes Exchequer and that at or
within the respe&bholigct;ive, times limitted by this A&bholigct; or in case such Receiver Generall or his Deputy shall pay any
part of the said Moneys by any Warrant of the Lord Treasurer and Under. Treasurer or either of them or
Co&bhooov;missioners of the Treasury for the time being or upon any Talley of Pro or Talley of Anticipation or, other
wayes or device whatsoever whereby to [divert or<ref idref="n13">13</ref>] hinder the a&bholigct;uall Payment thereof into the Receipt of the
Exechequer as aforesaid That such Receiver. Generall shall for every such offence of himselfe or his Deputy forfeite
the Summe of Five hundred pounds to him or them that shall sue for the same in any Court of Record by Bill
Plaint or other Information wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law is to be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s17">
			<head>XVII. Treasury not to dire&bholigct; any Warrant for Payment of Monies other than into the Exchequer, nor for striking of any Tally of Pro or Anticipation.</head>
			<para id="p90">
				<emph type="i">Teller not to throw down any Bill, &amp;c. till he shall have received Money.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p91">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Lord Treasurer [or<ref idref="n14">14</ref>] Under Treasurer or
Co&bhooov;mis?ers of the Treasury for the time being or any of them doe not dire&bholigct; any Warrant to any of the said
Colle&bholigct;ors or Receivers Generall or their Deputyes for the Payment of any part of those Moneys to any person or
persons other then into the Receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid nor shall they [nor<ref idref="n15">15</ref>] any of them dire&bholigct; any
Warrant to the Officers of the Exchequer for the strikeing of any Talley of Pro or Talley of Anticipation nor doe
any other matter or thing whereby to divert the a&bholigct;uall Payment of the said Moneys into the Receipt of the
Exchequer nor shall the Officers of the Exchequer dire&bholigct; or strike or record the strikeing of any Talley of Pro
or Talley of Anticipation upon any of the said Moneys upon any Account or Warrant whatsoever nor shall any
Teller throw downe [any<ref idref="n16">16</ref>] Bill whereby to charge himselfe with any of the said Moneys untill he shall have a&bholigct;ually
received the same.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s18">
			<head>XVIII. Regulations as to Treasurer signing Warrants, &amp;c. for issuing Monies.</head>
			<para id="p92">
				<emph type="i">Auditor not to draw Order for issuing Money to any other than Treasurer of the Navy, &amp;c.; nor dire&bholigct;, nor Teller, &amp;c. record or make Payment of such Money otherwise than as mentioned in the Warrant.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p93">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer, or
either of them or the Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being doe not signe any Warrant or Order
or doe any other matter or thing for the issueing any of the said Moneys out of the Exchequer to any
person whatsoever other then the Treasurer or Paymaster of the Land-Forces or to and for the speedy and
compleate paying and disbanding the Forces Officers and Soldiers raised since the Twenty nineth of September
One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven or for the Repayment of Loanes upon the Credit of this A&bholigct; or
Interest of the same as by this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed. Nor shall the Auditor of the Receipt draw any Order for the
issueing of any part of the said Moneys to any person whatsoever other then the Treasurer or Paymaster of the
Land Forces or to and for the speedy and compleate paying and disbanding the Forces Officers and Soldiers raised
since the Twenty ninth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven or for the repayment of
Loanes and Interest for the same as aforesaid, nor shall he dire&bholigct; or the Clerke of the Pells record or the Teller
make Payment of any of the said Moneys by vertue of any Warrant or upon any Order or other, way or device
whatsoever other then for the uses aforesaid and to be soe mentioned and expressed in such Warrant and Order.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s19">
			<head>XIX. Loans upon the Credit of A&bholigct; appropriated to Payment and disbanding of Forces raised since 29th Sept. 1677.</head>
			<para id="p94">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That all Loanes upon the Credit of this A&bholigct; be
and are hereby appropriated to and for the speedy and compleate paying and disbanding the Forces Officers and
Soldiers raised since the Twenty ninth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven nor shall they be
issued out of the Exchequer to any other intent or purpose whatsoever nor by any, other Warrant or Order but
wherein it is expressed that the same is to and for the speedy and compleate paying and disbanding the Forces
Officers and Soldiers raised since the Twenty ninth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven
nor to any person whatsoever but to the Treasurer and Paymaster of the Land Forces.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s20">
			<head>XX. Treasurer or Paymaster of the Land Forces to keep distin&bholigct; the Accounts respe&bholigct;ing the said Monies.</head>
			<para id="p95">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Treasurer or Paymaster of the Land
Forces (of whome good Security shall be first taken by the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer or Commissioners
of the Treasury) shall keepe all such Moneys paid to him distin&bholigct; and apart from all other Moneys and that the
Treasurer or Paymaster of the Land Forces doe not issue or pay any of the said Moneys but by Warrant expressing
that the same is to and for the speedy and compleate paying and disbanding the Forces Officers and Soldiers
raised since the Twenty ninth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s21">
			<head>XXI. No Warrant to be signed but for paying and disbanding the Forces.</head>
			<para id="p96">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That such person or persons as doe signe the
Warrants to the Treasurer or Paymaster of the Land Forces shall not signe any Warrant or doe any other thing
for the issueing and paying any of the said Moneys to any use intent or purpose whatsoever other then to and
for the speedy and compleate paying and disbanding the Forces Officers and Soldiers raised since the Twenty
ninth of September One thousand six hundred seaventy and seaven and to be soe expressed in the said Warrant.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s22">
			<head>XXII. Officers misapplying the said Monies.</head>
			<para id="p97">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p98">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any of the Officers or other persons aforesaid
shall after Receipt of any of the said Moneys divert or, misapply the same or any part thereof by vertue of any
Warrant from the Lord Treasurer for the time being or other superior Officer contrary to the true intent and
meaning of this A&bholigct; that then such Officer or Officers soe diverting or misapplying the said Money shall forfeite
the like summe soe diverted or misapplyed which said forfeiture shall be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint
or Information in any of His Majestyes Courts [of Record<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager,
of Law shall be allowed One Moyety of which Forfeiture soe to be recovered shall be to the Informer or him
that shall sue for the same and the other Moyety thereof to be distributed to the poore of the Parish where such
offence shall be committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s23">
			<head>XXIII. The like Offence by any Officer of the Exchequer.</head>
			<para id="p99">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p100">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That if any Officer or Officers mentioned in this A&bholigct; or
in any wise belonging to the Exchequer shall wittingly and [willingly<ref idref="n18">18</ref>] offend against this Law or any Clause therein
by diverting or misapplying any of the Moneys colle&bholigct;ed by vertue of this A&bholigct; or any Loane had thereupon contrary
to the true intent and meaning of the said A&bholigct; that for any and every such offence such Officer and Officers soe offending
shall forfeite his Office and Place and is and are hereby disabled and made incapeable to hold or execute the
said Office or any other Office whatsoever for the future.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s24">
			<head>XXIV. Further Regulations as to paying and disbanding the Forces by Paymaster.</head>
			<para id="p101">
				<emph type="i">Certificate by him to Exchequer of Monies paid, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p102"> And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the said Treasurer or Paymaster of the Land Forces
shall in the first place pay off and discharge the Wages and Pay due to the Officers and Soldiers at the respe&bholigct;ive
time of their disbanding and shall within twenty dayes after the disbanding of any Regiment Troope or Company
or any number of Horse or Foote returne into the Receipt of His Majestyes Exchequer a Certificate fairely written 
in Parchment of the Money he paid and the numbers of men together with the dayes of their Muster whereby a
due account may appeare thereof and out of the residue of the Money he sail pay and discharge what appeares
due for Cloathes and other Necessaries and Charges relateing to the said Forces and shall in like manner returne
Certificates of the same into the Exchequer. </para>
		</section>
		<section id="s25">
			<head>XXV. No Stay of Prosecution admitted in any Suit for Recovery of Penalties.</head>
			<para id="p103">Provided alsoe and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That noe stay of prosecution upon any Command Warrant Motion Order or
Dire&bholigct;ion by Non vult ulterius prosequi shall be had made admitted received or allowed by any Court whatsoever
in any Suite or Proceeding by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information or otherwise for the recovery of all or
any the Paines Forfeitures or Penalties upon any person or persons by this A&bholigct; infli&bholigct;ed or therein mentioned or
for or in order to the Convi&bholigct;ion or Disability of any person offending against this Law</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s26">
			<head>XXVI. Limitation of Prosecution.</head>
			<para id="p104">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That noe person to be prosecuted for any offence by diverting or misapplying
any Moneys contrary to the intent and meaning of this A&bholigct; shall be prosecuted thereupon by any Plaint Bill, A&bholigct;ion,
Suite or Information [unlesse such Bill Plaint A&bholigct;ion Suite or Information<ref idref="n17">17</ref>] be exhibited and commenced within two
yeares next after the offence committed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s27">
			<head>XXVII. Soldiers disbanded deemed Inhabitants of Parish, &amp;c. where last settled before Enrolment into the Service.</head>
			<para id="p105">Provided alsoe That all such Soldiers as shall be disbanded by vertue of this present A&bholigct; shall be deemed
Inhabitants of such respe&bholigct;ive Towneshipps Parishes and Hambletts of which they were legally setled Inhabitants
next before their Inrollment into his Majestyes Service Any Law to the contrary notwithstanding Soe as such
Souldiers soe disbanded doe returne to their respe&bholigct;ive Habitations where they were last legally setled as aforesaid
on or before the Twenty ninth of September next.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s28">
			<head>XXVIII. Apprentices, &amp;c. disbanded, rendering themselves to their Masters, and Masters refusing to receive them, not to be sued, &amp;c. on Indenture, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p106">And whereas severall persons who are Apprentices and Servants by Indenture or otherwise out of their Loyalty
to their Soveraigne and for the good of their Country have taken up Arms and listed themselves in the Army
or Forces which are now to be disbanded by reason thereof themselves or their Friends may be sued or molested
upon their said Indentures Contra&bholigct;s or Covenants For remedy whereof Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid
That if any of the said Persons or Souldiers who shall be disbanded by reason of this A&bholigct; shall before the Nine
and twentyeth of September next tender himselfe to his said Master to serve out his or their time and if the
said Master shall negle&bholigct; or refuse to take him or them againe into his service That then and in such case
neither he nor they nor any of his or their Suretyes or Friends shall be sued or molested upon his or their
Indenture or Indentures or upon any Bonds Contra&bholigct;s and Covenants for or by reason of his or their departing
out of his or their said service.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s29">
			<head>XXIX. Recital that His Majesty has been at great Charge in fitting out a Navy, and Payment of Portion of Princess of Orange.</head>
			<para id="p107">
				<emph type="i">29 C. II. c. 2.; Twelve Months Assessment of Grant of &pound;412,925. 14s. 6d.; How payable</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p108">And whereas Your Majestie hath beene at an extraordinary charge in fitting out and prepareing a Royall Navy
and provideing Ordnance for the same for the defence of this Your Majestyes Kingdome and alsoe that Your
Majesty stands ingaged for the payment of the Marriage Portion of the most Excellent Lady Mary Princesse of
Orange Your Majestyes Neece And whereas Wee Your said Majestyes obedient Subje&bholigct;s the Commons of England
in Parlyament assembled are engaged unto Your Majestie for the repayment of the summe of Two hundred
thousand pounds which Your Majestie hath beene pleased to raise upon the Creditt of a certaine A&bholigct; passed in
this present Parlyament in the Twenty ninth yeare of Your Majestyes Raigne entituled An A&bholigct; for an additionall
Excise upon Beere Ale and other Liquors Wee Your Majestyes most Loyall and Dutyfull Subje&bholigct;s the Commons
of England in Parliament assembled have for the ends and purposes aforesaid further given and granted and doe
hereby give and grant to Your most Excellent Majestie the Summe of fower hundred and twelve thousand nine
hundred twenty five pounds fowerteene shillings &amp; six pence to be raised leavyed and paid unto Your Majestie
as is hereafter dire&bholigct;ed and appointed And wee doe humbly beseech Your Majestie that it may be ena&bholigct;ed and
bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall
and Temporall and of the Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authority of the same
That the Summe of Fower hundred and twelve thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fowerteene shillings
and six pence shall be raised levyed and paid unto Your Majestie within the space of twelve Moneths in manner
following (That is to say) The Summe of Thirty fower thousand fower hundred and ten pounds nine shillings
six pence halfe penny by the Moneth for twelve Months begining from the Fower and twentyeth day of February
which shall be in this present Yeare of Our Lord One thousand six hundred seaventy and eight by fower
quarterly Payments in the severall Countyes Cittyes Burroughs Townes and Places within England and Wales
and the Towne of Berwicke upon Tweede according to the severall Rates and Proportions and in such manner
as is hereafter expressed (That is to say) For every Moneth of the said twelve Moneths</para>
			<para id="p109">For the County of Bedford the summe of Fower hundred forty eight pounds eight shillings ten pence
halfe peny</para>
			<para id="p110">For the County of Berks the summe of five hundred sixty six pounds three shillings three pence halfe peny</para>
			<para id="p111">The County of Bucks the summe of six hundred fifty seaven pounds thirteene shillings two pence
halfe peny.</para>
			<para id="p112">The County of Cambridge the summe of five hundred and ten pounds</para>
			<para id="p113">The Isle of Ely the summe of One hundred seaventy fower pounds eighteene shillings and eleaven pence
halfe peny</para>
			<para id="p114">The County of Chester the summe of three hundred seaventy three pounds eighteene shillings and seaven
pence</para>
			<para id="p115">The Citty and County of the City of Chester the summe of Twenty six pounds fowerteene shillings and
two pence</para>
			<para id="p116">The County of Cornwall the summe of seaven hundred and seaventy pounds nine shillings one penny
halfe penny.</para>
			<para id="p117">The County of Cumberland the summe of eighty fower pounds three shillings one halfe peny</para>
			<para id="p118">The County of Derby the summe of fower hundred thirty one pounds fower shillings and two pence</para>
			<para id="p119">The County of Devon the summe of One thousand six hundred and fowerteene pounds nineteene shillings and
seaven pence</para>
			<para id="p120">The City and County of the City of Exon the summe of fifty eight pounds three shillings and eight
pence</para>
			<para id="p121">The County of Dorset the summe of six hundred seaventy two pounds five shillings two pence halfe peny</para>
			<para id="p122">The Towne and County of Poole the summe of five pounds nine shillings and ten pence</para>
			<para id="p123">The County of Durham the summe of One hundred sixty one pounds eighteene shillings fower pence
halfe peny</para>
			<para id="p124">The County of Yorke with the City and County of the City of Yorke and Towne and County of Kingston
upon Hull the summe of One thousand seaven hundred thirty fower pounds twelve shillings and seaven pence</para>
			<para id="p125">The County of Essex the summe of One thousand five hundred forty nine pounds fower shillings and
five pence</para>
			<para id="p126">The County of Gloucester the summe of nine hundred and fower pounds five shillings one penny halfe peny.</para>
			<para id="p127">The City and County of the City of Gloucester the summe of nineteene pounds fowerteene shillings</para>
			<para id="p128">The County of Hereford the summe of five hundred sixty five pounds sixteene shillings eight pence</para>
			<para id="p129">The County of Hertford the summe of six hundred seaventy two pounds eighteene shillings one peny
halfe peny.</para>
			<para id="p130">The County of Huntingdon The summe of three hundred and sixteene pounds seaventeene shillings one peny.</para>
			<para id="p131">The County of Kent with the City and County of the City of Canterbury the summe of One thousand six
hundred sixty three pounds nine shillings and fower pence.</para>
			<para id="p132">The County of Lancaster the summe of five hundred and three pounds six shillings and nine pence</para>
			<para id="p133">The County of Leicester the summe of five hundred forty two pounds seaven shillings one peny halfe peny</para>
			<para id="p134">The County of Lincolne with the City and County of the City of Lincolne the summe of One thousand two
hundred eighty seaven pounds eleaven shillings</para>
			<para id="p135">The City of London with the Liberty of Saint Martins Le Grand the summe of Two thousand one hundred
forty five pounds fifteene shillings and eight pence</para>
			<para id="p136">The County of Midlesex with the City and Liberty of Westminster the summe of One thousand five hundred
and twenty pounds and five shillings.</para>
			<para id="p137">The County of Monmouth the summe of One hundred ninety five pounds</para>
			<para id="p138">The County of Northampton the summe of Seaven hundred and six pounds nineteene shillings one peny</para>
			<para id="p139">The County of Nottingham with the Towne and County of y<emph type="p">e</emph> [Towne of<ref idref="n19">19</ref>] Nottingham the summe of Fower
hundred thirty six pounds fowerteene shillings</para>
			<para id="p140">The County of Norffolk the summe of One thousand six hundred eighty five pounds six shillings</para>
			<para id="p141">The City and County of the City of Norwich the summe of Ninety [pounds<ref idref="n19">19</ref>]</para>
			<para id="p142">The County of Northumberland with the Towns of Newcastle and Barwicke upon Tweede the summe of One
hundred eighty six pounds seaven shillings and ten pence</para>
			<para id="p143">The County of Oxon the summe of Five hundred sixty seaven pounds fifteene shillings fower pence.</para>
			<para id="p144">The County of Rutland the summe of One hundred and twenty pounds fower shillings five pence halfe penny</para>
			<para id="p145">The County of Salop the summe of Six hundred and one pounds seaventeene shillings one peny</para>
			<para id="p146">The County of Stafford the summe of Foure hundred twenty six pounds five shillings and ten pence</para>
			<para id="p147">The City and County of the City of Litchfeild the summe of Six pounds ten shillings</para>
			<para id="p148">The County of Somerset the summe of One thousand three hundred eighty five pounds fifteene shillings and
fower pence</para>
			<para id="p149">The City and County of the City of Bristoll the summe of Ninety nine pounds fowerteene shillings and
two pence</para>
			<para id="p150">The County of Southampton with the Towne and County of Southampton and Isle of Wight the summe of
One thousand ninety fower pounds fourteene shillings and fower pence</para>
			<para id="p151">The County of Suffolke the summe of One thousand six hundred forty nine pounds five shillings and fower
pence</para>
			<para id="p152">The County of Surrey with the Burrough of Southwarke the summe of Seaven hundred ninety eight pounds ten
shillings and one peny</para>
			<para id="p153">The County of Sussex the su&bhouov;me of Nine hundred and ten pounds thirteene shillings and ten pence halfe peny</para>
			<para id="p154">The County of Warwicke with the City and County of the City of Coventry the summe of Five hundred
ninety six pounds fower shillings fower pence halfe peny</para>
			<para id="p155">The County of Worcester the summe of Five hundred twenty six pounds nineteene shillings six pence</para>
			<para id="p156">The City and County of the City of Worcester the summe of Twenty seaven pounds fowerteene shillings and
nine pence</para>
			<para id="p157">The County of Wilts the summe of Nine hundred eighty three pounds eight shillings nine pence halfe peny</para>
			<para id="p158">The County of Westmorland the summe of Fifty eight pounds</para>
			<para id="p159">The County of Anglesey the summe of sixty two pounds sixteene shillings and ten pence</para>
			<para id="p160">The County of Brecknocke the summe of One hundred forty one pounds five shillings two pence three
farthings</para>
			<para id="p161">The County of Cardigan the summe of Fifty two pounds seaventeene shillings ten pence three farthings</para>
			<para id="p162">The County of Carmarthen the summe of One hundred thirty six pounds three shillings and fower pence</para>
			<para id="p163">The County of Carnarvan the summe of Seaventy three pounds six shillings one peny.</para>
			<para id="p164">The County of Denbigh the summe of One hundred eleaven pounds fifteene shillings three pence halfe peny.</para>
			<para id="p165">The County of Flint the summe of Fifty nine pounds eight shillings eight pence</para>
			<para id="p166">The County of Glamorgan the summe of One hundred eighty nine pounds eight shillings and eleaven pence</para>
			<para id="p167">The County of Merioneth the summe of fifty pounds eight shillings and one halfe peny</para>
			<para id="p168">The County of Montgomery the summe of One hundred and thirty eight pounds six shillings and one penny</para>
			<para id="p169">The County of Pembrooke the summe of One hundred sixty three pounds five shillings</para>
			<para id="p170">The County of Radnor the summe of Eighty seaven pounds three shillings and fower pence</para>
			<para id="p171">The Towne and County of Haverford West the summe of Seaven pounds eleaven shillings eight pence halfe peny.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s30">
			<head>XXX. Appointment of Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p172">And bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That for the better ordering and levying of the said Twelve
Moneths Assessment soe as aforesaid limitted and appointed to be paid That all and every the persons appointed
for the assessing and raising the said Two hundred and six thousand fower hundred sixty two pounds seaventeen
shillings and three pence shall be Commissioners for assessing and raiseing the said Fower hundred and twelve
thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fowerteene shillings and six pence within all and every the severall
and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cities Burroughs Townes and Places as is herein before mentioned.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s31">
			<head>XXXI. Commissioners to meet together on or before 23d Day of March; and may divide themselves.</head>
			<para id="p173">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the severall Commissioners aforesaid shall meete together at the
most usuall and common Place of meeting within each of the said Countyes Cityes Burroughs Townes and Places
respe&bholigct;ively on or before the Three and twentyeth day of March next And the said Commissioners or soe many
of them as shall be present at the said first Generall Meeting or the major part of them are hereby authorized
and required to put this present A&bholigct; in Execution according to the best of their Judgements and Discretions
and shall then if they see cause subdivide and distribute themselves into lesser numbers as two or more of the
said Commissioners may be appointed for the service of each Hundred or other Division and as may best conduce
to the carrying on of His Majestyes Service hereby required.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s32">
			<head>XXXII. To declare what Number shall a&bholigct; in each Division.</head>
			<para id="p174">And for the more effe&bholigct;uall [performing<ref idref="n20">20</ref>] thereof bee it ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the Commissioners at their
aforesaid first Generall Meeting or the major part of them shall agree and sett downe in writeing who [or<ref idref="n21">21</ref>] what
number of the said Commissioners shall a&bholigct; in each of the said Divisions or Hundreds and shall deliver a true
Copy of such writeing to the Receiver Generall to the end that there be noe failer in any part of the due
execution of the service by this A&bholigct; required.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s33">
			<head>XXXIII. Receiver General to give to Commissioners Receipts for Payments made.</head>
			<para id="p175">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every Receiver Generall from time to time
within the space of one Moneth next after he shall have received the full summe that shall be charged upon any
Hundred or Division for each particular payment that is to be made to such Receiver Generall by vertue of
this A&bholigct; shall give to the Commissioners that shall a&bholigct; in such Hundred or Division a Receipt under his hand
and seale acknowledgeing his Receipt of the full summe charged upon such Hundred or Division for such
particular payment which Receipt shall be a full discharge of such Hundred or Division for such particular
payment both against His Majestie His Heires and Successors</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s34">
			<head>XXXIV. Two Commissioners may cause Proprtions charged on Divisions to be taxed, and appoint Assessors.</head>
			<para id="p176">
				<emph type="i">The Duty of Assessors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p177">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Commissioners within the severall
Divisions or Hundreds or any two or more of them are hereby authorized and required to cause the (<ref idref="n22">22</ref>) severall
proportions charged on the respe&bholigct;ive Divisions and on every Parish and Place therein for the said Twelve Moneths
Assessment to be equally assessed and taxed and to appoint two or more Assessors in each Parish or Place for
the perfe&bholigct;ing there of who are hereby required with all care and diligence to assesse the same equally by a Pound
rate upon all Lands Tenements Hereditaments Annuities Rents Parks Warrens Goods Chattells Stocke Merchandices
Offices (other then Military Offices and Offices relateing to the Navy under the Command of the Lord High
Admirall and Offices within His Majestyes Household) Tolls Proffitts and all other Estates both Reall and Personall
within the limitts circuits and bounds of their respe&bholigct;ive Parishes and Places.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s35">
			<head>XXXV. First Payment to Receiver General on 24th May 1678.</head>
			<para id="p178">
				<emph type="i">Second Payment on 24th August 1679.; Third Payment on 24th Nov. 1679.; Fourth and last Payment on 24th Feb. 1679</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p179">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the summe of One hundred and three thousand
two hundred thirty one pounds eight shillings seaven pence halfe penny being the first of the said fower Quarterly
payments hereby imposed shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid unto the Receiver Generall of the said severall
Countyes who shall be appointed by his Majestie on or before the Fower and twentyeth day, of May One thousand
six hundred seaventy eight, And the summe of one hundred and three thousand two hundred thirty one pounds
eight shillings seaven pence halfe peny being the second of the said Fower Quarterly payments on or before the
Fower and twentyeth day of August One thousand six hundred seaventy nine. And the summe of One hundred
and three thousand two hundred thirty one pounds eight shillings seaven pence halfe peny being the Third of the
said Fower Quarterly payments on or before the fower and twentyeth day of November One thousand six hundred
seaventy nine. And the summe of One hundred and three thousand two hundred thirty one pounds eight shillings
seaven pence halfe penny being the Fowerth and last of the said Fower Quarterly payments on or before the
Fower and twentyeth day of February One thousand six hundred seaventy nine.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s36">
			<head>XXXVI. Assessors to deliver a Copy of Assessment subscribed by them to Commissioners, who are to sign and seal Two Duplicates, thereof, and deliver one to Colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
			<para id="p180">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners to deliver a Schedule of Sums assessed to Receiver General to be transmitted to the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p181">And for the compleating of the whole summe charged upon the same and to the end the aforesaid summes
makeing together Fower hundred twelve thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fower teen shillings and six
pence charged upon the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cityes Burroughs Townes and Places may be equally
and indifferently assessed according to the true intent of this A&bholigct; and the Money duely colle&bholigct;ed and true account
thereof made the said Assessors are hereby required to deliver one Copy of their respe&bholigct;ive Assesments fairely
written and subscribed by them unto the said Co&bhooov;miss[ion]ers and the said Commissioners or any two or more of them
are hereby ordered and required to signe and seale two Duplicates of the said Assesments, and the one of them
to deliver or cause to be delivered to one or more honest and responsable person or persons to be Colle&bholigct;or or
Colle&bholigct;ors which the said Commissioners are hereby authorized to nominate and appoint for each Parish or Place
with Warrant to the said Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors to colle&bholigct; the said Assesment payable as aforesaid soe as the said
severall summes may be paid into the [said<ref idref="n23">23</ref>] Receivers Generall at the respe&bholigct;ive times aforesaid. And the said
Commissioners are hereby required to deliver or cause to be delivered a Schedule or Note containing the particular
summes assessed upon each Parish or Place to the Receiver Generall of each County City Burrough Towne or
Place respe&bholigct;ively to be by him the said Receiver Generall transmitted into the Kings Remembrancers Office in the
Exchequer which the said Receiver Generall is required to performe accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s37">
			<head>XXXVII. Colle&bholigct;ors to pay Money received by them to Receiver General, who is to give Notice to Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p182">
				<emph type="i">Receipt of Receiver General a Discharge</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p183">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Money received by the said
Colle&bholigct;ors within the respe&bholigct;ive Divisions or Hundreds shall from time to time be duely paid to the Receiver Generall
or to his Deputy or Deputyes to be appointed under his hand and seale whereof notice under the hand and seale
of the Receiver Generall shall be given unto the Commissioners or any two of them within the respe&bholigct;ive Divisions
or Hundreds within ten dayes after the first Generall Meeting and soe from time to time within ten dayes after
every death or removeall of any Deputy if any such shall happen And the Receipt of such Receiver Generall his
Deputy or Deputyes or any of them shall be a sufficient discharge unto every such Colle&bholigct;or</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s38">
			<head>XXXVIII. Particular Colle&bholigct;ors to pay in Money received by them to Receiver General.</head>
			<para id="p184">
				<emph type="i">Not obliged to travel more than 10 Miles to pay Money.; Salary to Receiver General</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p185">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the particular Colle&bholigct;ors are hereby required to pay in all and
every the Summes soe received by them unto the said Receivers Generall aforesaid or their Deputy or Deputyes
for payment whereof the said Colle&bholigct;ors shall not be obliged to travell above Ten miles from the Places of their
Habitations which said Receivers Generall are hereby required forthwith to transmitt or cause to be paid the
moneys by them received into the Receipt of His Majestyes Exchequer and the said Lord Treasurer is hereby
authorized to allow the said Receiver Generall of each County City and Towne respe&bholigct;ively in case he hath
returned up as aforesaid a Duplicate of the Assesment of each Parish or Place in the County City or Towne
for which he is appointed Receiver Generall a Salary for his Paines not exceeding Two pence in the pound upon
the clearing of his Account which Duplicate soe to be returned into the Kings Remembrancers Office in the
Exchequer is intended to containe noe more then the Summes in Grosse to be colle&bholigct;ed by each Colle&bholigct;or and
the severall Names of the said Colle&bholigct;ors.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s39">
			<head>XXXIX. Allowance to Colle&bholigct;ors.</head>
			<para id="p186">
				<emph type="i">Allowance to Clerk of Commissioners</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p187">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That the Colle&bholigct;ors of each Parish or Place which shall be
appointed [Colle&bholigct;ors<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall upon Colle&bholigct;ion of the whole Summe appointed to be colle&bholigct;ed by them
and payment thereof as is hereby before appointed have and receive for their paines in colle&bholigct;ing and paying the
Moneys Fower pence in the pound which the said Colle&bholigct;ors are impowered to detaine out of the last payment
of the Money of their severall and respe&bholigct;ive Fower Quarterly Payments And the said Receiver Generall upon
the Receipt of the whole Assessment of the County City or Towne for which he is appointed Receiver Generall
in case he hath received the severall Duplicates of each Parish or Place therein and not otherwise shall allow and
pay according to such Warrant as shall be in that behalfe given by the said Commissioners or any three of them
One penny in the Pound for the Commissioners Clerks for their paines in faire writeing the Assesments Duplicates
and Copyes.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s40">
			<head>XL. Persons charged refusing, &amp;c. to pay; Distress.</head>
			<para id="p188">
				<emph type="i">Colle&bholigct;ors may break open Doors, Chest, &amp;c.; calling in Constables, &amp;c. who are to aid Colle&bholigct;ors</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p189">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That if any person shall refuse or negle&bholigct; to pay any Summe of Money
whereat he shall be rated and assessed that then it shall and may be lawfull to and for the said Colle&bholigct;ors or any
of them who are hereby authorized and required thereto to levy the Summe assessed by distresse and sale of the
Goods of such person soe refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing to, pay dedu&bholigct;ing the Summe assessed and reasonable charges
of destraining and restoreing the overplus to the Owner thereof and to breake open in the day time any House
and upon Warrant under the Hands and Seales of two or more of the said Commissioners any Chest Trunke Box
or other things where any such Goods are and to call to their assistance the Constables Tythingmen and Headburroughs
within the Countyes Cityes Townes and Places where any refusall negle&bholigct; or resistance shall be made which said
Officers are hereby required to be aiding and assisting in the Premisses as they will answere the contrary at their
perils.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s41">
			<head>XLI. Queftions upon Distress determined by Commissioners.</head>
			<para id="p190">And if any question or difference happen upon takeing of such distresses upon the partyes distressed or destrained
the same shall be ended and determined by the said Commissioners or any two or more of them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s42">
			<head>XLII. Persons conveying away Goods, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p191">
				<emph type="i">Commissioners may imprison,; except Peers.; Tenants may pay Rate, and dedu&bholigct;.;Landlords to allow Dedu&bholigct;ion</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p192">And if any person or persons shall negle&bholigct; or refuse to pay his or their Assessment or convey his or their
Goods or other personall Estate whereby the Summes of Money soe assessed cannot be levyed according to this
A&bholigct; Then the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any two or more of them are hereby authorized to imprison the
person (except a Peere or Peeres of this Realme) and him and them in Prison to detaine and keepe untill the
Moneys soe assessed and the Charges for the bringing in the same be paid and satisfyed and noe longer And
the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Tenant or Tenants of all Houses and Lands which shall be rated by vertue of this
A&bholigct; are hereby [authorized and required<ref idref="n24">24</ref>] to pay such Summe or Summes of Money as shall be rated upon such
Houses or Lands and to dedu&bholigct; out of the Rent soe much of the said Rates as in respe&bholigct; of the said Rents of every
such House and Lands the Landlord should and ought to pay and beare and the said Landlords both mediate
and immediate according to their respe&bholigct;ive Interests are hereby required to allow such dedu&bholigct;ions and payments
upon the Receipt of the residue of their Rents.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s43">
			<head>XLIII. Tenant paying, acquitted to amount of Payment.</head>
			<para id="p193">And it is ena&bholigct;ed and declared That every Tenant paying the said Assessment shall be acquitted and discharged
for soe much Money as the said Assessment shall amount unto as if the same had beene a&bholigct;ually paid unto such
person or persons to whome his Rents should have beene due and payable.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s44">
			<head>XLIV. If Difference between Landlord and Tenant as to Rate, Commissioners may settle the same.</head>
			<para id="p194">
				<emph type="i">If over Rate, appeal to Commissioners</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p195">And if any differences shall arise betweene Landlord and Tenant or any other concerning. the said Rates the
said severall Commissioners or any two or more of them in their severall Divisions shall and have hereby power
to setle the same as they shall thinke fitt And if any person or persons shall finde him or themselves agreived
in that the Assessors have overrated him or them and shall in six dayes after demand made of the Summe of
Money assessed on him or them complaine to two or more Commissioners whereof one of the Commissioners
who signed or allowed his or their Assesments to be one the said Commissioners or any two or more of them
shall have and have hereby power within twelve dayes after the demand of the Assessment as aforesaid to relieve
such person or persons and to charge the same on such other person or persons as they shall see cause</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s45">
			<head>XLV. In case Proportions of Rate are not fully assessed, or assessed upon Persons not of Ability;</head>
			<para id="p196">
				<emph type="i">or upon Empty House, &amp;c.; or if Assessments not paid to Receiver General; Commissioners, Assessors, &amp;c. are to assess or reassess.; Such new Assessment to be made, &amp;c. as the former Assessment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p197">And in case the proportion sett by this A&bholigct; upon all and every the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cities Townes and
Places shall not be fully assessed levyed and paid according to the true meaneing hereof or that if any of the
said Assessments shall be rated and imposed upon any person not being of ability to pay the same or upon any
empty or void House or Land where the same cannot be colle&bholigct;ed or levyed or that through any wilfulnes
negligence mistake or accident the said Assessment charged on each County City Towne or Place by vertue of this
A&bholigct; happens not to be paid to the Receiver Generall his Deputy or Deputyes of the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes as in this
A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed That then in all and every such Cases the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners Assessors and
Colle&bholigct;ors aforesaid and every of them respe&bholigct;ively are hereby authorized and required to assesse or reassesse or
cause to be assessed or reassessed levyed and paid all and every such summe and summes of Money upon the
respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cityes Townes and Places or upon any the Divisions Hundreds and Parishes therein as to
the said Commissioners or such number of them as by this A&bholigct; are authorized to cause the first Assessment hereby
required to be made shall seeme most agreeable to Equity and Justice the said new Assessment to be made
colle&bholigct;ed and paid in such manner and by such meanes as in this A&bholigct; for this Assessment is declared and
dire&bholigct;ed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s46">
			<head>XLVI. Persons not executing A&bholigct;, Commissioners may fine not exceeding &pound;20, for One Offence to be levied by Distress;</head>
			<para id="p198">
				<emph type="i">and paid to Receiver General, and by him into the Exchequer</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p199">And bee it further declared and ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any person or persons shall wilfully
negle&bholigct; or refuse to performe his or their duty in the due and speedy execution of this present A&bholigct; the said
respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any three or more of them have hereby power to impose on such person or persons
soe refuseing or negle&bholigct;ing their dutyes such Fine or Fines as by them shall be thought fitt and to cause the same
to be levyed by distresse and sale of his and their Goods. Provided That noe Fine to be imposed by any of the
said Commissioners shall for any one offence exceede the summe of Twenty pounds and that all Fines that shall
be imposed by vertue of this A&bholigct; shall be paid to the respe&bholigct;ive Receivers Generall and by them to the Receipt
of His Majestyes Exchequer.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s47">
			<head>XLVIL. Colle&bholigct;or negle&bholigct;ing to pay, or detaining Monies;</head>
			<para id="p200">
				<emph type="i">Proceedings by Commissioners; Commissioners so proceeding, to appoint a General Meeting of Commissioners; Notice thereof.; Colle&bholigct;ors not paying; Proceedings by Commissioners, or such General Meeting</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p201">And it is further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That if any Colle&bholigct;or that shall by vertue of this A&bholigct; be appointed for
the receipt of any summe or summes of Money thereby to be assessed negle&bholigct; or refuse to pay any summe or
summes of Money which shall by him be received as aforesaid and to pay the same as in and by this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed
&amp; shall [detaine in his or their Hands any Money received by them or any of them &amp; not pay the same as by
this A&bholigct; is dire&bholigct;ed<ref idref="n25">25</ref>] the Commissioners of each County City (<ref idref="n26">26</ref>) Towne respe&bholigct;ively or any two or more of them in
their respe&bholigct;ive Divisions are hereby authorized and impowered to imprison the person and seize and secure the
Estate both Reall and Personall of such Colle&bholigct;or to him belonging or which shall descend or come into the
Hands or possession of his Heires Executors or Administrators where ever the same can be discovered and found
And the said Commissioners who shall soe seize and secure the Estate of any Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors shall be and
are hereby impowered to appoint a time for the Generall Meeting of the Commissioners for such County City
Towne or Place and there to cause publique notice to be given at the place where such Meeting shall be appointed ten
dayes at least before such Generall Meeting and the Commissioners present at such Generall Meeting or the major
part of them in case the Moneys detained by any Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors be not paid or satisfyed as it ought to
be according to the dire&bholigct;ions of this A&bholigct; shall and are hereby impowered and required to sell and dispose of
all such Estates which shall be for the cause aforesaid seized and secured or any part of them and satisfie and
pay such County and Place the summe that shall be soe detained in the hands of such Colle&bholigct;or or Colle&bholigct;ors
their Heires Executors and Administrators respe&bholigct;ively.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s48">
			<head>XLVIII. At the Expiration of Times for quarterly Payments, Commissioners are to call Colle&bholigct;ors before them, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p202">
				<emph type="i">and in case of Failure, Commissioners to cause same to be levied and paid</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p203">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That at the Expiration of the respe&bholigct;ive times in this A&bholigct;
prescribed for the full payment of the said Fower Quarterly Assessments the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners
or any two of them within their Division and Hundred shall and are hereby required to call before them the
Colle&bholigct;ors within each respe&bholigct;ive Division and Hundred to examine and assure themselves of the full and whole
payment of the particular summe and summes of Money charged upon the same Division Hundred and every Parish
and Place therein and of the due returne of the same into the Hands of the Receivers Generall their Deputy or Deputyes
of the said County City Towne and Place respe&bholigct;ively and by such Receiver Generall into the Receipt of His
Majestyes Exchequer to the end there may be noe failer (<ref idref="n27">27</ref>) of any part of the Assessment by vertue of this A&bholigct; to
be assessed and paid nor any Arreares remaine chargeable upon the said Countyes Cityes Townes or Places
respe&bholigct;ively and in case of any failer in the Premisses the said Commissioners or any two of them are hereby to
cause the same to be forthwith levyed and paid according to the true intent and meaning of this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s49">
			<head>XLIX. On Questions in which Commissioners concerned, they have no Voice.</head>
			<para id="p204">And it is hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That in case any Controversie arise concerning the said Assessment or
the divideing apportioning or payment thereof which concerns any the Commissioners by this A&bholigct; appointed That
the Commissioners soe concerned in the said Controversie shall have noe voice but shall withdraw at the time of
the debate of any such Controversie untill it bee determined by the rest of the Commissioners</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s50">
			<head>L. Privileged Places or Persons, &amp;c. not exempt from Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p205">
				<emph type="i">Fee Farm and other Rents, Annuities, &amp;c. liable.; Tenants to pay proportionably; indemnified from further Payment</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p206">And bee it hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That noe priviledged Place or Person Body Pollitique or Corporate
within the Countyes Cityes and Townes aforesaid shall bee exempted from the said Assessments and Taxes and
that they and every of them and alsoe all Fee Farme Rents and all other manner of Rents Payments Summes of
Money Annuityes issueing out of any Lands within City or County shall be lyable towards the payment of every
Summe by this A&bholigct; to be taxed and levyed and all the Tenants of every Fee Farme Rent other Rent Summes
of Money or Annuityes aforesaid are hereby dire&bholigct;ed and authorized to pay them proportionably according to the
Rates and Assessments by this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ed and appointed and all such Tenants shall be hereby saved and kept
harmelesse by authoritie of this A&bholigct; from any further payment of such Portion of any such Rent Rents Summes
or Annuityes either to the Exchequer or to any other person or persons to whome any such Rent Rents Summes
of Money or Annuityes as aforesaid should or ought to be paid to all intents and purposes whatsoever as fully and
amply as if they had paid the same into the Exchequer or to any person or persons to whome the same is
reserved or become due.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s51">
			<head>LI. Proviso for the Colleges in the Two Universities, the Colleges of Windsor, Eton, Winchester, and Westminster, and for Hospitals, in respe&bholigct; of the Scitea of Colleges, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p207">Provided That nothing contained in this A&bholigct; be extended to charge any Colledge or Hall in either of the
two Universities or of the Colledges of Windsor Eaton Winton or Westminster or any Hospitall for or in respe&bholigct;
of the Scites of [any<ref idref="n28">28</ref>] the said Colledges Halls or Hospitalls nor any Master Fellow or Scholler of any such Colledge
or Hall or in any other Free Schools or any Reader Officer or Minister of the said Universityes Colledges or
Schools or of any Hospitalls or Almeshouses for or in respe&bholigct; of any Stipend Wages or Proffitts whatsoever ariseing
or growing due to them, in respe&bholigct; of their said severall Places and Imployments in the said Universities Colledges
Schools Hospitalls or Almeshouses nor to charge any of the Houses or Lands belonging to Christs Hospitall Saint
Bartholimews Bridewell Saint Thomas and Bethlehem Hospitall in the City of London and Burrough of Southwarke
or any of them for or in respe&bholigct; of any Rents or Revenews, payable to the said Hospitalls being to be received
and disbursed for the immediate use and reliefe of the poore in the said, Hospitalls.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s52">
			<head>LII. Houses held by Lease from Hospitals to be rated at their yearly Value.</head>
			<para id="p208">Provided That noe Tennants that hold and enjoy any Lands or Houses by Lease or other Grant from any
of the said Hospitalls doe claime and enjoy any freedome exemption or advantage by this A&bholigct; but that all the Houses
and Lands which they soe hold shall be rated and assessed for soe much as they are yearely worth over and above
the Rents reserved and payable to the said Hospitalls,</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s53">
			<head>LIII. Person having a House in one Parish, &amp;c. and Goods in another, to be charged for such Goods, &amp;c. where he dwells.</head>
			<para id="p209">Provided alsoe That where any person inhabiting within the City of London hath his Dwelling House in
one of the Parishes or Wards therein and hath any Goods Wares or Merchandices in one [or more<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] of
the other Parishes or Wards within the same That then such person shall be charged taxed and assessed
for such his Goods or Merchandices in the Parishes or Ward where he dwelleth and not elsewhere within the
said City.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s54">
			<head>LIV. No Clause in this A&bholigct;; to extend to lessen the Rate.</head>
			<para id="p210">Provided neverthelesse That noe Clause or Provisoe in this A&bholigct; shall extend to the lessening or abatement of
the full Summe by this A&bholigct;; appointed to be taxed levyed colle&bholigct;;ed and paid but that the same be fully assessed
taxed [colle&bholigct;ed levyed<ref idref="n30">30</ref>] and paid in the severall and respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cityes and Townes aforesaid in such manner
and forme and to such uses as herein before is mentioned and declared</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s55">
			<head>LV. Proceedings in case the assessing by Pound Rate be found to obstru&bholigct; the speedy bringing in of the Assessment.</head>
			<para id="p211">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby ena&bholigct;ed and declared That in case the way or manner of assessing by a
Pound Rate shall prove any waves prejudiciall or obstru&bholigct;ive to the said speedy bringing in of the Assessment or any
part thereof appointed by this A&bholigct; That then and in all such cases the respe&bholigct;ive Commissioners or any two or
more of them are hereby authorized to order and dire&bholigct; their respe&bholigct;ive Assessors who are hereby required to
proceede accordingly to assesse the respe&bholigct;ive Summes charged on the respe&bholigct;ive Countyes Cityes and Burroughs
Towns and Places mentioned in this A&bholigct; according to the most just and usuall Rates held and pra&bholigct;iced in such
Countyes Cityes Burroughs Townes and Places respe&bholigct;ively Any thing in this A&bholigct; to the contrary thereof contained
in any wise notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s56">
			<head>LVI. Proviso for Contra&bholigct; between Landlords and Tenants.</head>
			<para id="p212">Provided alwayes That nothing in this A&bholigct; contained shall be construed to alter change determine or make void
any Contra&bholigct;s Covenants or Agreements whatsoever betweene the Landlord and Tenant touching the payment of Taxes
and Assessments Any thing herein before mentioned to the contrary notwithstanding</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s57">
			<head>LVII. Places used to be assessed, to be assessed and pay in such Counties, &amp;c. as heretofore.</head>
			<para id="p213">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and declared by the Authority aforesaid That for the avoiding of
all obstru&bholigct;ions and delayes in colle&bholigct;ing the summes by this A&bholigct; to be rated and assessed all Places Constablewicks
Divisions and Allotments which have used to be rated and assessed shall pay and be assessed in such County
Hundred Rape or Wapentake as the same have heretofore beene usually assessed in and not elsewhere.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s58">
			<head>LVIII. A&bholigct;ion brought touching Execution of this A&bholigct;;</head>
			<para id="p214">
				<emph type="i">General Issue; Treble Costs</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p215">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the authority aforesaid That if any A&bholigct;ion Plaint Suite or Information shall be
Commenced or prosecuted against any person or persons for what he or they shall doe in pursuance or in execution
of this A&bholigct; for or concerning the assessing colle&bholigct;ing levying and raising the said summe of Fower hundred twelve
thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fowerteene shillings and six pence such person or persons soe sued in
any Court whatsoever shall and may pleade the Generall Issue (Not guilty) and upon any Issue joyned may give
this A&bholigct; and the speciall matter in evidence and if the Plaintiffe or Prosecutor shall become Nonsuite or forbeare
further Prosecution or suffer a Discontinuance or if a Verdi&bholigct; passe against him the Defendants shall recover their
treble Costs for which they shall have the like remedy as in any case where Costs by the Law are given to
Defendants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s59">
			<head>LIX. Proviso for a Decree in Chancery respe&bholigct;ing Lands in Sheriff Hales, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p216">Provided alwayes That nothing in this A&bholigct; shall [be construed to extend or<ref idref="n31">31</ref>] invalidate a Decree lately made in
the High Court of Chauncery for the quieting of Suites betweene the Countyes of Salop and Stafford and for the
setleing all future payments to be imposed on certaine Lands in Sheriffe Hales within the County of Salop and for
exempting the said Lands from paying hereafter with the County of Stafford but that the said Decree shall remaine
in such (and noe other) force as it did before the makeing of this A&bholigct; Any thing herein to the contrary
notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s60">
			<head>LX. Receivers General and their Deputies to give Acquittances to Colle&bholigct;ors without Fee.</head>
			<para id="p217">
				<emph type="i">Such Acquittances to be a Discharge</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p218">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authority aforesaid That the severall Receivers Generall which shall
be appointed according to this A&bholigct; their Deputy or Deputyes shall from time to time at every payment appointed
thereby give unto the severall Colle&bholigct;ors within their respe&bholigct;ive Precin&bholigct;s upon the payment of the whole summe
due at such times of payment from their respe&bholigct;ive Parishes Constablewicks or Places within each of their
Colle&bholigct;ions severall Acquittances under their hands without takeing any thing for the same and that in like manner
at every time of payment appointed by this A&bholigct; the Receiver Generall of each County his Deputy or Deputyes shall
give unto the severall Colle&bholigct;ors aforesaid upon the payment of the whole summe or any part thereof due for their
Parish or Place respe&bholigct;ively at each time of Payment aforesaid severall Acquittances under their hands and seales
without takeing any thing for the same which said Acquittance of the Receiver Generall his Deputy or Deputyes
shall be a [sufficient<ref idref="n32">32</ref>] Discharge to the Colle&bholigct;ors [&amp; the said Acquittances of the Receiver Generall his Deputy or
Deputyes shall be a sufficient Discharge to the Colle&bholigct;ors<ref idref="n29">29</ref>] and to such Parish and Place respe&bholigct;ively and to every
person charged within the said Colle&bholigct;ors Charge against His Majestie His Heires and Successors for the summe [and<ref idref="n34">34</ref>]
summes of Money soe acquitted.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s61">
			<head>LXI. Where Lands, &amp;c. unoccupied, and no Distress found, Colle&bholigct;ors, Constables, &amp;c. of Parish obliged to pay may enter and distrain;</head>
			<para id="p219">
				<emph type="i">Proceedings thereon</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p220">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That in case any Lands or Houses in any Parish or Place or
Constablewick shall be unoccupyed and noe Distresses can be found on the same by reason whereof the said
Parish Place or Constablewicke are forced to pay and make good the Taxe assessed upon the said Land lyeing
unoccupyed that then it shall and may be lawfull at any time after for the Colle&bholigct;ors Constables or Tythingmen
of the said Parish Place or Constablewicke for the time being to enter and destraine upon the said Lands or
Houses when there shall be any Distresse thereupon to be found and the Distresse and Distresses being the
proper Goods of the owner or any claimeing any Estate Interest or Proffitt under him if not redeemed within
fower dayes by payment of the Taxe and charge, of the Distresse to sell rendering the overplus to the owner or
owners of such Distresse and the said Colle&bholigct;or Constable or Tythingman is hereby enjoyned to distribute the
Money raised by the said Distresse or sale thereof proportionably to the partyes who contributed to the Tax of
the said unoccupyed Lands.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s62">
			<head>LXII. Where Wood-lands assessed, and no Distress had, Colle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. may enter and cut Wood, &amp;c. growing;</head>
			<para id="p221">
				<emph type="i">Buyers of such Wood may sell the same, rendering Overplus to Owner</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p222">Provided alwayes and bee it ena&bholigct;ed That where any Woodlands shall be assessed and noe Distresse can be
had That in such case it shall and may be lawfull (<ref idref="n35">35</ref>) for any Constable Colle&bholigct;or Headburrough or Tythingman by
Warrant under the hands and seales of two or more of the Commissioners of that Hundred or Division at
seasonable times of the yeare to cutt and sell to any person or persons soe much of the Wood growing on the
Woodlands soe assessed as will pay the Assessment or Assessments to be behinde and unpaid and the Charge
incident therunto And that it shall and may be lawfull for the person and persons and his and their Assignes to
whome such Woods shall be sold to sell cutt downe dispose and carry away the same to his owne use rendering
the Overplus (if any be) to the Owner Any [thing<ref idref="n36">36</ref>] to the contrary notwithstanding.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s63">
			<head>LXIII. Proceedings where Assessment charged on Property not ; distrainable.</head>
			<para id="p223">Provided alwayes and bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That where, any Tax or Assessment shall be (<ref idref="n37">37</ref>) laid upon any
Tythes Tolls Proffitts of Markets Faires or Fishery or other Annuall Proffitts not distrainable in case the same
shall not be paid within Fifteene dayes after such Assessment soe charged or laid and demanded then it shall
and may be lawfull to and for the Colle&bholigct;or Constable or other Officer thereunto appointed by Warrant under
the hands and seales of any two or more of the Commissioners authorized by this A&bholigct; to seize take and sell
soe much of the said Tythes Tolls and other Proffitts soe charged as shall be sufficient for the levying of the
said Taxe and Assessments and all Charges occasioned by such non payment thereof rendering the overplus to
the Owner (if any be)</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s64">
			<head>LXIV. Commissioners for Middlessex may appoint Assessors to rate Offices,</head>
			<para id="p224">
				<emph type="i">who are to deliver Surveys to Commissioners; to the end that an equal Pound Rate may be apportioned</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p225">And whereas the County of Midlesex and City of Westminster are raised in the Monethly Assesments by
reason of the new Buildings lately ere&bholigct;ed and that Offices are made chargeable towards the payment of such
Assessments to the end that an equall Rate may be made and imposed upon the sever all Divisions Parishes and
Hambletts within the said County and City Bee it ena&bholigct;ed by this present Parlyament and the Authoritie thereof
That the said Commissioners appointed for the said County and City of Westminster or any Three of them shall
(if they shall thinke fitt) cause two or three of the honest and able Inhabitants in the severall and respe&bholigct;ive
Parishes Towneshipps and Places within the said County and City to be named and appointed Assessors who
(or any two of them) are to ascertaine and rate the yearely value and proffitts of all Offices belonging to the
Courts at Westminster and other Offices chargeable by this A&bholigct; towards the payment of the said summe sett
upon the said County, and City and all Towneships Parishes and Places for which they are appointed Assessors
and to returne the same to the said Commissioners or to such persons as shall be appointed to receive the same
which said Assessors are to deliver in their severall Surveys perfe&bholigct;ed and subscribed by them unto the said
Commissioners or unto such person or persons as shall be appointed by them or any three or more of them to
receive the same two or three dayes at least before the second Generall Meeting of the said Commissioners to the
end that the said Commissioners may deliver in all the severall Surveys to be made throughout the said County at
the said second Generall Meeting at which said Generall Meeting the said Commissioners or the major part of
them [then<ref idref="n38">38</ref>] present shall upon view and perusall of the said severall Surveyes cast up the true Revenue and yearely
Proffitts of the whole County City and Offices aforesaid to the end that an equall Pound Rate may be apportioned
upon every Office chargeable by this A&bholigct; Division Hundred Towneshipp and Parish according to the proportion
and summe of Money charged upon the said County and City by vertue of this present A&bholigct; which the said
Commissioners or the major part of them then and there assembled are by vertue of this A&bholigct; authorized and
appointed to proportion and make accordingly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s65">
			<head>LXV. Proviso for Peers, Clergy, Cinque Ports, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p226">Provided alwayes That nothing herein contained shall be drawne into example to the prejudice of the auntient
Rights belonging to the Lords Spirituall and Temporall or Clergy of this Realme or unto either of the Universityes
or unto any Colledges Schools Alms-houses Hospitalls or Cinque Ports.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s66">
			<head>LXVI. Receiver General certifying Arrears due where Monies have been received;</head>
			<para id="p227">
				<emph type="i">Penalty to Party; Penalty to His Majesty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p228">And for the better preventing of such unjust vexations as might be occasioned by such persons as shall be
appointed Receivers Generall of any of the summes of money granted by this A&bholigct; and to the intent that the
said Receivers Generall may returne a true account into his Majestyes Court of Exchequer of such summes of
Money as shall be received by them and every of them their and every of their Deputy and Deputyes Bee it
further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any such Receiver Generall shall returne or certifie into the
said Court any summe or summes of Money to be in arreare or unpaid after the same have beene received
either by such Receiver Generall or by his Deputy or Deputyes or any of them or shall cause any person or
persons to be sett insuper in the said Court for any Summe or Summes of Money that hath beene soe received
That then every such Receiver Generall shall forfeite to every person and persons that shall be molested vexed
or damaged by reason of such unjust Certificate Returne or setting insuper treble the damages that shall be
thereby occasioned the said damages to be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or Information in which noe
Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or Wager of Law shall be allowed nor any more then one Imparlance and shall alsoe forfeite
to His Majestie His Heires and Successors double the Summe that shall be soe unjustly certifyed or returned or
caused to be sett insuper.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s67">
			<head>LXVII. Quarterly Payments to be made to Receivers General, and by them into Exchequer, within 20 Days after the Times before mentioned.</head>
			<para id="p229">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed, by the Authority aforesaid That the said Fower Quarterly Payments of Thirty fower
thousand fower hundred and ten pounds nine shillings six pence halfe peny per mensem amounting in each
Quarter to the Summe of One hundred and three thousand two hundred thirty one pounds eight shillings seaven
pence halfe peny shall be assessed colle&bholigct;ed levyed and paid to the Receiver Generall of the severall Countyes
that shall be appointed by the times mentioned and expressed in this A&bholigct; and shall be paid by the said Receivers
Generall into His Majesties Receipt of Exchequer within twenty dayes after the times mentioned and expressed
in this A&bholigct;.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s68">
			<head>LXVIII. Colle&bholigct;or unduly keeping Money in Hand, or paying to Persons other than Receiver General, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p230">
				<emph type="i">Penalty &pound;5.; Receiver General or Deputy paying to any other than Exchequer; or paying otherwise so as to hinder Payment into Exchequer; Penalty on Receiver General, &pound;500</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p231">And it is hereby further ena&bholigct;ed and declared That if any Colle&bholigct;or of any Parish or Place shall keepe in his
hand any part of the Money by him colle&bholigct;ed for any longer time then is by this A&bholigct; dire&bholigct;ed other then the
Allowance made unto him, by this A&bholigct; or shall pay any part thereof to any person or persons other then the
Receivers Generall of such County or place or his Deputy That every such Colle&bholigct;or shall forfeite for every
such offence the summe of Five pounds and in case any Receiver Generall or his Deputy shall pay any part of
the Moneys paid to him or them by any Colle&bholigct;ors by vertue of this A&bholigct; to any person or persons (<ref idref="n39">39</ref>) other then
into the Receipt of His Majestyes Exchequer and that at or within the respe&bholigct;ive times limitted within this A&bholigct;
or in case such Receiver Generall or his Deputy shall pay any part of the said Moneys by any Warrant of the
Lord Treasurer Under Treasurer or either of them or Commissioners of the Treasury for the time or by any
Tally of Pro or Talley of Anticipation or other way or device whatsoever whereby to divert or hinder the
a&bholigct;uall payment thereof into the Receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid That such Receiver Generall shall for
every such offence of himselfe or his Deputy forfeite the summe of Five hundred pounds to him or them that shall
sue for the same in any Court of Record by Bill Plaint or other Information wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion or
Wager of Law is to be allowed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s69">
			<head>LXIX. Treasury not to dire&bholigct; Warrant to Colle&bholigct;ors, &amp;c. for Payment other than into Exchequer for to Officers of Exchequer for striking of Tallies of Pro, &amp;c.</head>
			<para id="p232">
				<emph type="i">Officer not to strike, &amp;c. any such Tally, &amp;c</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p233">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer or
Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being or any of them doe not dire&bholigct; any Warrant to any of the
said Colle&bholigct;ors or Receivers Generall or their Deputyes for the payment of any part of these Moneys to any
persons or persons other then into the Receipt of the Exchequer as aforesaid Nor shall they or any of them
dire&bholigct; any Warrant to the Officers of the Exchequer for the strikeing of any Talley of Pro or Talley of
Anticipation nor doe any other matter or thing whereby to divert the a&bholigct;uall payment of the said Moneys into
the Receipt of the Exchequer nor shall the Officers of the Exchequer strike or dire&bholigct; or record the strikeing
of any Talley of Pro or Talley of Anticipation upon any of the said Moneys upon any account or Warrant
whatsoever nor shall the Teller throw downe a Bill whereby to charge himselfe with any of the said Moneys
until he shall have a&bholigct;ually received the same</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s70">
			<head>LXX. Persons lending Money to have Tally of Loan, and Order for Repayment with Interest at &pound;7. per Cent, per Ann. Payable every Three Months.</head>
			<para id="p234">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed and ordained by the Authority aforesaid That all and every person and persons
who shall lend any Moneys not exceeding the summe of Two hundred thousand pound to His Majestie upon
the Credit of the Fower hundred and twelve thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fowerteene shillings and six
pence given by this A&bholigct; and pay the same into the Exchequer shall immediately have a Talley of Loane strucke
for the same and an Order for his repayment beareing the same date with his Talley in which Order shall be
alsoe contained a Warrant for payment of Interest for forbearance after the Rate of Seaven pounds per Cen? per
Ann&bhouov; for his consideration to be paid every three moneths untill the repayment of his Principall.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s71">
			<head>LXXI. Books to be provided.</head>
			<para id="p235">
				<emph type="i">Officer of Exchequer to keep Accounts of the said Monies distin&bholigct;</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p236">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed That there shall be provided and kept in His Majestyes Exchequer (to witt) in the
Office of the Writer of the Talleys and Counter Talleys at the Receipt of the Exchequer commonly called the
Office of the Auditor of the Receipt one Booke or Register in which all Moneys that shall be paid into the
Exchequer as aforesaid upon the said Fower hundred and twelve thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds
fowerteene shillings and six pence shall be entred and registred apart and distin&bholigct; from all other Moneys paid or
payable to His Majestie upon any other account whatsoever and that there be one other Booke or Registry
provided and kept in the said Office of all Orders and Warrants to be made by the Lord Treasurer and Under
Treasurer or by the Commissioners of the Treasury for the time being for payment of all and every summe and
summes of Money to all persons for Moneys lent upon the Creditt of (<ref idref="n40">40</ref>) the said Fower hundred and twelve
thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fowerteene shillings and six pence and alsoe of all other Orders to
be made by the Lord Treasurer and Under Treasurer or either of them or by the Commissioners of the Treasury
for the time being for payment of any of the said Moneys by His Majestyes dire&bholigct;ion and that alsoe there shall
be the like Booke or Registry provided and kept by the said Writer of the Talleys or Auditor as aforesaid of
all Moneys paid out or issued by vertue of such Orders and Warrants.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s72">
			<head>LXXII.</head>
			<para id="p237">
				<emph type="i">Orders for Repayment to be registered according to Date of Tally, and paid in course</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p238">And that it shall be lawfull for any person or persons willing to lend any Money on the Credit of the said
Fower hundred and twelve thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fowerteene shillings and six pence given by
this A&bholigct; and for any other person who is to have Orders registred thereupon at the usuall [time<ref idref="n41">41</ref>] when the
Exchequer shall be open to have accesse into and view and peruse all and every or any of the said Bookes for
their Information of the state of those Moneys and all ingagements upon them for their better encouragement to
lend any Moneys as aforesaid and all Orders, for repayment of Moneys, lent shall be registred in course according
to the Date of the Talleys respe&bholigct;ively and that all other Orders for payments dire&bholigct;ed by His Majestie shall be
registred in course according to the times of bringing the same to the Office of the Writer of the Talleys and
none of the said Orders for Moneys shall have preference one before another but shall be entred in their course
as they are in point of time respe&bholigct;ively before each other</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s73">
			<head>LXXIII. Persons having their Orders first entered to be paid first, and so successively.</head>
			<para id="p239">And all and every person and persons shall be paid in course according as their Orders shall stand entred in
the said Registers Booke of the Receipt soe as the person Native or [Forreigner<ref idref="n42">42</ref>] his or her Executors Administrators
and Assignes who shall have his or her Warrant or Order Warrants or Orders first entred in the said Booke
of Registry in the Exchequer as aforesaid shall be taken and accounted as the first person to bee paid upon
the said Fower hundred and twelve thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fowerteene shillings, and six pence
to come in by vertue of this A&bholigct; and he she or they that shall have his her or their Warrants or Orders
Warrant and Order next entred shall be taken and accounted the second person to be paid and soe successively
and in course</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s74">
			<head>LXXIV. Monies to come in by this A&bholigct; liable to satisfy such Loans.</head>
			<para id="p240">And that the Fower hundred and twelve thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fowerteene shillings and
six pence to come in by this A&bholigct; as aforesaid shall be in the same Order lyable to the satisfa&bholigct;ion of the said
respe&bholigct;ive Partyes their Executors Administrators or Assignes successively without preference of one before another
and not otherwise and not to be divertible to any other use intent or purpose whatsoever</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s75">
			<head>LXXV. No Fee for providing or making Books, &amp;c. or for Payment of Money lent.</head>
			<para id="p241">
				<emph type="i">Penalty; Punishment.; Undue Preference by Officer; Penalty.; Undue Preference by Deputy; Penalty</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p242">And that noe Fee Reward or Gratuity dire&bholigct;ly or indire&bholigct;ly be demanded or taken by any of Your Majestyes
Officers from any of Your Majestyes Subje&bholigct;s for provideing or makeing of any such Bookes Registers Entryes
View Search or any other thing in for or concerning the payment of any Moneys lent or the Interest thereof as
aforesaid or by any of their Clerks or Deputyes on paine of payment of treble damages to the party grieved by
the party offending with Costs of Suite And if any Officer in his owne person shall take, or demand any such
Fee or Reward every such Officer soe offending shall forfeite the Summe of Ten pounds for every such Offence.
And if any undue preference of one before another shall be made in point of registring contrary to the true
meaning of this A&bholigct; by any such Officer or Officers Then the party offending shall be lyeable by A&bholigct;ion of Debt
or on the Case to pay the value of the Debt Damages and Costs to the party grieved and shall be forejudged
from his Place or Office and if such preference be unduely made by any his Deputy or Clerke without
dire&bholigct;ion or Privity of his Master Then such Deputy or Clerke onely shall be lyable to such A&bholigct;ion Debt
Damages and Costs and shall be for ever after uncapeable of his Place or Office</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s76">
			<head>LXXVI. Auditor, Clerk of the Pells, or Teller not making Payments in due Order;</head>
			<para id="p243">
				<emph type="i">Penalty.; How all such Penalties to be recovered</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p244">And in case the said Writer of the Talleys or Auditor as aforesaid shall not dire&bholigct; the Order or the Clerke,
of the Pells record or the Teller thereunto required make payment according to each persons due place and
order as aforedire&bholigct;ed then he or they respe&bholigct;ively shall be adjudged to forfeite his or their Place and Office And.
the respe&bholigct;ive Deputyes and Clerks herein offending shall be lyeable to such A&bholigct;ion, Debt, Damages and Costs in
such manner as aforesaid All which said Penaltyes Forfeitures' Damages and Costs to be incurred by any of the
Officers aforesaid or any their Deputyes or Clerks shall and may be recovered by A&bholigct;ion of Debt Bill Plaint or
Information in any of His Majestyes Courts of Record at Westminster wherein noe Essoigne Prote&bholigct;ion Priviledge
Wager of Law Injun&bholigct;ion Order or Restraint or stay of Prosecution by Non vult ulterius prosequi shall be in any
wise granted or allowed</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s77">
			<head>LXXVII. Proviso where several Tallies bear Date the same Day.</head>
			<para id="p245">Provided alwayes and bee it hereby declared That if it shall happen that severall Orders for the payment of
Loanes or for the payment of Orders dire&bholigct;ed by Your Majestie as aforesaid beare date and be brought the same
day to the (<ref idref="n43">43</ref>) Writer of the Talleys or Auditor of the Receipt to be registred Then it shall be interpreted noe
undue preference which of those he enters first soe as he enters them all the same day</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s78">
			<head>LXXVIII. Paying subsequent Orders, if first demanded, no undue Preference, if sufficient reserved to satisfy preceding Orders.</head>
			<para id="p246">Provided alsoe That it shall not be interpretted any undue preference to incurr any penalty in point of payment
if the said Writer of the Talleys or Auditor dire&bholigct; and the Clerke of the Pells record and the Teller doe. pay
subsequent Orders of persons that come and demand their Money and bring their Orders before other persons
that did not come to, demand their Money and bring their Orders in course soe as there be soe much Money
reserved as will satisfie such Orders which shall not be otherwise disposed but kept for them Interest upon Loane
being to cease from the time the Money is soe reserved and kept in Bank for them.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s79">
			<head>LXXIX. Orders for Payment of Money lent may be assigned by Indorsement.</head>
			<para id="p247">
				<emph type="i">Memorial thereof without Fee.; Assignee may in like manner assign.; Assignee not to release the same</emph>.</para>
			<para id="p248">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That every person or persons to whome any Money
shall be due out of the Fower hundred and twelve thousand nine hundred twenty five pounds fowerteene shillings
and six pence by vertue of this A&bholigct; after Warrant or Orders entred in the Books of Register aforesaid for payment
thereof his Executors Administrators or Assignes by Indorsement upon his Order or Warrant may assigne and
transferr his Right Title Interest and Benefitt of such Warrant or Order or any part thereof to any other which
being notified in the Office of the said Writer of [the<ref idref="n44">44</ref>] Talleys or Auditor of the Receipt aforesaid and an Entry
and Memoriall thereof alsoe made in the Booke of Registry aforesaid for Warrauts which the Officer shall on
request without Fee or Charge accordingly make shall entitle such Assignee his Executors Administrators and
Assignes to the benefitt thereof and payment thereon and such Assignee may in like manner assigne againe and
soe toties quoties and afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person or persons who have made such
Assignements to make void release or discharge the same or any the Moneys thereby due or any part thereof.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">obliterated, on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n2" number="2">Twenty fourth <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n3" number="3">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n4" number="4">Receiver <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n5" number="5">the <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n6" number="6">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n7" number="7">before <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n8" number="8">incapable <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n9" number="9">according <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n10" number="10">Clerkes <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n11" number="11">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n12" number="12">seaventy and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n13" number="13">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n14" number="14">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n15" number="15">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n16" number="16">a <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n17" number="17">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n18" number="18">willfully <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n19" number="19">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n20" number="20">performance <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n21" number="21">and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n22" number="22">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n23" number="23">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n24" number="24">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n25" number="25">required and authorized <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n26" number="26">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n27" number="27">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n28" number="28">in the payment <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n29" number="29">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
			<note id="n30" number="30">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n31" number="31">levyed colle&bholigct;ed <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n32" number="32">extend or be construed to <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n33" number="33">full and perfe&bholigct; <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n34" number="34">or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n35" number="35">to and <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n36" number="36">Law <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n37" number="37">charged or <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n38" number="38">interlined on the Roll.</note>
			<note id="n39" number="39">whatsoever <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n40" number="40">of <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n41" number="41">times <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n42" number="42">forreigne <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n43" number="43">said <emph type="i">O</emph>.</note>
			<note id="n44" number="44">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


