<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47486" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1680</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter I. An Additionall Act for burying in Woollen. [Rot. Parl. 32 C. II. (<ref idref="n1">1</ref>) Recital of 30 C. II. C.3. &sect; 5.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head/>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Reasons for passing this A&bholigct;. Where no Justice resides or is found in the Parish, of Burial, the Parson, Vicar, and Curate (Exception) may take Affidavit of Burial in Woollen only.; Affidavit taken by Parson, &#x0026;c. as effe&bholigct;ual as by 30 C.II.c.3. &sect; 5</emph>.</para>
		<para id="p2">Whereas in one A&bholigct; of Parliament passed in the thirtyeth yeare of his Majestyes Raigne that now is
entituled An A&bholigct; for burying in Woollen it was amongst other things ena&bholigct;ed and ordained That the
Affidavits which were to be made of any persons being interred in Woollen according to the dire&bholigct;ions in the
said A&bholigct; should be made or taken before some one Justice of the Peace or Master of Chauncery Ordinary or
Extraordinary Maior Bayliffe or other Chiefe Officer of the City County Burrough Corporation or Market Towne in
the County where the said partie was buryed who are thereby authorized and required to administer the said Oath
and to attest the same under their Hands upon such Affidavit gratis. And whereas by reason of the distance of
the Habitations of the persons before whome such Affidavit is to be made and other accidents diverse persons
who have had occasion to make such Affidavits have beene necessitated to travell many miles for the makeing
thereof to their great losse of time and hinderance of their other Affaires Bee it therefore ena&bholngs;ed and it is hereby
ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most excellent Majestie by and with the advice and consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and Commons in this present Parliament assembled and by the authoritie of the same That from and
after the second day of February in the yeare of our Lord One thousand six hundred and eighty (where noe
Justice of Peace shall reside or be to be found in any Parish where any party shall be interred) the said Oathes
or Affidavits may be administred not onely by any Justice of the Peace or Master of Chauncery Ordinary or Extraordinary
Maior Bayliffe or other Chiefe Officer of the City, County, Burrough Corporation of Market Towne in the County
where any party was buryed but alsoe that the Parsons Vicars and Curates in every Parish or Chappell of Ease
within the County where any party shall be interred (except onely the Parson Vicar and Curate of the Parish or
Chappell of Ease where the partie is interred concerning whose Interment in Woollen such Affidavit is to be
made) be and are hereby authorized and required to administer the said Oathes or Affidavits and to attest the
same under their Hands gratis, And that every such Affidavit taken before them shall be of like force and effe&bholigct;
as if the same had beene taken and administred by the persons authorized to administer the same by the A&bholigct;
aforesaid.</para>
		<note id="n1" number="1">The A&bholigct;s on this Roll are not numbered.</note>
	</section>
</report>


