<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "../dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="47481" pubid="351" publish="true">
	<title>Charles II, 1677 &amp; 1678</title>
	<subtitle>Chapter IX. An Act for Preservation of Fishing in the River of Seaverne. [Rot. Parl. 30 C. II. pt. 1. nu.9.]</subtitle>
	<section id="s1">
		<head>Fishing in the River Severn contrary, to Stat. 1.Eliz. c. 17. or with Net of undue Mesh; or fishing with more than One Net at a Time;
or taking Fry of Eels; Penalty &pound;5.</head>
		<para id="p1">
			<emph type="i">Watering Hemp or Flax in the said River; Penalty &pound;5.</emph>
		</para>
		<para id="p2">For Preservation of the Fishing in the River of Severne in the Countyes of Worcester Salop and Gloucester and
for the Preventing of severall abuses lately pra&bholigct;ised by diverse persons fishing in the said River tending to
the destruction of the common Piscary especially of the Spawne Fry and young breed of Fish in the said River Bee
it ena&bholigct;ed by the Kings most Excellent Majestie by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spirituall and
Temporall and Commons in this present Parlyament assembled and by the Authority of the same That if any person
or persons whatsoever<ref idref="n1">1</ref> from and after the First day of August next shall in the said River of Severne fish with any
Nett Device or Engine or make use of any Nett Weare Speare or other Engine or Device whatsoever whereby any
Salmon Trout Pike or Barbell under the length appointed by the Statute made in the First yeare of the Raigne
of our late Soveraigne Lady Queene Elizabeth shall be taken or killed or if any person or persons whatsoever shall
from and after the said First day of August within the said River fish with any Nett whatsoever for the takeing
of Salmon Salmon Mart Salmon Peale Pike Carpe Trout Barbell Chub or Grayling the Mesh whereof shall be
under two inches and a halfe square by the Standard and not extended that is to say two inches and a halfe
square from knot to knot allowing to each Mesh fower knots or which shall be above Twenty yards in length
and two yards in breadth or depth or above Fifty yards in length and six yards in breadth or depth in the wing
of the Nett in any part of the said River of Severne from Riple-Lockestacke on the edge of the said County of
Worcester to Gloucester Bridge which is upon the said River of Severn or above Sixty yards in length in any
part of the [said<ref idref="n1">1</ref>] River of Severn below Gloucester Bridge and Six yards in breadth or depth in the wing of the
Nett or shall fish with more then one of those Netts at any one time (that is to say) with two or more fixed
together or with any Drag Nett, Tramell or any other Nett fixed to the same or shall use any Nett Engine
Instrument or Device whatsoever for the takeing of the Fry of Keles commonly called Elvers Every such person
offending as aforesaid shall forfeite the summe of Five pounds for every time that he or they shall fish with any
of the said unlawfull Netts Instruments Devices or Engines and alsoe the Fish soe taken or killed together with
the said unlawfull Netts Engines Devices and Instruments whatsoever they be wherewith' or whereby such offences
shall be made committed or done and alsoe shall forfeite the like summe of Five pounds for every time that he
or they shall water any manner of Hemp or Flax in the said River</para>
		<section id="s2">
			<head>II. Persons, during the Spawning of Fish, laying Nets, &amp;c. in the Fords, &amp;c. of the said River, &amp;c;</head>
			<para id="p3">
				<emph type="i">Penalty 40s.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p4">And bee it further ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie aforesaid That if any person or persons shall dureing the time of
Spawning of Fish (to witt) betweene the First day of March and the last day of May draw or lay any kinde
of Netts Instruments or Engines in the Fords Streames or Shallows of the said River where Fish doth usually
spawne or shall doe or committ or cause to be done or committed any Act whatsoever whereby the Spawne or
small Fry of Fish shall be taken killed or destroyed every such person or persons soe offending shall forfeite
and lose the summe of Forty shillings for every offence and the Netts Instruments or other Engines soe used
placed or imployed for the purposes aforesaid.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s3">
			<head>III. Justices of Peace in Worcester, Salop, and Gloucester, to be Conservators, with Power to make Under Conservators.</head>
			<para id="p5">
				<emph type="i">Warrants to Under Conservators, &amp;c. to search suspected Houses, &amp;c. for Nets, &amp;c. and seize them, such Nets to be burnt, &amp;c.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p6">And to the intent that a perfe&bholigct; execution may be had of this present A&bholigct; bee it ena&bholigct;ed by the Authoritie
aforesaid That the Justices of the Peace within the said respe&bholigct;ive Countyes of Worcester Salop and Gloucester
wherein they shall be Justices shall be and are hereby appointed Conservators of the said River and to make one
or more Under Conservators within their respe&bholigct;ive limitts and that the said Justices of the Peace shall issue forth
their Warrants under the hands and seales of any two of them dire&bholigct;ed to such Under Conservator or Conservators
or to any Constable Tythingman or Headburrough where any such offence shall be committed upon their owne
knowledge or information to them given to search in the day time in all suspe&bholigct;ed Houses and places for all such
Netts Instruments Devices and other Engines and the same to seize and bring before the said Justices or in their
open Quarter Sessions that the said unlawfull Netts Instruments Devices and Engines may upon the view thereof
be burnt destroyed or made uselesse.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s4">
			<head>IV. No Convi&bholigct;ion but by Information, &amp;c. before Justices of Assize, &amp;c. or General Sessions.</head>
			<para id="p7">
				<emph type="i">Convi&bholigct;ion, Court to award Execution for Penalties.</emph>
			</para>
			<para id="p8">Provided alwayes That noe person or persons offending as aforesaid shall be punished for any of the offences
aforesaid unlesse by Information or Indictment before His Majestyes Justices of Assize and Nisi Prius Oyer and
Terminer and Generall Goall Delivery or in the Generall Sessions of the Peace to be holden for the said Countyes
respe&bholigct;ively wherein the same shall be committed And upon convi&bholigct;ion of any person or persons for any of the
offences aforesaid the said respe&bholigct;ive Courts shall award Execution for the said Forfeitures the one Moyety thereof
to the use and benefitt of the Poore of the Parish where the said offence shall be committed and the other
Moyety to such person or persons as shall prosecute the same by Fieri facias or Capias ad satisfaciend? as the
Kings Majestyes Justices at Westminster may and use to doe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s5">
			<head>V. Proviso for Jurisdi&bholigct;ion of Lords of Leet and Franchises.</head>
			<para id="p9">Provided alsoe That this present A&bholigct; or any thing herein contained doe not extend to abridge the Jurisdi&bholigct;ion
of the Lords of Leets or Franchises within their respe&bholigct;ive Leets and Franchises but that they may proceede to
enquire heare and determine any the offences aforesaid within their respe&bholigct;ive Leets and Franchises as formerly they
have lawfully used to doe.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="s6">
			<head>VI. General Saving.</head>
			<para id="p10">Saveing alwayes unto our Soveraigne Lord the King His Heires and Successors and to all and every person and
persons whatsoever all Rights Titles and Interests whatsoever that they either have or may lawfully claime in the
said River as if this A&bholigct; had never beene made.</para>
			<para id="p11">ITEM qu&aelig;da[m] Petitiones privatas personas concernentes (in se forma A&bholigct;us continentes) exhibite fuerunt p&bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o
Domino Regi in Parliamento p&bhopcrl;di&bholigct;o quar? Tituli subscribuntur vizt</para>
			<para id="p12">10. An Act to supply an Omission in the Setlement of the Estate of Sir Trevor Williams Baronet made upon
the Marriage of his eldest Sonne and to enable his eldest Sonne to make a Joynture to a second Wife.</para>
			<para id="p13">11. An Act for encreasing the Revenue of the Deane of Saint Pauls and assureing the Estates of his Tenants
in Shadwell in the County of Midlesex.</para>
			<para id="p14">12. An Act for vesting the Re&bholigct;ory of Westerham in the County of Kent in Trustees to be sold for payment
of the Debts of Edward Gresham Esquire.</para>
			<para id="p15">13. An Act for the better enableing the Trustees of Sir Thomas Cave Knight and Baronet deceased for the
selling of Lands for the performance of the Will of the said Sir Thomas Cave and likewise for the vesting and
selleing of other Lands.</para>
			<para id="p16">14. An Act for, uniteing and consolidating. the Churches of. Beaumont and Mose in the County of Essex.</para>
			<para id="p17">15. An Act on. the behalfe of John Fortescue for the executing certaine Trusts devolved upon Infants.</para>
			<para id="p18">16. An Act, for makeing part of the Parish of Saint Martin in the Fields a new Parish to be called The Parish
of Saint Anne within the Liberty of Westminster.</para>
			<para id="p19">17. An Act to enable Trustees to sell the Lands of Tanfield Mulso Esquire late deceased for payments of his
Debts and makeing provision for his Children.</para>
			<para id="p20">18. An Act for naturalizing of John Schoppens and others.</para>
			<para id="p21">19. An Act to make good a Mortgage made by John Forth deceased to Thomas Cooke and Nicholas Carey
and for makeing provision for Henry Forth sonne of the said John Forth.</para>
			<para id="p22">20. An Act for makeing navigable the River Fale alias Vale in the County of Cornwall.</para>
			<para id="p23">21. An Act to enable Thomas Plater Gen? to sell Lands for payment of Debts charged upon the same and
reimbursing him such summes of Money as he hath or shall lay out in repaireing the Breaches made by the
Inundation of the Sea and keeping the Waters out.</para>
			<note id="n1" number="1">
				<emph type="i">O</emph>. omits.</note>
		</section>
	</section>
</report>


